Hello there.
This is the De La Rue.
And welcome back.
So we looked at primitive variables which have primitive types as the variable types.
And we looked at the primitive types and they come with the Java language.
So they are inbuilt into the language.
So variables can be primitive variables, or they can also be object references.
And with object references, the type of the variable will be a class or an interface, and interfaces
are something that we will discuss later.
But in our student class we created one object reference here in the main method.
Here we are creating a student object and this variable as is an object reference and it's type as the
student class.
So essentially variables can be of two types.
They can be primitive variables or object references.
Now, regardless of whether a variable is primitive or object reference, the variable will play a certain
role depending upon where it is declared.
So it will play a certain role if it is declared here at the class level.
Directly within the class and it will have a different role if it is declared here.
So there are different kinds of variables, three kinds of variables, and we are going to study that
in this particular lecture.
The first kind of variable is called as the instance variables.
So so far we have been saying that variables hold state and those variables are nothing but the instance
variables and they hold the state and they are called as instance variables because they are related
to instances of a class that is nothing but the objects of a class, because instance is a different
term for object.
And in this case the object is the student object.
And these variables, the instance variables, hold the state of that particular student object.
So that's instance variables.
And then another kind of variables are local variables which are declared within the method, and such
local variables help in performing certain computations within the method, and they're called as local
variables because they are local to the method and they cannot be accessed outside of the method, so
they can only be used within the method.
So that's local variables.
And there is also a third kind of variable called static variables, and static variables are also referred
to as class variables because they are specific to the class.
That is, the values that they hold are specific to the class, whereas the values that instance variables
hold are specific to the instances of the class, that is the objects of the class.
So those values are unique to the object, but when it comes to class variables, they are specific
to the class and it will be clear as we are doing the demo.
So it will get clear and the suggestion I have is as I'm going to demo this program, I would also like
you to type in the program because here we are going to create multiple objects and we are also going
to initialize their state.
So it will also give you a good feel of creating objects and initializing their state.
And that's a very important step when we are learning about object oriented programming.
So that's the first step and you will get a good feel for that.
So if possible, do try to implement as I am demonstrating this program.
So let's get started and let's get started off with the instance variables.
First thing is, let me change this age to eight.
So this is our student class and we have all we have the state here and the student object is created
in the main method and we just have one method called compute where we are displaying all of the values
and here we are just computing the tuition fees depending upon whether the student is an international
student or not.
So that's just a quick recap of the student class.
So the reason I'm changing it to end is because we said that one of the suggestions is to stick to only
eight and double.
Right now long is needed because form can have a value that is outside the range of eight.
And so we are using the long type.
So this is what we have and thus here the student does not have a name, so he's an anonymous student.
So let's give the student a name.
So let's declare a variable called name whose type is string.
And as I mentioned earlier, strings will be discussed later, but they are initialized in this way.
So we are initializing using a string literal.
So the name is John.
Next, let's also create another variable called gender.
And let's initialize it to mail.
So this is the student object, and the student object is created here.
Now, let's say I want to create another student object who will have a different state.
Now, how would that be possible?
Because the student state is already defined here.
So how can we create a second object and give that student a different state?
So for that, we need to initialize it in a different way.
We need to use the DOT operator and we have to do it from the main method.
So here we are hardcoded in the state and we shouldn't be doing that.
So let me just take all of these things here.
Let me just copy them so that we can initialize the state here.
Now here, let's call it a student one because we are going to create multiple students.
This and dot.
Object reference on DOT.
And here, let's initialize it to false.
So, John, as not an international student.
So let me just indent this and then align it so that it looks clean and neat.
And here this is for the compute method.
So that's what you would do if you want to initialize the state.
So you would say object reference dot the variable name and you would assign a value to it.
So this is not the normal convention to initialize the state.
Typically you would initialize the state using constructors.
And constructors are something that we will look at towards the end of this section.
So but this this way is also fine.
It's just not the normal convention.
So this is how the variable can be accessed and this is how the method is invoked using the object reference
followed by a dot followed by either the name of the variable or the method name.
And here, let's also remove all of these because we are initializing the state using the object reference.
So here they will all get default values for ID.
We know it gets a zero value string is an object and it gets a value of null.
And we will look at that later.
Phone will be zero.
GPA will be initialized.
Will get a default of zero and international as boolean.
So it gets a value of false.
We know that.
And these two, let's leave it like this with this initial values because they would be common for all
of the students.
So let's leave it like that.
So for instance, variables will get default values and they need to be declared directly within the
class here and here.
Let me.
Add something first, let's add an empty line here so that when we are creating multiple objects and
printing their data, there will be at least one empty line separating the different data that we have
that we are displaying.
And let's also print.
The new variables called name and gender.
So we have everything set up now.
And let's go ahead and compile and run it.
If you go.
So it prints all of the values here.
John Mill 18 and so on.
So that's how you do it.
So that's the first to object.
Let's go ahead and create the second student object.
So that's how you would create an object and initialize the state.
And this is the second student.
So let's, let's call it a student to.
Okay.
It's a new student object.
And it will we will invoke the compute method on the student object.
So let's change the data.
Let's say the ID is 1001 name.
Let's change it to Raj.
Male as a gender, it's age is 21.
Let's make this 9999 GPA, let's say 3.4 and degree.
Let's say he is a master student international.
Let's make it true.
And that's it.
So this is the first student object and the information of that particular student.
And then we are creating a new student here and we are initializing the state.
And then when we invoke the compute method, it prints all of this data about the second student.
So now I would want you to do something.
So here are how some sample data for you.
So I want you to create a third student object, call the variable student three and just initialize
the state in this way.
But using this data.
So the name is Anita, gender is female, it's her age for Gpps 4.0.
It's a perfect 4.0.
So Anita is a good student, so just pause the video and create these different statements.
So I have the code here.
So let me just copy it and.
I mean, replace this with this.
And I hope you have already created these statements.
That's it.
So we have the new student.
So that's how you would create objects and initialize the state.
And each object has its own unique state.
So that's done using the instance variables.
Now let's look at the second kind of variable.
So you're invoking this compute method.
Let's say we want to keep track of the number of times this method is invoked.
And it doesn't matter whether we are invoking it via student one or student two or student three.
So for instance, here, if we invoke the count, should be one.
And here the count should be incremented to two.
And we are invoking when we are invoking it for the third time, it needs to be incremented to three.
So we want to monitor that the number of times the compute method is being invoked.
So for that, let's introduce a new variable called.
Compute count, let's call it as compute count.
And it also gets a default of zero.
And since we want to increase the count value when compute method is accessed.
So we will.
Incremented here.
Plus one.
So that's how we would increment.
And let's also print the output here.
So let's go ahead and see what we get.
Recompile run it.
So the compute count is one.
It's one here and it's one here.
It should have been two here and it should have been three here.
And the reason I think you might have guessed, because compute count is an instance variable and it
is specific to the object only.
Right.
So when here when we are invoking compute count because it is 2.1, the compute count would be zero.
And when we invoke compute here, it gets incremented to one.
Now when we create second student object once again for the second student object, compute count would
be zero and it gets incremented to one in the compute method and same goes with the third student object
also.
So it would be zero initially and it's incremented to one.
So that's not what we want.
We want the value of compute to be incremented each time compute method is invoked.
So it needs to be a global value.
And for that we will use a class variable.
So it has got nothing to do with object.
It needs to be a class variable, which is nothing but the static variable.
So we need to add this keyword called static, and with that it's going to be a static variable and
static variable will hold values that are unique to the class itself.
And we know that objects are created from the class.
So now if we recompile.
As you can see, it is one here, two here and three here.
So a compute is always going to increment.
So let me just copy this.
Thus three more times.
So.
And you will see that.
It would have got finally it would have got incremented to six.
Here it is complete control.
Incremented to six, five, four, five, six.
So that's because of these three statements that we are adding.
So that's how it works.
So that's the static variable.
It maintains a single copy of the variable.
So the variables value will be like a global value and each time it is incremented, or if we change
that, the same value will be accessible to all of the objects or even to some other class that is accessing
the student.
So what I mean is so here we are directly accessing the compute count here and we are displaying it.
But let's say if there is an external class, another class which wants to access the compute count
value, then it can also do that.
And all it needs to do is it needs to say the class name, which is student dot, the variable name,
which is compute code.
So that's how it can access it.
Let's assume let's also do that.
So let's print.
That value using the class name.
So just assume that here.
Let's call it student dot compute code because it is a class variable.
We are using the class name to access it.
So just assume that this particular statement is in some other class.
And from that some other class.
If you want to access this variable, we need to qualify that variable using the name of the class student.
So that's what we are doing here.
So.
Her recompile.
You could hear it as printing the value three.
So this is the last value at this instance of time.
Now you can also do this.
You can, instead of the name of the class, you can still use an object reference.
If we have an object reference here, so that's also fine.
It still shows the value of three.
Although we have used the student to the object reference.
That is fine, but it is still valid.
But it is not the recommended way to do it because it is an a static variable.
It needs to be accessed using the name of the class.
It is a class variable.
As I said, class variable is another name for student for static variable, and the proper way to access
it is using the class of the variable, which is student.
Otherwise it leads to unreadable code if you are using the student object references.
So that's the thing.
And here, also here you cannot.
So this is, for instance, for your international.
We are using an object reference, but for to access instance variables, we cannot use the class name.
So if you do this, then that will lead to a compilation error because these are instance variables
and instance variables have to be accessed using object references.
You cannot use the class variables.
The class name.
Class name is only for class variables and to access state you need to use the object reference OC the
particular object reference so that you get the state of that particular object.
So that's one thing.
So those are instances and static variables and here is some notes about them.
So both of them have to be declared at the class level.
So they need to be declared here in the class level and they will be visible in the entire class.
So you cannot declare them within a method.
So if you do that, then they are no longer instance or static variables.
So in the method you will only have local variables.
So they have to be declared here and they call it as the scope of the variable.
So if you declare them here, the scope will be the entire class.
We will discuss the scope later on in a more formal way, scope of the variables, which is nothing
but where the variable is accessible.
But we will discuss that later in a more formal way, in a different lecture, but at least you need
to be aware of that.
So the scope is entire class and they all get default values.
So here also this has got a default value of zero because the type is end and for this instance variable
also it gets a default of zero and they cannot be initialized directly but within the class and we already
know about this, so you cannot so here the default value is zero.
Now you cannot do this.
So this was demonstrated in the lecture on variables introduction.
So you cannot do like this because that would be wrong.
So this is an assignment statement.
An assignment statements can appear only in methods or constructors or places like that, but within
the class.
So I'm calling this as the class level because here we are directly within the class classes body.
You can only have declaration statements.
So that's what this says.
And we have already seen that earlier.
So that's those three are common to both instance and static variables.
They're declared at class level, their scope is entire class and they get a default value, both of
them, and they cannot be initialized directly within the class.
Now instance represents the state of the represents object state instance variables.
So the values are unique to the object as we have seen.
And if you want to access from outside the class, you can do it via object reference like the way we
are doing it here.
Typically all of this code would be in some other class OC main method is just for testing, but it
would be in some other class.
And this is how you would access the variables of the methods.
We are the object reference, but within the class itself, within the method, you can access them
directly, like the way we are doing here.
But outside of the class you would have to you can use an object reference and for static values are
unique to the class so only one copy is maintained per class and that value will be shared across all
the objects and even classes.
Other classes can access it using the class name and both instance and static variables are also referred
to as fields or attributes.
Typically when somebody says fields, they would be referring to instance variables.
So just keep that in mind.
Attributes is also probably more commonly associated with instance variables, but typically among the
two, mostly you will hear the term fields.
So if you hear me using the word field, generally think that it would be an instance variable.
So that's the second one.
Now let's look at the third variable kind of variable called local variables, and local variables are
declared within a method.
Here is a local variable next ID and they help in performing certain computations and they are local
to the method and they cannot be accessed outside of the method.
And local variables are declared here, but they can also include method parameters which are declared
here in between the parentheses.
So when we declare, when we discuss methods formally, we will also discuss method parameters and true
method parameters.
Some data can be passed to the methods.
So here in the main method we do have this variable called ARX.
So this is a string array and array will be discussed later.
But this is a, this is a method parameter and this would also be considered as a local variable.
So in the main method we have for local variables, one is ARX and we have three object references.
Student one.
Student three All of those are local variables.
So totally we have four local variables in the main method and here we have one.
So and local variables are not accessible outside of the method, which means that their scope ends
only with the method.
So they start here at the point of declaration and their scope ends at the end of the method, so you
cannot access it.
So let me just have a print statement here, for instance.
Or Let's make it.
Student three dot next ID and let's compile and see.
You know, it says next ID cannot find the symbol next ID, so the variable next ID is something that
the compiler is unable to find because it is not declared in this method.
So it's only visible here.
So it exists.
It is alive only as long as this method is executing.
When you invoke the compute method, then next it will be there and its scope.
Well, it starts here and ends here.
That's the scope of the local variable.
And here we have seen that the scope of static and instance variable variables will be for the entire
class.
Now local variables.
One thing I mentioned earlier is that local variables do not get a default value.
So we also saw this earlier, but let me just show it to you one more time.
So let me remove that.
So that's the fees, international fees.
So here it will not get an default value, but we are trying to use it here.
So when we compile it.
So it says variable internal international feeds might not have been initialized.
So it needs to be initialized here or it needs to be initialized right before or somewhere before it
is accessed for the first time.
It is being accessed here somewhere.
It needs to be initialized.
So this is also good and we know about that.
So it compiles fine and if you execute it, you will see the output.
So default variables do not get a sorry, local variables do not get any default values.
But these variables static an instance do get a default values.
So let's quickly also address why that's the case.
Now, let's say, for instance, here they get a default value, but let's assume that they do not get
a default value.
So let's say it does not get a default value.
So it is kind of undefined.
Now, if we invoke the compute method here in the main method, when we invoke the compute method,
so control comes here and what would ID value be right?
Because it has not been initialized.
It has not been initialized.
And it is also not getting any default value.
So it will be undefined and we may get some unexpected output.
So for that reason, these variables, both of these variables get a different value.
But when it comes to local variables here.
Here.
Here the developer is using this variable and the intention of the developer is to use this variable
to perform some computation.
So here, when, when he or she is declaring a variable, the scope is restricted to this method.
And we know that methods are used for computation.
And if they are declaring a variable, then they also it also implies that they want to use it for certain
computation and they must be having certain value in mind.
If by chance, if they did not, if they forgot to initialize it, and if the compiler gives some some
initializes initialize a set with the default value, then the output when we execute it can be some
unexpected value.
So that might not be what the programmer is intending.
So the compiler is forcing the programmer to initialize it with certain value.
Now this is not documented.
So this is just a very good guess.
And it has I think it's a reasonable, reasonably very good guess.
So that's the thing.
So methods are helping performing some computation.
And so if a developer is using a local variable, he or she must have some value in mind.
And so they are being forced to give a value initialize with some value if they are not initializing
it.
So that's about it.
Thank you.
And I hope you have also typed this program.
So we looked at the three different kinds of variables, and we have seen how variables can be declared
and authority objects can be created and their state can be created and the state can be initialized.
And we have also looked at the static variables and the local variables.
So that's about it.
Thank you and happy coding and I'll see you in the next lecture.