Hi there.
This is De La Rue.
And welcome back.
Let's now look at the concept of jar files.
It's a very simple concept, and we have already used a few jar files in this course.
For instance, we used a jar to connect to the Mayan database.
Similarly, we used a jar for using the servlet API that is to create.
So let's end JSP.
Similarly, we have used a jar for creating unit tests using JAR Unit.
So we used a jar unit jar for that.
So a jar file essentially provides us with certain functionality.
Now let's go ahead and get a better understanding of JAR files.
Job files have an extension of dot jar and jar is simply a shorthand for Java archive, which means
it is an archive of some Java files.
And typically these files would be just Java classes.
But you can also have any associated resources like images or videos or text files, or even the actual
source code too.
So you can also have Java files.
But typically it would be just Java classes.
So JAR is typically just a collection of Java classes which together represent a Java library.
So a jar is essentially a Java library and on the internet there are tens of thousands of open source
Java libraries providing different kinds of functionality, which also makes Java one of the most popular
languages out there.
If you need some specific functionality, then it is very likely you have a Java library for that and
all you need to do is just Google for it.
The functionality could be as simple as parsing an XML document or a CSV document to functionality for
manipulating the code Java API classes like the String Class Apache Common Slang Library, for instance,
is a library that provides a class for manipulating the string class in certain ways, which is not
possible with just the string class itself.
So it provides certain extra methods.
And you also have libraries that are highly sophisticated for performing machine learning tasks or fast
searching of documents.
So all those advanced algorithms are also encapsulated within the libraries.
So JAR is just a deployment format of a Java library and we will soon see what it contains and to use
a particular jar file.
All we need to do is place it on the class path and if you're using an ID like eclipse we just add it
to the build path and we know how to do that.
And with that you'll be able to use the functionality.
And also just to recall, we also looked at the VAR files earlier.
VAR stands for Web Application Archive.
On similar to Jha.
It is also specific to Java and is the deployment format for Java EE Web applications.
So Java is the deployment format for Java libraries, while WAAS is the deployment format for Java EE
Web applications.
And it can include Java files like the MySQL jar or servlet API jar and it can also include other resources
like servlet, JSP, HTML files and regular Java files.
As we have seen, it is in fact a jar file.
A bar is in fact a jar file.
But as it represents a web application, it has its own internal layout like the web and a folder,
the web XML file or the lib folder within the web in a folder which includes the jars needed by the
web application.
So if you look at the books Aloha Project and if you look at the expanded form, you will be able to
see that there is a live folder within the web by enough folder.
And now let's look at a few core benefits of JAR files.
A JAR file is typically in compressed format and is based on the familiar zip file format.
As it is compressed, it helps with efficient storage.
And since it is based on zip file format, it can be unzipped using something like WinZip or any similar
archive manager.
And this is just for your information.
Within the Java API, we have these packages for manipulating jar files and zip files.
And as Java is based on zip format, many of the classes in the java util jar extend the classes from
java dot zip package.
And we will not look at these packages for now as they are not commonly used.
Typically you would use the jar tool that comes with JDK in order to manipulate jar files from the command
line.
And soon we will look at that and we will also see how jars can be created from within Eclipse.
That is very convenient and that is what we would be doing most of the time.
Now since JOD is compressed and is also bundled as a single file, it can be downloaded very efficiently
within a single HTTP connection.
Otherwise each resource would require a separate connection.
Now, you may have heard of Maven, which is a project management tool.
And one of the benefits of Maven is that you can specify what libraries your project uses in an XML
file.
And MAVEN would automatically download the corresponding jars of those libraries.
So each of those libraries is a jar.
And Maven would automatically download them.
So if your project requires, say, 50 jars, then they can all be downloaded very efficiently just
because of the format of jar file.
So if you use Maven, you do not have to explicitly add jars to the belt, but Maven will download them.
Another nice benefit is security, and this is not something we generally do.
But if needed, the jar contents can be digitally signed so that the receiver can recognize the signature
and can grant any necessary security privileges.
So that's just for your information too.
And it is an advanced concept.
So we are not going to look at look at it for now.
So these are a few core benefits.
And in the next lecture we will see a demo of creating a jar and also manipulating it.
But here are some common basic jar file operations, and you would use the JAR tool that comes with
JDK.
Now here, the first operation creates a compressed jar file.
You would just say jar space, cf space, the jar file name followed by the files to be archived.
The option C and CF stands for create and here asterisk for file names denotes that we want to archive
everything in the current directory.
You could instead have a dot to.
Instead of asterisk, you can also specify one or more individual file or directory names, and those
names would be separated by space.
Second operation is for viewing the contents of a jar.
The option implies table of contents.
Third operation is for extracting the files contained in a jar, and the option X implies that.
Here.
All files in the jar are extracted.
But if you want to extract individual files, then we need to list the file names at the end of the
command.
Finally, to update an existing jar file, you would use the option u in this example bar class in the
current directory would be added to foo jar.
So there is a food jar and we are just adding this class to that.
So those are the basic operations and you may never even use them to that is it could happen that you
would only use jar files in your career, in which case you would just add them to your belt path or
the class pop.
Next, we will actually try out these commands and we will also see how a jar can be created from within
eclipse.
Thank you.