Hi there.
This is Dana.
And welcome back.
Let's now go ahead and write our first Java program.
But before doing that, let's take a quick look at the structure of a Java program.
Java programs consist of classes.
That is when you write a Java program, you write at least one class, and from a class we can create
one or more objects.
And an object is a central concept, an object oriented programming.
And we will look at object and object oriented programming in the next chapter.
For now, let's just look at what constitutes a class.
What we see here are the elements or the program constructs in a class, and we have variable declarations,
constructors, methods, and nested classes.
Variables, constructors and methods will be introduced in the next chapter, while nested classes will
be introduced towards the later part of the course.
Typically.
Hello, World Program is the first program that is written when we are learning a new programming language.
And so let's also do the same.
That is, we will write a class called Hello World, and this class will have a single method which
prints the text Hello World.
And let's look at the steps we are going to follow for this.
We will first create this directory structure.
Java In-Depth here is the root directory and it contains other subdirectories ending with the directory
called basics.
The Helloworld program we will write will go into this basics directory.
On many of the Java programs we write in this course will be stored somewhere within this Java Indep
directory.
For now, let's not worry about this directory structure and it will be clear very soon.
Next we will write.
Hello world of Java in a text editor and you can use any editor like Notepad and I'm going to use notepad
plus plus on my Windows machine and on other operating systems, you're free to use any editor of your
choice on Mac.
You can probably use text, edit and on Linux probably g edit and it is up to you.
Note that we will use text editor for only the first 20% or so of the course and later we will switch
over to Eclipse, which is an idea and it stands for Integrated Development Environment.
That is it is an environment where a lot of development tools are integrated so that we can program
effectively.
And Eclipse is used by millions of professional developers and it is much more productive to program
using an ID rather than using regular text editors.
And the reason we are initially using a regular text editor is because at least for those of you who
are completely new to programming, I think it's important to actually compile and execute the programs
from the command line.
Now, if we use an ID like Eclipse compilation happens automatically and there are also many details
and ID hides.
So if you start off with something like Eclipse, you may never know how things work behind the scenes.
So we will use a regular text editor initially for the first 20% of the course and then we will switch
over to Eclipse.
Now when we do the switch, you will also see how easy and productive it is to program using Eclipse.
And there's also a very solid eclipse tutorial that comes later and it will teach you on how you can
use Eclipse at a professional level.
It's a very nice tutorial, but if you're familiar with Eclipse, you can also use it right from this
lecture itself.
Moreover, as with the text editors, you are free to use other IDs like IntelliJ or NetBeans, so it
need not be only Eclipse.
Now, once we write our program, we will compile and run it.
And just note that all the demos in this course will be shown on Windows Machine, but you shouldn't
face any problem if you're using a different platform to as the process is just the same regardless
of the operating system.
So now let's go ahead and follow these steps.
Okay.
So the first step is to create this directory structure which we have seen earlier.
So we need to create this.
And many of you might be familiar with creating directory structures, but some of you may not be familiar.
And so I thought I would also show you how to create directories.
So I'll show it to you on Windows and on Mac and Linux.
It is similar to Mac, so I'm not going to show it to you on Linux.
So on Windows we have this command mkdir space, the directory structure and it would create the directory
structure in the C drive.
So let me just copy this.
And pasted in my command prompt.
So here I am and my home directory.
And with that we would the directory structure would have got created.
Now if we want to move into that directory, we can use this command.
So it is Sid which stands for change directory space and the same path that we have here, the same
directory structure.
And there you go.
So we are inside basics now.
So next we will write our Java program, save it into this basics directory, and then we will compile
and execute it from this same directory.
And these commands will also be available in the resources section.
So you can also find it there.
So let's now switch over to Mac.
So this is the path.
It's also almost very similar.
So in Mac and Linux we use forward slash, whereas in Windows we use backward slash.
So let's go here.
So here, this is my Mac machine and I'm in the home directory right now.
So let me just paste it.
That's it.
The directory structure must have got created.
So let's move into that.
Okay.
So we are now inside basics.
Here it is.
So this is the directory structure.
So I'm not going to show the Hello World Program creating the Hello World Program on the Mac machine.
So I'm only going to demonstrate on Windows, but it's exactly the same.
So you would write it in the same way as I'm showing and save the file in the basics directory and then
you will execute the same commands for compiling an execute and executing it and it's going to be exactly
same.
So that's it.
And this you see, this is the admin, my home directory and you can go here from here if you're going
to go and if you say go to folder.
And here it is user slash admin.
In my case my name is admin here.
So if you had go then you're you'll be in this directory and here java in depth is there and you can
always.
Going to the subdirectories.
And your basics will be saved in this directory.
The program will be saved in the basics directory and to.
You can go into applications to find text added is here.
You can use it as your editor or you can also use any other editor, which it's up to you.
So that's about it.
Now let's go ahead and write the Hello World Program.
Every class begins with the key word class, which is a reserved keyword in Java.
So let's just insert that.
Glass.
And the key word is followed by the name of the class, which is Helloworld.
In our case.
And every class has a beginning brace and an ending brace.
So this is what we have.
So this is the class declaration here, class and Helloworld.
And within our class, let's have just one method.
And it's called the main method.
So here is the main method.
And the main method also has a beginning and an ending breast, just like the class.
So this is the name of the method which is main, and this is a method parameter and we will look at
that later.
But it's just an array of strings and this will be discussed later in the chapter and string strings
will be covered in a separate chapter.
And this is the method output.
In this case it's called as void.
And let's not worry about that for now.
So it has both input and output and public and static are both of them are called as modifiers public
is called as an access modifiers.
But let's also not worry about that.
There are other access modifiers too, and we will discuss all of that later.
And static is just a type of method and we will discuss that also later.
And let's just have one single statement within this class and it's going to print the string.
Hello.
Print, Helen.
Double quotes.
And every statement ends with this semicolon.
That's how it is in Java.
So this is our Hello World Program.
Let's just go ahead and save it as hello world dot Java.
Since we already created Java and directory structure.
So let's just go there.
Source.
Com Symantec Square Basics.
Extension is dark java.
And that's it.
So that's the Hello World Program and it has a single method main.
Now let's just go ahead and compile and run this.
So let's just go into the command prompt, which is the DOS prompt seemed.
But let's.
The restructure.
Let's go into that directory.
So for to compile, we use the Java command.
And here is the Java file.
So when we compile it, it's compiled.
So let's just.
So here we are in the basics directory.
So we have this hello java and the class file has been generated and this class file has the byte codes,
the our byte codes.
And so this is a Windows machine and we know that this class file can be executed on any platform,
whether it is Linux or Mac, it can be executed.
And that's the advantage we have in Java, which is the platform independence.
So let's just go ahead and execute it for that.
We use the Java interpreter.
Hello world.
So it is nothing bad.
Hello, world class.
So when we do this.
It's going to print the message.
So we compiled and we ran our first program.
So let's just go back here.
Now, this file, the class name is Helloworld and the file name was also Helloworld Java.
And it need not be same, at least in this particular context.
It need not be same.
So if you want, we can just change this to Helloworld one.
So which is the class?
The name of the class is Helloworld one.
The file name is Helloworld.
So now let's just go ahead and compile this.
Let's just call it as the file name is still Helloworld, so let's just compile it so it compiled fine.
Now if you look at the disk, so we see that.
So this is the hello world of Java and this was previously created.
Hello world class.
We don't need that anymore.
So hello, world one a new class file got created.
So this was the.
The file with the new name.
So this is just to show you that it need not be the same, but you shouldn't do that.
Typically, we always have the same name.
The file name and class name are the same.
So let's just change it back to Helloworld.
Actually, let me put it as level one, but generally we also have the modifier public here.
Typically we do that, but if you do that, then the compiler requires that both the file name and the
class name are same.
So in this case, let me just compile.
Let me just say hello world.
And there you go.
It says it gives another message.
It says Class Hello World.
One is public and it should be declared in a file named Hello World one dot Java right now the name
is Hello all that Java.
So if you have the public modifier, which is generally the case, then both of them have to be same.
So just keep that in mind and typically you will have the public modifier most of the time.
So just keep that in mind.
So always try to have the same name.
Now you can also have more than one class within this particular file, but normally you wouldn't do
that.
But let's just go ahead and create a new class here.
Call me.
Let's just call it as good goodbye.
And it's also.
Print the message.
Goodbye.
So both.
So there are two classes here.
Hello and goodbye.
And both of them have a main method, and both of them are printing something.
So let's just go ahead and compile the file.
Hello, world.
Let me just delete this.
Hello, everyone.
Its compiler.
Now you can see that it will create two class files.
Hello and goodbye.
So the compiler is going to scan this particular file and create separate class files for both of them.
But generally, you will never have more than a class in a single file.
There is something called nested classes where within this class you can have nested classes.
You can have other classes nested within this class so that we will see later.
But normally you wouldn't have a class external externally, like the way we see here.
That's something that you wouldn't do normally.
Probably if you want to do some quick prototyping on, if you want to have multiple classes, you might
do that, but generally you would.
You will not do this.
So let me just delete that.
So just it's just to let you know that you can have more than a class in a single file, but you shouldn't
be doing that.
So now let's switch back to our slides and discuss a little bit more about the main method.
Now, if you want to run a class from the command line, you need to have a main method in that class.
And let's discuss a little bit more about the main method.
Main method is where your program starts learning.
That is on executing Java space helloworld.
Jong-fast lauds the white coats that are associated with hello world class into the memory and then
it invokes its main method.
On main method must be declared as public, static and void.
Public keyword is required for JVM to invoke it.
Otherwise, program will compile but not executed.
And from the main method, we typically invoke other classes that constitute the software, and those
other classes need not have a main method.
So it's just the class which is being executed from the command line must have a main method.
UN program ends when the main method ends.
So that's about it.
We just wrote our first program and then compile and executed it.
Do write the same program on your end and compile and execute it.
Thank you and happy coding.