Hi there.
This is the row.
In the last lecture, we saw that we could not interrupt indexer threats that were waiting on intrinsic
locks.
That is the locks that come with synchronized methods and synchronized statements.
In this lecture, we will see how that can be addressed by using explicit locks that were introduced
in Java five.
It's an advanced topic and translating on such locks are interoperable.
Let's begin by looking at a common way of using explicit locks like synchronised.
They are also used for controlling access to shared resources by multiple threats.
Here we have the raw interface from the package java dot dot com current dot locks and re-enter and
lock is a class from the same package which implements the lock interface.
Next lock is acquired by invoking the lock method.
Then we have some critical section guarded by the lock, and at the end we release the lock in a final
block by invoking the unlock method.
Now, if unlock is not done in a final block, then lock will never be released.
If an exception is thrown in the critical section.
And that would be dangerous as there can be other threads waiting for the lock to be released.
So it is critical to release the lock in a final block.
Not that with intensive clocks they are automatically released when we exit the synchronize clocks.
So we need to be careful not to forget unlocking when it comes to explicit clocks.
And here is the lock interface.
The lock method, as we saw in previous slide, is used for acquiring a lock lock interrupt really is
what we need to fix the issue in the previous demo and by invoking it a thread would acquire the lock
unless the thread is interrupted or if the lock is not available.
Basically, if a thread is waiting for a lock by invoking this method, then it can be interrupted by
another thread by invoking the interrupt method.
With that, interrupted exception is thrown on the current threads.
Interrupted status is cleared.
Not that destroying of interrupted reception and resetting interrupted status will also happen if interrupt
method has already been invoked on this thread and then subsequently this method lock interrupt is invoked.
Next is Troy Locke method.
Here the Locke is acquired only if it is available.
If available, Locke is acquired and the truth is returned.
Otherwise, if false is returned and the method returns immediately.
Next is the timed version of trilogue, as you may have guessed.
Lock is acquired if it is free within a given waiting time, and the current threat has also not been
interrupted.
So the waiting time is specified as the first parameter and the unit of waiting time is the second parameter.
If the waiting time elapses and lock cannot be acquired, then this method returns.
A false and false is also returned if the lock is not available.
Not that like Locke interrupted method.
This method is also responsive to interruption.
Next is the unlock method, which, as we know, releases the lock.
Now one thing to note is that there is this concept of acquisition count or hold count associated with
each lock, regardless of whether the lock is intrinsic or re entrant explicit lock.
If a thread acquires the lock by invoking the lock method or entering a synchronised block, then the
whole count would be set to one.
Now, if the same thread holding the lock invokes the lock method once again, or if it enters another
synchronized method in case of intrinsic locks, then the whole code would be incremented by one.
Similarly, if the thread invokes the unlock method or exerts a synchronised block, then hold count
would be prevented by one.
And when our whole count reaches zero, then the lock would be released.
The thought is entrenched logic in place.
A thread having a lock cannot enter another synchronized block that uses the same lock.
Finally invoking the method new condition on the lock object will return an instance of condition which
is also another interface and jabber dot dot concurrent dot locks package like the weight method.
A condition object allows one thread to suspend execution until notified by another thread.
So a condition is a replacement for object methods such as weight notify and notify all.
And it includes methods such as a weight signal and signal all.
Later in the demo we will see how we can use condition object.
Note that clauses implementing lock interface must provide the same memory visibility semantics as intrinsic
locks.
So that's a requirement from the specification.
In the first slide, we instantiated three entrant lock and it has these two constructors.
The second constructor includes a boolean parameter called Fair.
And if we pass it through for this parameter, it means that threats get access to the lock in the order
in which they requested it.
And if we pass a false, then it means that threats may not get access to the lock in the order in which
they are requested.
That is, if a threat requests a lock and if at that instance of time the lock is available, then the
threat gets the lock.
Even if there are other threats already waiting for that lock.
However, if the rock is already taken, then the thread has to join the queue behind other waiting
threads.
By default, fairness option is false.
So invoking the first constructor, which does not have any parameters, is equivalent to invoking the
second constructor with false argument.
Now naturally having unfair option as the default option sounds kind of unethical.
But practically due to performance reasons, it is perfectly fine.
Creating fair locks comes with the overhead of threat, suspension and resumption.
That is, if a threat requests a lock and if lock is available, then suspending that threat just so
that some other waiting threat gets that lock upon resumption affects the performance.
Practically speaking, it seems that it is good enough as long as a blocking thread gets its lock at
some point of time.
On the exception when fairness option could be good is when the locks are held for a relatively long
time.
Finally note that intrinsic locks also do not make any fairness guarantees.
So unfairness seems to be fine here.
Next is the time to address this question.
Should we prefer re entrant or intrinsic loss?
It is recommended to use intrinsic as they are familiar and are widely used.
Also intrinsic locks are automatically released with explicit locks.
You may forget to release the lock and that would be dangerous, as we may have other threads waiting
for it and they would be waiting forever.
Next performance wise to intrinsic locks seem to be almost as good as re entrant locks.
However, in Java five, performance wise re intent blocks are much better than intrinsic locks.
In Java six, the algorithm for managing intrinsic clocks has been improved due to which there is not
much difference between the two.
Now here I'm only specifying the Java six.
And that's because this material, this fact comes from the Java Concurrency in practice book.
And that book was released at around the time that Java six was released.
So that's why I specify only Java six, but I'm pretty sure this also holds for other Java versions.
Finally you can go for re entrant locks if you need additional features like threat interruption while
waiting for a lock, which is what we'll be seeing in our demo.
Also note that with a re entrant lock, just like in the case of intrinsic logs, what we get is a standard
mutual exclusion log that is only one thread at a time.
Gets to hold the log.
But this logging strategy is conservative when we consider certain safe scenarios where it is okay for
multiple threads to hold the lock at the same time.
For instance, we can have a shared resource that can be accessed by either multiple reader threads
or a single writer thread, but not both.
For this case, where multiple threads can read at the same time, the mutual exclusion locking strategy
of re-enter and lock will not work.
So we need better concurrency here.
And that can be achieved via a read write log which is also from Java dot dot com current dot locks
package.
To read critical data, you would first acquire a read lock by invoking the block method.
Similarly, to modify data, you would acquire a write log by invoking the right block method.
The class.
Implementing this interface is free and current read write lock.
So you would create an instance of this lock.
So the earlier lock class that we have seen was just re entrant lock and this is re entrant read, right
lock.
I think if you're interested, you can read more about it from this class API specification.
Now, that's about the theory part.
Let's go ahead and look at what we have learned in action.
This is the way notify with incomplete interruption.
So this was the class that we have seen in the previous demo.
So we said that one limitation of this particular class is if a thread is waiting here in the indexer.
If the threads are waiting here for an intrinsic lock.
So in that case, we cannot interrupt.
Right.
So that was the reason why we are in this lecture.
So we are looking at explicit locks.
So what I have done is I have copied this entire code into this new class, called us explicit locks
with interruption because we are dealing with explicit locks.
And I already extended this class to some extent, and we will also write some code to fix the issue.
So this is the new class and we are just instantiating it here in the main method, explicit locks with
interruption.
So let's just go ahead and look at some changes that I have already made.
So here in the go method, in the Go method, we are iterating through each of the web lengths.
So what we need is a lock, right?
So we are creating this lock instance here, new entrant lock.
And if you recall in the lecture I mentioned that if we invoke new condition, then that would return
a condition condition object so that I'm calling it as page condition.
So these are the two things that I have added.
And in the constructor earlier we were only passing Weblink.
Now we will actually pass lock and page condition.
Just notice here that this page condition is actually coming from from the lock itself.
So using the lock object we are generating this page condition and we will look a little bit more about
this condition in the demo tool.
So we are passing these to new objects, lock and page condition to both downloader as well as indexer.
And the rest of the code here is just the same one.
We are just adding the the two threads to this two array lists one for downloader threads, the other
for indexer threads.
And we are just starting them here and we are waiting for 500 milliseconds.
Earlier I think it was 1/2, so I reduced it to find it milliseconds half a second.
And we are also doing the same thing.
If the time is up we then we want to interrupt the downloader threads, right?
So we are using this as a live method and for interruption we are just invoking the interrupt only on
the indexer thread.
So we are iterating iterating through both the thread list through both the URLs, but we are invoking
only interrupt on the indexer thread and that using that interrupt, we are indirectly going to interrupt
the download thread.
So that was all in the previous demo.
Now here in the constructors.
So since we are passing lock on page condition, so we need to initialize them.
So we have two variables here and we are initializing them and the same thing happens here also in the
downloader thread.
So okay, so it's just the exact same thing.
Lock on page condition being invoked here in the in the in the constructor.
Now let's go back to the indexer thread.
So previously we just have this code, say a synchronized or web link.
So the web link has a single lock and that is the intrinsic lock.
So any thread that is coming here has to acquire that lock in order to enter the synchronized block.
And if HTML page is equal to null, then we need to relinquish the lock.
So that is achieved by invoking the wait method on the same web link object because we are supposed
to release that same lock and that would be possible only if we invoke wait method on this particular
web link object, which is the object that is used here in the synchronized.
So that's one thing.
So web link object is the common thing between synchronized between here or here when acquiring as well
as when releasing as well as in the downloader thread here to enter the synchronize block and also for
notifying ET once the downloader.
Once the download process is complete, even here we are using the web link.
So because that's the common lock and we should do the same thing for for the explicit lock too.
So we would, we would enter the explicit lock, then we would invoke the, the await method in the
condition.
And the condition is already generated from the lock use by invoking the new condition.
And we need to instead of notify there is a method called signal and we need to use that.
So it has to be tied to the same lock, regardless of whether it is intrinsic lock or whether it is
explicit lock.
So I think that's good enough.
Now let's go ahead and make the changes that we need to make.
So let's go ahead and begin with the index thread here.
So we don't need this synchronized anymore.
So let's.
Do that.
So let's comment that out and let's so we already have the lock variable.
So the earlier the disadvantage was that we were not able to interrupt this particular any threats waiting
here we say lock lock uninterruptedly.
Right, because lock interrupted.
So that is what will help us to interrupt this threat.
Now.
Let's put it finally here, because the most important thing is to unlock it, right?
If you're not unlocking, then that's going to be dangerous because.
Other threads waiting for this.
We'll be waiting forever.
So that's one thing.
So that's taken care of.
Now, here, let me comment this.
And let's invoke the condition.
Condition was named as page condition.
It's the variable that we have used.
And let's say a weight.
So just the weight method is replaced with a weight method and we are doing it on page condition.
Okay.
So that's what we need to do.
So very simple.
Now, one other thing that we need to do here is if an interrupted exception is generated because let's
say a thread is waiting here.
If we invoke the interrupt method.
So it would generate an interrupted exception, in which case the thread does not have the lock.
So this.
And if you invoke unlock in that case, then we will get an exception called illegal monitor exception.
Let's look at it here.
I think it's not showing it here.
So that word exception will be generated.
So you would invoke this method only if you have if you're in possession of the lock, but if an exception
is generated, then you it means that you do not have the lock.
So we need to one thing we need to do is if an interrupted exception is generated, if you recall,
what is happening is the interrupted status is cleared, which means it is made false.
So what we need to do is we need to make it true once again.
And if it is true, we need not unlock, right?
Because there is no lock.
So we need to set the interrupter status to true.
And the way we would do it is by invoking the interrupt method once again.
Okay.
So.
So if you are coming here, it means that interrupted an interruption has happened.
But then the interpreter status is also reset.
So we need to set it again.
And if we set it again in the final block, we will have this condition.
So is interrupted would be true.
And if it is true, it means that we should not invoke this method only if it is false.
We would invoke this only if it is false.
It means that we executed the critical section successfully and so we have the log and we are supposed
to unlock it.
So that's one thing that we have to do here.
So that's about it on this end.
Now let's head over to the download thread.
In the download thread.
Also we have this.
Okay.
So synchronized is closed.
Now the lock statement can be here.
It need not be within the block.
In the other thread we had within the tree block because there we were, we were invoking lock interrupt
method which could throw an interrupted exception.
So here, we don't need that.
So we can just invoke this lock method.
We don't have to interrupt this one and.
So this is the background thread and we are using it to indirectly close this stop this thread by closing
the stream.
So here is a web link.
So we don't need this anymore.
Signal.
So this is the method that we are going to invoke.
So instead of notify, it's going to be signal.
So that's that's all there is here.
And now the interrupted is interruptible.
So let's go ahead and run this.
So it's done here.
So here we are.
The downloaded threats have kicked in and they're trying to download.
In the meanwhile, since we have set it only for half.
Second, the time is up.
And so we need to we need to close them.
We need to stop the threads.
So here we are saying the downloaded thread with with the ID 2000 is still active.
So we are stopping it and the way we are stopping yet as we are just invoking the interrupt method on
the indexer thread and that is going to throw an end that's going to throw an exception, interrupted
exception, because we are waiting here.
Because we are waiting here on the LOC and an exception is being generated.
And so we come here and we first stop the downloader thread in an indirect way by setting the stop status
here and the background thread that we are spawning in the downloader thread is going to close the stream
and that would trigger the stopping of the downloader thread that we have seen in the last thing.
And this is the code that we have just added and we are just unlocking it.
So that's what is happening here and we are doing the same thing for 2001, 2002.
Also we are also interrupted and here for 2003 it's interrupted.
But still the download process has was continuing and it has completed.
So at the instance when we were trying to interrupt it at that same time itself, the download has completed
but it is fine.
So here it clearly says that we are closing the stream.
So in the cleanup code we are invoking the set stop here.
By doing that we are closing the stream in the background thread in the downloader thread.
So we are closing the stream and because of that here we are saying it could not be downloaded because
the stream has been closed and the same thing is happening for the other web links also between one
and 2002.
So that's how it is done.
So Explicit Locks is helping us to interrupt.
Now, the one thing I want to say is when we are invoking this synchronized Web link, so basically
for this intrinsic lock, we just have one queue and all the threads that are trying to enter this block
will be waiting in that queue, but with explicit locks.
So we are generating the condition by invoking the new condition and essentially we can have more than
one condition.
So what that means is if we have more than one condition, each condition would correspond to one queue,
which means that multiple threads can be waiting in those queues.
So it need not be just one queue, as in the case of intrinsic lock, but it can be multiple queues
and that let's just head over to the API dock of the condition class interface.
Now a few seconds ago I mentioned that if a thread tries to enter a synchronised block and if the lock
is not available, then it would wait in the queue corresponding to the intrinsic lock.
So in our case we had synchronized off weblink.
So weblink is an object and it has an intrinsic lock which is associated with its own queue.
So that is right.
But the queue that I was I wanted to refer was another queue.
So it was a slight mistake from my end.
Basically the weblink object also has the weight method which it inherits from the object class.
Right.
And the weight method is also associated with the queue and this queue is called as a condition queue
because a thread would enter that particular queue because of some condition being true.
So in our case the condition is while HTML page is equal to null.
So in that situation the indexer thread will invoke the weight method and will wait in the queue corresponding
condition queue.
So because the page is not yet downloaded and it cannot index it so the condition has HTML pages equal
to null is called as condition predicate and the queue in which it is waiting the thread is waiting
is called as a condition queue and a different thread has to invoke the notify method in order for this
thread to wake up and acquire the lock and do any subsequent actions.
So there we had only a single condition queue and a single condition predicate.
Now here let's look at an example here in this interface where we have multiple condition predicates
and multiple condition objects.
So here it's a bounded buffer.
So it's basically a buffer which stores elements, but it is bounded, which means that we cannot have
more we cannot add more elements than the specified bond, which is 100 in this case.
And we have two methods put and take put is for inserting elements and take is for removing elements.
And here there are two condition predicates.
So if, if a thread tries to, wants to add an element so it gets into this method and if it sees this
condition, it says that the buffer is full, in which case it cannot add.
It has to wait until some space is available.
So there is so this is a condition predicate and there is a condition object corresponding to it here
and it would wait in the condition.
Q Corresponding to this particular condition object when it says await the same thing happens here.
If a thread enters the take method and if it finds that the buffer is empty, in that case it would
enter the condition q of a different condition object and both the condition objects are are generated
from the same block.
So that's what, that's what we have here.
And if a thread is waiting here because the buffer is empty now here, if an, if another thread is
able to add an element, then it would invoke the signal method which would wake up this particular
thread.
We can also have multiple, multiple condition predicates, but a single.
An object that's also possible.
Now, the disadvantage with that kind of a setup is that because of unfair ordering, there is a chance
that we can have trucks waiting on multiple condition predicates at the same time in the queue.
And if we invoke and notify all or a signal all method, then one of the threads will be woken up and
it will acquire the lock.
But its condition predicate might not be false, it might still be true.
And so it would once again go back into the state.
So that's the disadvantage.
But here we are invoking only the threats, waiting on a particular condition predicate.
So that condition predicate will be false and it can do other actions and other subsequent actions.
So we are going to invoke the wake of the right kind of threats.
So that's one advantage.
And the second advantage is we can invoke only the signal method rather than signal all if we have a
condition object associated with each condition predicate.
So we can invoke only a signal instead of signal.
And signal is considered to be more efficient.
So that's about it.
So just wanted to explain that you can also read from here.
So explosive locks are more advanced features.
And one way that we have seen is it helps with interrupting.
If you want to interrupt a waiting thread on a lock, then it is possible.
So that's about it.
Thank you and happy coding.