Hi there.
This is true.
Now, let's look at item 52, which says refer to objects by their interfaces.
Basically what the items are just is whenever possible, try to use an interface as a reference type
in all kinds of variable declarations and also use them as method return types.
Let's look at an example.
Let's consider this code fragment where the method fool has a single parameter which is of type ArrayList,
which is a concrete class.
The problem with this is we can now only invoke this method with an idealist.
That is, we cannot pass another similar implementation.
However, if we had the parameter type as a list, which is an interface, then we could have passed
out a list or if needed in future we could pass a linked list.
Or maybe even a trialist, which is from Apache Commons Library, which we know is a completely different
inheritance hierarchy, that is list is from standard Java API.
But the object that is being passed is from a whole different inheritance hierarchy and we are able
to do that just because tree list implements list interface.
So we are saying that one benefit is we can change implementations if needed.
But why would we have to change implementation?
A common reason is that new implementation offers better performance.
Of course, we also know about the polymorphic benefits of using a super type.
We get flexible code which is less susceptible to change as we can pass new object types that were not
there when the code was originally written.
So we can pass new implementations.
The code will also be a lot cleaner.
However, notice that now we are saying that it is maximum flexible code as opposed to simply flexible
code.
And that's because with interfaces, objects can come from any inheritance hierarchy.
That is, they need not be from the same inheritance tree as the interface.
And this is generally not possible with concrete or abstract classes, as classes are implementation
specific and are typically confined to one inheritance tree.
That is, typically you don't see them being subclass in a different inheritance tree.
But with interfaces we are defining a contract that is a specification and hence it is much more generic
and implementations can come from anywhere.
Let's also look at a couple of exceptions when we would have to go with classes rather than interfaces.
One exception is when there is no interface at all in such a case.
Try to use the least specific class.
A second scenario is there may be an interface, but we may have to use a specific subclass as a reference
type, as the subclass might be defining some specialized behavior and the methods code needs that specialized
behavior.
In that case, we have to use the subclass as a reference type.
So that's about this item whenever possible.
Try to use an interface as a reference type unless there are some exceptions like the ones we stated
here.
Thank you.