Hello there.
This is the Rue.
And welcome back.
So far, we have seen that each of our declaration statements were declaring a single variable.
Now, in Java, it's also perfectly valid to have a declaration statement declaring multiple variables.
Given that all of those variables are of the same type.
So you can declare and you can also initialize the variables in the same statement.
So let's go ahead and see how that's possible.
So here is the student class, and we have these two instance variables, tuition fees and international
fees.
So tuition fees is $12,000 and international fees is $5,000.
So those are two declaration statements.
Now let's just declare them using a single statement.
So I have removed that.
So let's just move it here.
So you'll just have a comma here and the new variable, another variable.
So that's it.
So let's just compile this.
So I'm here in the basics directory.
So compiles fine.
And it is printing the values.
So the student is a local student, so his fees is 12,000.
The final fees, whereas the last two students we know our international students.
So the tuition fees is 17,000.
So the logic is here and the compute method of the student is international.
We are updating the tuition fees, which would be the tuition fees for the local student, plus the
additional international fees.
So this is fine, but you cannot do this.
So let's compile and see.
So it gives a compilation error.
So this is not possible.
So you can specify the data type only once it needs to be specified here.
So you cannot have you cannot specify it multiple times.
Like for each variable, it means that you can also you cannot also do this.
So this is also not possible.
So all the variables will be of the same type and you can only specify the type once.
Now, let me just remove this.
So keep in mind that these are instance variables.
So can you guess what?
What would be the tuition fees?
Compiles fine.
So the tuition fees will be initialized to zero.
Right.
Because we are not initializing it.
And we know that, for instance, variables are four or four static variables.
They would get the default value of the data type.
The data type is double here, so they would get a value of zero.
So if we see the output, tuition fees is zero for John, who is a local student and it is 5000 for
Raj and Anita, who are international students.
Right.
So the tuition fees is computed here if they are international.
Now, let's move these.
The exact statement into the compute method.
So they are now local variables and.
Let's see what happens.
I think you can guess it.
So it says variable tuition fees might not have been initialized.
So here we have this statement where we are computing the tuition fees.
It says that the variable tuition fees might not have been initialized and that's because we did not
initialize it here.
And it's a local variable.
And we know that local variables do not get default values.
So before they are used, they need to be initialized.
Right.
So we need to do something like this.
So we can do this.
So let me compile it.
So we have already seen that it compiles fine.
So essentially, if you have this and if it if there are local variables, then they will not get default
values.
So we either have to initialize it or we need to re initialize before they are used for the first time.
But if they are instance or static variables, they do get the default value of the data type.
So that's with that.
Now, let me show you one thing here.
So this is tuition fees.
Let's initialize it to 100.
And here, this doesn't make sense.
But let me just show it to you.
Here we are saying tuition fees plus 5000.
So here what happens is the tuition fees is initialized to 100 and here in the international fees.
So that 100 is here, it's assigned here.
So international fees will be initialized, will be initialized as $5,100.
And of course, the tuition fees will be re computed here if it's an international student.
So essentially here, once we initialize it, the scope of this variable starts from here and it also
applies here.
So if there are any other variables which are using that variable, then it is valid.
And those variables will get the the value, the current value or the value of that variable.
So the scope starts here and it extends to any declarations towards the right of this variable and it
also extends to the end of the class because it's an instance variable.
So let me just compile and execute it.
So as you can see, the tuition fees is 100 for John because that's what it is.
We are initializing it to 100 and the international fees will be 5100.
Right.
So for both, John, for both Raj and Anita, it's going to be 5200.
So the international fees is 5100 as we are competing here.
And since they both are international students, we are adding the tuition fees once again here, the
100 and the final value of tuition fees is going to be 5200 here and 5200 for the last student also.
So that is how you can re-use the value of the tuition fees.
And finally.
Let's say this is $100.
This is the final thing that I'm demonstrating.
And then let's say we have it like this double.
So here we have tuition fees here, I'm saying.
So we have it like this.
So we have double international fees is equal to tuition fees is equal to 5000.
So here what is happening is tuition fees is initially $100.
Then it is getting re initialized to 5000 here and that 5000 is getting assigned to international fees.
So international fees will be 5000.
Tuition fees will also be 5000.
So let's compile and look at the output.
So the tuition fees is 5000, which is what we have here.
So.
So that's for John, who is the local student.
But the international fees is also 5000 because we are assigning the value of tuition fees to international
fees.
So both of these are 5000.
So the final tuition fees will be 10,000 for.
If it's an international student.
And that's what we see here for the last two students.
So essentially, we are re initializing tuition fees.
Now, you may recall that at the class level right here, both static as well as instance, variables
cannot be initialized.
For instance, we cannot have something like this.
Right.
We know that.
We have seen that.
But this is possible.
If you have it as part of a declaration statement, then you can re initialize it.
It's just that you cannot do this, so you cannot have an assignment statement by itself at the class
level, but you can still re initialize the variable in this particular way.
Perhaps that is possible because this is still a declaration statement.
So that's one sort of an edge case.
Now, if we remove this, then it's not going to compile.
You see, it says cannot find symbol tuition fees, which means that it should have been declared earlier.
And so we need to have this statement and then we can re initialize it.
So that's one thing.
So that's the thing.
So we have seen that we can have multiple variables declared within the same declaration statement given
that they are of the same type and you can only specify that type only once.
So this is what you will have.
Finally.
So this is perfectly fine.
So that's all there is to this lecture.
Thank you.
And I will see you in the next lecture.