Hi there.
This is Lou.
And welcome back.
Let's now go ahead and create a jar file and also manipulate the jar file.
So we'll be using all the commands that we have seen in the previous lecture.
But before doing that, let's go ahead and see how a jar can be created from within our ID, because
ID is something that we use all the time.
So we need to first see how we can create a jar from within our ID.
And that's the most convenient way to create a jar file.
So let's do that.
So here we have the eclipse and we have the trillion web project and trillion web has all of these different
packages which has the Java files.
So let's go ahead and create a jar file that would include just this package called util, which has
some utility files.
So we would create something like a utility jar.
And these utility files are very much reusable and they can be used across projects.
Or if you have some partner companies, you can actually give them the utility jar and they can add
it to their build path and start using these files by importing them.
So for this, all we need to do is we have to right click here on the package or we can also right click
here.
So let me do it from here.
And then later we'll come back and right click from here and create a jar from here.
First, let me show it from here.
So let me right click here and just click on export and click on export here.
And this would open this window.
So, so if it is like this, just expand the Java node here, click on the Jar Jar file or just type
jar here and it will show you just the just the jar entries.
So click on Jar File here, click on next.
Over here you need to select.
So this is the project which we selected because we right.
Clicked on that.
So let me just deselect them and this also we do not need and within the source we just need the last
one.
So let's select all of them.
Okay.
So the last one is the util.
So that's good.
And we are saying export generated classifiers.
So let's just select only class files.
So only class files would be included in the final job.
Now, if you also want the source files to be included, then you need to select this particular option
Java source file.
But typically jobs would include just the class files.
So let's just select only this.
And here you need to select the destination, the name of the jar file and also the destination.
So I have this destination and let's keep the name as util hyphen 1.0 like version one.
And here this is already selected.
It says compress the contents of the jar file so the jar would be in compressed format.
So let's say next.
And just leave these options as these.
And that said, you can leave everything as us.
So let me just go ahead and click finish.
So it's created and my destination and this is the one you tell hyphen 1.0.
And as you can see, it has around 3.97 kilobytes.
Now, let me show you the file size on.
Here if you go into.
It is around 6.23.
So roughly around two, two point something has been saved because it was compressed.
This is what we have.
So now let's go ahead and view the contents of this.
So.
So we have to go into this directory called semantics.
Semantics squared slash jar.
In my case.
In your case, it can be different.
So here it is, I'm there.
So I just want to view this.
So we would use the jar tool for that.
So Jar tool comes with VDC, so let me show you that.
So here I am.
So this is an C program files, Java, JDK 12, which is one of the latest versions.
If you have an older version, you can open that and within your JDK click on pen and within then you
can see that if you scroll down, you can see that there is the jar dot xy.
So this is the one that we are going to use.
So your path should include JDK and we know that how to do that, how to set the path environment variable.
So just go ahead and.
Open your command prompt and go into the directory where we have that.
So let's just go ahead and say jar.
And you may recall that to view the contents, you would say PT stands for table of contents.
F and you tell hyphen 1.0. jar.
That it is.
So it is showing all the three class files that we have.
And these this is the directory structure and there is also something called meta inf slash manifest.
So we are done with this particular command.
Now let's go ahead and extract this file and see what it contains.
So for that you would say jar and if you recall for extract it is ex f util hyphen one dot jar and we
want to extract that.
So you'll see meta hyphen and f.
Manifest Dot mf.
Okay.
There you go.
So a copy of that has been made here.
So the the manifest file is still there and in the jar file.
So it has made a copy of that and it is copied into the current directory.
So let's click on Matter Enough.
And this is the manifest file.
That's how you would extract any files.
So here we extracted manifest, but you can also extract any dot class file or any Dot's Java file that
you might want to extract.
So let me just open this thing.
So we are done with one more command.
So this is what we have.
And all it has is this information.
So manifest file is nothing but a file that contains the meta information about the jar file.
It just has the meta information of the jar file.
So it has entries such as this.
So this is an entry and it has a name and a value.
It says manifest hyphen version and thus.
And we can also add within the manifest file.
You can also add more entries.
Now, for instance, there is something called main class entry.
Now a jar file.
You cannot execute a jar file directly.
But let's say if you also want to execute a jar file, and by that I mean we can have a class within
this jar and the particular class would have a main method.
And if that is the case, we can actually execute the jar file.
But for that we need to set some meta information.
We need to add something called as a meta class or a main class, and we need to specify what that particular
file is.
So if you if your manifest file has that information, then we can actually execute the jar file using
our Java interpreter, just like the way we execute any Java class.
So let's also do that.
And with that we can actually look at the third command, which is the the final command, which is
the update.
And after that we will look at the create command, the create from the command line.
So let me execute first.
Let me just first execute this.
So it would be java hyphen jar util hyphen 1.0. job.
So if you do this, it's just a regular Java command.
So it says no main manifest attribute.
So we need to add something for that.
So I'll say.
Main hyphen plus column.
So we need to specify the name now among these three classes here.
The string util java has a.
Main method.
So let's add this.
Particular class.
So we'll say you take this.
Here.
Let's add it.
Let's say strong you.
Let me say that.
So this one is just this file which we just extracted.
So it is with ten.
This is the file and you can actually rename it to it doesn't matter.
So it is a file that is separate from what we have in the jar file.
Right.
We just made a copy of it.
So it's not the exact same file.
So that file is still there in that jar.
So we edited this one.
We did not edit the one in the jar file, so we just edited the one which we extracted.
Now let's do an update and when we do the update, the one in the jar gets updated and let's see how
that will, how that is possible.
So here, let's just say jar for update.
It is you and you'll have the usual F and after f, let's add M, which means that we want to use the
manifest file which we just edited and we want to use that information and add it to the jar file and
we actually do not even need this.
It's okay if we have it, but we do not need.
But you need to ensure that there is this empty line here.
That is a requirement.
If that's not there, then this will not work.
So let me go back here, you f m first thing is you need to have the one dot jar and meta enough.
So this is the one which we just edited and like I said, it can be anything.
You could even rename it to something else.
It doesn't matter.
So we are just going to add it and that's it.
So now the one inside the jar also got edited.
Now let's run this command.
So it is jar space, hyphen jar, hyphen the jar file.
Now, if you run it, you can see it as printing something, because we have a print statement within
the main method here and it prints something and encoded password of this thing.
So that's not important.
But we were able to execute the jar from the command, from the command line.
So that's what we could do.
Now let's extract once again.
Okay.
So we just extracted that manifest file.
And so it has overwritten the manifest file which we extracted earlier.
And as you can see, it has this three information.
So, so it has these three name value pairs manifest version created by.
So I'm using 1.8 here in this case 1.8 VDC.
So that's what is there in my Java underscore home and the main class.
So this is the main class.
So this is the exact content that is within the manifest file.
So that is how you can do it.
And now here, instead of doing it this way, you can also there is also another way to add this main
class.
So let me quickly show you that also from the command line, there is another there is a different way
to add that.
But without editing this manifest file, we can also specify this particular class name on the command
line itself.
So for to show that, let me go back.
Let me actually delete this one.
Okay, so let's recreate it.
But this time let's create it from here.
So earlier where I clicked on your web, this time let's just right click here.
This is easy export and jar file.
So everything is same and the say next, next finish.
Now it is there.
It would have created that.
So this time what we will do is we will just say we don't need this anymore because we want to specify
the file here.
Might would be you f earlier it was m so this time it will be e and you would have util jar which is
the file name and you would enter the.
Actual name of the class.
So we have the package name here.
We just need to edit string util.
So this will add that attribute and the main class attribute in the in the manifest file in the jar
file.
It's done.
So let me just execute this once again and you can see that it is done so we can also do it.
And this way you can directly specify or you can edit an existing file there.
Now let me just show how to create this jar and also specify the string you tell from with an eclipse.
So let me just delete this one more time.
You did this so, so very quick.
So just right click here and once on the package, say export.
Everything else is going to be just the same jar file next.
So we still have the util one.
And next.
Here, next.
Now, here we can see that there is this main class.
Now click on Browse.
Here.
It shows this thing within this package we have the string util class and this is the only class which
had the main method.
So it is showing only that otherwise it would have shown any other files to within this package.
So head.
Okay, so we are selecting string string util as the main class and hit finish.
Now the manifest file will also have the main class entry now.
So if we go back it would have created the jar here.
So just.
Go back and say.
Execute.
And that tells us that main class entry is there in the manifest file.
Just make sure.
I just want to reiterate one more time.
So if we are editing the manifest file, you should ensure that there is at least one one here.
One line is left here at the end.
Otherwise it will not work.
You need to have at least one new line entry here.
So that's it.
And here, within this folder, I also have this file called Helloworld class.
If we want to add that, then all we need to do is we have to just say.
You f we just use UDF command and we need to specify hello world dot class and we just need to remove
this one because there is no manifest file.
We are just updating this particular file so we are adding this to that.
So if you set.
It got added.
So if you say Java TX, so it will show you.
The Hello world class over here.
So that's that.
So we are done with all of the commands and we just need to look at the sea of command.
So for that, let me open.
I mean, go.
Here we are inside Jared.
And Jared is the workspace of my lips.
And within that, we have Trello Web project.
So let me click that.
So within your web, we have source and build.
So build is where we have all the class files.
So click on build and we can build.
We have classes and here is where we have the entire package, like the com semantic square Trello and
all of these.
But essentially in this path we will see only class files.
So we can also create a jar for this one.
So let me.
So let's go into this particular folder directory called classes did three little web build classes.
So we are here.
So let me open.
This one.
So I'm inside that.
And here, let's create a jar for this entire com folder.
So it would be jar C for create F and we'll just say com dot jar and all.
So this is the asterisk.
So this would just create a jar and it is about 45 kilobytes.
But if you look at this column folder, it is almost double the size.
It has around 85 kilobytes, so it is reduced by half.
And there are also options for specifying that we want to create this jar in an uncompressed format.
We can also do that, but typically we would want it in compressed format.
So that's why you would see this option.
So in the resources section, I'll try to include a document which will give you more options, information
about other options that can be used and perhaps some other resources also.
So do look out for any documents in the resources section.
Now, instead of asterisk, you can also you can also specify individual file names.
For instance, you can say C, F, and let's say you want to just include util.
So you will say util hyphen 1.1. jar and now you can specify semantic square slash.
Me go back here.
Does this thrill you and you tell.
So you're just specifying only the directory now.
So if you go back into classes, you can see that it created this.
So this is just a directory.
Now, if you want to create if you want to include just one class.
So you can also say and it's a string you tell.
Dot class, and if you want yet another class, then you would just put a space there and you would
include the next one.
So you can say something like this.
They just changed to hyphen two.
So.
So it has created this one.
So it will have only two files.
So that's the sea of command.
One other thing is I also mentioned about this thing that a var file is also a jar file.
So I also have this var file here.
So let me just wait for the box dot var which we created earlier.
Okay.
So Waterfall is also a jar file, as we said.
So we should be able to use the jar command.
So here it is.
So this is jar.
So let me just change it to.
Dot Bar.
Sorry it is.
Books.
Low hardcover.
There you go.
Now you can see the entire layout of this thing.
So as you can see, the web in the folder is there.
Then the web XML is there.
And within the banner there is the lib folder which has the jar files.
So what would have also the jar files?
That's the thing.
And with this command, like earlier, I showed you how to update.
Using the manifest file.
Just keep in mind that if we change this, if we make it u, m, f, instead of u f m, then this also
has to be changed.
If M comes before F, then the manifest file name has to come before the jar file name.
So just wanted to mention that.
So that's about it.
You now know how to create jar files and how to manipulate it.
So in future, if you create some reusable components, you know how to create jar files and those jar
files can be used across projects.
That's about it.
Thank you and happy coding.