Hi there.
Now let's look at Greece.
It will also be doing a demographic.
We will have to look at comparable uncompetitive interfaces that are probably popular among interviewers
.
One question could be what the difference is in between these two interfaces.
So this lesson will surely help you answer such questions.
It reset as the name implies uses a the data structure.
Specifically it uses something called the red black tree.
So it is a red black tree.
Best implementation of a navigable search interface.
OK.
And internally it uses a tree map just like the.
Set uses it Hashima on tree map stores key value based.
But resect has only elements so it will start the elements Eskies while it will store an empty object
that is an instance of Object class as the value.
Now if you recall Hastert also does the.
And if you're interested you can check out the source code of the augmented within that reset Plus we
know the preset elements will be unique are not also sorted.
And it is unique because it is a set although it is slightly slower than Hasek it still offers fast
Look up with a logarithmic complexity for I'd read more on contains methods for Hasek.
I recall that these operations were supported in constant time.
And here's an example where we are creating a Chrisette offsprings on adding three strings.
When we paint them we can see that they are sorted under string.
One one one gets printed as the first element which is followed by ABC which is then followed by D on
the rest of the lesson.
Let's head over to our editor and learn by writing some code.
OK here we are in the second more class so we look at this class and set them all on we had this method
call us Hassidim.
So for them all we are going to have a new method called Greaser's them.
OK.
And here it is.
So in this light we saw how we can create a set of strings.
Now let's see how we can create a three set off user defined object which is the book.
So in the Hassidim all we looked at this class called book which is defined here at the bottom of the
class and it had this state like title author on ear.
If you recall.
We also wrote a few methods like that to string hash called an equals method which you are needed for
Hasek.
OK.
They were auto generated.
So that's up on the cross on we are going to use the same class.
Quarte Chrisette also.
OK here we are creating four instances of book and just two of them have the same speed.
OK.
So they are Harry Potter books written by the same author and published in the same year and the third
book is valid and the fourth book is effective Djala.
Now here we are creating an instance of Chrisette.
OK.
Undestroyed set needs to store only books.
So here we are using the notation the gender X notation on saying that it needs to be every set of books
and that reference type is set.
The countries that implements a set and we are writing the four books year and we are simply rating
on printing the books.
And when we pass the book it's going to end with the postering matter.
We know that the posting method has been implemented in the book class so it overrides the string and
the objects.
So let's go ahead and run this.
Here it is.
So it is throwing an exception.
OK this class gasp exception and we'll see what light is being generated.
And it says it has something to do with comparable.
So when it comes to objects user defined objects we are encountering this problem which was not there
in the light which was about three set off strengths.
OK.
So there there was no exception.
But here we are seeing an exception.
So it has set the main concern was uniqueness.
OK.
And we were able to achieve it using hash Gaut unequals method.
And they also helped us with the Hoshko method.
Also how does it fast lookup bucket 3 set the how an additional requirement which is softening.
OK so it needs to be unique it needs to be fast and it needs to also socket.
So then Mrs. sautéing.
So there is some additional thing that we need to do which means that there needs to be an order among
the elements.
Right because we need to sort those elements in a certain order.
OK.
There are two ways to do it.
One is called us an eternal ordering which uses an interface called compatable.
We need to implement that interface call comparable which is from Damodar like package.
And the second approach is to use competitor OK it's also an interface from Dollar Audiard.
So keep this in mind.
So you have two approaches for this one is using the comparable which we are calling it as nature or
ordering.
On the other one is using competitor.
OK.
So you may have some interview questions on that.
So pay attention to that.
So keep that in mind.
Now first let's look at the comparable interface which is a natural auguring.
OK.
Uncomfortable interface is from the dollar not like package and it has exactly one muttered card compared
to OK.
Uncompiled boot will tell us where to place the element.
So compared to a third basically returns and value and that the anger value can be zero or one or it
can be zero or a positive integer or a negative integer.
Let's actually go ahead and look at the comparator in the API.
So this is the comparable interface from the Java 8 API and it has this method compare to.
OK.
Now what happens is let's assume that there is already an element in the reset and you want to add a
new element.
So what research is going to do as Treece it is going to invoke the comparable method on the new element
that you want to add and that will pass the existing element.
The only element that is there and the reason it will be passed under compared to amateur we'll see
whether we are too pleased or element if it returns a zero.
It means that the new element is a duplicate and hence will not be added but effort returns a negative
integer.
It means that a new element has to be placed before the element that is already there.
OK before the input element OK which means that it is done the input element.
But if it returns a positive integer it means that it is greater than.
So it needs to be placed after this element.
Now if there are more than one element in that reset then the comparative method will be in bold on
the new element that needs to be added but it will be added for each of the.
It will be invoked for each of the elements.
So that's what is going to happen.
And so far one of the elements if Cresap finds that if that element that we want to add is a duplicate
then it's going to roll down to zero.
It's not going to do any for the comparisons with the subsequent elements.
OK but if it returns or minus 1 x and replaces the element right before the existing element which is
being compared.
But if it returns a positive integer then it means that the newly added element has to be compared with
the next element.
OK.
So that's the comparable method.
And you can later when you have time you can also read about it.
One thing I want to bring your attention to is this statement here.
It says that if compared to Materi dunces zero when you do run ex-drug compared to white returns is
zero which means that the new element is a duplicate.
So in that case if the sample elements are also compared using equals mentored then equals also should
read neutral.
So they're saying don't try to have this kind of this kind of behavior.
And they are strongly recommending it but it's not mandatory.
And this is not the case.
So in that case you would have to indicate that whether you are implementing this method compared to
.
OK.
And here you need to have this kind of message.
It says that this class has a natural ordering that is inconsistent with equals.
So the next question is who is going to implement this comparable interface.
So the compatible interface will be implemented by the bookless.
OK.
So the book Class whose objects will be stored in a preset is going to implement to implement a compatible
interface and is going to override the compare to method.
So let's go ahead and do that.
It's actually done already.
So here it is implements comparable.
So this is from the law Gelada dot like package uncomparable net that is right here at the bottom.
So compared to object is taking an object an instance of Object as input.
So this compared to as we mentioned earlier is be really being worked on the new element that is going
to be added.
So this get Dido's right under title of the new element and we are calling the compare to method on
that idea.
So that title is a strength.
So there is a comparative method in the string class also.
So he's being in work and the object that we are passing as the input object since this is an off object
type of object class.
We don't just get the book and we are crutching.
It's vital so that both the titles are being compared.
So we are trying to sort by that item.
OK.
So that's the reason.
So let's just go ahead and run this.
Now if you see the elements got added on the second book did not get it because it was a duplicate.
So the uniqueness was uniqueness is there unmoral where the elements are also sorted.
So you can see the last one as a factor of Java then how the parts are done right.
OK.
Now in the slide we have seen a set of strengths and we did not see any issue with that.
And that's because as the string class also implements comparable.
Ok that's why we are able to invoke the comparative method on the string over here.
So that's why we did not see any issue with that and it's just like compair just like string we might
also want to add integers into it.
So the integer class which is the boxed but I do also implements the comparable interface.
Same also applies with same also goes with other boxes primitives like double float and on.
So all of them implement it so that those elements can be stored and treated and there can be are dead
.
They can be sorted.
Now the reason it is qualis natural ordering is because the elements themselves are seeing how they
have to be sorted.
OK so they are defining the actual sorting logic.
So think after you it as just a framework.
And it needs to be told how to suck OK.
And the first approach.
So which is the natural ordering the elements themselves which are going to be stored are seeing how
hard they need to be Socky.
OK that's why it's called us natural Adoni.
OK.
Because the sorting criterion is coming from the elements themselves.
So that's about nature ordering.
Now let's look at the second approach which is to use a competitor which is from the job what are your
package and with competitor unlike in the comparable case the sautéing criteria comes externally.
So the book objects will not define this art incredibly I forgot.
OK.
So let's also look at that not before doing that.
Let me just mention one more thing.
So the comparable method you know it is returning and which can be zero or it can be negative or positive
integer so that negative or positive integer is what is differentiating it from the equals method and
has said we looked at the he equals metric.
So in this guess since it's more than equal it needs to be more than equal.
So the goal is to not just detect uniqueness but also to sort.
So that's the reason we how the negative integer on positive integer being returned by this matter.
Now let's look at competitor.
So here is a competitor method.
And here is the compare matter undertakes two objects and it compares them.
OK.
So we need competitor needs to be implemented separately by a new class and you are going to do that
.
And it also has some other matters some static models but let's not worry about it.
The only abstract matter is the Complera matter.
Let's just go ahead and implement that.
And like I said earlier even the integer class has the compare to matter.
So let's go back here and let's implement a new class.
It's called a spiteful competitor which implements a better interface and much control.
Oh I do competitor now has to add an unimplemented method and unimplemented methods compare.
And it is comparing the two objects on one off the object will be the element that needs to be added
the new element and the other object will be an element that is already there.
OK.
So let's go ahead and use the same logic.
Use that title.
So you will see object 1.
It needs to be Doncaster to book normally to wrap this here.
And we need to get by in which are done a string and we can use a compare method of that.
So let's do the same thing but it will be.
So we are once again comparing that bitless.
So we are making use of the Compared to them and then we can actually use a compare to my girdled some
of the string class.
So that's sorting criteria and so on.
And when you do that's just common this out here it's actually not needed.
And we need to pass the competitor here.
Unique Retallack researched what logic has to be used for sorting since there is no natural ordering
anymore because we commentor are comparable.
What say I don't know let's go ahead and run this.
And as you can see you're looking fine.
Now if you do this which means that it is implementing compatible.
But we are also passing the competitor.
So in this case it will still use this one.
It will still use that I do competitor.
So the competitor implementation will override the natural ordering.
OK so if you put a print statement here you will be able to see that the computer that is being used
.
OK.
Now one advantage of using competitors is that in this case we are passing this particular competitor
but let's say if you want to also if you also define the author competitor so you can also sort by alter
.
So in which case at runtime you can specify which competitor to use if you want a competitor.
You'll say that I do compare let's say there is a user interface and the user chooses sort by title
.
In that case you will run this you will pass this instance to a competitor.
But if the user selects sort by author then you will pass on to a competitor or if the user selects
sort by publication date then you will write to support a new class for that and your competitor and
they will pass on instance of done.
So this kind of passing off competitors at runtime.
Basically the unpartisan strategy is being Basit at runtime.
So this kind of a strategy is going to this kind of an approach is called US strategy partan.
So that's a design by the end where the strategy the actual algorithm is being passed at runtime.
So in this gives the sorting strategy will be set at runtime.
So that's what I'd want is that you have using the competitor interface.
Now one other thing I want to tell us this is regarding the mission ordering.
So if I call Amandus somebody moiling the competitor and I'm also D-Mo. incompatible.
Now we saw that we have this exception.
Now this exception is generated when we are adding the first element Ritchson.
So that's because the trees are actually ensures that even the first element that is being added has
to be a subtype of compatible.
And in this case when it was trying because we are we have commented this out.
So it was trying to see if it can be Kostikov compatible it could not cost and so it generated that
last gasp exception.
So that's about it.
Let me stop here.
So we looked at what competitor uncomfortable and in the next lesson we will also look at the other
methods in the unnavigable set interface which And there are few other matters.
So they're in the next lesson we will try them out.
They are not very commonly used.
So let's just keep them as a separate lesson.
OK.
So that's about it.
So just keep in mind that we have embeddable on competitor compatibilism a total ordering and it has
only one metor compared to one competitor.
How does that compare to mentor underdose competitors from job to deal package.
Okay so that's about it.
Thank you.
And the court is available in the resource section happy coding.