Hello there.
This is the De La Rue.
Earlier I mentioned that a jour program can also have memory leaks, despite all the efforts from GC.
Item six from effective Java is about avoiding memory leaks and it says that eliminate obsolete object
references.
So let's go ahead and see what an obsolete object references.
Let's consider this example from item six, which represents a stack.
And for the sake of brevity, I included only the relevant parts of the code.
And if you do not know what a stack is, it is simply a last in first out data structure and it supports
two main operations push and pop.
Using push, you can add an element to the stack and pop would allow you to remove and return the last
element inserted into the stack.
And that's the reason it is called as last in, first out.
So basically Stack represents a collection of elements.
Now in our example here, you can see both push and pop operations and elements in the stack are stored
in an array of objects and the array is also named as elements.
The variable size represents the current size of the array, and it also acts as an array index and
its value will be one greater than the index of the last inserted element into the array.
It would be zero whenever stack is empty.
Here.
The push method first invokes a method called ensure capacity, which ensures that there is enough space
in the stack to add a new element.
That is, there is enough space in the elements array.
So if the elements array is already full, then it would roughly double the size of the array.
Next, the push method would add the element into the stack at the index position size and it would
then increment the size.
Similarly, Pop ensures that an element is returned only when stack is not empty.
As you can see here, pop is first incrementing the size and is then returning the element at that index.
But here we have a memory leak here.
Even after the method returns, the element at that index is still referencing the object which was
just returned.
So if we keep popping elements, then we are returning objects.
But the references are still being retained in the stack.
So those references are being referred to as obsolete references.
And the objects they are referring to are memory leaks.
Even when those objects do not have any references in the code that is invoking the pop method, garbage
collector will still not collect those objects as it considers them to be alive due to these obsolete
object references.
So if you recall, we said that a memory leak is basically an unused object that is never freed, which
is what happened in our stack example.
So GC is simply unable to recognize them as abandoned objects, as dead objects.
Note that each of these unused objects might be referencing other objects too.
And so those objects are not collected to.
So that's really bad.
So memory leaks will result in increased memory footprint.
Which would in turn imply increased GC activity.
And if there is a lot of GC activity, we know that there will be stop.
The world pauses and that means application, performance degradation.
And in worst case, if we are not lucky, then we may run into out of memory error.
And the solution for this is to null out obsolete references.
So here is the correct version of the pop method, and it sets the element in the stack to null and
uses another variable to return the object.
So no more obsolete references.
Now that you know about this, you shouldn't go about nailing every object reference, and that would
lead to unclean code.
Almost always you would let objects go out of scope and become dead.
That way they are garbage collected, nothing, not object.
References should be an exception rather than norm.
So the next question would be when should we be nailing out references?
Generally, you should be alert when your program is managing its own memory.
Like in the case of Stack example here, in such cases, there is a potential for you to end up with
obsolete references.
So just be alert when you're writing such kind of code.
In general, sometimes your program may be running for a very long time with memory leaks, and if you
are lucky, you may never get out of memory errors or you may not even see noticeable degradation in
performance.
But if you're not lucky, you may get out of memory error or your application might slow down.
In that case, you can use performance monitoring tools which can help you in detecting memory leaks.
In the resources section, I will include a list of a few performance monitoring tools and you can take
a look at them.
Sometimes you may not have any memory leaks at all, but your application might still be using a lot
of memory.
And if you don't see any issues in your code, which is highlighted by the performance monitoring tool,
then the only thing you can do is to allocate more heap space via the XMM X Command, which we saw earlier.
Or you can allocate more resources, like more CPUs or more memory.
So just to summarize this entire series on GC, there are two main things you should remember about
GC is that.
First garbage collectors employ market sweep kind of algorithms to identify and reclaim dead objects.
And these algorithms would require pausing the application completely.
And to reduce the times.
Garbage collectors use generational collection approach.
Certain garbage collectors use features like Multithreading to further reduce the pastimes.
Now keep in mind that from what we saw, Marcus copy algorithm was being used in young collection.
So just keep that in mind.
So that's about it.
And I hope you enjoyed learning about garbage collection.
Thank you.