Hi there.
This is Dana.
So far we looked at makes sense and representative interfaces, but there is also another kind of interface
called marker interface.
And let's see what it is.
We know that interfaces declare one or more abstract methods indicating either some capability or some
core functionality depending on the type of interface.
But market interfaces are slightly different.
They are simply interfaces without any methods.
That is, they have empty body.
However, they are still valuable.
They are mainly used to market class as having certain property that is any class.
Implementing the marker interface announces that it has the property defined by the market interface
and this property is explained in plain English words in the Java dock of the marker interface, which
basically is the marker interface specification.
So it is only plain English words and there are no methods.
The clients of the implementing class would then take some action based on the supported property.
To take that action, clients may have to invoke some of the methods of the implementing class.
That is the class that is implementing marker interface.
Sometimes the marker interfaces specification explicitly mentions about these methods.
Let's look at some example marker interfaces in the Java API.
First example is a market interface called Random Access, which is from the Java package.
Since it is from Java, we know that this interface is relevant to data structures.
And as the name suggests, any class implementing this interface declares that it allows fast, random
access of its elements.
That is, the elements can be accessed randomly and quickly too.
So fast.
Random access is the property that is defined by random access interface and ArrayList is one class
that implements this interface.
And in doing so it is declaring that it supports fast, random access of its elements.
We will soon see an example that shows how this information is used by one of the algorithms.
Second example is a marker interface called Serialize Realizable, which is from the Java package.
And as the name suggests, any class implementing this interface declares that it allows its objects
to be serialized.
So it is going to declare that it allows its instances to be serialized.
We will look at serialization in detail in the IO chapter, but what it essentially means is it allows
Java objects to be converted to byte streams so that the byte streams can be saved to hard disk for
later serialization or byte streams can also be transmitted to a remote JVM where they can be serialized.
This serialization is nothing but simply converting the byte streams back into Java object.
So in this case a property defined by serialize able interface is serialize ability.
Note that when we look closely, the semantics of the term property is a bit confusing here.
In the first example, a class implementing random access is saying that it has the inbuilt capability
to support fast random access, whereas with serialize able, the implementing class is simply saying
that it is giving permission for its objects to be serialized.
The actual capability to serialize objects belongs to an external class, so it is not with the class
that is implementing the interface.
So there is a class called object output stream in Java or IO package which does the actual serialization.
But the implementing class can provide certain assistance in the serialization and the serialization
process.
But for now, let's not bother ourselves about that.
So just note the difference in semantics for the term property.
In one case it was capability, while in the other case it was more often giving permission.
Now let's look at an example usage of the marker interface, random access.
We have the static method called shuffle in the class collections, which is also part of the Java package.
And this method takes a list and randomly shuffles its elements.
As the name shuffle suggests.
The shuffle algorithm applied depends on whether or not the input list implements random axis, and
for that the instance of operator is used as shown here.
If the input list implements random access, like in the case of ArrayList, then the shuffle algorithm
is applied directly on the list.
For this, the algorithm uses some of the methods of the input list, which would be ArrayList if ArrayList
is passed.
However, if the input list does not implement random access like in the case of link list, which also
implements list interface, then the method uses an alternative algorithm to achieve reasonable performance.
That's because without random access support, it would be expensive to apply the shuffle algorithm
directly on the input list.
So in this case, the logic is that first the list elements are copied into an array.
Then the shuffle algorithm would be applied on that array.
And finally, the shuffle elements are dumped back from the array into the list.
So as you can see, the algorithm applied is based on whether or not the input list supports the random
access property.
Note that random access is also utilized in several other methods in the collections class.
So that's about marker interfaces.
But there is one more interesting marker interface called Quotable, which we will discuss as another
example in the next lesson.
So just to recap, unlike mcshane's and representative interfaces, marker interfaces do not declare
any methods.
They are simply used to mark or tag a class as having certain property.
There are not many marker interfaces in the Java library.
C realizable is probably one of the commonly used ones.
But more than writing to hard disk these days, it is more common for certain complex and frequently
used objects to be cached in the memory.
This way we don't have to reconstruct these complex objects every time they are needed.
They can simply be fetched from the cash.
And cash is an object caching system and it requires all the objects it caches to implement realizable.
So the marker interface, so realizable has to be implemented.
So that's about it.
And thank you.