Hi there.
This is the model group so far.
We looked at the different data types and we also know that Java is a statically type language that
is once a variable is declared with a particular type.
It can only be assigned values of that type.
But sometimes we may have to assign the variable with a value which is of some other data type, and
in that case that value must be casted or in other words, converted to the data type of the variable.
And that's where typecasting comes into play.
So typecasting is necessary when we want to assign a variable or a literal of one data type to a variable
of another type.
For example, you might want to assign a variable or a letter of type long or a type byte to an end
variable.
And to do such assignments, type casting is required.
And typecasting is possible only between numeric primitive types.
And we know that a numeric primitive type can be any primitive type other than boolean.
Recall that even the data type car falls under numeric as it is represented by an unsigned integer.
So we cannot cost anything to bullion or vice versa.
That is, we cannot assign anything other than bullion to a bullion variable.
Similarly, we cannot assign a bullion literal or a bullion variable to a variable of some other type.
And typecasting can be either implicit or explicit.
First, let's look at implicit casting.
Implicit casting is required if we want to assign a variable or a literal of smaller type to a variable
of larger type.
In this case, we say that a widening conversion is being performed as the type of the value on the
right is being widened.
The notion of smaller and larger types is based on the range of values they support.
Here is an example where a variable x of type end is assigned to a variable Y of type long.
And for this an implicit casting is performed and it is done by the compiler automatically, so the
value assigned to the variable y will be casted so that it will have 64 bits as a bit.
Depth of long is 64.
Not that X will still have the value 65 with a depth of 32.
And this diagram shows the order of implicit casting performed by compiler.
As an example, you can see here that assigning byte to shot or to any other data type except car as
implicit as standing by to car would be explicit, which we will see next.
We can also see that assigning an integer to a floating point variable would fall under implicit casting.
For instance, even assigning 64 bit long to 32 bit float is implicit as a range of values for float
is larger than the range of values for long.
So range of values is what is dictating this order.
We can also see that assigning car to end is also implicit as the range of car is well within the range
of in data type.
We know that car is internally represented by a 16 bit unsigned integer.
Likewise assigning car to other larger data types like Long Float or double would also be implicit.
So that's implicit casting.
Now, if we reverse the direction of these arrows, then we would get the order for explicit casting.
And here it is where the direction of arrows has been reversed.
So that's the ordering for explicit casting.
And we need it if we want to assign a variable or a literal of larger type to a variable of smaller
type.
And in this case, we say that a narrowing conversion is being performed as we are narrowing down the
Now in this diagram, apart from reversing the direction of arrows, two new bi directional arrows have
been added, connecting current bite and current shot, implying that any assignments between themselves
would require an explicit cast.
For instance, assigning car to either byte or shot would be explicit, as car is not within the range
of values of these two data types.
Note that even though current shot have a bit depth of 16, assigning car to shot would still require
an explicit cast.
That's because for car the range is 0 to 2 to the power of 16 minus one.
Right.
But for shot two is race to the power of 15.
That's because the range is minus two to the power of 15 to 2 to the power of 15 minus one.
And so car can fall outside this range.
Just note that casting to car is always explicit.
And the reason for this is all these other numeric data types can have negative values while CAR is
represented by an unsigned integer, which can be only zero or positive but not negative.
Here is an example of explicit casting.
Here we are assigning a long variable with a value 42 to NW variable since long is larger than eight.
We have an explicit cast, so the INT in parentheses is the explicit cast.
Also the applied cast should be compatible with the data type of the variable.
On the left side, that is the type specified with the cast has to be same or of a lower type but not
larger type.
So in this case it has to be ENT or any type smaller than end, including car as car as unsigned integer.
Now without the cast, we would get a compiler error, even though 42 is a valid int.
That's because.
Why?
On the right hand side is an expression which will get evaluated to 42 only at runtime.
Compiler just does not know that.
And all it knows is that y is of type long and it wants us that we may be doing something wrong here
by assigning a larger variable to a smaller one.
So we need to inform the compiler that we are fine with the assignment by inserting an explicit cast.
Just note that with regards to implicit casting, although it is taken care of by the compiler, if
you wish to, you can still apply a superfluous cast.
In this example, a bite is custard to carp.
Since the byte value is 65, the corresponding UTF 16 value uppercase A is assigned to the variable
C.
Now here, both widening and narrowing conversion is being applied.
First bite is converted to end through a widening conversion and then the resulting end is converted
to car through a narrowing conversion.
Here car variable is assigned an integral 65 and in this case we do not need an explicit cast as 65
is within the range of cap.
However, if the lateral is outside the range of car, then we would need to insert an explicit cast
to avoid a compilation error.
Here a short variable is assigned a character literal here variable as gets assigned a decimal equivalent
65.
Once again, no explicit cast is required as 65 is within the range of shot.
The cast would be needed if the assigned literal was outside shots range.
But out of range assignments would also lead to information loss.
And let's look at that.
And here is one scenario where there is information loss due to out of range assignment.
Here the value.
One, two, three, four, five, six is outside the range of byte and there is an explicit cast here
and the variable gets assigned a weird number, which in this case is 64 and 64 is assigned because
JVM discards all but the lower eight bits of the binary equivalent of this number one, two, three,
four, five, six.
And those lower eight bits which appear on the right side of the bit pattern corresponds to that decimal
64 and that's how we get the number 64 here.
Only lower eight bits are considered as the variable.
Here is a byte which has only eight bits.
So there is an information loss here.
Essentially what is happening here is that the variable is a small container as it is a byte and we
are trying to fill it with something that is not going to fit inside that container.
So some of the stuff that we are trying to fill is going to spill from the container.
And so there is an information loss.
Second scenario of information loss is when we try to cast a floating point littoral or a floating point
variable to an integer or a car variable.
In this case, it will always truncate the number.
Recall that when we say Integer, it could mean any of the four data types by short end or long.
And we know that floating point would include float and double.
For example, when we try to assign a floor 3.14 to an end variable, then the value 3.14 gets truncated
to three.
Similarly, when a 00.9 is assigned to an end variable due to truncation, the variable is assigned
the values zero.
Here.
A double is casted to cap since the value is 65.5.
It would first be converted to end, which would be 65 after truncation.
And then it's corresponding UTF 16 value is assigned to the variable.
So the examples in this slide show that explicit casting could be needed even if we are dealing with
letters.
Just keep in mind that the main reason for explicit casting is because the value assigned could be outside
the range of the variable on the left hand side.
Now coming to information laws with regards to implicit casting.
Generally, you will not encounter information laws with implicit casting.
A lot of books and instructors do say that there is no information laws with implicit casting.
But to be precise, for few assignments, there is a possibility of some information loss.
For example, let's consider the depiction of implicit casting order once again.
This is the implicit casting order we have seen earlier here.
Assigning an end to flawed or along to flawed could lead to loss of precision as the resulting value
may lose some of the least significant bits of the value that is being assigned.
And this loss of precision may also happen when a long is assigned to a double.
But not that end.
To double is fine.
Let's look at this through a simple example here.
An ENT variable called Old Val is assigned to a float.
In this case, there would be a loss of precision.
And in the next statement we are casting that float back to it.
Variable new well and when we print new well, we will see that at a slightly larger than old Val.
So when all well was assigned to float, it was rounded to a larger number and hence there is slight
loss of precision.
So there can be some loss of information even with implicit casting.
But that's a pretty uncommon case.
So we're not clearly understand casting.
Now, let's look at a couple of common use cases where casting is applied.
First, let's look at an example for implicit casting.
Let's assume that we have these two variables.
F one and F two.
And let's also assume we have this method named CO, which takes two parameters as input, which are
of type double.
So here D1 and D2 are referred to as parameters and we will discuss methods very soon.
What the method go does here is irrelevant for this discussion.
Next we can call the method go by passing the to float variables as input so the two float variable
values will be assigned to the two double parameters that the method defines.
So the value of variable f one will be assigned to variable D one and value of variable F two will be
assigned to variable data.
And for this an implicit cast will be performed from float to double.
So this kind of implicit casting is pretty common when dealing with methods.
Next.
With regards to explicit casting, let's consider this example where we want to compute an average of
two numbers two and three in Java.
This would result in two rather than 2.5, as both two and three.
Here are letters.
Though we have a double on the left side, we still end up with the value two, and we will discuss
the reason for this later when discussing arithmetic operators.
So to get the right value 2.5, we would have to apply an explicit cast in this way.
So if you are performing such kind of arithmetic operations involving division operator, there is a
chance you may have to insert explicit cast.
So those are some common scenarios of using casting.
Casting is mainly needed when we want to assign a variable or a literal of one type to a variable of
another type.
And an explicit task comes into play when there is an issue with the range of values.
Now let's do a quick demo of some of the examples we already discussed.
A new method called type casting has been added to basic demo program, and you can find the updated
program in the resources section.
So let's just go ahead and look at the program.
Look, here is the new method typecasting.
So it has been appropriately named as typecasting as we are dealing with typecasting.
And in the main method we have commented on the previous two method invocations, print and primitives
as we are done with them.
And so there is a new method in location statement called typecasting.
So let's just go ahead and look at the type casting method and we are printing the statement saying
that we are inside typecasting and we have some of the interesting examples which we have seen earlier.
So let's just go ahead and look at each of the examples.
So the first example here demonstrates this, an explicit casting example.
So here we have the variable Y, which is of type long and it's being assigned to variable X of type.
And so this should give a compilation error because Y is of larger type and X is of smaller type.
So there needs to be an explicit cast.
So as you can see, it says incompatible types, possible lossy conversion from long to end.
So why here is an expression and it gets evaluated to 42 only at runtime.
So it compile time compiler.
All it knows is the type of y which is long and it knows that it cannot be assigned because there can
be a lossy conversion.
So we need to tell the compiler that it's fine by inserting a cast.
So that's what we are going to do now.
So now it's fine.
So that's the first example.
And in the second example, we have already seen this.
So this number literally is being assigned to bite and this demonstrates information loss.
But let me actually remove this here.
So this should also give a compilation error.
So this is a literal and in this case, the compiler knows that this value is being assigned to byte,
whose range is between -128 to positive 127.
So when you do this, it says it gives the same compiler error because in this case it knows that this
value itself, there is no expression here.
This is a literal, there is no expression like in the previous example.
But here it knows that clearly knows that this is false outside the range of byte.
So we need to insert.
A cast here.
So now if you compile it, it's compiles fine.
And if you run it.
It assigns 64 because there is an informal loss of information and some weird number gets assigned to
this variable called narrowed byte.
Now let's just change this.
Just to be a little bit more clear to 128.
This should also give a compilation error because 128 is outside the range of byte it's bytes ranges
-128 to positive 127.
So it gives the same error.
Either you need to insert a cast here, in which case there will be an information loss or it's got
to be some some number within the range.
So if you insert 127.
Then it is fine.
See no error there.
So let me just change this.
Mac.
So the third example here is about truncation.
So here we are assigning the value, the double value .99 and we are inserting a cast here.
So it's an explicit cast.
So this gets assigned, this variable I truncated will get assigned zero.
So let's just compile this.
So as you can see, it says zero.
So there is the 0.9 and got truncated to zero.
Now here in this example, it's an implicit cast X is of type eight, Y is of type long, so it's just
an implicit cast.
And so no compilation error two.
Now the next example is an implicit cast, but from car to end so carries a here and enters of a larger
type.
So it's going to be an implicit cast, but a value 65 will get assigned because for character A in UTF
16 for that the corresponding decimal value is 65.
And that decimal value gets assigned here because because of that data type end.
So if you go back here for I and it says 65, now here is something that's being cast to car and we
know that if anything is being cast to car, it's got to be an explicit cast.
So here we have byte here.
So it's being casted to car.
So the way it works is the byte first gets promoted to end and then from end there will be a conversion
to car.
So this value is 65.
So the corresponding UTF 16 value value is character A in uppercase.
We know that very well.
So it gets assigned here, over here.
So it's just we are calling it as a special conversion because initially there is a widening from byte
to end, which is then followed by narrowing from eight to car through the explicit casting.
So that's about it.
So those are the few of the interesting examples.
So just go ahead and download it from the resources and you can also type in the entire code and you
can play with it.
Okay then happy coding and thank you.