Hello there.
This is Lou.
And welcome back.
We have seen that variables of primitive types can hold raw data such as integers or characters or Boolean
literals.
Now, let's look at the second type of variables which can hold object references.
We know that this statement creates a student object and variable, as is an object reference here.
The type of the variable is referred to as reference type with primitive variables.
The type was primitive type and in this case it is a reference type and reference type can be either
a class or an interface.
In this case it is a class student and interfaces will be discussed later after a few sections.
Now this notion of reference type, we will revisit it later after a few sections when discussing about
inheritance.
It's a concept in object oriented programming here, as is a variable and it is an object reference
and not an object that is it holds a reference to a student object.
In other words, it holds bits that reference a student object in memory.
The statement has three parts in it, and each of them informs GM to do something.
And let's see what those three parts are.
The first part.
Student SE tells JVM to allocate space in the memory for a reference variable.
Then the part new student tells JVM to allocate space for a new student object in the memory.
So at this point we have space in memory for a reference variable and also a student object.
And finally the assignment operator assigns the memory address of the student object to the variable
se.
So variable se now holds the memory address of the student object.
So objects get stored in memory, but they get stored in a special area of memory which is assigned
to JVM.
So when JVM starts up, like any process, it gets a chunk of memory from the underlying operating system
in order to run its programs.
On one area of this memory is referred to as heap and all objects are stored on the heap.
This diagram shows the heap with all the objects and in our example the variable as references one student
object on the heap.
Internal section covers the heap concept and detail, but for now just note that we have heap and that
objects are stored on the heap.
We looked at depth of all primitives for object references bit depth is beam specific that is bit depth
of an object reference on one gvm may be smaller or larger than bit depth of an object reference on
another JVM, but on a given JVM, all object references will have the same bit depth regardless of
objects that they reference.
So the size of the object does not matter.
One object may have 20 instance variables, while another might have just one instance variable, but
the object references that are referencing them will have the same bit depth.
Default value for an object reference is null.
So if you do not initialize an object reference, it gets a default value of null and it is called as
a null reference and it implies object reference is not pointing to anything.
Just think of NULL as a special literal.
So you can also explicitly initialize an object reference with NULL.
So in this statement as will be assigned the default null.
And using a dot operator on SE which has null as a value will lead to an exception called null pointer
exception exceptions will be covered later in a separate section, and null pointer exception is simply
an error that occurs at runtime.
Now.
We already created objects and initialized their state to.
Now, let's quickly test what we see in this slide.
Here is our student class and in the main method we have created three student objects and we have initialized
their state.
Now let's take this third student and let's comment this statement.
And let's take this part.
Student.
Student three And let's move it to outside of the method.
Okay.
Let's make it static here.
And let's close the statement.
So.
Student three should get a default off.
None.
Right.
And it will give us an error at runtime, the null pointer exception because we are accessing the field
here and student three is null.
It's not referencing an object anymore, so it should give us an Al Pointer exception.
So here I am in the basics directory.
So let me just compile it.
Student.
So it gives us this exceptional point of exception.
So it has created the first student object and it has initialized the state and the compute method is
printing the state.
Similarly, for the second student object, also the state is being printed, but when it came to the
third student object here at line 66, it is giving us this exception or error at runtime.
So it is the null pointer exception.
So line 66 is right here.
So when we are trying to execute the statement, we get that particular error because Student three
is null and we cannot, we cannot access any field or a method on a null reference.
It needs to have a proper object so it can be a field or it can be a method, but we would end up with
a null pointer exception.
So that's about it.
Thank you.
And I will see you in the next lecture.