Hi there.
This is the De La Rue.
And welcome back.
Let's not get started with the collectors class and let's begin by looking at the two lists and the
two set methods, which we mentioned about earlier in the previous lecture.
And they're used to collect the stream of elements into a list and into a set.
So we have introduced this new method called collect to collection within the Stream Operations class,
and it's invoked from the main method.
So we are essentially collecting the stream elements into a collection implementation, which would
be a list or a set in our case.
So let's go ahead and look at the two methods.
So the input is the list of books which we know come from two different sources, the fictitious sources
in our example, Amazon and Book and Barnes and Nobles.
So we are going to work on this particular list.
So let's begin by looking at the two list method.
So let's build our pipeline sales stream.
Let's pick on the good books.
So we need a filter.
Be for books.
B don't get rating.
A good book would be a book which has a rating of at least 4.5.
And let's use a distinct.
Because we have the books from the different sources and we can have duplicates too.
So let's use distinct.
And let's use the collect method.
So here it is.
And it takes a collector.
So we need to use the two list method.
From the collectors class.
And this word written.
A list of book, let's call it list one.
Okay.
And let's go ahead and print it.
Let's say.
List.
One size thing that should be good enough.
Let's go ahead and run it.
So it has a size of nine.
So this is the second version of the collect method.
Now let's look at the first version of the collect method.
Just for the sake of it.
First is a supplier.
So let's create our container.
Okay.
Next is an accumulator.
So the accumulator is a by consumer.
So let's take a.
And I would stand for the container in this case the ArrayList.
So a would be the accumulator here.
And let's say a dot ad of t.
Tabulating the input stream element into this.
And finally, the combiner, which takes two, two containers, so let's say a one and a to a one dot
at all.
So if you remember, we had this kind of a method.
The list.
So here it would be a two.
So this is what we have.
So let me compile it.
So that's it.
Let's say this nine.
So this is how we can do it using the first collect method.
This is just to illustrate how it can be done.
But we do not want to do it this way.
We want to do it in the simplified way because there is already a predefined reduction for that.
So we would obviously want to use this one rather than this.
Instead of defining all of these, we would want to use this because there is already a predefined character
for that.
Now let's look at the second one, which is set.
So let me just copy this.
Let me just make it set here.
And let's call it set one.
And the filter is the same filter.
But we do not need distinct because we know that settlements elements are already distinct.
So let's say collect.
And collectors dot to set.
Okay.
Let's print it.
So it's just the same size.
So here we are doing this and we are able to do it because here we have already defined the equals and
the hashCode methods here.
So set actually to set returns A has set so internally in order to ensure that we have only unique elements,
the hash code and the equals method are used.
By this particular collector.
So that's there.
So those methods we have already defined.
So this is a hash set.
Now, let's say if we want to.
Just to test it out.
If we do this three set, then we get an error class cast exception because collect is returning a has
set and we are trying to cast it to tree set, which is not possible.
So that's why we have this.
But if we need this, then what we can do is we can.
Let's take this.
Use the.
To.
Collection method and let's say it returns set to and let's say we want a tree set to be returned.
Okay.
And we need to pass a supplier.
So supplier does not take any parameters because supplier has a method which does not take any parameters.
And we need to supply here a.
She said.
And that's it.
Now, in order to ensure the uniqueness, we know that we need this also the comparable method also
here it needs to implement comparable.
So book is implementing comparable here.
Here it is and it is.
It has the method compared to and it is ensuring that the elements are sorted using the ISBN.
And it also ensures a uniqueness.
So that's what we have here.
Okay.
So let me just print it.
So here it is.
So we are getting the size of the set, which is nine.
So it's just the same size.
So this is how we can do it.
We can just implement, invoke this two collection if we want some other implementation of a collection
so we can do this.
So that's these methods.
Now, here, in this version, we can also make use of.
Constructor references so we can say array list.
No.
So that would create a new construct, new ArrayList.
Then here we can use the add method and ArrayList.
So this is more.
Could be readable for some of us.
Some of them might prefer the earlier approach itself where we are using lambdas.
So that's it.
So we can also do this.
And if you run it once again, we have the same results.
So we can use method references in this way.
And here this is a constructor reference.
Similarly, even in here in the mutable reduction, let me comment this out and let's use.
The references.
So this is the first version of the collect method.
So here we need a string builder.
We need to construct a string builder so it's a supplier.
So we will say new.
So that's a constructor reference.
Then we need to use append.
So we'll say string builder.
So it takes a string as an input.
Now here we are appending a string builder with another append.
So it's an overloaded append method.
So this one is append, which takes the string as an argument.
And this, this append method takes a string builder as an option, but they are just overloaded methods.
So we can simply say.
String builder.
So we will once again use the same method.
So both of them are append methods.
But this one takes a string and this one takes a string builder.
So that's it.
But let's invoke the mutable redaction.
Here.
So let's just test the output once again.
Here it is.
This is the mutable reduction method and we have conquered too as a B, so it works, right?
Correctly.
So that's just to show you that we can convert this into method references.
Just wanted to show you that.
So we have all of these collectors methods.
So we can also make use of a static import.
So let me just go into the top and let's just say static.
Collectors dot all here.
And instead of using collectors, we can just set to set now to collection.
And even for the joining which we used in the earlier lecture, we can just do this.
So that's it.
So everything should work fine again.
That's it.
So that's the.
Collection methods, which would help stream elements to be collected into a list, into a set and even
a generic collection here.
So those are the methods.
And in the next subsequent lecture, we will look at other static methods that the collectors class
has.
So these are certain static methods and they are helping us to perform predefined collections.
And just to summarize, these methods would return an instance of a collector.
Collector is the interface and we discussed it in the earlier lecture.
Here it is.
If you say collect, it returns and collector.
So that's it.
Thank you and happy coding.