Hi there.
This is the Motley Crew.
And welcome back.
So we are now done with generics, which was a pretty long chapter.
It was a very comprehensive coverage.
And now let's go ahead and quickly review all the important features that we discussed in this chapter.
You may recall that the main motivation for introducing generics was to ensure type safety at compile
time.
Before generics was introduced in Java five, there was always a risk of running into runtime exceptions
that were related to type safety.
So generics is purely a compile time concept and there is no generics at runtime.
You may recall this example from the very first lecture and we said that this is how a class in pre
generics world looked like.
The stock class here can be used for storing and retrieving any object.
So the method parameter of set method is of object type and the return type of getter is also of object
type.
Then we had the developer, John, who stores the date instance from the Java SQL package and he also
retrieves the same object later and applies a cast in order to convert from object to date as the method
returns an object.
Next, Anita uses the same store instance that John created and resets the Date Object Store, but she
sets a date instance from Java util package rather than from Java SQL package.
And later, Jon Scott once again uses the same store instance and retrieves the data object.
And he also applies the data cast from Java or SQL, as that was what he used earlier while storing
the date instance.
And this would give a class cast exception at runtime as the date object now is from Java Util which
cannot be casted to Java SQL date.
Java is a type safe language and hence this exception was generated.
So language designers wanted to identify such kind of issues at compile time itself, and hence they
introduced generics.
So here is the same store class but with generics here.
Type parameter to use used which also acts as the type for the method parameter in the set method and
also as the return type for the getter.
He is also the type, for instance, variable a.
And here is John and Anita's quote, Due to use of generics, Anita's code does not even compile as
she cannot set a date store.
Instance can take only a date instance from Java or SQL as well specified when it was created by John.
Now another user, Raj, can use the same generic class store in order to store a book instance.
With this, one can only store and retrieve a book instance or any of its subtypes.
So with generics, we get compile time type safety and as an add on, the code is also cleaner as we
do not have to apply any explicit costs.
Compiler does that for us.
Code is also expressive as the programmer's intention is very clear, like storing a date instance or
a book instance code is also generic in the sense that client code can store any type of data like book
or date.
Of course, that can be restricted by using bounded type parameters.
Mostly generics and contact only with container type classes which are seen with collections framework.
It may not be very common for you to write such generic classes.
Just depends on your project.
So favor generic types when possible as this item from effective Java suggests.
But inexperienced programmers may still create road types, thus compromising the benefit of generics,
which is compiled type safety.
So this item wants us not to do that.
One reason why developers could be tempted to use raw types, especially for method parameters, is
because they don't know or they do not care what the object past US argument would store in such kind
of a situation instead of using raw type.
One can use unbounded wild card type which provides the benefit of compile time type safety, which
you do not get with raw type.
And here is an example use of an unbounded wild card type.
Here we can pass a list containing any type of element.
I know that wild card can only be used as a type argument, not as a type parameter.
Next.
The question is why not simply use object as type argument instead of a wild card as object is the superclass
of all classes and hence can be assigned any object.
But the limitation with using object as type argument is that you can only assign an instance that also
has object as type argument.
That is, you cannot assign something like a store of string.
And we know that this is due to invariance property which generic size which also helps with compile
time type safety.
But with wild card, we can assign an instance of any type that is store of a string or store of integer
or anything else.
So that's the benefit of using an unbounded wild card over using object as type argument.
And here is the Invariance property book is a subtype of bookmark, but list of book is not a subtype
of list of bookmark.
However for the same type argument inheritance of generic types hold.
So if type argument is bookmark then an array list of bookmark can be assigned to a list of bookmark
as array list is a subtype of list can be a little bit confusing, but just keep in mind that within
variants, type arguments are different.
This was the example we saw on why Invariance is needed.
This example explains what happens if invariants is allowed with generics.
Here we are passing a list of objects as argument, but in the method a movie object is being added
to this list and this could result in a runtime exception as the invoking code is always expecting that
the list would contain only book objects.
So invariance is needed.
However, we next discussed about how invariance is restrictive in certain harmless scenarios, although
it ensures compile time type safety.
One example was the display method, which would take a list of bookmarks and simply display them.
So no intention of inserting wrong type of elements.
But unfortunately, due to invariance, we cannot pass either a list of book or a list of movie in this
case.
So the workaround for such scenarios is to use either a per bonded wildcard or a generic method with
a bonded type parameter.
But we need to ensure type safety too.
And hence compiler has this restriction on a upper bounded wildcard.
We cannot invoke methods that use class level type parameters with any arguments except none.
Otherwise, there is always the chance of invoking such methods and past data that could break type
safety.
So if we invoke such methods with anything other than null, we get a compiler error.
Now with regards to invariants, we also discussed about the scenario where we would want to consume
data and still be able to pass different arguments.
We said that for this lower bound wild card can be used.
For instance, here, the method aggregate uses a lower bounded wild card type to aggregate data.
However, it can be invoked with either a list of bookmark or a list of object where object is the same
type of bookmark, but it cannot be invoked with a list of subtype of bookmark.
And here is the compiler restriction that would make a lower bound wild card type act as a consumer
of data and at the same time ensures that compile time type safety is not compromised.
So the rule says we can invoke methods that use class level type parameter only if argument is of lower
bounded type or one of its subtypes.
And we also discussed this important and interesting item which recommends using bonded wild cards to
increase API flexibility.
It says if parameterized type produces data use extents.
And if parameter type consumes data use super.
If parameter type produces data but does not know or care about type argument.
Use unbounded wild card.
Keep in mind that unbounded wild card is same as unbounded wild card, but with object as the invisible
bond.
Finally, if parameter type produces and consumes data, then you need to use exact match.
Also you can remember the text mnemonic.
And we also looked at few restrictions that go along with generics.
One of them is that class level type parameter cannot be used in a static context.
If our static method needs generic ness, then we can define a generic method.
Another restriction is that type argument cannot be a primitive.
And generics on arrays also do not mix well due to type safety concerns.
And such kind of method overloading does not work where the methods would end up with the same signature
after type erasure.
Remember that type erasure helps with interoperability with legacy code.
Keep in mind that with type erasure, the type parameter would be replaced with either object or the
leftmost bond if one or more bounds exist.
And finally, let's thank our awesome Java compiler for doing all these great things for us.
It ensures compile time type safety inserts, class performs type inference and finally does type erasure.
Does making generics a purely compile time concept?
So that's the end of this chapter.
And I hope you enjoyed learning about generics.
And as mentioned in the introductory lecture, if needed, do review generics concepts once every week
or a couple of weeks until you are completely comfortable with how it works.
That said, thank you and good bye for now.