Now let's focus on another runtime data area which is stuck.
But before doing that, let's review some of the stuff we covered so far.
We started the chapter by looking at loading a class when it is access for the very first time.
Unstudied about the lifetime of a type.
Output of this entire process is a class object.
We learned that class object, as well as any objects created out of it, are stored on the heap.
We also learn that the class data itself, which includes the meta information about the class plus
any method code, will go in the method area.
So we have objects on heap and class data in the method area.
Now as methods of an object or a class that is a static methods are being executed.
Then JVM somehow needs to keep track of those methods.
For example, GM needs to know what the currently executing method is.
Now, if this method invokes another method, then it needs to keep track of that method too.
And when that method finishes its execution, then GM should resume execution of the first method.
All of this information about the methods that are getting invoked and executed will be stored on stack.
Stock will also store the information about local variables in each of the executing methods.
Note that we are only talking about methods that are currently being executed and not the ones that
have either finished execution or the ones that have not yet been invoked.
So let's go ahead and learn about Stack.
It's a very important concept and you must know how Stacks work.
Stock is basically a leaf or data structure that is the last in first out data structure.
In the last lesson, we briefly discussed about what a stock is and it is one of the most fundamental
data structures.
Unlike Heap and Method Area, JVM creates a stack for each newly created thread.
For example, if you consider a web application and if you have two users accessing the application
simultaneously, then each of the users will be served by separate threads and each thread will be given
a separate stack, and the methods that get executed within the thread are trapped inside that stack.
There is no way for one thread to access another thread stack.
Not when a method is invoked, an entity called stack frame or simply just frame representing that method
is created and pushed down to the top of the stack.
As you can see here.
Now, if this method invokes another method, then a new stack frame will be created for that new method,
and that stack frame will also be pushed onto the top of the stack.
Frame holds a method state by holding information such as the local variable values.
Now a frame is popped off the stack when the method invocation completes either normally or abruptly
through some kind of an error.
Let's actually look at an example here we have three methods go foo and bar method go is invoking the
method foo which is in turn invoking the method bar.
No.
Let's have we first invoke the method go so off frame corresponding to method go gets created and will
be pushed onto stack.
Method CO has a local variable x and its value is also maintained on the stack.
Now we say that variable X is in scope and is alive as its method is currently executing.
Next method go is invoking method foo.
And so a new frame for foo is created and pushed on the top of the stack.
Foo has one method parameter y and also another local variable z, and both of them are stored on the
stack.
Now we say that both variables Y and Z are in scope and also allow, while variable X in method go is
still alive but not in scope anymore.
As method go is not the currently executing method.
That is it is not in scope.
Next method bar gets invoked and so a frame corresponding to it will be pushed onto the top of the stack.
Bar has one local variable called edge which is referencing an object.
Hello.
So Variable Edge is alive and in scope now while X, Y and z are alive but not in scope anymore.
Now here is the interesting thing.
Variable Edge is referencing an object, and we know that objects are stored on the heap.
So while Edge is on stack, the object it is referencing will actually be on heap.
So if a local variable is an object reference, then that variable is stored in its own stack frame
while the object it is referencing will be stored on the heap.
Now at some point, method bar finishes its execution and with that its corresponding stock frame will
be popped off the stock.
With that, its local variable edge is considered dead and the object it is referencing to is now considered
abandoned and so will be eligible for garbage collection.
No matter who is on top of Stack and its variables, Y and Z are both in scope once again, while variable
X is still alive but not in scope anymore.
Our next few finishes this execution and it's frame is also popped off the stack and with that both
its variables Y and Z are also gone.
At this point, method goes on top of stack and variable x is again in scope.
Finally method go also finishes and its tack frame is also popped off the stack.
So that's how stacks get populated.
Next, we will delve a little deeper and we will look at some of the data structures is dark frame holes.