Work and let's look at hash map.
But before going to the mall let's look at a few important things which are relevant to hash map.
I think we already discussed most of these points but let's do it one more time just for the sake of
completeness.
The methods get undermost brook and Constantine and that hash map insertion order is not preserved as
the elements are stored based on using it hash function hash map but it's not a lot of use.
And also one Halki.
Finally two methods are not synchronized unlike that legacy hash table class.
Now if synchronization is required it can always be taken care of externally.
As you'll see later when we get to the might be trading partner.
So that's about it.
And it's not time for that Demel took it for this demo a new class called map the more has been added
to the collections package just like bless them all.
I answered them all.
So in my of them all we have this matter hashmarks them all which we are going to fill now.
So in this demo they will test all the basic operations which we have seen earlier and we will also
look at how to iterate a map.
So we will be looking at the human.
So using the view that we can do it and initially we will create a simple hazmat later we will also
create a slightly more complex hash map.
So let's just go ahead and create a hash map.
That said the key is string.
So that's the generic notation.
So let me import let me just do a control of all.
And that automatically imported.
So here the brackets are empty here.
Just know that we can also have a string on integer specified here.
But it is automatically inferred by the compiler.
So here we are programming to an interface your map.
And so we have created the hash map.
Let's go and put some elements here
.
So here us three users John-Roger to iron.
Let's say these are their ages and we're on it.
Let's leave the value as another.
OK.
Now let's just print this
space map one.
So let me just run this.
It's in from the main You can search prints all of the values your key value pairs.
Now let's all right.
And it does mapping and axis and map.
My one word.
All right.
You let's just put some value here on the tree.
And
so as you can see the only value got over it and the new one.
OK.
Now let's try the contains ski operation.
So let me just say
map 1.
Lewinsky and it's just search for John
and it says Drew.
OK.
Now let's get a value.
So this is an Bensky operation that are done.
True.
Now given a key just fetched the values so that's the lookup operation.
That's the most commonly used operation with the hash map.
So let's get John's age now.
So we need to use get and John.
OK.
So that's the H here.
Now let's just go ahead and do it through the map.
OK.
So let's try hard but it don't matter.
There are a couple of ways to do it.
So first let's try to do that using the keyset method.
So keyset is one of the collection methods.
So let's get the research.
So let's just extract the keyset and for that we can use the keys at method.
So keyset what we've done is set.
So we call on the set of all keys.
So it's names you do control shift 0 9.
So use a for each statement.
I did it over the names.
OK.
Now we can say my plan got get all the name of the careers of the current name.
So let's just run it.
So here we are reading using keyset and we redid it in over all the names all the keys and for each
name we are we are fetching the corresponding h.
OK.
So that's one way off iterating on the second way as we can also do read using the entry set method
.
OK so let's also do that.
So the entry cert Vawdrey done a set of all mappings.
Let me just say.
And in this case it will be set off if you recall it would return an instance of the the entry interface
and we said it was an upstart interface.
So each mapping would be an instance of this particular nested interface and tree.
And the key value for that is we know that it's a strain.
Each entry is a string and the value is integer.
OK.
Just don't worry if it is a little bit confusing with the generics notations.
I think it will get uglier when we get to when we discuss genetics.
So now let's go ahead and iterate through this.
So here let's change your two mappings.
And here this would be let's just call.
Does not being.
And that type would be this would be done by the way.
Now for Meem we can just say my being d'arte get.
So this is one of the methods and entry interface.
Ok and for H It just see Dot get right you can not see.
So it's just going to print on the values.
So this is just an alternative way off iterating.
Personally I would prefer this one for iterating because you know we are fetching all of the entries
and all we need to do is invoke that for each entry we are invoking the get an get value had us here
.
This is also fast.
We are iterating through to each of the keys.
But then here we are doing a search.
Most of the time it's going to be constant don't really know but sometimes you know if a lot of these
get mapped to one particular bucket then it can be slightly ex-manager.
So probably this is a better way of doing it.
OK.
So we are done with that.
Now what we can do is we know that this return set is back but the original set.
So any changes we make here will impact the bact and the actual map also the Mac actual hash map.
So that sort of tells that.
So here let's just say names doddery more on that just right the remote.
Anita
So you run it as we can see we only see John and Raaj and the mapping corresponding and corresponding
to on it got deleted.
So that's about it that's the simple hash map lets start to create a slightly more complex hash map
so that we can see how flexible lead can be used.
So earlier it was a map of string and integer.
Now let's create a map of string and Adorama.
So the value will also be map I guess to do that.
So let's say map.
Now this map let's have string.
So earlier it was name and age.
Now here let's say this is the name.
And here will how a list of key value pairs.
So this would be some profile information of each user.
So we can now age department and stuff like that.
OK.
So this earlier we had only h.
So one value was good enough.
But since the how we want to maintain a list of values as part of the profile let's maned Let's use
a map here.
But instead of integer here let's say object so that we can store you know if it is an age it could
be integer if it is city to be string.
Ok so let's use a more generic object here.
It's called This Prufrock user profile.
OK.
So next steps just create this object here for this.
So let's just copy this.
It's called a profile
not its actual values
that department says.
And it's also the city of the user that say New York.
OK so that's that.
And next we need to add it to user profile.
Under law you would be fine.
So that's it.
And let's also create one more user to use the same profile variable that age.
Roger a destroying design department we can be right.
Yes you are.
And let's just put the second user let's it's that Raj.
So those are the two users.
Let's just go ahead and bring them
.
So as you can see it is printing the values so first one is John.
This is the key and this is the value which is Nestor's map.
OK Sambit here Raj under-invested map.
OK.
Now let's just go ahead and just retrieve the value of the information about about the first user who
John.
So let's just say
say profile one equal to
get would be John.
So the type here would be map all string an object and that's the profile of the user John.
So let's just go ahead and see and age.
Let's just get the age value.
So we need to do profile one not get of age but this one returns an object.
So we need to downcast it because it's an object here and you're not allowed to just simply print it
out age.
That's it.
So it's run out.
And as you can see the age 25 has been extracted from the profile and it's printed here.
So that's about it.
So that's the hash map.
So I would like to give a small exercise for you.
Just go ahead and try.
There is a second constructor in the constructor that we used was a constructor that is also of the
constructor which takes another map.
And it just creates a new map.
OK.
So I would like you to look at the API and try that out.
And also we did not try to put all matter.
You can also try that and you can also try all other matters like clear and size and there is one View-Master
values which would return the collection of all the values in the hash map.
So you can also try that out.
So in the next lesson we will extend this demo because we want we said that we the keys.
Generally it has to be immutable objects.
But if it if it is a mutable object then we need to be very careful.
So we will do all of that and we will see what kind of problem we can have.
If you use a mutable object as the key.
So that will be the next lesson.
Thank you.
Happy coding.
And you can find the code in the resources section