Let's now look at default methods which can be part of interfaces beginning with Java eight onwards.
As discussed earlier in item 18 prior to Java eight, one big issue with interfaces was that it was
difficult for them to evolve over time.
It may not be an issue for proprietary software, but when it comes to public APIs, it is absolutely
critical to get it right the very first time, because once the API is released and widely used, it's
very difficult to change the API and expect the client that is the implementers to also make those changes.
It can easily break their code.
This will soon be demonstrated in our demo.
We cannot blindly use abstract classes just because they will allow functionality to evolve without
breaking client code.
The limitation with them, we know, is that Java does not allow multiple inheritance.
And if a potential client is extending some other class, then they cannot directly extend our abstract
class.
Nova Java.
Interfaces can include something called default methods, and the main goal of introducing default methods
was interface evolution.
That is, we should be able to add default methods after the interface has been released and it should
not break the client code.
Here.
The phrase binary compatibility implies that the fact that default methods are added to an interface
should not require re compilation of implementation code.
So everything must work as before.
That is, clients of the implementers should be able to use the old methods as well as the new default
methods.
This will also be demonstrated in our demo.
So keep in mind the most important reason for introducing default methods is interface evolution.
You can also include default methods, right, when you design your interface the very first time.
In that sense it's an interface method with the default implementation and the subclass can provide
a more specific implementation.
Which means that default methods can never be final.
These are the two main benefits.
There are a couple of other benefits and we will discuss them after doing our demo.
Just note that default methods are also less commonly referred to as defender methods or virtual extension
methods.
Now let's just jump into the court and take a pretty in-depth look at default methods.
Okay.
Let's get started with the demo.
And first thing that you need to do is make sure that your path is pointing to Java eight.
That's because we are testing default methods which are introduced in Java eight.
In case you have been using Java seven and you don't have Java eight.
Please go ahead and download the Java, the latest version of Java eight from the Oracle website and
set your bar to Java eight.
So if you have both Java seven and Java eight, you can also use the command Java C hyphen version at
the command prompt to see which version of Java that you are using currently.
Let's just do a recap of the of our code.
So we are going to extend the code that we have written for Interface Demo.
So we have these three interfaces, a one of us, one is A with two abstract methods for one bar.
Second one is the interface.
B Third is another interface.
C Which actually extends.
A And then we have the skeletal implementation abstract.
A Which means that it implements.
A and it is providing implementation for one of the abstract methods bar.
And we also have a concrete method called X, which is extending abstract A and is implementing A,
B, C and learnable, which is from the previous demo.
And we have test client, which is the test class which simply tests the code.
And so let's just take a realistic look.
Now in our first let's just interface evolution the problem that we had before Java eight where interface
evolution is a problem.
So let's just look at that.
So let's just consider a more realistic situation.
Let's just assume that this interface C was written by a programmer at this company called ABC.
And let's assume that the concrete X, which is actually implementing C is written by a different company
called X, Y, Z, a developer at X, Y, Z.
So there are two companies now.
And let's also assume that this test client is the Y is another company called client who is using this
class X and he's using the reference as C and Instantiating class X.
So it's a different whole different company who is making use of the Class X?
Now let's just assume that the existing code that we have has been written some one year back and now
see this guy at ABC wants to introduce a new method go, abstract method go.
So he writes that OC and he compiles it.
Fine.
Next.
Let's say this guy at a client, he looks at the new package.
So it's like a new release, right, because of this new method.
And he, the programmer, wants to invoke that new method called go.
Assuming that he assumes that X has already implemented it.
So he just wants to use the new method.
Compiles that.
So he has the new method, compiles it and tries to use the new method and it says abstract method error,
which means that you are trying to invoke an abstract method.
So what that means is X has not yet provided a definition for go, has not overridden the method go.
So that's the issue.
So that's not a big problem because usually in such cases the developer would detect this problem during
development time and would take some action.
But the real problem would be with X itself, the guy working at the XYZ company.
So he also looks at the new code.
I mean the new library which has the the interface C and he downloads it and then he wants to use a
new library, right?
Normally you have better implementations, better you get newer code.
So he wants to use new code.
So he goes ahead and tries to compile it and it says you have not overridden abstract method, which
means that it's going he cannot use it and it's going to break his code.
He needs to use only his old version.
And so he definitely would be furious about this.
So he can he can no longer use the new version of the interface.
So that's a problem.
So it's an unprofessional way of writing code.
So, so the thing is, the guy working for ABC, they should have included this method long time back.
So they did not design it properly and that was the issue.
So to fix the problem, at least from Java eight onwards, this is no longer an issue because you can
create default methods.
So you just convert that into a concrete method to make it default.
You just add this keyword default.
Let's just have the statement saying that it's method, go and see.
Now you just compile this re compile compiling fine.
Now all you need to do is just execute this client that you want it's accessing.
So we haven't changed anything, right?
We haven't compiled recompiled exe after adding the new method in C.
So default method is helping us to evolve the interface without breaking the client code.
So that's the beauty of it.
So that's called us binary compatibility, which means that you don't have to recompile the implementation
code.
Now let's say if we recompile exe then it would still be fine.
And that's called a source compatibility.
So if you recompile and if your code works still works, then it's source compatibility.
But without really compiling if it works, that's called as binary compatibility.
So just two new terms that you can keep in mind.
And just note that default methods are instance methods so you cannot hear you cannot access them using
the interface name itself.
So that would give a compilation error.
And for that we have static methods which we will see later.
So if you do that, it will give you an error saying that non static method cannot be referenced from
a static context in back.
And so we are done with the default method, the core demonstration.
Let's say that we have this video.
Let's say this is from a different company.
And this guy also wants to add a method like this, wants to introduce the method with the same name.
So he calls it this and he calls this be don't go now let's compile.
It's fine.
Try to compile X, it says Class X inherits unrelated defaults for go from types B and C.
So we are trying to.
So Class X is implementing both A, B and C, and both of them have the same methods.
Go and there are method definitions right there, not just method declarations.
And so we have the classic diamond problem now.
So for this, the solution.
Only solution is you need to provide.
An implementation here.
But the thing is, you know, it cannot be default.
So you cannot use default keywords in classes.
There can be default methods can only be used in interfaces.
So we need to remove this here.
You can test it out later, what kind of message it gives so that and also this needs to be public,
right?
Otherwise it would say that this method cannot override because you are because in the in the interface
it was public and here it was default access.
So so it's against the overriding rule.
So you need to make it public and let's just make this X.
Now, this method X should get invoked.
So let's just go ahead and compile.
Desk client and let's run.
So it prints x go.
So basically we had multiple inheritance, the diamond issue, but it's being resolved right here at
compile time itself.
So it's not dragged to the runtime.
So in that sense, it's good.
Because we are able to resolve it at compile time itself.
Now also just want to let you know that we the issue we had was because we had we introduced this default
method and B had that same problem we would have even if this was abstract method.
So, so we have this method definition here, but if this was abstract, even then we would have ended
up with the compilation error so that also you can test it out later.
Now let's do something.
Let's me.
Comment this out.
You copy this?
And let me add this method here in abstract.
Let me make it public.
Now in test client we have this let me also comment it out here.
Okay.
So let me just go ahead and compile first X.
Let me compile this, although it's not required.
So let me just.
So all I did was I added a method, the same method go in abstract a and we also have, we also have
the default method go and see in B, I just commented it out and x also I just commented out the go
method, the overriding go method.
So we have only in two places.
One is in the in abstract A which X is extending and also in C.
So we have one implementation in a superclass and one in a super interface.
So let's see what happens in this case.
So it's.
Sorry.
1/2 here.
This was supposed to be abstract a but anyway.
So the one in the.
The version in the class is getting.
The version end the class is getting printed, right?
So what that means is the method in the in the superclass gets higher precedence over the the default
method in interface.
So that's a rule that the designers have placed.
So that's a conflict resolution rule.
So we know that the topmost superclass is object.
So which means that an object has some methods.
So this class C cannot override any of those methods.
Right.
Because of this, the the class winds rule that we just saw where the class has the higher precedence
because of that of that rule.
Any interface can never override a method from object.
Right.
Because of that rule.
But semantically also it makes sense because let's say, for example, you have this class X and you
are going to are going to make use of the equals method defined in object.
Right?
And then you have that code.
And let's say in future if somebody like in C, somebody introduces a new method called equals.
And that's and if the rule is that if it can override the the equals in object, then your semantics
are broken.
So semantically also it makes sense.
But from an syntax point also this rule is making sure that default methods cannot override methods
in object class.
So that's good.
And there is a link that I'm including in this supplementary notes.
Please check it out.
And it's from Brian.
It's a stackoverflow link from Brian Goats, who is a language language Java language architect.
And he also explains this problem.
So you can read that.
You can read his comments.
So he's one of the designers of the default of all these features.
Now, the next thing is how can is there a way for us to force X Java to actually use the version in
the version in C?
So let's see if that can be done.
And yes, that can be done, obviously.
The way you need to do it is you would say, see, dot, super dot.
Go.
Normally, you know we if to invoke a superclass method you would use supercool but if you want to invoke
a method, the default method, you have to do this.
So let's just go ahead recompile test client.
Let me run this and it is invoking the version and see so how we are forcing it to do that.
And another thing is you cannot do this, you can never do this, which means that you can only access
a super interfaces method, default method, but not the one from the from the parent of the super interface.
So you cannot do access the grandparents default methods.
And one more thing is you cannot have a supermarket go over here, so.
So this is interface.
See, you cannot have supermarket go here.
Only thing you can have as a supermarket.
So you cannot use just a super keyword and a default method.
So just wanted to point that out.
So two things I just mentioned.
One was you cannot use you cannot access a grandparent's method from here.
It should always go via the parent itself and you cannot use just the super keyword.
You have to qualify it with the interface name.
And also the same applies with the default method.
You have to do the same in the default method.
So it doesn't matter whether it's a concrete class or whether it is a default method in an interface.
So you need to keep that in mind.
Now let's look at another conflict resolution strategy.
Let me quickly comment this out.
So let me introduce this default method.
Here.
And let me call it a.
So let me recompile.
This is supposed to be default.
You know, it's so common, this sort.
So at this point we have only two implementations of go.
One is in C and another one is in A, which sees extending.
So in this case, it's pretty.
Obvious.
So it's accessing the ocean and sea.
So what that means is sub interface.
The version in sub interface wins.
It has higher precedence over super interface.
Earlier we saw that the class wins class wins over interface.
So class has the version in class has higher precedence now.
The second rule is that the version in sub interface has higher precedence over the version and super
interface.
So that's the thing.
So that's the conflict resolution strategy.
The second strategy and another thing is you can never use final keyword here and because these methods
should be over readable and you can also you cannot also use synchronized keyword synchronized.
We did not cover synchronized, but it is a modifier that we will see in Multi-threading chapter.
So you cannot use either of the keywords here.
One other thing is you can actually so interface a as defining this method go and if let's say interface
see you can actually make it abstract see which is extending it can actually make it abstract.
And why would you want to do that?
Let's say for example, the guy who is implementing interface see things that the default implementation
is bad and he wants to force his clients to provide an implementation so you can actually take a default
method and override it with an abstract version.
You can do that and that applies to abstract classes.
Also, you can have an abstract class which has a concrete method and it's subclass which is also an
abstract class, can actually make that concrete, turn that concrete into an abstract method.
So that's possible over there also.
So that's about it with the demo.