Hello there.
This is the motel room.
Let's now have a brief formal discussion on statements.
We already wrote several statements as part of our demo programs.
In fact, we know that statements are what constitute a program.
We know that every statement in Java ends with a semicolon and it is basically a command to be executed.
Declaring a variable is one kind of a command.
And the command could be to change the value of a variable.
Another command could be to invoke a particular method, which is nothing but to call a particular method.
So the statement basically changes program state.
That is as a statement is executed the state of the program also gets affected.
And the statement is made up of one or more expressions.
And we already know what an expression is.
We briefly discussed it while introducing variables where we mentioned that a variable can be assigned
a literal or an expression.
You can recall that expression is something which gets evaluated to a single value.
And note that this evaluation happens at runtime.
And an expression can be built using literals variables operators like addition or subtraction and even
method calls.
And here is an example of a statement.
Here get count is the method invocation and the value that it returns is multiplied with x, and the
result of this multiplication is then assigned to the variable count.
Now this statement includes four expressions, as we can see here, both x and get count are expressions.
Now, when x is multiplied with get count, we get one more expression and it is referred to as a compound
expression.
Finally, the value generated by this component expression is assigned to the variable count to form
another compound expression.
So compound expressions are constructed from smaller expressions and every expression, regardless of
whether it is compound or not, gets evaluated to a single value at runtime.
Formally speaking statements can be of three kinds.
First one is declaration statements.
They were discussed while introducing variables and they basically declare variables.
Not.
If expressions appear separately with a semicolon, then they are referred to as expression statements.
And here are a few examples.
First is an assignment statement.
Second one is a method invocation statement.
That is, we are invoking a method.
And the final one is an increment statement, which increments count by one.
This kind of annotation with two plus signs after the variable name is referred to as a post increment
operation and it will be discussed later.
The third type of statement is referred to as control, flow statement and control flow statements regulate
the order in which statements get executed.
Control flow statements will be discussed later.
But here is one example, and it is referred to as an if statement which you will use extensively.
Probably you are already familiar with it if you already have some programming experience.
It basically lets you execute a block of code if the condition in parenthesis is true.
So if the value of count here is less than 100 only, then the code inside the curly braces will be
executed.
Now, one important thing to note here is that among these three types of statements, only declaration
statements can be defined at class level that is directly within the body of a class.
In between the two curly braces, you can have only declaration statements.
But not expression or control, flow statements, expression or control.
Flow statements can be part of methods or other similar class level declarations which we will discuss
later, such as constructors, nested classes or interfaces or initialize blocks, all of which will
be discussed later.
And we will get a compiler error if we try to declare expression or control flow statements directly
within the body of a class.
Let's quickly look at this in our editor.
Okay.
This is our basic demo class and we have these methods, print primitives and type casting, which we
have written earlier, and we have the main method.
So let's just go ahead and create a field called count.
So it is static and.
Count that's initialize it to 25.
So this is a declaration statement and we can have declaration statements right within the class at
the class level, or we can also have it in other places like in methods or constructors, which we
will see later.
So this is fine and if we compile it, we will.
Not have any issue here, but we said that we cannot have expression statements here, so let's just
reassign this to something else.
Let's say 34.
Now this will give us a compilation error.
As you can see.
So you cannot have expression statements right here.
So this is an assignment statement and you cannot have it here directly within the class classes body.
But you can have it here in a method.
Or you can also have it in other places like constructors, which will which we will see later.
So now there is no compilation error.
So that's an expression statement.
Now you cannot also have a control flow statement as mentioned in the slides.
So.
Let's just have an empty body here.
So basically you cannot have this kind of a control flow statement.
So if you compile it.
So we get some compiler error.
So let me just.
Here now.
This should be fine.
Okay.
So no more compiler error.
So both expression statements as well as the control flow statements cannot be declared directly within
a class at the class level, but they can be declared in other places like methods or constructors or
in other declarations that we will see later.
So within the class you can have directly, within the class you can have field declarations like count
here, so you can declare fields or you can have method declarations like these methods.
So these are method declarations or you can have constructor declarations and constructors are something
we'll see later in the in the section.
Or you can also have nested classes or nested interfaces and they will be covered later.
Or you can also have instance and static initializes, so which will also be covered later.
This will be initialized.
So will be covered in a couple of sections, whereas nested classes and interfaces will be covered much
later.
So only declarations can be can be defined here right within the class at the class level.
So just keep that in mind that we cannot have expression statements or, or control flow statements
right within the, at the class level.
So that's about it.
So we looked at statements in a formal way.
Thank you.