Hi there.
This is the Ramona La Rue.
In the last lecture, we saw how we could use a fixed apple.
We also saw that the demo program had the limitation of wasting CPU cycles.
Another limitation was that GM could not be shut down, even though tasks ran to completion.
In this lecture, we will see how this limitations can be fixed, but the demo will be part of the next
lecture.
Execute a service is what we are going to use to fix the issues.
As mentioned in the previous lecture, it's an interface that extends executor invoking new fixed method,
returns an executor service.
Since executed, the service extends executor.
In the last lecture, we had the reference type as executor when new fixed thread method was invoked.
Executed had only a single method.
Execute and execute a service is much more extensive and provides methods for submitting tasks as well
as managing termination.
First, let's look at methods for submission in executed service.
It provides a method called submit, which is a better submission method compared to execute in the
executed interface.
Just like execute, we invoke submit method on the executor which is not an execute or service.
Submit method takes a task as input and returns an instance of future, which is another interface in
the Java concurrent package.
We will discuss future in a bit.
Not here.
Tusk can be a rumble as before, or it can be a callable, which is another interface in Java concurrent
package.
Keep in mind that double is from Java LAN package and Java.
Concurrent was introduced in Java PHI and all the concurrency utilities fall under it.
So a task can be either learnable or callable.
What that means is we have overloaded submit methods.
Now callable is a better representation of the task when executing the task to completion can take some
time and we would also need the result of the computation.
For instance, in our download downloader an indexer example we can make download a task, implement
a callable instead of a vulnerable as we have been doing so far as it could take a while to download
the web page and once downloaded, the web page is needed by indexer.
So submit method returns a future instance and future has a method called get which blocks until a task
is completed.
The method returns immediately if the task has already been completed.
In our demo examples.
If we pass downloader task to submit method then in working get on the return future instance would
block until web pages downloaded.
So future docket is kind of similar to the weight method.
That is, it does not waste CPU cycles and it blocks until the result is computed.
So this is how we are going to address the limitation in the previous demo where CPU cycles were being
wasted.
If the task is callable, then future target would actually return the result computed by the task.
If the task is a reasonable, then future target would return a null value rather than the completed
result.
Not that method would block regardless of whether the task is callable or readable.
It is just that with callable get can return the result that was completed.
And here is how the colorful interface looks like.
It has a single method called call.
So a task would implement this interface.
Now recall that run double has a single method run.
As you can see called method unlike run and run a ball returns a result and may also throw an exception.
Not that one method invulnerable does not throw an exception.
And by exception I mean it.
Check the exception.
However, run method can throw an unchecked exception that is within the run method.
You can catch a checked exception and in its place you can throw an unchecked exception.
The data thread would be terminated with this.
So that's something that was not specified earlier during our discussion on reasonable.
So a callable can return a result and can also throw an exception.
In fact, the value returned by future target is the value returned by the call method.
Later in our demo we will see how download our task implements this interface to return the downloaded
web page.
Note that if the task does not have to return a value, then you can implement it as a reasonable.
In our demo indexer tasks can implement this roundabout instead of callable as it does not have to return
any value.
We looked at the submission process of executive service.
Now let's look at how Executor Service manages termination process, which addresses the second limitation
in the previous demo, where Gvm continued to run despite all tasks run to completion.
Executive service life cycle has three states running, shutting down and terminated.
Initially execute service will be in the running state.
And in this state it accepts tasks and executes them.
Next execute.
A service can be moved into shutting down state by invoking its shut down method or shut down no method.
Once one of these methods are invoked, no new tasks will be accepted by execute or service.
Trying to submit new tasks will result in a runtime exception.
If Chandan method is invoked, then executed will shut down in a graceful way.
That is, all the tasks that have been submitted so far will be executed.
If Saddam now is invoked, then, as the name suggests, executor will be shut down abruptly.
What that means is all currently executing tasks will be interrupted via interrupt calls, and all tasks
that are waiting in the queue to be picked up will not be processed on these tasks.
Waiting in the queue will be returned by the method so that they can be saved for later processing.
So shutdown now can be viewed as threat interruption in non executed context.
Once again, note that once any of these methods are executed, the executor will not accept any new
tasks.
Finally, once all tasks have been completed following the invocation of shut down or shut down, now
executed moves into terminated state.
There is also a method called is terminated an executed service which tells whether executed reached
terminated state or not.
One question we can have is why do we have to care about whether executed, terminates or not?
One use case is for the purpose of monitoring.
For example, in a large scale application where we might have hundreds of tasks, we might want to
reuse the same executable, and at some point we might want to shut down the application, in which
case we can invoke the shutdown method, which will let all existing tasks to complete and will not
accept any new tests.
Right.
But if the tasks are taking too long to complete, then we might want to expedite the process.
So we can wait for a certain period of time by invoking a termination method and execute the service
which returns a true if all tasks are completed.
And it returns false if time what happens?
In which case shut down now can be invoked, which we know ignores the tasks that are waiting in the
queue and interrupts the ones that are being currently executed.
Please note that there is no guarantee that interrupt would really interrupt an active task.
The task might need to have the logic to respond to the interrupt call.
So we can invoke a termination one more time and if executed still does not reach terminated state.
Then we can print the statement that executed could not terminate.
So that's how we can monitor the state of the application when we are trying to shut down.
Finally, let's discuss a bit about future.
We saw that a future instance would be retained on invoking the submit method on the executor, and
a future instance represents the lifecycle of a task.
In other words, it can be used to track the progress of a submitted task.
From the way it has been named.
You can think of future as an object that has been pushed into future, but with some incomplete computation
which is needed by some other parts of the program.
So a future object can help in looking back to know whether the incomplete computation has been completed
or not.
We already discussed about get method which blocks if task is not yet completed.
And once the task is completed, it returns the completed result.
If the task is callable, but if task is unable, then it returns a null value.
And here is our interface definition of future and its methods do represent the lifecycle of a submitted
task.
The Council method here can be invoked to cancel the task.
It would return a false if task cannot be cancelled.
And that could be because task has already run to completion or it has already been cancelled.
But if task is not yet started, when the cancel method is invoked, then it too would be written and
the task will not be started.
But if the task is currently being executed, then it would be returned regardless of what is passed
for the method.
Parameter may interrupt if running.
If a true is passed for this parameter, then the running task may be interrupted.
Next is his cancer method, and it would return a true if the task was successfully canceled earlier.
We are invoking cancel method.
Next is is done method which returns it true if the task was completed due to normal termination or
an exception or due to cancellation.
Next is get method which we already know.
Final Method is a timer version of gat, which waits for at most the specified amount of time for computation
to complete, and it would throw a timeout exception if specified time elapses and the task is not completed.
In our webpage downloading use case, if we do not want to wait on the download or task to finish downloading
for more than one or 2 seconds, then we can use this time get method.
One of the follow up lectures will focus on placing time limits on our tests.
Not that among get on time get except for timeout exception for the time get method.
Both methods can throw to check the exceptions.
One is interrupted exception.
Another is execution exception.
Since these methods block their respond to interrupt calls by throwing interrupted exception.
Execution exception would be thrown if the underlying task itself through some exception and the actual
cause of the execution exception, can be inspected by invoking the get cost method.
Also, both methods can throw an unchecked exception or cancellation exception if the task was cancelled.
So those are the different methods in future interface.
The actual future instance written by the executable submit method is an instance of a class called
Future Task, which implements future.
Now finally, let's summarize what we have learned.
Although it was a long lecture, it's actually pretty simple.
First step was to get an executed reference type would be the more extensive executed service instead
of executed interface.
Next is to submit the task to the executor via the Submit method which returns a future object.
Task here can be either returnable or callable.
Callable can return a result and can also throw a checked exception.
Next step would be to invoke the get method on the returned future instance.
And this method would block until the task is completed.
Get would return the result of the computation if the submitted task was callable.
Otherwise it would return a null value.
Finally, we need to shut down the executor and we need not shut down immediately after processing few
tests for applications where we may have large number of threads, we may want to keep the executor
alive for a long time so that it can be used to run different tasks.
So that's about it.
In the next lecture, we will do a demo of what we have learned in this lecture.
Thank you.