So let's go ahead and look at few other important bytecode instructions.
One minute if you're doing water and instructions called in work special on Iraq which we'll just recap
here like in the case of a real CPA you JVM that is an abstract computing machine also has an instruction
set.
We know that a method bytecode stream would act as instructions for the JVM and the bytecode instructions
also have a similar representation as regular instructions office EPU each bytecode instruction basically
involves a run byte opcode followed by 0 or more options.
The awkward specifies the operation to be performed when the operands specific additional information
.
For example the I add instruction that we saw earlier was just were adding two values.
In this case I add is the opcode and there were no options open and so actually implicit.
The upward sort implies popping the end values at the top of the operand stack and performing the necessary
operation.
We also have that Iler instruction.
One example was I load underscore one here the suffix one.
So says the opera and that is the instruction is telling JVM to dig the value at index 1 in the local
variables Ari on push it onto the top of the operands like like C.P. you DBMSs execution engine also
follows fetch on execution lifecycle.
And we know that that is GBM would fetch an upcourt on any trailing operands then it would execute the
operation requested by that upcourt and then it fetches the next instruction and so on.
Now let's use this simple program to review the bytecode instructions that it generates.
You can also find the program in resource section.
The program has a main method and one additional method called string which basically overrides the
string method in the Object class.
This method has a system that overprint Allen's statement underlines the string hello.
The main one that creates an instance of this class and simply in with a string method on that new instance
not to look at the bytecode we will use a jalopy too which is basically a bytecode disassembler that
comes with it.
We looked at it when discussing method binding.
It can be used to disassemble one or more class once and it can also take multiple command line options
.
For example if you include the option hyphen C it would print the byte code for each of them methods
in the class.
But if you can grab the option hyphen we are hyphen bobos then it would still print the byte code of
each of the methods.
But in addition it would also provide the dark constant boune on some additional information in case
you want to view all the possible options.
You can use hyphen help.
So let's go ahead and use hyphen VI option on the Hello class as shown here under the bytecode.
OK.
Now here is the Hello class.
So you're not going to look at that.
So I'm just going to compile this first and then.
So I'm just going to run the jalopy down with the hyphen B option.
OK.
And it's going to be hello dark class here.
OK so we are running or we are running it on the classified.
Now here is a byte code.
And we can see that this is the method called by a byte code Fard the two string mentored.
And similarly we have the bytecode for Main method here.
And this is the bytecode for the for the constructor for which is which is inserted automatically the
default constructor.
And we're going to analyze each of them separately the constructor and the two methods.
And then look at the byte code generated by them.
And here is the constant pool.
OK so this is the constant pool that's generated.
It's this constant pool and all of this is there.
And this was generated because of the hyphen v option.
OK.
And that is summertime information too and that's about it.
So let's just go ahead and review each of the methods under constructor.
Let's begin with looking at the bytecode generated for the constructor which was inserted automatically
by the compiler.
Now if you recall compiler when it auto inserts of default constructor it also ought to insert a statement
for invoking the superclasses default constructor.
And we know it's due to the constructor chaining process.
The first two byte code instructions that you see here correspond to that statement.
And let's see what they signify the first instruction here is in order underscores zero earlier in the
bit I load instruction the prefix in this gives indicates an object reference.
Well in the case of I load the prefix i indicates an in data type.
Other than the small difference the operation performed is identical.
That is it tigs the element at the specified index in the local variables array and pushes it onto the
top of the upper and stock index because the index is zero.
Not index zero we have this reference and that's because Kunstler is like an instance method unreleased
because that for instance Medders the zeroth element in the local variables will be a reference to the
current object that is this reference.
The reason why we have this reference is because it allows the code in the method or the constructor
to access any instance variables.
Similarly if the current method or constructor is invoking another method or constructor in the same
class or in a superclass then the this reference will be set in the local variables array corresponding
to that method or constructor next instruction is an expression and it has one operand which is hash
one getting a constructor in the superclass which is the object us apart from constructor.
Invoke special instruction will also be generated when we are in working either a private method or
when we are in Woking as superclass method we are the supercooled.
So you can try that out just are a private matter and then and look at the byte code and you should
be able to see and invoke special instruction.
Now here we are referring the constructor as instance initialization method and that's because of JVM
to do it.
In fact what we are seeing here in this particular snapshot is an instance initialization method and
such a method is inserted for each constructor in that class.
But in addition to constructor called this instance initialization method will also initialize all the
instance variables which in the source code might have been initialized outside of the constructor.
Let me actually show that to you in the code.
So let me go ahead and I had an instance variable here.
Should I use it to 3 so it's initialized outside the constructor.
In fact there is no constructor here.
So let's just go ahead and compile this and then do a java command.
Now let's look at the construct of code.
As you can see here in the constructor called.
So we have these three bytecode instructions in order underscore zero icons to underscore three and
put free.
So this is the code that is initializing the instance variable.
So that's the thing.
So in addition to the constructor code itself which is in this case in working the superclass constructor
it also initializes the instance variables.
How in this instance initialization method is also referenced using a special name called in it which
you can see here in the common the name here in the signature.
It still has the class name but in the constant bool it really did it for instance in it and we will
see that in a moment.
No come into the operation hash run it is simply an offset into the runtime constant pull of the current
class.
So let's look at the relevant section of the constant pull period is the constant Paulas sequential
number but to highlight only the relevant part.
I extracted only the relevant lines from the constant pull index one is basically a symbolic reference
to him either.
And in this case it's a constructor index one is referencing two other indices mind and pointy and nicks
nine is referencing in index 28 which is a symbolic reference to the object us.
Similarly in next one p is intended for rinsing.
And this has been an 11 word 10 gives the method name which as mentioned earlier is especially in that
index Levan holds information about what is called does matter descriptor which includes the matter
parameters under it and type.
In this case there are no parameters.
We only have an empty promises when the return type is void which is indicated by the letter B.
Know at runtime.
When GBM and contest this in Rook's special instruction it performs a few actions.
First it performs method resolution which in this case is a resolution of the instance initialization
method.
We know that this would entail replacing symbolic reference with direct reference.
Next JVM creates a new stack frame for the instance initialization method and pushes it onto the stack
.
Nexted pops this reference from the operand stack and started index 0 of the local variables array of
the newly created stack.
So the reason for having Elorde underscores zero was for storing this reference variable on the stack
so that Iraq's Special can use it next.
Know the instance initialization method is ready to be in work.
And so the program counter will be set with the first instruction in the instance initialization method
of the superclass.
So the execution continues from the first instruction.
So that was a constructor court.
I need an artist to review the Invoke special instruction.
Now let's look at the main method byte order.
The first statement in the main method creates a new instance of Hello.
Now this statement generates the first three bytecode instructions that you'll see here.
So let's start to make sense of this mapping.
The first bytecode instruction which includes a opcode new creates an instance of hello on pushes the
object reference onto the operand stack.
So at this point only the object is created but for it to be fully formed we need to also in the constructor
code.
For that we know that we need an in special instruction but that's the third instruction.
And there is a second instruction.
The second instruction is doop and it basically makes a copy of the item which is on the top of the
operand stack and also stores it on the top of the opening stack.
Now we need to make this copy as one of the things in walks Bishan does is to pop the top element from
the operand stack and store it as the zero element and the local variables array off the new frame that
it is going to create.
But if we don't have the loop instruction then invoke special would Bob the only object reference that
we have and with that we will not have a way to end with the string method which is the second statement
of the main method.
So we do need the instruction.
Next the following three bytecode instructions correspond to the second statement the instruction A-story
must go to one Bob's the hallowed reference from the operand stack unstarted at.
And next one in the local variables at it.
But if you are storing it index one at index 0 we have the only method parameter off the main method
which is a reference to the string theory.
Next a lot underscore one does the exact opposite.
That is it moves the element back to the stack from the local variables adding finally in-work which
will BOP's the hallowed reference from the stack.
And it also in wig's that boosting method.
Know if you recall we discussed in work which will indeed did in the method by adding lesson which was
covered in the inheritance and polymorphism chapter.
That lesson we said that for instance methods met that signature binding happens at compile time itself
but the method implementation binding happens only at runtime.
That's because with instance methods we do not know which method to work until runtime.
That is it is dependent on the object in context.
For example here you can see that at compile time method signature is bonded to the string method in
that object class.
But at runtime the string method in the Hello class will be executed just like in the case of in Woakes
mission.
Let's also review the steps performed when in which what is encountered also autoloader the pop instruction
which is the next one simply pops the top element on the stack.
It has a value returned by the spring mother.
Finally the return instruction at the end simply implies right as written.
When JVM encounters in-work what will it Fussball force method resolution which in our case is the resolution
of the string method and the object us.
This could simply mean pointing to an index in the metric table of the object class and the element
there would point to the actual string method code.
But the method to be executed is dependent on the actual object for that runtime.
We know that the operand stack has a reference to this actual object.
So JVM performs a lookup operation here.
It starts with the reference on the operand stack and follows it to the object on heap and then into
its method table.
In the metro area the actual implementation will be in the metal table at the next phone doing the matter
resolution step.
So the index number found during method resolution step then applies here in them at the table corresponding
to that Holocaust.
We discussed this when discussing method tables and we said that we are able to use the same index member
as a reference type of the variable is a class not an interface does not that using Mathare table in
such a way for a method implementation binding is entirely up to JVM implementation.
Some implementations might do it in a different way too.
At this point we know the method to be executor.
So the next three steps are identical to what we saw in works Bishan that is create a new stack frame
for boosting that and push it onto the stack.
But this reference from operand stack unstarted that index zero of the local variables array of the
new stack frame find a decent program counter to the first instruction of the new method.
Now here is a last snapshot which corresponds to a boosting method heading through quota system not
all that Prindle and segment which prints a string hello.
It also returns a string literal Hello no in the expression system that called We know that system is
a class an out is a static variable defined in that class.
The type of code really obvious but in stream from the Java dot or package sprint and method is invoked
on the reference variable.
So we need to forestall the old reference variable in the opening stack and this is done by get static
instruction.
So it basically pushes the value of all credible onto the open and stack next instruction LTC gets the
reference to the string literal Hello from the runtime constant pull on pushes it onto the open and
stack.
Finally invoke what you want.
BOP's both the string literal hello and the reference.
And in walks the print method.
Then the string literal hello as the argument.
No the last two instructions correspond to retaining the string Hello Azmat that's output under instruction
.
Arrogance simply implies that we are returning an object reference.
There are other variations we're primitive types like I've written for returning an end date type.
So that's about it.
They look at both in word spatial and in word what you're willing to put in was started in detail and
method by adding lesson.
And it is related to in working static methods.
You can review that read you again if needed another instruction you know as in rock interface in our
program the reference type is a class object and the actual type of the object was hello.
But if the reference type was an interface then it would have generated and invoke interface instruction
.
So you can try it out by making the Hello class implement an interface Resorcin section includes a pointer
to the JVM specification page that includes detail information about all the bytecode instructions.
So if you want to get a more in-depth understanding of any of the instructions that recolored or if
you want to learn about any new instruction then you can refer to this page.
So that's about it.
Thanks and I hope you'll enjoy learning about the bytecode instructions.