Hi there.
This is the De La Rue.
Now, let's go ahead and implement some of the stuff that we have learned in the previous lecture about
executive service and future.
Right.
So here for this demo, I created this new class called as Future Indexer, and this would be an improvement
over now executed indexer, which had two limitations, as we know.
One of them was that the indexer task was wasting CPU cycles and we are going to address that using
future and execute service.
And the second limitation was that GM was not shutting down even after all the tasks ran to completion.
Right.
And we know that execute a service has some termination methods which will help us with that.
So this is a future executable, future indexer.
So I already made some changes here.
It's an improvement over the now executed indexer.
So some changes have been made and some we need to fix.
So the downloader task is something that we need to change.
So earlier the downloader task was implementing error.
Now we need to change this to callable.
And the second thing is.
Indexer will remain as it is.
So it is implementing run double because we don't have to.
The indexer does not have to return anything, whereas the downloader has to return a web link.
And then the go method is where we are making some changes.
The changes have already been made.
There are some compilation errors here because some of the code has been changed and some of them,
some of the code needs to be updated, which is what we are going to do here.
So this is the main method and we are instantiating future indexer and adding the for web links as usual
and we are invoking the go method.
And in the go method here it is now at the top.
Here we are creating the executables.
So as you can see now the executor is executed service.
Earlier it was executed.
So executed service is more extensive as we already know.
So that's one change.
And here in the go method, when we are iterating through the web links, we are getting a web link
and we are we we have to submit the web link to the download executor, which is now an executor service
and that word return.
Since the task now will be a callable, it would return a future and that feature will be added to an
array list which stores some features.
So we are going to add the return future into this list of ArrayList, which which we are creating here.
So it needs to be added here and then we are going to process it further so that the indexer executor
will do the execution off of the web page.
So this is the code.
We'll get back to this.
But first let's go ahead and modify the downloader task.
Here it is implementing learnable.
So let's go ahead and change it to callable.
And this one needs to be.
Change to call.
And call would return a value.
We know that the result that is computed and the result is actually the web link.
So let's gentrify this particular class.
Let's say V here or let's call it T.
Now here.
Let's say DH extends.
Web link.
And it's also change this to to.
So it's a bounded parameter here type parameter.
That's it.
So all we did was change callable and it's see.
Change change run double to callable and the run instead of run method we are implementing call method
and call method can return a value and the value that we want to return is the weblink.
After.
After we download the HTML page, we set the HTML page and then we want to return the web link.
And.
We're going to move this.
So that's the change that that we had to make and we made that.
So the indexer remains just the same.
It implements reasonable.
So it's going to get the HTML page and index it.
Now here, as we mentioned earlier, so we are submitting the web link.
We are getting the web link from the queue and we are passing the web link which has the URL to be downloaded
and we are passing it to the downloader task.
So the task is a callable.
Now downloader is is a callable and we are submitting it and the submit method we know returns a future
and that future is being added to to this list which is named as futures.
So it has a list of futures because we are iterating here and in each iteration we are going to add
a future and then here we are going to process each of the futures and we are invoking the execute method,
right execute method here.
We don't need submit, execute and we are passing the index task here which is a reasonable and to the
indexer task.
We're passing the web link and the way we are passing it is we are invoking the get method and the get
method would return a web link, right?
So that's what we are doing here.
So let me just go ahead and run this.
And here, as you can see, we have this interrupted execution and execution exception.
Because future GATT can be blocked and we can have any of these two exceptions because it can be blocked,
it can through an interrupted exception and because the the task itself, the callable can throw an
exception.
We are also having this execution exception.
So let me just go ahead and run this.
So all the pages have been indexed.
But we have an exception here.
It's a runtime exception.
The reason for that is because after shutting down here, so we also have these two statements.
We are shutting down both executables.
And we know that once we shut down, the executor cannot accept any new tasks.
But then here I have added this statement called Submit, and I'm trying to submit a new task just to
show you that no new tasks will be accepted and a runtime exception will be generated.
So it's called a rejected execution exception.
So that's the exception that is generated.
So we cannot add any new tasks once we invoke shut down or shut down now.
So that's just for demonstration, but all of them have been downloaded.
Now, one limitation here is that in this particular code is here we are iterating through.
This is the main method, still the main method, and we are iterating through the list of features.
And in each iteration we are invoking the future.
So when we are in the first iteration future dot get can block here, right?
Because the web page is not yet downloaded because that's how the the get method works.
So the get method would block.
So if it is blocking, it means that the main thread is not going to proceed until this method returns.
So that's a limitation here.
So the way we need to code it is we need to actually pass only future here.
That's one way to code this particular logic.
So you don't invoke the get method, but you actually pass a future to the indexer task and then execute
method is executed.
It creates a tadpole so the executor method will invoke the run method and within that run method you
can invoke the get method.
So if you do that, then you know, then this whole thing can work in parallel concurrently.
Otherwise, this get method can block here and we can have issues like we can amend it.
The program will not proceed, may not proceed.
So the better way to implement is just to pass the future object and so that the threads within this
thread pool will execute concurrently and within each of those executions in the run method, we can
invoke the get method here, get.
So since there will be working concurrently, then we will not have this issue of at least one thread
blocking another thread.
So that's some change that we can make and we will do it in the next demo where we will actually place
some time limits on the tasks that we do not want to, to wait for the page downloading to take to too
much of time so we can place a time limit on that.
And we know that we can use time to get for that.
And there is also another way to do it.
So we will look at both of the approaches.
So that's an interesting demo.
So we will look at that in the next lecture.
And at the top we have some text also having included some text.
One of them is about memory visibility here and it says that actions in a thread prior to the submission
of a readable or callable task to an executor service happens before any action taken by the task.
So actions in a thread prior to the submission of a task to an execute or service happens before any
actions that might happen within the task, which in turn happened before the result is retrieved via
future dot get.
Okay.
So that's the memory visibility guarantee that we get here.
So just, just want to highlight that.
So that's about it.
And you can also go ahead and look at executable service API and also the future API and because they
have a few more methods, but we will explore a couple of more methods in the next lecture.
That's about it.
Thank you and happy coding.
And this and this program will be available in the resources section.