Hi there.
This is the room on Uluru.
Before moving on, let's look at a couple of other important benefits of default methods.
We already to discuss the two that we see here, which are kind of the fundamental benefits.
We know that the main purpose of default methods is interface evaluation.
Just note that it has to be methods with implementation.
That is, default methods cannot be abstract methods.
And if they were abstract, then it means that subclasses must implement them.
So that's the reason default methods have a method body and default methods are something that are really
useful for API designers whose code is used outside of their immediate organization so they can use
default methods to evolve their interfaces.
We also know that default methods basically provide a default implementation of the interface method
and subtypes can either use it for free or they can override it.
Now third benefit says eliminate utility classes.
And an example utility class is the collections class in the Java package.
It includes very generic utility methods that operate on data structures, which are implementations
of few interfaces from Java package.
Most of the methods in this class have an interface as the method parameter type as recommended in item
52 from affective Java, which we studied earlier.
For example, there is a sort method which has list as a parameter, and list is an interface in Java
package.
So this method sort can accept list implementations like array list and what sort the elements of the
list in ascending order.
For example, if the elements are integers, then they are sorted in ascending order.
Now, with the introduction of default methods, instead of having this sort method in a separate utility
class like the collections class, it can be included as a default method in the list interface itself.
This way we can simply invoke the source method on the list object itself as shown here.
That would be a much more elegant implementation.
In fact, with Java eight list interface actually includes a default sort method and the source method
in the collections class simply delegates to the default version in the list interface.
Let's actually look at the source code of the source method in the collections class.
Here we are in the Grip Code website and we are looking at the source code of the collections class,
which is the utility class.
And we are specifically looking at the source code in the Java eight package.
And here is the method sought.
It has a single parameter list and the parameter type is list, which is basically an interface in the
Java package.
So this method can be invoked with any of the list implementations like an array list or a link list.
And you can just ignore all this greater than symbols on the less than symbols.
They are related to generics, which will be discussed later and within the method body.
We are simply delegating to this method called sort, which is the default method defined in the list
interface.
You can also ignore this null argument.
It's not relevant here.
So from Java eight onwards this delegation is happening.
So even we can use this method directly, or we can also invoke this utility method in order to sort.
But it would be much more elegant to directly invoke this.
So that's about it.
Just wanted to show that.
And back to the slide.
So basically by defining such default methods in the interface itself, we can eliminate the need for
having such methods in a separate utility class.
So that's the third benefit.
Fourth benefit is related to functional interface.
A functional interface is simply an interface with exactly one abstract method.
So it's another type of interface.
And we already looked at marker interfaces which do not declare any methods at all.
And we also have the regular interfaces that can declare one or more methods and functional interfaces
have exactly one abstract method.
We will look at functional interfaces and nested classes as well as when discussing lambda expressions,
which are also introduced in Java eight.
But let's look at a simple demo involving a functional interface and a lambda expression, and we will
see how a functional interface remains as a functional interface, even after adding a default method.
Okay.
Here we have a functional interface and it has also been named as functional interface itself.
So it has only one abstract method called test and this one is commented out and we will look at that
later.
Now let's assume that I work for a company and I have designed an API and this interface is part of
my API.
So I'm going to first compile this.
So it got compiled.
And let's say I give this particular API, which includes this particular functional interface to a
client, and let's say this is the client here.
So the client is a different entity.
So this is the client, and the client will actually write this kind of method, let's call it as Lambda
Test, because we are going to use lambda here, lambda expression.
So the client is has this method and the input parameter is F is the functional interface.
It's the same type here, it's the functional interface.
So the data type of this particular parameter method parameter is the functional interface.
And the functional interface has this method abstract method test.
So this particular method is actually invoking test.
So this method has to be passed an instance of functional interface.
And the way this client is doing it is he's creating an instance of this class.
The name of the class is Test Client and is invoking the method lambda test and this passing lambda
expression.
So this is a lambda expression and we will look at lambda expressions later.
But essentially this is an implementation for the test method within the functional interface.
So this is considered as the implementation for that.
And all it is doing is it is simply printing the text Java in-depth, which means that the test method
is actually printing this message.
So this lambda expression is basically an implementation of the test method.
So let's go ahead and let's also compile and run this.
So at Prince Java, Indep.
So it is nice and good and the owner of this particular class is also happy.
But now, let's say after an year or so, I want to introduce a new method.
So I create this.
It's another abstract method.
Now the test client is this.
So the test client, also the owner of this class, also will download the latest version of the API
and he or she wants to compile this, compile the class once again.
When they compile it, it's not going to work.
And the reason for this, it says incompatible types at line 29.
So here Lambda Expression would work with only a functional interface because this is some this is a
this is the methods body the body of a particular method that needs to be invoked.
But now the interface has two methods.
It's no longer a functional interface.
And so the compiler is, it is not sure which of the two methods this particular function, this particular
function that is represented by a lambda expression, which of the two functions this lambda expression
would represent earlier when we had only the test method.
This would act as the implementation for the test method, but now it has two methods and the compiler
is confused.
Confused as to which of the two methods this this particular lambda expression would represent as an
implementation.
So that's the reason.
This is not going to work.
So what we can do is with Java eight, we can use a default method, right?
So if I make this a default and we know the default method has a body, it has some body empty body
in this case.
So with Java eight, this will not be an issue.
But before Java eight, the client would definitely be furious that it has been changed, that the that
the API has been changed.
But and it was, it was a pain process before Java eight.
But now as an API designer, I'm much more relieved.
I would be much more relieved because of the default methods.
So now if I add this default method, let me just recompile it.
Recompile just the functional interface.
It compiles fine.
And now let's say the client has downloaded the latest version of the API, which has this interface.
No, it compiles fine.
So that's the interface interface evolution.
And in this case, the functional interface remains as a functional interface, even after adding a
new method, which is a default method.
So a default method is allowing us to retain the functional interface capability.
So the functional interface will remain as functional interface.
So that's about it.
So we looked at a couple of more interesting benefits of default methods.
And that's about it.
And thank you.