Hi there.
This is the day.
And welcome back.
Let's now continue our discussion on the first statement.
And in this lecture, let's learn about a type of first statement called for each statement.
For each statement was introduced in Java five, and it mainly helps with conveniently iterating over
arrays and other data structures, which we will see later in Collections Framework Chapter.
Now we are saying that it allows for convenient iteration, and that's because for each statement has
a much simpler and a cleaner syntax.
Now in the last lecture we looked at the first statement and we can refer to it as traditional first
statement as it was there right from the beginning of Java.
But for each statement cannot be used in certain scenarios.
And for those scenarios we have to use the traditional first statement.
And at the end of this lecture we will look at those scenarios.
Now in the last lecture we looked at this particular array declaration where we have an array with ten
elements, 0 to 9, and we were iterating through the array and printing the array elements.
And we also said that this is the most common way in which a first statement can be represented.
We also looked at different representations, but we specifically said that this is the most common
way in which first statement is used at least until Java five was released.
And the reason for that is because normally in this common representation we will have an initialization
statement such as this one, where we will declare a single variable and then we have the condition
statement.
And the condition statement mostly would look something like this.
If it is an array, we would just ensure that we are iterating until the size of the array is reached.
And regarding the expression list here, we would simply have a single post increment operator.
That is, we would always increment by one.
So this is the most common template, most common representation.
And we can think that 95% of the time we would be using such kind of representation at least until Java
file.
So since it is being so commonly used, I think Java, the Java designers wanted to come up with something
which would be much more simpler to represent but will also accomplish the same thing.
And that's because it is so commonly used.
So in that regards the Java designers have come up with for each statement and let's see how the statement
looks like.
It is very straightforward.
So it would have the same for keyword and parentheses and the body and closed end braces.
Now let's go ahead and print the same array so it will also have int i then a colon and it would be
followed by I array.
So but here I actually represents the elements of the array, whereas here I represents the index of
the array.
Right?
I here is the index of the array.
And in order to access the element we had to do something like this array of I only then we would get
the array element.
But here I is not the index and I is the actual element itself.
So if we print it, we would do something like this.
So we don't need this because I itself is the other element.
So this is what we have.
And as you can see, it is much more simple, much more simpler.
So the index variable is still there, but it is implicit in this for each statement it is hidden and
the condition statement is also there, but it is also implicit.
Similarly, the increment, the post increment operation is also happening, but that is also hidden.
So the index variable is hidden and we don't have any of these expressions here.
So that makes it really cleaner.
So this is array, but it can also be other data structures too.
Now in English we can read it.
As for each element.
I n I agree.
So this is how we can read it as in English.
And here for each element i.
So this is AI and in.
And we can think that colon is n.
And then we have the we have the array.
So that's what it is.
So now let's let me just go ahead and compile and run this.
So this is still the basics demo class and this isn't the main method.
So let me just compile and run it.
Here it is.
So it prints all of the elements 0 to 9.
But traditional fa fa statement is not restricted to just arrays or other data structures, and it can
also be used for representing other kinds of logic.
And we already we already looked at one kind of problem in the last lecture where we looked at counting
devices.
So we were trying to count the number of divisors of a particular value, right?
So there we used a traditional first statement and traditional first statement has to be used for such
kinds of problems.
And we will also look at few other scenarios where we have to use a traditional first statement.
So this is all we have for for each.
Now there is an item in effective Java.
It is item 46, at least in version two of the book.
And the item number could be something else in a different version.
So that particular item, it says prefer for each loops to traditional furloughs.
So let me just copy it here.
So that's what it says.
It says that you need to prefer for each loop whenever possible to traditional far loops.
And here are the reasons.
One is the cleaner syntax which we have already see, which we have already seen, and there is also
no performance penalty in using for each.
In fact, it seems that it can be slightly better if we are dealing with arrays because with traditional
for loop here with each iteration we are computing the length and that is taken care of implicitly.
That is in for each statement.
It will be done only once and that value will be reused for each of the iterations.
So that could give a slight performance benefit with regards to arrays, but there is definitely no
performance penalty when we are using a for each statement and it will also eliminate any opportunities
for error.
Now so this is a newer lecture, but earlier I had a different version of the lecture, and when I was
preparing that lecture, I was trying to make up an example for demonstration, and I actually ran into
an issue when I was trying to use the traditional first statement.
So let me just show what the issue is.
So the problem is to display all the different combinations.
When we roll a pair of dice, Dice has a single, dice has six, six values, and if we want to roll
a pair of them, and if we want to display all of the different combinations, we want to print those
combinations so we can use a nested first statement.
So let me just go ahead and write an straight for statement for doing something like that.
So we need to dice.
So let me declare the first one as and let's call it dice.
One equals to.
One to.
Just copy this.
Is true.
Now, let me put the nested first statement.
Now generally what we do is we just copy this.
And we paced it.
That's what we tend to do as programmers.
And this one, let's make it J and J less than dies to dot length.
And let's go ahead and print the other elements.
Dies two of J.
Now let me go ahead and compile and run this.
You let me do this?
Here it is.
We are putting the roll of the dice and after printing a few rows we are getting this exception error
called our index out of bounds exception because we are trying to access an array element that is outside
of the array.
So we are trying to reach out to an index that is outside the boundary of array.
And that is happening here because we made a copy and paste error.
This was supposed to be plus plus, but we had it as a plus plus.
In this case, I did it deliberately, but like I said earlier last time when I was trying it, it did
happen that I did make that mistake.
So when it was A-plus plus plus here.
So this is what we have here.
Let me just show you why we are getting this error.
So in the first iteration, it would be this one of zero and this would be dice two of zero, which
means that it would print one and one, as we can see here.
Then in the second iteration of the inner loop, it would be dice one of two, right?
Because we had it as it would be dice one of one sorry.
Dice one of one which is here two.
And then this would still remain as dice two of zero because we are not incrementing anywhere.
It would be dice two of zero, which is one.
So it is printing two and one.
And then in the third iteration I get incremented once again.
So it would be dice one of two and dice one of two as this one, three and dice two, it would still
be zero.
So it is printing three and one one because the first element is one here.
So similarly we will have dice, one of four dice, two of zero dice, one of five dice, two of zero
dice, one of six.
And that's when we get the error and DBM throws this error.
It says Arrays array index out of bounds exception because we are trying to access index six, index
six and we only have six elements.
So but we are trying to access the seventh element by doing an index dice one of six.
So that's why we are getting this error.
Now, if we change this to J.
As you can see, prints, all of the different combinations.
One, one, one, two, one, three, two, one, two, two, six, three, one, two, three, six.
And so on till six one, two, six, six.
So that is what it is.
But if we use a nested first statement, we will not have this problem.
And with the nested four, we simply do this.
Let's say we just copied, just like in the case of traditional fare.
And we did this and let's, for instance, let's.
That's even forgot to change this to.
Jay.
So in this case, if I compile it, we just get a compilation error.
It says what variable AI is already defined and method mean.
So even if we made a copy and paste error, we would get this error.
And this error is because.
So we are inside the main method and this is one local variable and this is one local variable.
So one local variable cannot shadow or hide another local variable.
So that is there.
And we will also look at that in one of the follow up lectures when we are discussing about variable
scope.
But we know that a local variable can hide or shadow an instance variable.
Right.
We have seen that.
In which case we would have to use this this reference in order to access the instance variable.
So a local variable hiding an instance variable is perfectly fine, but a local variable cannot hide
another local variable within the same method.
And that is what is happening here.
This we are trying to hide this with this one and we get a compilation error.
So it is very easy to fix now.
So we will just say that and we just take this thing.
And we don't need any of that.
You just need to let me comment this out.
There you go.
So we have the same output.
So it is this for each statement is especially preferred for nested iterations.
So that said, so the last thing that we want to look at is so we looked at for each statement and it
is allowing us to conveniently iterate through through arrays and other data structures.
So when we prefer.
When would we prefer?
Traditional first, we would want to do that.
If we need if we need access to index, that's when we would have to use a traditional furlough because
for each does not give access to index.
Now there are certain scenarios where we would need that.
For example, you want to transform the array, so you have the array and you want to do you want to
say shuffle the elements of the array?
Or if you recall in the last lecture, we looked at this particular example where we had this array,
but we did and reverse all of the elements of the array.
So we did a reverse of array and we wrote this logic for that.
And by the end if a print it was printing the array elements in reverse order, right?
So the elements were being swapped here in each iteration.
So if you want to do that, then we have to go for the traditional third because we need to in each
iteration, we need to swap the elements and so we need access to the index.
So there we were transforming the array.
So that's when we would need that.
And the second thing is, if we want to do a parallel iteration, we parallel iteration is in each iteration
of our loop, we have multiple arrays that we need to iterate over.
We need to iterate through multiple arrays in the same iteration.
Then we call it as parallel iteration, and for each would not support that.
So let's just take this one, for instance.
Actually this one.
But we don't need a nested fir.
We can take this here x.
And.
Stick it here.
And we can initialize j equals zero over here.
And we would say.
G plus plus.
And we can remove this whole thing.
So it's just a single iteration single for loop.
So it would print dice one of zero, dice two of zero and so on.
So let me just.
Okay.
Let me just put an empty line there.
So here it is.
This is the last one.
So this is a parallel iteration of two arrays.
So if we want to do that, we have to go for traditional four, because with for each statement, we
can have only a single array.
We cannot have multiple because that's the syntax of for each.
So that's the parallel iteration.
And third one is.
Backward iteration.
So if you have to do it back, if you have to iterate backwards, then you have to go for traditional
first statement.
And if you recall in the previous lecture also before we implemented this, before we did the reversal,
we actually had a first statement where we were displaying the elements from the backward direction,
and so the index variable had to be documented.
So if ever we have to do something like that, we have to use traditional fur and with for each, it
is always going to be only forward iteration.
So that said and the item, the item 46 in the effective Java book also talks about one more scenario
called us filtering.
So filtering comes into play when we are looking at other data structures from Collections Framework
chapter, where as we are iterating in a given iteration, we would have an element and if we want to
remove it, that's a scenario where we would need something like a traditional first statement.
And this for each will not work for that.
So that's one example.
But since we are not dealing with those data structures here, we do not have that example here.
So we are not going to discuss it any further.
But something like that will be discussed in the Collections Framework chapter.
So that's about it.
So that's the for each statement.
It is mainly useful for conveniently iterating through arrays and other data structures.
So it is it is used as an alternative.
So to this common template that we used to have with traditional FA and it has a much simpler syntax
and it doesn't have any performance penalty and it also eliminates any opportunities for error.
So that's the for each.
So whenever it is possible, you have to use for each loops as this item recommends.
Prefer for each loops to traditional for loops.
That's it.
Thank you and happy coding and see you in the next lecture.