Hi there.
This is Lou.
And welcome back.
Now it's time to extend our project.
We have learned a lot about concurrency, including some cool, advanced stuff that can be used in large
production systems.
Now let's go ahead and incorporate some of the Multithreading stuff, which we have learned in this
chapter into our project.
It's going to be a very simple extension related to downloading Web pages, and I hope you will like
it.
And we are very well aware of how to download Web pages concurrently.
Right now, let me first switch over to my editor to show you what parts of the project we are going
to change.
Look, here we are in the Thriller Project.
And you may recall this class called us view, which basically represents a UI.
And here there is this method called Browse, which simulates the user's browsing pattern.
So the input to this method is user and a bunch of bookmarks, and it simulates the user browsing through
this bookmarks via this far loop.
And here in the third loop, we are iterating through each of the bookmarks.
Now, if the user wants to bookmark a particular item for that, we are using a randomized function.
This particular method called get bookmark decision.
It uses a randomized function.
You may recall that and it decides whether this bookmark should be bookmarked by this particular user
or not.
If it returns a true, it means that the user has to bookmark it.
And we are invoking the method save user bookmark, which takes two parameters user and bookmark and
it will save the bookmark for this particular user.
It establishes a relationship and it is inside the controller.
It means that from the view we are invoking the controller, which is how the MVC pattern works and
let's go here.
So here we are in the bookmark controller.
From the bookmark controller, we are invoking a similarly named method called save user bookmark.
Inside the manager manager has the business logic and here is a business logic.
Here there is this entity called user bookmark, which maintains the relationship between the user and
the bookmark that he or she is interested in.
So we have the user bookmark and we are setting the user and we are setting the bookmark and we are
checking here.
If the bookmark is an instance of web link bookmark, we know that can be a web link or a movie or a
book.
Now if it is a web link, in that case, we are actually downloading the web page.
So this is the interesting part for us.
And at the very end, we are also saving the user bookmark.
So that's not relevant here.
But we are downloading the web page and this is happening for all of the bookmarks that the user is
interested in.
So now what we want to do is now that we know how to download Web pages concurrently.
So let's go ahead and make that change so that we can download all of the bookmarks in a concurrent
way.
But let's not do it here.
This downloading process will be done as a separate job.
We will do it independently of this particular code.
So we will write a background job for that.
And that would be the extension and the background background job where we will actually download these
bookmarks in a concurrent page.
Now here we are downloading the web page.
Here it is.
We are downloading the web page.
And if the web page is not equal to null, then we are writing it to disk and we are going to make only
the downloading pass part to work concurrently.
So if there are multiple web links, then we are going to download them concurrently.
But the writing to the disk part will be done sequentially.
So we are going to change that here.
So let me just comment this out.
And now let's head back to the slides to look at the specific goals for this extension.
Okay.
Now, the goal for this extension is to implement a background job that would download Web pages concurrently.
Specifically the background job should be able to download all the web links in the system and we can
use a boolean flag for that.
And if the Boolean flag is true, then it will download all the web links in the system.
Now, when we are starting the system for the very first time, so we have some web links and we are
starting the system, the server for the very first time.
In that case, we might want to download all the web links because the software itself is being launched
for the very first time.
So we need this particular task of downloading all the web links.
On the background job.
We'll also periodically download any new web links added into the system.
Now it's natural to expect that in a very heavily trafficked Web site, it's common for new bookmarks
to be saved every few seconds.
Right.
So the background job would periodically check if any new Web links were added since the last time it
performed a download operation.
And finally, we want to place time limits on the downloading process.
And we very well know how to do that.
And we will be using the time to invoke all approach that we have seen earlier.
So we are going to use a lot of code from that particular demo.
Now note that in professional environments, background jobs are used to do things like sending out
marketing emails or performing analytics on the data that is generated by the website or even download
web pages as we are attempting to do here.
Now in a framework like Spring, we can use a library called Quad Scheduler, which is basically a background
job scheduling library, and it can run our Java programs periodically.
Let me actually show you the setup just so that you can get an idea.
But we are not going to implement the quad scheduler here because we are not implementing spring framework.
Right.
We are not using the spring framework.
So we will write our background job in a manual way.
It works in a manual way.
But I just wanted to show you how the quad scheduler looks like within the spring environment.
Look, this is the code base for the real trivial project, not the one which we are implementing now,
which is a simulation of this.
Now here in the Real Project, we are actually using the spring framework.
And within that framework we have this file called us schedulers dot XML.
So it's an XML file and we can see that there is some XML content here.
Now here, these are the things that you can look at.
Now here there is this class called this movie index delta scheduler.
Let's not worry what that does, but it's basically a background job and we want this background job
to start at some point.
Now, whenever the web server is going to be started after it starts, we want to start this.
We want to launch this particular background job and we want to run it once every 2 minutes.
And for that, the spring framework.
Within the spring framework, we are using this job scheduling library called squad scheduler.
So here this is one of the classes from that from that particular library.
It's called a simple trigger bean.
But the actual Java program, which we have written, is actually this one.
So this is the background job and this is just some class from the third party library.
And we want this particular background job to run once every once every 2 minutes.
So we are we are specifying all that information in this particular XML file.
Now, so this is the job scheduling class class that we are using.
And we are also saying that we want to invoke this particular method called process within this job
scheduler.
So this particular class has a method.
Let me just open that.
Here it is.
It just has a simple method called process and it is doing something here.
So, so we just want to invoke that particular method.
So we are also specifying the method name also.
And we want to run it once every 2 minutes.
So that's the that's how it is implemented within the spring framework.
So whenever you learn about spring spring framework, you might also learn about scheduler.
Okay?
But now for our project we are going to implement this job scheduler and we are going to we are also
going to make it run once every some specified time, but we will do it manually since we are not using
either the spring framework or the scheduler.
So we'll just we are just going to simulate this.
So but that will give you a pretty good idea about how background jobs work.
So let me switch over to our project.
Here it is.
So the first thing is let's look at this class called us web link.
You may recall that web link is from this particular package called com dot semantics .3. entities.
So it is an entity and it extends bookmark and it also implements shareable.
You may recall this particular interface.
So Web link is basically a bookmark, right?
And other entities are book and movie.
And we also have some other entities like user.
Now previously there were only two fields.
Here you are and host and a new field called the HTML page has been added.
Now you may recall from our demo that within our demos in the Downloader Indexer programs, we also
had a static nested class called as Web Link, right?
An asset class called Web Link.
And we and it also had a field called HTML page.
So when the downloader thread or the task has downloaded a web page corresponding to a particular URL,
we were storing that particular downloaded web page and this variable HTML page by invoking said HTML
page.
So we also need that.
So that's why I introduced this particular field called HTML page.
I will also provide this class in the resources section.
Now, apart from that HTML page, I also introduced this particular enum called this download status
and it has for fields not attempted success failed and not eligible.
And there is this field called a download status and its type is this enum type download status.
By default it is not attempted, which means that a particular web link instance by default it it will
be in this state, which means that it has not been downloaded yet.
An attempt has not been made to download it, but once an attempt has been made so and if the page is
downloaded successfully, then the state will be changed to success.
Or if the webpage could not be downloaded, then it would be changed to fail.
Now, sometimes the web page may not be downloaded, cannot be downloaded in the sense if it is a PDF
document, we may not want to download it, which is actually the case in our project, in which case
we will just say that the download status is not eligible.
So those are the different states here.
And.
Yeah.
Here, for example, earlier I commented this out and here we were saying that we want to download the
page only if it does not end with the pdf.
So we want to download only HTML pages.
So I already commented that commented on that code because we want to change that now.
So this is what we have in the web link.
So the goal is for the we have looked at the specific goals for the downloader job and the background
job and the background job itself.
We will see it in the next next lecture because there is a lot of code to write for that.
So in this particular lecture we are going to make some changes in this particular class called us bookmark.
So Bookmark now is basically a dove class and it interacts with the database, right?
All the classes interacts with the database and in our case the database is nothing but that data store
class.
You may recall that.
So the data store class has all the data that we need, right?
And so the classes interact with the, with the data store.
It means that they will fetch data from the database.
That's what they are going to simulate in an ideal real world.
We will have a SQL queries here.
Now, the background job, if you recall, there are two tasks.
One is that we need to download all the web links.
So that was one of the, one of the requirements.
So we need to provide a method for that.
And another requirement is it needs to periodically download any new web links.
So what that means is we need to download only those web links which were added since the time we we
downloaded the last set of Web pages.
So all those new Web links will have the status of not attempted and all the downloaded ones where an
attempt has been made, they would have a status of success failed or not eligible.
But for the new ones it would be not attempted.
And we want to download only those web links.
So we need a method to get all the web links which have this status of not attempted.
So when the background job is going to periodically run, it's going to look for only those web links
which have the status.
So basically we need to methods here and the template that the steps are already provided here in the
bookmark class.
So one of them is get all web links and in reality we will actually have an SQL query here, but or
or a hibernate query.
Hibernate Hibernate is also a library which can also be used for fetching data from the database.
So for now, since we are using the data store, so we are going to fetch the data from our data store.
Okay, so get all web links is one method and the second method is get web links on both.
These methods will be invoked from the background job, so both of them will return a list of web links.
So that list will be stored in this data structure list of web links.
So it is called as a result.
So let's go ahead.
And now within the data store class, you open the data store.
So the DataStore class has all the bookmarks stored within this.
And this in this data structure, which is a list of list of bookmarks.
It's called bookmarks.
Here it is.
So it is a list of list of bookmarks.
And so each element is a list of bookmarks and the zero element is basically web links.
Because those are getting populated here, then we are invoking this method load data.
We are initially loading the users, then we are loading web lengths, then the movies and the books.
So the list of web links are actually being stored at the in the zero position, the list of web web
links in the zero eight position.
And this in this list and in the first position, it will be storing a list of movies which are also
bookmarks.
And finally, in the second position, list of books will be stored, but we are interested only in
the list of web links.
So we need to get the we need to invoke this method and we need to get the zeroth element.
So that's what we need to do here in the bookmarks dot.
So let's go ahead and invoke that particular method here.
Okay.
So this is a method.
It returns a list of list of bookmarks.
And we just need the zero element.
So let's copy this.
Let's call it us all.
Web links.
Now we need to return a list of weblink.
But here it is.
A list of bookmark.
So.
We need to Doncaster.
And it goes into result.
So that's it.
That's about that method.
Actually, this needs to go here.
I'm sorry.
This needs to go here.
Okay.
So next we need to get all the Web links, given the status.
So what we can do is we can invoke this method, get all Web links, and we can and then we can filter
them out.
We can get only those web links which have this download status, which would be this one.
What is it?
Which would be this one?
Not a template.
So that would be passed as an argument.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So let's just say if.
Web link dot.
Get download status.
It equals.
The input download status.
Then we need to add it here.
Okay.
So that's it.
And reality, this would translate into a very simple SQL query, but now we have to write this.
So I guess that's about it for this particular lecture.
And in the next lecture we will actually go ahead and we will implement the the background job and we
will do that in the next lecture.
So that's about it.
I'll see you in the next lecture.