Not it's just because a very important topic called variable scope every variable has a scope which
is basically the part of the program where the variable can be used and you get a compiler error if
you try to use it outside off at school different kinds of variables have different scopes.
That is variable is declared a class level have a different scope compared to variables declared in
methods.
Let's look at scope of class level variables variables declared at class level like instance are static
where tables are considered global and they are accessible anywhere in the class only exception is that
a class level variable cannot be assigned to another variable declared before.
And here is an example.
Here we are declaring three class level variables.
I janky these variables are accessible anywhere in the class so as you can see they are also accessible
in the method for you can also see that variable is declared.
And in the very statement we're assigning it to variable g so that it's perfectly valid.
But we also said that a class level variable cannot be assigned to another variable declared before
it so here you can see that we are declaring variable k but we are assigning it to variable in the previous
statement.
So this is invalid as gay is not declared when we are doing this assignment.
Background is that the same statement J called ok is valid within the method for.
Even though we're able K is declared below method for that because by that method fools and broke all
the class global variables are already initialized so it just doesn't matter.
Vary your methods are written within the class so that's a large scope of class global variables.
Next lips look at scope of local variables.
We know that local variables are declared within methods or constructors are within block statements
like statements a lookup table is accessible from the point of declaration.
And if it's block hit block and be method constructor can go a statement here's an example.
Here we have a method called fu the metalworkers for local variables b x z n y be them the metal parameter
on your scope is the and dark matter.
This scope of the x and z is also shown not the scope of media will X also includes the declarator site
that is a part that declares variable z.
That's the reason we're able to assign extasy but not that Z cannot be assigned to x when declaring
X that is you cannot how N x is equal to Z commas equal to something that will not work CSCOPE would
include any declaratives on the right plus the rest of the block next video right is part of an IF block
.
Unsoiled scope and so with that particular block.
So as you can see accessing variable right outside of the if statement is invalid and it leads to compiler
error and the other thing to note is that within the scope of a local variable you cannot really clear
that same variable.
For example you can see that a variable x is declared twice and the second declaration falls within
the scope of Fosdike tradition and hence is invalid.
Here is another example illustrating that within the scope of a local variable but you cannot really
clear that same area.
But here we are really getting variable x in the initialization part of the for statement and it is
invalid in the earlier example really coloration was done in an IF statement.
So what we just saw was that in local variable cannot be shadowed or hidden but we know that a local
variable can hide a class level variable.
We have seen that in the previous chapter so even though the class level variable scope is still valid
.
It can be done by a local variable.
And here is an example.
He had the class level variable x is hidden by the local variable x which is defined in the motard for
.
So when X is incremented it is basically incrementing the local variable x to access the class level
variable x.
We know that we need to use this reference Finally any mentors invoked from the current block will get
a new scope that is very declared in the current block are not accessible in the invoke methods.
Here is an example here and we have a method foo with a local variable x method isn't working method
bar Witan method bar b cannot access the variable X declared in method foo so that's about it underscores
the scope of both plus local variables and local variables I would say this just try out some of the
examples myself for book Class level and local variables.
Thank you