Hi there, this is Lulu and welcome back from Java.
Eight onwards we can have static methods and interfaces and we have already seen how interfaces can
have default methods.
Let's see what benefits we get by making static methods part of interfaces.
Well, first, let's look at why interfaces did not have static methods before Java eight, as both
interfaces and static methods are stateless.
That's an important question which we need to ask.
One very good reason for this could be that interfaces are abstract specifications.
That is the define only contracts.
So including static methods seem to be against the spirit of interfaces, as static methods would include
implementation and a contract means no implementation.
But interfaces can be associated with utility methods.
And we know that static methods so as utility methods.
For instance, we may want to have a method called MN copies, which will take two parameters.
One is MN, which is an integer, and the other is element, which is some kind of an object.
And we don't have to worry about the object's type.
And this method would return a list.
Implementation analyst, as mentioned in an earlier lecture, is an interface from the Java package.
And the return list would include and copies of the given element.
As the method name suggests.
So if end was three, the written list would include three copies of the given element.
So this is a utility method and is associated with an interface list as it is returning one of its implementations.
And to accommodate such utility methods.
The convention or the pattern is to provide a companion utility class with the interface.
An collections class from the Java package is an example of such a companion class.
Collections class was also briefly discussed earlier when discussing default methods and the PN copy
method which we just discussed, is actually a static method in the collections class.
This collections class is a companion class for an interface named collection, which is singular singular
collection, which is one of the main interfaces in Java util package.
And the list interface is actually a sub interface of the collection interface.
And the collections class includes two kinds of methods.
The first one are algorithmic type of methods.
And these methods have some interface as a method, parameter type, and they apply some algorithm on
the objects that get passed into that parameter.
Here are some examples and we already looked at the source method which has list interface as a method
parameter type and it sorts the elements in the input list object.
Second method would shuffle the elements of the list, and we discussed it briefly in an earlier lecture,
and the third one would simply reverse the elements in the input list.
These methods would work well as default methods if they are moved into the appropriate interface corresponding
to the input parameter type, like moving the source method as a default method into the list interface.
As we have seen in the previous lecture, that way those default methods can directly be invoked on
the object itself.
So in case of the source method, it can be invoked on the list object itself.
The second kind of methods in the collections class represent factory methods which construct objects
of a certain interface type which is indicated by the methods written type.
We already discussed the first example here, and let's not worry about the other two.
And these methods cannot be used as default methods as there is no object on which they can be invoked.
They are simply factory methods.
And they would work very well as static methods if they are moved into the interface corresponding to
the methods written type.
In this case and copy, this method can be moved into the list interface, which is the method written
type.
This way.
Utility methods specific to the interface would live with the interface itself rather than in a separate
companion class like the collections class.
So language designers seem to have realized this and were fine with interfaces having static methods.
Due to this, we can now have static methods and interfaces.
So it is like the integer class, which includes static methods that are very specific to integer class.
So I think going forward we may not encounter companion classes very much, as at least most of the
utility methods can now be part of interfaces as either default or static methods.
And also note that default methods in an interface can invoke static methods in the same interface.
Not that like in the case of default methods, interface evaluation will still hold if we add only static
methods to an existing interface.
For instance, a functional interface will remain as a functional interface, even if static methods
are added to it.
In an earlier lecture, we have seen how a functional interface remained as a functional interface after
adding a default method.
So that would work if instead of default method, we defined a static method.
But the main advantage of having static methods in interfaces seems to be the one which we have seen
earlier, where static utility methods can live with the interface itself instead of in a separate companion
class.
That seems to be the main advantage.
Finally, let's look at some specific properties associated with static methods defined in interfaces.
First one is obvious.
We need to use a static modifier in the method declaration.
Second property is that unlike static methods in classes, static methods and interfaces are not inherited.
According to Brian, who is one of the Java language designers.
It seems that the inheritance of static methods and classes is itself a design bug, and after careful
consideration it seems they did not want to extend it to interfaces, especially considering that two
super interfaces can have identical static methods.
So static methods are not inherited.
Finally, static methods and interfaces can be invoked only via interface name.
That is, they cannot be invoked using an object reference.
And we know that interfaces cannot be instantiated to.
Also, since static methods and interfaces cannot be inherited, we cannot even use an instance of a
subtype of the interface to invoke that method.
So it's got to be via the interface name.
And recall that starting methods which are part of classes can be invoked.
We are instances of those classes even though it is not recommended way to do it.
So as you can see, there are some unique properties associated with static methods defined in interfaces.
Let's now go ahead and look at a quick demo of static methods.
In this demo, we are going to extend the quote from the previous demo.
So here we are looking at the Interface C, which we know extends Interface A and I just introduced
one static method which is also named as static method.
And as you can see, we have the static modifier here and the usual print message saying that we are
inside the interface C and inside the static method.
Now let's go to test.
Client to test.
So here we are creating an instance of x.
X is the concrete class.
We know that and C is the reference type and we are invoking the static method via the reference type.
And this is not possible, as mentioned earlier.
So let's just go ahead and compile this.
See it says illegal static interface method called so the receiver expression should be replaced with
the type qualifier.
See.
So we need to qualify it with the interface name.
So let's just do this and this should work.
We run this.
So it's printing the message.
And we also said that static methods cannot be inherited.
So.
So I added this method called inheritance test in the concrete class x.
Here is the inheritance test and here is the static method.
So we are just trying to invoke the static method.
And this should not work either because static methods cannot be inherited.
So let me compile this.
And it says cannot find symbol static method, which means it is invisible here.
So let's just close it.
But go is.
It is a default method and it can be accessed directly.
It's defined in the interface.
See in the last demo itself.
But here I just added one statement.
It is invoking the static method.
So from the default method we are we are calling the static method.
So static method is like a helper method.
So let's just assume that the method go is using the utility method, which is the static method.
So let's just simply compile and run this.
So here it is.
First, the method go is getting invoked from here.
So because method go, which is a default method is inherited and it's getting invoked and it in turn
is invoking the static method.
And so we are seeing the two messages and that's about it.
That's about the demo.
Let me quickly also open up the Java doc and show you one of the interfaces it's called.
Competitor interface, which is from the Java package and we are inside the Java eight dock.
So this competitor interface, we will look at that in the Collections Framework chapter.
But here it is.
As you can see, the Java dock looks slightly different.
It is it has tabs and it has some static methods.
Here you can see the static modifier and as usual it also has some abstract methods.
So static methods were added recently with Java eight and this tab shows only default methods.
The default methods tab shows only default methods that were added into this interface and instance
methods is basically a union of both abstract as well as default methods.
So it does not include static methods.
So it includes both abstract as well as default methods, whereas abstract methods include only abstract
methods and default in only default methods.
So just wanted to show this difference in the Java doc and if you just replace this eight with seven.
Then we see the old UI or the docks.
So this is from the Java seven docks.
And as you can see, there are only two abstract methods.
So with Java eight, both default and static methods were added.
And so the API dock also looks different.
So that's about it.
That's about static methods.
That's it.