Hi there.
This is LA and we'll come back.
Now let's go ahead and implement the background job.
Now here for this particular extension, I created a new package within the year project and it's called
as complete semantics 30. BG Jobs.
It means background jobs.
So we will write our background job here.
So the background job at template, the template code has already been written and we are going to fill
the rest of the class here.
And it's called US Web Page Downloader Task.
Now here we have this class called us launch dot Java.
You may recall this.
And this was used for launching the application itself.
So you may recall that within the main method we were invoking load data which will basically load the
data into the datastore right, which is our database, and then it invokes the start method.
And within the start method the we are simulating the users browsing the bookmarks.
Right?
We are iterating through each of the users and we are we are simulating the browsing pattern here by
invoking the Browse method.
We also looked at the Browse method earlier and after doing that we are going to invoke this new method
called as run downloader job.
So here it is, the run downloader job.
It's a private method and here we are instantiating this new class called web page downloader task and
we are passing a value.
True here it's a boolean flag.
If we pass for true, it means that we also want to download all of the web links that are there in
the system.
Now, so this will be run as a separate thread.
So we are passing this task to this new thread and we are invoking the START method, which means that
web page downloader task is actually a run.
And here it is, iterable and we have some variables here.
Here is the constructor and the flag.
Here is download all if it is true.
If a true is passed here, which means that we are going to download all of the web links and we have
the bookmark down in the last lecture we have.
We have enhanced this class in order to fetch all the web links.
And also we wrote another method to fetch only Web links with a particular status value.
Right.
And here is the timeframe.
So we want to place a time limit on that on the downloading process.
So a particular Web page should be downloaded within 3 seconds, and we already know how to do that.
And I also mentioned that we'll be using the code from the Invoke all demo program.
Okay.
So this is some template code and this implements run table here, which means that we need to override
the run method.
And within the run method, we also want to have this respond to any interruption.
So if we are if you send an interrupt signal to this particular task from anywhere we want to interrupt.
So we also have this vital loop.
And since it's a background job, the the job keeps waiting here.
So we also have the rate method.
So once the job is done, it waits for certain seconds and then it continues with the new set of web
links.
That was one of the goals.
So we need to fill this up.
So there are basically three things that we need to fill.
We need to get the web links for that.
We will use the methods in the bookmark down.
Then we need to download the web pages concurrently and we already know how to do that.
So we will use some of the code from the from our demos and then we'll finally wait for like 15 or 20
seconds here.
So let's go ahead and fill this up.
So initially we need to have the static variables, then the instance variables.
Now let me open the time to invoke all index program.
Here it is.
So if we go here.
So we need this particular statement.
Okay.
Now next we need the download or thread, so let's also get that.
The downloader task which is here it is.
It is a callable.
So we need to get this.
Let me also make this file so we can have fighter jets in our threat pool.
It's.
Copy this.
No, let me make this in that particular code, we have it as web length in lowercase, which was a
static nested class.
Let's do this because the entity that we are using is actually it has L in uppercase.
So let me import that.
Now http connect.
It is here in the util.
Okay.
So it was just importing the HTTP connect from our demo.
We don't need that.
So that's the downloader class.
So we have some code already here and you can notice that we are also following the coding conventions.
First we have the static variables, then the instance variables, then the static nested class.
So first we have the variables here with the static variables following the instance variables.
Then the static nested class.
If you recall from our coding conventions class, that's a lecture which we have done a long time ago.
So we have these structure, class structure rules, then comes the constructor.
So that's what we had.
Now, next, we also have to.
Shut down.
Once we are done, we can do that also.
So here after the while loop.
You can have this.
Now here, we need to make a few changes.
Okay.
We want to download only those links which do not end with pdf dot pdf.
Now that code is actually here in the bookmark manager.
So we can have this code here.
I can have this if statement.
So if the weblink does not end with PDF only, then we want to download it.
But first, let's set the status here.
Initially let us set it to failure.
And once the Web page is downloaded, we will set it to true.
It will be failed.
And later, we will set it to success once it's downloaded.
Now, here.
Let's also have the slope.
And it means that in the loop it's a PDF document.
It means it's not eligible for downloading.
So we had a state for that.
Here it is.
And that's it.
And the call method returns the web link.
So that's with the download Downloader task.
Now it's time to fill this up.
So the first thing is we need to get the Web links.
So let's go ahead and write a simple method here.
Let's just call it get.
Web links.
And it should return a list of web lengths.
Let's just write some template code here.
Me imported.
So if you have at least one weblink, then we want to invoke the download method, which is a method
that we are going to write next and we will pass the web links and it will download all the pages concurrently.
Else.
Okay.
Let's just put this out.
And say no new.
So this is just the template code which we are writing and we are going to fill up these two methods
next.
And here let's put it now wait statement, let's say.
I'm unit.
Let's wait for 15 seconds.
So the background job well will try to download once every 15 seconds.
We'll look for new web lengths and time unit.
Here it is.
Import this.
Okay.
Let's go ahead and fill up this.
So we had the field called Download all which was initialized in the constructor.
So if it is true, it means that we need to download all the links.
And we also had the variable, the Dow here, the Dow variable.
So we are going to invoke the method which we have implemented in the last lecture.
It's called get all web links because we want download all and web links.
They'll be initialized with this.
And once we are done with that, we can say.
This way, you know, once the background job finishes downloading and then it waits for 15 seconds
and then it repeats.
So when it repeats, it's not going to after 15 seconds, it's not going to download all the Web links.
Again, we don't want to do that, and that's why we are setting the download all flat to false here.
So it will only look for any new any new web links that got added.
So now let's invoke this one with the download Status of Not Attempted.
And.
That's it.
So we are done with that.
We are getting the Web links and we are passing the Web links to this new method called Download.
So let's go ahead and implement that also.
Okay.
So for this we can in order to download we said that we are going to use the invoke all method.
So let's go here in the invoke all method.
We were invoking the timed executed here.
So we need.
You can copy this code.
And we can make some changes.
So we need a bunch of tasks here.
So we only have web links.
So we need to convert from the Web links.
We need to get the downloader tasks right because task is what we are going to submit here to the invoke
all method and we don't need this time left.
What we need is just the time frame.
So we already had.
The variable declared time frame at the top, which is 3 seconds.
And these are the tasks and we don't have the cue here.
We just have the tasks.
So we can remove this code.
This is just for the demo.
There.
So we need to get the tasks here.
And this needs to be.
Weblink.
Blink.
Now.
We need to get the download our tasks here.
We need to submit the task to the download executor.
So we already have that downloaded here.
The task here.
So for that, let's write this method called get tests.
Let's pass the Web links.
Me.
Create another private method here.
Okay.
So we need to return a list of downloader types.
So.
Just copy this.
Another is gentrified.
We know that.
And we just need to add the blank.
So we are writing this small method here called Get.
So now we have the TASS and we just need to submit the TASS to the invoke all method and invoke all
we know.
Returns a list of features.
So we need to to iterate through all of the futures now so we can use this.
Code here.
Some of this code.
So future.
And once again, this needs to be a blank.
And if it is not canceled, we know that the invoke all method will download all of the web links and
if it if any particular downloader could not download a page, then it would be canceled.
The downloader task will be cancelled.
You may recall that.
Now, we don't need this here, right?
We don't.
We are not indexing anything, so let's remove that.
Now.
Future target will return a web.
Right.
Which will.
Will return a web link.
And.
It's called weblink.
And from the weblink, we can get the web page once it is downloaded.
So get hatch HTML page.
We can say if the page.
Not equal to null.
It means that it has been downloaded successfully, in which case we can write it to the disk and the
code to write to the disk is here.
Here it is.
The thing is this.
This needs to be caps.
And.
How will you tell is a class here in the util package?
You may also recall that.
So we wrote that when we were dealing with the IO chapter.
Next, we need to set the status to success because we downloaded the page successfully.
So let's just take this here.
Let's also put a simple statement here.
And let's print.
The URL of the web page.
So this is just.
The system called statement and.
Let's call it the page download, not download.
Let's just say not downloaded.
Because the reason could be that it's a PDF to.
All right.
So let's just say Web page not downloaded here.
Okay.
So we are printing that and Trask is canceled.
And this method I will tell, right?
Actually, if the page is downloaded successfully, it will write it to this folder called Pages.
So if you go back to that lecture and in the Evo chapter where we had made an enhancement to the project,
you will you will see that we were actually writing to this directory called Pages.
Right now it is empty.
So we will do that.
And let's go ahead and.
This.
I think because of all the copying that we are doing, we are also importing these statements.
So the only other exception is this one needs to surround with trite catch.
So.
I guess we are done with all the enhancements now, so let's go ahead and run this.
From the launch.
Program.
Here we are.
Some of this webpage could not be downloaded and here it is.
Download Success.
Now you see that no new web links to download.
So I downloaded a few pages and then it says it waited for 15 seconds because it's a background job.
After 15 seconds, it tried to download new pages and there are no web links.
So once again, we can see another statement.
So after the 15 seconds has passed, it tried to see if it could download any new web links.
But there are.
But since we are not adding any new web links, there were no web pages to add and to download new pages
to download.
And this continues with every 15 seconds.
So that's how the background jobs work.
Let me refresh this.
Here it is.
Four pages have been downloaded that are actually five pages, but one of them is here is a web link.
One of them ends with a dot PDF which we are not downloading.
So that's it.
So this is what we have.
So I think that's it.
So now you have some understanding of how background jobs will work.
This is how the background job will work.
If it was a spring framework, we would just we would still have this class.
But this rescheduling part will be will be declared in the XML file itself, like the way I have shown
in the previous lecture.
And that's about it.
I hope you like this nice extension.
It was easy for us because we already had an idea of how to download web pages concurrently based on
what we learned.
So this is some really good stuff that we are looking at.
So we are using the executed service.
So we are using the concurrency utilities and we are also placing time, time limits.
So it's some really good stuff.
And then in your professional life, if you have to do something with this so you already know how to
how to implement it.
Thank you.
And that's about it.
And happy coding.