Hi there.
Now let's look at another class from the jackpot out Udal package which just called us artists.
So we looked at tons of they walked us in this chapter and now let's go back to our old unreliable friend
which is an art.
The class Arias is a generic utility class and it helps us in manipulating memory through its various
methods.
It has methods which can help us can work on our end to an idealist.
Similarly it also has methods that can help us sort of through our search for an element in an eddy
or even make a copy of an array or compare it to our race to see whether they're identical contents
.
So it has lots of useful utility markets and in July 8.
So what are the new methods that support bodyless operations have been added with this class.
But in this class we will focus on only its core methods which are sequential.
But in a subsequent lesson they will look at the paralyzed methods befre.
Finally note that most methods in this class how overloaded with sions to support race of different
pyramidal types.
Also you will see overloaded methods that big arrays of object by present.
In this demo we will mostly focus on methods that are in our ideas of object By-Passed parameters other
overloaded motions look in the CMB.
So let's go ahead and look at what this class has to offer.
So here we can see that the R is glass is from the door Trudel package and a new class called is devil
has been added to the elections package on that than this I raised a glass.
We have the sequential order so that we can demonstrate all sequential operations in this response.
So here I have already written a lot of code here.
So we want to demonstrate many of the methods in this class.
So in the interest of time I wonder did it end up in locations.
So we don't have to write any code now.
OK.
Because I predict all of nine so just go ahead and look at all of the code that I have already written
and I'm going to blurt very strongly very clearly so that we can look at each method in a very clearly
.
So the first method that we want to look at is as a list and this is probably the most commonly used
method which you will use from this class and what this method does is as the name indicates it takes
an input re and it returns a list list B.
So it is saying that give me a list view of the right.
So here we how string are it.
Let's look at this definition.
So this is the awesomeness.
And here we have a wad of spectrometer and we know that this is a generic notation.
So this is a type and we are saying that the return list should also how elements of that are in here
.
We are creating a string array and passing that string as an input to this method as honest and it reads
a list of strings and intermediate and so on our list.
But the thing is this other list will be off fixed sites.
OK so that's the most important thing.
So always remember this thing if ever you want to convert an array into a list and do not eat less than
you would use this method as a list.
OK.
Just always keep that in mind since it is an idea we will use to address costs.
Here we are printing the strengths.
So let me just run this case or it prints Rajan on it.
So there's a list.
Now it's a fixed size list and what it means is that you cannot remove an element or you cannot identity
make.
If you try to do that the return on their list will throw an error.
OK.
So let's also try that.
Let me just remind you to try to run it as you can see it says unsupported operation exception.
So the written order list is not going to support this anymore operation.
As soon as we can walk it it will through an unsupported operation exception.
And here it is.
X is not the same thing happens with.
I'd also let you go.
But you can actually update the value.
That is fine.
So let's update the 0 8 value value John and that would reflect in the order you're not added to.
So this other list is backed by the original not it.
So let me just print that.
So as you can see here we are printing and Ari does the original array a latte and it is printing the
updated values.
OK.
John I 90 earlier it was rajin on it.
Now here I'm using this method called just to string from the artist class itself.
So the string method will take an array and will return a string representation of the elements so it
will concatenate all of the elements using comma.
And it really and goes it in and square brackets on to display the output.
Search says that's returns a string the presentation of the contents of those mystified.
It's all there does.
So we will be using this tool string method from the IRS class in this Demel.
Now let's go ahead and look at more of the methods.
So here we know that it returns a fixed size order list.
Now if you want to take an RV but if you want to idlest to be modifiable then you could use something
like this so here all we are doing is to shift goal.
So we are still invoking the as just matter which we're done at a fixed size idlest that is being passed
as the input argument to the idlest constructor.
So there is a constructor which were big this collection has input and we are simply passing this on
to this.
So now once you do that you can modify the resulting string.
Now the strings as it will be it will be modifiable eyewitnessed.
So that's how you would create a modifiable list from an input.
Now the ostlers method we know it takes a lot occiput ometer.
So it's sort of passing or not it.
We can also pass Comus operator lists so that we don't so much problem.
So here we have seen that the Azi just matter is taking an input array which is already populated.
Now let's say we just want we don't have any idea but just popular with data but we simply want to create
an other list of fixed size.
Then here is the idiom we can follow this.
So here when we say as a list and we are passing a string array.
Which means the resulting idlest should include strings and we are saying the size should be three.
And this gives greater done or not a list of fixed size.
And this does not have any elements.
So it would be nullable Yes it would be filled with not.
And it is a fixed size.
So that's how you do it.
If you recall the idlest class is orderless constructor.
There was one constructor which takes capacity as input.
But if you use that constructor it would create an order list of that capacity.
But as soon as the capacity is reached the other the size will be automatically increased.
OK so it's not really a fixed size idlest.
So if you do that you wouldn't get it fixed size or it is.
So if you want to create a fixed size artists and this is the idiom that you need to follow next.
Now let's look at one more example grid example here.
So here we have this other list as list and we are using an end.
So this is an object or ELF object.
But here this is an hour off.
And so this wouldn't work.
So you cannot expect that it would return a list of integer and that's because this new age of two is
not auto boxes.
OK so you it will knock on what this Indu new in digital.
If it was new in digital photo then it would work fine.
OK.
So let's just make this new integer in that case it does fine but it does just primitive then it will
not work.
And we knew we already know the reason for that because in auto boxing you recall our auto boxing lesson
we said that arrays are not auto blossomy which means that this will not be converted into new off integer
offered.
So because of that property This assignment will not look to be get a compilation error but this would
still work.
So if you have something like this as list new and off to denigratory done and list off in digerati
.
So this would create an idealist underground how only one element which would be an ID and the size
of that is true.
That is fine.
Let me just print this.
So as you can see the size of this of a fixed fixed let's do is 1.
So that's about as list not it's more to the next category of models which is soc.
And let's look at two soft methods one of them is sacque undertakes an object array under it and so
why it and this particular method uses a much sought bit natural oddity which means that the idea that
the elements should have implemented compatible interface.
Now the specification also says that effort is partially soccer at it.
If this idea is already partially sorted then we would need far fewer than analogon comparisons and
logging to compare results.
Mozart needs analogon but it will be far fewer than that if it is partially sawder and if it is almost
soldered it would be approximately and comparisons only where n is the precise.
So let's go ahead and run this string array.
I mean common this out from here.
As you can see it prints on it donjon.
So it has been.
It has already been sorted out.
Now there are some additional comments that this particular makes.
It says that it is well suited for merging two or more socket ideas.
So if you have two or more arrays which are already sorted then the way you would much them on your
website as you would simply concatenate the address and then sort the resulting at it because they're
already partially.
Each of the ideas are already sorted which means which means the munged entries are partially sorted
.
So we have a much faster way to sort the much edit so the resulting ID will be sorted in a very efficient
way.
So that's with an object array no lips sought an ID.
OK if it is an array of primitives then the saut method would use a quick song.
So let's here we have a new array and it has these three elements.
So if I run it.
So the elements are Saltaire.
OK and once again we are using the string method and passing the IRA I know as I mentioned there are
some overloaded versions of a lot of overloaded versions.
This is taking an entire day but you also have or a double idea and so on.
Now there is also another version of SOC which takes a competitor.
Here we have general extradition which is fine.
We can you will understand later but it takes a competitor.
So earlier post natural ordering about this sort of notion sort method will take a competitor and uses
that competitor to sort the elements and the commandant out in here.
So you're done with sorting we are done with as list next is binary search on the binary search method
.
Basically it takes an hour day and will search for this.
It's a search method Mystikal your search matter under which it uses binary search algorithm.
So it is used for searching for this element.
The second parameter in this input.
OK on the return type is if the element is fun done the group returned the index of the element in the
Arctic.
Otherwise the binary search method then look at the index position where this element can be inserted
.
If the element is not then and it returns the insertion point and negates it and oxyd minus one.
And the specification also says that the input must be sorted.
Otherwise the behavior is undefined but does the specification but it all depends upon the JVM implementation
and on my mission.
Even if that is not sorted it still finds the element Anderton's the appropriate index even if it is
not shocking what can go ahead and look at this burn statement here.
So we have the Areff 4:23 and fifty nine and we are trying to search for this element for under childred
done the index 0 undertaken zero.
Now let's look for five under-achieved return.
I guess Heterodynes minus two minus two.
OK because you would have been inserted here at the first position.
And we are right in your minus one quick K minus off one and another minus one.
So that's about the binary search matter.
Now let's look at copy off.
So as a name names I'll just copy off what's included in a copy of this idea.
And we are also specifying the method.
OK.
We are also specifying the Nant of the new ID.
Now if that length is greater than the length of this input array then for all the remaining slots.
OK it would copy all of the elements from this from.
From this era into the new array.
But for all the remaining elements remaining slots it would add a zero.
So the new array will be written here.
So to me you know and so here is a new audit.
Now data size has been increased often you already are just filled with zero.
Next is this is a slight detour.
There is an audit copy mattered in the system class which is from the dollar dot like package on it
but almost the exact same thing.
So I just want to show that also I think we'll discuss this matter earlier involved that occurs.
So it takes this input it which is the source.
And this is their destination ID.
And this is the position in the source are they from where we want to start copying the elements.
And this is their destination.
And this is the start position in the data destination are they where we want to copy the elements from
IRA and Ira learned as the number of elements that need to be copied and if new or it happens to be
a larger area than all the all the slots of the remaining slots will be filled with zero.
This doesn't that all be all.
So let me just run that also.
He does search just the same array.
So these are two different areas.
In fact copy off actually in dentally uses a copy but probably does a slightly cleaner way to do it
because the the other you don't have to pass on our eight week new ID.
It in itself is creating order under disorder Dunning it.
So that's the added copy.
So that's how you do it instead of creating a for loop and rotating.
I needed to the follow up on creating a new ID and copying that immense friend.
You can use a single statement in this way.
Next as a film after the film that basically takes an ID and fills each element with this element.
So once you invoke this every element will have in the table have this 130.
So that's got you.
Or does the new array now has only 30 so that's a good way to initialize not a bet on the one element
.
Now next this equals my third equals but that basically takes both the address and would return true
if both the items are equal which means that dot is off the same type of the same size and they have
the exact same contents.
So let's just try that on your phones because Ira has these elements 4:23 19 but nobody has these elements
.
OK.
So it's not equal.
So that's the equals method.
Now finally let's look at these medical deep equals.
So it is also equals third but it does it beat equals which means that if we have mastered Aarhus then
it would still be able to compare the IDs.
No it's not just a single dimension but multi-dimensionally is going to start out is but this metric
takes an hour off object.
So here we can see that it's an array of objects to or else objects are just the comparison.
So if our eyes are deeply equal to one another and by deeply it means that there are more than what
are appropriate for nested M.S..
OK so let's go ahead and look at a few examples here we have to be buddies.
They are a one on deep or two which are three dimensional arrays and these are the elements.
And in this print statement we are working with the artist you just run it and you agreed and said to
my wife I changed this to sixty one.
OK.
Now it does not equal under two fonts.
Knowledge is a two dimensional not a.
Here going the same elements and it will also work fine.
OK.
Now let's take the next example which is of one dimension.
Now with this we get a combine.
OK.
That's because all of these ideas cannot be assigned to idea of objects.
The reason is this whole thing is just an object.
It is not an idea of object if it was an object then it would have been fine.
Now here this is an odd off in art and art is an object so an art off and art is basically an idea or
object.
And so there was no problem.
But here it is just an object.
It's not an object.
So this they call it does covariance let go and variants as if there are two types.
Let's say one of them is object on the other one is an integer.
Now we know that indeed there is a subtype of object.
So if that is the case then it also means that object.
RFE RL object is a supertype of integer so if integer is it's a type of object then an integer is a
.
So pipe all idea off ogic.
So that's what covariance means.
OK.
And that does not work here as in but it is not as a type of object or object at it.
OK but had it been like this then it would be fine now.
So this does not compile.
OK so that's what's also that's an important thing.
And we'll get back with this covariance thing and generics lesson because in genetics with genetics
we have a property called invariants.
So when we get data we will once again discuss this covariance property off ice and here.
So here earlier it was a off object was a barometer of the quotes.
So we are just demonstrating something here.
So here we are trying to assign an three dimensional not so here this would be an idea or object right
.
So I guess it would be an idea off and in two dimensional I guess it could get stronger as a two dimensional
body not a three dimensional body on here.
And this equipment the value of zero of two it would be three.
So that's all it is just a monster.
The same thing we have these three statements.
Let me also show the API.
So as you can see each Metford like the binary search has all these different parameters.
There is also some arrangement there.
Here you can take a look at this.
So each degree of methods have several overloaded versions.
So that's the artist class and that's it.
And the court will be available in the resource section and that's about it.
Thank you and I'll be quoting