Hi there.
This is De La Rue and welcome back.
So we now understand what methods are and a method can be of two types.
It can be an instance method or it can be a static method.
And the class can have only instance methods or only static methods, or it can have both instance as
well as static methods.
Let's just look at instance methods.
As the name implies, instance methods are methods of instances of a class that is the objects of a
class, that is the represent behavior of objects.
And they can be accessed via object references.
We use a dart operator on an object reference in order to access instance methods of the object.
And we discuss this at the beginning of the section while introducing class and objects.
And the methods of an object are invoked in order to perform some action on behalf of the object.
And in doing so, they usually affect the object state.
That is, the state is changed.
And instance methods do this by directly manipulating instance variables which we know represent object
state.
And when we say manipulate instance variables, we mean that values of one or more instance variables
are updated.
And objects that can also be affected.
When instance methods invoke other instance methods within the same class as those other instance,
methods may also manipulate instance variables.
And shortly we will do a demo where we will extend the currency converter class from our assignment
and we will see how instance methods can be used in order to manipulate object state.
Next, we have static methods.
Here we will just look at what static methods are.
And later we will revisit them in a different section and we will get into a few more additional details.
Static methods have the keyword static in the method declaration and absence of static keyword implies
that it's an instance method.
Static methods are class level methods.
That is unlike instance methods they do not deal with object state.
This implies that they do not have access to either instance variables or instance methods within the
same class.
That is from a static method.
If you directly try to access an instance variable declared within the same class, then you get a compiler
error.
Similarly, you cannot even invoke an instance method within the same class.
So if we are unable to manipulate state, then the question is what purpose do the so?
This of US utility methods.
Utility methods are methods which typically take some input and perform some action based on that input
and generate some output.
An example is the sum method, which we saw in an earlier lecture where the sum method accepted two
numeric values as input and returned the sum of those two numbers.
The sum method used only the method parameters.
So static methods are typically dependent on just the input parameters, and they cannot access any
instance variables which are object specific.
However they can access static variables.
If you recall, static variables are class level variables.
That is, they are also not object specific and so can be accessed from static methods.
Static variables are variables which are shared across different objects of the same class.
Static variables will also be revisited in a later section where they will be discussed at a greater
detail.
A static method can directly access other static methods in the same class.
Since there are class level methods, they are invoked using a dot operator on the class name.
Main method is an example of a static method.
So static methods have nothing to do with the object state within the same class.
In fact, the methods which we wrote in our demo are also static methods and they are accessed directly
from the main method where main method is also a static method.
We could have defined instance methods instead of static methods, but to access those instance methods
from the main method, we would have to first create an object of the basics.
Demo class as main method is a static method and we cannot directly access static methods from the same
class.
So we would have to create an object of basics demo and using it we would have accessed those instance
methods.
But creating an object of basics demo is just some extra bit of code, and we are keeping it simple
with just using static methods.
Now let's go ahead and extend our currency converter class from the assignment.
Here we are in the currency converter class from our assignment.
Some of you might have skipped the assignment.
So let me just explain what we have in this class and in this demo.
We are going to extend this class.
So in this class we are first declaring a variable called US exchange rates, which is a double array.
And we also have this method called print currencies where we are printing the values in this array
and then we have the main method where we are instantiating this class and we are invoking this method.
So in this particular array, what we have is the exchange rates of different currencies relative to
1 USD, for instance.
The first one here corresponds to Indian rupee.
So what it means is 1 USD is equivalent to ₹63.
Similarly, for instance, here 107 is the Japanese yen.
So 1 USD equals 107?
Yes.
So here we have different currency exchange rates of different countries.
And within the print currencies method, we are simply printing these values.
So for instance, for rupee, we are printing the value at index zero.
And for dirham this is for our hum.
So we are printing the value at one.
Similarly for Australian we are printing the last value.
This is the one.
But instead of using six, we are using the length field and we are subtracting one here in order to
print this particular value.
So we just wanted to use the landfill.
So in the demo we are simply creating a double array and we are printing the individual values.
So that's what we wanted to test and that's what this class does.
So this class is still incomplete and it can be extended mainly such kind of a class will be useful
in money transfer services like PayPal, for instance.
Let's say if you are in the United States and if you want to transfer some money, like $1,000 to say
some local bank in India, then you would use a service like PayPal.
And PayPal would use this kind of a class in order to convert those $1,000 into Indian rupees.
So it would use this exchange rate and it would multiply it with 1000 in order to get the converted
value and Indian rupees.
So that's the background.
One of the things that we have said is the instance methods can manipulate state.
So here we have this instance method and let's go ahead and write a couple of more instance methods.
So first let me run this program here.
So I'm in the basics directory.
So this class is in the basics directory.
So here it prints the values.
Now, just note that here we are instantiating currency converter.
And we said that in order to access an instance method, we need to use the object reference.
So that's why we have the object reference followed by a dot.
Now if you do not use it.
Ed gives us a compilation error.
Because Maine is a non is a static method.
And from static method we cannot access any state related stuff.
So print currency is an instance method and we cannot reference it from from a static method.
So we need to have the.
Object reference in order to access the instance method.
Now here.
We have these values now.
Let's say initially it's null.
Let's say it is null.
If we are not initializing it, it's null and we will try to set those values from here.
So let me copy it here and let me write a new method called set exchange rates.
And using that we will initialize the exchange rates variable.
And let's define this variable called rates here.
It has to be an array.
So this is a matter of definition.
So to this set exchange rates, we are going to pass this.
So let's call this as.
Rates itself.
It can be any name.
And that's a c c dot.
Pastor Rich now with this.
So when control comes here, set exchange rates would be involved and these rates will be passed and
the rates here will be assigned to exchange rates.
So that's how we are going to initialize exchange rates.
So let me just compile this.
So it prints all the values and we are good.
So initially this was null, but using this instance method, we are manipulating the state and we are
changing it from null to these values.
So let's go ahead and change it one more time.
Let's say this is on January 1st, so exchange rates would be computed once every day.
So let's say that was on Jan first and.
Let's say on June 2nd, we have a different set of values.
So we have the same rates here.
So let's just change this to 65 and maybe this to 500.
The rest of them are same, or they might change.
But let's leave it like that.
Now here it's giving some error.
And can you guess what the reason is?
The reason is because this is an assignment statement and in an assignment statement you cannot initialize
the array in this way we have to use.
This notation, because this kind of the simplest way applies only in a declaration statement.
And you may recall it from an earlier lecture.
So it needs to be like this.
Here you go.
So when it was invoked for the first time, these were the values on the second time, on the second
day, the values of Ruby and Ram got updated to 65 and the RAM from 3 to 5.
And we are printing the the updated values.
So as you can see, the state of the object has been updated.
So initially the state was null, then we updated it to the first set of values and then on the second
day we are updating once again with new set of values, but we are using the same object reference.
So the state in the object reference has been changed from null to these values and from these values
it has been changed once again using the set exchange rates method.
So that's how we can manipulate the state from the instance methods.
Now let's try another method to update just a single value.
So let's call it an update.
Update exchange rate and let's update only a single element.
So let's declare a variable called index and let's update it with a new one.
Let's say some mistake happened and it was not set correctly.
So we want to update that particular element.
So here it is, exchange rates off our index.
So this would be the specific element and we are updating with the new value.
Now let's go ahead and invoke this method.
It's.
Let's call it a date exchange rate singular.
Let's say we want to update the value of rupee, which is an index zero, and we want to say update
it to 66.
That's what we have.
So let's go ahead and print these values.
Okay.
So we are passing the values zero.
Which corresponds to rupee.
So that gets assigned to our index and the new value is 66.
So that gets assigned to here.
And so we are updating the value at zero position with the new value.
So that must be clear.
Clear the screen.
And there you go.
So it is 6 to 6 now from 65.
It got incremental to 66.
So that's the only thing that we incremented.
Now, let's also write a couple of methods.
More methods.
So one of them.
So here we are updating.
Now let's fetch a value, let's say.
Let's call it.
That's double and let's get an exchange rate.
For a particular.
Country.
So here.
It would be exchange rates of this array index.
So if you pass zero, it would return the value at index position zero.
Now let's also declare.
Let's make it a little bit more realistic.
Let's assume that a money transfer service like PayPal would be using it.
So let's say we want to transfer a certain amount of US dollars.
So for that, we can declare this variable called compute.
Transfer amount.
And let's have this other index.
And let's define a variable called amount.
So this is like the US dollars.
And here we want to compute, let's say if 1000 is passed here, which is thousand.
So we want to let's say if zero is passed here, which is for Indian currency, then we want to compute
the the transfer amount.
So we need this amount thousand.
It needs to be multiplied with the exchange rates of this index.
But instead of using this, let's use this method called get exchange rate.
Okay.
Now, so this is for computing transfer amount.
So we are invoking the compute transfer amount, which is an instance method, and that method is in
turn invoking the get exchange rate.
So if we are passing zero on 1000, so we want to convert 1,000 USD into rupees.
So 1000 is multiplied here, so thousand gets assigned to amount and that we are multiplying with get
exchange rate.
So we are invoking the get exchange rate method and passing this array index as this.
And that would return the exchange rate corresponding to this index, the value at that particular index,
which would be like 66.
And then we are multiplying it and then we are returning it.
So here, in order to access this method, we can access it directly.
But to access the first time, we have to use the object reference.
But from within this instance method, we can invoke other instance methods directly.
It's got to be close this amount.
Here you go.
So we get 6 to 6000 because we are passing $1,000 and it's ₹4 and rupee is 66 and we get that final
amount.
So that's with the instance methods.
And for static methods, we have already seen static methods in the last in the previous demo.
So where we declared this method called a sum which computes the sum of two numbers.
So it's a static variable.
Here it is.
Now, as we mentioned, it only works on the method parameters.
It doesn't access any instance variables.
So it is just taking these parameters and completing the sum and returning the sum.
So that's how static methods work.
So they are mainly for utility methods, they service utility methods.
And here also this method average is is invoking this sum method.
So that's about static methods.
And static methods will be discussed later also along with static variables.
Now just for example here, let's say if I make this static, static void print currency is static and
it is accessing instance variables here and that should not be possible.
So let me just compile and show it to you.
So it says that non static variable exchange rates cannot be referenced from a static context.
So we cannot access an instance variable from a static method.
Now if we make this static.
Then it would be fine.
So it compiles fine.
And in fact, it runs fine too.
So both the method as well as the variable is static.
So that's good.
Now next question you might ask is from here.
This is a static method and we are accessing a static variable, which is good.
But here we have instance methods and these instance methods are accessing the static variables.
So that is possible because static stuff, any static stuff is global, which is accessible across all
of the objects.
So here this is an instance method and it belongs to a particular object and it can access any static
stuff.
So from this instance method, you can access static variables or static methods.
It's just that from a static method you cannot access instance stuff.
That's because instance stuff is specific to objects from an instance method.
Once again, from an instance method, you can access static stuff because static stuff is global and
is shared across all objects.
But from an static method you cannot access instance stuff because instances, instance stuff is specific
to a particular objects.
So that should be clear.
But we will get back to both static methods and static variables in a subsequent section.
So that's about it.
And this code will also be available in the resources section.
But I would advise you to type in everything.
But for this particular file, if it is saved as dot text and the resource section, just convert it
to dot java extension and you should be able to compile and run it.
Thank you and see you in the next lecture.