Now let's look at break statement.
We have already seen it's used with switch statements.
Now let's see how it can be used with loops like far and while.
A Brecht statement is used to exit immediately and closing switch or a loop.
Like for or while or while.
So any statements immediately following the break statement are not executed.
Let's look at a few examples where break is used.
Here is a simple four loop template with a break statement.
In this case, the break statement would simply exit the FA loop and the control would continue with
the statement following the furlough.
Not that this would happen.
Even if the envelope did not complete all of its iterations.
So once you hit a break statement, any subsequent iterations would be skipped.
Here's another follow up containing an EFF statement and the break is inside the EFF statement.
Even in this case, Brick would simply exit the envelope.
So it is not exiting the if statement, but still the enclosed first statement.
Now, this is how typically you would see brake statements being used.
That is, you would have a four or a while loop and then there would be some if statement nested inside
it.
And when the if condition becomes true in one of the iterations, then you would break out of the loop
without having to complete the rest of the iterations.
So that kind of flow is dictated by the business logic.
But in case of switch, it is different.
We use it at the end of a case block so that the control would exit the entire switch statement itself.
Otherwise, we know that subsequent case blocks would be executed until it breaks and content.
And here's a nested loop.
We mentioned that break would exit immediately and closing switch or a loop statement.
So in this case, the brake would exit the inner far loop and then the control would continue with the
statement following the inner loop.
Here we have a switch statement nested inside for loop.
So going by the definition, the break would exit the switch statement.
So brake will always exit the innermost switch or a loop statement.
Just note that in all of these examples we may as well use wild loops instead of furloughs.
So with a while loop, the break statement would break out of the loop without rechecking the while
condition.
So a brief statement basically exits the end closing loop abruptly, regardless of whether it is a for
loop or a while loop or a do y loop.
Here is an invalid example where brake is inside an if statement.
That is there is no enclosing switch or a loop.
So a brake statement needs to be within a switch or a loop statement.
Otherwise we get a compiler error as in this particular example.
We saw that in case of nested statements, brake always exits the immediately and closing switch or
a loop.
How about if you want to exit from one of the outer switch or a loop instead of the immediately and
closing one?
For this we can use a labeled break.
For this, we need to first label the block of code from which we want to exit using a break.
This block of code could be the order for statement in case of nested for loop.
A label here is simply any valid Java identifier and it needs to be followed by a column which is in
turn followed by a block statement.
No block statement is a new term here.
We discussed about the three different statement types.
But block statement was not part of it.
So let's take a few moments to discuss about it.
A blog statement is sometimes simply referred to as a block.
It is basically a statement and it contains zero or more statements and closed in curly braces.
Some programming languages refer to such a block as a compound statement, as it typically would contain
at least two statements.
Any controlled flow statement with braces is a block statement here.
In this statement, we say that there are two blocks, the block and the block.
Another example would be an initial riser, which will be discussed later.
The statement in a blog are executed sequentially and a block can be nested to that is it can have other
blocks inside it just like the nested for loops.
So basically we can label any block statement.
So once we have labeled a block statement, in order to break out of it, we use a labeled break where
the keyword break is followed by the label name.
Now here in our example, we can see that a block statement can be an if statement too.
And what does that mean?
It means that a label break can be used with an F statement.
That is, you can do something like this where there is no enclose switch or a loop.
But as I mentioned earlier, this is not possible.
So an unlabeled brick cannot be used with an F statement, but a label brick can be used.
Let's not do a short demo of label break.
We will write a new method called Label Break.
In our basic demo class.
So let's hop on to our editor now.
Look, here is the label break method.
So let's just go ahead and fill up this method.
Here we are declaring a variable called NUM, which is initialized to zero and we are printing its value.
So now let's just go ahead and add a for loop, a nested loop, and within the nested loop we'll be
incrementing num.
And finally, its value will be printed and we will be mainly testing the labeled break.
So let's just go ahead and put a nested four.
So here is the outer for.
So Ultra is iterating for ten times.
Let's have a new variable J.
Let's make it iterate for ten times to.
Now let's increment num here.
So now Numb will get incremented 100 times because the inner loop is going to iterate for a total of
100 times.
For each outer iteration, it's going to iterate ten times.
So now let's put a condition here.
Say A equals five and J equals five.
In this case.
Let's break.
Let's put braces to.
So in this case, the break would break out of the loop.
But let's break out of the outer furlough.
So let's label it here.
Let's call it as outermost.
So that's the label.
And let's break out of the.
Outermost four OC.
So in this case, since we are saying that IE is equal to five and j equal to five, this number get
incremented to 55 and that's when it would break because here we are saying I equal to five.
So for all the previous values from 0 to 4, which is total of five, for all of those five iterations,
the inner for loop is going to iterate ten times, so it's going to be 50.
And then when I is equal to five, J is going to iterate for five times and when it reaches, when it
hits five, it's going to go into this if statement and the break statement would get executed.
So it would be another five times during the last iteration.
After that, it's going to break out of the outer loop and the value of 55 would get printed.
So let's just go ahead and compile and run this.
As you can see, it's printing 55.
So that's the label break statement.
It's going to play.
We are going to break out of the outer furlough.
So just go ahead and you can find this, the updated basics demo program in the resources section and
you can download and you can you can also test it.
Test it out.
So let's just head back to the slides now.
Now here is an invalid example of a label break.
Here label one is used with a nested first statement and it also includes a valid labeled break.
Now Label two is also used within a state first statement.
However, the contained label break is referencing label one and not label two.
So this is invalid and it generates a compiler error.
So the label used with a break statement must be the label of the block in which the break statement
appears.
So we cannot have such cross references.
So that's about it.
So a break statement is used to break out of the immediately and closing switch or a loop statement.
If you have to break out of a switch or loop, which is not immediately enclosing, then you can make
use of labeled break.
So that's about it with the break statement.
Thank you.