Hi there.
This is Jayaraman and welcome back.
So far, we looked at a method invoking another method for accomplishing something.
Now let's look at a method invoking itself in order to accomplish something.
And we refer to this as recursion, which is an interesting as well as an important programming technique.
So the method that invokes itself is also referred to as a recursive method, and we refer to such an
invocation call as a recursive call.
So when a method invokes itself, it essentially means that the method is actually executing again.
And during that execution, it may make another recursive call.
And so the method would execute once again.
So this process of re invoking itself and the method executing again can happen for a certain number
of times until a condition is met in one of the executions, one of the executions of the method.
And with that, recursion would stop.
And with such recursion, what we get is a compact and elegant code.
That is, the code is very easy to understand.
Now, only certain kinds of problems can be implemented using recursion, and those kinds of problems
can also be implemented using a non recursive way where loops such as while and far can be used.
That's because with recursion we have this repetitive invocation of the method so that repetitiveness
can also be simulated using loops such as while or firm.
But when implemented in a non recursive way, what we get is a complex code.
So what recursion is buying us is clearly expressed code and we will see this shortly in a demo.
Now we know that a method call would address some problem.
But with recursion, when a method invokes itself, it would be to address a sub problem.
That is, the problem would still remain the same, but the input data for that particular instance
of method execution would typically be a smaller subset.
So with each recursive invocation, the problem gets smaller and smaller until it cannot be made any
more smaller.
At which point we say that we reached a base case.
So this is the condition that would satisfy in one of the method invocations.
That's what I was mentioning earlier.
So when the base case is reached, recursion stops.
And Factorial is a typical example that is used when introducing recursion.
Here we have four factorial, which we know is four times, three times two times one.
And more generally we would have this for n factorial.
It would be n times and minus one times and minus two and so on until we get to one.
And this can be expressed as end times and minus one factorial.
As you can see, we have a recursive representation here.
That is when NW is replaced with NW minus one, we would get NW minus one times and minus two factorial
and next with NW minus two factorial we would get NW minus two times and minus three factorial and this
would continue until we get to one times zero factorial.
Now let's go ahead and actually implement this factorial functionality using recursion.
For this demo.
A new class called Recursion has been created within the basics directory, so you can also go ahead
and create this class called recursion within your basic directory.
For this demo, I'm going to show this in my Eclipse editor.
So I'll be executing this program from within Eclipse.
And if you're using the regular text editor, you can compile and execute it from the command prompt.
So we are going to implement factorial using both non recursive as well as recursive approach.
That way we can see how the code looks more readable using the recursive approach.
So for both of them we'll have two different methods.
First, let's look at the non recursive approach and the method has been named as factorial and R where
an R stands for non recursive and the method is implemented.
So we are just going to look at that.
But after that we are going to implement the recursive approach using this method called factorial.
Now here the input is end, which means that we need to compute and factorial.
So this non recursive approach uses a while loop for implementing it.
Here the first thing that we are doing is we are checking if the input MN is either zero or one.
If it is either zero or one, we would return the value one because zero factorial or one factorial
is one.
Now if it is something other than that, then this condition would fail.
Now, the assumption here is that we are only going to pass a positive value.
So the value has to be either zero or greater than zero.
It cannot be negative.
So if it is something other than zero and one, then we are coming here and we are assigning MN to this
temporary variable called factorial and the factorial is computed here.
So we are using a while loop and the condition is and greater than or equal to two.
And we do this iteration and with each iteration we are also incrementing and so we do that until and
reaches two.
If an is four, then we would we would iterate this until and becomes two.
And in each iteration we are computing the factorial.
Here we are saying factorial times and minus one.
So that's how factorial is going to be computed.
So if it is four, it would be four times, three times two times one, right?
So initially, let's just take an example and let's look at it.
So initially, let's assume the value that is passed is four.
So we need to compute four factorial, which is 24.
So here again would be four.
So factorial would be four here.
And within the loop here, because the condition is true for greater than or equal to two.
So this would be four times and minus one.
So it would be four times three, which is equal to 12, and we are incrementing an to three.
So next in the next iteration, three would be greater than or equal to two, which is true.
And here the current value of factorial is 12.
So now it would be 12 times three minus one, which is two and here and would be limited to two and
this would be 24 here.
So factorial is 24.
The current value of factorial and two is greater than or equal to two, which is also true.
So in the next iteration it would be 24 times two minus one, which is one.
So this would be 24 and would become one.
After that the condition would fail and we would exit the loop and we would return the current value
of factorial, which is 24.
So that's factorial.
And.
Now let's look at the recursive version.
So we know that it has to be and times factorial.
So this is a recursive call and minus one and let's just say written.
And let's run it and see what happens.
Now, both of these methods are invoked from the main.
First, let me run that factorial and ah so this factorial and are of four is being invoked from within
the println statement here.
So let me run it.
So it returns 24 for one and is equal to four.
Now, let's see what happens if we invoke the recursive version.
As you can see, we are getting an error called Stack Overflow Error.
So this is what we are getting when we are invoking the recursive version.
This 24 here is for the non recursive version, the value returned by that.
So Stack Overflow error.
Now let me just explain this concept called a stack and stack frame, but we will be looking at it in
detail in the JVM internal section.
So here we are just going to discuss it very briefly just to give you an idea.
So when JVM starts up, it gets a chunk of memory from the operating system, and part of that memory
is called as stack stack space.
Now the stack space, it has some limited amount.
Now, when a method is invoked like this, let's say a factorial of four, then something called a stack
frame.
Stack frame is different from stack.
So a stack frame would be created and it would be stored in stack.
Stack frame goes into stack.
So for factorial or for a stack frame would be created and it would go on the stack.
Now here factorial.
Okay.
We are to be factorial of four.
And that in turn is making this invocation factorial of three and four that a new stack frame would
be created and that would be stored on top of the previous stack frame, which was created for factorial
of four.
So factorial of three is there.
So we it gets a new stack frame and when factorial three gets executed in the next iteration, it would
be factorial of two and that would result in creation of yet another stack frame on the stack.
So there are three stack frames now.
So factorial of two will would be invoked again and that will result in a call of factorial of one.
And then we will have factorial of zero, factorial of minus one, and that's never stopping here.
So it's like an infinite invocation at some point.
So all these stack frames are getting stacked on the stack and the stack has limited memory, and we
would run out of space and ultimately we would get this error called Stack Overflow error because the
stack is getting overflow.
So the problem here is there is no base condition.
So we need to put a base condition so that recursion would stop.
And in our case, the base condition would be and is equal to zero.
At that point it would be zero factorial and we would return one.
So this is what it is.
And now it would.
There is a closure to it.
And so if we run it, so we get 24.
So let's actually look at this.
So initially, let's say an is equal to four.
So it would be N times.
Factorial off and minus one, right?
It would be three times three, four times factorial of four minus one, which is three and factorial
of three, gets invoked at this point.
So nothing is being returned here.
It's just that return is there, but it is n times factorial of three, so in which case the control.
So there is this recursive call and the method would be executed once again with this value three.
So with that the method executes again.
And so we would come here and it would be three times factorial of two.
Okay.
And this would correspond to.
Two times factorial of one.
And in the next loop it would be.
One time factorial of zero, and when factorial of zero is invoked and would be zero and the base case
would be true and a one would be written.
So when one is written this that one.
The factorial of zero is returning one.
So we would have one here.
And so this is one and this is getting returned here, right?
So it essentially means factorial of one.
So that is nothing but factorial of one.
So that is what is happening.
So we are saying in the next statement we will have returned.
Two into one.
So when this is returned, it would replace factorial of two with the value that is written with this
two, and this would correspond to six now and six would be returned, which means that factorial of
three would be would be replaced with six.
And now we are in the first invocation and that would be 24 and finally 24 would be written.
So with each invocation, the method is getting invoked.
And finally, when the base is reached, when the base case is reached, you know, the entire process
would go backwards until we reach the first invocation and then we would return that value.
And the method stops and the method completes its execution.
Okay.
So that's the recursive call.
And as you can see, the code is the code is much more cleaner.
So if you look at both of these implementations, the recursive version is much more cleaner as we can
clearly see, whereas the non recursive version has all of this.
So with recursion, what we get is a cleaner code, we get a cleaner code, but it would be slightly
slower because we have all of these with each call where a stack is being created.
And so that would take up some time and it would also take up some space.
Also for each invocation, a new stack frame is being created so that that involves both time as well
as space.
And so it is a little bit inefficient, but the code is much more cleaner now and much more clearer
now, and that is what we need.
Sometimes we can compromise efficiency if we if the code is much more readable and that's what we get
from recursion.
So that's about that.
So the next question is when do we use recursion?
Recursion cannot be used for all kinds of problems.
It comes into play only if the problem can be addressed.
We are similar sub problems like in this case where each invocation, where there is this problem where
we have to find factorial of and but that can be addressed via factorial off and minus one, which is
a sub problem and that can be in turn address using factorial of and minus two.
So if that's the kind of problem that we are dealing with, then we can use recursion.
And here are a few example problems that require recursion and there are many more.
But these are some simple examples that you may be aware of.
One is the binary search, which is about searching for an element in a list of elements, and the next
is Towers of Hanoi.
So if you have a computer science background, you might have come across this in your data structures
class, which can also be solved using recursion, and the next one is word frequency count.
So if you have a document and if you want to search for a particular word and also you want to search
how many times that word is appearing in the document, then it can be implemented in a recursive way.
So we have looked at factorial.
Now let's also look at binary search quickly because binary search is a basic interview problem.
And moreover, if we also look at this, it will give you a better understanding about recursion.
So with binary search, we are searching for an element among a list of elements.
Let's say we have these set of elements here and they are all for binary search.
The requirement is that the elements have to be sorted first, so which means that they need to be in
ascending order.
In this case, they are all in ascending order.
So that's the requirement.
Now, if you do not use binary search, the way to implement it is using a linear search, which means
that you would search each of these elements and check if the element that you are searching for appears
anywhere in the list.
So you will scan the entire list.
Now, if you have million elements, you will scan the million elements.
In the worst case in the in the worst case, you would scan all of the million elements and you wouldn't
find your element.
So that we call it as a linear search and the algorithm efficiency for that would be off.
And we say that it is linear.
Now with binary search, it's going to be much more efficient because of the algorithm itself.
And there the efficiency, the algorithm efficiency, we say that it is logarithmic so it will be big
or off log n so binary search is more efficient than linear search and let's see how it works.
So here we have eight elements.
Let's say the first invocation is this binary search of a a is nothing but the array and zero is nothing
but the zero index and eight is the last index.
So there are nine elements.
We are passing eight and this is the element that needs to be searched and the binary search would return
if the element is present anywhere here in this case it is present here, then it would return the index
position of that element.
So that would be 501, two, three, four and five.
But if the element is not found, then it would return a minus one.
So it's going to return the index value here.
And essentially what binary search does is it does not scan the entire the entire array, so it only
scans certain areas of the array.
And that's why it is much more efficient.
And the way it does is once you invoke this, the first thing it does is it computes the middle.
The area, which is nothing but zero plus eight by two, which is nothing but four.
So it computes the the value four.
So zero is the lower element, lower index and eight is the higher index.
So now later we are going to fill this method.
So the method signature is also here.
The first element is a, the second is lower index, higher index and the key to search.
So it will be eight plus two by a zero plus eight by two, which is four at that.
Next, we will check if this if the element at this index, whether it is the which is whether it is
the key.
So the element at four position four is 55, which is not equal to 65.
Had it been the same element, if if this was 65, then the method would have retained this particular
index as the output.
But since it is not the case next it will check whether whether the key is greater than or less than
55.
In this case, 65.
Our key that we are searching is greater than 55, which means that it has to appear only in this part
of the array so we can ignore all of the elements that appear before 55.
And that's what gives us the efficiency.
That's what that's what makes the binary search faster.
So we are skipping all of these elements and we are focusing only on this part.
So which means that.
We can make a recursive call now and we'll just say binary search.
And we need to pass the era and we need to pass the indexes.
So the mid was for here this was the Met.
But since the element is greater than this, it's got to be from here.
So for lower we will pass mid plus one and for higher we would just pass whatever we have here, which
is eight and the element will be passed again.
So this plus one is nothing but fine.
So this is the next recursive call and for this we would once again compute med.
So it would be five plus 813 by two, which would be six, it would be 6.5, but truncate it to six.
So next we are going to look at a of six, which is nothing but this 171 and we are comparing it with
65 and 65 is less than that.
So which means that we need to look at only this area.
So in the earlier we constrained ourself to this part.
But now with this invocation, since 65 is less than 71, it cannot be part of this.
So it has to be only in this area, which means that our next call would be something like this.
Binary search of a.
And it has to be the leftmost part.
So in this case, lower would be same.
So we will still have five.
And the upper part would be mid minus one.
So earlier mid was here.
So it would be mid minus one.
So mid was six.
So mid minus one will be five and we will also pass 65.
Now once again.
So this is what we have now with this invocation.
Both lower and higher are equal and that would be our base case.
If lower and higher are same, then we have to stop our recursion and we will check if the element at
this position five whether it is 65 OC and in our case at the elementary 60 at the position file is
indeed 65.
So we would return that particular value.
So that's what is happening.
And when we return the so we would return the value five.
So but if it was not 65, then it would have returned minus one.
So that's how the algorithm would work.
Now let's just go ahead and quickly code up this one.
So it should be interesting.
So we have the method here.
I just need to fill this.
So this one would have a logarithmic efficiency.
And so first thing is, let's write the base case.
So we have L and our indices.
So we'll check if L is equal to H.
If that's the case, then we need to check if our key is equal to A of L.
That's how l.
Or it doesn't matter if it is same, then we need to return the index.
L Right, because we found our element as we would return minus one.
Okay.
Now, if that's not the case, it means that we are supposed to make a recursive call.
First, we need to compute the middle element, which would be L plus H by to make sure the parentheses
is there.
Because otherwise, without the parentheses, this would get higher precedence.
It would be H by two and then it will be added to L.
So we need the parentheses here.
Now we are going to check if a.
If our key is equals to a off med.
Then we return met.
And if key is greater than.
A med, then we can skip the left part of the array and we can.
We can only search for the upper part of the area which is from med plus one.
So we would say binary search.
So in the new invocation, lower element has to be made plus one.
So we need to pass plus one and the higher would be the same one.
So whatever we have higher, higher index, we just pass the same one and we also pass the key.
Now, the final one is if.
If this also fails, which means that key is less than a mid.
Then we we have to scan only the lower part of the array.
So we would say return.
A lower part of the area.
For the lower part, the lower index would be the same index that we have.
L and the higher index in the next iteration it would be mid minus one and it would be key.
So this is what we have.
So this is the default.
So if both of these fails, then we get to the default one where key is less than a off.
So this is what we have.
Let's go ahead and execute it.
So let me just copy all of this into the main method.
And this one returns the index.
So let me say index equals this.
So let me just run this.
So it has to print the index value as fine.
Now, if you pass, let's say 34 here.
It would print three because 34 is appearing at the third position.
Similarly, if you pass 100, which is not there, it has to return minus one.
So minus one is being written.
So that's all there is to binary search.
So it's much more efficient and compared to factorial.
Here we have having two invocations, but only in a given execution of the method.
Only one of them would be invoked.
So it is slightly different here.
But in for example, for towards of NOI, we would also make two invocations something similar to this.
But there we wouldn't have such kind of an F condition.
So both of the invocations would be executed and it, it would work in a slightly different way.
So that's it.
And so we now have a good idea about how recursion would work, and that's about it.
And this code will be available in the resources section.
Thank you and happy coding.