Hello there.
This is the De La Rue.
And welcome back.
Now let's learn about another fundamental construct of a class called US constructor.
As the name suggests, it has something to do with constructing something and that something is an object.
So constructors are all about constructing or creating objects.
But we have already been doing that with our student class.
We have been creating our constructing objects.
So there is this thing called constructor within the student class.
The thing is, we were dealing with constructors implicitly.
That is a compiler was creating the constructor for us and we were using it implicitly.
So everything was happening implicitly.
So when we compile our class, the compiler was automatically inserting a constructor into the bytecode
and we were using it to.
Now generally the main purpose of a constructor is to initialize the state of the object, that is to
initialize the instance variables of the class.
It can also do other things, but the main purpose is to initialize the state.
That is what constructors normally do.
Now in our student example, we were initializing state.
We are the object reference.
Right.
So we are saying object reference dot and the field name to initialize the field.
But this is not the right way to do it.
And the right way would be to initialize state via constructor.
So for that, we need to define a constructor in our class and that would help with both object creation
and initializing state.
So the initialization statements will be part of that constructor.
Now a constructor is just a block of code, like a method, but with some differences, as we will soon
see.
So in this lecture we are going to learn about constructors.
Now, before looking at the syntax of a constructor, let's consider our student object creation statement
as we are using a constructor here.
So we are going to look at that.
Now we know that this particular statement has three parts in it.
We discussed about that and each of those parts tell JVM to do something.
Let's look at the three parts once again.
So this part tells GM to allocate space for a reference variable.
And this part tells GM to allocate space for a new student object.
And finally, the assignment operator assigns the memory address of the student object to the variable
s and this particular fragment.
And the second step is actually an invocation of the constructor.
Notice that we are using the term invocation, just like in the case of methods as constructors are
similar to methods and hence we can see the parentheses following the class name.
This fragment essentially executes the constructor code.
The second step here does three things.
First is it creates an object in memory.
Then it invokes the object's constructor.
And finally it returns the memory address of the created object.
And here is the syntax of a constructor.
It has the same name as the class syntax.
It looks very similar to a method like methods.
It can optionally have parameters.
And the main difference is that constructor doesn't have a written type.
And like methods, a constructor can also have a var parameter.
And here's an example class definition with a constructor that has a single parameter.
As you can see, the constructor has the same name as the class.
The class has a single instance variable ID which is initialized to its default zero and the constructor
has a single statement which is re initializing the ID field to a new value and the new value is passed
as an argument to the constructor.
So basically the object state is being initialized in the constructor.
And here's the new student object creation statement with a value of 1001 is passed as an argument to
the constructor.
So the ID field will be re initialized to 2001.
So instead of doing this to initialize state, we are now using a constructor and this is how it needs
to be done.
Now if we do not provide a constructor in our class, then on compilation the compiler automatically
inserts a default constructor.
So this is what was happening all this time with our student class.
And the default constructor doesn't have any parameters.
Now, since it doesn't have any parameters, the default constructor is also referred to as a new ARX
constructor.
So this is a term that you will be frequently using or you will be frequently encountering.
Note that this would happen only if the class definition does not include a constructor.
But if the class includes a constructor and that constructor can be a constructor, or it can also have
parameters.
But in that case, the compiler will not insert the default constructor.
So keep that in mind as this is something that you may forget.
And here's an example where the class definition does not have a constructor.
So when we compile the class, the compiler inserts say No, our constructor into the bytecode.
And this allows us to create an object by invoking the No Arks constructor, which is what happened
with the student objects that we created.
And here is an example with the constructor.
So in this case, as mentioned earlier, the compiler will not insert a default constructor.
So here we can create an object by invoking the given constructor.
But we cannot create an object by invoking a no ARX constructor.
Now, if you want to do that, then you would have to manually add a NOx constructor.
So basically the compiler will not auto insert a default constructor for us.
And since constructors do not have a return type, they can not return any value, just like methods
with avoid return type.
However, like we see here, they can still have an empty return statement.
That is the return keyword followed by a semicolon.
Now, when this statement gets executed, the control immediately returns from the constructor.
So the control returns from the constructor.
Now, if we have any code immediately following the return statement, then it is unreachable and we
will get a compilation error and we would have to fix that.
I think in practice it would be pretty rare to have such a return statement in a constructor.
And here is an example where a written statement makes sense.
Now the code in the if statement executes if the condition is true and at the end we return the control
using a written statement.
In this case, the code following the if statement will not be executed.
But it is still reachable and valid and it would be executed when the condition in the if statement
is false.
So when condition is false, the body of F will not be executed and only the code following the if statement
will execute.
Note that we can also have such empty return statements in a method which have void as written type,
and it is perhaps more common to see such statements in a method rather than in constructors.
So that's an introduction to constructors.
A constructor is used in the context of creating an object and is almost always used to initialize object
state, although it might also do other things.
Now let's go ahead and extend our student class by adding a constructor and initializing the state.
We are that constructor.
Here we are in the student class and before we define our new constructor, that takes parameters and
initializes the object state.
Let's add a new constructor and let's make sure that it doesn't make any difference in the output.
So currently we do not have any constructor and we know that the compiler adds a default, no constructor.
And so by adding a new constructor, it shouldn't make any difference in the output.
First, let's go ahead and run our program the way it is.
So let's just look at the output once again.
So here I am in the basics directory and it's already compiled and the compiler must have added a default.
No constructor.
So let's just execute this.
And here it is.
So we have the three student objects that got created and their state is being printed.
So let's go ahead and add a new ARX constructor.
Let's add it here right after the instance variables.
So the constructor name is the class name, which is student, and there is no return type as we know.
And no ARX constructor does not have any parameters and it's an empty body that's about it.
So the compiler would add something similar in the bytecode.
Now let's go ahead and compile this.
So it's just the same output.
So this is a no constructor.
Now let's go ahead and extend this constructor and make it into a parameterized constructor.
And this constructor will help us initialize the state.
So let's do that.
So we are calling it as a parameter based constructor because it has parameters.
So let's go ahead and add all of these parameters and let's call it a new ID.
Let's add them in the same order.
New name.
New Age.
I'm just calling them as new age, new gender and so on.
But later, we'll come back and change this names in a different lecture when we are going to learn
about a new concept.
Next is long new phone, double new GPA.
And the final one is international.
And let's call it as.
Ease International.
It doesn't matter later we are going to change this anyway.
So let's indent it.
And here we are going to initialize.
One, two, three, four.
Our variables are ID equal to new ID.
Name will get the value of a new name.
New gender.
And I hope you are also typing this along with me.
If not, please do so.
H.
Which phone?
Finally, international is equal to is international.
So all of the variables have been initialized now.
So they got their defaults and now we are initializing them with the values that are getting passed
into the constructor.
So that's our parameter constructor.
Now the next thing to do is to invoke this constructor.
So here and we are just going to pass in the same order thousand.
Be for bachelors and false as John is not an international student.
So let me just delete all of this.
So we don't need this because we are using the constructor to initialize the state and I would like
you to do the same thing for the second and the third object two.
So just pause the video and do it.
And I will come back and I will show you the.
The completed statements.
Here are the completed statements.
So we have the second student object and the third one.
So let's just go ahead and compile and execute it.
There you go.
So we have the same output.
And now the the object state is initialized via the new constructor.
So we don't have all of those initialization statements anymore.
So that's something new and interesting.
Okay.
So that's good.
So we have our first constructor and it is helping us to initialize the state.
So it's a parameter constructor.
Now we said that if we have a constructor, then the compiler is not going to add a default constructor,
right?
So the next thing is let's go ahead and test that.
And to test that, what we are going to do is so we will remove the state information from here and
we will make an invocation of a no ARX constructor, which is not there because the compiler is not
going to add.
So it should give us a compilation error.
So let's see what the error says.
It says constructor student and class student cannot be applied to different types.
So this is what we have.
And it says that the constructor is having these parameters.
That's the required.
But what you are doing is you are not passing any arguments.
So the actual and formal argument lists differ in length.
So you may remember this terminology from our methods lecture.
So formal argument list is nothing but the constructor parameters and actual is what we are passing.
So the differ in length because here we have empty.
Whereas in the constructor we have some number of parameters.
So that's the thing.
So we cannot do that.
So what we need to do is we either have to pass this state or the fixes to add a new constructor.
So let's do that.
So compile fine.
And if we execute it, so it executes fine.
So for the first and the second object, we are invoking the first constructor.
But for Anita, we are invoking the second one, the No Arcs constructor.
And we can see that only the default values are getting printed because there is no re initializing
that is happening for Anita.
There is no re initializing that is happening for Anita because we are not invoking this particular
constructor for her.
So that's why for name it's the default null, gender, null, id zero.
And for everything we have the default zero.
So.
But that's not what we want.
We do want to pass the state.
So let's add it back.
But let's leave it like this.
Let's also have the new constructor and we can see that we have two constructors now and that's nothing
but constructor overloading and that's the subject of the next lecture.
But we are not yet done with this lecture.
So we still have something more to look at.
So we have the two constructors.
Now the thing, next thing that we are going to do is we will actually invoke the compute method from
here.
So from a constructor, we can also invoke a method.
And let's remove these statements here because we don't need them anymore.
So the compute method is computing the fees.
The final fees and the final fees can be adjusted.
It can be modified if it is an international student.
That's it.
So let's go ahead.
So we're invoking the compute method from here.
Here is where the tuition fees is getting recalculated.
Recompile.
We execute.
So everything works fine for the student.
Non international student is 12,000 for the last two students it is 17,000 because they are international
students.
So we can invoke methods from constructors.
That's one thing.
And the final thing that I want to show is the constructors cannot return any value, but they can have
empty written statements.
The same goes with methods with void, return type.
So we have this this method which has void return type.
So let me just show it here.
So here, let's add a written statement here.
That's it.
And what should happen?
We get a compilation error at line 42 because line 42 is here.
So this is the statement after this, the compute method the control would return from.
Compute method should return from compute method.
But then there is no point in having these statements because they are unreachable.
So that's what the compilation statement says.
That line number 42, the statement at line 42 here is unreachable.
So we discussed this earlier.
So that doesn't make sense now, but we can have it here.
Now, this means that if the student is non international, which is John.
So for him this block will we know will not execute this entire F block and only these statements will
execute and it will be printed.
But for Raj and Anita, international is true.
So the fees will get recalculated and when it comes here, the control would return and for them the
state will not be printed.
Right?
So this is perfectly fine.
So let's go ahead and look at the output.
So as you can see, only the state information for John is getting printed for Roger Anita.
The state is there.
It's just that it's not getting printed because the control is being returned from this empty written
statement.
So you would see such a return statement.
It is more common to see here in a void method, but in constructors it is relatively, I should say
it should be very rare because generally we have only object state initialization within the constructors,
but methods we can have a lot of business logic so we can encounter such written statements in a method,
but it's not that common in constructors.
Now let's go ahead and remove this whole thing, move everything into the constructor.
Here.
Let's just keep it like this.
Instead of having a compute method.
So all it does is just recalculating the fees.
That's all it does.
Now, only thing is the compute count is here.
So the compute count is a static variable.
And we, we were using it to track the number of times the compute method was being invoked.
Now, since the compute method is not there, we do not need it, but we can use it to track the number
of times a constructor is being invoked, which is nothing but the number of objects that are getting
created since we are creating three objects.
Finally, this has to be three, but the name is Compute Count, so let's change it to student count.
More makes more sense.
So it's student count.
Let me just copy it.
So every time a constructor is invoked, the student count also gets incremented.
And we are also printing it here.
And finally, we are also printing it here once because it is a static variable.
We are using the class name to access it, so it should print three.
I think we still have the written statement.
So let me just comment this out here.
Now it will print.
There you go.
So we have all three objects and their state is getting printed.
And the student count.
Here it is.
One, two and three.
And the student dot student count is also printing three.
So that's all there is.
So we define our student constructor here.
So this is a parameter constructor, our first constructor, and we are now initializing our state using
a constructor.
Thank you.
And I hope you have enjoyed learning about constructors and I will see you in the next lecture.