Hello there.
This is Lulu and welcome back.
So we know that a constructor helps in constructing objects and it can also help in initializing state
of those objects.
In the last lecture, we refactored our student class to define a parameter constructor which helped
with creating student objects and also initializing their state.
In student class, we defined a single constructor, but a class can also have multiple constructors
and if there are multiple constructors they will all have the same constructor name as a constructor
has the same name as the class name.
So what we have is one or more constructors with same name but different parameters and that's nothing
but constructor overloading.
So we have overloaded constructors and it is similar to method overloading where we have multiple methods
in the same class having same method name but different parameter lists.
Providing such overloaded constructors makes it convenient for clients to construct objects.
And soon we will look at an example.
So let's go ahead and learn about constructor overloading.
Constructor overloading, as I just mentioned, a similar to method overloading.
So we have the same overloading rules as methods.
That is, the constructors must have different parameter lists.
Otherwise we would have duplicate constructors and would get a compilation error.
And objects can be created using any of the overloaded constructors.
And why do we need overloaded constructors?
As I mentioned earlier, the reason is convenience.
They make it convenient for clients to construct objects.
That is the help in having simpler object creation statements.
Let's look at an example from the Java Library.
So this is from a class called as file output stream, which we will discuss later.
And this class is helpful if you want to write some data to a particular file on the disk.
And as we can see, this class has five overloaded constructors and they have different parameters.
Now let's consider the fourth constructor, which has two parameters file here as simply another class
in the Java library.
And let's not worry about it and we will look at it later.
But it simply represents the file into which we want to write our data.
And second parameter is to indicate whether we want to append data to the file or overwrite the file.
So if the file already exists on the desk and you simply want to open data to it, that is, you want
to write some data at the end of the file, then you would pass it true for the second parameter.
But if you want to overwrite the contents of the file, then you would pass a false.
Note that if the file does not exist on the desk, then this constructor would create a new file.
So if there is a file called blood or TCD and you want to simply overwrite its contents, then you would
create a file output stream object in this way.
As we can see in the first argument, we are creating a file object corresponding to blood or text and
then we are passing a false for the second argument.
Now, instead of doing this, we can actually use the second constructor, which is provided only for
overwriting.
So if we use this constructor, we would create our file output stream object in this way.
And as we can see, it is much more simpler and we just pass the file name so we don't have to create
the file object.
And there is no boolean argument that we need to pass.
However, this constructor internally invokes the fourth constructor and passes the file object for
the file and passes a false for the append parameter.
So this constructor is simply delegating to the fourth constructor.
So the library designers have provided the second constructor so that we can easily create our objects.
Similarly, if we want to append data, we can invoke the first constructor and pass it through for
the second parameter.
First parameter is for file name and using this constructor is convenient than using the fourth one
as we don't have to create a file object.
And this constructor also internally delegates to the fourth one.
So sometimes we can have this sort of overloaded constructor where there is a primary constructor like
the fourth one and others simply delegate to it.
However, we can also have overloaded constructors where there is no such delegation and the constructors
are completely independent of each other.
And there is a class called tree map in the Java library which has such overloaded constructors that
are independent from each other.
However, even in tree maps case, the constructors still provide the convenience factor that is, without
them, extra code would have to be written to construct tree map objects.
Tree map will be discussed later in the Collections Framework section and it is a class in the Java
library.
Now as we can see here, the constructors also are associated with certain capability.
That is the help in constructing objects, having certain capability.
For instance, the second constructor helps in creating objects that can help in overwriting file contents.
Similarly, first constructor can be used to construct objects that can help with appending data to
the end of the files.
So each constructor is helping in constructing objects with certain capability or property.
For the second constructor, the capability is overriding, and for the first constructor, the capability
is appending.
But that need not be the case all the time.
That is, objects created from the different overloaded constructors can have the same capability to.
But that's not very common.
But that's possible.
For instance, let's say the program has only partial data available.
That is, it has only values for some of the instance variables.
In which case we may have a constructor only for those variables and for the remaining variables we
get default values.
But if we have all of the data, then we can have a constructor that takes all of the values, and that
would be the primary constructor.
Now, let's go ahead and fire up our editor and add an overloaded constructor in our student class.
Here we are in the student class.
And if you recall from the previous lecture, we already have overloaded constructors in this class.
So we defined our parameterized constructor here, which was initializing the object state.
And at one point we also created a new ARX constructor.
So this was added to just show that the compiler does not add a default constructor if there is already
a constructor in the class.
So we had this constructor and we did not have this.
So what we did was for to the third student object, we removed all of these arguments.
So it was invoking a no ARX constructor, which was not there in the class.
So when we compiled it, the compiler gave us an error.
And so to fix it, we added this new constructor, right?
And then we added the state back.
So all of the three student objects are using the first constructor.
So we already have overloaded constructors and this is not being used anywhere.
But let's just leave it as it is.
It is harmless now for all three students.
We are using the same constructor.
The first student is non international and the second and third are international students.
Now let's do this.
Let's create a new constructor just for non international students and we will use that for non international
students and for international students we will use this constructor.
The only difference is we will not have this particular constructor parameter for the new constructor,
for the new overloaded constructor.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Let's just copy this.
So let's make it the first constructor.
So at this time we have two constructors.
And they have the same parameters.
All right.
So let's also remove this one here.
This is not needed for the first constructor because it is for non international students and we don't
have to recalculate the tuition fees for them.
So at this point, both constructors still have the same parameter list and it should give us a compilation
error.
So because they are duplicate constructors.
See it says constructor student is already defined in class student This is at line 43.
So at line 43 is where the second constructor is starting and it says that this is going to be a duplicate
because there is already a constructor with the same parameter list.
So we cannot have it this way.
So we need to remove this.
And let's also remove this statement here, because that variable has just been deleted.
And this is good.
And here for John, who is a non international student, a local student, we will use the first constructor.
All right.
And for the second and third, they use the second constructor.
Here you go.
So for the first constructor, the tuition fee is for a local student, the tuition fee is 12,000.
For the international students, it is 17,000.
And that's what it is, because we are recalculating here and adding an additional fee for international
students.
So that's overloaded constructors for us.
Now here, just think that this particular software is being used as part of a some university web application.
And let's assume that there are two different screens, web pages, one for two, create accounts for
international student and another for non international students.
So if for a non international student, if an account is being created so there would be some form and
once the form is filled for the student, let's say it is John.
When we hit submit, all of that information will be sent to the web server because it's a web application.
And on the web server there would be some sort of a Java program which would take all of that information
and it will create a student object by invoking this particular constructor.
And then subsequently the data could be added into the database or whatever.
So that's one thing.
Similarly, there would be another form for international students and for a given student.
If once the information is added or is entered and submitted, the data will be sent to the web server
and the program would construct an object using this constructor so you can visualize it in that way.
Now here you can see that all of this code is also in the second here in the second constructor.
So there is code duplication.
Now, this is not good because it can give us maintenance issues.
Say if there is some change that needs to be made, then we need to make the change and both the constructors
and if we forget, then we can have issues.
Let me give you a couple of examples.
Example scenarios.
Let's say we want to there is a requirement to convert the names of the students to uppercase.
All of the characters have to be in uppercase.
So for that, there is a method called to uppercase in the string class and let's say the developer
does this later we will look at this method when we are dealing with strings.
So here it is.
And let's say the student has done it here, but he or she has forgotten to make that same change.
And this constructor.
So.
That will lead to some inconsistency.
So as you can see for.
Oh, sorry, I said lowercase.
Right, so let's make it uppercase.
So there is a method called uppercase for that.
And lowercase is for.
Four lowercase.
So for John it is in capitalized, but for Raj and Anita, it has been converted into uppercase.
So that's an issue.
So if we make any change, we need to make it at all of the places.
Right.
Now, let's also let me also show you another example.
Let's say if the GPA is greater than, let's say 3.5, then we want to give a discount of $1,000.
So let's do that.
For that, we will use another if statement and we will say if this GPA here is greater than 3.5.
Then we will say.
Tuition fees -1000.
So this greater than symbol is a relational operator.
And we will look at that in the in the next section.
So let's say the developer has added this over here and has forgotten end to add it in the in the first
constructor.
So naturally when we compile.
So we can see that.
Let me just show you the objects here so we can see that for John, the GPA is greater than 3.5.
For Raj, it is 3.4.
So for any tie it is perfect 4.0.
So for both John and Anita, there should be a discount of 1000 and not for Raj.
But if you look at the output for John, he's not getting any discount because the developer has forgotten
to add that logic in the corresponding constructor.
But Raj, there is no discount.
So it is 17,000, but for Anita it is 16,000.
So she gets a discount, but not John.
So those are the sort of issues that we can have if we have duplicate code.
So let me just remove this also.
We don't need this.
So what we need to do is we need to invoke because everything is same in both the constructors.
We need to invoke the second constructor from the first constructor and this is what we did, this is
what happened.
And with the file output stream class, so we discuss that that the control is delegated to from one
constructor to another.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So for that, all we will do is we will say this this indicates the same object.
And because it's a constructor, we will have an invocation.
So we use something called this invocation statement to invoke an overloaded constructor.
So you're not going to say we're not going to use the class name here, but we will use this keyword
here.
So this is called us at this invocation statement.
So if you use student, that would be invalid.
So it has to be this invocation statement and then we will just pass whatever is being passed here.
So we will just add all of these.
Parameters.
So let me just copy that.
Okay.
We just need to remove the types here.
So in an invocation statement, you will never have types, so we need to remove that.
So we are just relaying whatever we are receiving.
Right.
But this one accepts bullion.
So that's the last one.
So we will just pass false, right?
Because this constructor is for non international students and for non international students it is
a false.
So this is what we are doing.
So we removed that logic of discount.
So that's why we don't see that that discount anymore.
So this is what we need to do.
So this here, this acts like a primary constructor.
So we have seen that with the file output stream also.
Now, there are certain rules that we need to remember when it comes to this invocation statement.
So keep them in mind and probably make a note of them.
So within a constructor, this invocation statement has to be the first statement.
So, for instance, we cannot have another statement here.
Let's say, for instance, cannot have something like ain't I is equal to any statement, it doesn't
matter.
So if we have this as the first one, then we get a compilation error.
All right.
See, it's this call to this must be first statement and constructor.
So that's not possible.
So that's the first one.
It's got to be the first statement.
And you cannot also have more than one this invocation within a constructor.
So once again, we will get a compilation error here.
Call to this must be the first statement in constructor.
So it shows at line 22, which is where it is.
So you cannot this is not possible.
So let's remove that.
Now, the next thing is so two of them.
One is it needs to be the first one.
And the second one, you can have only one within a constructor.
So the second one is actually a byproduct of the first one.
Now, here, we cannot invoke the same constructor.
There cannot be a recursive invocation, they call it as a recursive invocation.
So, for instance, if we remove this, it's essentially a call to the same constructor.
So that would be meaningless, right?
Because you call it.
And then once again, the control comes here and then it gets called again.
So the loop never ends.
So that is wrong.
So that's called as a recursive invocation, and that's not feasible and that's not allowed.
So it says recursive constructor invocation.
So that's not possible.
So that's one way of having a recursive invocation.
A second way would be for this constructor to invoke this one and for this to invoke this one.
So that's an indirect recursive invocation, and that's also not possible.
Let's also test that one.
And this is this has to invoke the first one and it does not how this parameter.
You say it says recursive constructor invocation at line 17.
So.
So that's not possible.
So we need to remove that.
And the final one, which I want to show is.
Here.
So we are passing all the method parameters that we are receiving.
But you cannot include an instance variable here.
Let's say it is an instance variable.
It's not a local variable, it's defined here.
So you cannot have an instance variable in this invocation statement.
The reason for that is this variable is not yet initialized at this instance.
So at this instance, what is happening is the control is getting passed here, right?
We are calling this and from here before this statement gets executed, what happens is there is something
called a superclass and the superclass also has a constructor and that constructor gets invoked.
So this superclass is something that we will discuss when we are discussing about this concept called
us inheritance.
So which will which we will discuss later, a few sections from here.
So it's a very important object oriented concept.
So when we are dealing with inheritance, we have this notion of superclass and subclass.
So this is like a subclass and then there is a superclass.
It's like a parent class.
So what happens is when control comes here, the parent class also has a constructor just as this particular
subclass.
And once the control comes here, the control moves into the superclass constructor.
And at that instance, all of the instance variables in the superclass and all of the entire superclass
constructor will be executed.
And then the control comes to the subclass, which is this one, and all of these variables get initialized
to their defaults and then the control comes here.
So there is an implicit call to the superclass constructor, but you may ask, where is the superclass
here?
The thing is there is a superclass and it is implicit.
So first thing is let me just compile this.
Let me just show you the error itself.
You see it says cannot reference ID before super type constructor has been called.
So super type constructor has not yet been called at this point.
It is it will be called here.
So once the control comes here, the super type constructor will be invoked.
Super type is nothing but the superclass or the parent class.
So there is a parent, there is a superclass involved here and it is being used implicitly.
And that class is called us.
The object class.
The name of the class itself is object.
And we will look at the object class later after discussing inheritance.
So that's something related to inheritance.
So I just wanted to highlight the fact that we cannot pass an instance variable.
So it's got to be these constructor parameters or it can be a literal like this.
Or if you have something like String or any other object, any other class, then you can create an
object here and pass an object here, an instance of that class.
So that is possible, just like the way we are passing this particular literal.
So the only thing is you cannot pass a.
Instance variable.
So if you if if it is confusing when we are talking about the superclass and subclass, just don't worry.
It's just to let you know that we cannot pass this.
But it should be clear when we get to the concept of superclass and subclass will be clear when we get
to the inheritance concept.
So what that means is this is not the end of our discussion on constructors.
So when we get to inheritance we will revisit this topic and we are going to talk about that.
Invoke invoking of super superclass constructor from subclass.
It's called as constructor chaining.
So at that point we will get back to this constructors once again.
So that's that.
And finally, I just want to show the file output stream class.
So this is the file output stream class and this is my eclipse ID.
So this is from the Java library.
And let me just click here and here we can see all of the overloaded constructors that we have seen
in the slide.
So we discussed about this one.
This was also we discussed.
So let's look at this.
This is for overwriting.
So as you can see here, also, it is using this invocation statement and there are two arguments.
So you can ignore this syntax here.
So but this is for the first argument.
And for the second argument, we are passing a false implying that we want to just override the contents.
And let's look at the other constructor, which this one is invoking.
So we just hit F three for that.
And this is the constructor.
This was the fourth constructor in the slide.
So this is the primary constructor.
And that constructor is invoking this.
Similarly, there is also another constructor, this one which is also invoking this one, and that's
for appending.
So we discussed this.
So but I still wanted to show that even these classes are invoking the constructor, using this invocation
statement.
So that's about it.
Thank you.
And I hope you enjoyed learning about overloaded constructors and I will see you in the next lecture.