Hello there.
This is Lou.
And welcome back.
You may recall that when we first defined this parameter as constructor, I mentioned that we are going
to come back and change these constructor parameter names and it's time to do that.
It is a bit odd to have these sort of names like new ID, new name, new gender and so on.
It is actually a bit challenging to come up with these names because these names had to be different
from these instance variable names as these variables are being used to initialize the instance variables,
right?
The values that these variables hold will be assigned here.
So we had to come up with some names that are different from the instance, variable names, and so
it's a bit challenging.
So these are odd looking names, but in reality we can use the same names as these instance variable
names.
So let's go ahead and do that and let's see what happens.
And in the process we will learn about a new keyword.
So let's do that.
Let's do that first here in the second constructor.
So it would be I'd.
Name.
And this one is international.
So it did not have that keyword new.
And we need to change these also because we no longer have those variable names.
And International.
Right.
So the names have been changed.
Now, in the main method, we are creating these student objects.
And let me also add some new statements here.
Then we put a new line here just so that we can distinguish this statement.
And here, let's just print the name of each of the student objects.
So let's call this.
Name of student one So this would be student one.
Dot name.
Actually let me copy this one here.
You replaced this.
Just so that it'll be easy to change student to.
Okay.
That's it.
So let's go ahead and compile and run this.
Okay.
So here you can see that.
Within the constructor.
It is printing the name John, Raj and Anita.
But here with the new statements that we just added, it is still printing now, so it is not printing
the state information.
So what is happening here?
So here both these ID variables are referencing this ID.
So this particular ID is not referencing the instance variable ID.
So because of that, all of these variables are not getting initialized.
And so here it is printing the default value of name, which is none.
So the reason for that is because here this these variables here these are local variables.
And these local variables have the same name as the instance variables.
Recall that when we consider a method, these method parameters are also local variables.
Similarly with constructors also the constructor parameters are also considered as local variables of
that particular constructor.
And this is also a local variable, but the constructor parameters are also local variables.
So next ID is a local variable which is declared within the constructor.
But the constructor parameters are also local variables.
Now here what is happening is we are using the same names as the instance variable names.
So if local variable names have the same names as the instance variable names, then we say that those
local variables are hiding or shadowing the instance variables, or they can be static variables to.
But generally you will see them hiding the instance variables.
So when we say that they are hiding the instance variables, what it means is if we use that variable
name within the constructor, then it would reference the local variable rather than the instance variable
or the static variable declared at the class level.
So these variables are hiding this or shadowing these variables.
So that's the reason why the use of these variables are referencing local variables.
So how can we access the instance variable?
And for that we used something called this reference because it is a reference.
We can use the dot operator here and with that this ID variable will be initialized.
Now notice that I'm calling it as this reference.
Here we have this invocation.
So that is something different because we are invoking an overloaded constructor.
But this one is this reference and I'm calling it as a reference.
So the question would be, what is it referencing?
It is referencing the current object.
Now we know about object reference, right?
Here we have three object references.
Student one, student two and student three.
Student one, for example, is referencing the student object, right?
So this is an object reference and it is referencing the student object.
And within the object, let's say within the student object.
If we want to reference that particular object itself, the current object itself, then we would use
this reference.
So for instance, within the student object, if we consider the constructor code or any of the instance
methods, right, we can also access instance methods via the object reference.
Student one Earlier we used to have the compute method, so that was an instance method.
So if you are inside such an instance method, so if that instance method is executing, then within
that instance method you can reference that particular object, the current object using the this reference
or inside a constructor.
So that is what this reference is.
So what we need to do is we have to use this here, so let's do that.
So earlier the same local variable was getting initialized with itself.
So which is sort of meaningless.
And we don't have to do that for tuition fees because tuition fees is not hidden by any of the variables.
So tuition fees is is not hidden and hence it can be accessed directly.
It is also an also an instance variable and international fees is also an internet is also an instance
variable.
But both these variables are not hidden by any of these local variables and hence they can be accessed
directly.
Okay.
Now, here.
We can leave them as it is, or we can add.
We can also access them this way.
Otherwise, it's just going to access the local variables.
So for next ID, it's just a local variable.
So you cannot use this reference here because it is declared here.
So for tuition fees, we don't need that.
And this can be used to access a static variable to student count as a static variable.
But you don't do that.
Normally you would just use it only to access hidden variables.
That's it.
Now let's just go ahead and compile and execute it.
As you can see now, it is printing the names John, Roger and Anita.
So the instance variables got initialized this way, this time.
So that's what this reference is.
So this reference, you will use it to access any hidden variables, hidden or shadowed variables.
Shadow is another term that is used and it can be used to access static variables to.
But that is very uncommon.
Or you may never even do that.
So typically it is used to access only hidden instance variables and you can also use it because it's
just a reference.
You can also use it to access instance methods also, but once again you wouldn't do that.
So typically you can directly access the instance methods.
There is no reason why you need to use this because they are not hidden.
So it is only used useful for accessing hidden variables and those variables that are not hidden like
tuition fees, you can access them directly and these variables typically you will see them being exe
being used here in constructors, but you can also use them in methods also.
So let's just define one method called.
Update profile.
You may recall from the very first lecture we mentioned about this method, having this method in the
student class.
So we are introducing it now.
So we will say a string name and we want to update the name.
So will just say this dot name equals to the name.
So this is a method and let's just return a default of true.
So what we will do is we will just change this to Joanne.
Let's assume that the user has entered a wrong name.
And we need to correct it.
So here we will say.
Student one dot.
Update profile.
So Student has realized that he has entered his name incorrectly, so he comes here and updates it from
the update screen and somehow this particular statement gets executed and we will just print it.
I think we don't need this.
And here.
Let's say.
Updated name of student one.
Okay.
And here it has to print.
So here it will print Joanne.
And here it will print John.
So.
So initially it printed Joanne and now once it got updated, it printed the correct student name, which
is John.
And the next thing is this.
This is actually an instance variable and it is allowing us to access instance variables and also instance
methods.
So this cannot be used within a static method.
So in this class we have this static method called main.
We can also have other static methods.
But within the static method, we cannot use this reference because from static method we cannot access
any instance stuff.
And this is an instance variable.
It's a, it's a reference instance variable, which is an object reference, but a reference to the
current object.
So we cannot use that.
So if we compile this, you can, we can see the output, the error message.
So it says non static variable this.
So non static means instance variable.
This cannot be referenced from a static context.
So it highlights the error that we cannot use it.
So it calls the static method as a static context.
So we cannot do this.
So it's, it has to be.
Student one.
So that's it.
And just keep in mind that this and this are different.
This is an invocation statement and we are invoking an overloaded constructor and this is a reference
variable object reference, but a reference to the current object.
So these are two different things.
And since it is an object reference, we are able to use the DOT operator and since this is an invocation
statement, we are invoking a constructor.
Let's also change this for here.
Also, let me just copy all of these.
And replace this, that it's much more simpler.
And let's go ahead and change these also.
So that's the last update.
So with each.
Enhancement.
We are simplifying our code.
Right.
That said so.
Now let's compile.
Let's ensure everything is running fine.
Okay.
So everything is perfect.
So that's all there is.
So we have learned about this reference here and it is helping us to initialize the state and it is
useful for accessing hidden variables.
Alright, thank you and I hope you enjoyed learning about this reference and I will see you in the next
lecture.