Hello there.
This is the Domaine de la Rue.
And welcome back.
Now, I would like to spend a few more minutes on ensuring that we really have a firm understanding
on how object references behave when they are reassigned with other object references or with entirely
new objects.
Essentially, we want to study the memory state when such reassignments happen.
And this is related to pass by value mechanism, which we discussed earlier.
We know that in Java data is passed to methods via pass by value mechanism.
And we also said that it would be the same with assignment statements, but with assignment statements
we may get into situations where the same object reference is reassigned multiple times with different
object references.
And we need to be clear about how that affects the memory state.
So I think it will be really good if we spend a few more minutes on this particular topic as it is really
fundamental and there is no point moving ahead without a firm grasp on this particular topic.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So this is the student class and we are creating the student objects here.
Right now, if you recall our first lecture of this section, we discussed about having two classes.
One is the student class and also another class called Student Test.
And from the student test, we would create the student objects.
So let's just do the same thing now.
So we are at the very end of doing that.
So so far we had only student class.
So let's create a new class called Student Test in the same directory called basics.
I already did that.
So I have this class called student test and all we will do is we will move this entire code.
Look the main method.
Into the student test.
So this is what we have and this is what we are going to run now.
And it should all work in the same way.
Now, one thing I want to tell is I have deleted the dot class file of student, so there is no student
class.
But when we compile this particular class, so the compiler will see if student class exists because
we have this statement where we are accessing the student class.
Now, if class does not exist, then it will automatically compile student cluster.
So it's going to compile student class and then it will compile student test.
But if the dot class file exists, then it's not going to do.
It's not going to compile it.
But it would compile a student class once again.
Only if some change has been made in the student source code.
So even if you have a class file, but after the class file has been generated, if you make any changes
in the student class in the source code, then it would still recompile that class.
So it depends on that time stamp.
So now at this point, the student class class is not there.
So let's just compile the student test and it will all and it will also compile student Java.
So I'm here in the basics directory.
So it compile let me just show you the basics directory so it compiles student test OC and we can see
that it also compiled student plus.
So that's the thing.
And this can be student test or it can also be named as something like student admissions.
So that's a class that would create student accounts.
I think that it is part of some admissions office or admissions software, and it is responsible for
creating student objects or student accounts.
So that's the thing now.
So this is what we have.
So for this demo, I'm going to copy some code here.
I have some code.
So in the interest of time, we are just going to look at this code and analyze the code.
And discuss it and.
And said so let me just copy it here.
Let me just indent it properly.
So this is what we have.
And.
So here we are creating the three student objects and we are printing their names.
And here John was initially misspelled as Joanne.
So we are updating the profile of the student object and we are updating it to John here.
So let me make it caps and we are printing the name and here is the new code.
So let's go ahead and look at what we have now for this demo you can ignore.
For now you can ignore the student object, the third student object, and we will just use the student
objects one and two.
And we have a new student object called Student four.
So this is the first statement here.
So let me just do this.
Let me just comment this and let me also comment.
Discord here because.
This is a lot of statements and in the output we would have to scroll a lot in order to see this new
text that we are printing.
So that's why I'm just commenting it out so that it is easy to follow.
So here the first thing that we are doing is we are assigning student one to this new variable called
student four.
So student one is holding a reference to student object.
So it's not holding student object, but it is holding the memory address of the student object.
And now when we assign in this way, it's going to make a copy of the memory address that student one
is holding, and that address will be assigned to.
Student four Right.
So at this point, both Student four and Student one will point to the first student object whose name
is John.
So in the next statement, we are printing the name using student four and it should print John because
that's the student object.
So let's do that.
Lets me recompile this.
Here it is.
So this is the new statement and it is printing, John.
So that's the thing.
So now we have to object to Francis pointing to the same object.
Now.
Since two four is also pointing to the same object as student one If we make any change, we are.
Student four That change will be reflected if we access that particular state using.
Student one So here we are invoking the update profile method on student four and we are updating the
name of the student from John to Mike.
And in the next statement here we are printing the name of the student, but we are printing it.
We are.
Student one So if we do that, the name would be printed as my right.
As you can see it is Mike.
In the previous statement it was John but using the student for we updated the name of the student to
Mike but we are printing it.
We are.
Student one And it is printing.
Mike So that is as expected.
Now in the next statement we are re assigning student for vet student to.
So earlier, both student.
Student four was initialized with student one.
Now student four is re initialized with student two.
So which means that the first object is referenced by only student one which is Mike with the updated
name.
Now Student four and student two would now reference the second object.
So what we are doing is student two is referencing the second object here, which is Raj.
So the memory address that Student two is holding, which is of this object, a copy of that is made
and is assigned to Student four.
So at this point, the first object is referenced by only student one, whereas the second object is
now referenced by both.
Student four and student two When we print the name using student four, it should print.
Raj.
As you can see, it is Printing Ranch.
So that's the reassignment of student for which student two.
Now here what we are doing is student two is now being reassigned with student one.
So at this instance, both student two and Student one are pointing to Mike, which is the first object
and student for, well, 10.2, Rach.
So because of this reassignment, don't assume that student four will also point to, to the first object,
which is Mike.
So that is not going to happen.
So at this instance, Student two was assigned to two.
Student four.
So the memory address that student two was holding is assigned to.
Student four a copy of that.
So both Student four and Student two were referencing the second object, right?
But here, Student two is reassigned with student one the copy of the memory address that student one
is holding.
So both student two and student one will now reference the first object, which is Mike.
But Student four Will is still holding the same memory address that was assigned here.
So and that is referencing the second student object, which is Ruch.
So this first statement here will print, right?
Because we are saying student four name and the next one will print.
Mike.
Let me just clear the screen.
There you go.
So.
Student four Still pointing to Raj and STUDENT two As pointing to Mike.
So both.
Student one STUDENT one Are pointing to Mike.
Now, finally, what I want to do is let's reassign student four to a brand new object.
So we are invoking this one.
No constructor in student class.
There is a new ARX constructor here, so we manually provided that, which means that all of the instance
variables will get their default values.
But what we are doing is we are invoking the update profile method so that the name will be reassigned
with whatever value we are passing here.
So we are passing Alex.
So Alex will be assigned to name and the rest of the fields will have default values.
So Student four is now referencing the new object called Alex.
So that's the thing.
And so that's so when we print student four dot name, it should print Alex.
Student two And student one are still referencing the first object, which is Mike.
And we will see what will happen to the the object that Student four was earlier referencing which is
off ranch so that we will discuss after looking at the output.
So as you can see here, STUDENT four is now referencing the new object, Alex and STUDENT one and Student
two are referencing Mike.
And the object that stood out that Raj was being referenced by, which was Student four.
So the Raj object does not have any references anymore.
So now we say that the object Raj is abandoned.
It is still on the heap.
It is still on the memory, but it is not being referenced by any of the object references.
So it is essentially a useless object.
It is just taking up space.
So we say that the object is abandoned or orphaned and we need to reclaim the memory.
Otherwise that memory will be wasted.
So that's where our beautiful garbage collector will come into play, GM's garbage collector.
And it will reclaim the space so that that particular space can be used by some other object.
So that's the automatic memory management.
And we will discuss all the details about garbage collection and the JVM internal section.
So Raj Object is abandoned here.
So that's about it.
So that's what I wanted to talk in this particular lecture.
So I hope the memory state was clear when all of these object visualizations were happening.
Now, I would like to give a small assignment here.
Let me just comment this entire code that we just discussed.
So it started from here.
So let's go back to where we started.
So this is what we had.
So we have three student objects.
Now, let me just create a simple array.
A student, R.A. And let's call it a students.
And let's initialize it with the three student objects, John.
Raj.
And the third one was Anita.
So this is what we have.
Now, what I want you to do is I want you to write the code, the code to swap these two elements.
So I want you to write the logic so that student three would come in, would be stored here in the,
in the zero eight index and student one will be stored in this index.
So I want you to do that.
So just pause the video and just try to spend a little bit of time on this.
And then you can come back and look at how the logic looks like.
I hope you have done it.
So let me show you how that can be done.
So the first thing is we will create a new student object called tem, an object reference.
What we will do is we will see student saw is 2/10 of zero here.
So at this point both temp as well as students of zero are referencing.
John Right.
Now what we will do is we will update this.
So the memory address of John is stored and temp and it is also in students of zero.
But since it is stored in temp, so we have like a backup so we can update it.
I mean, students of zero can be reassigned, right?
Can be reassigned with students off to.
So at this instance, both zero and two.
So which is this one?
And this one are referencing the last object, which is of Anita, which is referenced by students of
two.
And now we will say students of two.
So students of zero as student of zero.
Here, students of zero is now referencing Anita.
So as students of two.
So one thing is done.
So this is stored here.
Now we need to update students of two.
And for that we just say we have the memory address.
You know, the backup was taken.
So that's the temporary variable.
So that memory address is being assigned to students of two.
So at this point.
Let me print them.
So this would be students.
I hope it's clear now.
So let's just recompile here.
We need to see students of name here.
Dot name.
As you can see, Anita is in the zero eight position, is a student now and third student is John.
So we just swabbed them.
So that's how it is.
I hope it is clear now.
Now, one last thing that we can do is let's move this into a new method called swab.
Here we have done it in this way, but it would be just the same if we also write a method.
So let's write a static method for that.
Let's say static void.
Let's call it a swab.
And this method to this method, we will pass.
It will take a single parameter called students.
And instead of this, we will just say.
Slap of students.
It's just the exact same thing.
So it is demonstrating that we are able to demonstrate that it just works in the same way, whether
it is whether we are passing to a method or whether we are reassigning.
So here we will.
One sec.
So let me copy all of this here.
Students.
And let's pass the index numbers as zero and two.
Right.
But here, let's call them -- and let's say first.
Index and.
Second index.
So this first index will be this one zero at one.
And this is.
The second index will go here.
This is a sign with the temper.
So that's how we can write a generic method.
Okay.
So that's it.
So when we pass students here, it's an object reference, right?
Students is an object reference.
A copy of that memory address will be made and will be assigned to the students here and zero and two
will be passed and the swap happens and that will be reflected here because this variable here and this
parameter will reference the same student object.
So we don't have to return anything.
So so it's so we are just passing the memory address of the, of the object itself.
So we should still get the same result.
As you can see, Anita and John have been swapped.
So that's about it.
And I hope you now understand very clearly about how object reference reassignment will affect the memory
state.
If it is not clear, just spend a little bit more time on this particular program or on this lecture
and it should be clear.
Thank you.
And I hope you enjoyed learning about it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.
Happy coding.