Hi there.
This is the Domaine de la Rue.
And welcome back.
In this video, we are going to look at the solution for the exercise, along with at least one best
practice in implementing the solution.
So even if you have completed the solution correctly, it may still be useful for you to watch this
video because we are going to discuss that best practice.
I hope you were able to implement the solution correctly.
If not, this video should be really very helpful and it would surely reinforce the concepts that have
been learned so far.
In case you could not get started, then just don't worry.
You don't have to be disheartened by it.
And this discussion should be very helpful, since we are still at the very beginning stages of the
course.
It may take a few exercises for you to get comfortable with programming.
That can happen if you are entirely new to programming.
However, I'm hoping that you did try your best to implement the exercise as these exercises have been
designed to test what you have learned so far.
If you could not complete the exercise, then do implement it.
As we discussed the solution here.
The more you code, the more you will be comfortable with programming.
And for those of you who are able to complete the solution, like I said earlier, I would still recommend
to view the video as we will also discuss at least one best practice, especially in terms of implementing
constructors and that can be helpful.
So three things we are going to discuss here.
First is the correct solution.
Then we will also look at the best practice suggestion in terms of implementation, and we will also
look at common mistakes that students were making.
I must have looked at at least a few hundred solutions so far, and I could see some common mistakes
that were being made, and we can discuss them and that can help, help in avoiding such mistakes in
future.
So let's go ahead and look at what we have here.
So this is my Eclipse editor.
I'm showing it in my Eclipse editor.
And this is an instructor class.
So a template of this has been given to you and this is the book class.
So the book class was also provided to you.
So let's go ahead and look at the instructor class.
So these are the different fields here of the instructor.
So this is the idea of the instructor.
This will hold the name title department and the books that the instructor has written.
So the title here is the title of the instructor.
A few students were getting confused with this.
They were thinking that this is somehow related to the title of the book, and that's not the case.
This is the title of the instructor, which could be something like assistant professor or professor
or associate professor.
Now let's go ahead and look at the constructors.
So these are the four constructors we have.
So these are overloaded constructors and this is the one of the constructors.
And if you invoke this constructor it is going to invoke this constructor using the this invocation
statement.
So this particular the second constructor has four parameters and it is being invoked from this one.
And this in this particular constructor is invoked from here, and the final one is invoked from the
third one.
And in each of the constructors we are initializing one of the instance variables.
So constructors are used for initializing variables, the initializing the state.
But the way we are doing it is we are invoking the overloaded constructors in order to do that.
And in each of the overloaded constructors we are initializing one of the instance variables.
So that's what is happening here.
And this invocation statement, we call that it has to be the first statement in the constructor, if
at all.
We have this invocation statement in the constructor.
It needs to be the first one.
And in order to access the instance variables here we are using this reference.
Few students have got confused between this invocation and this reference and they are completely different.
This invocation is just to invoke an overloaded constructor and this reference is used for accessing
an instance variable and we would need it only if there is a local variable in the constructor which
is hiding the instance variable.
For instance, here we have books, so this is the constructor parameter and it is a local variable
and it is hiding or shadowing the books instance variable which is defined here.
It is an array of books.
So here, if you directly access books, it's going to refer to this particular local variable because
it is hiding the instance variable.
So it would offer this and if you want to access the instance variable, then you would have to use
the this reference.
So that's what we have here with the constructors and we will get back to constructors at the end when
we are discussing about the best practice.
Now here let's look at the methods now.
So this is the first method.
Get most recent book title and it returns a string.
So it is supposed to return the title of the last book stored in the books.
So here.
The code is going, the client code, the code that is invoking this class would create an instructor
object and is passing all of the state here.
And one of them is books and the books array has a bunch of books and we are supposed to return the
last element, which is considered as the most recent book that has been added into that particular
books.
Are it in order to return the last book?
We would say books dot length minus one and we need minus one because indexing an array starts from
zero.
So that's why we need to do that.
Had it started from one, we would have said books dot length, but since it starts from zero, we need
to say minus one.
If you just say bookstore length, then it would be outside the boundary of an array and it would return
a error.
So this one, this expression here essentially is returning the last book stored in the books.
So it is a book object.
And since we are supposed to return the title of the book, we are just invoking the get title method,
which would return a string.
So if you look at the book Java class, so this is the book class and this is the constructor and there
is only a single instance variable called title and we can set the title here and we can get the title
here, we can say get title and it would return the title of the book.
So you can do that or you can also directly access title feel.
You can say dot title here instead of accessing the get title method.
So you can also do that, but you shouldn't be doing it.
As we will learn later in one of the subsequent sections when we are dealing with information hiding.
So there we will see that we should always access the values, the values of the fields.
We are such kinds of methods.
These are called less access methods because we are going to access something, but we shouldn't be
accessing the fields directly.
And in order to prevent doing that, we use the private keyword.
But since we are at the beginning of the course, we are not going to get into private public on all
of those things which are called US access modifiers.
So this is just for your information that when we are accessing the state of a particular object, we
need to use access or methods like this instead of accessing the fields directly.
So that's just for your information.
So it's not a good practice to access the title field directly, and the title field should ideally
be declared as private.
Similarly, all of these fields should also be declared as private, but that is something that we will
study later.
So that's it.
Now, few students, many students actually did something like this.
They set books off to get title because they assumed that the books would always have only three books.
That's because in the problem description, I gave an example where the books that was getting passed
here was having three books, and they for some reason thought that it will it will always be like that.
So that's not the case.
That was just an example and it was also mentioned in the problem description.
So the books are read that gets passed, can have three books, can have 50 books or can have 100 books.
So you cannot do like this.
You cannot hardcoded the, the index value like this.
It's called as hard coding.
In programming terms, you shouldn't be doing that.
It has to be generic in this way.
So that's one of the common mistakes that few students made.
Now, let's look at the second method, the update book method.
So the update book method is taking these two parameters, index and title, and it needs to update
the title of the book at this particular index in the books.
So that's what the second statement is doing.
So we are saying books of index and we want to update the title.
So we are invoking the set title method and we are passing the new title.
So that's what Update book does.
But it has to return the title that was pre that was there before this update has been done.
And we need to return a book instance here.
Okay.
So what we are doing is we are creating a temporary variable and we are calling it as old book.
So the data type is book and we are creating a brand new object here and we are assigning the title
of the book at this particular index.
So we are saying books of index don't get title and the title is being assigned here it be it's being
stored in the book object.
And then after doing that, we are then updating the title of this book or in the second statement and
we are returning the old book.
So the old book essentially has the title of the book at this particular index before it got updated.
So that's all we are doing.
And we are using we are using a temporary variable.
Few students just had this these two statements and they were retaining the books index here.
But that would be incorrect because in that case, the object that is being written will have the new
title.
So that's not what we are expecting here.
So that is wrong.
So you need to use temporary variables in such scenarios if you want to store a value before it gets
updated.
So that's what you would do.
And the second thing was few students actually implemented it in this way.
So it's just a way in which they implemented, which is incorrect.
So the last two statements were right and they used a temporary variable back to the temporary variable.
Instead of creating a new object, they just assigned books of index.
So once you do that, we know that both books of index as well as old book will reference the same book
instance.
So when you update the the title here using books of index, it would also give you the same title.
If you say all books get title, which is what my test cases are doing because we are returning this
old book and when I do old book dot get title, it returns the title that got updated here.
Okay, so here we are having the same book object that is being referenced by two different variables.
One is books of index and one is all book.
And this is what we discussed during a pass by value mechanism when we in that particular lecture and
also in the lecture prior to the exercise.
So if you are still confused, just go back and look at those two lectures and it should be clear to
you.
So this is not what we need to do.
We need to create a brand new object, and then we need to set the title.
Okay.
So that's the thing.
And here is a second version of the same method.
So here what we are doing is the last two statements are the same.
But instead of invoking this particular constructor, which takes title as an argument, we are invoking
in No Ark constructor here.
So if you recall, I said that there might be some change that you need to make in the book class,
but it is not really required as shown by this particular method.
But the change that you can make is to introduce a new constructor here, and if you do that, you can
use this kind of logic.
So we are creating an empty book object and we are setting the title with the title of the book at this
particular index.
It's just a different way of implementing.
But for that, we do need to add the.
No R constructor here because the compiler is not going to add this.
We know that if there is no constructor within a class, then the compiler automatically inserts a no
constructor and that would be added into the byte code.
But if the class already has a constructor, then it's not going to do this.
So if at all, you need a new constructor in such a case, you need to add the constructor manually,
or you have to just invoke this particular constructor.
So that's the change, but it was not really required.
And finally, here is the third update book method.
The second update book method, which also returns the book, which has the old title.
So it takes an index and book.
And in this case we are creating a temporary variable, but we are assigning books of index, the book
that is at this index.
And then to that books of index, we are assigning the book that was that is passed into the method.
So at this instance, at this end, after the first statement, both old book as well as books of index
are referencing the same object.
But after this statement, Books of Index is referencing a new object which is referenced by book,
whereas the old book still references the old book object which was assigned to it through this statement.
So here we have two different book objects after this.
One of them is referenced by old book and the other one is referenced by books of index.
And we are returning the old book here.
So that said, that's what that I hope this is also clear.
So both the updated book methods are updating the books at this particular index, but the method methods
themselves, the written book instances that have the title before updating the title of the book at
this index before it got updated.
Now, few students have done this, like, for example, instead of books of index, they had it as
this book of index, which is really not required.
It's not wrong, but it's not required.
You would say this dot books when there is a local variable within this method which had the name,
which has the name books.
If that was the case, then that would hide the instance variable.
And in that case we can use the this reference.
But here, since there is no local variable called books, we can directly access the instance variable.
So that's one thing.
And finally, main method is also not needed.
But let me get to that later.
First, let me talk about the best practice, also one of the best practice.
So instead of declaring like this, we can actually do it in a slightly different way, which is the
normal convention.
So let me just copy this.
Okay.
So now what we are going to do is we have this box.
Let's also say copy this here.
I'd name all of the fields will be instantiated, will be initialized here.
And then we have this title.
And this dot department.
So all fields are initialized here.
And so this is like the primary constructor.
And we can still have these other constructors.
For instance, we can have this constructor here.
But this will invoke.
The first constructor.
And for department, it will it will also pass department.
But for books, it doesn't have books here because only four of the parameters are here.
It would pass some default value.
In this case we can pass null, so the same thing can be done for all of the constructors.
So for instance, we can also have both of these.
Let me just copy them.
This and this would be.
Title and it can either invoke this constructor or it can directly invoke the primary constructor to.
But if it invokes the primary constructor, it needs to pass values for department and books.
Once again, it can pass some default values like this and we can remove this.
And the same thing here.
You can test this out and it will give you the same result.
It's just a different way of initializing state so that set strings can be assigned null and that's
why we are passing now.
So all of these three constructors are just invoking this particular instructor constructor, which
is doing all of the initialization.
So all initialization is happening in one single constructor.
But here that was not the case.
So this in this particular constructor was initializing two fields and each of the other constructors
were invoking the an overloaded constructor, but were initializing only one of the fields.
So this one is initializing blocks.
This is department and this is title.
So the nice thing about this is all of them are done at one place.
So we will have all of the logic here and all the other constructors are invoking that.
So even in Java Library, many classes are written in this way.
So this is you can think of it as a convention, but strictly you don't have to follow this.
You can still do this, but this is the normal convention.
And so all of these different constructors will invoke this, but it need not be like that.
This can also invoke this and this can invoke that, invoke the primary constructor even.
That's possible.
And one other thing to note is just because we have overloaded constructors in this way, don't assume
that an overloaded constructor would invoke another constructor using this invocation that need not
be the case.
It's just that it is like this.
In this case, sometimes you may have overloaded constructors, but there wouldn't be any this invocation
statements between them.
So they will not invoke each other and they will be entirely independent of each other.
So you can also encounter such cases.
So that's one best practice convention to have a primary constructor and all other constructors invoking
it, and that's it.
And one other thing is you can see that there is no main method here.
So for the solution, if you are going to submit it, we don't need a main method.
Main method is needed only if you want to run, run it from the command line.
So that's mainly for testing purpose.
But in order to submit it into the platform as your solution, you really do not need main method.
So think of this class as being used as part of a larger program, things that think that there is some
university management system and that university management system has some kind of user interface where
you instructors will be registering into the site and when they register we will create an instance,
we will create an object of a particular instructor and we will further process it and store it in the
database or something like that.
Similarly, I have a test case that I have installed for testing this program.
You can also think of that the test case program, the unit test case program has that larger program
too.
So it is also going to create instances of these instructors and pass different values to these methods.
And if the expected output, if the output returned is same as the expected output, then it means that
the method has worked correctly.
Otherwise it will say that the method is incorrect.
So that's with that.
And if you have the main method also, you can think of it as the main method being that larger program
from which we are creating these instances of the instructor class.
So that's about it.
I hope you found this solution helpful and hopefully it will be helpful and solving the future exercises
too.
Thank you and happy coding.