Hi and welcome back.
This email because we are here for a very quick step which is just to create all the global fireballs.
The configuration of our model so that we can define it later.
So let's do it right now.
The first thing that we wanted to define is the size of the vocabulary so we get it by calling took
an idea that's vocab size then we will define the time it is that we want to use for all models so I
picked a limiting dimension of two hundredths the number of filters will be one hundred the number of
units in the feed forward thoughts will be 256 the number of classes we can just get it by calling the
length sets train levels.
So then let's define the drop rates all points to and the batch size which we will set to thirty.
And finally the number of epochs for our training phase let's say five so those are numbers that I found
worked quite well achieved good accuracy with them.
These are maybe not the best ones you can actually do a whole optimizing work with that but they work
pretty well.
And if you want to play with each other to improve the accuracy even more after training please do that.
So here we are.
And we're ready for our next step which is to finally create the objects and then and trainings.
So it's using.