Hello and welcome back to this tutorial.
Here we are.
Final step of all I propose processing.
We are almost ready to start building our translator.
We just have to do two final things.
First one is to pad all inputs and outputs which means that we want each sentence to the same length.
And the second one is just to create the data set to shuffle back and do all the things that are necessary
before using them as training sets.
So let's go.
We start by bypassing the inputs using TFA to cure us.
That's true processing that sequence that part sequences.
We want to put the inputs we want to use the value zero which is a value that is not used by the two
can either encoding.
So we are sure that it doesn't really corresponds to a word.
And anyway you will see later that the algorithm will not have access to those values because we will
use a mask that doesn't allow the attention mechanism to look at those spending values.
Now we just tell how we wanted to pad each sentence and the way we want to do this is costs which means
that we want to add the zero at the end of each sentence.
And finally Max Len will tell how long our sentences will be which is exactly what we used before.
Max van here we are.
Small spaces to make it clean.
And now that our inputs our is let's do the same thing with the outputs
outputs small white spaces to make it cleaner.
And of course this is the outputs that we want but so that's for the putting step.
And now final step let's create 0 data sets.
We will first decide of the budget size that we want to use.
Let's say 64 again this is something you can play with when you try to improve your translator emphasize
these would be Father shuffling of the data sets.
Let's set it to 20 thousands and this time to create our data sets data sets equals T F dots data that
data sets.
Woops that's that from.
That's from 10 so slices and the slice we use is simply inputs outputs.
Here we are.
We have a data sets.
Now in order to optimize it and to make it fully ready to be used by our training phase we will first
use these small two which is called data sets that cash.
This is just something that improves the way the data sets is stored and the way we can have access
to the data during the training.
These just increases the speed of the training but has nothing to do with the performance by itself
by the accuracy of the model.
So even if you don't use it it will have no impact on the performances.
Now let's just shuffle and batch these data sets so Let's shuffle with the buffer size we created before
and batch everything with this batch size and finally one last little thing that we can add to make
it even faster is these two data sets that fetch and stand out a way to use it is to use t after data
the experimental that's the tune.
So again this is the same thing as the cash two lines before it will just improve the speed of the training
because we can access to the data faster but that's all it does.
So here we are.
Now finally people says the data and have a data set that is ready to be used for training phase.
So now let's get to the fun parts and start building all our translator popularity.
See you soon.