Hello and welcome back to that one of course in our programming.
Congratulations on completing this section of course on our preparation.
And today we'll quickly recap on what we've learned.
All right.
So let's get right into it.
In this section we learned number one the factor of variable trap.
So we had a quick refresher on factors and we also saw that factors sometimes need to be converted into
numeric variables sometimes otherwhere and sometimes America variables age converge factors and that's
easy but when factors need to be converted to numerics you have to be careful not to accidentally pick
up the actual facts or factorisation value.
You need to pick up the value which is stored within the variable itself.
And we learn how to do that.
We learnt that you first need to do an intermediary step for instance convert the factor into a character
and then convert and numeric.
So that was a very interesting tutorial.
Next we had how to use a sub and sub functions for cleaning adorer.
So we had examples of fields where there were DOLLAR SIGNS commas or even words or spaces and we need
to get rid of them for our to successfully be able to recognize those fields as numerics.
So we learn how to do that with these two functions.
Next we're talking about methods for dealing with missing data.
And we covered off a few methods we covered off the role of missing data ignoring the missing effect
.
The data is missing and in some median imputation method we talked about factual analysis we talked
about calculating.
So we covered off quite a few methods and that's I think an important sub topic within data preparation
because inevitably in your career you're most likely going to deal of missing data and it's good to
have some sort of preparation in this sense.
Next we talked about the and so and these are a third logical concept.
And we went into the very fundamentals of it and and they.
So we saw sometimes people just know that it's there but we actually discussed why is the third logical
constant.
And we had a few examples of why you can compare names to names or to anything else.
And hopefully that will lay that great foundation for dealing with in ways going forward in your work
.
Our next we learn how to calculate missing how to locate missing data.
We use the complete case as function we had a very elegant blueprint for locating a missing data and
then we also learned the filtering techniques which include though which function.
And that is a function so as to which function to filter doorframes to find records which don't include
missing data and then we use the is in a function to filter doorframes to find records that do contain
missing data in the column that we're after.
Then we talked about the median imputation method and there was quite a few tutorials dedicated to this
method.
So we learnt we had a lot of hands on experience I'd say hands on practice with the median imputation
And hopefully now after this section you're very comes off it and not only you know how to replace missing
values with the median across a whole lot of frame.
You also now have a quite you should have a quite a good understanding of when to look for similarities
in a data set.
So for instance if you have columns like industry or maybe gender or something that categorical type
of where you can group your variables maybe that's something worth considering and splitting your daughter
said into those groups and then searching for the median within each group.
And that way you might be able to get more accurate results.
It's not always the case but sometimes it can help your analysis.
And finally we talked about the fact factual analysis and deriving of values and methods.
So once again we talked about how if you can predict something we're 100 percent certainty then it's
not actually missing data if you can predict that 100 percent certainty.
And also deriving values methods with is like a mathematical relationship.
We had a few examples of those when you can calculate a missing value based on other values in the data
frame.
And moreover you should also take that into consideration.
So you should take into consideration those mathematical relationships when using the median imputation
method because for instance we had example we have three values expenses revenue expenses and profit
.
And out of those three we would only use the median imputation for two.
And then for the third one we would have to use the deriving value method because otherwise our dataset
wouldn't add up and says things like that you should also take into consideration.
So there we go that is the section on data preparation.
Now we didn't cover off everything about our operation and that's because that is virtually impossible
to grasp.
In one course or even probably in a lifespan there's so much to data preparation.
But what my goal was for the section was to cover off all of the main fundamental basics that will give
you a taste for data progression and also give you some of those blueprints so that when you walk into
a project where operations required you really have somewhere to start with.
And then anything else you need.
You'll be able to pick up along the way and you know you'll be able to also avoid pitfalls like the
fact Berbel chat because you already know about it.
So hope you enjoyed the section hopefully picked up a lot from here learnt a lot.
And of course had fun along the way and I can't wait to get started on the next one.
And until next time happy coding
.