Hello.
Welcome back to that was of course on our program today we're kicking off the section on the up life
having a function is going to be quite an interesting set of tutorials and quite challenging as well
.
And as always in this first tutorial we're going to upload the data set for the section into our studio
So let's jump into it.
First thing we're going to do is we're going to check the working directory by running get w d and here
you can see that even though the conjecture is the same as what we had in the previous sections actually
the files for this section are located in a subfolder in this.
I put them in a subfolder called weather daughter because there were quite a few files didn't want them
to get mixed up.
So this gives us an opportunity to practice how would we access that subfolder.
Well one way is obviously to take this line of code and then just go set where can directory and just
paste copy it again from here.
So I just copied and pasted in here and then put in the folder name which is whether a daughter for
me.
Right.
But this is quite a long approach and there's a shorter approach so it's just commented out and the
shorter approach is to set the working directory thriller relative paths.
So if you set a Daut and then a slash This means all the door actually means the current folder that
you're already in.
As we know that's the folder we're in.
So that means basically this door will be automatically replaced by all of this text which is great
.
So all we have to do is add this last bit which is weather data.
The name of the subfolder.
So that way we can already access our conjectures on that and get working directory.
Here you can see that this is exactly what we're after.
Now bear in mind on Windows as usual the code will be a bit different.
On Windows it'll be set to working directory and maybe it was a smooth comment for now.
So pretty much the same thing dot.
But then in the server side is the double backslash weather data.
There we go.
So that is your code for Windows.
Otherwise on a Mac that is the code.
If you're already in the grateful if you're not then just run something similar to that.
There we go.
Oh of course that is provided that you did put the files in a separate subfolder.
All right.
So now let's go ahead and read the data.
Read data and let's go.
So first we're going to read them the files one by one we have a few files to look at.
First of all it's going to be Chicago so we'll just say read ADOT see a Svea Chicago hyphen F for Fahrenheit
CSV and then Arrau dot names he equals one.
Why do we need road names.
It equals one so let's let's try without it for a second.
So far on that and I look at Chicago so it's from Chicago.
So here what she can see is that the road names are not picked up.
So basically this column is being seen as a separate column in reality so the column names are always
picked up by Reed says because that's how it operates it looks for call names.
But then in our data set we know that we have call names and January-March hyperreal and so on.
And also we have road names here they are.
We don't want them to be seen as a separate column in our data set.
We want them to be here instead of these numbers.
So that's why we're going to say come on road dot.
Names equals one.
That means that take the wrong names from the first column.
And if we're on list now and then we look at Chicago you'll see that now these values in the first column
have actually become the names of the rows so all your daughter is contained within this block where
all the numeric data is which is correct.
And then you've got call names for this matrix or for this data.
And you've got the wrong names.
So that's why we're putting the wrong names he calls one a handy little feature that you can use in
our.
All right.
And now we're just going to copy this couple times because we have four cities.
So next will be in New York.
We're going to go clockwise around the U.S. next on will be Houston.
Next one will be San Francisco.
All right.
And don't forget to change the name or here as well.
Otherwise that will not be correct of course.
All right so there we go.
And another fire ran over it around that one.
So let's run that one.
That one and that one.
And of course we can now quickly check.
All right.
So let's say Chicago check.
Let's check out Chicago and we'll just have a look at Chicago.
There you go.
Then we'll have a look at New York.
Always good to check at the very start.
Just to make sure you're on the right page and also to make sure that you didn't pick up any of the
identical data so that that's 32 That's 39 OK.
That makes sense that's different.
Actually we don't really need these.
Chicago New York Houston and San Francisco.
All right.
Beautiful.
Looks like everything is picked up very nicely.
And what we want to do is we you want to see how this door has been imported.
Naturally when you use $3.60 imported as a doorframes so is check if these are indeed doorframes.
So these are doorframes.
So just quickly check that is dot dot frame and then we're going to say Chicago.
So each car is going to be her test Abani for most of the section because it did come first here.
So we're just going be working with Chicago a lot of the time when we need to work with just one of
them.
So is that a frame in Chicago.
Yes it's true.
So what we want to do is we want to convert it to a matrix Why do we want to convert to Matrix.
Well because all the elements inside this object are actually the same they're all numeric.
So there's no real need for it to be a door frame.
And moreover some of the things that we're going to be practicing Don't be applicable to matrices so
it's a good opportunity for us to quickly convert it to matrix so that we can actually get through all
of the things that we want for the section.
So let's convert to matrices.
All right.
So the first one will be we'll just override the originals just so that we don't have too many objects
to floating around.
So in Chicago and we're going to say as matrix so we're changing it from a doorframe to Matrix Chicago
run that and do all of these.
So this is going to be New York.
This is going to be Houston and this one is going to be San Francisco built of data preparation as usual
at the start of the section.
It's not a worry sometimes or even always it's necessary.
So for on that we've got these matrices and now let's check.
So is dot matrix.
We're asking a question Is Chicago Matrix now.
It is it's a matrix.
That's good.
All right.
And finally let's put all of these into a list.
Let's put all of these into a list so we'll call the list.
Whether because we're dealing with weather data and we're going to say list and here we're going to
say Chicago New York Houston and San Francisco.
So we really know how to deal with lists and this is the function that creates a list.
Now if I look at whether or I see I see a list of four components.
So there's our first component which is a matrix second component third and fourth component which is
the matrix.
And the only thing here is that these lists don't have all these components don't have proper names
they just have indices.
So we're going to give them names and we're going to use that method where we give the names.
At that point in time when we creating the list so we're going to type in Chicago equal Chicago New
York equals New York Houston Houston because Houston and San Francisco San Francisco.
Remember you don't need quotation marks if you're doing it this way because our is smart enough to understand
that these are indeed the names that you are passing to this list so far on that.
There you go you can see now we have a list of four components and all of them have names so this is
Chicago New York Houston and San Francisco.
So that just makes it easier to address each one of them individually so we can say let's have a look
.
Let's try it out.
We can say weather and let's say the we want to access the first element also of the third component
on Access Houston.
So remove the double square brackets which will give us just the component in not in a list.
And if we want the component as a subset or we want to subset the list then we'll just say whether 3
that will give us this.
As you can see based on this this is indeed now a list of one component.
Whereas if we do the double square brackets it's just the matrix by itself.
So this is the actual component.
And also we can say whether a dollar sign.
Houston so far and that's exactly the same as doing the double square brackets.
All right.
Great.
Now we are all set to learn about apply family functions and get some really valuable hands on experience
.
Are you excited.
I'm pretty excited about this.
And on that note let's move on to the next tutorial.
I'll see you there.
And until next I'm happy coding
.