Hello.
Welcome back to the course in our programming.
So far we've learnt so much already about the Apply family functions.
We've learnt the L apply as apply and apply functions we've learned how to use the air supply.
Just recently we learned how to add our own functions or NEST our functions and apply functions we've
learned how to combine the L plus function with square brackets operator.
We learned how to use apply apply we learned how to recreate the Apply function with loops and so on
.
So we've learned very interesting techniques.
And today we're going to learn yet another one of them.
Today we're going to learn how to nest apply functions within apply functions.
So this is going to be similar to nesting our own functions within functions but at the same time it
might come off as a bit more complex because this is getting into one of Inception stuff where we're
using an apply function to get a result and then another apply function on top of that result.
So very interesting topic.
Let's get started.
What are we going to look at is we're going to start by looking at that one example that we worked with
.
So we worked with this example here l apply whether road means.
And so let's first look at whether that's a weather list which has these four cities and now we're looking
at El apply it where the road means which will give us the road means for each one of these matrices
and it will place those means into a list.
Now what you'll notice is if we look at questionmark road means which we have already done it will zoom
in here quickly so we've got call soms rose some skol means road means right but there's nothing like
that for for instance maximum or minimum.
How come there isn't a predefined function and are to look at the road maximums and how can we work
around it.
How can we create our own.
Well that's what we're going to start by doing this tutorial.
So l apply where the romance is great to get the means how do we get the maximums.
Well the first thing like we did before.
Let's see how we do it just for the one matrix.
Let's look at Chicago.
There it is.
How do we get that road maximums here right.
So we don't have a function that would allow us to just quickly get the maxims from every single row
.
We don't have it handy so how are we going to do that.
Well we're going to remember about that apply function which we haven't used in a while.
The plie function applies something across all of your either of columns.
So this see how we do that if that plot function would apply.
Chicago they don't want to do it across the rows that's the one we want to do the max.
So far on that that gives me the max for every one of these rows as the output which is great.
Well now I don't want to just apply it to this one major Chicago I to apply to every single matrix in
my weather list over here.
So how would I do that.
Well let's treat this as if it were one of our own functions and then we'll use an apply function to
apply it across that whole list of matrices.
I know this might sound super confusing but in reality it's very simple.
So let's jump into it.
We've got apply right so I might just put a quick comment here to apply across whole lists just to separate
this bit of code from this bit of code.
So here's apply right.
How does it work.
It goes Give me a list.
Here's the list whether And I'm going to iterate through the components of the list which are matrices
and I'm going to apply whatever you tell me to apply.
What do you want me to apply.
So here I can put a function.
For instance I could put row means right like we had over here and put Romains but I don't want to apply
Romains.
I want to find the maximum of each row.
So in sort of Romains what I would do is take apply this same line here put it here.
The only complication here is that it's not just always going to be Chicago right.
L apply will iterate through the weather list and it will decide every single time.
Which component of the list will be used with this function.
So this will be selected by L applied.
So therefore this has to be deleted and that is where we need to use these to take them out and put
them as optional parameters so I'm going to just delete all of that.
So that's how closing bracket for apply and then apply and then comma.
These are our optional parameters.
So they go.
That's how it works.
Apply will iterate through the where the list.
It'll pass on those matrices one by one to apply apply will take the Matrix and add on these optional
arguments.
So if I run this you will see that I have got the maximum for every single row of the Chicago matrix
and I've got the maximum for every single row of the New York matrix and so on.
So here I've got the maximum of every single row for the Houston matrix and so on.
All right.
So that is how we nest and apply function inside and then apply function the other way you could have
done this just for kind of like to understand what's going on is you could have said apply apply whether
.
And then there's nothing stopping you from using this method saying that we are actually building a
function function X right.
And then you just take this what you had and then sort of skurry just put the X.
So that's pretty much the same thing.
So basically you're defining your own function here and you're saying it's going to be a function which
is actually going to apply X one max then whatever else applies iterating through so those components
they're going to become X and then you get to pick them up and put them in here.
This is identical to this same thing.
So if I run this you'll see that we get exactly the same results.
Eighty four six eight 413 84 68 413 exactly the same result just two different philosophical approaches
.
This one's a bit shorter because you're not actually creating your own function you're putting your
own function wrapper around and apply a function so that it's more convenient or easier to understand
what's happening but if you get your head around this approach where you just apply and in the first
argument is going to be passed on and then these are going to be picked up then this approach I would
recommend using this one this one is better is just better because you don't have to reinvent the bicycle
and create a function wrap her around the function just makes it more cumbersome.
So this is preferred.
Let's just put the stakes here and say preferred approach.
All right so what else can we do then we can make this nice and tidy so you can see that once again
it's a list.
How do we make these things nice and tidy tidy up.
Well we were you know we just take this and we say as apply.
Right.
So there are maximums for all of the rows and supply.
Same thing minimum there are minimums for all the most beautiful.
So this is going to be our deliverable three and this is going to be our deliverable for that is beautiful
.
And as you can see they are very very compact matrices.
Everything is presented very nicely and it is easy to understand and easy to read.
All right so that is how you nest and apply function within another apply function.
Nothing too complicated.
It might seem a bit confusing but at the same time it is actually very simple and straightforward.
Hope you enjoy this material and I look forward See you next time.
Until then happy.