Here we are in the first demo of this module.
Here I will show you how to use SpEL with the @Value
annotation to wire bean properties.
We will specifically look at writing literal expressions,
using basic operators, calling bean properties and methods,
how to do setter method wiring, and, finally,
using @Value annotation in constructor parameters.
I'm going to demonstrate all of this through our E-Commerce application.
We will extend the application by adding an Order bean to it.
Then we'll write SpEL expressions in User and Order
beans to demonstrate all of the above.
If you remember in module 1,
we created this application to be a Spring web application.
So we can now add a RestController class and some services to
demonstrate our SpEL usages in this application.
Finally, we will call the RESTful APIs from a REST client.
I will be using the Advanced REST Client available in Google Chrome.
You can use your favorite REST client.
And then we can see the results that we get.
I'm in the Spring Boot project that we created in the first part of this course.
So let's go ahead and add a bean named Order.
Create these properties, amount, discount, daysToDeliver, origin.
Create getters and setters for them.
Let's leave that for a bit and go to our User bean,
which is already created,
and let's go ahead and use the @Value annotation and write an
expression like this with a literal string and a literal integer to
set default values to those two fields.
Notice the syntax here, hash, open curly brace and close curly brace.
Let's go back to the Order bean.
And to the amount field,
let's use the @Value annotation and give a simple expression
like this with a mathematical operator, addition.
Of course, if you are implementing this for production use,
you'd not use hardcoded values like this.
You'll probably add up values coming from some other bean's property.
But here,
I just want to demonstrate the capability of doing the
mathematical operation of adding in SpEL.
Moving on, let's do another operator, this time on the discount property.
Let's write this expression to give a 5 percent discount
if the order amount is 1000 or more.
Notice here we are using the value of the amount property,
a relational operator, as well as mathematical operators in this expression.
You can also see that I've used the ternary operator here.
Then let's go to the daysToDeliver property.
So say we want to set it based on the user's country.
Let's write the expression as if the user's country is US,
and the time zone is New York, it will take three days to deliver.
If not, 14 days.
So there's the logical 'and' operator in action.
Next, let's go ahead and set the origin property.
We want to set it to the user's country.
So we write an expression in the @Value annotation to
call the User bean's country property.
So there you go.
That's how you call a bean property.
Now let's look at how we can do a method call.
So for this, let's first add a property called formattedAmount.
Basically, we want to format the amount value according to the user's locale.
So we are going to write the expression for it like this.
We are going to get the currency instance of the NumberFormat class.
GetCurrencyInstance is a static method,
so we put a T in front of the fully qualified class name.
To the getCurrencyInstance method,
we pass the default locale of the user by calling the
getDefault method of the Locale class, which is again a static method.
Then we call the format method and pass in the
order amount to it to be formatted.
This returns the formatted value as a string,
which will be assigned to the property formattedAmount.
Now, to see a setter method wiring in action, let's go back to the User bean.
Here, we already have a setter method created for the timeZone property.
So let's go ahead and wire it by giving the @Value annotation.
We will use the user's timezone from the systemProperties
predefined variable and write an expression like this.
This should wire the property with the user's timezone value.
Finally, in this demo,
we are going to look at how @Value annotation can be
used in constructor parameters.
So let's say we want to initialize the country and language
properties of the User bean in the constructor.
So let's go ahead and add a constructor to the User class.
In constructor parameters,
we will write expressions like this to initialize the country
property to the value of the user's country and the language
property to the value of the user's language from the
systemProperties predefined variable.
So that's it for this demo.
Now let's add a RestController class called OrderController.
And in it, we would need to auto-wire the Order and User beans,
and just add a few basic services to get the customer's name,
the order amount, the discount, the origin,
days to deliver, and the order amount formatted in the user's currency.
Let's run the application.
Then go to Chrome Advanced REST client and call the APIs,
and you'll see the results like this.
So there you saw bean wiring with SpEL. More to come in the next demos.