Let's check out another useful feature available in SpEL, expression templating.
Expression templates let us mix literal text with one or more evaluation blocks.
Each evaluation block is delimited with a prefix and suffix,
which would commonly be hash and open curly brace and a closing curly brace.
This allows you to concatenate literal text with the
results of evaluating expression blocks.
If we take a closer look at how it's done,
literal text can be mixed with one or more evaluation blocks that can
appear in the middle like this surrounded by a prefix of hash open
curly brace and a suffix of close curly brace.
The expressions are written inside of the evaluation blocks like this.
Here is how SpEL expression templating can be done in plain Java code.
Notice that we pass a TemplateParserContext to the
ParserContext parameter of the parseExpression method.
The TemplateParserContext determines how the string expression should be
parsed when it encounters the prefix and suffix characters.
The default TemplateParserContext class The default
TemplateParserContext class looks like this.
Notice the default prefix and suffix.
Note that you can define your own prefix and suffix
characters as well if you want. But here, we'll just go with the default.