Now let's see expression templating in action.
I'm going to show this to you by adding a new property
called orderSummary to our Order bean.
Then we will use expression templating to populate it with a value at runtime.
As usual, with a new RESTful service added to our controller,
we can see the results.
Go back to the Order bean and add a string property named orderSummary.
Let's say we want to display a summary of the order to the user
with a few important pieces of information,
like the user name, the order amount, and the discount.
So I'm going to write an expression using expression templating by mixing
literal text with evaluation blocks to access name,
amount, and discount properties from the User and Order beans like this.
Simply run it, and you can see the summary like this as the output.
Notice how the literal text is mixed with expression evaluation results. So that's how you use expression templating in SpEL.