Before winding up this module,
I would like to discuss a few typical scenarios where SpEL can come in handy.
You can choose to use SpEL when your application needs to dependency inject
an existing bean or its properties into another object,
as we saw in a few instances of our E-Commerce application.
You can also use SpEL when you want to dependency inject a bean or set
bean properties based on some environmental situation or condition such
as the scenario we saw in our E-Commerce application to render the order
details based on the user's locale.
And in general,
whenever you need to access and manipulate object graphs at runtime, you can choose to use SpEL.