Hi everyone!
My name is Buddhini Samarakkody, and welcome to my course,
Spring Framework: Spring Expression Language (SpEL).
I'm a Java developer and an independent consultant,
and my passion is to teach and share my knowledge.
SpEL is a powerful expression language that can be
used within the Spring portfolio, as well as independently.
This course is a quick but comprehensive course that gives
you hands-on experience to work with SpEL.
Some of the major topics that we will cover include writing and
parsing basic SpEL expressions using plain Java,
using evaluation context, using SpEL with @Value annotation,
collection manipulation with SpEL, and expression templating.
By the end of this course,
you'll be fully equipped with all the knowledge required to
apply SpEL to an application of any scale.
Before beginning the course,
you should be familiar with Spring fundamentals and Spring Boot.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn SpEL with the Spring
Framework: Spring Expression Language (SpEL) course, at Pluralsight.