Now let's see the evaluation context in action.
Here, we will be creating a StandardEvaluationContext in our parser class,
add code to resolve a field using the evaluation context,
create a bean named User,
set it as the root object in a StandardEvaluationContext for
demonstrating resolving of bean properties.
We are back again in our Spring Boot application,
and now we will create a StandardEvaluationContext in our parser class.
Let's set a variable called greeting to this evaluation
context with a value of Hello USA.
Now we write our SpEL expression to access and do some simple
processing to its value and parse the expression.
And now we can print out the value that we get in return like this.
Run it and you'll see the output as USA.
Let's add a second StandardEvaluationContext and set a
variable with the exact same name, greeting,
to this evaluation context, this time with a value of Hello UK.
Repeat the same steps as before and run the class.
You'll get the output as UK this time.
The evaluation context resolved the field when
evaluating the expressions respectively.
Now let's go ahead and add a bean called User.
Add a few properties to it, along with getters and setters.
Then create a new User object in our class and set it as the
root object of our StandardEvaluationContext by passing it
to the constructor like this.
We can use an SpEL expression to wire the country property with a value.
When doing this, we pass our evaluation context like this.
Similarly, we can set other properties of the User bean.
Now when you check out the values of the User bean's properties,
you can see that the values have been correctly wired to them.
So once the root object is specified, SpEL knows how to resolve its properties when evaluating expressions.