Another interesting feature that SpEL provides is the
systemProperties predefined variable,
which we will soon be using in our demo application.
System properties is an object of key/value pairs that stores
information about the current runtime environment.
These include information such as the operating system,
the user's locale-specific information such as country,
language, time zone, and many more.
This information becomes extremely useful when we need to conditionalize the
behavior of an application based on runtime properties.
SpEL makes accessing of these system properties in expressions convenient by providing an in-built variable called systemProperties.