In this demo,
we will look at how the systemProperties predefined variable
can be used to access the user's country,
language, and time zone, and set them to our User bean.
Our aim here is to be able to render the order details depending on the locale
of the user at runtime using dynamic dependency injection.
Here are the steps.
Add code to the ExpressionParser class to be able to
access systemProperties in SpEL expression.
And then wire the User bean properties dynamically at runtime
based on the user's locale-specific information.
Getting back to our parser class,
we create a StandardEvaluationContext to be able to use the
systemProperties variable in the evaluation of our expressions.
Then set the systemProperties as a variable in this context,
and then we'll be able to parse expressions that access
values from the system properties.
Then wire our User bean properties with those values,
the country, language, and time zone, like this.
Prior to running this,
you should go to Edit Configurations in IntelliJ and set the
VM options for the parser class like this.
From here,
you can simply simulate running with different values for user.language,
user.country, and user.timezone system properties. Run it and you can see the values being set accordingly.