Congratulations, you completed this course,
you learned a lot about Javascript, the many ways of using it, all its core features,
how to use it in a browser and do amazing things there, how to use it in a different environment with Node.js
and so much more.
So what now,
how do you continue? Well you finished the course,
your journey does not end here
though. There's always more to learn not just because Javascript is an evolving language and browsers
are evolving and adding more and more browser APIs all the time
but in general because there are always more pattern to find and more things to learn.
Use this course as a resource and reference,
it's not just a course where you should go through once and be done with it.
You have all these sections which focus on different topics,
you can always revisit the sections if something isn't 100% clear or you forgot something or it's
a very important concept and you just want to make sure you got that right.
So use this course as a go-back reference and not just as a use once resource. Also dive in to examples
you find on the Internet via Google and so on,
also build dummy projects, for example clone simplified workings of popular web applications or
add certain features driven by Javascript to your existing web page.
So practice the things you learned,
also dive into things which we haven't covered in exactly that way in this course
so that you can apply the knowledge you did get and combine that with other things you find via Google,
other snippets you find and then really build the web applications you want to build. And also last
but not least, build a portfolio, dive deeper into Javascript and into all the browser APIs.
As I said, things are evolving and you want to stay up-to-date,
you can dive into a progressive web apps for example which is a pretty interesting set of features exposed
by browsers that builds up on Javascript, that uses Javascript but allows you to build applications that
work without an internet connection for example. Dive into on the edge APIs which might only be supported
by one browser, not by all but still support might get better in the future and maybe you can build
something cool in that one browser where it is supported. Explore single page applications, also called
SPAs which can be developed with frameworks like Angular or Vue or React and its ecosystem, so
that you can build web applications driven entirely by Javascript. For all of that, you will need the
knowledge you gained in this course and you should never stop learning and growing because the web never
stops growing and evolving, Javascript evolves, so do browsers, so build up on the knowledge you gained here,
practice, dive deeper and dive into different ways of applying that knowledge. Now of course the question
is, where can you learn more?
Well of course you have this course as a reference as I said, where you can go back into and dive into
certain sections, revisit concepts from time to time and so on
but this is not all and
it does not cover all browser APIs
for example, it does not cover everything you can do in a browser because it's a Javascript course, not
a browser API course I guess
and because that's also evolving and changing all the time,
instead for that you have resources like MDN, which is a huge documentation about basically anything related
to Javascript and browser APIs,
so you start to learn more about what you can do in browsers or learn more about a certain Javascript
features and all the ways of configuring something there,
all the niche cases which we might not have discussed in this course,
so that is a great resource
you should check out. Also have a look at Stack Overflow, Stack Overflow is a great discussion board
where you can find interesting discussions, a lot of solutions for common problems
and of course also dive into discussions to help others,
this allows you to grow and get an idea of how other developers are solving certain problems or are doing
certain things.
We also have another documentation which I haven't used too much in this course but that would be the
Google Developers documentation.
It offers a lot of great articles on Javascript basics and also more advanced topics and you will
also often find that if you simply just google because that ultimately is the solution to everything
right,
no seriously googling for problems you want to solve with Javascript, for error messages you might get
and so on will give you a lot of interesting blog posts, tutorials, documentation articles and much more
which allows you to solve the specific problem
you might be facing well and ultimately of course check out other courses, not so much other Javascript
courses, you can do that of course but this is the most comprehensive course you find here on Udemy
but instead other courses on niche or specialized topics. For example I do have courses on Angular,
React, on Vue, on Progressive Web Apps and much much more
and you can simply check out all my courses to learn more about these things here and learn more about
these technologies.
So explore other courses, of course not necessarily just my courses though I'd be more than happy to welcome
you there, to dive into different ways of applying Javascript and using it.
And with that you're well-prepared to become an amazing Javascript developer and I wish you all the
best for your future career,
definitely share anything you build with me here in the Q & A section or as a private message,
I can't wait to see what you're building and I hope that you got a lot out of this course.