Time for another module about functions.
Wait, didn't we already have two modules that talked about functions?
Well, that will be the last one
but in this module, we'll dive into some advanced concepts which you need to know about Javascript functions,
which are definitely not beginner level but which are important.
Specifically, we'll have a look at pure functions and side effects,
what that is and why it matters.
We'll have a look at factory functions, what that is. We'll have a look at closures and therefore revisit this
concept of scope which we already learned about
and last but not least, we'll explore a specific way of working with functions,
we'll have a look at recursion,
what this is, what it means and when it can be handy.
So with that, let's not waste any time and dive right in.