Before we now dive deeper into other Javascript topics and there are many other topics left, I think
it's time to practice programming with classes, with this object oriented approach again,
though I will say this module is entirely optional,
if you're not interested in this or if you want to practice a little bit later, you can just skip this
module and continue to the next one.
Now in the next module, we'll actually use the result, the little application we work on from this module
but of course you'll find the finished app,
the finished project attached at the beginning of next module, so if you skip this one, you'll not see
the process, how we got there but you'll get the result and the result will only contain things you already
learned.
So skipping this module is possible but if you feel like practicing, I would definitely recommend that
you dive into it right now with me. In this module, we'll work on this little application, this little demo
here and you will find this starting project attached to this in the next lecture and in the end what
you'll find there is what we always worked with, an HTML file with some content in there, some styles and an empty
script file and we'll work on this script file, we'll populate it with some life and we'll make sure that
we can click the finished button or the activate button and move items around from box A, from the active
projects box to the finished projects box and the other way around.
So nothing too fancy but plenty of opportunities to practice a lot of the things we learned thus far.