With all the basic knowledge we gathered, it's now finally time to also work with the HTML document
our script is running on on our own because thus far in all the tiny projects we worked on, I always
gave you that vendor.js file, that black box code which in the end established connections to certain
elements in the HTML code.
Now it's time to fully understand how we can establish such a connection because there's more than one
way of doing so
and how you can in general work with the HTML page that was rendered, manipulated and so on.
Specifically in this module, we'll have a look at the HTML code, how it's loaded, something which
is called the DOM and what this means and how Javascript fits into the equation.
We'll have a look at nodes and elements which are two important types of objects
if you want to call it like that with which we're working if we're working with the HTML content through
Javascript. We'll have a look at how we can query DOM nodes, so how we can get access to parts of the
rendered HTML code and how we can move around there in Javascript to select different elements and
do stuff with these elements because we'll also have a look at how we can read and manipulate the DOM,
so how we can for example change the style of an element or anything like that
and of course we'll also have a look at how we can add brand new elements to the rendered HTML page
or how we can remove such DOM nodes which will turn out to be HTML elements.
So a lot of content in this module, let's not lose any time and jump right in.