So let's dive right into Javascript, into its core syntax and some core features which you'll need in
any Javascript program you're going to write, specifically in this course module,
we'll have a look at the core syntax, so how you write
valid Javascript code. We'll explore variables and understand what we use them for, how we create them,
how we use them in our program and with which kind of data we can work in our program.
We'll have a look at operators,
so how we can actually run calculations and execute some code by combining values and by doing something
useful
and we'll also explore and use functions, an important language construct which you'll find in actually
pretty much any programming language you can work with
and therefore it's also part of Javascript and
here we'll have a look at what functions are, why we use them and how we use them and we'll do all
of that,
all these things in the context of a basic application we're working on where we can also see something
on the screen and where we see these things come together in a real life example.