Let's take a step back from the web page, from working with the DOM into more Javascript theory or into
important data structures you have in Javascript.
To be precise, let's have a closer look at arrays and iterables
in this module. Now of course, we already worked with arrays but always in the very basic way,
turns out there are many interesting things you can do with arrays,
many things you can know and therefore,
that's exactly what we'll have a look at in this module. In detail,
we'll have a look at different ways of creating arrays, we'll have a look at how to work with arrays,
how to manipulate them, how to add or remove items,
what's special about them and how they behave.
We'll have a look at a lot of important array methods which exist on arrays in Javascript, that help
us transform array data, summarize array data, sort arrays and all kinds of stuff
and we'll also have a look at other important iterables which you'll find in Javascript, namely maps
and sets
and I will also clarify what iterable actually mean.
Well let's start with that right away.