In this course we wrote a lot of code and we tested a lot of code of course.
We always tested it manually by simply clicking around in our web application.
In this module here, we'll dive into automated testing,
that means we'll write code which will actually test our code,
so code that runs to run other code and evaluate the results.
This is indeed what this module will be about,
we'll dive into what exactly testing is and why we use it,
we'll have a look at different kinds of tests namely unit tests, integration tests and end-to-end tests
and we'll also explore how we can test both synchronous and asynchronous code and in general, get a thorough
introduction into the world of testing.