So we saw promise chaining in action and really important to emphasize here,
you don't have to return a promise in here, you can return any kind of data and it will be converted
to a promise and wrapped into a promise,
the core idea of promise chaining is that you can have step after step and this step here for example,
the second one, will only execute once this step is done, so once this promise is done,
we make it into this step and then once whatever we return here which is wrapped into a promise,
if it is not a promise already,
once this is done, we make it into this step, a very powerful concept.
Now let's have a look at errors because of course, things can always go wrong,
for example when we're getting the position, we have this error callback in our promisified
version here.
Now what if we have that arrow case, because for example permission is not granted?
Well then previously, we would handle our error here but now since I have moved this into a promise, I want
to pass this onto my promise chain so that we can somehow handle it here.
Now that is done with this second argument, this configuration function for the promise constructor gets
the reject argumen. We can call reject here inside of the arrow callback
and for example pass our error object into reject.
Now what reject will do is it will mark the promise as failed,
I mentioned that a promise can be pending or resolved,
it's pending whilst we're waiting for it to be resolved
basically, once we resolved it, we can set it back to pending by returning something in the then block.
Now there is another state and that is the
failed state basically, that we have an error. So the promise is now not resolved,
it's not pending but it has an error. Now
errors are not handled with the normal then functions here, with these functions you pass to then I should
say, instead then takes a second argument.
The first argument here is the callback function that should be executed if the promise resolves,
the second argument is the potential error function we might have.
So here, we could expect our error object, you can name it however you want here
and for example log that here or send it to your own server where you want to write some logs or do
whatever you want.
So that's a second argument I'm passing to the then method here,
it's a second function I'm passing to then, the first function is the success case when the promise resolves,
the second argument here is the failure case, when a promise does not resolve but instead rejects.
So now if we go back and reload and I click block here, we see that error here for example, user denied
geolocation. We also got this output,
I'll come back to it in a second but for now we see that the error is being output here,
so this code executes here.
Now you might argue that we're losing some of the benefits we gained with promises
if we have a second argument here, a second function. Whilst it's not nested into another callback, we
have more callbacks next to each other
and whilst this is perfectly fine to use, you have an alternative to that, you have another methods
you can add to your promise chain,
for example here and that's the catch method.
Now the catch method can be added on a promise and you can add it anywhere in this chain, right after
executing this function which returns a promise or anywhere thereafter, though the exact position doesn't
matter.
Let's for example add it here after the first then block, add catch here and we have a then block thereafter
which belongs to the same chain still
and here you can now have your error function.
Now let's try if it works before we dive into what it does. If I click track me and I block, we get that
error output
so it works
but what does it do?
Catch actually does exactly the same as if you pass it as a second argument here to one of your then
block,
so it's really just an alternative to that but both approaches,
no matter if you use the second argument or a catch block works such that they catch any errors, any
rejections produced anywhere in your promise chain prior to this catch block or prior to the place
where you added it as a second argument.
So if we had more then blocks here, which we don't have in this promise because it doesn't make sense
there, it won't work there
but if we had a longer promise chain with multiple then blocks, then no matter if you have an error here
or in the promise returned here or here or here, if any of these promises rejects, this logic will run
or the logic in the nearest second argument.
So if this promise rejects for example, it's not just the case that this then block will be skipped,
instead all then blocks thereafter will be skipped until we reach a catch block or a second argument
to handle the error.
So in this scenario here which will work, this then block is skipped if this promise which was returned
by get position, if this rejects,
so this then block is skipped and instead we make it into this catch block but this then block will then
execute again,
so the catch block, this catch method does not cancel the entire promise chain,
instead it just does its thing and you can even return something new here which can be a promise or
some other data that will be wrapped into a promise, just as it's the case in the then method and now
any then blocks thereafter will continue to work.
So the positioning of the catch block doesn't matter, if you want to kind of cancel the promise chain,
you have to move it to the end of all your then blocks because only then you make sure that if one of
them rejects, the other ones are skipped and you make it into catch.
If you add catch somewhere in the middle, then all prior ones are skipped
if one of them rejects but then blocks after catch will be executed.
So here in catch, what happens is we cancel or we skip all previous then blocks if one of them rejects
but then here we return new data
for example, even if you don't return anything, you return undefined basically
and that sets the promise back to pending
and if you have more then blocks thereafter, those will execute once the pending promise resolves again.
So it does not cancel the promise, it allows it to continue.
So here for example if I return on we go and you will see I click block, we print on we go here, we still
get undefined because position data is undefined because we skipped this then block
as I explained
but data here is what I returned here in the catch block and that's not a bug,
that's of course very useful because it allows you to structure your chain such that certain parts
of it can be skipped if necessary but it doesn't necessarily crash entirely just because one part failed.
If you wanted to crash entirely, you can always force that by moving catch to the end of course.
If you have catch somewhere in the middle, then the promise chain continues after catch and of course,
you could have another catch in there to handle an error in here because if this rejects for some reason,
this catch block which came before it will not do anything, you would need a new catch block or a new
second argument to handle any errors here or in other then blocks thereafter.
So this is error handling and how promise chaining works with errors,
really important to understand that, gives you a lot of power and all the flexibility you need to write
great applications which also can deal with errors in a graceful way.