So let's now continue and make sure that the computer also makes a choice. So for that,
we can add a new function here, get a computer choice, an anonymous function stored in this constant
here and there,
I want to calculate a random number between 0 and 1 and if it's between 0 and .33, let's say
that's rock,
if it's between .34 and .67, it's scissors and so on, so that a third of that range
is reserved for every choice.
So we can get the random value here, store it in a constant of any name of your choice with math.random.
We haven't really used that before,
math is a globally available object
you could say, made available by the browser in Javascript and it has a random method which generates
a random number between 0 and 1.
Now we can add an if check here and see if the random value is let's say smaller than .34, in that
case let's say the choice is rock.
So here we can return rock and since we return this function, we'll then stop at this point of course,
else if let's say the random value is smaller than .67 which we only reach if this was false,
so this will not kick in for a value like 0.2 because of course that would be true for that
value but so is this and since we handle this true value here already,
this other else if block will not kick in, no matter if we return here or not.
So if we are greater than .34 but smaller than .67, I return paper and last but not
least if neither is the case,
so for all other cases,
so for any value above .67, I return scissors. So that's how the computer chooses a value,
it's simply a random choice, does not take into account what we chose because of course like in real
life, we want to choose simultaneously without knowing what the other party chose
and therefore now here, we can store the computer choice here in a constant by calling get computer
choice.
So now we have both choices stored,
now it's time to find out who won and for that,
I'll add yet another function which I'll name determine winner or get winner,
however you want to call it and this function
should now actually take some arguments.
It takes the computer choice, I'll name it see choice here and the player choice as arguments
and then we just need an if check where we go through the different combinations we have.
Now the first combination we have is that the computer choice is equal to the player choice, in which
case we have a draw,
right?
So I want to return draw here and just as before,
if I use string identifiers, I want to use a global constant for that to rule out typos.
So here, I'll add a result draw constant which includes that draw value,
then here a result player wins constant where I maybe store player wins as an identifier and then result
computer wins where we store computer wins as an identifier,
the exact values for these identifiers of course are totally up to you.
So now with that here, I want to return result draw
in the end. Now else if, so if we don't have a draw, we want to find out if the player or the computer won.
So here we want to check if, let's say the computer choice is equal to rock and the player choice is
equal to let's say paper,
then we know the player won right because the player chose paper, paper beats rock,
so in this case the player would have won but of course that's not the only combination.
So we need to add another block and we can do so by adding the or operator, thanks to precedence,
this is combined together and then compared to whatever we have after or, this is exactly what we want
because these two belong together.
So that's one possible win condition, if this yields true, then the player won. Another possible win condition
is that the computer chose let's say paper and the player chose scissors, then the player won as well,
so here I want a group together all the conditions where the player wins.
Let me add the if body thereafter,
so the curly braces and use the autoformatting shortcut to autoformat this, now this also added
some parentheses here to make this easier to read,
technically they're not required,
you can add them and autoformatting will re-add them but you don't need them here because of precedence,
just want to highlight this again.
So let's add the last combination here and that's that the computer chose scissors and the player
chose rock,
in this case we also won, right?
So in all these cases, we won and therefore here we can return result
player wins, else we know that the computer won,
so we can return result
computer wins.
So that's now our get winner function
and now we can call that down there in our anonymous function which we call when we start the game. I
add a winner variable or constant here since we never assign a new value and we can call get winner
here and forward the computer choice as a first argument
and the player selection or to be in line, we can also name this here player choice of course, doesn't
matter, as a second argument.
So this will give us the winner and for now, I'll just log winner here, of course
that's not the final output, to see whether that works.
So let's save all of that and reload here, start a game
and now let's choose paper and looks like we won.
Now we don't really see what the computer chose but we won,
that's good, right,
so yes we'll probably find out what the computer chose later once we add more code. So let's reload
because right now we can't restart the game in any other way,
so let's reload and let's maybe go for scissors and looks like the computer also chose that.
Well let's also see if we can lose if I choose rock,
well computer also chose that,
let's go for rock again,
wow,
computer won now
so looks like the computer chose paper.
So that works,
of course we don't really have the best possible output because we don't really see what the computer chose
but we'll get there. Before we get there though,
let's take a step back and learn more about functions and a different way of creating functions.