So now in this module you had an introduction to Data Structures and Algorithms queue time complexities
and also saw some example algorithms in action.
There is a great GitHub repository besides that article I mentioned earlier which I would recommend
as a source to dive in deeper.
You of course all defined this linked in the last lecture of this module.
This is a repository where you see a bunch of data structures you could build on your own as well as
a bunch of algorithms including a little hint Weber there for beginners or advanced users that you could
implement with JavaScript.
You see a bunch of different examples here and this is a great place for practicing algorithms and for
all of course practicing for interviews you'll find some algorithms here which we also saw in this module.
But of course as you can tell there are way more you can dive in now for every algorithm like the knapsack
problem you can dive into get an explanation of the problem and what you're trying to solve then.
Mathematical pseudocode explanation.
And then you also find JavaScript files where the concrete algorithm is implemented.
So where you can see what you do to solve this problem.
Now this year by the way is a robber complex one which is why it's a lot of code.
There of course also are easier ones in there which you also can use to practice javascript and algorithms.
Now what you don't see in here at the moment is the Big O notation of an algorithm.
But that is of course something you can derive on your own with the knowledge you gained here and with
help of the extra other article I mentioned.
And in general if you're not sure about the time complexity of something and you want to validate your
result you can always search for something like Javascript and then the algorithm name time complexity
and you should find discussions and articles that help you understand this algorithm and also its time
complexity.
So that is something you can also check out.
For example here on Stack Overflow.
To learn about your opinions of other people what they write about it and what the time complexity offers.
Algorithms should be in this case for example time complexity and times logarithm of n now for interviews.
It's important that you don't try to learn all these algorithms here by heart but that you really just
learn how to think about algorithms and how to come up with them so that you get into this problem solving
thinking and you simply can combine the different skills you gathered for all this course and with the
help of other resources as well to solve problems that might be thrown at you.
In interviews it's also rarely important to get the right result.
Instead interviewers want to see how you approach to problem how you think about is that you know what
Big O notation is and how to derive it.
And even if you then make a mistake people can still see that your way of thinking is correct and data
is what matters here and yet.
So if these sources and what you learned in this module you should now be well prepared to dive deeper
into algorithms and data structures and ace your next job interview Sten.