Now that we know about the heap and the stack,
it's time to dive into a super important concept which even if the rest is not interesting to you, you
absolutely have to understand because it's super important for Javascript and it can be very confusing
when you work with Javascript, when you don't understand this concept.
It's about primitive versus reference values,
now what is that? In Javascript,
we have two categories or types or of values
you could say.
So with that, I don't mean strings and numbers because that would be wrong,
we also have booleans, objects, null, undefined and so on
but I really mean these data types which you already learned about,
so boolean, strings, numbers and objects and so on, these can be categorized into two categories.
We have primitive values and we have reference values and that's an important differentiation which
you need to understand.
Now primitive values are these six types of data - strings, numbers, boolean, null, undefined and symbol which
we haven't learned about which we'll learn about later which is very advanced, it doesn't matter right
now,
these are primitive values in Javascript.
So every number that you create and which you then store in a variable or which you use in a calculation
is created by Javascript or by the browser behind the scenes as a primitive value.
Thus far, that didn't really matter to us and in many cases, it won't matter to you but there will be
one important difference to the reference values later.
So it's stored in memory, normally on the stack because normally these are relatively short living because
Javascript can get rid of them relatively easy,
they're cheap to be recreated so it can easily duplicate them,
this doesn't cost too much,
not much memory is consumed by these values in the end and therefore, they're typically stored in its
stack memory.
Now if you keep that picture in mind where function calls are pushed on top of each other,
remember that I called the stack concept for managing execution contexts,
well you could say each function there has its own execution context, right? The overall script has some
global variables maybe which are part of that anonymous execution context, another function which has
an internal variable has its own execution context. So primitive values typically are stored in the stack.
I'm saying typically because they could be stored in the heap as well if it's a long running operation
and in the end, it's the browser which decides which data ends up where. It actually doesn't even matter
for what I'm explaining here, I just want to briefly mention it here that these primitive values are generally
managed in the stack. More important to us and the key difference between primitive and reference values
is that when you copy a variable, which means you assign it to a new one which holds a primitive value,
then the value is actually copied.
Now we took this for granted thus far but the implication is quite important.
If you open up your browser developer tools console on any web page you want, maybe the one we just
worked on or a brand new one, doesn't matter. In there,
if you create a variable with let, let's say you name it name but that does of course not matter, you
can name it however you want it you store a value of Max or any other string in there, then this obviously
is a primitive value as you just learned,
strings are primitive values and therefore Max is stored in there.
If you now create another variable, another user or whatever you want to name it and you assign name
as a value to that variable, then you're basically telling Javascript
take the value, store the name and store it in another user.
Therefore another user
of course also has Max as a value.
Now it gets interesting, if we now change name to let's say Manuel, so we assigned a new value to that variable.
If we now look into another user though, we see that still is Max and this kind of is what we expected
and what we used thus far throughout the course. Whenever we took some value in a variable or maybe in a parameter
of a function and we stored that in another variable, it was always clear to us that if we change that
original variable, the other variable where we stored it in would not change as well and that's the case
because primitive values are copied by value, which means when we do this assignment here, we're telling
Javascript and the browser, hey take the value which is stored in name, in this variable, create a copy
of it and store that copy in another user.
Don't forget that all data, including strings and numbers needs to be stored in memory somewhere.
Now as I said, typically that's the stack and we don't have to worry too much about where exactly it
is but because it needs to be stored somewhere, it's not obvious or not something we could expect that
Javascript always creates a copy when we want to store it in a new variable,
it could also just tell the variable
well take that exact same value in memory, store it in the same place in memory and store this address
of that place and memory in the variable instead of the value itself
and if that would be the case, then changing variable one should also impact the value stored in variable
two because they're effectively pointing both at the same value
but that's not what's happening with primitive values,
instead there, a real copy is created.
So that's the behavior for primitive values.
Now you can probably already guess what behavior for reference values will be but let's still have a
look, what are reference values to begin with?
Well all other objects or generally, all objects in Javascript.
Now technically if you want to be really correct, string numbers and so on are not objects but are dynamically
transformed to pseudo objects you could say when you do something like name.length.
We have used that before in the course but this gives you the length of the name and with the dot notation,
it kind of implies that we're accessing a property of name which then in turn implies that name would
be an object but it actually isn't,
it's a bit more complex than that and we don't need to dive in all the internals here but in the end
what happens here is Javascript dynamically transforms a string or a number, so any primitive value to
an object temporarily if you use the dot notation on it but other than that, it's a primitive value and
it's always behaving as you see it here in the left no matter if you're temporarily transforming it or
not.
Now all real objects which always stay objects are handled differently because they're more expensive
to create
you could say. A real object which you create on your own or which might be built into the browser and
exposed to you, like that math object where we also called the random function earlier in the course,
well these objects as you can imagine hold a bit more data than just a couple of characters or just
a single number,
they're more complex to manage and therefore creating them takes longer, occupies more memory and so
on.
Therefore the browser typically stores these in the heap but again, the exact allocation logic is something
the browser is responsible for, not you or Javascript but that's what the browser does
and important, a variable then only stores a pointer,
so the address of that place in memory and not the value itself.
For primitive values, a variable really stored the value itself in it, for reference values
that's not the case
and instead the value is stored somewhere in memory, somewhere in the heap and the variables stores
the address of that place in memory,
so a pointer at this place a memory you could say. Therefore if you copy a variable which holds a reference
value,
so if you assign it to a different variable, you only copy the pointer, the reference and not the value
itself.
Now what's the implication of that?
Let's go back to the browser and reload
and now let's create a new array let's say and arrays are just objects.
So here, I have my hobbies array which currently only includes sports and now let's create another variable,
new hobbies or however you want to name it and let's store hobbies in that by assigning it like this.
Now if we output hobbies here, we see that's the sports array and new hobbies of course also is that same
array,
so thus far you could think that the value was copied.
Now let's actually go to hobbies,
so to the original array and push a new element onto it, let's say cooking,
so this new string is pushed onto hobbies.
So if now I output hobbies, I of course get that array with sports and cooking
but as you now probably expect, new hobbies also includes cooking, even though we never touched new hobbies
but it includes this value because when we assigned hobbies to new hobbies, we only copied the pointer,
we only copied the address of that array. So the element itself, the value, the array itself was never duplicated
or copied,
instead we only copied the address and that means if we change one array, we automatically change the other
array because there is nothing like one and the other array, there only is exactly one array in memory
and then both variables hold the same pointer at that place in memory. It's the same for objects by the
way, if we have person here and this person let's say has an age of 30
and then I have another person and I assign person to that, if I then, to mix it up, go to another person
and set the age here to 32, then if we have a look at person, we see there the age changed as well for the
exact same reason.
Now what can we do about that?
Well in general, you don't need to do anything about that,
that is a default behavior for a good reason, to avoid unnecessary duplication of data, to avoid cluttering
your memory, to be more efficient, provide better performance and so on
but of course you sometimes have cases where you need to copy data, where you need to store it somewhere
else and where you want to make sure that if you edit the "copied" in quotes because you're not really
copying it,
so when you're editing the copied data, that the original data isn't.
Now we'll have a closer look at solutions in the arrays and objects
Deep Dive sections which will come soon after this one, where I explain a bit more about the solutions
and how they work.
For now, I'll just quickly show them to you and we'll dive into the details later because right now, we
don't really need that in the course
but I also don't want to hide that solution from you right now.
So let's say we now want to create a real copy in yet another person in this variable and there, I want
to copy person.
Now as you learned, like this it wouldn't work. Now you can use a different syntax, where you create a
new object with curly braces right,
this creates a brand new object
and if you do so, then you can add a brand new operator which we haven't used before and which I'll cover
in more detail in the objects and array sections I just mentioned. It's three dots, which looks rather
strange but this is an operator built into Javascript,
it's called the spread operator
and after that, you can add person.
Now what this operator does is it pulls out all the key-value pairs in person and adds them as new key
value pairs to this new object
and since this is a new object, it's a real copy, it's a new place in memory, new address, the old person
also still is there
but this also is now a new object.
So if we do that, then yet another person of course has the age of 32 but if we now change person.age
back to 30, you will see yet another person still has an age of 32 because now this was a real copy.
Now for arrays, a similar approach exists and if we have our hobbies here with sports and then we have more
hobbies and we want to create a real copy, then we create an empty array,
use that same spread operator,
so the three dots and then the existing array and now just as it pulled out the key-value pairs for
the object, here it basically pulls out all the elements of the array and adds them as elements to this
new array which we create with the help of the square brackets.
So therefore now if I go to hobbies and I push cooking as a new hobby onto that array,
you'll see that more hobbies
still only has sports. Again
that's the quick introduction to that solution,
a closer look at the spread operator will be taken in the arrays and objects modules. So now that we covered reference
and primitive types,
we can also dive in to something else which I already showed earlier but where we had no great explanation
of why that was happening.
I'm talking about a use case where we have maybe a person, let's name it person1, where the age is
30 and then another person2, where I don't assign person1 but I instead create another new object
with curly braces where the age is also 30.
So to us these are exactly the same objects and still if I perform a boolean comparison here with either
two or three equal signs, doesn't matter, you'll see the result is false,
so they're not equal.
Well now this makes a lot of sense,
keep in mind that what we actually stored in person1 and person2 is a pointer at a place in memory
and these are two totally different objects, even though they hold the same data but they are two different
distinct objects stored in different places, so at different addresses, in memory and since person1
stores the address of this object and person2 stores the address of this object and these are
two different objects,
we have two different addresses and therefore if we compare person1 to person2, what we effectively
compare is whether the address of person1 is equal to the address of person2 and that is not the case.
This is why we get this false result here and
this is why they're not equal, because of that reference type thing
and it's the same for comparing arrays. Another important implication which also can be confusing when
you work with reference types
is this one. Previously I created hobbies with let, right,
now here's something which might confuse you. If I create it with const hobbies and I have an array there
which includes sports and nothing else, then let me try to push something onto hobbies, let's say cooking.
Would you expect that this works?
Keep in mind that it's a constant
so we can't change the value after it has been created. Well you might expect an error therefore and
yet if I hit enter, we get no errors
and if I have a look at hobbies, we see cooking was added.
So how does that work?
Well again keep in mind, this array gets created somewhere in memory and what's getting stored in hobbies
is the address of that array or of that object,
arrays are objects as you learned, so the address is getting stored in this constant.
Now when we call push, we certainly do manipulate the data in memory but what do we not manipulate? The
address,
it's still the same address. The data in memory changed but it's still at the same address, maybe more
memory was allocated to it,
that's something the browser does but we don't care, we don't care if more memory was allocated, the address
is the same.
So in this constant, the value never changed because the value is the address and the address didn't
change, just the data behind the address
but that's not what's getting stored here,
therefore here we can change this like this without getting an error.
It's different if we try to assign a new array like this here,
sports, running.
If I try to do that, I will get an error,
why?
Because we used the equal sign here and that means we try to assign a new array.
Now of course as you learned, the array will never really be stored in there but what matters is that
we do indeed create a brand new array here, which means a brand new place in memory, a brand new address
and therefore Javascript tries to store a brand new address in hobbies.
So now the value of hobbies would get changed and that indeed is not allowed because it's a constant.
So using constants with a single equal sign to assign a new value is never allowed but changing the
objects which might be stored in them,
that is allowed as long as you use something like push.
Now of course, you can't change primitives stored in constants because these are not stored in memory
and there is no address stored in the constant but instead the real value is stored in it
but for objects and arrays, this works.
So just to also give you an object example, if person would be stored in a constant and I set the age
to 30, I can of course output it but I can also access the age and set it to 32 and if I now output
person,
this would work because now I only change data in memory.
You could argue that I am using the single equality operator, so the assignment operator here but I am
using it on age, not on person,
right,
I'm not saying person is equal to something, that would fail if I set person to a new object,
this would fail but I'm setting age inside of the person to a new value, not person itself.
So I'm only setting a part of the data stored in memory to a new value just as we did it with the array
a second ago and therefore the data in memory certainly changes, the address does not and therefore the
address stored in the constant person also does not change.
I'm really emphasizing this because it is such a crucial concept and that can lead to a lot of confusion.
Constant, arrays and objects which suddenly change are a common source of confusion and the same is true
for data which you change in place A and it suddenly also changes in place b because people forgot or
never were aware that there is something like reference values which really matters a lot because it
explains all that behavior.
So this is a must know when you work with Javascript and I hope that these lectures really made it clear
what primitive values and reference values are, how they work, how they behave, why they are important, why
they are useful and how you work with them.