With event propagation, you can do quite interesting things,
specifically you can implement a pattern which is also called event delegation,
let me show you an example. Let's say in events.html,
so in our little demo file here, we have an unordered list here or any kind of list data,
that's where this pattern typically shines, with a couple of list elements in there,
item one and
then we also have more items - two, three, four and five.
Now I'll quickly add some style so that we can have some output there or that we see this at least a bit and
I'll style each list item to simply have a padding of 1rem and to have a border of one pixel solid
and then some other color here and the unordered list will get a list style of none to remove the bullet
points.
So some basic styling you can add to events.css and then this basic list here which I added to
my HTML file.
Now if we reload this, we see this list down there.
Now we want to be able to click on these items and color the clicked item red,
let's say that's our goal here,
if it is red already, we want to remove the color. Well for that, let's go to events.js and now of course
we've got two possible approaches.
One is that we select all list items and we add multiple listeners, so we could get all list items here
with document query selector all, select all li's and then use list items, forEach for example
to go through them or use a for/of loop of course and then on each list item, we can add an event listener,
for click event and then have a function in there where we get the event object and then in here,
we can say event target and then let's a class list because event target is a DOM element,
so we have the class list property available even though my IDE doesn't know it
and then here we simply toggle the highlight class let's say and now we just have to add this highlight
class to events.css, like this and there,
let's say we have a background color of red and a text color of white then. So this is something we can
do, define this highlight class, register multiple click listeners on all the elements
and now if we save and reload, we should be able to click them and toggle our colors here.
Now that is working,
however this approach has a couple of disadvantages.
For one it's pretty cumbersome to add multiple listeners like this,
additionally it can get bad from a performance and memory perspective because we got a lot of event
listeners out there.
So let's have a look at the alternative which uses this delegate pattern, this delegate approach. There
instead of adding multiple listeners on each list item, we take advantage of event propagation, of the
event bubbling up and therefore we get access to the entire list with document query selector ul,
so with the list that holds the list items.
Now we can register an event listener on that list, so I listen to a click event on the entire list because
since events bubble up, we can also listen to a click on the list when we actually clicked on a list
item because that's how Javascript events behave,
most events at least. So here I can now copy this logic here, this function, copy it in here because I
still want to use the event target and toggle highlight
and that's now by the way also the advantage of event target.
Even if my listener is registered on the list, event target will refer to the actual target on which we
clicked,
which in this example is our list item.
So now if I save that and I reload, I got the same behavior as before
but now with only one event listener instead of multiple event listeners because we're taking advantage
of event propagation and then we're adding a listener on the next higher element which in this case
is the list instead of every child element itself,
this is the event delegation pattern.
Now this event delegation pattern can become problematic if we have a more complex structure.
Let's say here for our list items, they are not simple like this,
instead inside of li, we got a h2 tag which wraps our item one text here and then next to that
or below that,
we also got a paragraph with some text.
Now let's say we have a couple of those items here,
so I'll just quickly copy and paste them and change the numbers here so that we can differentiate them
and auto format
and now if we reload, we have a problem, if I click on the title,
yes
now you see this gets the red background, not the entire element.
If I click somewhere else, the entire element might get this or just a paragraph.
So now because we were referring to event target, we have a problem,
we have a problem because event target is the actual DOM element on which we clicked
and that's the lowest possible element,
so that's either our h2 tag or if we clicked outside of h2 and outside of paragraph, it's the
entire list item or it's just a paragraph or whatever else we might have in there,
so just coloring or using event target is not helping us here.
Now we also do have another property available and that is event.currentTarget.
This is different from event target,
let's see if that helps us. If we reload and I click somewhere on the h2 tag,
well event current target is the entire unordered list here because current target, unlike target is
not the actual element on which you clicked but the element on which you added the listener.
So current target here always refers to the list element because that's where we register our listener.
So that can also be useful sometimes but here it isn't,
it's still not the element on which we clicked,
it's still not the list item, it's just a list which also is not what you need.
Well we can use a combination of event target and DOM traversal which I covered earlier in the course,
in the DOM module to get access to the list item.
What do we know about event target?
Well we know it's inside of our list and if we have a look at our list, we see it's definitely somewhere
inside of the list item,
right,
because we have just the list and the list items.
So we know it's inside of our list item,
hence it's either the h2 tag, the paragraph or the list item itself.
Now you learned about a specific method that can help us here and that would be on event target which
is some DOM object inside of our list,
the closest method. Closest exists on all DOM objects and it traverses up in the ancestor tree
and there you can select the closest element with a certain CSS selector, you could select by ID, by
class or just by tag
and in this case I'm looking for the closest li.
The cool thing is closest does include this element on what you call it itself.
So if we clicked on the list item itself, this will give us the list item itself, if we clicked on some
h2 tag inside of the list item,
this will give us the closest li ancestor which is this list item.
So it always gives us the closest list item which is exactly what we need here
and therefore here, we can now call class list toggle on the closest list item
and now this will work because now, no matter where we click, you see I always select the entire list
item and color the entire list item.
So this is now the perfect event delegation pattern because now we delegate our event and we still make
sure we worked with the right element, with a combination of event target and DOM traversal.