In this dummy application which I'm giving you here, we now actually already achieved the most important
improvements,
now there are smaller things where we could consider alternative code which might be better, though here
we really also get closer to these micro optimizations which you generally want to avoid and I'll come
back to them and why you might want to avoid them in a second.
Let me show you one thing or one part of our code that we could improve though,
for example here in delete product, this code for deleting a product. We can improve it and for performance,
we might gain a little bit
but we can at least improve it for simplicity reasons
because what we're doing here in the end is really a complex way of overriding our products array with
a new products array which of course also therefore is stored in memory and occupies some space there
when we don't really need to do that,
instead what we could do here is we could simply use the products array we're importing, arrays are reference
types
so when we work with the imported array here, we work with the one array which is set up and stored in
memory here and instead of overriding it with a new array of products, we can just get the index of
the item which should be deleted, deleted product index for example by using products find index, looping
through all products here in the anonymous function and finding the product where the ID is equal to prodId
I'm getting as an argument and then we can reach out to product, so to our array and use the splice
method you learned about in the Arrays and Iterables section to splice the element at this ID and
only that element and this would be a simple way of updating our products here.
Now I need to forward the deleted product here, so I want to store it before I remove it from the array,
deleted product, by reaching out to products and accessing the item at the deleted product index.
So now we store a pointer at this product here before we remove it from the array,
therefore since we still have a pointer it will live on and
we pass that pointer to update products. With that if we save that and we go back here and delete,
this still works but now actually here we have less complicated and probably also a bit faster code.
Another improvement we could make is in add product,
I'm always getting new access to title el and price el. Now since add product potentially runs more than
once,
we can also grab that because these elements will always be the same and turn them into module wide global
constants which we can use in the entire module file here because these items will never change. Also
when we select items here,
we have a bit of a too complex selector,
this will work but actually since every input here and in the end I'm reaching out to my inputs here
has an ID, we have a title ID and we have a price ID, we can also just use document get element by
ID instead of query selector because it turns out that document get element by ID is a bit faster
than document query selector,
so here let's call get element by ID in both places.
Make sure to remove the hash symbol here, the hashtag,
you don't need that when using get element by ID.
So now down to add product, we now of course can still retrieve our values here,
we can still do our validation, create a new product and add it so that's all fine
but now we improve this a little bit as well.
Now you should be careful with such optimisations though.