And this is it for this module.
We learned a lot about numbers and how Javascript works with them internally,
why we sometimes get strange results when working with floating point numbers and what we can do about
that.
We learned about the number and math object and had a look at how we can generate random numbers in
a certain interval for example
and now at the end, we had to look at strings and there specifically, at template literals with the tagged
templates syntax here where you have this strange combination of function and template literal
to have a function which Javascript with calls for you with certain arguments, which then allows you to change
your string, update it, run more complex logic to transform it or return even something totally different
than a string.
Now that might not be something you need every day but occasionally, it can be quite interesting to work
with that especially if you want to transform a certain value,
let's say you do have a price but you don't want to print the price
but such a category, the more categories you have, the more cumbersome it can get to do this all with
a ternary expression down there and then such a tagged template like we have it here can be a great alternative.