We're making progress and we're now able to render some text through our Web component.
Now still a lot of the logic is missing.
For example where we hover over this we get no event listeners that would do anything.
But we're getting there.
Step by step.
Let's now add such event listeners to see how we can quickly add more logic to this component which
we then can easily reuse by reusing our custom selector our custom aged him tag.
We want to listen to when we hover over that tooltip icon.
And then we want to show a tooltip for this.
I would simply add an event listener.
This is a normal DOM element and therefore we can call add event listener and we can listen to the built
in mouse enter event which is fired when the mouse enters.
This span in this case because I'm attaching it to that tooltip I can span.
Then I want to execute a function and for this I will create a new method which is simply a function
inside of a class.
And I will add this to this class.
Now I will name this method show tooltip.
Now I add it does underscore here to kind of make it clear that I only intend on calling this method
from inside this class.
As you learned earlier in the course JavaScript in the past didn't really have private methods and it
doesn't even have to write.
Now in all browsers there is is extra syntax with the hash in front of properties and methods to signal
that they should be private but it's in the early stages it's not supported everywhere.
So I'm using this convention which you'll find in a couple of programs out there where you add an underscore
in front of properties or methods which you want to mark as pseudo private so that you only intend on
calling these methods from inside the class.
And therefore even if you name it like this you can call it from outside to a by the way if you're wondering
what I mean with from outside.
Well since this is now a normal html element you can of course also select it with document query selector
and then you can access its properties and call its methods just like you can do it on any other H2
Al element.
So with an underscore in front of this name though I'm indicating that this is a method you should not
call.
You can still do it and we can't stop that but at least we're clear regarding our intention of how this
component should be used and if our developers are then using it or we are using it some time in the
future after we don't exactly remember how we created it then we know OK this is a method which should
only get called internally which we don't have to care about when we work with our component from outside.
So this show tooltip method is what I want to call.
So here I will call this show tooltip and important I don't add parentheses because I don't want to
execute this method here.
I only saved a pointer to this method and set this up as my event listener.
So did Wendy mouse entry Bento curse then the browser can automatically execute show tooltip now inside
of show tooltip ident 1 I will create a tooltip element which I can display for this altered and you
constant and I'll name it tooltip container and with documents create element.
I'll create a new element of type death again using one of the built in H two male elements.
If you have multiple custom elements you can of course also create those.
But here I will build an element that only uses primitives so only use this built in elements.
So I create a death here and in that tooltip container I can then set a text content of desist the tooltip
text which will make more generic and sellable by the user later.
And now of course it's all about attaching this container to the DOM and showing it there.
So for dead again I will access this.
This referring to the tooltip element and now there's just one thing to watch out for.
Due to the way that this keyword works in JavaScript we need to call bind this here when we point at
show tooltip.
This ensures that this keyword instead of show tooltip always refers to this class now here I can append
this child I can append my tooltip container to styling will be awful but it should work if we now save
that and we reload the browser.
If I now hover over it is question mark.
Indeed we see this as a tool to text.
Now it's not getting removed when I hover a way though you see that when I leave with the mouse it's
still there.
And if I hover over it again it adds more and more of these texts.
That makes a lot of sense because we never remove that when we leave with the mouse.
So I will duplicate my event listener up there and besides mouse enter.
I will also add mouse leave here and I will add a new private method height tool tip which should in
the end remove this tool tip container.
Now to access the tooltip container which I create and show tooltip and which therefore is not accessible
from insert height tooltip.
I'll turn this from a constant and show tooltip into a property of the whole class.
For it isn't a constructor which is a great place for basic initialization.
I'll add a new property by using this keyword and then dot and then the name of the property and that
property is basically just like a class wide away level variable and I will name that underscore to
all the marks that this is only used from inside the class underscore tooltip container and I will not
set an initial value so it's basically undefined initially but then here in Show tooltip I will store
discrete a div not in this constant but in this underscore tooltip container and that of course means
that the places where I used to the container like this and now have to become this underscore to the
container.
The advantage of this approach is that the newly created def is now stored in a class property and unlike
the constant this property is not just accessible from inside this method but from all the methods in
a class.
So now in height tooltip I can also access this tooltip container and remove that note and for that
I will actually access this remove child and I will remove that to the container.
Child now when we leave this with the mouse if we don't hover over the question mark anymore this tool
to container which was added should be removed.
However of course that means that I now also need to hook high tooltip up as a method that should be
executed for mouse leaf.
Now if that if I save that and we reload this page now when I hover over a question mark the tooltip
still gets added but if I now leave with the mouse it's gone and now we have a tooltip that only shows
up whilst we hover over the question mark.
Now obviously styling is missing and the question mark is still positioned incorrectly but this is a
never great step forward and we can already see some custom logic doing its job in our web component
because you must never forget that this whole hovering lodge against on all happens inside of our web
component and that already means that if we copy that and we add another tooltip.
So another instance of this element somewhere else.
Here we go.
Then there will also have this question mark or which we can hover so we can easily reuse this functionality
already.
Now of course it would be nice if we had more styling more flexibility regarding our tool to text and
so on.
So let's work on that tooltip text next because having this generic dummy text here this is the tooltip
text does not make a lot of sense.
The text here should be sensible from outside instead.
So let's take care about that in the next lecture.