So let's copy the link into the clipboard and for that of course, we can use the clipboard API.
I briefly touched on this already in earlier modules,
If you search for MDN clipboard API, you can learn more about it and most importantly, you'll learn
that browser support is mixed.
So we should definitely check whether it is supported by the browser we're running our code in before
we just blindly use it.
So first of all, I'll comment in this add event listener code here in the constructor and point at a let's
say share place handler method,
this share place handler.
Now we have to add such a method here, maybe directly below the constructor for that to work and in there,
I now want to use the clipboard API of course.
So I'll first of all check if navigator clipboard is not a thing, which means the browser does not support
it
in which case I want to return and not continue
and instead as a fallback, just select the text, so that at least the user just has to press control
c and doesn't have to select the full URL. Now to select the URL, I need access to the input, for
that we can copy that code here where we get access to that input element, of course we could have also
therefore initialized it here in the constructor and stored it in a property if you wanted to, here
I'll just copy it and then in here in the if statement, set or call shared link input element select. We
trigger the select event here which the end selects the entire content in there and marks it. Just to prove
that it works, let's do it outside of this if check and let's then get the current location so that
such a link gets generated and now if I click share place, you see this is selected. So now I just have to
press control c which is better than nothing but of course if the browser supports it, I want to take
that one step further and not just do this as a fallback in this if check but if we make it past this
if check, we know we have support for the clipboard API, then I want to use navigator clipboard and call
write text, this write
text method on the clipboard object and write my text which is in that input into the clipboard of
the user, so shared link input element.value, that's the link we generated and that's now stored in a
clipboard of the user.
Now this returns a promise and we could use async await, just to mix it up here, I will use then and catch
and in the then block, we know that this succeeded,
so here I'll just throw an alert, copied into clipboard so that we get some feedback
and here we might get an error which I will just log here to the console,
we could then as a fallback since it failed at least mark it again.
So now with that, if we save all of that and I clear my clipboard by copying something else, you see now
I got enabled in my clipboard,
now if I click get current location, still got enabled there,
if I now click share place, it's copied into clipboard and indeed, here it is.
So now this worked,
now I got this in my clipboard and now the only missing thing is that if I visit this page here, we load
a new page as you can tell, we load that other index.html file in the my-place folder, here I want
to show the address here in the header and render the map here,
share a new place always takes us back to this page
so I just want to make these two things work now and we'll be done for this little demo application
here.