Time to comment this all out again and dive in more examples.
So let's say here, we have another array, prices where we have a bunch of numbers like
this
and now we want to do something with every price,
we want to add tax on it. So we might have a tax here,
Germany that's 19% value added tax and now we want to get the adjusted prices, so tax adjusted
prices is an empty array initially.
Now what we can do is we can add a for loop and go through all prices, like this here and then we could
push a new item onto tax adjusted prices,
we can do that despite it being a const because it's a reference type and we never assign a new value
to that constant,
we just change the data in memory, check out the behind the scenes module if that's brand new to you,
there I talk about that.
So now we can push a new item onto it and that would be price times one plus tax for example
and if I then console log the tax adjusted prices here, that will just work. If I now reload this, here
we have the tax adjusted prices.
Let's ignore this strange float value here,
that's something I'll come back to in the number
deep dive section,
it's not a bug or anything like that,
it's just some number imprecision
computers can have with floating point numbers. So generally that all works though, that's the main takeaway
and there's nothing wrong with that.
They're just also is an alternative to the for/of loop,
not saying though that anything is wrong with the for/of loop
but if you would for example need the index for some reason, then you don't have that available here
in the for/of loop, instead you could use a regular for loop of course where you manually manage
the index in the end or you just use another nice method you have on arrays and that's the ForEach method.
The ForEach method, just like find and find index, takes a function and that function which it takes
takes three arguments or up to three arguments. The value it's currently looking at, because just like
the function you pass to find and find index, this function executes for every element in the array,
so here we get our price let's say, then the index or idx or however you want to name this argument
and then the full array in case you're interested but I won't need that here, just for completeness sake
I'll add it here. By the way, the fact that I use the same name as I do here is not an issue here because
of shadowing, this has a different scope here,
right?
It has its own block scope in the end,
this is in the end like a variable of this block
so it has its own scope and therefore if I use a name that's defined outside of it,
well for inside this function, this outside constant is simply overwritten, not here of course
so this will work, just if it would try to access it from inside the function.
Of course you could also pick a different name here for prices but due to this shadowing process and
block scope, it also won't be a problem.
Well and now in here, we could do the same thing I did in my for/of loop. So of course the only difference
therefore is that I don't use for/of which on its own isn't necessarily an advantage but the advantage
could be that if you need it you have to index available here.
So if you also would want to transform your entries to objects where you store the index, that would
be fairly easy to do here. Price object could be an object where you have the index, which is now that
idx value and then the tax adjusted price which is that price we're calculating with that formula
and then we could push the price object here and now we get access to the index which we don't have
in the for/of loop.
So with that if I now save that and reload, we see we now have an array of objects with index zero tax adjusted
price, index one tax adjusted price and so on.
So that's ForEach, an alternative for/of
which has the extra benefit of giving you easy access to the index
and in general, simply an alternative you could use instead of for loops if you want. Using for loops
is not bad though, both is possible and simply an option.