So in this module, we had a thorough look at Javascript's
different versions, its past and its present, at var and let, block scope versus function and global scope,
the implications of that. Strange behaviors you could implement especially when using var and strict
mode to avoid that, though as I mentioned using let and const already prohibits a lot of these strange
behaviors
and in general the syntax and the patterns I show you in this course will use none of these strange and
actually to be avoided patterns and behaviors.
And besides all these language specific things, you also learned a lot about how the browser actually handles
your code, how it interprets and compiles it. You learned how your code executes with the help of the stack,
the heap and what the Javascript engine does with these things. You learned about primitive and reference
values, important concepts which can lead to a lot of confusion if you don't understand them
which is why I covered them with great detail in this module and we also finish this up with a look
at garbage collection and how to avoid memory leaks, though as I mentioned, we'll have a whole module
later where we dive into performance optimization and avoiding memory leaks in Javascript programs.
So that is a look behind the scenes of Javascript,
a look into its past, into its weaknesses and potential fixes for it, like the modern syntax, strict
mode and so on and what the browser actually does with our code and how it works internally.
That is super important to know if you want to be a Javascript developer because you need to know your
language, you need to know what it does and you need to know how to write proper code. For all of this,
this module hopefully was very helpful. With that,
let's go back from the theoretical side here, back into more code and into more language features which
we can use in our scripts.