So now we had a first look at classes, we're using some classes to split our logic and we're also using
classes in different ways.
We have our class with the static properties and the static methods to glue together some of the other
classes and that's just one possible use case, static methods and static properties are always a good
idea if you want to share some functionality across different parts of your application
or like in this case, if you want to share some data or use this as kind of a communication interface
you could say.
Now of course that's not all you can do with classes or that's not all
that's to classes. Before we dive into more things we can do with classes though and before we can
work on this app a little bit more because right now for example this cart total of course is not
behaving correctly,
let me take a step back and go back to the relation between classes and the objects you work with in
Javascript.
For one of course it's important to realize that if you're not using a class in a static way like this
here but instead by instantiating with new, what new shop in this case here returns,
so what's stored in the shop constants here is a regular Javascript object or a reference to that object
to be precise.
So it's in the end the same as what you get with that object literal notation,
I really want to emphasize this. As a result, you can of course use all the things on these objects as
you can do on normal objects because these are just normal objects.
You can for example use destructuring to get the cart out of shop if you wanted to do that,
something like that is possible, it's really important to understand this relation.
It's also important to understand when to use classes. You might think that with classes,
the old way of creating objects with the object literal notation is obsolete and that would be wrong,
It's not obsolete,
it's great to use that object literal notation if you have some data collection, a couple of variables
which you in the end want to group together and where you only want to do this once or in one place of
your app, of your code and you don't plan on reusing that.
So not as we're doing it with the product where we need that in different places, where we want to
ensure that they always have the same structure but where you quickly want to create such an object on
the fly,
that's a perfect use case for using object literals.
They're quick and easy to use,
you have no extra overhead and you also have a small performance benefit versus this class based
instantiation which is quickly made up for though
if you would unnecessarily create multiple objects with object literals instead of using classes and
therefore sharing code, just to also say that. So classes in general are a good idea
if you have some logic which you want to reuse, if you want to recreate the same type of object with
the same structure and the same attached logic over and over again like in that demo application we worked
on. You have a little bit more overhead initially because you need to write that class definition but
thereafter, you have that easy object duplication, of course not really a duplication instead
new objects are created with that same internal structure but with different data, depending on how your
class works of course.
So both is important and both has its place in Javascript and it's simply also something that comes
with experience and with you working with Javascript, that you get a better feeling for when to use which.
In this example application here, classes make a lot of sense because that allows us to cleanly split
our code and we are actually reusing quite a lot of these classes or the logic attached to these classes
in different places of our code.
So here, having classes makes a lot of sense.