Now let me have a closer look at our text here, at our string which we're combining from a couple of
substrings.
Now for one I mentioned that you can use single or double quotes and the decision is really up to you,
you can go for either of the two solutions,
I will use single quotes throughout the course but that's just my personal preference, not something you
have to use.
However, you should be consistent and stick to your choice thereafter.
What you can't do is mix your characters, so you can't open a string with a double quote and try to close
it with a single quote,
this will not work,
you always have to close a string with the character,
so with double quote or single quote with which you opened it.
So this string here for example is opened with a double quote and then I have no other double quote,
therefore this string never gets closed,
that actually therefore is invalid Javascript code and hence my IDE already complains here that
this is an unterminated string literal so that this string has no end
and if we would try to run this code and reload our page,
indeed if you look into the developer tools again, you'll get an error.
Now the interesting thing actually is if I do close it with a double quote,
now everything in between will be treated as one text.
So when you open something with single or double quotes, everything in between the opening and closing
single or double quotes will be one piece of text, which makes sense if you think about it.
How would Javascript know whether you want to create a new string there,
there also is nothing like a string inside of a string?
Instead if we now reload the page, we got rid of our error but now our whole we want to create a string
code is actually treated as one piece of text and therefore output as such here.
So you always have to close your string with what you opened it and everything in between will be treated
as text.
Now you can take advantage of this if you for example want to print this single quote character because
right now if I use just single quotes and no double quotes and the same would be true if you were just
using double quotes and no single quotes, if I reload, we get the output we saw before
but what if I actually did want to output a single quote character here?
Well then, you could try to add a single quote inside of a single quote but this won't work, instead
what now happens is that Javascript creates a string here and creates a string here and in between, it
has this bracket which actually leads to some invalid Javascript code overall here because we're not
using any operators that would try to concatenate that and even if we would, a single opening bracket
like this is not valid Javascript code.
So if you want to output the single quote character, you can actually take advantage of the double quotes
and for example wrap your code, your string that contains the single quote which you want to output, between
double quotes because now we use double quotes to create the string, everything in between the treated
as text and therefore if we save that and we reload,
now we see the single quotes here as well.
So that's one way of outputting single quotes if you wanted to, you could deviate from the rule of sticking
to either a single or double quotes and make an exception if you really want to output the single or
double quotes you otherwise use as your string delimiters.
Here of course, I don't really want to print my single quotes so I don't need to do that.
Now we'll dive into strings again and again throughout the course because there are more things you can do
with them,
one thing I want to do right away is restructure this string.
We're building our string here with three pieces of text you could say, with the opening parentheses,
with this code thereafter or with this text thereafter and with the value that's stored in default result.
Now in such cases, you can actually also use back ticks instead of single quotes.
So this is now not a single quote,
this is the back tick character which you'll find on your keyboard, get rid of all other single quotes
you actually have and get rid of these pluses you used to combine your strings, only keep the plus which
you want to output on the page and replace the closing single quote
also with the closing back tick or with the back tick.
So now I got two back ticks which surround my text and therefore now if I save this, unsurprisingly here
I say default result instead of the value which is actually stored in that default result constant
but now back ticks give you access to a special syntax.
You can now use a dollar sign in here and then an opening and closing curly brace and now you can put
your variable or any expression which yields some result, which can be output as text,
so you could also have a calculation like one plus one in here, so you can put that between your opening
and closing curly braces
now and what this does is it tells Javascript to output the value that's in this constant in this case in
this place of your text. So it will not output the dollar sign or the curly brace,
instead it will output the value of the expression as it's called,
so in this case of the constant you have between the opening and closing curly brace. So if you now save
that file and you reload, you'll see zero here which indeed is the value we have in default
result. This only works with back ticks, if you used single or double quotes,
this dollar sign curly brace thing would be treated as regular text and therefore output as such as you
can see.
So this is a really nice feature, using these back tics with this dollar sign curly brace thing,
if you have some text in which you want to embed or inject some dynamic value, so the result of some
calculation or the value that's stored in a variable or a constant, then this is simply shorter, it saves
you the manual string concatenation which we previously had to do where we combined multiple strings with
the plus operator,
this is simply a bit shorter and therefore how you typically would build a string that includes dynamic
values.
This overall construct here is called a template literal, so if you ever Google for Javascript template
literal, you'll find exactly this piece of syntax.
Now there's actually more to it and we'll dive deeper into it throughout this course
but this is the most basic and I would say most important form of using it because that's the form
where you will work with it most often to have some text into which you inject or embed some dynamic
value.
Now some additional information about strings and template literals as we have it here.
One convenient thing about template literals is that you can easily write multiline strings there. Now
with multiline strings, I mean strings which really do have a line break in them.
So let's say here in front of the asterisk character, I add a couple of line breaks and hence this string
looks like that might look a bit strange at first but this is valid Javascript syntax,
we opened a string here, we close it here and since it is a template literal with back ticks, this is
allowed. For a normal string with single or double quotes, this would not be allowed but I will come back
to that. Now if you save that and you reload this in the browser, you'll not see a difference, though if
you have the developer tools opened which you can always open with view
developer, developer tools and you then click on this select icon there and you select this part of
your webpage, you will see that indeed the whitespace is considered here,
it's just the browser and the default behavior of the browser and the h2 element that basically strips
this redundant whitespace but it's output there and depending on where you output this, in which element
and how that element is styled, you might also get that whitespace or the extra line break here in your
webpage.
So the fact that we don't see the line break here in the middle is really just due to how this is styled
and rendered.
If you go down here to the elements style of the h2 element which is selected and you add whitespace
pre for example, then you will see the whitespace here as well because this is some CSS styling
which does not omit the extra whitespace but instead render it, here in this case that means it renders
this extra line break. So you can easily add line breaks here when using the template literal syntax,
this can help you with readability because you might be able to read long strings easier or better here
in the IDE if you add line breaks but you should always keep in mind that this is not just a visual
thing for you in the IDE but that the line breaks really are part of the string.
The same is true if you indent this, for example you could think that if you write it like this, it's
a normal string but it's more readable to you as a developer.
Well if you save that and you reload, our styling will be lost because we reloaded but here on the right
you can see this extra whitespace,
it really is part of the string and if we re-add this style here to our h2 element here in the developer
tools by setting whitespace to pre, you see we really do have the line break and the extra whitespace
in here. So be careful when you use that and really only use the line break or extra whitespace feature
here
if you want to build a string that has the extra whitespace or that has the line break, don't do it just
for readability.
Now if I come back to normal strings, there
let's say we have an error message which we don't need for this app or for this website here but just
to demonstrate how we work with normal, which means non-template literal strings,
then of course you use single or double quotes and you might have a message like an error occurred, something
like this.
If you would want to split this across multiple lines, you have two options - you can close the string
here by adding a single quote and then reopen a new one and combine them with a plus and then add a
line break,
this is valid Javascript code, you can span expressions that use operators across multiple lines,
that would be possible here for mathematical operations just as it is possible for concatenating strings
with the plus operator
and here you can also indent. If you do this and you would output this somewhere on the webpage,
this indeed would not include a line break and also not extra whitespace because this is really just
something we do for us here in the IDE to make this more readable. The string that's getting constructed
only consists of these characters between the single quotes, so there's no line break in there and there
is also no extra whitespace.
Now if you would want to add a real line break here in a string enclosed by single or double quotes,
that is possible with a special character or a special combination of characters - you add a backslash
and then n. What this will do if it would be rendered to the screen is it will not output \n
there but instead it will treat this as a line break. To show this,
let's temporarily output the error message here instead of the calculation description, just temporarily
so that we can see that.
Now with that if you reload here, we see an error occurred and if we go back and add our good old style
here to the h2 element right in developer tools down there by setting whitespace to pre, you see the
line break here as well and you can also see it here,
there is a line break after error.
So with this \n, you can add a line break in a string no matter if you use single or double
quotes, you could also use this here in the template literal by the way,
it's also supported there but there you don't need it because there you can just add a normal line break
and since you're in a template literal, that will add a line break to the string as well.
So there, this is available, here in a normal string with single or double quotes, you need that \n
thing.
And by the way, using a backslash in a string has a special meaning, it escapes the character that comes
after the backslash, which means the character after the backslash is not treated as a normal character
with its normal meaning but instead combined with the backslash, it gets a special meaning.
In this case here, we escaped the n and therefore we don't just output n here but instead backslash
and n combined mean line break.
You have more such combinations and attached, you will find a list of available shortcuts or combinations
here in your strings. One other important combination for example is backslash and then a single quote.
This is helpful if you want to output a single quote in your string, especially if your string is enclosed
by single quotes. Without the backslash, we would have a syntax error here because what happens is we
open a string with a single quote, here we then close it and then here in this case, we have a redundant
single quote that tries to open a new string which then never gets closed.
So we have to tell Javascript that this single quote should not be used as it normally uses single quotes,
i.e. to close that string but instead that we want to output this single quote here as a normal character
in our text and adding a backslash in front of it escapes the meaning the single quote would otherwise
have and therefore allows us to do that, and of course an alternative always is to use double quotes
to surround the string instead of single quotes and then you can use single quotes in the double quoted
string without issues and without escaping it because it then won't have that special meaning of finishing
your string or closing your string because you can only close a string with the character with which
you opened it
and since here, we opened a string with a double quote character, we can only close it with such and Javascript
won't interpret a single quote as please close my string character,
still useful to know that you could escape it like this. By the way if you want to output a backslash
in the string, you need to escape this as well because otherwise, a single backslash always tells Javascript
that the character after the backslash should be considered or should be escaped.
So if you want to output just a backslash, you put another backslash in front of it to tell Javascript
hey the character after this backslash has a special meaning and double backslash then in fact tells
Javascript I want to output a single backslash here as part of my string. So these are some of the useful
things that you should know about strings,
you will encounter them throughout this course
and throughout your career as a developer. You don't need to learn all these things by heart,
the attached list of escapable characters might be useful, though \n, \\
and backslash single quote are the most important ones I would argue, the ones you typically use most
often.
And being aware of the template literal, that you can interpolate content here and that you can easily
add line breaks and whitespace in here,
that's also something which is good to know I guess.
And with that, I reverted all of that, again I'm sending a calculation description to output result and
I deleted the extra error message variable because we don't need it here to continue,
I just wanted to dive into some of these string specialties and things you should know.