Let's explore memory leaks.
Now for that we got that memory tab and attached you find an article from the official Google Chrome
developer tool documentation where you can learn all about that tab
and here one of the most useful things you can do is click on take heap snapshots to take a heap snapshot,
then do some operation for example delete a carpet and take another snapshot and then go to comparison
here in the dropdown to see the difference to the last snapshot
and this allows us to find out what changed in memory which can be helpful for finding problems. So here
for example we see a script element was added, which makes sense,
that's the lazy loading going on, that's what webpack does behind the scenes when we load the code for
deleting and yes other than that, a bunch of things were added,
lot of things which are going on here are really just not directly related to your code.
What we can see is that for example when we talk about HTML elements, it doesn't look like we have
a difference, it doesn't seem like we actually got rid of a button and an li element,
so that's not too good because we removed one so it should be gone.
So let's maybe run another snapshot and compare it to the previous one and see if we see a difference
there, maybe by sorting for delta and looking at the things which got removed first
but even there, we see what was touched is not really the li element, the button element and so on,
right.
We had one deleted but we also had one added,
so it doesn't really look like we got rid of our element here with the current approach. If you click
on that garbage
icon here, you can also let the garbage collector run but if we take another snapshot thereafter,
well we still don't see any difference right.
No matter how we order this, nothing was removed.
So it looks like our li elements are not getting removed here from the DOM when we actually delete
items.
So now let's see how we can find and fix this potential memory leak
we have. For that again, I'll take an initial snapshot here, then delete an item,
take another snapshot, confirm that we still have that potential issue
by having a look at my changes here and here, oh it now actually is gone.
Now you might or might not be seeing this,
i ran this multiple times and most of the time i didn't see this getting cleaned up here,
now it is cleaned up though.
Well let's give it another try,
let's clear these profiles,
take a snapshot,
delete an item,
have a look at the comparison,
check
delta
and we're back to where we were before.
So let's have a look at the summary then
and there you can search for li element and you'll find this HTML li element summary here.
Now if you expand this, you'll see a bunch of li elements, more than we have on the page,
we have four,
here i see eight
and now let's see if we can kind of find out which element here belongs to which element on the screen.
For that, we can select an element here and then at the bottom, you have this retainers view and
here we see just a bunch of strange proto stuff.
So this doesn't look like an actually rendered element here because if we go to the second one and
we close this, here we actually see related elements or objects and for example we see a HTML
button element and if you hover over this, one of the buttons on the left should highlight.
So this clearly is an element which is currently rendered.
Let's go to the next element, close this, find the button, hover over it,
okay
this is the last element,
so this also seems to be rendered.
Let's check this element here, hover over that button,
it's the second one.
So let's go to this element,
hover over the button,
it's the third one.
So we can say that these three elements here are currently rendered,
they also all have the same retained size here on the right
which makes sense since they're all in the same state.
We don't know what the first one is, might be the internal constructor function which Javascript is
aware of of course because if you create a new HTML li element, Javascript in the end will call
such a constructor function
so that's probably what this is
and these three here, these are really just old objects lingering around ready for cleanup. Here if i see
that, i also got a button element but if i hover over this, no button is getting highlighted. We also
see this has a greater distance than the other items, the distance in the end is kind of an indicator
of how actively this is used, the smaller the distance, the more actively it's getting used,
so this is clearly not getting used a lot and the retained size is also smaller.
So it's probably a browser thing that this doesn't get removed,
it's probably not a mistake on our side.
Now let me show you how a mistake and a real memory leak could look like though. Let's say for whatever
reason we're keeping track of all the elements we're creating,
so we have a constant, maybe here, rendered products which should be an array which exists in the rendering.js
file. Now this is an array
and now whenever we add a new product, we want to add this here,
so we have our rendered products and there I push my new product el onto this array. We're maybe doing
this so that thereafter we can console log all the rendered products we rendered in the past or
we have currently on the screen.
Now if i save this, now we go to the console first of all, if I now add a new product here, we see this list
item. If I add another new product, we see both list items here in the array,
so that is working.
However if i now delete an item here, you will see that if i add yet another new item, the one which
i deleted is also still part of the array.
So we can already see that we might have a problem here and i can prove that we have a problem if we
go to the memory tab,
let's clear the existing snapshots and take a new one
and now let's delete this item and take another new one.
Now if we go to comparison view, we still don't see that a list item was removed here.
Now we had this before but if we now go to the summary view and search for list element, then we see
a problem here. We see in the HTML li elements, we've got a bunch of elements here, 10 to be precise
and there are some which are currently rendered, here if we hover over the button, we see which button
gets highlighted
but we also see some, for example this one here, which is currently not rendered.
Now we had this before but now this is probably not a mistake by the browser here because we also
find this detached HTML li element thing.
So this is a hint that
something seems to be wrong with our li element and indeed we see it stored in some array. So whilst
this might be hard to read because there's a lot of stuff in there, we suddenly have a new element here
in our list here, the detached HTML li element
and when we inspect it, it tells us that it's stored in some array, that some array holds a reference
to it.
So these are now indicators before we also had some li elements here which weren't cleaned up but
we couldn't find any issue in our code.
Now here with this extra hint, we should take another look and indeed of course here we have a memory
leak, every newly added item, every newly added DOM object is added to this array.
Now since i don't remove the items from the array when we remove them from the DOM, they are in a detached
state,
the DOM node was removed, the underlying Javascript object wasn't. Normally when you remove a DOM node,
the browser also destroys the underlying Javascript object but if you have another reference to that object
as we do have it here where we also point at that DOM object from inside an array, the browser of
course does not delete the Javascript object because it thinks you still plan on working with it,
well maybe you do but here it's just an oversight.
What we should do when we really want to keep track of elements like this is we should try to also clean
them up when we remove them from the DOM, for example by ID or of course we just don't keep track
of them at all,
maybe there is another way of achieving what we want it to do.
This is a typical example for a memory leak, that you point at elements in your code which you remove
in the DOM but which you then don't clean up in your code and with the memory tools here in the browser
dev tools, as you just saw you can search for such problems.
It requires some experience and trial and error probably but you can look for strange patterns and
see if there is something you should check in your code which might not be entirely correct.