So we got syntax errors which we can typically fix right in the IDE, other runtime errors which we can
fix with the help of error messages by looking at them,
now let's have a look at logical errors which are a bit harder to find.
Let's say in my application here, when we add, then we're getting the user number input here,
right,
so that's triggering this function and there, let's say we're not doing that in parseInt, we're not converting
this to a number.
Of course we're doing it here
but let's say we're not at this point yet,
we forgot to add this code. That would be a typical logical error,
everything will work technically but the app will not behave the way it should
because we have a logical error in our code because now if I go back and I reload this page and I go
back to the console here, you see if I enter a five here, we get this output which we saw and fixed in
the last course module right, where the text is kind of concatenated instead of being calculated as a
number.
Now, we got no error message here
so that's hard,
so what can we do in such a case?
Well we can get started with some good old console log debugging.
We know that the behavior is not correct when I click the plus button,
so we could go to that add function here which is the function getting triggered when we click the plus
button and there, we could throw in a console log statement.
Now let's console log the entered number here and let's maybe also console log the current result and
you can console log multiple values here in one and the same console log statement.
You can also combine this with some text, for example here I'll output input and this will simply print this
text next to these values here so that if you have multiple console log statements, you can find this
quicker.
OK,
so with that added, let's go back,
let's reload here and here five, hit plus, we see input, then we see five and then we see zero
and this doesn't make it super obvious the way it's printed here but we can see that 5 and 0 look
different right
even though both should be numbers. The 0 is blue and looks more number-ish if you will, the 5 is black
just like the input text.
So if you're really having a closer look here, you can already spot the problem which of course is that
5 is treated as a string and 0 is treated as a number and therefore as you learned, this will be concatenated
to a string instead of combined as a number or added as a number
but it's still a bit hard to spot it here but you can get there with console log debugging.
You can also have multiple console log statements in your code to understand the flow of your code,
if you're not sure if something is executed in the right order, you could throw in multiple dummy console
log statements to see if they are executed in the right order. Now
as I said, we can fix this error here with console log but we might not be able to spot the problem just
yet. In such a case, you can use the Chrome dev tools and there,
go to the sources tab where you essentially find all the files Chrome loaded for displaying this web
page.
So here you find your HTML file but then you basically find the same folder structure I have because
that's the folder structure that was loaded for this web page and you can go into the scripts folder
and there you find the two scripts that make up this web page and here we can go into the app.js file
and find the exact same code I wrote here because that is the code that was loaded by the browser and
now here you can do something neat,
you can place breakpoints.