There are two other ways of transforming an array.
Let's say instead of getting our tax adjusted prices here, we're happy with the original prices array
but we want to sort it because right now as you can tell, it's clearly not sorted. For that you have
another method which you can call and I'll store that sorted array in a new constant, sorted prices and
you call that on an array, just like map and so on
and that's the sort method.
Now this will sort the array and let's see what this gives us, if we console log sorted prices here and
save that and I reload,
these are my sorted prices.
Well, are they? This does really look sorted,
it's certainly not the original order though. There, 5.99 was the second element,
now it's the third one but it's also not sorted correctly.
Well the thing is sort by default converts everything to a string and then it's simply sorts this
in a string logic and there, one is smaller than three
for example, this is how it sorts it,
now that's not what we want here.
The good thing is you can pass your own function to sort, a function which takes two numbers, a compare
function in the end. You can label these parameters A and B, the name is up to you and what this does
is it executes these functions on pairs of elements here and it always gives you these two elements
which it's currently comparing and then you should return for that pair of elements which it is comparing,
whether A,
so the first value is greater than B, if they're equal or if B is greater and then it will swap these
two values if needed based on that and move on to the next pair,
so to one of the values it just swapped and the next value in line. Let's see that in practice because that
will clarify things.
So here we can add an if check in a function because we will need to return one of three values, is A greater
than B,
are they equal or is B  greater? So let's check if A is greater than B, what should return in that case is
1.
So you return 1 and it should be 1 if A is greater than B,
else if A is equal to B and it's up to you whether you will use a triple or a double equality check here
depending on which kind of data you are sorting, you return 0.
So if they're equal, you return 0,
well you can probably guess what you return in the else case which is that B is greater than A, well then you
return -1.
So 1 positive if A is greater than B, zero if they're equal, -1
if B is greater
and if you now do that and you reload, now this looks much better
and now we have a correctly sorted list here for our number logic.
Now of course which logic you have in here in your function you pass to sort totally is up to you
and depends on the kind of data you have in your array which you are trying to sort.
Here for numbers, such a comparison makes sense,
you could be checking anything in here though.
Now that sort
kind of related to it is another function which you can call on arrays and that is reverse.
Well and this does just what it sounds like,
you can't pass any arguments to it, it simply reverses in array.
So here I first sort the array and then I output the reversed array, so hence if I reload
now we get the highest number first and the lowest number last.
Now side note, here of course I'm just showing that to show you reverse,
if you indeed do find yourself writing such code, it would always be better to just inverse your sorting
logic,
this would also sort from highest to lowest and save you that extra reverse call here,
right?
So no need to do that double sorting and reversal if you can just adjust your sort logic,
so this here also yields the same.
I just wanted to show you reverse here
and of course it's good to know reverse because you're not always sorting, sometimes you have an array
which generally has the right order, just for this specific use case,
you want to reverse it,
well then reverse is your friend.