Now with our two workflows setup, we're generally done but there are two improvements I want to implement
here,
one is our assets scripts folder, it grows and grows and whenever we build something new and files our
names slightly different, the old files are kept around and the new files are added.
Now this is not ideal,
instead I would want to clear my scripts folder with every build and then just add the newly generated
files there to get rid of the old files which I really don't need anymore
and that's easy to do with webpack,
we just have to tweak the configuration a little bit,
we have to install a new package first of all with npm install --save-dev, you know that,
and then it's clean-webpack-plugin. This installs a new package which we can implement in
our webpack config, in our webpack workflow that cleans up the
webpack output folder, so the path you're specifying here, in our case assets scripts. To use it in a webpack
config file,
I just have to import it, again with this const syntax, clean plugin could be a name you want to use
there and require clean-webpack-plugin. Now clean plugin can be used in our webpack config file,
we just have to add a new entry, a new config item there which is called plugins. Now plugins is a
concept in webpack which allows you to apply various optimizations or transformations on the generated
output so to say, so not on the individual files but on the generated output or in case of the clean
plugin, on the output folder before the output is written to it.
Plugins is an array because you can apply more than one plugin but here I only need one plugin and
that's my clean plugin. For that here, for this plugin,
we create new, then clean plugin.clean-webpack-plugin and execute this as a function,
so we create a new object of that type so to say. In case you're wondering how I know this, from the official
docs, you learned all of that in the official docs and the docs really are the place to learn that.
Now of course I don't just want to add this here in the normal webpack config file but also in the prod file.
So there let's also add a comma after dev tool and add plugins
and of course also add the import here,
so copy that from webpack config into webpack config prod. If we do that and we repeat npm run build
prod, we'll see that our scripts folder now is a bit emptier because all the unused files were deleted
which is indeed what I want.
So that's one nice thing that's good to have,
that's one useful improvement, another improvement is the naming of these files.
I'm generally fine with these names but if you would deploy these files to a server, so if you take your
web page or the HTML files and the scripts that belong to them and you move that onto a server and users
start visiting your page, then browsers will typically cache Javascript and CSS files which means
they store copies of these files
and if the file hasn't changed, the next time the user visits a page, they will keep that stored, that
cached file.
Now that is an improvement which often makes sense and you can control it from a server side by setting the
right headers on your resources which is a server admin task and not really directly related to Javascript
but you can also force browsers to download a new version of a file by simply changing the file name
because then it's a new file to the browser and it will therefore for download it and not use any cached
version. Now for that, we want to generate these file names automatically and generate a new file name
whenever we produce a new build
and that's something where webpack also helps us.
It makes it easy for us to add, not a random but a deterministic but unique element to every file name
which changes with every build. For that
all we have to do is go to our config and there, let's say to our production config because that really
only matters for our production output and there in the output config, in the file name, we can add a
dynamic element, we can add square brackets here like this and there, enter content hash and it has to
be written like this because this is a keyword to webpack which tells webpack that a hash should be
generated here, a hash that is different whenever a file changed,
if a file didn't change, webpack will keep the existing hash. If we do that and we save this, you'll
see what I mean when we rerun npm run build prod.
If we have a look at our output in the scripts folder, you now see we have names like this.
So this is now an output which will change every time we change the underlying files and we rebuild and
therefore since since the file name now changes, browsers will redownload these files.
Of course we now just need to make sure that in our index.html file, we update this import to
meet our latest hash here, only for production
however because if I go back to dev, then this will not be the case,
there output files are actually not written to the scripts folder which is why it's now empty but instead
store it in the memory
but they also wouldn't be renamed because in the webpack config file which is used for development, I'm
still using app.js as an entry file.
So there if we test this during development with the webpack dev server at localhost:8080 here, it still
works as before, if we build for production however, we get our output files in the scripts folder and
then they will have these dynamic names, then we'll just have to adjust this name here in index.html
and then we can take our code and upload it to some server to have the changed file names
if our content change there and we therefore want to reflect this on our server and force browsers
to take the latest version of our scripts. And that's the final optimization I wanted to implement here
to make sure that we really produce output which is production ready and could now be pushed to a server,
something we'll by the way also do in the deployment section of this course.