Now we're done for this module
but here's a little bonus. With our enhanced project setup now where we use npm to manage our development
dependencies and webpack to bundle our code and the webpack
dev server, we now also got a new way of adding third-party packages.
Let's take lodash again as an example,
you saw that in the libraries module, here
I will add it again. Now in the libraries module,
I showed you that you can download the script or fetch such a CDN link and add all these imports in
your index.html file.
Well now that we actually use npm and bundling, we got a third way of adding lodash or any other third
party library
basically. We can scroll down to the installation and there we see that with npm, we can actually install
lodash with this command,
so let's copy that and execute it here in the terminal navigated into our project folder.
It's npm i which is just a short form for npm install --save, not save dev because it's not
a development dependency but actually a dependency which we need as part of our final code which we
ship and then the name of the package which is lodash.
Now if you hit enter, this is getting installed and once this process finished, it will for one be added
to the node modules folder and you also see you now have a new dependencies entry with lodash
as a dependency in your package.json
file. Now
that alone does not add it to your project though,
it just added to your folder but not to your web application, to your script.
if you would want to use lodash though, let's say here in the app.js file, you can now import it,
the convention is to import third-party packages first but that's not a must do and you can import it
as shown here, with this require syntax here in Node.js but actually also with another syntax which
I want to show you here. You can import everything as let's say underscore to keep that's special variable
name lodash uses from lodash.
Now here, we don't have a relative path to any file, instead
this is simply an instruction
webpack will understand when it analyzes our imports and if you have a path or a package name like this
which is not a path, so which does not start with .. or ./, then webpack will go ahead
and look for a package with this name in node modules and import the package from the node modules folder.
Now here, I'm storing everything in this underscore symbol and therefore here we could try to console
log lodash difference between let's say 0, 1 and 1, 2 and with that, what we would do is we would run a
similar example as before but now with the lodash imported differently. If we now run npm run build:
dev again to restart our development server,
this should work and should include lodash into our bundle.
So if I reload my page here, indeed it works and this is the output I'm getting from my app.js file
related to that lodash code.
Now some libraries and lodash is one of them also offer some improved imports to not import everything
because if you just import from lodash, you import the entire lodash package. If you're only interested
in some features, you could import from lodash/array for example to only add array functionalities
and difference is an array functionality.
So now this would still work as you can tell but we would actually import less and therefore have a
smaller bundle.
It always depends on the exact library you're working with, each library has its own import syntax you
can use and the official documentation is typically the best way of finding out how you can add
this library to your project and how you can import from that library.