Now at this point of time, I want to talk about arrow functions real quick because here we can really
see why they shine. With arrow functions,
you can shorten this code a lot.
It's already quite short and it would definitely be longer if you had the function keyword here but
with arrow functions, the examples like this one where I really only use the price, we can drop the
other two arguments, therefore we can drop the parentheses as you learned and since we only have one
expression in there, we can even drop the curly braces like this,
then we also have to remove the return statement and also the semicolon and instead write this code.
This expressions result will then be returned by the function automatically
and if this isn't short, well then I don't know what's short.
This is super short and concise and of course you could even make it shorter by shortening this argument
thing,
of course you should try to still make sure it's readable and understandable but this should be understandable.
So this is how short this can be
and of course there are other places in the code we wrote thus far where you can also shorten your
functions.
So that's why arrow functions really are a great addition to Javascript in general and why they really
shine when we talk about these array methods.
It's just something I wanted to highlight here because I often write a bit more verbose code to be
as understandable as possible but this is also what you can do
and this is super short and concise as you can tell.