We added our shadow Dom and this changed things by a lot.
It is the right way to go but we're now missing our text.
We had there initially and will now dive into a feature called templates to define our base H2 melt
structure of this H2 male element of our custom element and two later all to bring back that text we
passed between the opening and closing tax of our custom element now for templates we got two alternatives.
The first alternative for adding a template to our custom element is to go into our H2 female document
and there we can add a new element the template element.
This is a simple element built into the browser understood by the browser and the important thing here
is that this element is not rendered automatically now.
Here we can take our question mark and added in there like this we had it in the spans let's wrap it
in a span here to
select at.
Now we have a template which in the end is just dead span with the question mark inside of it.
So this is now our template and now we want to use that template as a blueprint for the age team Al
content that makes up are a custom element.
So previously we simply created that age similar content in the Connected callback and we happen to
have a very simple email template for our tooltip.
We only have this span with the Question Mark being added but it's easy to imagine more complex custom
elements like a video player which has a dozens of buttons and so on.
Now to use that content of the template in our web component.
Now all first of all give this template an idea of tooltip template for example and now in the tooltip
chars file in the constructor where we can access to normal Dom.
Just not the dom of this tooltip.
But we don't need that here there.
I will now get my template an old story and a constant by using the document query selector again accessing
the normal page dorm not the dom of this custom component.
And there I will use the I.D. selector to select the tooltip template so I'm using that I.D. which are
just added to my template now get access to this template and now I'm when I'm basically copy the code
I set up in that template.
So this span in this case here and use it as a template for my custom component.
And for that I will simply access my shadow route which is a way lable because I attached to shadow
Dom and there I will call append child.
I can do that here because I can already access the shadow Dom even before the element has been rendered
to the real Dom because the shadow Dom remember is kind of abstracted away from the real Dom anyways
so this is a way little in the constructor and now I will append a child here and the child is my template
and there we can access a content property to access basically the content inside of the template and
all the content we can call clone.
Note and there you have to pass a boolean indicating whether you want to do a deep clone or a shallow
clone a deep clone means that you would clone any nested elements in there too.
So if you had like a h1 tag inside of that span you would clone that too if you set the argument to
true.
If you set it to false you would only clone the top level of elements.
Now I will perform a deep clone here by setting this to true and with that for now safe that and we
reload that page we see double quotation marks here actually.
The reason for that being that we still have our code in there to add another question mark.
So we should remove dead and in addition I will just changed is a little bit down there.
Here I will set my tooltip icon equal to this shadow root.
And now here I want to find that span by simply adding a query selector because we can query to shadow
Dom just as just as we can query in a normal Dom.
Now we'll find that spanned there and with dad if I save that and we reload this page we have one question
mark only.
But I can still hover over that.
So now we are using our template our HDL template here.
Now this is one way of doing it but of course this has a couple of drawbacks.
For example this web component now requires some content to be added to our t email file where we in
the end just want to use that Web component.
And of course we're still losing that text here.
Now we can fix that text even with this approach but it will all just show you an alternative.
Cuties approach because it would be nice to have all the web component being composed in our JavaScript
file here so that we don't have to add a template to the civil code and we'll show you both this solution
and a solution for our lost text here over the next lectures.