Now we adjusted all classes to use this concept of inheritance,
now we can also improve that code a little bit and I will definitely say there are tons of different
ways of implementing this,
so if you want to try this on your own and also experiment with that and maybe find another or a better
solution, a shorter solution,
definitely try that.
One thing I want to do here is these render calls here right are kind of redundant,
we create a product list and then I manually call render, well that should be done as part of the creation
process I think because I'm always doing it thereafter manually.
So I'll say product list render gets removed, gets removed here for the cart hence here,
I'm not even interested in storing the product list anywhere,
same for the shop, can simply remove that, I need to store to shop in a constant though because I need it
here but I don't want to call render and if we go to the product list class itself where I render all
product items, I also don't want to call product item printer and therefore we don't need to store
the product item anywhere.
Instead now what we can do is we can of course call render here in the constructor or this render to
be precise of course as my IDE corrected it because we were referring to this method on this
object but even that would be redundant, we would add this logic to every constructor of every subclass.
So since we are calling the parent constructor anyway, since since we're sharing this parent, let's just
do it in the parent.
So in component here when we construct this, I will call this render.
The only thing I will now also do there is I will add a render method here and this is an empty method,
so it doesn't do anything useful here.
I'm adding it so that if someone looks at this class, this person doesn't wonder why we're calling
render here, so that we at least see that such a method exists.
Now we can still do something which is called overriding it because in all the parent classes, I basically
implement a special version of rendered thereafter.
So when we do this in a subclass, when we override a method that's defined in the parent class,
this will fully replace it.
So if thereafter in the parent class, we call this render here,
it will not refer to this render method there but instead it will do this in the subclass and this can
be counter intuitive but there is one simple rule and it's a rule you already learned actually. Always
remember that this refers to what called the method and for the constructor, that basically is always
the object you are creating. That can get bit strange because in the end you're creating an object by calling
new, right, here new product item
but in the end what the new keyword does is it make sure that a new object is created and that this
inside of the constructor is set to that object,
so that's a little bit of magic the new keyword does for you,
that's something you can memorize, inside of a constructor,
this will refer to the object that is being created,
that's what new does for you so to say. And therefore this always refers to the object which is being
created and the object which is being created is always product list or product item or shopping cart,
it's not the base class. We're calling the constructor of that but we're doing that in the process of
creating a shopping cart or a product list and only one object is being created and that is the subclass
or an object based on that subclass.
So when we call the constructor of shopping cart, a shopping cart is getting created, an object based on
shopping cart. The parent constructor of component is also getting called but this in this parent constructor
will refer to exactly the same as this in the child constructor, in the subclass constructor,
it will refer to that object that is being created. And therefore since that object which is being created
has its own implementation of the render method,
this render in the parent class will refer to the render method in the to-be-created object which is
based on the subclass.
So now with that, we're almost there,
the only thing that's missing now is in the shop because if you now reload, you'll see an empty screen
and that is because when we create our shop here, the shop class doesn't have a constructor where we
would call the parent constructor due to the way shop works.
So in the end, here in shop, I want to add a constructor and in that constructor, I want to call super
and we don't need to pass an argument to super actually because that render hook ID is not required
for the shop, the way render works here,
we're not calling this createRootElement here,
so we don't really need a render place for shop, though we could also certainly restructure this code
to make it work as such but we definitely need to call super to make sure that the render method is
getting triggered.
Now of course that also means that we need to extend component here however, otherwise there is no base
class which we could trigger with super or where we could trigger the constructor with super.
So now, now that shop also extends component and calls super, we can reload here and we'll actually get
a different error but at least we can already see the cart is getting rendered. Now just before we fix
that error,
an alternative here of course would have been to also just call this render like this because we need
nothing else from the base class, so you might argue that extending it might not make that much sense,
so you can go either way,
you can definitely also just call this render here and not extend component here because we're not
interested in any other feature from the base class, so extending it might be a bit unnecessary.
Whatever approach you chose, let's now make sure we understand and fix this error.