This error is related to a little specialty regarding fields.
In the end it's just a case that these fields are created as properties automatically when the constructor
gets called but only after the parent constructor which you call with super has been executed and by
the way, you would also not be able to create your own properties here in the constructor with this something
equals something before super has been executed.
So all your fields are basically translated to this this field name equals field value syntax here in
the constructor but they're magically added after the super call
so to say
which is why inside of the parent constructor or inside of methods triggered by the parent constructor,
you can't access any of these fields
but as I just explained, you also wouldn't be able to access any of the other properties of this subclass
here because you can only add properties, you can only use the this keyword in your subclass constructor
after the parent class constructor finished execution and that includes any methods that might have
been invoked by that parent class constructor. So that's the problem we're facing here with this render
method being called by the parent class constructor. In a constructor, we already go ahead and we execute
render and we rely on data which hasn't been created yet.
Now it's just important to be aware of that,
there's no huge issue with that,
it's just something we have to fix here and here,
we can fix that by taking that array and let's say we initialize products to be an empty array,
we could also remove it and instead set this products equal to the array here then
which means we create this instance property during the constructor.
Now with that if we save that, it would still fail because the order is wrong,
I'm calling super before I do that and inside of super, we call render.
So here is a case where we should move super after we initialize our local data which we know the parent
component will in the end depend on because it will call render for us which then needs that data.
So after we switch that order, you see that is gone.
Now the problem just is that we're not allowed to call super there,
indeed we have to call it first or at least before we do anything with this in our subclass,
so that's not allowed.
So how can we solve that issue then?
Well this is a quite common use case,
you might wanna do something with some data which might just not be there yet when you get started
and indeed, the products data would probably not be hardcoded into our code here but we might be fetching
it from a database,
so indeed it might really not be loaded when we try to render everything here. So to simulate that, I'll
cut that code and add a new method here, fetch products
and here we could be reaching out to a server, we'll learn how that works in a separate module later when
we learn how to make HTTP requests,
for now I'll just set my products there. So I simulate that in this method, I then have access to these
products before I didn't.
So here I want to call this fetch products inside of the constructor.
Now of course, render will also be called but here we simply know our render method depends on something
where we don't know yet if it's there.
So we could add another method here, render products and move that code where we go through all products into
render products
and here in the main render method, we can check if this product, if it is set and if this product's length
is greater than zero, so if we have something to render, then we call this render products and in our example
here, this will not be the case when render is called for the first time and that's fine, we'll just
create that root element and we're done
but I also want to call render products here in fetch products,
so also call it here once I got my products. And now with that we have a setup for a solution which
solves a problem you'll encounter quite often, that data arrives after you want to render some initial
content
and here we do render that initial content,
we do render that list,
it's just an empty list initially but then we add the product as soon as we have them.
So now if you save that and we reload, we'll find a similar problem,
now it's stemming from line 97 and this is from inside the product item. There we also call render in
the end as part of the constructor and we only store our product thereafter and we need that product
to render it right. Now we can employ a similar solution there or to show you an alternative, go to the
base class and since we have problems with it rendering too early, maybe accept a second argument, render
or should render and set this to true,
so use a default argument and then here we check if should render is true and if it is, we call render
but now we can override this when we call the parent class constructor and that's an alternative strategy.
So here where we know I want to call render myself, like in the product item, we could pass in false
as a default value for or as a new value for that default argument, so for should render so that
the parent component will not render and we instead call render manually after we know that the product
was set. Of course this is an approach we could have used down there as well
but here I also wanted to show how you could deal with data that actually is loaded at a later point
of time,
so where we don't just talk about different sequence steps but where we might have a bigger delay if
we are reaching out to real server. Here it's just this sequence which is wrong and with this approach,
we could fix that and therefore get rid of that and now we would render everything and we get the same
behavior as before.
So that was quite a lot of work with the base class and with the subclasses and some different use
cases you could encounter and how you can work around them,
overall it just takes some practice and of course experience to get a feeling for how you split your
code and when you use which approach.
The great thing about programming is that you can be flexible and that there are different solutions,
different approaches you can take as I hopefully showed you thus far.