Now with our own template being defined here we can now also define some styles here.
And by the way this would have been possible with the template and The Age html file too because in
here we can now of course also add style tags as we can do in any javascript fall as we can do in normal
H2 L2 and the styles here and that is the interesting thing since we do that on inner city middle of
the chateau route.
The styles here will only apply to the H to melt code in our template.
So to this span here or to the div we add dynamically and this means that we can now add all these styles
down there in our style tag here.
So I add a div selector and now I want to set the background color with normalcy is asked because this
is now a normal CSR as written in a string.
So the background color is black.
Let's say the colors or the text color is white.
The position is absolute.
The set index is 10
and now I can't go down there and remove all these manual style assignments and still if we save that
and we reload we have the same styling as before but now we can write all styles conveniently as you
are used to in H2 mellower in CSA s syntax and it is scoped to disk component only.
Please note that I'm using a general def selector and yet if I go to index H Tim L and I would add a
day off here.
This does not get the Web component styles because of the shadow dom.
So if I now reload you see the orange border which makes sense because we set this up here but you don't
see the black background.
This has all the not have the absolute position because we really have scoped styles thanks to the shadow
Dom and our styles being set up as the inner turmoil of that shadow Dom for our custom Web component.
And this gives you a lot of flexibility regarding how you style your components regarding the template
you set up for them regarding the elements you add to them and all of them as part of your custom element
and does not spill over to your normal Dom.