Now that's the bonus life functionality,
what about resetting the game
once it's over? For that, I will add a new function here which I'll name reset, not reset game because
that's actually a function I have here in the vendor.js file to update my health bars there,
So I will just name it reset here in the app.js file because these names are shared globally across
scripts as we learned and here in the end I want to basically do the same
I did here. So I want to copy that code into reset, without let though because I don't want to reinitialize
these variables, instead I want to use the global ones and just set them back to the chosenMaxLife
here. I will not reset the bonus life,
that's not the idea of this game here,
I don't have a function in vendor.js to update the UI,
so.
if you would want to add such a functionality, you would have to write such a function on your own,
not the goal here.
Bonus life only exists once across all games,
I will just reset the health and therefore also call reset game here which is that function in the
vendor.js file which resets the health bars there.
Now we can call reset whenever we want to reset and that of course should be the case whenever we lost,
we won or we had a draw,
so whenever the game is over. This means here in and round, in all these cases here, we can call reset,
just like this.
Now there is nothing wrong with doing it like this, calling reset in three places, a bit of code duplication
which you can't really avoid.
If you would want to rewrite it and I would argue that this is not necessarily shorter but if you would
want to rewrite it, you could add a new if check which runs after this one, where you check basically
all conditions combined
and then you call reset.
So here you would check if current monster health is smaller or equal than zero and the current player
health is greater than zero, in which case the player won or
and now we got
and and or combined, due to the way operator precedence works,
this is executed first,
thereafter the part after or and then both combined with or, so after this, I check this condition here and
let's now split it across multiple lines to make it easier to read.
Here my IDE automatically added parentheses for readability,
these are not required, due to operator precedence this code will work in exactly the same way, no matter
if this is wrapped into parentheses or not because and has a higher precedence than or which means
this is evaluated first,
then this and then the result of both operations are compared with this or operator.
So if this yields true and this yields false for example, the overall result will be true because with
or, if one of the two conditions is true, the overall condition is true.
Now of course we're not done here though,
I check for the monster health and for the player health,
now we can also add another condition and that would be this one here and with that, we have all these
conditions up there combined and we call reset thereafter.
Now actually, we can shorten this though and then this becomes a better alternative,
I wanted to show this first to practice the combination of and and or. In the end,
the only thing we care about here is whether the monster or the player health is below zero,
right,
because in either way one or the two lost or it's a draw but we don't care whether it's a draw or if we
have a winner here,
we just care whether some value, some health is below zero because that means the game is certainly over,
no matter who won or if it's a draw and therefore we want to reset. So we can shorten this a lot
and again then it becomes a real alternative to calling reset three times here.
We can shorten this a lot because all we have to do is, we have to check if the current monster health
is smaller or equal than zero
or if the currentPlayerHealth is smaller or equal than zero.
Now we have a very short condition here and we want to call reset if that's the case, if that yields
true because that means we have a winner or we have a draw,
in either case we want to reset.
So now with that, let's save it,
let's reload and let's try.
Let's hit this and we won, after clicking OK
this should normally reset but it didn't,
yes because reset game of course takes a value here, the value to which it should reset our bars and
that's of course the chosenMaxLife which we need to pass in here, in our reset function.
And with that, let's give it another try,
let's hit attack here,
looks like the monster is going to win now. Well we have our bonus life,
right
but if I click attack again and again, now we really lost but thereafter we reset this and now maybe
with a couple of strong attacks, we should win and we do
and now let's see if I can get a draw here
but that's actually quite hard to be honest.
Yes it's really hard,
you might get a draw here, you will see that even there you will reset this in the end. Now
here is a draw,
yes. So this all works,
now we can reset this, really nice and with that, the one thing that's missing here is that we let
the player, the user, the user of this website now, not you as a developer but the user of this website,
that the user may decide what the initial health values are - 100, 50, 1000, that is something
the player should decide and that's what we will implement next.