So what's up with this ES5 versus ES6 thing? Now
ES stands for ECMAScript and you might remember from section one that ECMAScript
in the end is the language behind Javascript so to say, you could say Javascript is a specific version of
ECMAScript,
of course the most important version. So ECMAScript in the end is the language being standardized by
this ecma
international body and these are the guys and of course in that process, there are many people working
at the common browsers involved,
so these are the guys who work on new iterations of ECMAScript and therefore of Javascript, so they decide
what ends up in the language and what not and then the browsers adopt this into their Javascript engines,
this is something I already explained in section one of the course. On this ecma international page,
you can always dive into the ECMAScript specification, this is the technical description of how ECMAScript
and therefore Javascript should work
and yes you can really dive into that but to be honest, this is is not a resource you'll commonly work with,
this is mostly important for browser vendors who need to make sure that their Javascript engine follows
this ECMAScript definition. So that is what ES stands for,
ECMAScript. Now ECMAScript and therefore also Javascript is still under active development,
so people from the different browsers and also other people involved in that process are still working
on the ECMAScript and therefore on the Javascript language, they are thinking about new features that
could be added to make it better, on maybe fixing some things that don't work as expected and as you
can imagine since Javascript is that widespread and since people use that many browsers, of course that
it is a process that has to be done with great care because you can't change the language such that suddenly
existing web pages stop working in older browsers, so you can basically only add new features you could
say, you can't really remove existing features, at least that is very very difficult to do. So over time,
ECMAScript and therefore Javascript evolved, it dates back into the 90s of course when it got started but
then we had a slow evolvement and it became more and more important and one major version that was released
in the past was basically ECMAScript version 5
you could say, this is just a term that was assigned to one specific version of that standard that was released
and that was agreed on you could say. Now ECMAScript 5 included some important improvements and most
importantly, standardization back then because before that, a lot of browsers basically did what they
wanted and this was the first real big standard
after ECMAScript 3 which also went into this direction where the browsers could agree on and where
we then had one common ground for browsers to implement features,
so that was very important.
Now one other very important major in which was kind of finalized in 2015 and therefore is also known
as ECMAScript 2015 or also another version number assigned to it, ES6,
so another major milestone was released in or was finished in 2015
and from that point on slowly integrated into browsers and that's also important to understand.
Just because there is a new standard, a new draft on which the people involved in the standardization
process agreed on does not mean that all browsers suddenly ship all these features, instead features
are getting added to browsers incrementally, so step-by-step and at different speeds and old browsers,
so for example Internet Explorer version 9 of course
don't include these new features.
Now that's a totally different topic and I'll come back to that in the browser support section of this
course where we talk about supporting different versions of browsers, especially also older browsers
and still using modern Javascript syntax when writing the code.
This might sound impossible but it actually is possible and I'll cover it later,
so what you'll learn in this course is really something you can use and which will even be usable by users
who use older browsers.
So that's just a side note,
ES6 was another major mark in development of Javascript and since then more, features have been added,
we just don't have these striking new version numbers, instead
now it's more of an incremental process where we have basically small advancements that are integrated
by browser vendors step-by-step.
So ES6 and later is what this course teaches from the beginning on because we have some huge syntax
changes from ES6 to ES5
and as I mentioned earlier, changes really means new features added, not old features removed, so you could
still use the old syntax, the old features but ES6 introduced many new exciting features and since
then, many more exciting features have been added
and again in this course, we only use this modern Javascript syntax
so that you learn the latest version of Javascript.
Now as I mentioned, the ES5 and older versions of course have great browser support, including old versions
of Internet Explorer
because these versions have been around for much longer
but for example one major difference which we have in there, which I'll come back to in the next lectures
is that in ES5 and older, we only had a var keyword for creating variables and not let and const.
This might sound like a minor thing but it's a huge thing actually as you will learn in the next lectures
and it's one of the most important changes from ES5 to ES6
though there also are a couple of other exciting changes. Generally of course Javascript still is the
same language there
but again ES6 and later versions introduced many exciting new features.
Now what about browser support for ES6 and later?
Well modern browsers have pretty decent support,
also keep in mind that all these modern browsers and that includes Edge of course have an auto updating
functionality which means people don't have to manually install new browser versions, which was the case
with older versions of Internet Explorer and therefore features can be integrated into browsers at a
much faster pace and more and more users will automatically use these latest versions of browsers because
the browsers themselves automatically update,
so that's really cool.
So we have great support for all these modern Javascript features in modern browsers,
so basically any user who uses Chrome, any user who uses Firefox and most users using Edge have access to
these features and again in the browser support module later down the course, you'll learn how you can
even make sure that people who are not using such modern browsers can still work with your web page
that uses modern Javascript syntax or where you use modern Javascript syntax to build it.
So we have great browser support in modern browsers here
and the cool thing about ES6 and so on as I mentioned is that it introduced many new features that
in the end all aim to help us write cleaner, better and faster code and need less workarounds or hacks
because with ES5 and older, you had quite a lot of situations where you needed hacky workarounds,
where you needed a third-party package which in the end just implemented the hacky workarounds then
to solve common problems.
So it was easier to write bad code with that older version of Javascript and many of the new features
introduced with modern Javascript, with ES6 and later simply make it easier for us to write shorter,
cleaner code.
Now as I mentioned, it's still under active development but ES6 was simply a big milestone,
it's not like the latest version and nothing happened thereafter,
we have a continuous development process there,
we just don't have these big labels on all these new versions,
instead new features are getting added to the ECMAScript specification all the time and then browser
vendors,
so the people behind Chrome and Firefox start implementing those into their Javascript engines.
So that's the Javascript evolution.
Now I did highlight that var, let and const thing,
what's up with that?