Now let's start with numbers.
Numbers are of course an important construct in Javascript and it's important to keep in mind that in
Javascript, every number is a float, a floating point number which means a number with an integer place
and then also with a couple of decimal places.
So there is no specific integer type for numbers without decimal places,
that does not exist in Javascript.
We do have a special integer type in certain other programming languages but Javascript is not one of them,
every number instead is a float which means a number with decimal places.
Now internally, numbers are stored as 64 bit floating points, so there are 64 bits available to internally
represent a number, bits are these things which can be either 0 or 1.
One bit is reserved for the sign,
so if it's a positive or negative number and the other bits are basically there to represent the digits
of the number and where the dot is,
so where the decimal separator sits and the combination of these bits is therefore capable of describing
numbers, of course within certain boundaries.
Now before we have a closer look at these boundaries, if you want to learn all the theory about floating
point arithmetic and how numbers are represented as bits, not just in Javascript but in any programming
language, you can check out some of the attached articles and resources like Wikipedia article or
this discussion on stack overflow.
There you can dive much deeper into this, something I won't do here simply because it's not really the
core of Javascript, it's definitely interesting to notice and to understand this but for your day-to-day
work, you typically won't need this
which is why I will ignore it here.
The important takeaway from these resources or without them by just listening to what I'm saying here
I guess is just that of course, due to the fact that we have 64 bits available to represent a number,
there are certain limits in Javascript,
there is a maximum and a minimum number
and there also is only a certain amount of precision we can get regarding the decimal places of a number,
so you can't represent every number in Javascript and there are of course certain ways around that if
you really need to, though of course we're talking about very large numbers or numbers with lots of decimal
places
and the question is how often you really need to work with such large numbers or with such detailed
numbers but be aware of the fact that there are certain limits and these limits are actually with what
I want to start here.
Attached you again find a very basic starting project, HTML file and an empty script and for now
we'll just work in the console here.
Now in Javascript, we have a maximum and a minimum number and you can easily find out what the maximum
and the minimum is by using the global number object which is built into Javascript and then with a
dot, you got a couple of methods and properties available and for example, there is a MAX_SAFE_INTEGER
and this gives us just what it sounds like,
this is the biggest possible number you can represent with the normal number type in Javascript, that's
9 quadrillion,
so a relatively large number and just in case you're interested, it's basically the same as two at the
power of 53 - 1 which you can calculate with the math object where you we have a power of
function,
basically the same function we wrote in the functions module with our recursion built into Javascript
on the math object and there, you can enter two at the power of 53 - 1, this is the largest
number Javascript can reliably produce.
Now you might wonder why we then can also print this number,
the thing simply is whilst Javascript can display this number, calculations with such a number will not really
work,
for example if we add one here to this limit, you see this number was not changed,
we get the same result as when we just output the number.
So that proves that this is the highest possible number we really can work with.
Of course if you would add anything to that number, we again would enter that range where Javascript is
not able of representing it and therefore working with that number is only possible if you deduct something
from it basically or if you divide it by some other number,
so that's how you can think about this maximum number.
Of course you don't just have a maximum integer, you also have a MIN_SAFE_INTEGER which is essentially
the same number with a negative sign in front of it and you also have a max value here,
the difference is that this is actually a decimal number,
so here we don't have the largest integer but the largest number we can express and in the end, that's
1.79 and so on multiplied with e at the power of 308,
so that's the biggest value you can work with in Javascript, not the biggest non-decimal value, so not
the biggest integer but the biggest value in general and these biggest and smallest values and integers
simply result from the fact how Javascript numbers are represented internally, how they are stored
in these 64 bits in the end.
Again, the resources attached to the last lecture are a great way of diving deeper into that if you want
to learn all the theory behind that.
The core takeaway here is that if you ever should work with such detailed or large numbers or integers,
you want to be aware of the fact that there are limits, you want to be aware of the fact that for example
you can't deduct anything from that number because it already is the smallest possible integer,
you can't deduct any other integer I should say. You can't add anything to that number because it already
is the biggest number you can represent in Javascript.
Now if you still do add something to that number or you do deduct an integer from that number, you don't
get an error as you see if I deduct 10 here,
the thing just is Javascript gives you an imprecise result,
for example here you see we exceed that bit range and therefore we simply get the result where Javascript
cuts the number after its 64 bits and then converts this back to a decimal number,
so in a decimal system I mean, with a base of 10 and that would then be this number. So it can be difficult
to wrap your head around that because we're also working with two different number systems here,
the decimal system with a base of 10 and the binary system with a base of two which of course gets used
when we work with bits where we only have 0 and 1,
that is what the binary system is all about and therefore, Javascript internally works with the binary
system and then always converts it back to the decimal system when it outputs that number.
This is how is such a strange result happens when we deduct 10 from this number,
we exceed that bit range which is available for numbers and then Javascript just cuts off the bits
and converts that bit, that binary number back to a decimal number which would be this one.
Now again, it can be tricky, you rarely of course work with such large numbers or with numbers with that
many decimal places here in the end but it's important to be aware of the limitations you might be facing.