So first, a quick summary,
what do we already know about functions?
Functions are these constructs which allow us to define code on-demand
and when Javascript reads our script, it basically goes through the entire script first, finds all
these function declarations which we added, registers them and then it really starts executing the script
and we can call our functions as often as we want,
so we have code which we can execute multiple times from different places in our program.
You also learned that if you create variables or constants inside of a function, they belong to that function
because of that block scope thing covered in the last module. Functions can take parameters, also called
arguments and can return a value, they have to do neither of that and they can take as any parameters
if you want, if you need them but you can also write functions that neither take parameters nor return
anything.
As I mentioned, functions can be called multiple times and of course you typically would pass different
values for these arguments then because that's the cool thing about a function,
it's code on-demand and it is able to be dynamic because it can take arguments and the arguments can
differ from function call to function call,
so the same function will typically produce different results for different calls because of different
arguments for example and you can also call functions kind of directly or indirectly, where directly
was when you called a function by adding parentheses after to function name and indirectly was for example
the case when you bound or when you attached a function to a button with the help of the add event
listener call which you saw.
So that's what we already know,
now let's see what we can learn about functions.