Now for that to get started, attached to find a little starting project and there I already set up
webpack for you,
so we will use webpack to bundle our code. In webpack,
we also use Babel to translate our code to older Javascript code that runs in older browsers as well,
for that in the package.json file, I got a browsers list entry where you see that I target browsers
which have at least a market share of .5%
and in this folder you find a dist folder, there we got HTML files in the root folder and in the my place
sub folder with some basic HTML code in there as you can tell, this is all prepared for you so that
we don't have to write it here. In the assets folder in the dist folder,
you find a styles folder with a couple of styles and these style files are already getting imported
into HTML files as you can tell
and we've got a script folder which is empty because we'll not write our scripts and put them in here,
instead we will write our scripts here in the source folder where I have two empty scripts file for
you to start with and webpack will then take these two script files,
so we got two different entry points and build bundles based on these script files and place them in
the dist assets scripts folder and that's where I'm also pointing at in my HTML files,
so here I try to import these script files which will be generated there.
So this is our starting setup and with that starting setup, we can start write some code here in the
source folder in Javascript files and make sure that we build a nice application where in the end users
are able to pick a location, either by entering an address or by autolocating themselves and then we
want to display that location on a map, for that we'll use Google Maps and you'll see how to integrate
that library into this project and with all of that, we'll then be able to create a link which can be
shared, also with the clipboard API so that people don't have to manually use control c to copy the
link and that link will load that other HTML page and display the place there.
That is the goal and for that we'll dive into many concepts we saw and also a couple of new concepts.
Now to get started,
we should run this build dev script here which spins up the webpack dev server so you can open the
terminal which is integrated into Visual Studio Code to have a terminal or a command prompt which is
automatically navigated into that folder and then simply run npm run build: dev to spin up that
development server
and of course then as you learned it, keep that server running so that whenever you change something in
your source Javascript files, it will automatically rebuild and reload the page. With it running,
you can visit localhost:8080 here and this is what we start with, right now if I press these buttons
of course, nothing will happen,
indeed when we press find place we even reload the page and these are of course all things we'll work
on. With that,
let's get started writing some code.