So what are web components web components really are just your own custom.
H Tim L. elements HCM all elements that are not built into the browser but that are created by you as
a developer or by some other developer and you are now using them in your project.
And what could be easier to dive into them than to just use such a custom Web component.
So let's have a quick look here.
I have a simple index H html file and I opened it in visuals do you code.
The idea I'm using in this course you can do this in your normal system text editor that really does
not matter.
It's a normal HD him L5 skeleton we have here.
You'll find this exact file attached to this video in case you want to start with that too.
But there is nothing special about this file.
Now in that file let's say we're creating an application where we want to show a modal so that info
box pop over overlay thing you see on many pages.
Now obviously we can create one from scratch.
We can add a dev here add some styling to the div and then write some javascript to conditionally show
and hide that div and also add a number div that can act as a backdrop.
So this gray area behind the modal that blocks access to the rest of the page we can write all of that
but we can also create our own Web component for that or use a web component someone else created.
And here I created one for you.
And you also find data attached to this video.
There you will find this modal jazz file which you can just download and drag and drop into the same
folder as DHL file you created or you downloaded.
Now you can go through this file in the end.
Here we create or I created a so-called Web component a custom H html element and we will do this together
in this course.
This is taken directly from the course we will build this component later in the course.
So I won't go through that right now.
There is a lot of stuff in there we don't know yet.
And this video is not about understanding all of that.
This video is about seeing what custom elements do or what such custom Web components do.
This web component the model here is in the end registered as a custom element with do you see modal
tag.
That is what I can tell you right now about this code.
This creates a new age team attack that we can use in any file that imports this modal jazz file.
So let's do that.
Let's add a script import here and the head section so that it gets loaded early and let's point at
that modal jazz file and for that it needs to be in the same folder.
As I just mentioned now with that imported we can use the U.S. modal element as if it were a normal
HDD him Al element.
And of course this is not a built in element normally using this tag would do absolutely nothing because
the browser doesn't recognize that.
But it now does as my JavaScript file registers a custom element under this tack.
Now this modal happens to work in a way where we need to pass in some information between the opening
and closing tag.
For example age 1 tag the modal title where we set the title of the modal and there we use a feature
called slots which you learn in detail throughout the course which tells that web component where to
position that content inside of the component.
So here I can say slot equals title because this is one of the reserved slots I have in this component.
And now we also need some content that is shown below the title there I'll add a paragraph.
This is our first web component with this added If we now double click this index aged hymnal file you
will not see anything because the modal isn't opened right now.
You can open it by adding a special attribute to does using modal tag and Dad's all logic we added or
we will add in this modal jazz file so that is why this will work.
You can add the opened attribute.
Make sure to spell it right after you did this.
If you reload.
Hey here is a modal and you can even close that by clicking one of the buttons or clicking the backdrop
and you see we have a nice animation there too.
And this again is all stuff we will build throughout this course.
Now of course we can also open doors programmatically if we wanted to.
So instead of hard coding open in there we could add other scripts so other javascript code which is
not related to the web component which could be our normal application code for this web app we're creating
and there the cool thing is we can interact with our own custom elements just as with native HD him
elements.
So here I'm getting access to my mobile and I'll stored it isn't a constant named modal by the way I
will have a javascript refresher where I explain what concept is in case you don't know that.
And now I can use the normal Dom operations like document query selector to get access to an element
with a CSA as selector.
And here I will use U.S. modal my own tag as a selector and with that let's say we add a timeout here
and after three seconds I want to open the modal for Dad all add an anonymous function here an arrow
function in this case and there I can access my modal and call it open method and does open method all
the exists because I edit the logic for this method in this web component and we will do this together
later in the course.
So now with that if we reload there is nothing there but after three seconds you will see that modal
opening and you can still closed with the buttons and so on.
So this is how a web component works and what a web component is it is your own HDD him out element
which you can configure in the way you want behind the scenes.
Such a web component all the just uses native elements like divs or a header as you can see and we will
learn all of that step by step in the course but we can group that together add additional logic like
here.
The open method the open attribute and so on add special styling and add for example and animation and
hide that all under an HDMI old hack that we can dump into any project which imports this web component.
That is what web components are in a nutshell and that is what makes them awesome.
But now let's have a closer look at what makes up the web components specification and why we might
want to use them.