So what is performance?
Now when we think about performance in the context of a web site we're visiting, performance can be a
lot of different things
but I think there are two main categories into which we can split this term performance.
We can have a look at the startup time of a web site, of a web application and we can have a look at
the runtime performance because these are really two different things that of course in the end work
together end and which both matter. Startup time is all about the question how long does it take to see something
on the screen and how quickly is a user able to interact with the page,
we all know how it feels like when we visit a page which is slow, which takes forever to load or which
at some point seems like it loaded
but when we try to click something, nothing happens,
so we all know that and therefore this is of course one important part. But then once a page did load, of course
it should also offer a great performance and also avoid certain bugs.
Here the question is how is smooth the application runs in general,
does it occasionally freeze or lag?
We of course don't like visiting pages where we for example try to enter some text into a text box and
it takes us forever to do so because our input is only picked up with a lag, especially web sites or
web applications, I use these terms interchangeably as you can tell, with a lot of animations could
end up in a state where we have a lot of visual lag, a lot of visual change where the animations don't
play smoothly or anything like that or where a running animation prevents us from doing anything else
or of course we could have a web site with certain memory leaks which add up over time,
so where some part of the code is buggy and actually occupies more and more memory the more often it
runs and depending on the device you're running this website on, eventually the device or the page might
run out of memory and the browser might shut it down therefore,
so that of course is also something we want avoid but it's also important to understand that performance
is not just about Javascript but about everything that's involved when it comes to visiting and
using a web page.
It's influenced by a lot of factors, the CSS code and HTML code also play a role.
If you have very complex CSS selectors, that takes the browser longer to apply styling. If you have a
lot of unnecessary HTML code, that is more code which needs to be downloaded initially hence slowing
down the startup time
but of course Javascript is a major factor because that influences a lot of the parts related to runtime
performance
and if you're downloading a lot of Javascript code, it of course also influences the startup time negatively.
Also of course the speed of the server you're hosting your web site on, as well as the configuration
of the server can have a negative impact on your users.
If you have a server that resides in the US and you have a lot of users from let's say India,
well it simply takes you a bit longer to get your data from the server.
Now of course we're talking about milliseconds here and it might not really have an impact
but the bigger your application is, the more users you're reaching, the more you want to think about all
the factors that influence performance or that could potentially influence performance and optimize
them.
In this module however, I will focus on the Javascript performance part but I want to put that out
there that there are other factors which also play a role.
Now when we talk about Javascript performance, what influences our performance there? When we think about
our Javascript execution,
of course here again we have two different areas,
we have the startup time,
the question here is how fast the script loads and is able to execute and we have the runtime performance
and here it's all about the work
the script has to do and how efficiently it does that work
and it's not just about the work the script does on its own but also about the interactions with our
other web page,
when you work with the DOM for example, when you add and remove HTML elements via Javascript, that can
have a negative impact on the overall web application performance
if you doing this in a poor way and I'll come back to that in this module and of course we have this
memory thing. You want to avoid memory leaks to make sure that you're not slowing down the application
over time or that you even have the worst case scenario of the browser shutting down your application.
Now also it's important to understand that I talked about the browser here,
I talked about the DOM but of course Javascript as you'll learned does not just run in the browser.
Now the startup time, that's really a thing that is primarily related to the browser side because when
we're talking about server side Javascript with Node.js, then there is no download delay or anything
like that,
The code already is on the server where it will get executed,
so that whole startup time thing is less of an issue on the server side because all the code is already
there
so therefore it can be executed very efficiently and quickly by default.
But when we talk about runtime performance, that affects all Javascript environments, all places where
we can execute Javascript.
Of course there are certain problems which can only occur in the browser,
for example when we talk about DOM interaction but there also are other parts, other things about Javascript
which apply to both browser side and server side Javascript.
In this modular, I will focus on the browser side because there we actually have more pitfalls but we'll
also have a look at certain things which you will see really affect any Javascript code no matter where
it runs.