So what is object oriented programming,
also often abbreviated as OOP?
It's an approach, it's a way of writing and of structuring your code in the end,
it's a way of thinking or reasoning about your code and planning your code and the idea behind object
oriented programming is that you work with kind of real life entities in your code.
Now I already mentioned this before when I talked about objects,
so that's not that new.
We use objects to group data together in the end and we do so to for example create a movie object
so that we can work with such a movie in our code and we can think about our code in terms or in a way
that's easier to think about
to us humans. Now object oriented programming is just that, it's all about embracing that logic,
that we work with objects, that we work with objects only almost in our code and we put all our code into
different objects, so into different methods of objects in the end.
Now here's an example,
let's say we're building a very simple online shop. There we might have a list of products and hence
we might build such a product list component which in the end holds all the data and in methods, also
all the logic that is related to outputting such a list of products.
So it holds the logic for rendering a list of products but also for fetching that list of products
and it probably also has a property or a couple of properties which help us store that loaded product
data.
So it's an object that holds the rendering and fetching logic and all the data that's related to it.
Now we might have another object which reflects a single product,
this object might be responsible for rendering the details about a single product and maybe it also
renders a button and it holds the logic to add a product to a cart.
So that's the responsibility of this product and therefore of course in this example, this product would
be kind of linked to the product list,
so inside of methods of the product list, we might be working with this product object. And then we might
have a shopping cart object which is also kind of linked to our product because we trigger the addition
to the cart from inside the logic stored in this product object and that shopping cart is responsible
for let's say outputting all the products that are part of it and the total sum and it may be also offers
a button to the user or renders a button to the user and holds the logic that is executed when the button
is clicked to order the items.
So that's a theoretical example,
it is actually the example we'll have a look at into some module to learn about object oriented programming
and to also learn about another important feature, classes.
But let's first of all start with this object oriented programming approach,
let's start with this way of thinking about it because for that, we don't really need classes.