You heard me say DOM or refer to something called the DOM on the last introductory lecture here.
Now what is that DOM thing? For that, let's understand what the browser does with the HTML code
which is part of any web page we create and how Javascript works with that.
So we get Javascript and we get the browser,
these two pieces which interact all the time
and now let's say on our web page where this Javascript code is loaded eventually, we also render this
basic HTML code.
Now of course we also have a head in our HTML code but let's say this is what's in our body there.
So what actually happens is that when this HTML file, the HTML document is downloaded, the browser
goes over it and parses it and renders it
and I showed you this earlier in the course already when I showed you the different ways of loading Javascript
files and how that affects the parsing of the HTML code because the browser simply reads that HTML
file from top to bottom and when it encounters a script, it executes it, when it encounters other
HTML elements, it simply parses and renders those and in the end, it then renders the pixels on the screen
which you need to see to see a button, to see a title and so on,
so that's what's happening here. Now Javascript might be part of that web page,
Iitcertainly is in all the web pages we work with in this course
and it's loaded by the browser.
Now don't forget that Javascript is a hosted language,
I mentioned this in the first course module,
that means the browser provides the environment for Javascript to run,
it provides the Javascript engine which in the end parses and understands all the Javascript code and
executes it in the end.
So the browser provides that, it also provides a bunch of APIs, a bunch of functionalities into which
Javascript can tap so that Javascript can interact with the browser.
We also saw that already and it will become super important here now when we work with the loaded and
rendered HTML code because the browser actually exposes functionality to let Javascript interact with
that rendered HTML code and in the end that's called the Document Object Model,
the abbreviation of course is DOM and that's where this term comes from.
So the DOM in the end is this loaded and rendered HTML code or to be precise, the
object representation of this code which the browser creates behind the scenes into which we can tap
with Javascript. So Javascript can work with a bunch of objects which will be exposed to us as Javascript
objects which in the end represent what the browser rendered or what the browser made of that HTML
code which was provided. And in Javascript,
we got certain methods, certain functionalities, like here this document query selector code that allows
us to reach out to the loaded HTML code and for example with this code snippet which you see here,
we get access to the first h1 element we have in the loaded HTML code and of course you learned about
all the different ways of querying HTML elements and how to configure them in this module.
I also briefly want to mention that the DOM is not strictly tied to browsers,
there are other tools which can also parse HTML that's not even restricted to Javascript,
so in other languages like Python you also can find certain tools or certain plugins, extensions which
allow you to read and work with HTML code or also with Javascript
if you're running it through Node.js. let's say, that does not have this DOM functionality built in
because you typically use it on the server side or it's simply detached from a browser but you
can still add certain packages to kind of bring that back in and still be able to parse and read a HTML
file.
The browser however has it all built in for you and in the end, it has to import and built-in global
objects you could say which kind of grant you this access and we can see one on this screen already,
this document object here in the end which is globally available which is not created by you but which
the browser exposes to you to give you access to all the different ways of interacting with that HTML
page.
Now I mentioned the document, this is one important piece in working with the loaded HTML code,
there also is another important global object and actually, document is a property of that other global
object
and that's the window object.
Now the difference is that document in the end is the root DOM node which the browser exposes to you.
That means that
this is really the topmost entry point to get access to all that rendered HTML code.
So this provides you various methods and functionalities to get access to the elements, to query for elements,
to query for HTML elements, to interact with its DOM contents, so to interact with a loaded HTML
code. window on the other hand is a global object which as I just said actually has document as property,
so window is the real topmost global object made available to you in Javascript in the browser and that
in the end reflects the active browser window or tab if you want to call it like this.
So it's basically your global entry point, your global storage if you want to call it like this for your
script, so it gives you access to all the features that the browser wants to expose to you,
the root entry point is always to the window object but it also gives you some window specific properties
for example for measuring the window width or anything like that which we'll also have a look at throughout
this module of course.