So what exactly is browser support?
What do I mean by that term?
Well consider an application where you're writing some Javascript code and you want to use the fetch API,
you want to send an HttpRequest with that fetch API
you learned about in this course. You as a developer want to use this because it's nice to use, it is promise
based out of the box,
it's easier to use than XMLHttpRequest in many regards and you might not want to use a third-party
library like axios
so therefore you decide to use fetch.
Now the problem you as a developer have when writing Javascript for the browser and of course this really
only applies to the browser therefore is
you can't control which browser your users will use,
you don't know if people use Internet Explorer, if they use Firefox, if they use Chrome and which version
of that browser they use,
that's something you can't control.
You can test your code in a certain browser and you might as a developer be using cutting edge browsers
but you can't rely on the fact that all your users do the same because indeed as you of course know,
there is a broad variety of browsers users can use, even more than what I'm showing here and for these browsers,
we even have different versions for desktop, iOS and Android and whilst they share the same branding,
the browsers for desktop
and iOS and Android also don't necessarily have to be the same and support the same set of features.
So for example here, fetch would be supported in Chrome since 2015 already, in Firefox
also since 2015 but not in Internet Explorer.
Now of course Internet Explorer is an old browser,
Microsoft is now working on Edge which now also actually is based on the chromium project, so it has a
similar core as the Chrome browser
but there still are users out there, especially in some companies that still use Internet Explorer even
though it's outdated,
so that might be a problem because for those users, your code that uses fetch would simply not work, it
would throw an error and your application would crash.
Now to complete this picture, Edge actually is supporting this since 2016 and Safari is also supporting
it since 2017.
So fetch has decent browser support but it has one browser, Internet Explorer, no matter which version
you are using there, where it won't work.
So that can be a problem and that's a problem you as a developer have to work around because as a developer,
it's your responsibility to make sure that you write code that works for all the browsers you're targeting
with your web page.
It's also important to differentiate between browser features and Javascript syntax,
sometimes it does not matter but sometimes it does.
When we talk about browser features, we talk about the APIs a browser exposes, whereas Javascript syntax
really is about all the keywords, all the functionalities and features that are built into the Javascript
language,
they're of course kind of related but not exactly the same. For browser features,
these browser APIs, the browser decides which features it offers and
examples there would be the fetch API, geolocation, the DOM API,
so all these objects and functions and methods that are exposed by the browser in Javascript. Of course
you worked with these features in Javascript but they're not part of the core Javascript language,
instead the browser as you learned provides a bridge to these functionalities and exposes APIs in Javascript
so that you can conveniently use these features. On the other hand when we talk about Javascript syntax,
I really mean parts and features that are built into the Javascript engine and there, it's the browsers
Javascript engine that defines which syntax and which version of the Javascript language is supported.
Now there also, a browser might have an engine that supports some features but not all
and ultimately of course it's the developers of the Javascript engine that decide what is supported
and often these developers are part of the browser developer team but technically, there is a differentiation
and these teams might not always be the same.
Examples for Javascript syntax would be things like let, const, async await, promises,
so all these core functionalities that are baked into Javascript.
Now why does this matter?
Because browser features typically are implemented individually,
so one feature at a time. There might be some new feature which is coming up and let's say the team behind
the Chrome browser decides that they want to implement it.
They might just go ahead and offer this feature as part of Chrome, other browsers might not yet offer
this feature and they might not even plan to offer it in the near future at all.
So then you can only use this feature in Chrome browser and hence if you're using it in your application,
only users using the Chrome browser could use that feature.
Now for the Javascript syntax, it's of course a bit related but there, features sometimes are also unlocked
or implemented individually but also sometimes in chunks,
for example for Javascript there is a specific version, ES6, which brought a lot of changes. It introduced
let, const, arrow functions and much more
and of course all these features also were implemented step-by-step by browsers but they all worked towards
that goal of supporting these features at some point,
so it was like a big chunk of features where all browsers kind of agreed that they want to implement
this
and that's a difference you can be aware of.
It's typically safer to rely on certain Javascript syntax features to be available at some point than
it is for certain browser
APIs, especially if it's very new experimental APIs, then it might take way longer until all browsers
support it.
Additionally, for Javascript syntax features, you will learn in this module that there is a way of writing
code with all the latest syntax features and compiling it down to older code that works in older browsers
as well.
For DOM APIs,
that's not really possible. If one browser gives you the functionality of getting the user location and
another browser doesn't,
then there is no way of magically making it work in the browser which doesn't offer that,
so this is another important difference here.
And in general the takeaway is that not all browser support all features and that browser support changes
all the time in modern,
also sometimes called evergreen browsers, the browsers are also called evergreen browsers because they
automatically update. If your users are using Firefox,
they're typically using the latest version or one of the latest versions
because the browser updates itself behind the scenes. For older browsers, also called legacy browsers,
for example Internet Explorer 8,
that's not the case,
so people who are using Internet Explorer 8 would have to manually switch away or manually install a
new version at least
and if that doesn't happen, well then these users will never get the new features.
So that's browser support and the difference between browser APIs and Javascript syntax.
Now how can you find out which features are supported where?