So what exactly is typescript that's important to understand right.
Because without knowing that it will be hard to learn it and to use it.
Now it's important to understand and I really want to stress this the typescript is not a brand new
language with a totally different syntax.
No it builds up on javascript.
It is a so-called super asset to JavaScript which in the end means it is javascript but it adds more
features more syntax features you can use.
Now it is worth noting as I mentioned that typescript does not run in browsers browsers don't know how
to execute typescript they know how to execute javascript.
So whilst you will learn how to write type code in this module here it's not a language you can use
like this in browsers instead and that's of course also something you'll learn and as a module we need
the extra tool which compiles typescript code to JavaScript code so which converts the code to javascript.
So did we have javascript code we learn about but during development when we write type of code we have
a better experience because of all these extra features.
Now speaking off that which features desk types could add.
Well most importantly the thing that gives typescript its name it adds types.
And with that I mean data types.
Now of course in JavaScript we also know types you'll learn about the core types Chavez could pass strings
numbers boolean objects and so on.
Now it is important to understand that JavaScript is I dynamic weakly typed language which means that
types are evaluated during runtime.
So when your script executes but they're not something you define when you write your code of course
you might know that here you're working with a string and in another place you're working with a number
but you're not putting that into your code.
And let me give you an example where this might matter considered as simple add function which adds
to numbers presumably at least.
But now let's say you're calling this function with two strings which you're passing and please notice
the quotes around the numbers.
Now of course you might wonder why you would do that.
But consider that this is coming from my input field in your dorm and your web page.
What you get from there will always be a string.
So even if the user enters a No dear it's technically will be a string.
Now if you add these two strings here you will actually find a bug in your application.
It will not crash or show an error.
But what you will get is basically to concatenated strings and I can quickly show this to you here in
the normal javascript console in a browser.
If I add five plus three we get 50 free as a string because it simply concatenate those instead of adding
them.
Now that's probably undesired and entire script.
You can a white this because in typescript you can add types and this is now a syntax feature which
is added by typescript which does not exist in JavaScript noticed a colons after a and b in the parameter
list of the function.
And after the colon you see the word no.
This is typescript certain text which in the end tells typescript that both a and b in this case here
should be of type No.
So we must only call this function with two numbers being fed and not with two strings.
So here in typescript when we compiled is to javascript I mentioned that it needs to be compiled we
will get a compile time error giving us as a developer a chance of fixing this before we even tested
in the browser so we can catch errors or bugs like this way earlier.
And that's the huge thing about typescript or one of the huge things now besides adding types types
but also adds some other nice features which don't exist like this in javascript of course these features
since TIBCO doesn't run in browsers are always compiled down to JavaScript work arounds to make the
same feature work there as well but in times it's often easier to implement certain things thanks to
these extra features.
And in addition types all the compilers next generation javascript code to old generation javascript
code you could say.
So the thing Babel does the tool we learned about in the browser support module types could actually
has this built in typescript also allows you to write modern javascript types could code in the typescript
files and as a result get JavaScript files which will run in older browsers as well.
So type sounds pretty interesting to me.
Let's take a close look at it.
Let's see how we install that compiler and let's write some type of code.