So the order matters for variables and constants,
it does not
for functions. There is one more interesting thing in our code here and that's that we have a constant
here in the function and we have a variable and a constant outside of the function.
Now when should you use what
and what's the difference?
Is there a difference?
Well there is a difference
and generally, if you use some data only in the function, like this result which I use in the function,
I return it here,
then you want to define it in the function.
I could have said let result here and then just assign a new value here and then we could even do something
strange, we could say add like this and set current result equal to result.
This code would technically work because what I'm doing here is I'm defining this result variable globally,
so in my script, then I assign a new value to it in a function
because in your functions and that's one important thing to keep in mind, you can access any variable
or constant defined outside of the function, so you can read variables or constants defined globally,
so we can interact with this result variable and I'm assigning a new value to it
and therefore when I thereafter call the function, I actually don't care about the return value, I let
that go into the void
but since inside of the function, I assigned a new value to result, I can use that global variable and
store it in another global variable or use it anywhere else,
whatever you want to do. This however would not be very good code because we have a function that manipulates
a global variable, that's sometimes something you want to do but often that makes your functions harder
to understand and harder to predict what they're going to do and in addition, that we return this
value here is totally redundant,
so not the best code we could write.
Instead it's way better if we go with the setup we had before, where we have our contained constant here,
we returned this and the function therefore works standalone.
It doesn't magically change our global variables,
instead we know when we call the function,
this function will not alter anything, not anything global,
instead it will only work with its internal data and then return us.
This is called a pure function,
it gets some input, returns an output, for the same input
it always returns the same output and it doesn't manipulate anything global but it is worth noting that
functions can access global variables,
they can also access other functions you might have defined, so you can call a function from inside a function
and that is built into Javascript
and it's a good thing which we'll also use from time to time.
Now the other way around won't work though, if you define a constant or a variable inside of a function,
then this has a so-called local or block scope which means it's available inside of this block, the block
is surrounded or marked by these curly braces and we can use it anywhere in this block but we can't
use it outside of there.
So if I try to throw an alert where I want to output the value that's stored in result here
after defining the function, you will see that if I reload this, nothing happens. You see we seem to have
an error and indeed if I open my console in the developer tools again, I get a reference error that result
is not defined because I'm trying to use a variable here in line 9,
so in this line here, which wasn't defined because as I just explained, you can use global variables and
constants and functions inside of functions but you can't use local variables or constants or functions,
so variables or constants or functions defined inside of functions
and yes you can define functions inside of functions, something I'll dive in later, you can use those
from outside of the function.
So using result outside of the function won't work because this is a constant defined inside of the
function and it won't work no matter if we use it here or here after we call the function because you
could think we only called a function here,
so thereafter result has to be defined and now it should be available.
Well actually as it turns out, if you now reload, you still get the same error here,
now in line 11 instead of line 9 because I moved that code but still, result it's not available
outside of the function and that's one important thing you need to understand with Javascript. Functions
have full access to their surrounding context, so to all the variables and so on that are defined above
them or outside of them
but what you define inside of a function is only available in there,
the only way of kind of getting it out is by returning it.
Now at this point you might also wonder, what if a variable is defined globally and then we try to create
it locally in a function as well?
So we have it declared with let or const globally and then we want to do the same with let or
const in the function,
so not overwrite the existing one but create a new one,
is that possible?
And the answer would be yes, this is a process called shadowing and in the lecture after this one,
I'll dive a bit deeper into this.