And that's it for this module and for HttpRequests.
You learned about two alternatives and how HttpRequests in general work, why we might want to send such
requests and how we do that.
You learned how to add data, how to promisify XMLHttpRequest, how to handle errors,
also with the fetch API where this is a bit more tricky and you learned about different data structures,
JSON and FormData.
Now as I mentioned, there is of course way more you can do with HttpRequests,
it would be enough content for a separate course actually. The core parts were covered in this course though,
pretty extensively actually.
If you want to dive deeper, definitely check the resources attached to lectures in this module and also
linked In the last lecture of this module,
these resources will allow you to dive deeper into XMLHttpRequest and into the fetch API and learn
about things like file upload and way more. With the content covered here
however, we already have a pretty good understanding of how it works and why we do that. In the next course
module, we'll learn about third-party libraries which will make certain tasks like for example sending
HttpRequests even more convenient.