So we had to look at sets,
let's have a look at maps then. Let's say we have a person here,
person1 which has a name of Max maybe and another person, person2 with a name of Manuel.
Now these are not maps, these are normal objects.
Now a use case where you could use a map is that you want to attach some extra information to each person
here but you don't really want to merge it into this object because you use this object in multiple places
of the application,
maybe you even copy it and you don't want to bloat it with this extra information and you also want to
make sure that in other parts of the app where you work with this object, you have a lean object to work
with without too many properties where you have to guess which one you need
in this case here and instead some extra information which you might need in another part of your application
could be managed in such a map. So we could create a constant or a variable, person data and you now create
a new map with the new keyword and then map,
so just like set but with map.
Now this map constructor here can be initialized with an array of arrays and it's an array of array because
each array in that array is one key-value pair.
So here you could have key and then some value and the key can be of any kind,
doesn't have to be a string, can be a number, can be another object and values can also be of any
kind.
So here for example we could initialize this map with one entry,
so with one nested array here where the key could be person1,
so the object itself, the address of that object but therefore it is the object itself which is used
as a key here and the value could now be the additional information which you want to store for that
person which you don't want to merge into that person.
So let's say another array here which holds information about purchases this person made,
so it might be an array of objects even where you have a date, yesterday might not be the most usable
date but it will do here and then price, 10.
So quite a lot of nesting going on here,
we have one array overall with a nested array in there which is one key-value pair we want to add to
this map where we have a key and where the value is then simply another array here, doesn't have to
be an array,
as I mentioned, you could have anything as a value here - an array, an object, a number, whatever you want.
Now if you create it like this and we then console log person data here to have a look at it, let's see
what we get.
Let's save that and let's reload and you see we get a map here which looks a bit strange but if we drill
down, we in the end find this entry here where we see we have an object as a key and an array as a value
and if we expand it, we see the key is this object and the value here is in the end an array with one
object which in turn has a date, key and this price,
so this is what I created.
Now the idea again is that you can have any key and for example the advantage here is that we can
use an object as a key and attach extra information to it.
Now this extra information is not merged into the object or anything like that,
it's stored in the map instead
but we can use that map in the part of the application where we need that extra information and have
that tight connection to this object and since we use that exact same address, we can also easily extract
data from that map as I can show you here by simply using person data,
so my map here and then here, you can call get, to get a value by key and just enter this object and
it's the same object since I add this object,
so the exact same address here as a key which I use here to retrieve it,
this behind the scenes uses an equality comparison and works because it is the exact same object, not a
copy or anything like that, the same pointer at the same object.
So this can save you the hassle of having to for example add an ID to every object so that you can
use the ID which might be a string in a regular object as a key and then extract a value by the
ID of another object from that yet another object where you stored the extra information. With a map
where you stored the extra information, the object itself can be the key and therefore you don't have
to add any ID or extract that or create arbitrary string keys, instead you can use the object as a
key and retrieve values by just using that object as a key and hence if you save that and you reload
here, you indeed get this object output there,
so this works just fine.
So this is by the way how you get data from a map, of course you can also add data to a map after it
has been created and you do this with the set method. There you set a key-value pair,
so the first argument here has to be a key which again can be of any value,
you can also have mixed key types in the same map, so you can have a map where one key is an object and
another key is a string
but here I'll actually use person2 as a key and then the value for that person,
well in my case here it'll again be an array where you might have your purchase objects in there, date
two weeks ago,
price 100,
just like that.
So that's just a dummy example here of course.
but now we also got that other person stored in that map and hence if I reload and we have a look at
this map here, we see we got two entries in there with our two different objects as keys.
So a map is really versatile regarding the keys and it can therefore be great for use cases like this.
Now you can also output all information in a map in three different ways, always using a for/of loop.
So for one, we can loop through all the entries with for const of entry or any name of your choice of
course, where you then access person data.entries which is a method, you might remember that from the set,
there
we also had this entries method which returned this strange array with the same value twice.
Well let's see what this yields us here,
so if I console log my entry here when we go through all entries and we save that and then reload, this
is what gets logged here,
these two entries.
Now what you see here makes more sense than for the set, we log an array essentially with always exactly
two elements, where the first element is the key and the second element is the value.
So for a map, it makes sense that this is an array of exactly two elements because we can then have key
and value combined in one value, in one array here.
And for the set as I mentioned, they just did the same
so that you could easily reuse code I guess. Now therefore since you also learned about array destructuring,
you could of course also rewrite this as key-value and pull out the key and the value, these names are
totally up to you,
out of this array which is guaranteed to have exactly two elements, the key and the value and store
them in constants, which are available inside of that for loop, of that name.
So then we can output key and value like this for example, using this array destructuring syntax you
learned about. Since we get an array with exactly two elements, we can use the syntax to pull out these
elements and assign them by their order to these variables or to these constants which we can use in
here.
So if we save that and reload, you'll see this output, key-value, key-value, so that also works.
So that's one way of going through all entries, another way is to again use a loop here but maybe you're
just interested in the keys let's say.
Well then you can go through all the keys by using person data or whatever your map name is,
keys. Keys is also a function which you execute and as the name suggest, this gives you access to all
the keys and nothing more.
So if you only need the keys and you're not interested in the values, of course you could also use this
approach and just not do anything with the value
but this is then a bit cheaper and shorter,
it just goes through all the keys and unsurprisingly, logs them here at the bottom,
this here from line 26. Well and you have the same for values,
so if I duplicate this, we can also go through person data.values, may be name this value therefore,
of course as always
this name is totally up to you though
and now we only go through the values. So whenever you just need the value,
well that's also possible with this approach. Well and then you have a couple of other nice methods
on a map here,
they should be pretty self-explanatory. The clear method clears all data from a map,
the delete method deletes a single entry by key from the map, ForEach allows you to go through all items
which is an alternative to the for/of loop, has allows you to check whether a certain key is part of
the map, set allows you to set a value and size tells you how many items are in the map at the
moment.
This is not a method but just a property which you access, which you can output like this. So if we do
that here and reload, here at the bottom we see two because we have two key-value pairs in the map. So
that is maps.