Speaking of built-in types, there also is a global object type or a class and you can use that to create
objects,
indeed you can do new object like this.
Now when you do that, object here in the end is just an empty object,
indeed new object like this is pretty much the same as doing this here, creating an object with an empty
object literal.
Now this here, the object literal is actually preferred because this is a little bit slower, both to type
and regarding the performance
and it doesn't yield an advantage here.
It's just a built-in base class which will become a little bit more important in the next module,
typically you don't use it like that though. You might also remember that we did new array to create
a new array or that we could do that at least
but there also the literal notation is preferred and you got a couple of other built-in classes and
we'll see them from time to time throughout the course,
no worries.