So this is it for this module, you learned a lot about objects and there most importantly, about object
oriented programming and classes.
Classes are blueprints, blueprints you use to create objects based on them
with the help of the new keyword. The new keyword and then by executing the class like a function, like
we're doing it here for example.
This creates a new object which you then can use or you can ignore like here if you don't need to do anything
with the object but you can and that's the important thing about classes,
you can add data and logic inside of the class.
You can use public and private properties,
you can add a constructor to define logic that executes right away when the object is created.
You can group any logic you need into that class and you can also use inheritance to share common functionalities,
like here createRootElement.
This allows you to split your code into reusable units where your objects and your classes are the units
that hold your logic and your data and you then build your app from these units.
Certainly a different way of thinking about your program, also not the only correct way,
you can also work with functions and so on
but an approach which often helps you structure your code in a cleaner, easier to understand way.
Therefore classes are super important as always and as you saw already in this course, we'll of course
keep on using the features you learned about
and of course we'll keep on using class as you will see them again in other parts of the course,
it's a core concept of modern programming and something you'll see in many applications you build with
the help of Javascript,
it's not a must use everywhere but really useful to understand.