The problem is the type of the value we're using here.
Current result in the end is a number right,
we start with zero here.
Now what we add to current result here however and that's something you've just got to know which is why
I tell you, is a string because I'm getting this from this user input
and even though I entered a number here and even though this user input actually even is of type number
here in the HTML code, whatever you get from a user, from a HTML input in your Javascript code will
always be a string, just something you can memorize. An input element,
if you read its value, will give you a string,
that's how Javascript in the browser works.
It doesn't try to be smart and check whether that should be a number or not, it doesn't make any assumptions,
It just gives you a string, text and therefore what happens here is that we have a number and we have
some text and now Javascript is in
it has a problem because we're trying to combine a string and a number and how would it do that?
Well we saw how it does that earlier when we built this calculation description. There,
we also combined text with a number because the default result we use there was just a number and
Javascript concatenated that to one long string
and it's the same here.
It got a number and the string, instead of converting both to a number and doing a calculation,
it does the safer thing because it doesn't know where what you entered here as a string could be treated
as a number or not
and it therefore simply converts it to a string and concatenates it to a string and that's what we see
here.
We started with an initial value of zero,
it concatenated 5,
then we had 05, it added 10,
so this is now that one long string which we got
and again it does so because it doesn't know whether what you entered here can be used as a number or
whether it just is some character which it can't use as a number,
therefore the default is that it builds a string here.
Now of course we want to build a number here however and we know that whatever the user enters here
should be a number so that it can be used in mathematical equations.
Now how can we convert this value to a number then to tell Javascript that we have a number and a
number and it should therefore do a mathematical calculation instead of string concatenation? To convert this
to a number,
you have a function built into the browser or built into Javascript, a bit like the alert function you
used earlier which is called parseInt.
You also have parseFloat, the difference is that parseInt will try to parse some text, so a string, as
number without decimal places and parseFloat will do the same with decimal places.
So with parseFloat if you entered 10 here,
this will be parsed as 10.0, with parseInt if you entered 10.1 here which actually this input
doesn't allow
but if you would do that, it would give you 10. So parseInt and parseFloat are functions built into Javascript
that will in the end take a string as an input, take a string as a parameter you pass in and will then
convert this text into a number.
Now of course that can fail, if you had some text here like hi which again I can't enter here because
this is configured to take a number but if you would have hi here, parseInt would actually of course
not be able to convert this to a number,
instead it would convert it to a special value which I'll show you later.
For now, we know we get valid numbers and therefore we'll be able to parse it,
I also only work with non-decimal numbers here, so only with integers as it's called,
so numbers without decimal places and therefore parseInt will work. So now if I save this, we're doing a
calculation here with a number and a number and hence if we reload and I enter 10 here and I then click
plus, we see 10 here and this is now not 010,
so not some concatenated string, instead if I enter a 5 and I click plus again, I see 15,
so this is now a real number. Now instead of parseInt, you can also use a plus here by the way, even without
parentheses.
So we have a plus here,
that's the operator, another plus in front of the string will then also convert the string to a
number.
So that's the shorter form of doing that conversion
and it's up to you whether you prefer the plus or parseInt, parseInt and parseFloat is of course more
explicit about what it's doing,
the plus here is easy to overlook
and if you know I want to have a non-decimal number or I absolutely need a decimal place,
well then parseInt gives you that extra control, the plus will just give you the best fitting number.
So if it's a number without decimal places, it will keep that, if it's a number with decimal places, it
will keep that as well. So parseInt and parseFloat
also allows you to be more specific about which kind of number you want.
Now if you ever would want to convert a number to a string, you could do this as well by adding dot to
string.
That's another built-in function
tied to the number here which converts this number to a string.
This however is definitely used to in less cases I'd say because more often, you need to convert a string
value to a number to use it in a calculation than the opposite way around
because as you saw earlier, the default of Javascript was to concatenate two strings,
so we had that default behavior of treating this here or using this number here in a string
anyways. So with that out of the way, we're doing that conversion correctly and the add function is working
therefore. Now we can still improve this function a little bit or improve this overall code
and also of course improve the output we're outputting here.