Enough about this for now,
there's one last nice feature which I want to introduce here and that are getters and setters,
now what's that?
Now we have normal properties here, info for example
and sometimes we want to control how a property can be set,
so how a value can be assigned or how you can get it,
so how you can retrieve it. Let's say here on our title, here
I'm checking the validity of the inputs and then I'm assigning these properties all in one go when I
create the new movie object.
Well let's say for the title,
so for properties where we know in advance that they will be part, I want to do that differently.
I remove the title check up there and remove it from down there from info,
instead what I'll do here in info is I will add a special keyword, get, then the property name of my choice,
in this case,
still title, then the parentheses as if this were a method and then curly braces for the method body.
Now what this will do is it will create a so-called getter,
so Javascript detects the special get keyword and in combination with a method thereafter,
this can actually be accessed like a property, so without adding parentheses to call it in quotes but
still execute some logic to retrieve the value and the same can be done for setting. We can add the
set keyword, then the property name and then again parentheses in curly braces.
Now here for setting, we also have to accept the parameter and that's the value parameter,
of course you can give it any name you want which holds the value you're trying to set. Now inside of
the setter,
you can now target a property with this which refers to new movie
if you call new movie.title later and for example set another property here, not the same so not
title but often you use something like _title to make it clear that this is like the internal
value and for the outside world, you have title with your getter and setter and set this equal to val
for example but here you can now also perform an extra check and see if val trim is equal to an empty
string and if that is the case, maybe set this to another default value, default like this
and then return to not continue with this line here.
Now of course the result will not be the same as before,
before we stopped the entire function execution for an invalid input,
now I continue and I just set a default value but that's exactly what I want to show.
If you have such a scenario, you can use a setter to do some validation when a value is assigned to the
title property and either accept it or set any other value, well and for a getter, you now have to define
what you want to do
if people tried to access title. You can also omit it, then you have a non-readable property, by the way
if you omit a setter, you have a read-only property
but here I added both
and here I will just return this._title,
so referring to this internal property which I create here on the fly.
So how do we now use that?
Well you can simply go to the line after this new movie creation here and then call new movie.info
and then in there, title. You use it like a property, so you don't add parentheses here, instead you can
assign a value like you assign it to a property because setters and getters are a special kind of property,
a special syntax
understood by Javascript and you can for example assign this title here which we got there.
So now if that title is empty, we'll not stop here because I'm not checking for an empty title anymore,
instead the setter which will be triggered whenever we assign a value to this title property because
the setter is on title here will then check the value we try to assign, this value here which we assign
is automatically passed in as this single parameter here and then we either accept it or if this happens
to be empty, we set a default and the getter is triggered whenever we access the property, for example
like this. When I access it and want to read from it, then the getter runs,
so then Javascript looks for this title property and again even though this looks like a method, we
don't execute it as one because combined with the get keyword, Javascript allows us to access it like
a normal property and it will execute this function for us
and here we could also do additional transformations, additional checks and for example here we could add
our to uppercase transformation and we wouldn't need this method anymore,
I'll keep that method for reference though but this would be an elegant way of always converting this
title to uppercase when you retrieve it even if we saved it in different casing
but again I'll not do it here to keep that code and hence here, I'll just return the unchanged code.
Now let's have a look at this and reload here
and if I now enter Javascript here and enter the other fields here as well and click add movie, Javascript
is getting logged here,
that's from line 74 which is where I access my getter,
so that works and setting also seemed to work
otherwise we wouldn't be able to get it and otherwise you wouldn't get the output down there.
Now side note, you'll also see that internal variable now being reflected here as well,
the _title thing, you would have to exclude this now here in your if check by also checking
if key is unequal to _title so that this is not output. So this should
be added if you plan on using this pattern here so that we don't output the _title when we
go through all properties. So getters and setters can be nice if you want to add some extra validation,
maybe a fallback or add some extra transformation when getting a value
and as I mentioned, what also is nice is of course that it allows you to also work with kind of read
only values. If we wouldn't have a setter here, if we tried to assign it like this,
we'll actually get an error if I reload here and we try to enter Javascript here and then any values
here, you'll see I get an error because I can't set a property which only has a getter.
So this allows us to add read-only properties and make sure you can only assign it here initially maybe
but never thereafter by adding a getter but no setter. You can also add both or none of that, you'll not
need getters and setters for every single property you use in your projects,
actually you will only use them sometimes but it's nice to know about them and to be able to create
read-only properties, to add extra validation with fallback values and to also set up some default transformations
for when you're reaching out to some data
for example.