And with that, we're done with this objects module.
Now the next modules will actually also talk about objects and about different ways of creating objects
for example and dive into more advanced topics that are related to objects because it turns out you
can use them for so much more than for the already a bit advanced data storage we're doing here
but again we're just scratching the surface here.
Nonetheless, these are super important concepts because you will also work with objects in exactly that
way a lot,
what you're going to learn in the next module will not render this knowledge here obsolete,
instead it will add onto this knowledge and give you different tools for different jobs
and knowing this syntax, how objects behave, knowing about this and how this behaves, knowing about
arrow functions and this, about bind, call, apply and knowing all these things about object destructuring,
the spread operator and how properties and methods are related, what they do in objects is super important,
that's the bread and butter of Javascript I would say. The next modules will add onto that, they will
add very important, additional pieces of information which allow you to write even more powerful applications
with more reusable code and really awesome features related to objects but you need to understand these
basics here in order to understand the next modules. So really make sure that these concepts here and
these ideas about objects are set.