So let's derive an algorithm.
Now we have a certain input in this case.
We have an array of numbers 3 1 2.
And what's important here.
And that of course is simply just something which is the case for this example.
This here is an unordered unsorted array so it's not sorted in ascending or descending order.
It's randomly sorted.
You see we have the smallest item here in the middle.
So it could be anywhere.
And now our goal is to get the minimum number here.
So in this case we would want to get one as a result because that of course is the smallest number in
this given array.
Now the question is how do we get there.
Well there are actually different approaches we could follow.
One approach is that we simply write an algorithm where we loop with a for loop maybe through all the
items and in every loop iteration here we basically check if the item we're currently looking at.
So we go through all the items from left to right.
If the item we're currently looking at is the smallest item.
So for that before we actually entered the loop for the first time we save a let's say cur Min variable
and set this simply to the first item India rate.
So in this case two free.
And then in every loop iteration we check if the next item in the array.
So 1 if that is smaller than the current mean.
So if I is smaller than the current mean and if I is smaller than the current mean then we set current
min to I.
So to the item we're currently looking at.
And then the next iteration will compare the next item with the new current minimum.
And if the next item is not smaller than the current minimum we skip this part here in the if check.
So instead we then just continue.
And if we do all of that once we're out of debt loop here.
So once were often that loop we will have a current minimum and then we just return this current minimum.
Dad would be a simple algorithm we could derive.
Here we go through all the items and we compare them with each Java so to say and return our derived
minimum at the end.
Now this year what I laid out here is basically my algorithm written in some pseudocode.
So this is not actual code of course but it is good enough to explain my ideas.
Now we will implemented in java script and the implementation of an algorithm in our concrete programming
language is then called the program.
So now we're going to write a program for this problem which basically implements this algorithm to
hopefully give us a solution to find the minimum.
Now for that I'm back in a very simple new project with an empty aptly as file and the index H CML file
where I only import this file and then my contact files here and now here an apparatus I want to basically
implement this algorithm.
So actually I will rename this to L 1 minimum and I will import this here.
And of course so that's alg 1 minimum JSA which I import here and now in alg 1 minimum J.S. I want out.
All right does logic I just describe.
So let's add a function maybe call it get Min because that is what we'll do.
And in there we'll get our array of numbers.
So I will name the parameter numbers and I want to return the minimum number.
So for this let's create a new variable current minimum
and we'll initialize it in a second and at the end we'll return the current minimum and then we could
simply have our test array here or our test numbers and that would be free 1 2 that's our array and
I want to get the minimum by calling get men and passing in the test numbers and then if we console
lock Min that should be one of course for this provided array.
So with that let's go to our concrete implementation of this algorithm.
Now as I sketched out before I want to initialize current minimum with the first number I have in my
array I get here.
So that's simply my assumption because I have no better assumption initially that the first number in
the array so the first number I get to know is my current minimum because it's the only number I know
from the incoming array.
So for the moment it is the smallest number I know from there.
Now of course theoretically numbers could be an empty array.
So we could check if numbers length if data is equal to zero so if it is an empty array and if that
is the case we could throw an error or if we don't want to support this.
So we could throw a new error and say should not be an empty array.
Something like this.
That's something we could do for Dad.
We can all check if not numbers length which does not just catch the length equals zero case but also
the case that we have no length at all.
So that we didn't even fit in and any.
And we can also check whenever scenario we check that numbers length is equal to 1 which means we have
exactly one item.
Well if that's the case we don't need to check anything.
Then we can just return numbers.
And then the first item here.
Because if it's an array with only one item in there of course that only one item is the smallest item.
Right.
So these are two special cases we can check upfront.
And now we can actually implement our concrete algorithm.
So the heart of this task here.
So we initialize current minimum with the first number we find in the array and then we need a for loop
a for loop where we go through all the items India array so where we have a variable I and we actually
start at a value of one not at zero because I want to start at the second item with index one India
rate because the first item is assigned as my current minimum here and then here I keep on going as
long as I is smaller than numbers length and I increment I by 1.
So in the end here I go from my numbers array as long as well I am within the boundaries of it.
And since the index starts at zero and I want to start at the second element I start with one and then
I keep on going as long as I is smaller than my length because if it would be equal it would exceed
the array because as I mentioned t index starts at zero.
So now for example if we have disarray which has three items we would set current minimum equal to three
so the first element then we would go into the loop where we start at index 1.
So at this item here which also has a value of 1 coincidently here.
So we started this item and we execute whatever will be in here and then we'll increment i to 2 because
we start at 1.
So we look at this item and execute this logic.
And now I is 2 The length is free so we execute this but now we thereafter increment i to free.
Now the length of our array is free.
So this condition is not met no longer true.
So we won't make it into here a third time.
Which is exactly what we want.
We don't want to make it there a third time.
So we then return our current minimum.
Now we just need to update the current minimum in here.
And for that we need to check if numbers for the current a next.
So for I is smaller than the current minimum we saved because of dead new number relooking at 40 index
i if that is smaller then of course I want to update current minimum and set two numbers I otherwise
if it's not smaller I will just do nothing and continue to the next loop iteration and then by the end
we should have a current minimum and that should already be all here.
Now technically we cannot also remove this check up here because if we take a closer look at our algorithm
we see that we set the current minimum to our first number here and if we only have one element India
rate we won't make it into this for loop anyways so this check is a bit redundant and we can't just
keep the first check in case we don't get an array.
So that could be our final algorithm.
And now let's simply try it.
I'm importing it in an index each time out.
So let's simply load this page in the browser and reloaded and I get a value of 1 year for every reload
which is exactly what I want.
So it seems to work but let's verify it.
Let's also try some other values.
Let's say I only have one element free if I now save this I get free.
Now if I feed in an empty array again an error should not be an empty array.
So that's also good.
Now what if I have 1 5 1.
So if I have a small list value twice.
Well I still get one as a result here.
Now what if I fit in 10 minus five minus five.
One hundred ninety nine minus two I had minus five which is the smallest value of course.
So that seems to work.
Looks like we found the algorithm that does exactly what we want here.
Now is this the best solution though.
Are there other ways of solving this.
And how could we then compare these different solutions.