What if you want to create an array?
Simple right,
you use the square brackets.
Well, did you know that there are a couple of different ways of creating an array?
Now these are not all totally different methods as you see but actually, how these methods create arrays
also sometimes depends on the kind of data you pass to that method.
So let's have a look at the different ways of creating arrays before we then work with them
and for that of course, we'll not just have a look at that,
we'll also see how that behaves and when you might want to use which. For that again attached, you find
a simple starting project, an empty HTML file which only imports a script which then also is empty
and in there of course, we can create an array of numbers, for example with the square bracket notation
and I will say right away this is the most common way of creating an array,
it's the recommended way,
nothing wrong with that at all,
so definitely use that to create an array only in very rare cases you want to create an array in
a different way.
Now here also of course as you saw throughout the course, you separate values by a comma,
you can also have a trailing comma at the end,
this won't hurt,
you can have that for readability if you want it,
here my auto formatting removed it
and with that of course unsurprisingly if I log my numbers here and then load this page and reload it,
here is what I get in the log.
Now that's not too new,
that's what we knew. By the way, regarding how to read that,
this is the array
and this here is the length of the array.
That's what's displayed there,
you also see it if you expand it, here you also have the length.
Now as I said, this is one way of creating arrays, as you saw on the slide,
there are other methods,
for example let's create more numbers here and another way of creating an array is by using a special
keyword,
the new keyword and then array.
Now this uses a so-called constructor function,
something we'll also build on our own soon,
for now let's just take this for granted and new array builds a new array.
Now if we console log more numbers here like that and please note that I didn't pass anything to this
array constructor thing,
so if we log it like this and we reload this page, we see an empty array was created here
therefore with a length of zero. So new array like this is equal to this.
Now if we change that and we pass in let's say hi and welcome,
so two elements separated by a comma and you can pass in as many parameters in the end because you're
basically calling a function here,
so you can pass in as many parameters as you want, then you will see if you now save this and you reload,
well of course we've got an array with these items here and a length of two therefore.
Now it gets strange if we change that here and we pass in numbers. If we pass in two numbers, everything
is good.
If I pass in one and five and then we reload, we see an array with one and five and a length of two.
Now the strange behavior starts if I pass in just five let's say, doesn't matter which number it is.
If you do that, then we get this. We got an array with length five which actually is empty,
we haven't seen that before.
This is essentially an empty array with a fixed size, with a fixed length.
Now you will rarely need that to be honest but this is a strange way of creating an array, which as I
said you won't need that often but you should be aware of the fact that if you use, for whatever reason,
this new array, way of creating an array, if you pass a single number, this will be interpreted as the
length of that to-be-created array and an empty array of that length will be created instead of an
array with that single number as a single value.
Now that's just some specialty which you should be aware of.
Now as I mentioned, in the vast majority of cases, you will create arrays with the square bracket notation,
that's also better from a performance perspective by the way
but if you ever encounter code where you see something like this, in some code you haven't written or
in code written by you where for some reason, you create an array with the new keyword, then be aware
of this special behavior.
Now another way of creating an array by the way is by omitting the new keyword
and that will behave in exactly the same way as if you add it.
So here we get an empty array, as soon as we add more than one number or any other kind of value, even
if it's then just one element, we get an array with these elements.
So new or not, you can add it or you can omit it, this in the end calling array as a function will give
you an array like that but again typically, you should use the square brackets instead of that. Now another
way of creating an array, yet more numbers is with array.of.
This is a special method on this globally available array object
and there again you can pass in values, pass in two arguments here for example, two numbers
and if we now console log yet more numbers here, you will see that this generates an array with these
numbers.
Now again, you should use square brackets,
this will be slower from a performance perspective than that.
You might wonder why it exists then, same for that,
there are rare niche cases where you might need such functions because you need to dynamically create
an array of a specific length
but in the end, for now I just want you to be aware of these methods because you might encounter them
in other code snippets,
you will not really have any use cases where you would need to create an array with these methods.
So let's just comment this out but be aware of them.
Now more helpful is a different way of creating an array
and that is, now I can use more numbers again because I comment this out, and that is array.from,
array.from is special.
It does not take multiple numbers like this,
if I would try to do that, if I would try to console log this here with multiple arguments passed
in,
you see I get an error because I must not pass in multiple arguments here,
instead this takes an iterable or an array-like object and that's the interesting thing. Array.from
in the end allows you to convert an iterable or an array-like object which isn't an array yet to an
array. Now of course you can pass in an array here but that doesn't make too much sense because that is
an array already,
so if you do that and you reload, it works but you don't gain much.
It's more interesting if you have an array-like object or an iterable which you want to convert to
an array, let's say here a string, hi.
If we pass this into array.from and we reload, you see now we get an array where this is split into separate
characters that make up that array, that can be useful if you have some string which you want to split
into its individual characters, array.from makes it really easy and gives you a real array with which
you can work and you will see later in this module what you can do with a real array,
it's a lot. This method is also useful if you have let's say a couple of elements in the DOM which you
want to select as a node list or as a HTML collection as you learned in the last lecture and then
you want to do something with these nodes which you can only do with a real array.
So here for example, I can have my list items and I can get them with document query selector all li,
this will select me all list items but as you learned, this gives you a so-called node list. If I console
log list items here and I reload, you see I get a node list. This is an array-like object because it has
indexes and a length, it's also an iterable because we can use for/of on that but it's not a real array,
all of these array specific methods you learned throughout it this module will not exist on that node list.
Now if you would want to use one of these methods I'm about to show you later,
well then you just have to take the list items here and pass them to array.from and now we have array
list items
if you want to call it like this and if you do that and you save that, now you'll see if I reload here,
we've got the node list and then here we get the same elements
but now here in our real array and the difference will be that you can now do anything with that real
array that you can do with real arrays,
use all these useful methods you learned about throughout this module.
So that's how you can create arrays,
the short summary is that you typically want to use the square bracket notation and that array.from
can be useful for converting array-like or iterable objects to real arrays.