So again I'm in a brand new project with you as always find attached and it's the project structure
you already know,
it's a very simple index.html, got a style import, got a script import and got this div which doesn't
hold any content, it will become important later
and then we got some styles which you can of course browse through and we got this empty app.js
file.
Now I will build this very simple dummy shop here,
not a real shop where we can really place orders because for that, we would also need a backend,
we would need a server with a database and much more than we are able to build right now
but we will build a part of the frontend here,
a list of products where we can click an Add To Cart button which will then increment the total amount
in a shopping cart
and this will allow us to dive into the concepts which are important when you think about object oriented
programming
and then later in this module when we work with classes.
So let's go to the app.js file and as I mentioned, I want to render a list of products and I want to
make sure that we can click on a button.
Now the traditional way of doing that which we used thus far would be to simply execute a sequence of
steps here, to have a couple of functions in here which we probably connect to some event listeners
and which we also call ourselves from inside to code and then write our logic with that.
Now let me make it very clear that this traditional approach doesn't have to be bad by any means,
indeed you can also write big Javascript applications only in a functional way,
so only where you have all your code split up into different functions which you then call in each other
basically but this object oriented approach might also be worth a look,
so let's have a look here.
So we need a list of products and for that, we probably need a products array first of all with a couple of
products in there.
Now let's say in there we create products which should be objects, where every product has a title let's
say a pillow, has an imageUrl
and for that of course you can take any image you want, here
I picked one in advance simply on google image search, so find your favorite imageUrl there.
Let's say we also want the price in the product, maybe 19.99 and a short description where
I say a soft pillow,
so this again is a string,
this would be one product here.
Now I'll add a second one and here I picked a carpet, also again a URL I found on google image search
and I mean I'd
say it's a pretty expensive carpet or cheap one depending on which carpets you regularly shop
and a carpet which you might like or not.
So we got only two products here but that should do the trick.
So thus far we're doing nothing
object oriented
other than that we store our product data and objects but that's what we did before already,
it makes sense to group that data together instead of working with a couple of independent variables
where it's not clear that they're related.
Now comes the interesting part,
now let's add a product list object and that's new.
Previously, we wouldn't have done it that way,
previously we would instead now have selected a part in our HTML code,
probably a button but we don't have a button here so we'll have to render one
but anyways we would have selected some part in our HTML code and then we would have executed some
logic to for example in this case render a button.
Now I want to move all my code into objects so that I only work with objects in my code
and the idea here is that the code then becomes easier to understand because since all logic is attached
to an object, it's easier to just look at an object and you know okay, everything in there has to be related
to rendering a product list
for example. If we then also have a cart object later, everything in there has to be related to
working with a cart.
So here, I have my product list object and now actually we might want to move our products array into
that if we think about it like that because rendering a list of products, the products themselves
should probably be stored in that object then,
so let's turn products here into a property of product list by replacing the equals sign with a colon
and removing a semicolon at the end
and let's add a method, maybe a render method
and here I'm using that method shorthand notation.
Now the idea behind the render method is that it should render that list of products.
So now in here I will need to select that part of my application, in this case this div here where
I want to render everything
and then do render everything in there. So I'll go here to the render method, get my render hook or
however we want to name it,
so basically a reference to the place where the app should be rendered to
and since this is a div with an ID of app, we can of course select the element by ID with
get element by ID, the ID is app and then in this render hook, we can append some content but
for that, we need to create some content first.
So here, I'll create a prod list and for that, I can create a new element of course with document create
element,
that should be an unordered list probably because I want to have a list of product,
so it makes sense to have an unordered list to render all these products thereafter, it could of course also
be an ordered list if you prefer to
but here I'm going with an unordered list and to that prod list, I also want to add a class name,
so I'll set the class name equal to product-list, simply because that is a CSS class which is
prepared in here in the app.css file
to provides a nice styling.
So now that's that and now on that list, I want to render my different product items, so in a different products
I have here.
So now we need to add the logic to render a single product here.
So for that we can go through all the products of this product,
so this here if we call render correctly should refer to this product list object and therefore this
product refers to this array,
so I'm going through all the elements in there
and then for every product there, we also need to create a new element which we can append to the DOM.
So let's create a prod el here with document create element, here a list item makes sense.
Now on that prod el, I also want to set a class name and there we can set it equal to product-item,
another CSS class which I predefined in app.css
and then to prod list, I want to append my prod el. Now this prod el however, this product element, should
of course also output some content about the product. So we can set prod el
and then maybe innerHTML to some HTML code in the end which has the structure we want.
So here I am using back ticks so that I can write a multiline string here simply because that makes
it easier to structure the HTML code which should be rendered here and there,
I want to have a div that surrounds everything let's say and then in there, an image with a source of and
now we can use this interpolation syntax to interpolate product.imageUrl, every product here
has an imageUrl property and since we're looping through all products, we can access this here, alt
so this alt text before we close that,
that can be product.title. Below the image source, we can now add another div let's say, a div which should
have a CSS class for some proper styling, a CSS class of product-item__content
,
so these are two underscores here and then in there, a h2 tag which we also have to close where
we can output the title again. Then below that, maybe a h3 tag which we should also close where
I output the price and for that, I want to have a normal dollar sign,
we have to escape that here to make clear that we want to use the dollar sign character in this template
literal here and not the meaning of the dollar sign which would allow us to inject some content
and then here I can refer to the price and thereafter
let's add a paragraph here where we output the description let's say, so
this, not this, prod.description. So that's wrong,
this should not be this,
this should be prod of course in here as well
and then below that, we can also add a button where we say add to cart. For now this button won't do anything
of course, we'll have to select it in add an event listener
but let's worry about that later.
So with that, we're setting some innerHTML,
then I'm adding product el to the product list. Product list
therefore probably is finished and now we can append this product list here to the render hook, so render
it into this div. Now with all of that, we got all the logic stored in the product list object and now
we can go to product list here and call render. If we do that and we save that entire file and I reload,
then indeed we get the products rendered here.
Now the obvious question you probably have at that point is, what's the advantage of that?
We put all the code into an object here,
we don't really save much by that.
Well that's the problem with this object literal notation here.
It's hard to write proper object oriented code because with that object literal notation which is great
if we just need to create an object on the fly or just want to group some data together
but with that notation, it's hard to write reusable object code, for example these objects here,
they always have the same structure.
Now whenever we add a new object here, we have to add it manually with an object literal notation and
we have to make sure that we don't mistype or forget a property.
It would be nicer if we had some way of getting some blueprint for this object which we can just
call, some function we can call which gives us such an object or anything like that, which in the end just
makes sure that we have to pass in a certain amount of arguments and then we always get such an object
generated
and of course we could write a function which builds such an object, a simple function which returns
such an object, that would be possible and the same here.
This logic for rendering a single product element, it's now part of the product list.
It would be nice if we could have a standalone object which we could create multiple times, once for
every product we have here in our products array which holds all that logic so that we don't have to
put that logic in here but have that logic stored somewhere else in our code
and then here we just execute it.
Of course that can all be achieved by splitting our code into functions,
don't get me wrong and that's not wrong and that's also not a wrong approach but it might be easier to reason
about it
if you split it into objects where you have a product component object let's say which is responsible
for rendering that part, a product list component which is responsible for rendering the overall list
and later also a cart component, maybe a header component which renders some header
and besides these components which should be normal objects that just know how to render something, we
also have non-component objects which are just regular objects that hold some data and that's something
which we can build with classes
and once we work with classes, it will also be clearer what I mean.
So let's have a look at what classes are.