For that, we can simply open a brand new folder with nothing inside of it,
here I just got my IDE configuration file and the git config file, you need neither of the two,
so you can create a brand new folder and open it in your editor, in Visual Studio Code here and in
there we can add a script, app.js maybe
and now here we can write some code which does not depend on the browser APIs and executed with
Node.js, for example to have a very simple script,
we can add console log in here and say hello world.
The console object and the log method on it is provided by the browser but Node.js also offers this,
so this is actually a functionality we can use both in browser side and in Node.js side Javascript.
It's not part of the core language, not part of the engine itself but it is provided as an API so to
say by both environments.
Now if we save that, the question is how can we now execute that file if we don't load it into a browser,
into a HTML file
and the answer is by using Node.js. You can visit nodejs.org,
you most likely already did this because we had to install Node.js already to use webpack and so on.
If you haven't done it, make sure you install the latest version of Node.js
now, in my case 12.11 but of course that will most likely have changed by the point of time
you're watching this but simply download this latest version,
download the installer you find there and run through that installer to install Node.js.
Once you did that and Node.js is available for all operating systems,
once you did that, you can run this app.js file with the help of Node.js. For that simply open your
terminal,
for example here with view terminal or open it outside of the IDE and navigate into the folder you
created with the cd command and then you have a node command available now that you installed Node.js,
you might need to restart your system to ensure that this works.
Type node into the terminal and then the file name you want to execute, app.js and this will tell
Node.js which was installed in your system to run this Javascript file,
basically the same the browser does with files it encounters in the HTML code.
So if we hit enter here, you should see hello world as output here because Node.js has executed that
file and of course if you would try to do something which Node.js doesn't understand, for example use
query selector and search for a button, if you execute this file, you would get an error,
here you see I'm getting an error
that document is not defined. that's what I mean with the missing browser APIs but all the core
Javascript features exist and
we can for example also create a new variable or constant with the const or let keyword, user name and
name that Max and change this here maybe to use a template literal, that's also supported here,
so with these back ticks and say hi user name like this
and if we now execute this file with node app.js, we see hi Max here. So that all works and this is
Node.js, it's Javascript running outside of the browser.
Now you can use Node.js for anything you want,
you will often find it in the context of web servers because indeed you can use Node.js as a server side
language, you can write a web server with it and write all the web server logic for handling incoming
requests and for sending back responses, you can do all of that with Node.js but you're not restricted
to that. In the end, you can execute any Javascript code you want here and Node.js for example
also gives you certain tools which we'll have a look at that allow you to write a file or to read a file,
so that's also something you can do with Node.js and you could therefore use Node.js to write your
own utility scripts that do a task you want to perform on your system, that download your latest bank
statements from a server and store that in files or anything you want, you can write your own utility
scripts with Node.js if you want to do that, you can write Node.js code that parses an excel file
and reads in the data, all of that is possible with Node.js or especially if you then add third-party
packages which of course also exist for Node.js apps and not just for browser side apps but we don't
even need to look at such more complex examples.
If we have a look at the practice app we worked on in an earlier module, there
we also use Node.js without even noticing it.
The webpack-config.js file is a Javascript file,
now who do you think is in the end using and executing this file?
It's not the browser, we're not importing this into HTML and for example this here, this module
export thing would also be something HTML doesn't understand or the browser doesn't understand,
the same for these strange imports up there.
This is Node.js syntax and I'll dive into this in a second
when we write our own script but this is Node.js and and therefore in the end, what's executing this
config.js file and what's taking this into account is a Node.js script. In the end when we run npm
run build or build dev,
we use the webpack tool or the webpack
dev server and what happens there is behind the scenes, Node.js is used there to execute certain Javascript
scripts which do not run in the browser but which utilize Node.js methods to read your files because
Node.js is able to read the file system and parse files. So that's what webpack does behind the scenes,
it uses Node.js to read in your files,
it uses Node.js to have a look at the webpack-config.js file and to then use this configuration. So
webpack runs on Node.js, it's written in Javascript to work with your Javascript code but it uses
Node.js because it of course does not run inside of a browser.
We don't load webpack in the browser, we load the finished result into our page here not the webpack
script itself.
So there, we implicitly already use Node.js
with the help of this webpack tool and therefore back to our script here,
let's now see what you can do with Node.js outside of a web server environment before we then later
also have a look at how we can use Node.js to write our own simple web server, server page and receive
incoming requests.