Typically it's a good idea in programming, not just in Javascript but especially in Javascript, to aim
for pure functions without side effects simply because they are predictable
and if someone calls them without knowing the function definition, it's always good if you can rely on
the fact that this function doesn't do anything strange behind the scenes.
Now that being said, when you're building an application, when you're writing code, it will be impossible
for you to avoid introducing side effects at some point of time.
A function might need to set up some event listener or might need to send some data to a server and
that is absolutely fine.
The goal just is to minimize the amount of functions which are impure or which have side effects, just
work with your code in a logical way,
try to keep your functions predictable and pure
and if you then occasionally have some functions that need to perform a side effect or that needs to
be impure, that's absolutely fine.
Maybe just try to be clear regarding the function naming that this might be a function that does something
as a side effect,
for example a function which is named send data to server would be expected to send some data to a
server and it wouldn't come as a surprise
that this function as a side effect produces an HTTP request. A function which is just called add
on the other hand should probably not create some side effect or be impure because a function with this
name,
well we would expect this to be pure, right?
As always, it comes with experience and now of course it's OK to not be perfect regarding that, you should
definitely be aware of this concept of pure functions though and as I said, aim for more pure functions
and less impure functions that might introduce side effects.