So let's dive into these different storage mechanisms. For this,
again you find a very basic application attached or a basic starting project I should say, index.html
file with two buttons, some styles and an empty Javascript file,
if you load that, you should see this here.
Now this is what we'll work with and I'll briefly walk you through all three storage systems,
this module here should only act as an introduction, if you want to dive deeper into these different
storage systems, especially into IndexedDB which can be quite complex depending on what you want to
do with it,
then of course as always you'll find further resources in the last lecture of this module.
So I want to start with local storage and session storage and I'll also show the difference there,
let's start with local storage.
Local storage is a great, easy to use key-value storage where you can store basic data.
Let's say you have some userId for the user of this web application, so the user using your site on
this machine which you want to store in local storage so that you can attach it to every request you're
sending to your server to identify that user.
Now you should be aware by the way that all that data can be manipulated by the user,
so you should never treat this as the single source of truth but instead just as a starting point which
you then could validate with some other mechanisms.
So here we have the userId, u123 let's say and we want to store that in local storage.
You can access local storage by just typing local storage like this,
starting with a lowercase L,
of course it's part of the window object but as you learned, you can omit this
and then here, you have a couple of options.
You can clear it to erase all data that's in there,
you can try to get the data for a specific key if you already stored some value there,
you can have a look at the key at a certain index,
so at the fourth item that is stored in there for example, you can find out how many items, how many
key-value pairs you did store in a local storage.
You can remove a single item,
so if you don't want to clear all of them, you can remove a single item by key
and of course you can set an item
and that's what we'll do here.
We'll call set item and that takes two parameters - first parameter is a key, name of your choice which
has to be a string,
second argument is a value which and that's important also has to be a string or something which Javascript
can convert to a string easily, like a number.
So here we can store that under let's say uid and then as I said, you could pass in a number or
anything which can be converted to a string, here I'll pass in userId. By just doing that,
if we reload this page, that will be in the storage.
Now we can see that in the developer tools in Chrome if you go to the application tab and keep in mind
that every user of your web page is able to do that, not just you the developer. There, under storage
you see a couple of storages, web SQL by the way is deprecated which is why I didn't discuss it
on the slide earlier,
you shouldn't use that anymore.
Other than that, you see the storages I talked about and there if we expand local storage and click on
file here, we see the data I stored here,
that's actually some test data.
I stored earlier. This here is the data we just stored here,
our key and the value for that key and as you saw, I just deleted the test data,
I can also delete this here, simply by hitting the delete key or the backspace on Mac
and that is something every user can do, also every user can add data here,
so you should, as I said, never take this as a single source of truth because this can be manipulated
easily by the users of your application,
it should just be a starting point or hold data you need in your Javascript code to enhance the interface
because of course as you see here, you can interact with that from inside Javascript.
Let's actually wire up our two buttons - the store button and the retrieve button and make sure that
these do the heavy lifting here.
So we have the store button which we get with document get element by ID, store-button was the
ID and the retrieve or retr button which we get with
document get element by ID and then it was retrieve button.
Now we can do something we did many times in this course,
we can add some event listeners to these buttons here,
here I'll just work with a couple of anonymous functions for the retr button and the store button
and in the store button,
we can have our set item code, in the retrieve button,
we can now of course also reach out to local storage and get item by key and here for example get the
uid key, so the userId we stored here and store that result,
it's a synchronous action so it's actually not asynchronous as you could think,
you don't need a promise or a callback here,
this synchronously access the storage and gives you back a data immediately.
So here we then got the extracted ID which I store and we can use it in the very next line already,
we could check if extracted ID is a thing and then output got the ID, dash plus extracted ID,
accidentally added this here and otherwise in the else case, we can output could not find ID,
something like that.
Now with that if we save that, we will see if I click store here,
if you watch the right, that key appears here
and if I click retrieve and we go to the console, we see got the ID.
If I delete that ID in the store here manually from the developer tools and I try to retrieve it, I
of course get could not find ID.
So this is how you can work with local storage and you can see how easy it is to work with it.
Now you can also store more complex data,
yes it has to be a string but keep in mind what you learned about JSON in the HTTP module.
If we had a user object here, which has let's say a name key and an age and maybe also some hobbies, where
we have sports and cooking and we want to store that in local storage, we'll have a problem.
If I access local storage here, call set item and store my user here like this by pointing at that
user constant,
let's see what happens. If I save this and I go back and click store and then I now go to the application tab,
we see actually this object object thing was stored because what actually happens when we store some
data here is that Javascript will call toString on whatever we pass in and for an object, it doesn't
give us human readable or machine readable version of the object, it gives us this square bracket object
object output but what we can do is we can convert this to JSON because JSON actually is a string,
remember it's called JSON.stringify.
Now JSON is this format which also uses curly braces and so on but actually, the entire JSON data and
that's just something you have to know is wrapped into quotes you could say. JSON data is string data,
it's a machine readable string where the content of the string is such an object with the structure and
the rules
I explained in the HTTP module. So therefore we can stringify that data to store our user data in here
and if we then want to get it back, the extracted user, we can of course call JSON parse on the result
of local storage get item for the user key and we could then console log the extracted user and maybe
also first check if we really got it but that's something we can do.
So with JSON.stringify and JSON parse, you can even store more complex data in local storage if you
want. So after reloading here, you'll see now if I click store, I store that here and if we now go to the
console and click retrieve, we correctly retrieved and parse it to the user. Be aware that any methods you added
here will get lost because they're not encoded into JSON and also keep in mind that you don't want
to store overly complex data in local storage because that's just not what it's built for.
In addition you can't rely on the data to persist because users can delete it and browsers also can
delete it if they're running out of disk space for example,
these are things you have to keep in mind. And with that, to finish up the local storage part, let's see
what session storage is about and for that, I'll actually store the userId with session storage and
hence of course also extract it with the help of session storage.
So now for the userId, I'm using session storage instead of local storage.
Now to see what this does,
let's first of all reload the page, go to application and clear uid here for local storage,
we're not accessing it anyways but to be super safe that it's really gone and let's check session storage,
it's empty. Now if I click store, you see the userId added to the session storage, not to local storage
but to session storage because we change the code and if I now retrieve the data and we have a look
at the console, we see we are able to get that data from session storage.
Now if I go back to the application and I reload, you'll see after reloads, the data also still is there
in session storage but now copy the URL, open a new tab and close the existing one and reopen the
page,
so we basically closed the browser and reopened it.
Now you see session storage is empty,
If you check local storage though, the data still is there and that's the difference. Session storage
data lives
as long as your page is open in the browser,
so as long as you have it in an active tab even if you reload the page. Thereafter if you ever close
that tab or close all tabs where your application is running or a close the entire browser,
session storage is cleared.
Local storage survives this, local storage is never cleared unless the user clears it manually or the
browser clears it because it's running out of space or anything like that and that's session storage
and local storage.