So let's work on a very simple example application and this indeed will be a very trivial application
here.
It's an application where I in the end have a HTML file which renders a form, a form with two
inputs and then with a button and I got some styling so that this doesn't look super ugly. Now we
can simply open this by in the end double clicking that index.html file in the finder or Windows
Explorer
and what we get is something that looks like this.
Now here nothing happens, if you enter something here and click the button, you'll just submit the form
and therefore reload the page,
besides that nothing will happen.
We will now write code that changes this and we will write this application code three times in the
three different programming styles and we'll start with procedural because as I mentioned, this might
be the style you used when you started with Javascript because I would argue it is the style that's
the most obvious to use
if you're getting started with programming. So let's add a new script here here, procedural.js,
you can of course name it however you want and in the index.html file, below that link here,
I'll add a script import and point at procedural.js, add the defer attribute to make sure
that this script only runs after the entire file has been parsed
and of course closed the script tag as well
and now we are importing this and we're ready to write some code
and now we can really think about the different steps we want to execute because that's what procedural
programming is all about.
So if we have a look at our HTML file, what do we want to do?
Well we want to listen to a click on this button of course or to be precise, we want to listen for the
submission of the form, we want to get the values the user entered for the username and for the password
and we might want to validate those values,
so at least make sure both fields are not empty,
show an error message if they are empty
and then in the end if everything has been valid, do something with the data, let's say create a new object,
a new user object and then log that to the console or something like this.
So something fairly trivial, that is what we could do here.
So for that, back to the procedural.js file, what do we need to do here?
Well we need to get access to the form and to the two inputs so that we can work with the data there
and then we can add a listener to the form and so on.
So getting access to those things is easy,
we have IDs, we have the user input ID on the form, we have the username ID on this input and the password
ID on this input, so we can use these three inputs to gain access. So I'll store the form in a form constant
or I'll store a reference to the form in the form constant and we can get access with get element by
ID
and then here it was user-input and then the second const that I want to create here is the username
input, we can get access with document get element by ID username and last but not least, the password,
so the passwordInput, that can be fetched with document get element by ID password like this.
Okay, so we get this access, let's now add an event listener.
So on the form I'll add an event listener to the submit event because that is the event we want to listen
to,
right
and then we want to trigger a function when that executes,
we could use an anonymous function here but I will create a named function, the signup handler let's
say. It will get an event object automatically and I will point at this function when this event is triggered,
when this event is fired.
Now this is vanilla Javascript and of course even though we're using the procedural style, we are allowed
to work with functions as well,
this is not forbidden,
we just don't organize our code around the idea of using functions all the time.
So we point at this function here when this event is triggered and now in this function, we write all
the logic, again step-by-step which you want to execute.
So thus far our logic is get access to the different elements step-by-step and then define this function
and then set up this listener.
Now when this function runs, we need to get the inputs here, the values the user entered,
we need to validate them and then create a dummy user object with that data and actually first of all,
I want to call event prevent default to prevent that browser default of sending the form to a backend
server which in the end leads to a page refresh which I don't want here,
so let's call this as well and now we can get started.
Let's get the concrete values the user entered.
So we got the entered username and we can get this out of usernameInput.value, we can access
.value here because we know that the element we're selecting here is an input element which will have
a value property. Side note, you could actually also only get access to the usernameInput in here if
you wanted to because we really only need the two inputs here inside of this function,
so you don't have to do it globally here, in this function it would also suffice,
so maybe let's reorganize our code to do that inside of this function, maybe even after preventing the
default, really right before we need a value, that's not required but it is a possibility.
So we get the entered username,
we can also get the entered password and we get that from the passwordInput.value of course,
just like this. Now with the two values, we can validate them,
we could do this with an if check where we check if the entered username, if we trim it to remove excess
whitespace at the beginning and end, if the length is equal to zero which means this is an invalid input,
it's empty.
In this case, we could show an alert to the user and say invalid input, username must not be empty,
that's something we could do here and we also return here which means we cancel this function execution
so that we don't continue in the code. If we make it past this if check, we might still have an invalid
input because our password, our entered password, with a double s here,
entered password,
that might also be wrong, so we trim this and check if the length is zero
or maybe if it's smaller or equal than five because let's say we want the password which has at least
five characters,
if it is too short, we can say invalid input, password must be six characters or longer
and again we thereafter return so that we don't continue with the function execution.
If we do continue, we made it past both
if checks and we now know we have a valid input and that's where we now could create a new user object,
simply with an object literal. Again just like functions are not forbidden here, objects are not forbidden
here,
it's not like you're only allowed to use objects when you're writing object oriented code,
it's more about how you organize code
and here it's really a step-by-step execution and we're using a very simple literal object here to store
some data, to group some data.
So here we then have let's say the username which is our entered username,
we have the password which is our entered password, entered password
and with that we're good
and now we can console log the user and maybe also send a greeting with Hi I am plus user.username,
like this.
With that, we had a very basic procedural program.
If we now save this's and we go back to the browser and reload this page, if I enter Maximilian here and
then any password of my choice which is let's say too short actually, I get this error, invalid input password
must be six characters or longer. If I don't enter Maximilian here but I leave this empty, I get this
error regarding my username and if I do have valid inputs in both fields here, you see we're logging
the user, we're logging Hi I am Maximilian.
Now as I mentioned, this code here should look fairly straightforward to you,
there also is nothing wrong with it but this would be the simple procedural way of writing your
code, you think about the different steps you need to execute and you then just write them down and don't
get me wrong, code will always be executed from top to bottom but you could also organize this differently.
So let's have a look at the object oriented programming style next.