So what's React?
It's a Javascript library for building user interfaces in the end.
Now as I mentioned, library because technically it focuses on that user interface building part but
enriched by everything else the ecosystem that it spawned offers,
it's basically like a framework
you could say.
Now the user interface part is important though, React's all about building user interfaces that look
good but more importantly than that, that update reactively, so that you for example can define if this
button is pressed,
this data should change and if that data changed, instead of outputting this text down there, I want to
output that text.
So you basically define different kind of scenarios and results you could say and React will then do
the heavy lifting of reaching out to the DOM, adding elements, removing elements, adding CSS classes,
removing CSS classes so that you don't have to manually write all these instructions,
instead you just manage the state as it's called of your application and React will then update the UI based
on what changed.
This is called a declarative approach because you declare the goal, you declare what you want to see
on the screen in different scenarios and React will then handle the way of getting there. The opposite
of that would be an imperative approach and that's basically what we did thus far in the course where
we manually had to say
now add this button, add this element, add this event listener. Now doing that in bigger projects quickly
can become cumbersome and difficult to manage and such a declarative approach definitely has certain
advantages over this because it allows you to focus on the result and the state instead of the way of
getting there and this is less error prone and gives you more power. In React and also in Angular and
Vue, you do that by defining so-called components which are reusable UI elements, now not HTML elements,
these are not elements the browser would understand,
in the end these are just components,
basically Javascript classes you could say which you define in your code which then at runtime when
your code and React's code executes on the page are interpreted by React so that React then knows what
to touch in the DOM and what to render where.
So you don't render real HTML elements, in the end you just use something which React then understands
and which then in the end tells React what it should render on the screen under which circumstances.
So let's have a look at that,
this should make it clearer.