But the concept I explained in the last lecture can have a downside,
what if we have certain operations that take a bit longer and that expectedly take a bit longer?
Let's say we have this code here,
we have a console log statement but then we set a timeout and then we execute more code.
Now the problem is setTimeout might take 2 seconds, 5 seconds, 10 seconds or maybe just 100 milliseconds
but even 100 milliseconds would be a duration
we probably would not want to wait because this operation could in general take longer and therefore
block our code execution, so it prevents more code from being executed until setTimeout is done, at least
if Javascript would treat this in the same way as it would treat all other code blocks.
Now we of course don't have to have timers, other examples could be HTTP requests you're sending where you
are maybe waiting for a response, something we'll have a look at in the next course module or you might
be getting the user location,
I scratched this when I introduced you to the navigator object earlier in the course.
We simply have certain operations which can't be finished immediately,
it's not just timers where we as a developer decide how long it should take,
it's also other operations like HTTP requests or getting the user location which simply take a bit longer
and typically you don't want to block your entire script until these operations finish because blocking
your script would not just mean that the next line doesn't execute immediately,
it would also mean that no other code can execute.
So for example if you have an event listener to listen for a button click, then this handler function
that should trigger when the button is clicked would also be blocked until the timer expired or until
your HTTP request is done, so you would be blocking your entire page with these longer taking
operations
and that's of course typically not what you want,
this operation shouldn't need to wait for the previous one for this longer taking one to finish and
thankfully Javascript and browsers have a solution for that,
we have asynchronous code execution. So if we take this example with the timer but really just to emphasize
this, the same would be true if we would be working with HTTP requests for example,
so if we have certain operations which typically take longer, then we can actually offload them to the
browser.
So what we do there is we hand this operation of to the browser, by calling setTimeout
we just tell the browser to set a timer but we then let the browser do that and therefore our code can
execute right away because now the browser is actually able to use multiple threads, one for Javascript
and one for another task for example and therefore this timer can be managed in the browser detached from our
running Javascript code so that our Javascript code is not blocked and the browser is responsible for
managing the timer and the same for HTTP requests where we wait for a response or for getting a
user location where we wait for the location, the browser takes care of these tasks, manages them in multiple
threads and therefore our Javascript code is not blocked.
Now the browser however needs a way for it to communicate back to our Javascript code and for that
we typically or we often use callback functions.
The idea here is that for example on setTimeout, we pass a callback function as a first argument if
you remember and that callback function is the function the browser should call once the operation is
done
so that the browser can kind of step back into our script and execute something there
once it's done so that we can have our script continue to run but then we're also able to do something
once this longer taking operation is done.
If you want to have a look at that, in this example here, I have an event listener and this is basically
a similar thing.
If we would have an ongoing listener, this would block the entire script execution because we would have
to wait for does the user now click, does the user now click,
that's not what we want to do,
instead when we add an event listener here, we also hand this task of to the browser which manages
these listeners behind the scenes
so that our script execution can continue but then we have this track user handler function here which
we pass as a second argument which effectively is this callback function,
the function browser should call once it's done,
so in this case not once it's done but once such a click occurs, so that the browser can always step
back into our script execution and execute this function once a click occurs.
So in this case here, we could simply console log clicked here and as you learned already in this course,
this will now only execute once a click happens
but what actually happens behind the scenes and that's what's new is that when we call this line,
we tell the browser to set up such an event listener and in Javascript,
we're done with it.
We're just telling the browser which function to execute
once this click occurs and that is it.
So now with that if we reload this and click this button, we see clicked here,
that's of course not unexpected but the magic happens behind the scenes where the browser manages this
here and that's how Javascript works,
everything you execute in code right away runs right away and it blocks other script execution until it's
done.
It's the browser which can help you with tasks that take longer and should not block your main thread.