We got quite a nice application going here, at least for the basics into which we're diving.
Now I want to dig deeper into some of the core Javascript features you've got to know because you will
need them in many of the projects or the applications you're going to create with Javascript
and one important feature if you want to call it like this is a special set of operators which you can
also use in your Javascript code.
Now we already saw the assign operator, the plus, the minus, the multiplication and the division operator,
we used those,
now there are a couple of shortcut operators if you want to call them like that.
For example here, what we're doing and not just for adding but also for subtracting and so on, what we're
doing is always we're assigning a new value to current result and that new value is based on the current
or the old value of current result plus, or minus and so on, a number.
Now if you have a calculation like this which is quite common, there is a shortcut,
you can absolutely write it like this but if you assign the result to the same variable you're using
on the right side of the equal sign,
you can omit that variable there on the right side, omit the operator and instead write plus equal,
so instead of a single equal sign, use plus equal
and that's exactly the same as having, in this case here current result.
equal to current result plus.
So you can remove that from the right side and add a plus here
and as you will see if I now save this and I reload this, if I enter a five here and I click plus, that
still works as before.
So that did not change,
that still works
but now we have a shorter code snippet here,
we have less code which we have to write. Now the same is available for all the other operators,
so instead of this code here with the minus, we can also write minus equal and the same for the multiplication
and division.
So we can take this, multiply this here and also remove that division code here and use this shortcut
and with that if we save that, you'll see that now as I reload this, we can add, we can subtract,
we can multiply and we can also divide. This all works,
now with this shorter code thanks to these shortcuts. Now there also are other shortcuts or other shorthand
operators as they're also sometimes called, if you have let's say the case that you want to set a new
value to a variable, let's say to current result and that is the current value plus one,
so exactly plus one, which we of course don't need here
but imagine we had that case, then instead of writing this, you can also write current result plus
plus. The same is available for minus,
we can write current result minus minus.
It's not available for multiplication or division because, what would that be,
multiply the number with one?
Well that's the same number and the same for division, right?
But adding one or subtracting one, that makes sense
and with this increment or decrement operator as it's called, that is possible in a very short way.
So if we do that here and I comment out this line for the moment, this by the way is a common pattern, that
you use comments to temporarily remove some code which you then can re-add later but since comments
are ignored, you can kind of temporarily remove code by commenting it out as it's called.
So if we do that and we therefore only reduce current result by one, if we click add, you will see that now
if I don't enter anything here because I'm not using the value anyways right now, if I add a plus, you
have a result of minus one, we can ignore this NaN thing for now, here the result is the thing
that matters.
So this gets lower and lower, always by one each time I click the plus button because we're decrementing
this here. Little side note, you could also write minus minus or plus plus in front of the variable,
and it will actually have a small impact or a small difference,
not if you just use it like this to change the value but if you're interested in the return type of
this operation,
if you add plus plus in front of this, it will actually add it to current result by adding one, just as it
does if you add it thereafter. If you have plus plus or minus minus in front of this variable, then this
operation returns the edited value, if you have it after the variable, well then this returns the value
of the variable before it was changed.
Now here we're not using the return value but if we would alert that return value, it still changes
current result always in the same way by adding one
but this operation returns a new value which you can or cannot use, depending on whether you want to use
it.
So here for example, I'm using it by outputting it with the alert
and if we do that and I reload here, you see I get one here,
so I get the result after the change.
If I add the pluses at the end here and I repeat here, save this and reload, then I get it before the
change. So this plus plus and minus minus operator return something,
it returns the value before or after the change depending on where you add the pluses and minuses.
Again in many cases, that doesn't matter because the variable itself is always edited in the same way,
it just makes a difference regarding the value which is returned.
Now of course here, I'm not interested in incrementing this so I'll just remove that line and comment
this back in, by the way in case you're wondering how I did this so quickly,
I use the shortcut here in my IDE, under edit, you can use toggle line comment to add or remove
a comment and to quickly comment code in or out.
So these are some additional operators which I recommend that you keep in mind and that therefore completes
our list of operators which we are aware of for now with these shorthand operators and the increment
and decrement
operator.