Now last but not least let me show one.
Totally optional optimization or restructuring in the code.
Right now I access the DOM here in Show tooltip when I append by tool to container and in height tooltip
when I remove it and there is nothing wrong with it and for a web component as simple as this one.
This might actually be the best way of doing it but it's also worth looking at a pattern which you see
from time to time in which I at least want to get you thinking about.
You can add a method in your class as we did it before.
Let's say we call it underscore render the name is totally up to you though it's not a reserved name.
I just want to make sure it's private.
To really make clear that we only call it from inside this class and I name ID render because this should
be a method which is responsible for updating the dom.
So what I now will do is I will go up to my constructor and add a new property.
This underscore tooltip wizard will and I'll set it to false initially.
So initially this should not be visible.
Now of course we're not using this property yet.
I want to use that in the render method.
Now here I'll check if this tooltip visible is true and if it is true then I want to create an append
dis element.
So here I'll go there.
Copy that code and append this child else.
I will execute the code for removing the child let me grab that and paste it in there does dissolves
the means that the tooltip container now can be converted back to a constant that only exists in the
render method because it don't exist anywhere else.
So I can go up there.
Remove the tooltip container in my constructor and in the render method I'll simply add a new variable
with let tooltip container and I'll then simply initialize it here set its text content here and edit
here in the end or remove it.
Here for this I'll just check if tooltip container is defined and I'll only try to remove it if it is
defined otherwise.
If this was undefined still and we somehow would end up here we would face a problem.
Now if the render method defined in show tooltip all I have to do is I have to switch to tooltip whimsical
property to fault edge a true excuse me and then execute the render method again because in there I
will then have all the logic for checking tooltip visible and adding the container and in height tooltip
I'll do the opposite.
I'll set tooltip all to false and then execute the render method
now what's the idea behind this approach.
Well the more and more logic you add maybe you all to render other things in your component at some
point of time the more sense it makes to do all that rendering in a central place so that you quickly
can have a look at all your rendering related code in one place instead of having different parts of
rendering different parts of your dorm distributed throughout your component instead.
Now we know in the render method we have all the logic for accessing our shadow Dom and for adding our
tool the container in this case.
But if we had any other things we wanted to render we would do it in there too.
And so we could always quickly see what we're doing with our Dom in our component and all the other
places and all the other methods of our component are only responsible for updating data which is then
getting used and render to update the DOM correctly.
Like we're using tooltip visible to update the DOM correctly by adding or removing our tooltip container.
And we're only setting the data here and then of course we always have to call render when we know that
we changed something that should trigger a rerun or we can also call render initially here even though
we don't require it for this component.
But we can call it initially here in the Connected callback to say hey when this component gets loaded
for the first time we all don't want to render it for the first time.
Now if a reload here does of course has no special effect because we don't show the tooltip because
initially we have to tooltip visible status set to false but we do render it as soon as I hover over
this.
Now it's not getting removed anymore if a away.
Let me quickly check that yeah this makes sense.
This check here and all of the way we removed this will not work to the container always gets read initialized
to an empty to an undefined variable when renderer gets called the old state is of course not carried
over.
So this will not be set.
If we call render after changing tool the visible to false.
So what I should do instead is I should initialize this with my loaded tooltip container.
If a whale so I will simply access my shadow route here and there.
All query for either a diff because I know my tooltip container will be the only death or of course
we could also assign a class to our to the container to carry by that or an I.D..
But here I'll do it by this.
And now if there's a set then I can remove it and I do loaded whenever render is called.
So if this change in place if I now reload this still everything works.
No errors here.
The hover over does get shown I can have a way and doesn't all works with this central render method
again not something we need so much for this trivial component.
But the more complex two components get the more different parts of your shadow.
Dom you might be updating the more sense it makes to do all this updating in one central place where
you can then quickly see all you're updating logic instead of having it distributed across your entire
component and all the methods in your component.