Now there is one last feature related to break and continue which I will be honest
you will very rarely need or use but I still want to show it to you because it's part of Javascript
and you should learn it in this course of course
and that's the so-called labeled statement. So let's say in this while loop but again, this works in any
loop,
we have a nested loop. So we are logging j here and then I have a for loop in there where I initialize
let's say k to be zero,
we could theoretically use i in here and it would create a new i detach from this i for this loop but
to avoid naming confusion, I'll use k in here and k is maybe smaller than 5,
that's our exit condition and we increment k and then I console log k here.
So, so far that's nothing too fancy, we have a loop in a loop,
if we now save that and we reload and we press log, maybe without doing anything before, we print 0, 1
2, 3, 4 that's our nested loop in this outer loop.
Now one tiny change, I'll set j to 0 here
so that we run this outer loop more than once as well.
So let me save that, reload, click show log and
now we have a lot of output here and we get that zero here, maybe to make it clear what's coming from
where, we can add outer as an identifier here and here, inner,
so I'll console log two things, an identifier and then the actual value so that we can see which value is
coming from where
and now we see we have the outer zero and this inner loop completes and the outer loop moves onto the
next iteration, its second iteration therefore we have a one there. We have a new inner loop starting at
zero again all the way up to four, a new outer loop iteration, a new inner loop and so on.
Now let's say you have some code and typically of course, you would not just be working with some numbers
here but you have some application, some other logic where you have some condition in your inner loop
that should actually finish the outer loop.
So for example here we could say if k is equal to three, then that is a reason for us to stop the entire
loop execution.
Now of course, we can do that with break
but what will actually happen here is that we just stop the inner loop because as I mentioned, break
will stop the nearest loop
so to say, the loop to which it belongs.
So if I now reload here and we execute this code with show log, you see outer actually continues to
work, we have outer 0 , outer 1 and outer 2 and just the inner loop always stops after two because
we break after a value of three or when k reaches a value of three.
Now what if we want to break the outer loop though?
Well you can do that with a so-called labeled statement and that's really something as I said which
you will rarely see and use in Javascript.
You can assign a name to this loop and that again works on any loop, actually not just loops, you can
assign it to any expression but it really only makes sense on loops.
You could name this outer while, so any name of your choice and then you add a colon and then a whitespace
and now this is a name for the loop in front of which you added this
and you can add this as I said, in front of any expression but you typically do it in front of loops because
there, you can use that because that is meant to be used with break and continue.
You can also but you don't have to add this here in front of that four and maybe name it inner 4.
And now here, you can use break like this to finish the inner loop but if you want to finish the outer
loop, now you can say break and then pass the name of the label you assigned to your outer loop,
so in this case outer while and now this allows you to break a different loop than you're currently
in.
So now if we do that here and I click show log, you see outer now actually finishes when inner reaches
a value of three and we have no other outer logs and you can do this not just from inside loops but
from anywhere in your code.
So if you have an infinite loop running in one part of your code and then you have another part in your
code where you kind of react to a button click and that should stop that infinite loop,
well then you could also work with labeled statements and called break and one part of your code in
your event listener to stop another loop where you assigned a label like this.
So these are labeled statements and how you can use them and you can not just use that with break
but if I comment this out, you can also use it with continue, works in exactly the same way, just with
the continue functionality where we don't stop the loop but only the current execution and therefore here
in this case, we just continue with our outer loop, though
now I actually created an infinite loop here so you will need to close that browser window here in this
place and I did create an infinite loop here because by continuing with the outer while, well we never
reach this j++ code here,
right?
We execute this outer loop,
then we start with this inner loop right away, there whenever we reach k which we always will at some
point of time, we continue with the outer loop
and therefore this j++ part which is important for our exit condition will never run,
so this actually is dangerous because we create an infinite loop here as you just saw.
So you should always watch out what you're doing with continue if you accidentally maybe create an infinite
loop which you probably don't want to do.
So that's one thing,
the key thing here are the labeled statements, though the labels you assign here to your loops which you
can then use with break and continue, again nice to know,
nice to understand if you encounter it in some examples or in an interview but really a feature which
you will rarely need as you will see as you work with Javascript.
This is something that comes with experience
but there you will see that you really don't have a lot of occasions where you would need this. Still,
since it's a part of the language,
I didn't want to hide it from you.