So with the backdrop added let's work on mobile so hashtag mobile selects the element with the idea
mobile and just to reiterate on that because we're in the shadow Dom this only affects elements with
the idea modal that are inside of our template here.
So basically only.
Well this element here and for the modal I want to have that in the foreground so I'll actually give
my backdrop a SET index of let's say 10 and modal.
WE'LL HAVE A SET index of 100.
Because it should have a higher set index so that the backdrop is in the background of the model.
I'll also give a positional fixed to position it in a fixed way in our viewport in our document from
the top.
Let's say we have a distance of 15 feet V H
and from the left we have a distance of let's say 25 percent and then we have a width of 50 percent
because we have 25 distance from the left then a width of 50 percent and then also 25 percent from the
right which is the left over space.
Therefore this should be nicely centered and you can set different styles optimized as for mobile.
I'm not carrying so much about the styling here I just want to focus on the general functionality and
not drive a ton of styles.
You could add media queries in here whatever you need for the right styling.
I'll go with this styling and I'll give it a background of white and to ensure that we can see something
for now.
I'll give it a height of let's say 30 REM and we might be able to get rid of this later once we have
some content in there.
I also want to have a border radius of let's say three pixels and I'll give it a box shadow of 0 2 pixels
8 pixels.
And then let's say this style here some transparent box shadow drop shadow.
And with all of that in place let's head over and reload this page and here's our model.
And obviously this is missing all the content but we're getting there.
Now we have the modal container.
We have the backdrop behind it.
Now we want to populate that modal with some content of course.
And I want to have some static content in there and I also want to have some slot content in there.
So let's add that next.