So it would be nice to generate similar log entries for subtraction, multiplication and so on
and of course that means we can grab that code here and copy that over to subtract, use subtract here
as an identifier
and that actually is all we need to adjust
but again, that means we're duplicating code here.
Now we already have one thing in common in all these functions here,
we call create and write output.
Now why don't we create a similar function for creating our log?
So I'll add a new function here where I say write to log and this expects to get the let's say operation
identifier or whatever you want to call it, the previous result,
the operation number if you want to call it like this,
so the number we used in the operation and the new result.
Now these are very long names here
and to make this easier to read,
I'll now actually all the split this in multiple lines with the code formatting shortcut, my IDE actually
does this automatically,
you can do that without issues,
Javascript understands this, you can write multiline code.
You have commas between your arguments here and therefore Javascript is able to understand where your
function parameter lists starts, here with the opening parentheses and where it ends,
and you can write it across multiple lines,
It's not a must do but I'd say it's a bit easier to read.
So that's my write to log function which gets all these arguments.
Now in the function body, I in the end want to do what I did here,
so I'll cut that code from add and add it here, create the log entry
and now of course all the values I use here are the values I'm getting here as parameters.
So for operation, I use my operation identifier,
so this argument I'm getting here, for previous result, I use previous result.
So here I have the same name for the argument I'm getting,
as for the key I'm using in the object, you can do that, you can avoid it if you prefer, it won't clash
because of course these are two totally different places where you use it,
so here Javascript knows that this here on the left side of the colon is an identifier in the newly
created object
and it would never look for a variable of that name because you can't use a variable here
and on the right side it knows it needs a value,
so it looks for a valid value and it could be something hardcoded like some string you enter in place
or it could be a variable that holds a value.
So here, Javascript will look for a variable or in this case, for a parameter which is like a variable
and therefore it will take that variables or that arguments value. For number, I want to use operation number
and for result, of course new result and now this is added and I also log this
and now we just need to call write to log and provide all these pieces of information,
so these four arguments. So here in add, we can call write to log like this and now the identifier could be
add, then our previous result and my IDE here gives me some autocompletion support to tell me which
value for which parameter I now need to enter.
So here for previous result, that would be the initial result variable value which I have stored here
so that this is provided to the function. For the operation number, that would be the entered number which
I want to pass into the write to log function and for the new result, that would be current result
at this point of time,
right
because we change it here,
so two lines thereafter it's still the same result and therefore I pass this to the write to log function.
And now we can copy that and call that here in subtract as well,
leave everything as it is but change the identifier and do the same here for multiply.
So here I'll add multiply as an identifier
and of course do the same here for the division and add divide as an identifier
and now we're reusing this write to log function to create our log object with different dynamic data
which we add in which we get as parameters in the function, which we then use to build that object which
we then add to our array, which we then log to the console.
So let's give that a try,
let's save that and reload and now deduct five,
so with minus five here we have an entry in the array and we see the operation was subtract, previous result
was zero, number
now is five or was five, result is minus five.
If I try to multiply this with seven, we get a new entry in the array,
this one is it.
Previous result minus five,
number seven, we multiplied it
so the new result is minus 35
and now if I divide this by let's say 2, we got a new output here. Divide, number is two, previous result
is minus 35,
therefore the new result is therefore half of that minus 17.5.
So that all seems to work, we're able to log that, we're able to reuse that logic and we're able to do
this basic work with our Javascript object here.