So I mentioned this concept of using classes and we haven't worked with classes at all in this course yet.
Classes allow us to build objects in an easier way or to build objects based on some blueprint to be
precise.
So we have objects and we have classes
and the idea is that objects are the things we work with in code and we worked with objects a lot in
this course already.
Now classes are something we can create in Javascript too, which do not replace objects but instead which
allow us to define blueprints for objects so that we can easily recreate objects based on these classes
because indeed objects then are also called instances of classes. So we can create an object based on
some class thereafter and therefore a class is just a definition of how the object looks like, which
properties and methods it has,
the place where we store our logic and then the object is the concrete thing we build based on that
class with which we work in our code. So this class based creation which I'll show you in this module
is an alternative to using object literals.
It's not always better, object literal notation is great if you will just want to quickly group some
data together but it's awesome to use classes if you have reusable logic which you wanted to define in
one place and then create multiple objects based on it.
So classes can make the creation of multiple, similar looking objects where the data differs but not
the structure much easier. So let's translate this code which I wrote here into a class-based system
and let's start with this object in this array. This object always looks the same and as I mentioned,
we could create a function that builds us such an object, well a class in the end is such a function,
it's just a different more powerful way or an easier way of writing such a function.
You add a class in Javascript by adding the class keyword just like this,
it's a reserved keyword
and then any name of your class,
the convention is to start that name with a capital character,
so here for example Product, like that. If you have a word that consists of multiple words like product
item, you would write it like this every sub word starts with a new capital character,
there must not be any whitespace or dashes in there, that would all be syntax errors.
You could theoretically also name your class like that starting with a lower case character but the
convention is to start with an uppercase character.
So now I got my product class here and then you add curly braces to define what's inside of that class
and what's inside of that class is basically your blueprint of how an object created
based on that class should look like. So you define which properties such an object should have and which
methods it should have.
Now for that, you go into your class here and there,
we can add a property or here we would call it a field and I'll come back to the difference in a second,
it's not that big, by simply adding it in here, for example title and then you can assign a default value
here because keep in mind the product class will always act as a blueprint,
that's why I'm saying default because typically you'll assign a new value but we can create a default
value of let's say default here.
Now one important note which you can see right away, inside of this class definition, you assign values
with an equal sign, not with a colon which you would do an object literal but with an equal sign and
you end a line after such a field with a semicolon, not with a comma.
That's one important difference
and classes do not replace objects as you will see, instead
as I mentioned multiple times, we build objects based on classes. So we might have a title, an imageUrl,
which could be an empty string or you just don't set any value at all,
then it will be undefined initially and also a description and also a price.
Now this would defined that objects based on product
will have these four properties thereafter.
Now I mentioned, I call in fields here
once we create an object, based on such a class every field will be translated to a property in that
object,
that's how that's related,
we just call it field here because the class is not the concrete thing with which we work here,
instead it's just a blueprint,
it's just a definition of an object and what becomes a property in an object is just called a field
here,
however for the rest of this course, I'll also use these terms interchangeably because in the end they're
closely related.
So now that's how a product would look like.
Now the question is, how do you now create an object based on such a class? Well you go to the place where
you need it,
that could be here in your global script or here in this array of products and then you refer to the
class name, product, you execute it like a function and very important, you add a keyword in front of it,
new and we've seen this new keyword before in this course,
I sometimes showed it. New in the end is a keyword Javascript understands that together with such a
function execution which is based on a class, it's not a real function but still, should basically create
a new object,
that's what new together with this function execution does. Neither of the two alone works,
we have to combine them.
So now this gives us a new product object,
this returns a new object which has this structure and therefore indeed if we comment this out for a second
and we just go here and we console log new product to have a look at how this looks like, such an object,
let's save that.
Since I added this globally, it should execute right away when a script runs and then reload this page,
also make sure you're using Chrome because classes are not supported in old versions of Internet Explorer
for example and I'll come back how to still make them work there in the browser support module. So reload
your page thereafter and what you should see is this object which is getting logged here which has a
title property with a value of default,
please note that this is a regular object with a regular property
hence we have a colon separated key-value pair and then we have the three other properties which are part
of the object but which have no value because we haven't assigned one here.
So that's the first step towards classes, we now know how to define one
but it's not that useful yet. When we create a product based on such a class, it would be nice if we could
create it with some initial values. We could of course assign all values in here
but then all products which we create based on the product would have the same values.
Instead I want to make sure that when we call new product, we can kind of pass our initial values here
to new product so that we can create a new object with some initial values.
Of course by the way, we could of course create a new product like this and then just assign values with
the dot notation but that's not what we want to do, we want to create it in one go,
so let's have a look at how that works in a second.