There is this term, this concept called prototypes in Javascript and it's super important to Javascript,
it's been around forever and Javascript indeed is a prototype-based language which uses prototypical
inheritance.
So these are a lot of strange terms,
what does it mean?
Well in the end the class syntax, that's important to understand, just is syntactic sugar for constructor
functions and also for working with the prototypes because working with them can be confusing,
classes make that easier but it's still important to understand what they do.
So constructor functions and these prototypes power Javascript objects, but what are prototypes then?
Consider this constructor function as I just explained it, a function which we can call with new, the equivalent
roughly would be such a class where we then build a person, a concrete object by calling that constructor
function with the new keyword.
Now this object which we build based on that blueprint, based on that class or this constructor function
has all the properties and all the methods defined in that constructor function.
So coming back to this example, when we create a person based on this constructor function, this p object
here has an age property, a name property and a greet property which holds a function and therefore effectively
that's a method because all of that is defined in here.
Now you learned about that idea of being able to inherit from other classes and therefore this has to
be possible for other constructor functions as well. In order to share functionality, to provide some methods
or some properties which are available in all objects based on this class or constructor function
or some subclass or subconstructor function in quotation marks because that's not an actual term. In
non-class based Javascript and also in class based Javascript but there it happens behind the scenes,
this is implemented with the concept of prototypes.
Every constructor function you build has a special prototype property which is not added to the objects
you create based on it because it's not part of the function body but a property of that function object,
keep in mind that functions are objects and that prototype is there by default,
you can also edit it, something we will do and it is then automatically assigned as a prototype to the object
which is created when you instantiate that constructor function.
Now a prototype is an object itself,
there are objects and every object has such a prototype
OK but what exactly is the idea behind a prototype,
why does every object have a prototype?
It's how Javascript shares code in the end and you can think of prototype objects as fallback objects,
objects
Javascript has a look at if it searches for a certain property or method it can't find on the object
it started looking at.
Let's say we have a person object which has a name property and a greet method and then you have some
code which calls person.sayHello.
Now clearly there is no sayHello method in this person object, right?
So normally we would expect this to fail and it might fail
if our prototype or the prototype of the prototype also does not have a sayHello method because
that's what Javascript will do, it will not fail immediately,
instead as I said, every object in Javascript has a prototype and a prototype is basically a connected
object which is used as a fallback object.
So here we have a prototype
and as I said, a prototype is just another object
and by the way in case you're wondering, yes this prototype object also will have its own prototype
and I'll come back to this chain of prototypes a little bit later
but back to this prototype here,
so this is the connected prototype to the person object and this prototype object might have a sayHello
method and if Javascript tries to access a certain method or property and doesn't find it on an object,
it automatically looks at the prototype object and looks for the property there
and if it doesn't find it there, it looks at the prototype of the prototype, all the way until it reaches
the end of that chain and didn't find that property or method anywhere and in that case for a property
it would return undefined, for a method it would throw an error.
So prototypes are in the end just connected objects which serve as fallback objects.
Now that might sound confusing,
let me give you an example. If I console log p.toString, you will actually see that this does not yield
an error but that this works, if I reload here, you see this strange output. The exact output doesn't matter,
the important thing is that we don't get an error. Just to prove that we should expect one,
if I call toStr which I know won't exist and I then reload, I actually get an error, toString is not
a function or toStr is not a function.
So why does toString work?
Because actually, there is some kind of invisible base object you could say on which our object is based,
of course it's based on this constructor function but this doesn't add a toString method.
So our constructor function somehow seems to point at some other base class, some other base constructor
function which also kind of is called or which kind of does something, which basically adds the toString
method to our object, kind of. Well indeed toString is not added to the object though, if we log the
entire object with everything that's in there, we see there are exactly three things in there but there
is this thing, the underscore __proto__property.
Now that's a special property, hence the strange name,
it's not really a property you should use to assign a value to though it would work but not really recommended
but it shows you what this so-called prototype of this object is and you can think of the prototype
kind of as the base class,
so a related, a connected object to which we can also reach out to ask it for properties or methods which
you're trying to access which don't exist on this object itself,
for example with toString. If we don't find the toString method in this object itself which clearly
is the case, Javascript will go to that prototype,
so to this object and look into that. If we expand that, here we don't see anything,
we see another object which has a constructor method,
that's a function right
so it's a constructor method
OK but then this also has a prototype and then Javascript goes to that prototype and oh, here we have
a more complex object and there for example we see the toString method and a couple of other methods.
Now actually that's the base prototype,
this object here is a base object, every object you create is based on in the end
if you go down that prototype chain. The concept of that prototype chain is indeed very important
so I want to dive into that again.
The idea is that when you build a blueprint with a constructor function or with a class which in the
end just uses constructor functions and prototypes behind the scenes and you then build an object based
on that constructor function, you can call a method on that object.
Now let's say we're calling the brief method here on person and let's say our constructor function
or class does not have a brief method.
What Javascript then does is it first of all when we call brief, it checks
is that part of the object itself,
so was it defined in the blueprint because as you learned, when you then instantiate an object based on
the blueprint,
the object has everything defined in the blueprint.
So is the brief method part of the person itself, of that object which we created based on the constructor
function?
If yes, then we can execute the method,
if no, well then we look to the prototype and that's just something you can memorize, it's called
prototype,
it's basically a base class
of this person object here in the end you could say. There is a connection which is automatically
set up and every object you create by default has such a prototype
even if you haven't set up any inheritance here.
So then this prototype is checked,
the object which is the prototype is checked,
does that have a brief method
and if the answer is yes, we're done,
if not we continue,
we go to the prototype of the prototype, so to the base class of the base class of our object so to say,
check for the brief method there
and we do that until we reached the end and the last prototype we check is the prototype of this special
object thing which I also showed you earlier. So let's understand this prototype thing a bit better. Here
in the code,
there seems to be this object prototype thing which in the end is connected,
let's ignore that for a second.
Let's instead output p.__,
so double underscore therefore also often called dunder for double under, proto__.
If we do that and we reload, we get this object which has a constructor method and
then also the __proto__ property which points at yet another object.
This object here which we're seeing here with these two properties or with this one method and the proto
property,
this is the default object every custom constructor function assigns to an object based on it
and let me now show you how you can tweak that prototype. Every constructor function here or every function
in general in Javascript is in the end stored as an object, right.
In the end a function is just an object,
therefore just as on any other object, you can assign properties by using the name of that object,
in this case the name of the function, person and just to prove this, if I console dir this to look
into it here before we do anything, if we do that,
you see this is the function object and in the end, it has the special way of being displayed here
but you see it has a bunch of properties, the arguments property you learned about earlier,
it has a name property, it has a proto, __proto property and it also has a property
which our other object does not have,
it has a prototype. Now that can be confusing, having __proto and prototype. In
short, __proto is present on every object in Javascript, no matter how you created
it,
no matter if that is a function object, a function object which we use as a constructor function, an
object you build with object literal notation, an object you build with the help of a constructor function,
an array,
you always have __proto because this shows you the connected prototype,
so this backup object if you want to call it like this,
this object is connected to. Now prototype sounds similar but does something totally different.
This prototype property does not exist on every object, it exists on function objects because Javascript
is a prototype-based language. We use constructor functions to build objects and whatever you set here
on prototype will be assigned as a prototype to any object that's built
based on this constructor function and therefore indeed we see that what's set to prototype here is an object
with a constructor method and also of course the __proto property.
So in short, the exact same object we're logging down here,
this here is exactly the same object, constructor function and then proto down there,
it's exactly the same and indeed that's true.
If we compare our object, our person object, what is set up as a prototype there to person.prototype,
then you will see that if I reload here, we log true.
So these are exactly the same objects, not copies, exactly the same object in memory.
Now this does not mean that our constructor function object and this person object have the same fallback
object,
they don't because that's stored in the __proto property. Prototype is not what person,
what this function object would reach out to if we called something on it like toString which we
can't find on the object itself,
this is not what prototype is therefore. This would be handled with the prototype being used as a fallback
value for this constructor function object.
Instead the prototype property and I know it's confusing, it's just how these properties are named unfortunately,
the prototype property of our function object instead can be used to assign an object which then will
be assigned as a prototype,
so as a fallback value to any objects you build based on this constructor function.
So here for example, we can set prototype to a new object with let's say a method of printAge, where we
then say console log this age. So now what I do here is I set that every object we build based on this
constructor function should have a prototype which is exactly this object.
The result of that is that if I now log p.__proto,
I see this object here indeed
and therefore we can for example also call p.printAge, not because there would be a printAge
method set up directly in the constructor function,
it isn't but we set it up on our fallback object and therefore this works. If I now go back and I reload,
you see 30 being printed here.
That's also important,
the this keyword inside of your prototypes always refers to your object on which you call the method
and that makes sense right,
you learned that
this refers to whatever called the method and that is also something you learned in the last module when
I talked about inheritance,
what's set up there in the base class, when you use this in some method of the base class,
if you then called it on the object that's based on a subclass,
this in the base class will refer to the concrete object on which you called it, not on the base class
itself or anything like that.
And indeed prototypes here,
that's in the end what class and extends do for you. When you create a class that extends something, you
in the end in form Javascript that you want to set the prototype to a new object or add some new methods
and properties to that prototype to be precise.
So what I do manually here is done for you when you extend something here.