So that was a lot about precision and numbers but it's important to understand it. In modern versions
of Javascript,
there actually also is an alternative to the normal number
we worked with all the time and that's a big integer.
Now the big integer type is a primitive value and its goal is to allow you represent numbers that are
above the maximum safe integer
we learned about, so a number bigger than that.
If you for example wanted to represent a number bigger than that by adding extra nine at the end, you
would see what I explained before, we get a totally different number because Javascript only works with
64 bits and we would exceed that and therefore Javascript cuts the number at a certain point and
shows a different number.
Now a big int can help us with that,
you create a big int by simply adding a n after your number
and now you see, this looks a bit different here in the console because it's a different type,
this keeps its precision, its value and we can represent arbitrarily big numbers with that because internally,
this is managed differently, not as a 64 bit floating point number but instead in the end as a string
and Javascript does all the heavy lifting of converting this around when you use it in calculations
and so on.
So the big int can be useful if you're working with very large numbers, of course not just positive ones
but also negative ones.
Now be aware that there is no floating point calculation there, that there are no supported decimal places,
you see I'm getting an error if I try to add a decimal place,
it's called big int because it's only about integers and it's the perfect type
if you are working with very large integers. Of course you can always represent smaller numbers with
that,
the question is if this makes a lot of sense and then you can also perform typical calculations with
it, just important, you can't mix big int and other numbers, for example 10n and -4, where 10n is a big
int but 4 is a normal number would yield an error,
you see you cannot mix big int and other types, use explicit conversions so you would have to convert this
to a big integer or this to a normal number before mixing it. You can convert it to a normal number with
parseInt for example, that would work or by converting four to a big integer by wrapping it with that
big int function call here, not new big int but just big int like this,
this is how you can convert numbers back and forth and this is how you then can work with them and how
you can run various calculations. Of course conversion is only needed if you want to mix types,
if you have a big integer and you want to multiply it with another big integer, you don't have to
convert anything, you can just run this calculation like that.
One important note, if you divide a big int, since decimal places can't be represented there,
Javascript will actually omit them and we don't see it here because this can be divided with a perfect
result without decimal places
but if we have 5n divided by 2n, then you see we're not getting 2.5n because this does not exist
as you see,
instead we get 2n because Javascript simply cuts off the decimal place that would otherwise be added.
So that's a big integer, not the type you'll use every day but can be useful if you have very large numbers
with which you need to work.