So we saw getBoundingClientRect which gives us some general data,
now you can also get more specialized data by diving into your DOM element with special properties,
for example there is offsetTop. offsetTop gives you the distance of the topmost point here to
the top of this coordinate or to the start of this coordinate system and of course you don't just
have offsetTop, you also have offsetLeft,
makes sense I guess.
So these are basically your x and y values here or your left and top values from that object we saw
before.
You also however have clientTop and clientLeft and now that's a different thing as you can tell, where
offset gives you the outer positioning,
so the position of the box in the coordinate system, the client properties give you the inner positioning
and specifically clientTop and clientLeft tell you how far it is from your left and topmost point
to your left and topmost point of the content of this box and the content of the box is basically the
entire box without any borders and potential scroll bars
that might be rendered in there.
So at the moment, there is no scroll bar here but I have a border of 15 pixels and therefore that's
exactly that value which we see here for clientTop and clientLeft.
You can also get some of the sizes for that, you can get the offsetWidth and you can get the offsetHeight
and that's the entire width and height of this box, including all borders and scroll bars. Now unsurprisingly,
you also have clientWidth and clientHeight and that's again the inner width and height without borders
and scroll bars, therefore for the width, it's basically the width of 300 which we saw just
a second ago minus the border times 2 because we got a border on the left and on the right and if
we had a scroll bar, that would be deducted as well, the same for the height.
Also interesting, this content here is scrollable as you can see, the scroll bar here on Mac is only
temporarily rendered and therefore not included in that calculation I just showed you
but regarding the scrolling, we can also get some interesting data, we can for example get scrollHeight.
Now what scrollHeight gives you is the entire height of the content including the part which is currently
not visible in the box, so which is outside of the box at the bottom here for example or now at the
top.
So scrollHeight is the entire height including the non-visible parts because they're currently scrolled
out of view.
You also have another interesting value, scrollTop,
scrollTop gives you information by how much you scroll that content in the box.
So if I scroll the content all the way to the bottom for example, you see now I have a value of 240 there
because I basically scroll the content up 240 pixels you could say. If I scroll somewhere in the middle,
that obviously shrinks, if I go all the way to the top
so I haven't scrolled at all,
I got zero again.
Now you don't need to memorize all these properties of course, on MDN,
you can check out the HTML element article and there, you'll find all the properties there and on the
element article to be precise
and there you can read more about that
and then of course also just play around with them to get a feeling for what these values do and what
they offer. Attached you also find this simple slide where I just summarized the key values for you
and what they mean and which values they give you.
One note about the entire document width, if you want to get that, you got two options, you can use
window.innerWidth and window.innerHeight and that should give you the width and height you have here
inside of your window,
so without the dev tools, without that URL bar at the top and so on
but the problem with that is that if you had a visible scroll bar on Internet Explorer for example or
on Windows in general, you might have that, then this will actually include the scroll bar and not subtract it
from the width and height and therefore actually give you more width and height than you actually
have available for your content. Hence a better way of getting the real available width and height
is to go to document, document element which is your root element including head and body so to say
and there you use the clientWidth and the clientHeight. Here,
this gives me the exact same values as window.innerWidth and innerHeight simply because I have no scroll
bar here
but again for the reason I just mentioned, if you had one,
these values are more reliable because they will deduct any visible scroll bars and give you the real
width and height that is available.