To act when we add does opened attribute we need to listen to changes and attributes obviously and you'll
learn how that works right.
Thus far we have all the logic in the constructor.
Now it's simply time to add more methods here and I will add the attribute changed callback here and
you remember that you here get the name of the attribute which changed the old value and the new value.
And then does will trigger for any observed attribute which changed.
For this we also have to add our static getter here observed attributes and make sure you get the the
naming right here.
Otherwise it will not work.
And there you have to return square brackets and then the name of the attributes you want to watch.
And here it's the open attribute.
And if you chose a different name that will be added here outside of your component.
Then you also have to listen to a different name in here of course.
Now for the addition of the open attribute this should be triggered.
And then when this runs maybe we also have other attributes.
So here I will check if NAME IS EQUAL TO opened and if that is the case we know that something happened
on the open attribute.
So we probably want to show our model but I can simply add another if check and see if this has an attribute
of open.
Now cause if that is now available then we know it has been added and then I know I want to change the
styling to set the opacity to 1 and 2 set pointer events to all.
So to react to clicks on my backdrop and my mode again.
And there are a couple of ways of doing that.
One thing we can do as we can access our shadow root and there of course query for our backdrop and
set the style of the backdrop.
And here simply add opacity or set opacity to 1 and then also the style of the backdrop pointer events
should be set to all to react to all clicks on the backdrop.
And then we do exactly the same here.
For our modal.
So there we all set you Pass City to 1 and the pointer events to all.
And if you save that and you reload that page and you click that button.
Indeed both shows up here and now we can't click this spot near anymore because the point or events
are on.
We now catch any clicks with the backdrop and with the motel.
This is one possible way of doing this.
There are other possible ways too but I will actually comment this out.
It might seem like the obvious way of reacting to the opened attribute but if all you want to do is
change some styling then there is a way easier approach to do that to get there.
You don't need attribute changed callback for that you don't need to listen to these changes.
Even so I will comment all of that out.
It's nice knowing that and you would need dead if you had any other logic you wanted to execute like
start a timer change some text add an element but if you just want to change some styles you can do
that with CSI as only because what happens when the open attribute is added to our tag here.
Well then it looks like this year right.
Our tag and then the open attribute and you might remember that in C as s there are attributes selectors.
So we can simply write to see us as rule that changes to style when the open attribute is available
on our root element on our host element.
So what I'll do is I'll add a new rule here colon host with the condition that the open attribute is
there and does all I need to write for this does no means for the host element which is our custom tag
when the open attribute is available and this is the normal attribute syntax you know from C as S then
I want to change his style and I want to change the style of my backdrop so I can still combine these
selectors and this just means select the backdrop.
If my host has the open attribute and then I want to set your passive t to 1 and I want to set pointer
events to all
and I can now of course do the same for my modal by simply repeating this with hashtag modal and with
this change in place please keep in mind that I commented out my attributes changed callback so if this
change in place up here we can go back and reload our page and still click that button and see the modal
and the backdrop and this is now the more elegant way of solving this.
If you only need to change styles if you need to do anything else like add an Schimmel element then
of course you would need to listen to that and then run whichever logic add whichever element you want
to add in your attributes changed callback.