The idea is that you wrap try catch around the code that might fail. So you might think, great
I'm going to put my entire program into the try block, right?
We put all that code here,
all of that,
we move that into try because then we catch any error that might occur
and even though we don't know yet what we can do then, this sounds good,
we catch any error and we'll probably be able to do something great and have our script not fail.
This is not what you should do,
don't wrap your entire script into try,
it's not good for performance and it's also a very bad programming style.
You want to write code that doesn't yield errors and you can use the debugging section to find and fix
logical and syntax errors,
you only want to move code into try where you can't control whether it throws an error or not,
as it's the case here, we can't control whether the user enters something valid or not.
So in the end, we move this line in here
but since I want to be able to use chosen life thereafter, I will actually create and declare the variable
before the try block, like this and then only assign a new value to it inside of the try block.
So now we have that try block which tries that code but just like that, it's not valid,
it's not helpful and it's also not valid syntax,
you also need to add a catch block. So you add the catch keyword and then you add parentheses and in
there, a parameter which you can give any name you want,
tpically you name it
error.
This now is like a function, so you add curly braces thereafter and inside of these curly braces, this error
which was caught is available.
So this is called like a function by Javascript and error is the error which was thrown, in this case
it's your own error object, if it's some system error, like with the network request
I already mentioned, then it will be that error object which Javascript created for you.
So here for example, we can now console log that error to have a look at it, to see what's inside
and we could now say
okay
chosenMaxLife in this case is 100,
that's our fallback logic. If this fails and if it succeeds by the way of course, this will not execute
but if this fails, if we get an error here, then this will not execute successfully
but this here will and therefore here we can now set a value with which the rest of our code works.
This is not always possible, sometimes the best you can do is show an error message to the user,
for example if a server is offline and you can't save data on a server, there's little else you can do,
you can just tell the user about that and tell him to not leave the page and try again later. In other
cases like this, you might be able to use a fallback value and fall back without the user even noticing.
You could of course also tell the user that you entered something wrong, default value of 100
was used
so that you fall back but you let the user know about that,
that's totally up to you.
So now with that, if we save that and we reload,
now if I enter
hi there, I get that you entered something wrong,
I get that console log which please note, now is not an error anymore,
we don't have that red background so this is not a system error anymore, instead it's just the normal
log message and our app works just as before with that value of 100 being used.
So that now all works and we can play with this game just as before
but now with our own error handling logic, in this case with a graceful fallback, in other cases showing
an error message might be the best you can do.
Now just to make this really clear again, of course the logic we had before where we had just this if check
and then also assigned a default value of 100 wasn't bad,
I wanted to show you try catch which here isn't bad
and in other cases is absolutely necessary because in other cases, you get an error
if you want it or not and you need to be able to handle it,
that's why it's a good time to already practice with it here even though in this exact case, since parseInt
doesn't throw an error, you could have absolutely kept the
old logic and avoided this try catch block.
Now I'm not entirely done with try catch,
you can also add another element to try catch and that's finally.
Now you add finally like this, you add the finally keyword after try or after try catch,
you don't need to have catch, you can just have finally here,
you need to have try though, try catch without try
doesn't exist but you can also have try catch finally
and the idea is that the code inside of finally will now always execute no matter if you had an error
or not.
Now you might wonder what the idea behind that is because the code after try catch, so all the other
code also executes here
no matter if we had an error or not.
So why would this be helpful?
Well you can use finally to do any cleanup work if you for example have a case where another error
happens inside your try catch block and be that only because you maybe throw the error
again, that's also something you will sometimes do the more advanced you become,
this is called rethrowing an error and we might do some error handling here,
typically not some fallback as we're doing it here though
but we might just be sending that error to our own analytic server for example
so that we are notified of that error we had in our application.
Maybe we can't fall back as we can here but maybe we can just show the user an error message and we
also want to log the error to our own analytic servers. So we might be sending that request to our own
servers here and then we rethrow that error.
We rethrow that error here
so that in some other part of our code, we can then handle it and show that
error message to the user.
Again, that's a little hard to imagine here,
I'm aware of that because this is some basic project, some basic program but you could have multiple
try catch blocks in different places of your app
and here, you only have the first one which sends it to your own servers and then you throw that error
again.
Now in that case, still maybe you want to do some cleanup work here, maybe release some data which you
save, maybe clear some variables, do something like this and then you could do that in finally. Now I
will be honest, in a lot of scenarios, you will not need finally, especially in this example you definitely
don't need it because we can perfectly fall back,
so the code after this will execute, there's no reason to rethrow the error.
If you would rethrow, the code thereafter doesn't execute and only finally will,
that's the difference then,
that's the advantage of finally, it executes even if you do throw an error here,
the other code will not because your script will crash if you then don't handle it somewhere else
but here, we don't really need that because we have a perfect fallback.
It's good to know that finally is there though in cases where you will have an error in catch, you rethrow
or you get another error and therefore you know the rest of your script will not be able to continue,
well then finally can be used for some cleanup work and that can be helpful at times. Now
just as with the other construct shown here, we'll also see try catch in action again later in the course
and especially when we work with network requests, it will make more sense because then we really need
it,
then there are things we can't do without it
but since it is a control structure, now is the time to introduce it,
keep it in mind, keep its general functionality in mind, that you try code and then you can react upon
an error and fall back or show an error message and you'll get more and more practice with it throughout
this course.