Now to conclude this module, let's come back to something we actually started the module with and that's
how we import our scripts into the HTML file.
I'm doing this here at the end of the body tag, at the end of the body section in the document and I'm
doing it here because our scripts rely on the HTML page being rendered. We are accessing items in
the page so to say, in the vendor file where I establish connections to the buttons and so on, to which
I then add event listeners here in the app.js file and in order to establish these connections, we
need to run the scripts after the browser parsed and rendered all the HTML code, otherwise the buttons
to which we want to establish connections simply don't exist.
So that's why I import the scripts down there.
Now this is still not entirely optimal and let me show you why. For this,
open your page here in a new incognito window here in Chrome and I simply use this incognito window here
because this allows me to rule out that what I'm about to show you gets distorted by any extensions
or browser plugins.
So I opened the page here in Chrome, in the incognito window and now we can again open the developer
tools which allow us to have a look behind the scenes and there, I increased them in size a little bit
and there you should go to this performance tab,
you can also click these arrows here if you don't find it here.
Now what's the performance tab?
The performance tab allows us to get an idea of what the browser does in detail when it renders
this page and
there are many things you can do with it but it's a great tool for understanding how the scripts are
loaded, parsed and executed and what might be the issue here.
So with the page being used here, press this record button here and then reload the page by using a
shortcut for it or using the reload button and then stop recording this.
Now you get this profile and this might look confusing at first,
I'm only interested in a short part of this timeline.
Now in this topmost window, you can select the part by holding the mouse button and dragging and I'm
interested in this part where we have these little hills down there you could say, where you have these
vertical lines.
Now if you select this, it gets zoomed in here in the middle and bottommost window and there, you see
which network requests were sent and what the browser did,
so what it parsed, what it executed and so on.
Now what we can see relatively quickly is that we have one long going network request which downloads
the fonts, this kind of distorts everything here
so let me comment out this link here which does load the fonts to not have this distraction in here
so that we can focus entirely on the scripts.
So comment this out in the HTML file so that this is no longer getting used, save the file thereafter
and then let's repeat it,
let's clear this, press the record button, reload this page,
stop recording this,
zoom in here. Now we have a clearer picture of what happened.
What happened is that here in that work tab, we first download the index.html file,
that's the blue part and thereafter the CSS file and the script files.
Now let's go to the bottommost window,
there we see what the browser did in detail and if we zoom in here, which you can do with the mouse
wheel, you see that in the end here we receive a data, that's the downloaded HTML file, if you see, this
roughly lines up, here in network tab it's done downloading the file, that's when this receive, data event
is triggered when it finished loading it and then it starts parsing the HTML code. Now it starts parsing
the HTML code and what you can see is that pretty much at the end of that when it's done parsing
this, it sends off requests to the Javascript files, the CSS file is sent off relatively early, if you
would draw a vertical line down there, that happens early when that gets parsed which makes sense because
we request the CSS files here in the head section but the Javascript files get requested a bit
later because we request them at the bottom of our HTML file.
Now obviously that's not a huge file, so there's not much time difference between but still we request
the Javascript files only after the parsing is done or when it's almost done entirely because we do
that at the bottom of the HTML file.
So that's why we only request the files once we're almost done parsing the HTML document as you can
see with this vertical line. Now what's the implication of that?
Of course the benefit is that the scripts only execute after parsing is done but we also see that we
start parsing and only when we're done, we download the scripts and only once the scripts are downloaded
way over here,
of course that's not that long if we have a look at the milliseconds, I'm only talking about a few milliseconds
here but still, only after this is done, we actually execute the scripts,
these are these yellow blocks you find down there,
these are the two scripts which are getting executed.
The other parts are the stylesheet being parsed and the styles being rendered,
we can ignore that.
So here we execute the scripts,
now what we effectively see is that we start executing the first script at around 930ms and
we're done passing at around 906, 907,
so there are roughly around 20 milliseconds of pause between us being done with parsing the HTML
file and executing the script.
Now these are all very small numbers which we can't even feel when we load the page because we have
small scripts and we have a small, short HTML file
but imagine that our scripts would be longer, that they would take longer to load and execute and that
we have way more HTML code that needs to be parsed. Then it's not that great that we wait for all
this code to be parsed just to start loading the scripts.
We certainly want to execute them after this was parsed because we rely on the parsed content, so that's
fine,
we don't want to execute the scripts earlier but loading them earlier, downloading them from the server
earlier,
that would be a good idea.
Also keep in mind that all the loading is very fast here of course because we're doing this all locally,
we're just accessing the file here,
there is no web server involved,
there is no latency, so this would be slower if we were really serving this webpage and hence we have the
ideal scenario here
and yet we have this unnecessary delay and we certainly want to shrink that delay if we think about
really hosting this on a web server.
We don't want to start loading the scripts once everything was parsed,
we want to load the scripts as early as possible and then still only execute them after everything was
parsed
so we want to get the best of both worlds.
Now of course we can grab the scripts and move them into head section, maybe here below the stylesheet.
Now if we do that and I clear here, this start recording and reload and stop, we get a better picture here.
If I zoom in, here we download the HTML file and now what we see is that we start parsing HTML.
Now we then fetch the styles and the scripts and we pause parsing here as you can see, we pause that,
we only pick it up back here when basically downloading the scripts finished,
we also executed the scripts here.
Now this looks a bit strange, looks like downloaded app.js for longer than it actually took because
we do execute it here
so this is a bit distorted.
The main takeaway here is that we start parsing HTML, then we encounter the script imports, we then
download the scripts and pause parsing therefore, this blocks parsing and then we execute the scripts and
only thereafter we continue parsing.
Now that's of course bad and this also causes an error because now we try to interact with the buttons
on the webpage without those being ready,
so that's also not ideal.
We download the scripts earlier which is great but we now also execute them too early. The solution is
an extra attribute which we can add to the script and that's the defer attribute.
You add it like this, without a special value, just like this to both script tags and defer tells the
browser that it should download these scripts right away but that it should not block parsing HTML
so that it instead should continue with parsing HTML and only execute the scripts after everything
has been parsed.
So it starts downloading early but it doesn't execute the scripts right away once they've finished downloading,
instead it guarantees us that it only executes the scripts once they were downloaded and once parsing
HTML finished.
So if we now save this and we go back, clear this again and create a new snapshot, reload, stop,
if we now zoom in here, we see HTML file is downloaded,
we start parsing it and then here what happens is that I download all the scripts and I execute the
scripts over there,
the two yellow blocks here but parsing HTML did finish before that.
This is the entire HTML document being parsed, this blue block here is the stylesheet, this is not HTML
and these are just some events in between these small blue blocks.
So now, the script downloading and execution doesn't block the HTML code from being parsed and rendered
and instead, that continues and the only thing that does change is that we download the scripts earlier
which is great.
Now again in this scenario here, that's all a bit hard to really see because it's all so super fast
because I serve it locally and we have very small files but the general concept and the difference should
be clear
and of course this matters way more if you really serve this on a server and if you have bigger files
and you can see that all this parsing and script execution is done roughly 20 milliseconds after we
started parsing the HTML document, so that is faster than what we saw previously when we started loading
and then executing the scripts at the bottom of the body tag.
So therefore what you should do when working with Javascript is you should import it like this in your
head section with the defer attribute because this ensures that it gets loaded early but executed
only once parsing HTML finished, so you have the best of both worlds. Now sometimes, you also have scripts
which you want to load early but which you then also want to execute early because maybe they don't
rely on the HTML code, you don't establish a connection to it and therefore you don't care whether
parsing HTML finished or not.
This can also be achieved by using the async keyword instead of the defer keyword. Async works a bit like
defer, it tells the browser to start loading the scripts as early as possible and then the browser is
not blocked but instead continues parsing HTML
but the difference to defer is that with async, the script then executes right away once it was downloaded.
So it does not wait for all the HTML code to be parsed,
instead it executes as early as possible. So then parsing of HTML will be paused until it is executed
and only thereafter it will pick up again. Here
therefore this is not the correct solution because that could lead to the script being executed before
all HTML code has been parsed but in other scenarios where your scripts don't interact with the web
page because you maybe just send some data to some background server, well in such cases, you could use
async.
One other important difference to be aware of is that with async, a script really executes as early as
possible, so as soon as it was downloaded. The order of the script execution is therefore not guaranteed,
the app.js script could execute before the vendor.js script if it is loaded earlier. With defer
on the other side,
the browser guarantees the order.
So even if app.js would be downloaded faster, vendor.js would still execute before app.js,
so the order is guaranteed with defer,
it's not with async, so async is really just a solution if you have a standalone script that doesn't
rely on your HTML content. Also note that defer and async are only available if you have an external
script,
if you have an inline script, so a script which you write right in here, in your HTML file, if you have something
like this, defer and async is ignored because what would that do,
there is no file to download,
this is embedded in the HTML file so this is available once the HTML file was downloaded,
so therefore defer and async doesn't make sense here because there is nothing that would need to be downloaded.
Such scripts are always executed immediately and therefore if those scripts which you embed here rely
on the HTML code, you'll always have to move them to the end of the body section
but in general it's not a good idea to have important or longer scripts here in your HTML file,
you should always use external files for that to keep your HTML files small and focused and don't
bloat it with a lot of scripts.
Also important,
you can't combine an inline script like this and then an import with the source attribute.
If you do that, then the inline script will be ignored and just the external file will be imported, so
you can't combine that. Now with that,
let me remove that and turn this back to defer because that's now our final setup
and if I now save this and I close the developer tools and I reload here and I also comment back in
my font because now I want to have it back, if I do that, you see this still works as before but now
it does so with the help of scripts that are loaded in a more efficient way which does not make a big
difference for this simple application, for this simple demo here but which does matter or could matter
a lot for bigger applications which you really host on a web server.