So now that we can close and open our mobile Let's dispatch our own events now how do we do that.
Well for that let me first of all except on the canceled event the event object we get this automatically
we get this automatically because we used this click event listener here and JavaScript just works in
a way that the method which gets triggered for does event automatically receives an object with some
metadata about the event that was created by javascript.
So about that built in event.
Now we don't need that event to dispatch our own once.
We will not copy it or anything like that.
But on this event with event target I get access to the target that is responsible for this event.
So in my case the button and this button just like every other age criminal element is capable of dispatching
a new event with the dispatch event method the dispatch event method takes a new event.
So a totally new event not this event we receive here a new event as an argument.
So you're all named as cancel events.
The name is totally up to you.
And I created with the new keyword which we use in javascript to create new objects based on constructor
functions or classes and I'll use the built in event object.
So this is built into javascript just SDH html element is so now I can create a new event here and we
give this event our own name by passing it in the constructor here between quotation marks.
So as a string and here I'll name this cancel.
And this is exactly the name to which we will be able to listen to from outside later.
So here I am listening to the cancel event in my integrated email file and this should work later because
I'm dispatching an event named cancel here.
So now I have has this cancel event to my dispatch event function.
And with that let's see if that works.
Let's go back and reload here click that and click cancel.
And we don't see canceled here in the console even though we should be logging that here when we listen
to the canceled event.
So somehow our own event doesn't really seem to be dispatched on our component and indeed it isn't.
It is dispatched on the button because and that is the only reason why I accept the Devens argument
here.
We're dispatching it on the event target of the cancel event or off key cancelled event handler I should
say.
And that event handler is used on the click event of the cancel button.
So the event target of that event is to cancel button.
So we're using dad H Tim Al element to dispatch the event here and therefore the only place where we
can listen to that well is that button.
So if I would add an event listener here and I would listen for the cancel event here and there I just
use an anonymous Erol function to quickly output cancel inside the component.
Then we should see that log once we click the cancel button because now we're listening to the same
element where we dispatched us and indeed here we see cancel inside the component.
So the good thing is dispatching our customer event works.
The bad thing is it is only available on our button.
It doesn't leave our component and that is not ideal.
Let's work on that and I'll comment this out here.
Let's work on this in the next lecture.