So our basic object here of course works.
Now let's say we created an object and then for whatever reason, maybe because the user click the button
and that triggers that we want to edit this object,
we want to add a property after this object has been created.
Now there are two approaches,
the more complex approach would be to create a brand new object,
for this we would have to turn this into a variable so that we can assign a new value to person because
with a const, this would not be allowed,
if you have a constant you must not ever assign a new value to it with an equal sign
and then we could recreate this object here.
Now we can copy over everything from there and of course then add whatever we want to add, let's say
isAdmin true.
Now of course that's super complex and not really what we might want to do,
also if we changed some value here, we have to ensure that we pick up any changes that were made between
this declaration and this reassignment,
so in some code in between.
So this is typically not what we might want to do in most use cases and certainly not manually by copying
all the code,
instead what you can always do on Javascript objects is you can use the dot notation and simply access
a property which you haven't added before,
for example isAdmin. At this point of time, person has no isAdmin property,
we didn't add it here but you can do this here.
Now if you try to log this, you will also not get an error and I'll remove that greet function call
here so that this alert doesn't always open.
So if we log that, we won't get an error,
instead we just log undefined.
That's also something to keep in mind.
If you access a property on an object which doesn't exist, you're not getting an error,
instead you get undefined but what you can do is you can simply assign a value to this property now,
even if you didn't define it before. You can simply set this to true and if you therefore console
log your entire person let's say, you will see that isAdmin is now a part of that person.
So if we reload this and expand it here, we see isAdmin has been added.
So adding properties on the fly is super easy,
you just access them with the dot notation and assign a value and it doesn't matter if that property was
part before or not, if it wasn't part of the person before it's now added,
if it was part, so if we would set person age to 31 for example, well then we of course overwrite
that old value.
So we even overwrite or we add and both works, both are supported and that of course gives us a lot of flexibility
there.
Now sometimes you also want to get rid of a certain property,
let's say you want to make sure that you actually delete the age here,
so instead of reassigning it here, we want to get rid of a property. That's also possible with a special
keyword
Javascript provides to you, the delete keyword. You just type delete like this,
then a whitespace so that this is a standalone keyword and then simply person. and then whatever
property you want to delete, for example age,
just like this
and this will delete the age property from the person object. So if we now save that and we reload,
you will see that in the logged person, age is missing.
So if you ever want to remove a property, that is one way of doing it. Now always keep in mind, if we thereafter
try to access age, we'll not get an error, we'll just get undefined,
so deleting a property is basically as if you would set it to undefined.
So if I reload here, we see undefined gets logged here.
Therefore another way of getting rid of a property is to use person.age in this case here,
so instead of using this and setting it equal to undefined.
Now this is not super clean though, it will work, it will do the trick and you can technically use it
but it is a good rule to keep in mind that you should actually never assign undefined to any value.
You might remember earlier in the course I mentioned that we have undefined and null. null is the value
we use if we want to reset something, if we want to clear something. Undefined is a value which we as
a developer never actively assign to anything, instead undefined just is a default value Javascript assigns
to uninitialized variables or properties in this case.
So doing this technically works and you can do it of course, it's not a hard rule that you should never
assign undefined to anything but you might consider if you really want to do that, this here might be
cleaner,
it clearly expresses what you want to do, the effect here is the same.
Now you would by the way not have the same effect if you would set person.age to null.
This will reset it but what you'll see is that if you now reload this, we log null here
and if I log the entire person, you will see that age is now still an active property of person so to
say because null is not exactly the same as undefined as you also learned. It's not exactly the same,
they are of different types in the end and therefore it's a difference, if you set something to null
which really just means the person has this property,
we just don't have a value in there right now
or if you set it to undefined which means this person doesn't even have an age property.
So these are tiny things where you want to be careful, if you do that, you typically do that in situations
where you say I'm going to assign some age later probably, I just don't have one right now
whereas if you delete it, you're basically saying I don't need that age on that person anymore, I will
never use it anywhere else in this program.
So these are the subtle differences when it comes to deleting and resetting properties in objects.