So that are factory functions and closely related to factory functions is the concept of closures.
Now here's an important rule which you can memorize for Javascript interviews, every function in Javascript
is a closure,
so why is every function a closure
then? What is that concept of being a closure then?
Well this is closely related to the idea of having scopes for our variables. As you learned earlier in
the course,
you have different scopes - you have block scope when we're working with variables that are created with
const or let and that simply means that inside of curly braces like for example here in a function
definition, if you create a variable in there or if you get a parameter, it's only usable inside of that
function but not outside of it.
On the other hand, global variables or constants which are created outside of functions can be used
inside of the functions,
that's something you already knew.
Now if you have a function in a function, that inner function can use all the variables or parameters
of the outer function and all variables that are defined globally,
the outer function can not access the inner functions specific constants or variables.
So for example here, amount could not be accessed from inside that outer function, only from inside
that inner function,
so that's what you already knew.
The more technical term for this would be that we have different lexical environments. Each function
has its own lexical environment and you have a global environment as well
and the variables and constants are registered in these different environments you could say. Now when
a function is created as we do it here with the function keyword by using this function declaration,
then this function creates a new lexical environment and registers any variables it has access to inside
of this environment.
So in this case for the outer function, the create tax calculator function, the tax parameter here for
example would be a variable of its lexical environment. The global environment would have the hobbies
constant for example. The inner function has its own environment with the amount parameter but it also
has access to the outer functions environment.
Now when we call create tax calculator, then this inner function is created, not before we do so because
it's inside of that creates tax calculator function,
so where this function the outer function is created when the script parses this file, the inner function
is only created when we call this function, when we call the create tax calculator function.
So when this function then is created in here, something interesting happens, it's in this case here logs
in the value for tax when this outer function runs.
So if you then call that outer function again with a different value, since we execute a brand new function,
since we have a totally different function execution, the inner function receives this brand new
tax value and is totally detached from that other function execution.
Now on the other hand if we have some other variable, let's say a multiplier for whatever reason we need
that, 1.1 and we refer to that inside of that function no matter if it's the outer or the inner
one, then this will be updated when it changes outside of this function.
So for example if I multiply this with multiplier here and I then call the create tax calculator function
and thereafter change the multiplier,
so after calling this outer function but before calling the inner function to 1.2, you will see that
a multiplier of 1.2 will be used, to make it easier to see,
I'll print the multiplier here. So let's save that and reload and you see 1.2 gets printed
here.
So what does this tell us?
It tells us that we do log in tax here because that's part of this specific environment of the outer
function
when it runs but we don't log in the concrete value of multiplier because that's part of the global
environment
and in the end what happens is just each function registers its surrounding environments and the variables
that are defined in there
and if these variables change and this function uses such a variable, then it takes the latest value.
Now for tax in this case here, that would be the case too
but when this inner function is created, it has a look at its surrounding environment which is this functions,
the create tax calculator functions environment for example
and there we have a tax variable, a tax parameter
and if that would change, the inner function would take the new one but this never changes because the
only time we pass in a new value is when we execute this function again,
this however will be a brand new execution and not change that inner function that was created on the
first function execution here, which is why that inner function created by that first function execution
still has its old environment with the tax you set up here as an argument. Now why is it called a closure
then?
Because every function closes over the surrounding environment which means it registers the surrounding
environment and the variables registered there and it memorizes the values of these variables.
If you then change a variable, well that is reflected inside of the function
but if it does not change, the function still is able to use for example the tax value you passed
in when you created the outer function.
That is not something you should take for granted because you could also read this code here in a different
way.
You could say when the outer function, when create tax calculator is called with a value of .19,
then what happens is that this function runs, a new function is created which for the moment is simply
a task that is done pretty fast
and then we return this created function. So you could say that theoretically tax isn't used anymore,
sure
the inner function uses it but Javascript could just ignore that. The outer function is done and it was
the outer function which received the tax parameter, so we could think that Javascript just gets rid
of that tax value and ignores it
and if we then eventually call the inner function, that might be missing. Now in Javascript, you can indeed
take for granted that it will not be missing
but I want to emphasize that this is not something you can take for granted in all programming languages.
It is like this in Javascript but it's not necessarily like this in other languages.
So a function, every function in Javascript is a closure because it closes over the variables defined in
its environment
and it kind of memorizes them, so that they're not thrown away when you don't need them in the surrounding
context anymore.
So even if multiplier wouldn't be used down there and therefore in the global context, it actually wouldn't
be used anymore,
Javascript will still not throw away the value stored in here because in this inner function, we still
might use it and therefore this inner function closed over the surrounding variables and stored their
values, so that even if you don't need them anywhere else, you can still use them from inside of the
function.
This is why we also call this a closure and why every function in Javascript is a closure because every
function in Javascript behaves like this.