So we saw some core types in action we saw type costing and action.
Now let's dive into a bit more advanced types objects and arrays for example.
Now thus far I only work with strings of numbers and yeah actually H HTML input element is an object
in the end just a specific type of object.
But let's have a look at objects in general.
Let's say for whatever reason when we calculate our result here we don't want a stored it in a constant
result like this or not just in that constant.
But instead we also want to create a result container and that should be a javascript object where we
have the rest property and that holds.
Our result of course it's a bit redundant to have an extra container but for demo purposes it's fine.
Now clearly we have an object here.
Now in this object we have one property the rest property.
Now which type is result container now.
Well it is of type object.
If I add object here this works.
I can't explicitly set this to type object and type won't complain.
Now one problem with this approach is that we don't get the best possible order completion and type
support.
If I access dot address here I get an error and if I annexes anything else here I also get an error.
Now for H that makes sense but rest should definitely work right.
Because we have a rest property here.
Well the object type is very general.
It just says it's an object but I have no information about it.
So that's not really the type you want to use state to date.
Instead we want to be specific and you can define an object type in way more detail in typescript instead
of using object here.
You can use curly braces here in the type assignment and this might look strange at first because it
looks like we are creating an object here.
But keep in mind we're on the left side of the equals sign here and we're after a colon.
So this Indian Justice finds a type and this is just us defining an object type because we can now define
all the key value pairs we have in this object.
For example we can say this object will have a rest property and the type of does rest property.
So the value is stored in the rest property will be a number and now we're making it very clear what's
inside result container.
So now I can access dot address here and I can do stuff with it that I can do with numbers but I can't
access to dot H for example because there clearly is no age property to find that this object type.
Now of course you can do that but it's redundant because if we remove that we see that's the type typescript
inferred anyways because again we can rely on typescript type inference and if we initialize an object
with a specific value then of course typescript in first the object type to fit that values structure.
So here since I initialize for salt container with an object that has a rest property which holds a
number types with correctly infers that the type of result container is an object type with a rest property
which hold a value of type number.
So we don't need to set it explicitly.
I will still do it though to have these for reference but you wouldn't do it in reality because typescript
inference does its job here.
Now let's take it to the next level.
Now let's say we want to store all the result containers in an array now.
So here we could have a results array and now for every time we click.
The add button we reach out to results and we push result container into results and then we log let's
say their results array here if we do that and we quickly compiled is code let's see what does gives
us if we reload this page and I add two numbers you see now I got an array with one element which is
an object which has that arrest property and the result.
And if I now add a second calculation we get two entries here with these two objects.
So this works as intended but we can't add anything to results here.
If I also add let's say the number five here.
This will all the work.
Now maybe that is what you need in your app but in most cases it's probably not what you want.
No the problem is that I initialize results here and I make it clear that it will be an array but I'm
not specifying which kind of array which kind of data will be in the array and in JavaScript of course
you can have mixed data.
And as I said sometimes you need debt but also a lot of the times you don't need it and you want to
have one data type in an array.
Now you can tell type could which data hyped it should be.
So let's assign a type here.
And in this case I want to have a collection of objects in these in disarray and the objects should
have this structure here.
So in that case I can add this as a type.
But now I would say that results should be an object of that type but it should be an array holding
such objects.
And we make it clear in typescript by adding square brackets here and with Dad we're saying OK this
is an array and the data types India array will be object of that structure.
And now you'll see I get an error down there where I try to push five because five is not a sizeable
to a parameter of type object which has this structure.
So now again we are wide an unnecessary mistake by being clear about the types of data we store.
And just a side note of course if we had let's say an array names here which we initialize with a value
then types could would automatically inferred the array.
Here it infers that this is an array full of strings.
So that is something we can always rely on and we can also turn isn't a concert by the way.
So that is something we can rely on and this is just needed here.
If we initialized as with no array or with an empty array and we want to be clear about the types of
data we can add.
Now with that let's take our object here to the next level though in here.
I now want you all to have a function print.
So I went to the method to be precise because a function and an object is called a method.
We can do it by adding print like this
and in there I just want to console log this rests.
Now I get an error here I get an error that I can't add a print method here because while I clearly
defined that my object will only have one property rest which is a number.
It won't have a print property which hold a function.
So maybe we should extend our function type here or simply get rid of it here and use inference.
Now this works here and surprisingly dissolves the works.
I can push this to my array even though in the array I say nothing about this function here.
Well that is how typescript simply behaves here.
It doesn't really see does as a problem that we have more properties than as I defined here.
It's just happy that it gets an object which at least has this rest property it doesn't care that we
have more properties still we could be more specific up there and make it clear that any objects that
go into that array should have a print method.
And if we're dead we now have a new question to answer how do we define that.
There should be a function in print which has certain types for its possible parameters and certain
return types well we assign a type to print and we use a so-called function type here.
This looks like an arrow function here.
We have a list of parameters and then an arrow.
But again just as with the object here on the left side of the equals sign this is not a new function
we create instead we're just defining the type of a function that will eventually be stored in print
and here in want of a function which returns nothing so which has a return type of void and which takes
no parameters.
And if it would take parameters we could simply add them here.
But the print function doesn't need any.
So with that I am making it clear that in results we have an array of objects where every object has
a rest property which is of type number and a print property which actually holds a function which takes
no parameters and which returns nothing.
And with that I can for example call results 0 dot print here like this and it should just work.
So let's try to compile this and it does compile without errors.
And if I now reload you'll see indeed it prints 10 here and that is coming from this line here so that's
really really nice and useful.
And this is how we can work with objects arrays and functions and how we can work with their types.
Now let's see which Abbott types types typescript has that we should be aware of.