Now what you're already seeing in the example I showed in the last lecture is that of course this if
else statement in the end allows us to write more reusable code.
Now calculate result is a function that works both for addition and subtraction but you'll also see
that two cases aren't enough here,
I'm not happy with just two cases,
we could also be multiplying or dividing. Well the good thing is besides if and else, you also have else
if. You can use else if to add yet another condition you want to check and you can have more than one
else if statement here.
An alternative would be a nested if statement where you now have an if statement in the else statement,
so that if this condition is not met, you can check another condition but you quickly end up with deeply
nested if statements in if statements in if statements
if you add more and more if statements in if statements and that can make your code harder to read.
So you would typically use such an else if statement here where you can check for another condition
here,
so here I could check if calculation type is equal to subtract and then execute this code and therefore
right now with this code, if calculation type is add, we run this code,
if it subtract, we run this code,
if it's any other value, that's also okay but then neither this code nor that code here runs.
So in that case, none of that code executes and this means that right now this function wouldn't really
work because that down here would be kind of broken but technically, you can also have if statements
in your code where you don't necessarily meet any condition, that might be okay,
it really depends on which kind of code and program you're writing. Throughout this course, you will also
see examples of if statements where we also have the scenario that no condition is met.
If you specify an else case however by the way, you are guaranteed that this code will always run if no
condition was met in advance. So you don't need to have an else block here,
then it might very well be the case that no condition is met and no code runs,
if you have an else block on the other hand then the else code will always run if no condition is met
in this if statement, this is how if statements work.
Now however here, I'm not just interested in adding and subtracting, instead I'll add another
else if statement and check if the calculation type is equal to let's say multiply.
If it is, well then I want to take this multiplication code from down there,
so set current result equal to current result times entered number and set the math operator equal
to this asterisk here and now we can add a normal else block and just perform the division here because
this is our last case.
Of course we could also use another else if block,
that really depends on how you want to do that.
If you just add an else block here,
this means that this code runs no matter what is passed in as calculation type,
so even if it's not divide but Hi, I am Max as a text we would still execute this,
this might or might not be what you want.
If you want to make sure it really is divide here, then you would have to add calculation type equal
to divide.
So now you would just run this code
if calculation type is divide,
if the calculation type is neither add nor subtract or multiply or divide, none of the code would run,
so that's really up to you.
Here I'll go with the explicit check
but you could also just use an else statement here, since we check all other options in advance.
Well and now we just have to make sure that we call calculate result,
so call it here
when we multiply and pass in multiply as a value of course and here for the division, pass in divide
and now we have way more concise and shorter code with our code reusage, we have all the logic in
one function which is good because it means we don't have to check dozens of functions to understand
our code,
instead it's all in here and we have very lean code in here.
Now let's just quickly validate this by running some calculations here
and we seem to have a problem with the multiplication, yes
because I have a typo here that should be multiply.
So let's fix that and reload,
so now multiply this, yes
this now looks way better and with that,
this is the basic introduction to if statements and how you write them and how you use boolean operators.
Now of course here, I always use the equality operator because equality is the thing I'm interested in
here,
this is not really a use case where I would use a greater than operator or anything like that but we'll
also see use cases for that throughout the course.
And of course you can also play around with your own basic if conditions and try them out with some
numbers and some greater than comparisons if you want to,
again this also is something though we'll have a detailed look throughout this module and throughout the entire
course again.