So when I call new product, I want to create a product with different values than the default values
here.
It would be nice if we could call new product and just pass information to that product function because
we call it like a function, wouldn't it be nice if you could pass some arguments like a title, a price
and so on here?
Well turns out you can do that
and for that, you go back to your class and you add a method to that class.
Now a method is added just by adding some name and this can be any name of your choice of course,
then parentheses and then curly braces.
So like this method shorthand you learned about, important you don't add a semicolon thereafter and you
also don't have an equals sign in here,
it's just this shorthand here, right after any fields you might have added and you can of course have more
than one method. You can add another method like this, just in a new line, no semicolon thereafter, just
like that,
basically like you would create a function outside of a class just without the function keyword.
So here however, we don't add the some name method, we'll add custom methods later
but now we need a special method, a method which Javascript automatically calls when we create a new
instance of this class and we create a new instance when we call new and then execute this class like
a function
and this special method which Javascript executes for us is called the constructor method or the constructor
function. We add constructor here as a method name
and that's a reserved name
and then parentheses and then curly braces.
The idea behind a constructor is that it can accept arguments like any normal method and there for example,
we could accept a title, an image or imageUrl or however you want to name it,
I'll just name it image, a description and a price. So we can accept any arguments, any parameters you
want
just like that and in the curly braces and that's the interesting thing now, you can assign the values
you're getting here for these parameters, so you can assign the arguments you're getting, to your class
field, so to the properties of the object when it is instantiated then and you do this with the good
old this keyword. This in here refers to your class or to be precise,
since this class will be used to create an object, to the object that is created. So we can then for example
say this title and set it equal to the title argument.
So this title here refers to the property title which is added to product,
so to the same property
this field would add, title here refers to the title argument.
Therefore we can also say this imageUrl and set it equal to image,
so to the value we get in this parameter,
same for the description. We can set this description equal to desc and this price equal to price.
Now that will create a bunch of properties on the object which is created with this call here and initialize
the values of these properties with the values you passed to the constructor.
So now we can pass in a value for title like a pillow, thereafter
second parameter is the image,
so let's grab that imageUrl and pass that in here as a next argument to our constructor call
and you call this like a normal function with the different values for the different parameters separated
by commas.
Third parameter is description, so let's grab this description here and add this after the image and
last but not least, I have the price which I add here.
Now let me restructure this with my shortcut and now we can get rid of this object because now we create
our object with new product and the same for the carpet of course,
here we can say a carpet, grab that image here and replace this image here with that image,
adjust the price to 89.99 and also replace the description and thereafter we can get
rid of this object as well.
So now we're using this class as a blueprint and the huge advantage here is that we now have an easy,
reusable way of creating objects which are guaranteed to always look the same,
it's impossible for us to omit properties or to mistype properties because it's all defined in here
in this class definition.
So now if we save that and we reload,
we get the same output as before
because we're working with normal Javascript objects in the end,
such a class when we instantiate it with a new keyword returns a normal Javascript object but in a more
convenient way as I would argue.