Now all the shortcuts don't help you if you write bad or incorrect code
but here again modern IDEs or editors like Visual Studio Code have you covered,
you get a lot of autocomplete here.
Let's say here, with our create and write output method, if I want to use this method, let's say I would
want to call it here,
I can type create and write or just create in my case and I get suggestions. I get suggestions of functions
or variables that I could use here that basically includes the words create and they don't just have
to start with it,
they include it anywhere.
It doesn't even have to be one word as you can see with the suggestions down there, all properties or
functions that includes the characters I just typed in the right order will be shown here and then the
suggestions are narrowed down the more I type.
So that's really useful because that allows you to write code quicker,
for example here, I can just type create, the IDE intelligently guesses that I probably mean create and
write output,
otherwise I could select a different option and then all you have to do is tap enter or tap to use that
and to complete that word, which of course saves you the hassle of writing it all on your own,
so that's much faster. Now in addition, you'll also find a short description of what you are going to
use here on the right, here for example you'll see that this is a function, that this is the name and that
this function will take a couple of arguments which of course allows you to find out if that is the
function you really want to use here.
Some functions and properties, especially the built-in ones even have short descriptions attached to
them which you then also find here in the panel on the right to learn more about it and learn more about
what this will do for you.
So this is very important and really helpful.
You'll also get something similar if you for example add a dot after an object or in this case here,
after an array which turns out to be an object. If you add a dot here, you get this auto completion that
offers you a list of all the properties or functions you can access on this object, like the push function
here which allows us to add a new entry, then you get a short description of it here on the right, you
see the arguments it takes, this syntax might not fully be clear at this point but that's not a problem,
we'll dive more into arrays later and you'll see that an array for example has way more methods or way
more functions attached to it
and I'll dive into way more of them in a separate module focused on arrays.
So this dot notation also comes with great auto completion and by the way, if this menu ever closes or
you accidentally close it, if you want to bring it back, of course you can delete the dot and add another
one but you can also just use a shortcut which by default should be control space and this will bring
up this suggestions menu again.
So this is another core feature which I would recommend that you use.
You can also hover over the things and you'll get a short description of what this is and what this
does for example that pushes a function,
it's called method here and I'll come back to what the difference is
but it's essentially a function and you see what it does.
So this is also helpful,
you can hover over the things to learn a bit more about it.
And when you call a function, like let's say create and write output and you enter the parentheses, you
by default get this parameter help here where you see all parameters and the value which you now need
to provide for the first parameter is even highlighted here, so that you know that whatever you're going
to type now will be received on this operator parameter
and once you enter this and you add a comma, you see that now the next parameter is highlighted,
now that's really convenient. If you ever close this menu for some reason, you also get a shortcut for
this,
so let's quickly check this and maybe just type parameter here.
What we see is we got this trigger parameter hints shortcut which is this combination - shift command
space in my case, so if I now type shift command space here, you see this menu reopens
so that's all the really convenient.
So these are the core features you should be aware of and you should experiment with and you should
leverage because that helps you write correct code faster and without errors
and that's always something you want to do of course.