So we set up this project to have a package.JSON file to be managed by npm therefore, we also installed
the ESLint extension in Visual Studio Code.
Now with that out of the way, we can install our first package by running npm install, a command we used
earlier already but now not -g because I don't want install it globally but instead
--save or to be precise, --save-dev which basically signals to npm we want install
the following package as a development dependency of this project, development dependency because it's
not a third-party package which I want to use as part of my project,
it will not be part of the code
I want to upload to some server, it's just a package I need to do something with the code during development
to optimize it, to check it,
anything like that
and then the name of the package here is ESLint,
one word,
that's the package we want install. You can by the way always search for
in this case npm ESLint and find out the npm js page about ESLint to read more about this package,
about its usage and so on,
for this specific package, there is a lot you can configure and I won't dive into all these details here
but of course therefore you have these official docs so that you can learn more about that.
So let's simply hit enter now and this will now install ESLint in this project here. It can take a while
here, shouldn't take too long though
and once this command finished, you should see some output like this and in package.json,
you now have a dev dependencies entry where you see ESLint and the version number under which it
was installed.
This symbol here simply means that we're not necessarily focusing only on this specific version which
is the latest version at the point of time I'm recording this but then we would be fine with this version
or any version higher than that.
We also have a package-lock.json file which holds more detailed information about this dependency
and all the dependencies of this dependency
and you can simply ignore that file, that package-lock.json file.
Now important, you also now have a node modules folder.
This folder holds the dependencies you installed and that's why this folder is quite big,
all the dependencies of this dependency and the dependencies of the dependencies of the dependency and
so on.
So we have a lot of packages in there and in the end here, we also see ESLint, here you can see the code
that the ESLint tool uses.
It's all Javascript code but important to you, you should never change code in node modules,
this is third-party package code,
none of your business,
we take it as granted and this node modules folder is managed by npm.
Indeed you can delete it and if you want to share your code, you always should delete it and recreate
it with npm install in your project folder. When you run npm install, npm will go into your package.json
file, look at your dependencies and development dependencies and install all the dependencies it
finds there,
in this case ESLint and all the dependencies the ESLint package needs
and that's also where this version number then is important, npm install will install at least this version
of this package because of this version number we specified here.
So if I hit npm install, it again we'll go ahead and download all required packages which in my case
is the ESLint package.
So with that, we have ESLint installed,
how can we now use it?