Now let's stick to axios here,
let's use that. Now
we learned about HttpRequests in the previous module,
there we learned how we can use XMLHttpRequest or the fetch API for sending requests.
We built our own utility function that made sending requests and working with the response a bit easier
but still it was a bit clunky, XMLHttpRequest was clunky because of this onLoad thing and so on
and the fetch API was a bit annoying because of the error handling.
Now nothing too bad, you can do that but the more complex your project might get, the more complex your
requirements might be for how you want to be able to configure requests and so on, the more annoying it
might be to manage your own utility function
that wraps the built-in native HTTP functionalities.
Now you can absolutely do that but you might reach a point where you don't want to do that and therefore
back in that project from the last module, let's now use axios. Attached you of course find my snapshot
of this project in case you didn't follow along. So in that project we worked on, we had the sendHttpRequest
function which we called from inside fetch posts and from inside create post.
Now let's use axios and for that, we first of all need to add it which we can conveniently do with this
CDN link here,
so we're not downloading it, we're just using this link.
Now if you wanted to, you could download it, for example you can just enter this CDN link here
in the browser without the script tags of course
and what this does is it loads the Javascript file and you could grab all that code and put it into
your own script file, into an extra script file which you import
but here I will just go for the CDN.
So with the CDN here, let's go to index.html and add it before our script import,
so here I'll add that script import and add defer because we have defer on our script import as well
to make sure that they execute in the right order.
So now we have these two script imports here and now we're ready to use axios.
Now you can always learn how to use a library on its official page or like in this case, on its Github
page where you'll find examples and a description and an overview,
also since it's open source, you could also dive into the source code here and explore that, though of
course depending on the complexity of the project, it might be quite complex to read and understand, it
is Javascript code in the end though.
So here however, we've got a good documentation and to use axios, we don't need to follow that step here,
that is only required if you installed it differently, since we use a CDN,
we'll have a globally available axios object. So here, I'll comment out this sendHttpRequest function
or actually we can leave it here but I'll not use it anymore,
instead here where I await
sendHttpRequest when we fetch posts, I can use axios.
Axios is a globally available variable now, it is made available by this script import,
that's why we can use it. Now axios is an object which has a couple of methods,
for example it has a get method to send a get request,
it also has a post or a put or a delete method.
Here we need the get method and the get method doesn't want the HTTP verb,
the HTTP method because it always is a get request, so we can get rid of that, it only wants the
URL.
Now what does axios then return? Axios always uses promises,
so that's quite convenient, we don't have to manually promisify it,
it uses promises out of the box.
So this get method returns a promise and therefore using await on it,
async await of course works.
Now what we get back here is some kind of response object and we probably want to find out what's in
there before we try to get anything out of it.
So let's console log response here in fetch posts and let's then go to our project, reload this and click
fetch posts.
Now posts are not getting rendered and we get an error because we didn't adjust all code right now
but this is what axios returns and that's actually great,
it's an object with the response status code but unlike the fetch API for example, it also includes the
ready to be used data. So we don't need to convert some streamed data into snapshot as we had to do
it here in the fetch API,
we also don't need to parse it from JSON to Javascript data,
instead we get that automatically converted snapshot data here as part of our response object on that
data field and that data field therefore in this case is this array. So here in our code, where I get the
response from axios, I can just say list of posts is equal to response.data because we have that
data property on the response object and that's it. Now what happens in the case of an error though, if
we send this to an incorrect URL?
Well if we do that,
so if I reload now and I click on fetch posts, I automatically get a nice error message here.
So axios also got me covered there,
unlike the fetch API
and unlike XMLHttpRequest, axios does not treat technically successful responses which have a response
status code though as successful,
instead it does the same thing we manually build here, it throws an error if we get a response that technically
succeeded,
so that was delivered without problems but that has a 400 or 500 status code, axios throws an error for
such responses. So it does not just throw an error if we have a technical problem like a network connectivity
issue, it also throws an error
if we have a technically correct response with an error status code though.
So here we therefore get an error and we make it into the catch block here without any extra work, which
is one of the reasons why axios is so popular,
it just works, using the data is simple, working with errors is simple.
So here we got our error message,
we can also for example have a look at the error.response to look into the response that
caused the error because technically it's a correct response,
so of course it has a status property, it has some data and if we need that, we can get access to it with
the response property on that error
object axios produced. By the way if you're wondering how I know that,
besides using console log to find out,
you'll find such information in the official docs typically.
So here if we now save this and we reload, if I fetch my posts, I do get the response that caused the error
so that I can have a look at the response body in case it included additional useful information.
So that's axios for getting data,
now let me fix that URL and see whether that all works now,
looks good,
so let's now make sure we also use axios to create posts. For that we want to send a post request and
therefore instead of sendHttpRequest, we can use axios.post, again
we don't need to specify the HTTP method because that will be set by axios now and it will now just take
a URL and the data we want to submit.
Now here, I don't want to send my FormData but my post here, so this object.
Now if we do that, let's add then here or use async await of course, since I have async here,
let's actually go for async await.
So here await and get the response, just to find out whether it worked, here
I'll console log the response now. If we do that, let's save this, reload and enter a new post,
does this work and click add and that's looking quite good,
we get back a response with the 201 status code and we see this is the data we submitted, so that works
and there is something interesting here. Besides this being very simple,
we also didn't have to add any headers here.
Please keep in mind that for the fetch API and XMLHttpRequest, we manually had to add the application/json
content type header,
now axios does this for you.
It takes the post here which by the way also is not JSON but a normal Javascript object
and for one, it's then transforms this to JSON
but b) it also adds the header for you
and axios doesn't always use JSON there,
it actually is pretty smart.
Here it analyzes the data you're trying to add
and if that's an object or an array, it assumes that you want to convert this to JSON,
so it's then stringifies this to convert it to JSON and sets the application/json header. If
we would add the FormData here, axios would detect this as well
and if we do that and we try to send some data and we go to the network tab, we see that now the request
actually automatically appended FormData and the content type was also set correctly.
So axios analyzes the body you're appending and then behaves correctly to set the right headers and convert
the data correctly,
so that's again extra convenience you get from axios. Now to finish it all up,
let's also make sure we handle a deletion and for that, we can use axios delete here, don't need to
pass in the method, just the URL and therefore with this added here, if we save that and reload, if
I click fetch posts and I then click on delete here, we see such a delete request is sent here successfully.
So that's axios, it's just one of many Javascript libraries, just like Lodash, it's a very popular library
and when working with HTTP, it really is a great alternative to manually using XMLHttpRequest or the
fetch API. You can use these options but the more complex your application gets, the more micromanagement
you might need to do to make sure that these APIs behave correctly, axios then might be a great alternative
which is simply easier to use.