Let me introduce you to a typescript feature that can help us simplify lines like this.
In this line we have a very long type assignment as you can tell.
This is all just defining the type of data stored in results.
Now of course that's OK we can do that but maybe you want to make it a bit easier.
Well in such a case we can use a so-called type alias.
We do all of that by adding the type keyword which is also only known to typescript not two javascript
and thereafter any name of our choice which typically starts with a capital character.
For example calculation results now.
This effectively allows us to create our own type now with an equal sign.
We now define the type of data on the right side.
So we'll cut it down there and add this here.
Notice can be deceiving because now the object in the array is on the Rights of the equal sign.
But keep in mind that with the type keyword This is a pure type feature.
This is in the end just telling typescript Hey I got my own type named calculation results and it in
the end is this type.
And now we can use calculation result down there.
And with that we simply outsource this long type assignment into this line.
And one advantage is that if we now use this in other places of the code as well which we don't do here
but which we could we could again use the same alias and we wouldn't have to repeat this long type everywhere.
So type aliases can make it easier for you to manage your own complex types and write them only once
and then use them in different places of your application and never need feature types good offers are
literal types and union types.
Let's start with literal types and for this I'll come back to print result.
There we get the result.
Now let's say we also get a second parameter print mode and that should be one of two aloud values either
console or alert.
So we could pass in a string here and then here we check if print mode is equal to let's say console.
And if that's true I will console log their assault.
Else if print mode is equal to alert let's say.
I will show an alert with the result.
And for any other value I will not do anything that is something we could have here.
And now if I go down to line 39 and instead of using my print method I again use print result I could
pass in my result from there so not the result container but just the result and then maybe pass in
console here and repeat the same with alert and now with that of course if we compile this code here
and we reload and I enter and I enter two values here I get 10 in the console but all a year as an alert
because I called it with both modes that could be a typical use case.
Maybe not with logging but in average scenarios like signing up a user where you even have to log in
mode or to sign up mode.
So actually we're not interested in any string here.
We're just interested in these two concrete values.
And for Dad you can use the literal types instead of just using string here.
You can be more specific and you can say I want to allow the value console or alert.
And this is now by the way a combination of multiple types of features.
This here is a literal type.
If you don't just have the overarching type but a concrete value for that type so you're a concrete
string.
And if we combine multiple types and we allow multiple types for one parameter or one variable we have
a so-called union type indicated by this pipe symbol.
This creates a union type which means multiple types of values are allowed in this case for this parameter
either this literal type or dis literal type.
Any average string will not be allowed the advantages that now for one we get better auto completion
here in the ITC as you can see.
And if I tried to call this with let's say any other value I get an error because this is not allowed
here in my union type of literal types.
So literal types and union types are ever very important features and typescript that allow us to write
cleaner code.
And of course we can also use them in conjunction with a type alias we could create our new custom type
alias here and name it print mode and say it's console or alert and then we could use this here and
anywhere else where we want to allow these two types.
So that's also something we can use type aliases for but even without type aliases literal types combined
with union types are extremely useful and union types of course can be used with any types.
You could also except that say here a string or a number.
As a result you want a print that's a number a use case of union types not just with literal types but
also with the main types types of supports.
So these are more type features you should be aware of when you're working with typescript since they
can simplify your life as a typescript developer.
Now I know we're moving fast here and you're learning a lot about the different types types good offers.
Now you don't have to remember them all of course using them comes with experience and if you for example
use a string instead of the more precise literal types.
Combined with that union type feature that's always not the end of the world here.
The official docs as well as dedicated courses like my understanding type of course can help you dive
deeper into TypeScript and get more accustomed to it and you can also always treat typescript as an
addition you can write your regular javascript code and enhance it in some places with typescript syntax
where you need that extra type support and where you want that extra type safety.
Now speaking of that let me add more features types called ads or let me show you more features typescript
adds We learned about union types and literal types.
Now when you have a situation like this in your code where you accept two possible values using a string
is of course absolutely fine you can solve the problem like this but you can also use another type introduced
by typescript which is the enum type.
This does exist in some other programming languages in JavaScript does not exist and enum type is created
by using the enum keyword.
And then any type name of your choice which just like the type alias here should start with a capital
character for example in this case output mode.
Now then you don't use the equals sign though but instead curly braces.
Now it looks like we're creating an object here but this is just the enum type syntax between the curly
braces you now enter all the values you want to allow.
And typically here you use all caps names like console and then with a comma alert.
Now this might look strange.
What is this doing.
This basically creates and you could say array of choices you can use in your code.
And here for example instead of print mode we could we could now use output mode and here check not
for a console but for output mode dot console.
And here
for output mode dot alert and of course now when we call print result we also have to pass in output
mode dot console and output mode dot alert.
Now this simply is an alternative to using the string literal union types you can of course use either
of the two approaches.
This year behind the scenes will be stored as numbers which just are encoded to human readable values
here in your types could code behind the scenes.
This will be the number 0.
This will be the number one and you can see this if you compile the code to javascript if we do that
and we have a look at the javascript file we see this looks quite complex but in the end output mode
is just an object which has properties console and alert which store numbers 0 and 1.
So that's behind the scenes stuff in front of the scenes in our code.
We simply use this with a dot then to access our concrete values.
And that's an alternative to using string literal with a union type simply.
So let's say enum something you can use if you have multiple choice says you want to using your code
multiple modes sort or something like this.
Then you can always use any name.
And with that I basically want to wrap up these core types introduced and added by TypeScript and instead
now have a look at some advanced types or other important type of features namely classes and interfaces.