So that were cross site scripting attacks,
the most dangerous attack pattern when we talk about Javascript code. They only affect browser side Javascript
code
but since this is the part where you typically run a lot of Javascript code, it is a thing you definitely
have to watch out for it and you have to be aware of. Now with that
however, let's move on to cross site request forgery.
What is this attack?
It can be related to cross site scripting attacks but it doesn't have to be. The idea behind cross site
request forgery is that people trick you into clicking on a link that leads to a prepared page where
they abuse your local cookies to then send a request to the page you would normally talk to as well,
let's say your online banking backend
but since you are coming from a prepared page, you then do something there automatically without you
recognizing that you don't want to do, for example send money to someone you don't want to send,
maybe that even as possible to happen behind the scenes without you noticing.
So this attack pattern also depends on injected content, so injected Javascript code but it can
also be just HTML content which submits a form to the trusted server,
the problem is that the form is part of an untrusted page which you might not recognize if the URL
look similar
and then requests on your behalf with your cookies can be made to the trustworthy server,
so the only danger and the only problem is that this is all happening from a malicious site.
So actions might be executed on the trustworthy page with your data without you knowing that it happens
and therefore you might want to protect against that.
Let's have a closer look at this pattern, though I do talk about it in more detail and also how to prevent
it
in my Node.js course because this is more a server side issue.
You need to protect against CSRF attacks on the server side by using a mechanism which is a CSRF token
and again I do discuss this in my Node.js course where we work on the server side on the backend all
the time.
So CSRF stands for cross site request forgery
and the idea is that if you're the user of a web app and you have some backend, let's say the online
banking site which uses Node.js or any other programming language,
this is not exclusive to Javascript, uses any programming language and it talks to database, the server.
Now you are visiting the frontend of this page,
let's say that the user interface of your online banking site and now when you have such a setup, typically
the server-side application identifies you with a so-called session,
so you logged in and then the server side generates this session object, stores session data on the
server and sends you the session ID which is stored in a cookie,
that's a typical authentication setup you have in web pages where frontend and backend work together.
Now then you might be sending an intended request, for example to send money to be and all is good.
The problem is that if you now visit a fake site because someone sends you a link to it, which looks
like the trustworthy site but which isn't, then you visit this page and there, people send a request to
the trustworthy backend, therefore the browser attaches cookies that belong to this trustworthy backend
which is your session ID for example and everything works.
The problem just is since you're on a fake site, the request might be one that is intended by the fake site
but not by you, for example to send money to C and this request will succeed because you sent the right
cookie, the right session ID and you sent it through the right backend.
So again more details can be found in a Node.js course
but this is also a potential tech pattern but not directly linked to Javascript.
It can be implemented with cross site scripting attacks but it can also be implemented by using such
a fake site which does not require cross site scripting attacks.
So therefore this is not really a Javascript security thing,
it's more a server side or general web application security thing
and therefore I do discuss it in more detail in my Node.js course where we write a lot of server side
code.