Before we move on to strings, here's a little demo with the math object and a little convenience function
which you might actually need in many of your programs.
We have math random to give us a random number,
now what does math random produce though? It produces a random number between 0 and 1.
Now that's nice but sometimes you need a random number between 10 and 20,
what can you do in such a scenario?
Well we can write our own function that builds up on math random and allows us to provide an upper and
lower boundary.
Now for that, I'll create a new function and of course you can create it in any way you want, with a function
declaration, function expression, arrow function, whatever you need and I'll name it randomIntBetween,
now of course the name is totally up to you.
Now here I expect two values, a minimum and a maximum value,
so my lower and my upper boundary and we want to return a number here.
Now it all starts with math random but of course, that is between 0 and 1 as we learned and that's not
what we want here.
Now to respect our minimum boundary, we can add the minimum,
if we call this function for example with a value of 5 for min, we now get a random number plus our minimum,
so we can't get a number lower than min because we add min,
so we're already respecting our minimum which sounds quite good.
Now we also of course want to respect the max
however. Now to respect the max here, we need to multiply our random number here.
What happens if we multiply it with our maximum? Let's say our minimum is 5, our maximum is 10,
this gives us a random number between 0 and 1,
we multiply this with 10,
So if we have 0 which is of course very unlikely, then we would stick to 0, we add min,
we have our minimum number, sounds about right.
If we have one, then we multiply this by max,
so if our max value was 10,
now we have 10 and we add 5 to it,
so now we would have a value of 15 which is above our maximum.
So we actually need to multiply it with max minus min,
so only with the range between max and min.
Now if max is 10 and I can put this here to make it easier to keep in mind,
so these are the values we're working with in our fictional example to verify the function.
If min is 5 and max is 10, then this yields 5.
If random, math random gives us 1, then this overall term produces 1 times 5 equals 5,
we add 5 to that, we have 10 which is of course our maximum
so that is all right. Now theoretically, that would be great
but even though it's not saying it here at the tooltip but you could find it on MDN for example, it's
important to understand that for the random method here on the math object, 1 is actually not included,
so the random number we'll get might be 0.99999 but we'll never get a 1.
So as a result, the biggest number we can get here is max minus min,
so that's 5, 5 times 0.99999,
so that's almost 5, plus 5 is almost 10.
Now if we want to include both the minimum and the maximum here,
so we want to make sure that both numbers can occur,
then we're not finished yet because right now this can never yield the maximum because random only yields
0.99999 and therefore we can only get close to the maximum.
Now to get the maximum, we can add one here to our multiplication term so that this actually is 6 for these
values we're providing here and therefore the biggest number we can reach right now is
10.99999,
right,
because we have six times almost 1,
so we have almost 6 as a maximum result here, plus min which is 5,
we have almost 11. Now of course we want to stop at max however which is 10 and not at almost 11
and now we can leverage another function on the math object and that's the floor function. Floor
rounds this number down to the nearest integer, so we can wrap this entire term with math floor and it
will basically just cut the decimal places you could say. So if we had this as a result,
then floor will turn this into 10
and now we have a function which yields a number between min and max where both values are included.
Now of course you can deviate that and you can play around with that and if you google for Javascript,
random between and so on, you'll find many examples where min is not included, where max is not included
and so on
but this here is a pretty common scenario which is why I wanted to show it to you.
Well and with that if we give it a try and we console log random in between let's say 1 and 10, let's
see what that gives us.
If we save that and we go back to our page and reload, now we should get a couple of integers randomly
but never above 10 or below 1.
So now we can run this as often as we want,
we'll never get a number bigger than 10 or smaller than 1.