So we know how we create an object, how we can dynamically add properties, how we can delete properties,
how we can read properties and how we can call functions in objects.
Now let's have a closer look at the property names we're using here,
so at these keys. Thus far I always use keys
like this, basically as I would use them for variable names, anything which you can use as a variable
name can be used as a key name and keys are even more flexible than variables,
so everything which you could use on a variable can be used as a key but not everything which you can
use as a key name can be used as a variable
and here's an example. Let's say I don't want to have name here as a key but first name but also not
written like this
but let's say written like this.
Now as you already can tell, my IDE gives me an error here because this actually is not a valid Javascript
syntax,
having two separate words here, Javascript doesn't know what you mean by that,
it tries to understand how these two words work combined and it sees that first is neither an operator
nor some other keyword,
so it doesn't know what first should do to name and that makes sense because if you had a variable or
a constant, you could also not use first name like that,
that's not supported, right?
You must not have a whitespace in your variable name,
it always has to be exactly one word without whitespace, without dashes and so on.
Now the same is generally true for these object properties, first name like this for example is also
not allowed but you have a way around that. You can use any string as a key in an object and actually
any key you enter is automatically coerced, which is this behind the scenes automatic conversion you
could say, to a string.
So even age is kind of converted to a string in Javascript, so an object really just is a dictionary
you could say of keys which are string values and of then values which can be of any kind of value.
And for first name, Javascript is not able to automatically convert this for us because before this code
runs and Javascript has a chance of converting it, it already breaks because it first of all tries to
interpret this in another way which is not valid.
Now therefore for names like this, we have to tell Javascript that
no we want to use this as a key, it's not some calculation which you should perform or anything
like that,
it should just be a key name
and how could we tell Javascript that this should be a key name which in the end is just a string?
Well we just wrap it in quotes,
single or double quotes, doesn't matter, either way works,
so you can just use any string here as a key name, with a dash, with a whitespace, with multiple words,
whatever you want,
these are all valid key names.
Now I will say that names like this are the exception though, you typically use names which you could
also use on variables because on variables, this does not work,
that's just an important side note.
You can't have const first name,
this does not work as you can already see in the IDE,
this is really exclusive to objects
and again, whilst you can use it there, it's not so common to use it like this.
But let's say we have first name like that,
now we have a new problem, how do we access this?
Well you would say okay person.firstName but we have pretty much the same problem as before now, Javascript
tries to parse this as an expression and in Javascript, this is never a valid syntax, having two words
after each other only works if one of the words is an operator or some keyword, like here with delete
person.age, with this delete keyword, this delete
operator here,
well Javascript understands this
and then it can have a look at the thing after that keyword and see how that is affected by that keyword,
by that operator.
Now it tries the same here and it sees I don't know first, it's not a built-in keyword, it's not some
operator which I know so I don't know what to do with that and what to do with the thing after it,
therefore this doesn't work in Javascript.
So how can we now access this key name, which I told you is valid and which we see, we're not getting
an error here, with this notation? Well the answer is with this notation, we can't
but there is an alternative way of accessing properties on Javascript objects and that's the square
bracket notation.
Now we know this notation from arrays, in arrays
we could also use that to access the elements at certain indexes. In the end,
that makes sense because arrays are just objects
and this is basically just a general object notation. For array objects, we just have that built-in special
behavior that we have certain methods to add elements to the array and they automatically get the indexes
assigned and so on
but other than that, we have this square bracket notation available on any object.
Now what we enter here is now not an index number because this person object doesn't have indexes,
it's not an array but instead here, you can enter any key name but that's now important,
not like this,
this would look for a variable age outside of the object and then try to read that variables value and
find a key with that variables value in here,
instead you pass in a string here.
So here, you can then type first name and this is
now how you can access the first name of person with that square bracket notation.
So now if we save that and we reload here, we see Max being printed here and that is that result of that
property access with square brackets.
So this is really important to know, that you have this alternative and that this allows you to use key
names which you normally could not use without the quotes around them.
By the way, this is also pretty interesting because you might remember that on DOM nodes when we worked
with the styles, for the things like background color, we had to use this camel case notation.
Let me quickly show you what I mean.
We have a bunch of stuff here in our HTML file and let's say I want to select that movie list for
now,
that's in the end an unordered list where I later want to output the movies we added. So right up here,
I'll add movie list with document get element by ID,
that's something you learned.
So now we have access to the movie list
and here, we can access the style object to work with the different CSS styles and as I said, we can for
example access background color, color written like this and set this to red and we have to use
this notation because background color like that would not work and therefore Javascript automatically
gives us these translated property names
if we want to call them like this.
So now we could see that,
however for this movie list we'll also have to set the style of display to block because by default
it's hidden at the moment.
So with these two lines added, if we save that and we reload, we got this red background down there.
Now the interesting thing is with the square bracket notation, we can of course also access background
color like that,
however not exactly like that but with quotes around it as I mentioned, without quotes this here would
lead Javascript to search for a background color variable in our other code and use the value inside
of that variable to then look for a key on the style object with that variables value.
So we have to wrap this in quotes and this will also work
if we save that and reload
but the interesting thing now is that actually the style object does not only have these translated
property names but you also find the original CSS property names in here
because if you wrap your property access in quotes and you use the square bracket notation, you can of
course use background color like this because your key is a string and in the string, you can have any
characters you want - dashes, whitespace, question mark, whatever you want, it's all possible.
So therefore now actually we can set the background color like this and it will also work as you can
tell.
So that's also nice to know I guess and it shows the power of this square bracket access feature and also
of the flexibility we have since we can use any string as a key name
and just again because it's important, all non-string keys here which I have, like age and hobbies are
kind of automatically converted to strings, coerced to strings by Javascript.