So here's our skeleton our HTML page and right now of course no interaction is possible.
Now the first thing that would be great if it worked would be that if I click Add movie we actually
display and overlay a so-called modal here which is like a pop up but not this alert which is controlled
by the browser.
But a pop up which we create visually in our web page which allows us to enter some movie data and India
e-mail code.
We actually already got everything for that.
This Dave here this one here this in the end is such a modal has some see us as classes to look nice
has an I.D. add modal which might come in handy for selecting it later and there.
I also already added a couple of inputs which allow us to add a movie title image URL and a rating which
we didn't enter a year and then some buttons to either cancel adding that movie which I also want to
support or for completing adding that movie would should then added both to a Javascript array but of
course also output it on the page.
If he's still down there I have an unordered list with no entries at the moment I want to populate that
list once we add movies.
So the goal is to show this div.
And of course therefore an important question is why is it not showing at the moment.
Well actually because if we have a look at the as this code in there I added a style to this modal class
which is the class I'm applying here to to stave which sets display to non.
Which basically means it's not added to the document flow it's not visible it's not clickable it's like
it wasn't there.
It's actually part of the DOM as you can tell if you go to the elements tab there you find that modal
but you don't see it anywhere on the screen if I hover over it here if I select that it's also not selected
on the left because it's well set to display non it's not part of the document flow just off the DOM.
That's important difference because that means we will be able to selected from Javascript and then
we can toggle this display style to show it actually there even is an easier way.
There is this visible class which we can add to a modal which will set display to block and also play
a nice little animation to faded it and to slide it in.
So actually our goal will be to make sure that when we click to add movie button we reach out to distaff
here with the idea add modal and we then add this visible class.
These are all things we of course learn so here already is a great place to pause and try this on your
own.
But of course after this short pause which I give you two pause to video we'll do it together so let's
try it together.
And we got two steps with which we should start.
We need to get access to this add modal diff and we can do this with the I.D. We could also try to do
it with a class selector though you should be careful because we also got a number modal here a number
div with the exact same classes.
So since is the first thing with these classes we would be able to use Carberry selector to select by
class because Clarice lecturer selects the first matching element but later when we need to access the
second modal for example we'll definitely need to use the I.D. or come up with some arbitrary unique
selection criteria.
So here I will actually go for the I.D. and selected by that and you also mustn't forget that we all
need to get access to this button so that we can add an event listener and for this if we scroll down
we can have a look here's the header and there is this ad movie button so we all probably want to select
this now we'll have to see how we can select it because this button has no idea or anything like that.
Now of course we can always add an idea and it might be a good idea give us some unique ideas which
we have used anywhere else on the page but also to practice the different ways of selecting stuff.
I will also use a different approach of selecting this button.
Now let's start with the modal though and let's go to app yes and then they're all at a constant because
I'll never assign a new value and I'll give it a name of ad movie modal the name of course is fully
up to you but it should describe what you store in this constant it here.
I mean you end storing a reference too.
Well my modal so to this overlay which you can add and it is the modal for adding a movie so I will
name it ad movie model seems like a fitting name to me.
Now we can elected with document and now we can use get element by I.D. because our model here has an
idea add modal.
So that is probably the most reasonable way of selecting it as an alternative to that just to all to
show this we could all use Kaveri selector and then we just have to add a hash here because a query
selector wants to see as a selector here.
This would work as well would all the selected this tends to have a bit better performance though for
disappeared really won't matter for most apps you'll probably not feel it but it's a little bit better
to use get element by Aidid than to use it for his selector if you really just want to get access to
an element by ID.
So that's just a side note.
And another way of getting access of course all that would have been to use our techniques.
For example we could dive into the body and then have a look at all its children so all the child element
notes and then pick the second child because the first child is this strange backdrop thing which will
become important later.
Second child would be that.
So another way of selecting this would have been to use document body and then their children and then
there the element that indicate one which is the second element.
All these approaches select as movie modal just to prove it all quickly.
Output it here.
Comment out the first two steps so that we don't get errors because I'm using the same constant over
and over again.
And now with that just go to the console here reload.
Now we see that select that does modal and that's also true if I um comments and comments back in and
then reload at the same modal here and also for completeness sake and this is the approach which I will
use if we use get element by I.D. we all locked at mode here.
So these are just some ideas of course there are more ways of selecting it.
Just to give you an idea for that but I will go with this approach because if you have an idea you typically
should strongly consider using that idea at least does all the will be very fast from performance perspective.
So there is little that speaks against using this.
So with that we select a d movie modal.
Now as I said we also need to get access to this button here to add movie button and for that I'll add
another constant here add movie button we're actually I'll name it start add movie button I'll name
it start add movie button because later I will also have a button instead of that ad movie modal so
interrupt that modal which we just selected there we also have a add button and I want to give this
to ad movie button named later because this will be the button when we press it.
That really adds a movie to our app.
The button in the header starts this whole addition process which is why I will call it start at movie
button.
Now how can we select that.
Of course there are different ways of selecting it.
We could for example say document query selector and then reach out into the header and then to the
button.
So here I am using TAC selectors because I only have one header on this entire page it's this header
here and then this is a normal see as a selector we select a button inside of a header element so we
only have one header element we select the first matching button which in this case also is the only
button in this header and therefore this would give us access.
So that's one way of doing it and no way of course.
And I will not always show all alternatives.
No worries.
But here I do want to show ID.
So in no way would be to use Cary selector header and then for example last element child because if
we have a look at our header here we see the button is the last element child instead of the header.
So that would be a no way of selecting it.
The downside of using this just as before with using document body children one for the movie model
is that whenever we change something in the structure whenever we add something in the header some of
content here often a button some some other title or anything like that then this way of selecting it
here will not work anymore because it always selects the last element child and if we change that in
the HTML code our Javascript code will select a wrong element.
So therefore you should be careful with using this selection technique in places where the HTML content
might change where you as a developer might change it later.
So they offer.
I actually prefer this approach as I mentioned earlier and alternative would have been to add an I.D.
to this button but also to mix things up.
Let's use discrete selector.