Now I already mentioned the splice method that would help us insert elements between two elements,
so between sports and cooking for example.
Now actually the splice method is an extremely useful method that allows us to do all kinds of things
with arrays.
Now let's start with that use case of adding something between two elements.
For that, you use your array and then you call splice on it,
that by the way is one of the methods which is only available on real arrays, not on iterables, not on
array-like objects. That might be one reason why you convert an array-like or iterable object to a real
array with array.from because then on that real array, you can use splice.
Now how does splice work?
It takes at least two arguments there
but there also is another version
if you click on that down arrow here which takes more arguments.
So there are two different versions of that function.
Now in that version here, you specify a start index
so that's zero based
and then the amount of items you want to delete from that index on.
Now we don't want to delete anything here
right,
so maybe we start with index zero for item 1 and then we add zero because I don't want to delete anything,
instead and that's now where the second version comes into play,
we can add more arguments and as soon as you add another comma, this automatically jumps to that other
definition,
now you can add as many other arguments as you want which will be items that are inserted in the place
of these deleted values here.
So now here, let's maybe add good food to mix it up and then console log
hobbies to have a look at that, save that
and if you reload, you now see good food is actually the first element.
Well that happens because here I chose to start at index 0 which is the first element,
let's switch that to one to start at the second element. If we now reload, now good food is inserted between
sports and coding. So the way splice works is that you tell it the index where it should start looking
including that index and that's index one,
so start looking at the second element, then delete as many elements as I specify here, zero and then
insert this in place of that element where you start looking, so in the second elements place in this
case. Now the current second element is not deleted because we didn't specify it here,
so therefore it's just shifted after our newly added element here
and as I explained, you can add more than one hobby here,
you could also add coding here again or whatever you want.
So this is how splice works and how you can use it to insert elements inside of an array.
Of course since you can specify that you want to delete items, you can also use it for deleting.
So here we can also call splice again and then for example say that we want to start at index 0 and
remove one element and this should remove exactly the first element of our hobbies array.
So if we now output hobbies here and we save that, previously we got sports, good food, coding,
now if I reload, we get good food and coding so sports is deleted which makes sense because we tell splice
to start at the first element and remove exactly one element, so therefore remove exactly the first element
and then be done.
Of course you could remove more than one element,
you can remove as many elements as you want, if you just specify splice like this by the way here, you
will see that if I reload, the array is empty.
So splice without an item count will delete all items from that index on,
so for index 0, it will delete all items in the array, for index 1
it would spare the first item but delete all other items and therefore typically of course you do specify
a delete count
but it really depends on what you want to do,
if you want to clear an array you can use splice 0, if you want to delete everything up from a specific
element, you would take that index of that specific element and therefore now delete everything past
that element,
so that's how you can use splice as well.
Now splice will also return something,
it returns the removed elements so that they're not lost.
So if your app needs it, you can now do something with these elements that were removed from the hobbies
array. Now
also nice to know, splice also works with a negative index here,
you can specify a -1 or -2 and what it will then do is it will go to the end of the array
and look from the right,
so if I specify -1, it will basically go to the last element of this array and then delete
one element, so this will for example delete the last element in the array.
So if I reload here, we see sports and good food but coding is gone which was our last element because
we started at the last element and deleted exactly one.
If we start at the second last element and delete exactly one, well then we delete that second last element,
which in this case would be the good food element we added here.
So if I now reload, you'll see good food is gone. So negative indexes are allowed here for accessing
this to access this from the right.
This is not allowed for your normal index based data
accessing here on the arrays
by the way. There where you can access the first or second and so on element, if you specify -2 or
-1, you get undefined. So there, this does not work,
this is really exclusive to a couple of methods and the splice method is one of them.