So we saw three different styles and of course, you can also mix these styles,
you could have a procedural style where you also work with classes and where you have multiple functions.
You can have a functional style where you somehow also sneak in some classes, though
then technically it wouldn't be a pure functional style anymore.
Which style is the best though?
Well the best style is the style which best works for you,
that really is the truth. Now,
there will be people who strongly disagree because like a couple of other things in programming, this
really is something where you can have religious debates.
You can really discuss this and for a lot of people, it seems to be the most important thing in life,
not to me though.
You can write code, you can write apps with either style and you should find the style that best suits
your needs.
Now the more experienced you get as a developer, the more you will see that for a certain application
types, some styles tend to work better than other styles
and again you can find discussions about this on the Internet,
some of them are even kind of friendly, which will show different applications and different examples
for when to use which style. You'll also sometimes have programming languages which strongly favor one
style over another,
for example C# is a programming language which is heavily object oriented, Javascript on the other
hand is pretty versatile, there you can follow any style and therefore sometimes you also are forced
into a certain style and sometimes you are not.
It's important to be aware of all these styles
and nowadays at this point of time, the functional style is really having a strong comeback and is super
popular and it does have great advantages.
It's quite readable,
your code is really nicely organized,
it's very straightforward,
functions tend to be relatively small
if you're using this style correctly and it also produces highly reusable code. Object oriented programming
was extremely popular
a couple of years ago and it's still far from being not popular,
don't get me wrong
and it does have advantages.
It's also producing reusable code and it splits your code into logical pieces.
Now with the classes, you sometimes have a little bit of overhead which you don't really want though
and sometimes it's easier to split it when following the functional style. The procedural style is not
bad at all and great for some simpler scripts, the more complex your application gets, the more complex
it might get to work with this style though because you will naturally end up with at least using some
classes or some other functions to make it more readable at some point because if you only use this
style and you write your code step-by-step your code can get harder to organize and to reason
about
but again here also, you can mix in more functions and so on and therefore also write great applications
with the procedural style.
I hope that this overview was helpful and that it helps you make decisions about which styles you want
and most importantly, that it helps you understand styles being used in different projects or in different
frameworks
you work with in your future as a Javascript developer.