So now did we learned about these different specifications and we will learn what they do and how we
use them in detailed step by step.
No Worries Now did we learn that though it's also important to recognize that not all browsers to support
all these specifications and especially older browsers like Internet Explorer eleven.
While support even less.
Now let's have a look at browser support today.
For now the easiest way of finding the browser support is by simply googling for web components.
And then you can wizard web components dot org.
This page there and on this page if you scroll down you will find this browser support table here and
there you see all major browsers and how they're supporting the different web component specifications.
As a side note here you all the CDC as modules specification that is something which I didn't mention
on the slide.
It's not directly a part of the web components specification set this in the end is related to how we
can import javascript falls into jobs good files and we will find a solution for that later in the course
to the first three rows mentioned the parts you saw in my slides though the custom elements D H2 out
templates in the shadow Dom.
And as you can see right now browsers support is already very decent.
It's getting added to edge too.
At the point of time your view and of course this might already have changed.
And until then we can use a poly fill.
So third party package that basically gets the browser to support this and therefore we can use what
you learn in this cause in all major browsers if you want to get a more detailed list of which browser
supports which feature you can google for it can I use and then for example custom elements and you
could also use Chateau dom or H2 Mal templates there and you will then find the Can I use page here.
There you take that custom elements have one link
and on this page you can see browsers support for this feature and this looks a bit worse than the prior
page because there is more red on it but this is the more helpful page because you will see that for
example and hasn't implemented this yet again you can make it work with poli filters though but you
can see that for development you should really use a modern version of Firefox or Chrome and then later
you will learn how to make your web components work in more browsers.