Now we had a basic introduction to testing now, to the core types of tests but thus far we always tested
relatively simple code, synchronous code where nothing special was happening, where no side effects
were involved like a HttpRequest going out when a function is called.
Now things like that can cause problems when you're trying to run tests because your tests will also
trigger that code which might send a HttpRequest or which might do something which makes the test take
longer, might hit a backend API
or might towards results.
So now we'll have a look at what we can do to make our test simpler and focus on the core things and
really only test what matters to us.
So for this, again I prepared a starting project which you find attached to this lecture here so that
you can follow along and if you start the project by double clicking the index.html file, you'll see
a button there, if you click that button, you will eventually see an all uppercase text being printed
here.
Now responsible for that output is this code here,
I got a very simple setup here using webpack
and here I'm getting access to a button in my DOM,
I'm adding a listener to print the title. In print title, I call load title which is this function here,
in that function I reach out to fetch data which is provided in a different file also created by me.
There, I seem to get some data object of which I extract the title, I then transform this title to
be all uppercase and I return that
hence I can print it here.
Now if we have a look in this HTTP file, into this http.js file, here I'm using a third-party
package, axios,
so this is not written by me,
this is another third-party package and here in fetch data, I make a get request to a dummy API,
so this is a real API in the web, a real request is made here,
this API is not maintained by me,
it's just an API we can use for playing around, for testing and there, I get back a response object, axios
gives me such a response object which happens to have a couple of properties, like the status code for
example but also the data property which I'm extracting here.
This is essentially what I do,
now let's write some tests.
I already installed the jest package here and I also already configured my test command here to use
jest,
I also have a project where I use Node.js import export syntax because jest uses that by default
and just as with my other testing video where I gave you an introduction to testing with jest, there
I explained that jest uses that syntax, that setting it up to understand a different syntax would be
more complex and I still don't want to do that here because here, I want to focus on testing async code.
So we got everything set up to write some tests, so
let's do that. You learned in that last video that you can create a new file with .test.js at
the end to have Jest.js pick it up and execute it automatically.
So this will be the testing file for app.js and let's say we want a test print title.
Conveniently I'm already exporting it here at the bottom,
so what can we do?
Well in app-test.js, we can use the test function which is globally available when we run that
file with jest, there we give it a description, some text, yes some description of what should be tested
here and there I have should print an uppercase text for example. I have my arrow function then that
should execute or that contains the testing logic and in there we define our expectations.
Now we could expect uppercase text with the help of some regex magic or anything like that but here
because we'll change that anyways, I just want to expect this text because right now I will always get
the text for the API endpoint I'm hitting. So I expect and now I need to import that function which
I want to test,
so that will be print title, I am pulling that out of my exported object in the app.js file,
so I expect a print title, the result of that function call to be equal to my all uppercase text here,
this is my expectation.
We can now run that test by running npm test and this executes all test.js files and this actually
fails because it fails to execute add event listener null.
Now the reason for that actually is that app.js contains some code that will always run when this file
gets executed and it does get executed when I import from that file and it tries to access the DOM here
which just doesn't work in this environment
here, the real DOM is not loaded here,
so an easy way around that is to take that function and export it into a separate file,
maybe a util.js file,
this is also something we did in the last video already, export print title here
and what this allows us to do is it allows us to import something from that file only without executing
app.js and therefore without hitting the real DOM. So we can rename that testing file here to
utiltest.js and we import print title from ./util and in app.js since I removed
print title from there,
we also need to import print title by requiring it from the ./util file here
and now for that to work, I'll also have to move load title over to util.js because print title
depends on that,
so let's move load title into that file as well.
That means that fetch data also needs to move in there,
so from app.js let's grab the fetch data import and move that to the util.js file
and now with that setup, if we rerun npm test here, now it should be able to run our test here and it
does
but I get an error that essentially it expected a string but it received undefined
and now this already shows us a problem we have with asynchronous code testing.
Well actually in print title, I am indeed returning nothing,
so getting undefined as a result makes perfect sense
but even if I would return something, like for example in here, if I not only log the title but I also
returned the title here, if I do that and I rerun, I will still get that error,
I can already say that. The reason for that is that and that has nothing to do with testing, that's normal
Javascript behavior, return statements inside of callbacks or inside of promise
then calls are not executed or are executed but Javascript does not wait for them,
it does not return this value as a return value for this overall function,
instead this is the return value of that inner function here
and we're not testing this inner function,
we're testing that overall function.
So in our case here, one simple solution would be to test load title. Here we return something in the inner
function
and we also return something in the main function,
we returned the whole promise.
So chances are that we get back a promise here to which we then can listen and that might allow us to
expect something helpful.
So let's change something, let's export load title here so that we can test it,
let's go to utiltest.js and there, I will not expect something like that but I'll get my title
but instead, I will import load title here and I will execute load title and this gives us a promise
so I will add then here and in there, I know I'll get my title because that's exactly the way I use
it in print title right,
I have load title and then I get my title.
So now I have the exact same usage here in utiltest.js and now here I want to expect something, that
my title should be equal to that uppercase title I got here.
So we can grab that title here, copy it and that is what I expect as a value. Now if I rerun npm test,
it actually passes because now this test succeeds.
So this is better,
this is how we could test our asynchronous code but we still have a problem here,
the problem is we're still hitting our API.
So here in util.js, I'm using fetch data and if you remember, we're defining that in the HTTP
file, so here and there we're making a real API request.
We typically don't want to do that in testing, we might exceed certain API quotas if we do that, if we're
testing post requests,
we might even edit something on the API which we certainly don't want to do as part of testing,
certainly not with our production API at least.
So hitting the API is typically not something we want to do,
there also are other reasons against it,
what would we achieve by really making that HttpRequest? Do you want to test if your API works correctly?
If you're building that API, you should do these tests during the API development,
not when working on your frontend,
these two should be separated,
so that is certainly not something you want to test.
If the API works or not is not something you test in your frontend code, you might test error fallbacks
or anything like that but not if the API works correctly.
You also don't want to test if the get method exposed by axios works correctly.
That is a method provided by a third-party package and we rely on that package doing its job,
so we also don't test third-party package functionalities.
We want to test our own code and our own code here for example is that we extract data and that here,
that we transform this to uppercase and that we pull out the title.