Now the format of the data is really important,
you exchange data between your client side and the server side in a certain format and technically,
there are no restrictions,
you can send plain text, you can send HTML markup, you can send XML markup, you can send csv
files or as you typically do,
you use this data format which is called JSON.
JSON looks like this, if you click on response, you'll see the raw response
and JSON stands for Javascript Object Notation.
Indeed as you can tell, this does looks a lot like Javascript objects in an array and JSON is derived
from Javascript data types, from arrays and objects in Javascript to be precise,
it's almost the same but there are a couple of differences. In JSON
you can only store data, you can't have methods in there and you can't send functions to a server.
In addition, your property names have to be wrapped between double quotes,
it must be double quotes and it has to be wrapped,
so userId without quotes would not be allowed.
It also would not be allowed with single quotes,
you need to double quotes. Now as values,
you can use numbers, booleans, strings, other objects or arrays, that's supported,
null is also allowed and then, this is basically it.
This is how the data looks like, you can also have nested objects and nested arrays,
this is all allowed and this is how the data is transferred between the two ends.
So here we received data in this JSON format,
it would now be nice to parse that from the response so that we can actually output it on the page at
a later point of time. Now for that
let's see, how can we get to the response here when we send a request?
We have to wait for the load event which is fired automatically once the data is loaded,
so once the request completed and we do so by setting up an event listener basically, however xhr does
not always support an event listener,
older browsers don't support that,
I think Internet Explorer does not support it at all and therefore the more common way of listening
to that is to assign a function to the event handler, to xhr.onLoad.
To this property, you assign a function and you saw this syntax in the events module where I showed you
that this is an alternative to adding event listeners, here we should use that because add event listener
is not broadly supported
and here we can connect a function, written in any syntax you want,
here I'm using the function expression syntax, that handles the incoming response.
Now we don't receive the response as an argument here however, instead we can extract it on the
xhr.response
key.
Now let's console log xhr.response here and see if that works. If we tweak the code like this and we
then reload here, this looks pretty good,
was very fast because it's a fast API but this looks pretty decent to me,
this is the output
JSON data which was fetched from the server and it's important.
This is not a native Javascript array with which we could work,
it's JSON data.
If you would try to store that list of posts from
xhr.response, you would not be able to for example push a new element there. If you tried to do that and
you reload,
you'll see you get an error because
xhr.response gives you JSON data and not an array you can use like that. In order to use it,
you have to convert the JSON data to Javascript types, to Javascript arrays and objects and so on and
Javascript has a built-in helper that helps you with that,
it has a built-in JSON constructor function or class which has a couple of static helper methods, parse
and stringify, stringify helps you convert Javascript code or Javascript objects and arrays
to JSON data and parse helps to convert JSON data back to Javascript.
So here we can parse the xhr.response
and now if we console log list of posts, we should have a Javascript array with which we could work.
So if we now save that and we reload, this looks better, this now really is a Javascript array and you
see for example the double quotes around the property names are gone,
this is now really Javascript data with which we can work. Now important,
you can manually parse it like this and I wanted to show you this
JSON helper object,
actually there is a little convenience built into the XMLHttpRequest object.
If you set xhr.response type here to JSON and it has to be exactly this term,
then this will automatically be parsed for you,
so then if you would duplicate this line, you could store the response without manually parsing it because
it will be parsed behind the scenes for you
if you add this extra configuration. So now with this code if I reload, we'll have the same result as with
the manual parsing.
It's important to be aware of that
JSON parse helper functionality though because often you will need that, not always
you can preconfigure it like this.
So now we got this list of posts, outputting it in the console is nice,
how can we output it in the index.html file?
Well there we get the unordered list with a class of posts and there I want to output and I get this
template which holds a list item which I want to use for outputting it.
Now to do that, we can add a new constant here, list element for example and get access to it with document
query selector and then select by the posts class because we'll only have one element with that class
on the page and get access to our template here and we might want to add an ID to that,
we could also select it by just a template tag
but here I'll give it an ID of single post,
that's totally up to you though
and now we can select this template, so post template with document get element by ID, single post and
now we want to add a couple of posts or this list of posts to our unordered list or maybe turn all
these posts here,
all these posts into list elements and to do that, we can loop through our list of posts,
so for and now we'll have a problem,
can we loop for our list of posts here?
We can't because they're only available here inside of this anonymous function.
This is when the response is there,
this happens asynchronously and as you learned, Javascript will not block code execution, it will continue
with these lines even though the response might not be there yet and therefore actually, we should do
our looping logic here inside of this function because that's the only place where we have the guarantee
that the posts are available, hence I will now also move that up there,
my two selections and now loop through my posts with const post of list of posts here inside of that
anonymous function.
Now the goal is to replicate the template for every post and add it to the list element here.
For that, we can get access to our post element with document import node and then we want to import the
postTemplate.content and pass through here to make a deep clone and on this post element,
I now want to select the h2 tag which we have in there,
we also have a paragraph in there thereafter
and then here, set the text content equal to post.
and now if we have a look, we see that every post which we fetched has a title property and then a body
property with some dummy text.
So here I want to set this equal to title and maybe to uppercase to convert it all to uppercase characters
and also post el query selector for the paragraph and there, I want to set text content equal to
post.body,
just like that.
Thereafter we can reach out to the list element and then append our post element like this. If we do
that and we post this, let's reload and see whether it works and that looks quite good,
we rendered a bunch of posts here in our list of posts, quite a lot of them
but that's OK. So this is now how we can also utilize the data we fetched and output it, not just in Javascript
but also on the screen.