With that let's move on to the reflect API,
now what is the reflect API all about?
It is totally not related to iterators and generators and symbols,
it is related to objects though. It is an API that allows us to control objects, to do things with Javascript
objects and in the end it's just an object itself,
reflect is an object in Javascript which groups, with a bunch of static methods on this class
so to say, which groups a lot of functionalities that help us work with objects.
It has standardized and grouped together methods and the reflect API, just like all these features, can be
used to control how our code is used, how our code behaves and so on.
Now let's see an example and let's see what the reflect API offers us. For this here, in our dummy app.js
file, I'll go down a bit further
and here I want to start working with the reflect API.
So let's say we have a new object here, to mix things up, I'll name
this object not person and so on, I'll just name it
course. Now a course might have a title, Javascript - The Complete Guide.
Now it's a very simple object of course and we worked with objects so much, shouldn't need much explanation.
Now we got this reflect API which we can access on this global reflect object by adding a dot thereafter
because this has a bunch of static methods we can use,
for example it has a define property method,
it has a delete property method,
it has a getPrototypeOf method and it has a setPrototypeOf method and
for example we can use setPrototypeOf to set the prototype of our course object to an object where
I have a to string method, my own to string method where I return this.title
and the consequence of that would be that if I now console log course to string here, we no longer
use the default to string method
but my own one here and hence if I save that and reload, I print the course title in this case. So the
reflect API helps us work with objects, with set prototype of
we can set the prototype of an object, with define property we could add a new property and not just
like this but also with such an object descriptor, this extra argument you might remember where we can
set whether this is writable,
so whether we can write to this property or if it's locked and so on,
I covered this earlier in a lecture where I talk about object descriptors.
So in the end, the takeaway is that the reflect API gives us a bunch of methods that help us change objects,
work with objects on a meta level because what we do here is typically something we do to prepare our
object to be consumed by some other part in our code.
Again, consider that you are the author of a third-party library and you expose certain objects as part
of this library and you want to make sure that certain properties can't be changed by the developers
using your library,
that could be one scenario.
Well then you can use the reflect API to for example set a property and set it to be non-writable.
The obvious question that just could arise at this point is why would we use reflect for this? If we
used a global object, object with a capital O,
we also have a setPrototypeOf method,
we also have a define property method and it generally works the same way as the reflect API methods.
So why do we have the reflect API
if we can already do these things with the existing object API? The reflect API is newer,
it was added recently with ES6 to Javascript, the object API is way older.
Now that alone of course is no reason for using it,
instead the reflect API has two advantages over the object API -
for one there are subtle differences regarding the behavior of some methods,
for example if a method fails to do its job, on the object API it might return undefined or fail silently,
on the reflect
API you might get a better error or it just returns True or False for a given method to tell you if
something works or not and attached you find a link with a comparison of the object API and the reflect
API that allows you to understand these subtle differences.
Additionally, the reflect API bundles all features that you need to work with objects,
for example it also has a delete property method which we don't find on the object API, there
this is not a thing,
if I try to call delete property here on course and pass in the title with the object API, then you
will see that if I print my course down there and I reload,
this does not work because object delete property is not a function.
The object API has no delete property, instead
previously in older Javascript, if you wanted to delete a property in an object, you would have to use
the delete keyword and then target the property you want to get rid of.
Now you can do that but it's a bit of a strange code, having this special operator here,
I think it's a bit cleaner to have a method you can call on an object if you want to get rid of a property
because on the other hand we also do have a method for defining a property, so why not have one for deleting
it?
Well that's for example one thing the reflect API
added, there you now have a proper delete property method and that simply is cleaner than using this
delete operator.
Here you can pass the object where you want to delete a property and then the property name and then
this will return true or false depending on whether it is operation succeeded or not.
So this is simply cleaner and more straightforward than using this delete
operator, technically is of course doing the same but that's why we have the reflect API,
it's there to group all the methods you need to configure your objects, to work with your objects and
you don't have to fall back to different approaches where some things are defined on object and other
things are not defined there and you suddenly need a special operator.
Now the reflect API gives you everything you need to work with objects all bundled in this global reflect
object here and that's basically the idea behind the reflect API.
Whenever you need to do such meta work on your objects - delete a property, define a new one, change the
prototype after the object has been created, then you should consider using the reflect API over the
other scattered methods or operators you might be able to use for that,
that's the primary reason for the existence of the reflect API.