So let's come back to that anonymous function thing. Here,
I created an anonymous function,
we could have assigned a name as you saw,
it doesn't matter here and I'll come back to what a tiny difference is in a second but we can also
create it like this because we don't really need the name here.
Now that's one place where you could use anonymous functions because you store them in a variable and
then the name of the variable is the name by which you call and by which you reference the function
as we're doing it down there when we add the event listener,
so that's one thing but you can also use anonymous functions in places where you don't even store them
in variables
and one place would exactly be a scenario like this one where you add an event listener. You might add
an event listener here and you can do so by defining an anonymous function in place here where you
need it.
Now important,
this is basically the same as if you define it before and store it in some variable and then just reference
the variable here.
This will not immediately execute the function,
why would it,
there are no parentheses after it, which by the way could write, this is valid Javascript syntax.
This would now immediately execute the anonymous function but this is not what we do here, this is not what
we need here,
instead this just creates a function in place and kind of passes the reference of this anonymous on the
fly created function to add event listener.
Now why would we do that?
Because maybe, we have no other place in our entire code where we ever need that function again.
Indeed that's actually the case for start here,
I can comment this out,
I will only call it when I click this button here.
So I will just move my code which I had in there into this anonymous function and I'm fine.
There is nothing wrong with having a separate function and as you learned in the behind the scenes
module, there might even be some memory leak considerations you want to take into account
but if you know you only add an event listener once here, then this doesn't really matter,
so there isn't a way of creating a memory leak here and then it just saves us some code
and if someone else reads your code, he or she doesn't have to find that function you're referencing
here, so if I read that for example, I have to look where the start function is, there it is.
So I don't have to do that if you use an anonymous function,
instead everything is defined in place here
and by just looking at this line, I fully understand what's going to happen when this button is clicked.
So this is a prominent scenario for using an anonymous function, event listeners or any use cases where
you pass a function, a reference to a function to another function, which is effectively what we're
doing here,
right?
We're passing a reference to this anonymous function or before to the start function to this add event
listener function.
So this function actually takes a function as an argument if you think about it like this, something
we'll also have a closer look at in this module and therefore this is a great scenario for using such an anonymous
function
if you never need that same function in any other place in your code.
So if I save that and we reload, you will see that works just fine,
so I can click this button because my event listener was added with this anonymous function. So why might
you still assign a name to this anonymous function though?
Because maybe that function throws an error. Let's say here,
I'm also trying to log age which is a variable which just doesn't exist, neither locally in that anonymous
function because of course anonymous functions, just like other functions, have their own local scope.
So neither there nor globally, nor in any other file,
so age here doesn't work.
Side note, name would work because there's a default name global variable available in your script, made
available by the browser,
so don't use name here but age will not be available and therefore if I reload here and I click the
button, I get an error.
Now what you'll see is if you want to find that error, of course it gives us the line number, so
that helps us
but what if we don't see here is the name of the function where this problem occurred.
Now since we have the line number, that might not matter but if you have a huge script and maybe you're
even running some automatically optimized version here in the browser, where the line number which is
shown here might not meet the line number you have in your code, then it would be nice to see the function
name here and we don't.
Now that's different
if we use a function defined in the old school style and old school is kind of a dangerous word because
it's perfectly fine to use that
but if I would define my function like this,
so not storing it in a constant or a variable but just declaring it like this
and I had the same code in here and I would then temporarily replace this anonymous function with that,
then you will see if we do this and we therefore encounter the same error,
it actually gives us a hint at the function name here,
it mentions that this is the start function. On the other hand when using an anonymous function here,
so if I revert all of that, if I use that anonymous function as we did before and we reload and we
reproduce this error, here it says anonymous because that's what it is, an anonymous function.
Now we can mitigate this by giving this a name, start game or whatever you want.
You can't call this function by that name as you learned, it's not declared and managed globally by Javascript
but that name is used for debugging, for throwing errors by the browser.
So if I now reload this and I produce this, you see start game here.
So that's a reason why you might want to give your anonymous functions a name,
you don't have to, obviously with the line number we would have found the problematic line as well but
it is worth a thought and this is why you might still want to assign names to your anonymous functions,
here I don't really need it because I don't plan on adding this error here
so I'm fine like this but that's just a tiny additional thing you should know about anonymous functions.