And that's it for libraries. As I mentioned,
there are thousands of libraries and therefore it's impossible to go through all of them. As you grow
as a developer, as you work with Javascript day-to-day,
you'll encounter many libraries.
It turns out you often just work with the same five or six popular ones
but if you have a specific problem which you want to solve, then as I explained, using Google really is
the way to read more about the problem and in that process, you'll often stumble across libraries which
you might want to have a look at
with the help of Github to find out how they work, if they're actively maintained, if they're popular
and so on and that's therefore then it. This is it for this module, this hopefully helps you use libraries
and improve your projects and it allows you to focus on your core business logic and not reinvent the
wheel over and over again.