So this is it for IndexedDB and for browser storage in general.
Now you can dive deeper into all of these methods,
I just wanted to introduce you to these concepts and give you an overview. Browser storage can be really
useful for some pieces of data, you should just always be aware that users can view and edit it, so it's
not secure at all
and then of course users can also delete it or the browser might delete it if it's running out of space.
Therefore this is great for data that can be used to enhance the user experience,
if you are building a rich client side application that needs to manage quite a lot of data, then having
something like IndexedDB is really great but it does not replace a server side database and storing
data on a server.