So enough of the positioning and sizing and scrolling,
let's come back to working with content and there, one thing we did a couple of times throughout this course
because we had no better way was that when we wanted to set up some HTML code that should be rendered
or some content, we always did this here in our scripts.
Now in this example here or in this project here, I actually have no HTML code in my script but it
would be easy to add some to the tooltip for example, you could say that when we create the tooltip here,
we don't just set some text content but we set some innerHTML here which for example includes
a h2 tag where we say more info and then below that, a paragraph where we output the actual text here
with string interpolation like this and if we do so and now reload and I click on more info, we
get this kind of tooltip here.
Now of course you could adjust the styling but the core idea is here that now I have this HTML code
in the script and this is not ideal because you might be working in a team where other people are responsible
for the markup and so on or you're not working in such a team but you don't want to have all that
HTML code in your Javascript code.
Now obviously, this is a very simple HTML code right
but if you had longer HTML code, lots of HTML code in there, this could get more and more cumbersome
and thankfully the web has a solution for this.
We can use a special HTML tag in our HTML code to kind of setup such to be used
HTML code which we don't want to render right from the start but which we want to eventually use
from inside our Javascript code and for this we can use a special tag, the template tag here. Just
add it in your HTML code, in your body and the special thing about the template tag is that its content
by default is not rendered but it's part of the DOM,
so you can query it and use it and then use it in your Javascript code but it's not getting rendered
by default at the beginning.
We can add an ID to the template, we can for example assign tooltip here and then move this HTML
code from our Javascript file into this template.
Now this string interpolation will not work here,
so for now I'll just have my empty paragraph here,
we'll have to insert content there from Javascript in a second.
So now we've got the HTML code in the HTML file which makes sense. Now in Javascript we can use
such a template of course, for that here, we can get access to our tooltip template with document get
element by ID and then looking for the ID we assigned to the template and now we get access to
this template element. Now to utilize this template, we can create a new constant here, tooltip body for
example and there we can use document import node to which we then pass tooltipTemplate.content
and this in the end gives us the content of our template tag,
so the h2 tag and the paragraph we set up there and essentially creates a new node based on that,
that's what this line does.
We should set up true here so that we do a deep import which means we really import everything in the
content of the template which is exactly what we want
and now we got that body available which we can add to our tooltip element.
So here we can call append and append the tooltip body, only thing we should do before we do that is of
course we should adjust the paragraph in there and insert our text and we can do that with tooltip body
query selector for a paragraph, first matching paragraph because we only got one and then there,
set text content equal to this.text.
Now of course this takes up more lines of code than the approach before did
but this simply moved the HTML code out of the script which is especially useful for longer snippets
of HTML code because now you can manage all your HTML code here in the HTML file and then
just import it into app.js, adjust it, tweak it and configure it, maybe insert your dynamic data and then
use that and that's the advantage of this approach.
So with that if we save that and we reload, we get the same result as before but now it's simply managed
in a more elegant way, which is much better and actually how we should do this since this helps us split
our HTML logic, our HTML code from our Javascript code which can help us work in teams and keep
our Javascript code easier to manage.
Last but not least, it's also more convenient to write HTML code in an HTML file in an editor
like this one than in Javascript in a string because we get better autocompletion and so on in an HTML
file than we do in the Javascript string.