So time for another class,
let's add a cart or a shopping cart
class here, up to you how you want to name it and in there
I want to have an items field which initially is empty
and I also want to have a render method here which renders something to the screen and that something
should simply be let's say the total amount and a button that allows us to order the items.
You could of course also go more fancy than that and also render all items
but to keep this module short or relatively short, I'll just render the total.
So in here, I'll create my cart element with document create element
and here I'll go for let's say a section element, section tag and then set cart el innerHTML equal to
some HTML code, again written across multiple lines to make it easier to read, where I want to have
a h2 tag which will output the total amount, then I want to output a dollar sign here so we have to
escape it with a backslash and then we can interpolate the total amount.
For now I'll just output zero here,
this will soon refer to something dynamic and then also a button where we could say order
now, like that. Now I'l also assign a class here to get some proper styling with a class name and set it equal
to cart,
that's another style you find in app.css and that should be a semicolon and of course later I'll also
add an event listener here but for the moment, I'll just return cart el here in the render method so that
wherever we create that shopping cart, we can append it to the DOM.
Now where is that place where I want to use the shopping cart though? Well that should probably be a
new class which kind of combines product list in cart because the cart item, the cart HTML content
is certainly not part of the product list,
so rendering it here would be incorrect but that is the thing which we rendered to the screen initially.
So we probably add a new class which you could name app or shop or page or whatever you want to name
it,
I'll name it shop and in there, I'll now also add a render method
and here I want to combine cart and product list.
So now in the end, I'll grab this code here, create my product list in the render method and also create
my cart here with new shopping cart and then call cart.render here. Now
product list right now always renders itself into that app place here of index.html, into that
div here, we now need to change that and kind of cut the render hook from the render method of product
list and move that into shop which is now the new place where we render everything to the screen
and now we need to make sure that instead the render method in product list returns that prod list, so
also cut this code and instead return prod list here just as we do it in the other classes and
then here in the shop component, we just need to store these returned elements. So here we got the cart
element and here, we got the prod list element
and then here in render hook, we append the cart and thereafter, we append the prod list element and here
of course the cart element.
Now we just have to create our shop here with new shop below all these class definitions and then call
shop render and this will then render the individual parts and the result should be that if we save
that and reload, indeed we now have that cart area here at the top.
Now for the moment of course nothing changes when I click Add to Cart though or we only see that output
but that does not change the number here and it can't because we haven't added any logic to do so.
So that's the next step
we should do and that will also force us to make sure that we can communicate between our different
classes,
something we haven't really done before.