So let's get started with Express.js now that we installed it and to get started in the app.js
file
we simply start by importing it with that Node.js import syntax where we require Express and then
store the imported package or the content of the package, the objects and functions exposed by the package
in this constant here which you can of course name however you want.
Now Express or what you actually get in there is is a function,
so what you can actually do here is you can simply create an app by calling Express like that, like a
function.
This gives you such an app object which in the end is an object with a lot of features and functions provided
by Express, so you set up Express by calling it like this and then it gives you access to all its cool
features on this app object
you could say and one thing you can do on this app object is you can call listen again
and this of course might look familiar because we called listen on our pure Node implementation as well
on the server. Now Express and the app object therefore sets up the server for us behind the scenes
and that's really important,
Express is simply a Node.js
framework, it does kind of the same thing we did here,
it calls create server for us but it does so behind the scenes and then exposes this server on this
app object together with a couple of other functionalities.
So with that alone, we would have a running Node.js server powered by Node and Express but this alone
wouldn't do much.
Now what we also typically want to do is we want to act on certain incoming requests and for that, it's
important to understand how Express.js works.
It's a middleware-driven framework,
now that sounds very fancy, what does it mean?
It means that in the end Express is all about funneling the incoming request through a bunch of different
functions which all received the request and all can do something with it
and each function can either stop the request and send back a response, at which point the request will
not reach any other function thereafter,
any other middleware or a function forwards the request to the next function, to the next middleware
in line. So a middleware is really just a function that gets the request and then can do something with
it.
Now let me show you what I mean,
we can register such a middleware by using the user method on the app object and the use method takes
a function as an argument.
This is a function which Express will execute for us and it is a function which will get the request
object and the response object and also an additional next thing, a next argument to which I'll come
back in a second.
Now what we got here is basically the same request or a similar request as we got it here in the function
we passed to create server but enriched with some extra functionality, the same for the response. We get
this response object so that we can work on the response we want to send back and also that when we're
done, we can send back a response.
So what we could do here is for example we could set a header on the response, let's say we want to set
the content type and we can do that in the same way we did it before in the pure Node.js example and
we set this to text.html.
Now that might be all we want to do in this middleware for whatever reason, then we can add a new middleware
simply thereafter and the order does matter,
this will execute first, then the request will reach this middleware,
so here we again pass in a function where we get the request, the response and this next thing and in
here we could then decide that we're done setting up the response and getting data out of the request
maybe and we want to send the response to the client,
we can do this with a special send method which is new which was added by Express.js which does not
exist in pure Node.js
and there we could send our h1 tag where we say hello world,
just like this for example to have a very simple response.
So we'll send back this string as our response data,
we set the header on the response before and this will be carried over into this function,
so the different middlewares all work with the same request and the same response object
so to say, so what you set up here on the response also is applied to this response
but then here I send the response.
Now with that we get two middleware
so now the only missing piece is we need to tell Express.js that from this middleware, we don't want
to stop the request,
we also don't want to send a response yet,
instead we want to forward the request after working on its response to the next middleware in line
and that's what we do with this next argument.
This actually is a function we can execute like this and all next
does is it tells Express.js that we're not done yet,
that instead it should move on to the next middleware in line and call that with the request, with
the response
and also again with next which we don't call in the second middleware though because we're done with
the response and the request here. We send back a response so we don't want to handle the request in
any other middleware thereafter because we already send the response,
what else would we do with the request,
right and
that would be a very basic setup which should render this to the screen.
So if we now save this and we execute app.js again, you'll see again we've got an ongoing process which
we can quit with control c but which of course shouldn't do as long as you're working with that server,
as long as the server should be up and running
and now if we go back to our page and we reload this page, we see Hello World
and if we inspect our request, we see on the response headers we have the content type.
You also see there are more headers than before, simply because Express.js also adds a bunch of default
headers anyway, so it automatically adds a bunch of headers which we don't have to add on our own.
So here we also see that Express.js is doing a little bit of extra work besides this basic node work
we did manually before. And now we already have a bit of a more convenient way of handling incoming requests
and sending back responses but we're not extracting any data at this point,
so that's something we might also want to do and
turns out this is also relatively easy with Express.js