OK.
So we created our first web component and it is working.
But obviously this component is not doing anything useful here.
Well it's time to now change that.
The core idea behind our own web components behind our custom elements is in the end that we attach
our existing age to male elements like divs and buttons and paragraphs to build more powerful widgets
composed of these different elements.
And by the way D already built in video element which is a normal age aged female tag is kind of like
a web component.
We could build on our own.
It's one age gym all tech.
But behind the scenes if we had a video being loaded here you would see that this made up of a couple
of buttons like to play buttons on and that is just what we want to build here on our own.
So since we want to render a tooltip there what would make sense is that we for example have a paragraph
with some text or let's actually say in the end we want to use that tooltip inside of a paragraph we
might have like web components are awesome.
This could be our text and our tool tip here should maybe be spanning dad web components word here so
that later when we hover over web components or over some icon which should be inserted next to it that
we then automatically see a tooltip with some text we also define not we're not there yet but we can
get there.
Let's start by actually adding a button or an icon after the text B pass here so that we can actually
see that for that.
I'll go back to the tooltip and instead of logging something to the console here we can instead use
this keyword which is built into javascript to access the the Web component object.
So the HD him El element object which will be created for us when the browser detects this tag being
used.
And here we can use all the features we can use on normal HD Himmel elements.
When we select them in javascript to for example we can append a child node so we can append a never
H to male element inside of our custom element.
And that sounds promising because there I actually want you append my own I can let's say my own I can
above which we later can hover.
And for that I can simply call document create element here and I will create a span here a span element
and that of course is not a custom Web component it is an element built into the browser because in
the end all your components your building will be made up of these core primitives of these built in
elements you just compose them differently style them differently and add your own event listeners your
own logic to do something when a certain button gets clicked and so on.
So all this composition all this logic will in the end make up your own element.
So here I'm creating a span and I will store that in New content.
So basically a variable which I'll never change.
This is also a built in jobs good feature using next gen javascript syntax which chrome the latest version
of it natively supports and all named is constant tooltip I can the name is up to you and on that tooltip
I can all then set the text content equal to a whitespace so I'll blank here and then parentheses and
let's say a question mark inside of it.
And you could theoretically all to create an image or element and render your own image.
Here I'll just go with text.
I want to add this.
This span here with this text content I want to add this now in my age html element and therefore here
I will call append child and I will append my tooltip.
I can hear with that if I now safe dead and I reload this page in the browser I actually get an error
here.
Now this is a bit of a cryptic error message in the end.
The problem we have here is the place where we try to append a child the constructor is the wrong place
for it.
Now to find the right place we need to learn how the browser or JavaScript to JavaScript engine actually
goes about creating our own custom elements because it follows a specific lifecycle for that.