Of course it's nice that we're able to get data but often we also want to send data,
for example here we have our form and when I click add here, right now the form gets submitted and hence
the page gets reload because the browser does its default thing and sends a request automatically to
some server, the same server where the HTML page is hosted on
and that's not the behavior I want. I want to send a request to this JSONPlaceholder page because
that if we click on guide does not just support getting resources or listing all resources,
it also allows us to create a resource by sending a post request and therefore that's what I want to
do here.
Now for that, we should restructure our code here a little bit,
we could of course also improve it a lot by for example using object oriented code,
I'll just tweak it a little bit by wrapping this HttpRequest sending logic into a separate reusable
function.
I'll create a function, sendHttpRequest for example which wants a method and a URL let's say
for now and in there, we have all that code, so let's cut it and move it in there and now replace get here
with methods,
so with the value we receive here and the URL here with the URL parameter, so that this is flexible.
Response type will always be JSON here so I don't need to tweak that or don't need to make that flexible
here at this point
and now in onLoad, I also don't want to have the logic, what I do with the response hardcoded in there,
instead how about promisifying all of that?
That would be easy,
we can create a promise here with new promise as you learned it, pass that function to the promise constructor
where we get resolve and reject as you learned it and then actually move all that code here into this
constructor or into this function we pass to the constructor
and now here when we're done, I want to call resolve and simply forward xhr.response because that's
our response data.
Thereafter, we can return the promise here and now below that, we can call sendHttpRequest to have
a reusable function, we'll have to remove that code from onLoad of course. We'll do that in a second,
first of all let's start by adding a new function, fetch posts and in there I will send my HttpRequest,
a get request to this URL which I cut and then with the response data in this function which I
pass to my then method and we could use async await instead of course, I'll use that code which I had
in onLoad before and move that into my then block here.
Now again, the alternative would be to use async await, add async in front of the function,
then we would get our response data here by awaiting for the response of sendHttpRequest, we would
remove then and instead add a semicolon and remove that extra function here which we now don't need
anymore, remove this closing parentheses here as well and now we would have this code.
So that is how we can do it with async await, await for this response, response data here and now we
can use response data here instead. So store that in list of posts, go through all the list of posts and
if we then call fetch posts here, we should still be able to fetch the post whenever we reload our
page,
yes seems to work.