This is it for this practice module.
We worked a bit more with classes, with this object oriented approach.
Hopefully again, that was a useful practice for getting a feeling regarding how you think about object
oriented programming and how you structure your app there.
We worked a bit with the DOM, we moved elements around, we worked with event listeners.
I also showed you this new callback pattern,
we learned about that before but now you saw it in practice where we passed functions to other instances
and to other functions so that from inside there, they could be called upon certain events
and with that we build this little application where we can move items around and this application will
be important, we'll also use it in the next course module
and with that finished, you're well-prepared for this module and you hopefully also got some additional
practice with classes and object oriented programming.