So thus far we haven't progressed too much into our game,
so let's work on that.
I'll get rid of that old code up there, of the commented out code, so that we just have our event listener
and so on and now in between, we need a couple of other functions which we can kick off when our game started.
When the game started,
we want to let the user choose whether he wants to use rock, paper or scissors,
that's the game, right? Now
for that, we can add a new function and I'll use that approach where I store it in a constant, again totally
optional,
though for now I would recommend that you also use that because we'll tweak this a little bit in a second.
So I'll create a constant and name it get player choice because this effectively is now my function name,
so it should also be named like you would name functions and I'll store an anonymous function in there.
Now get player choice should show a prompt to the user asking for rock, paper or scissors.
So we can get a selection stored in a constant by using the prompt function which is built into Javascript
and ask for rock, paper or scissors
and provide a default value of an empty string.
So now that will open a prompt to the user when we call that function and store the result in selection.
Now obviously, the user could enter anything in there,
so I want to check if selection is not equal to rock and selection also is not equal to paper and selection
also is not equal to scissors.
If that's the case and we can structure this across multiple lines and avoid typos here,
so if we add this if check and we make it into this if block here, I know that something invalid was
entered because the user obviously neither entered rock nor paper nor scissors.
So in that case, I want to let the user know that he or she made an invalid choice and that we'll use
some default for him or her.
Of course we could let the user choose again but I want to use a default in that case,
we chose rock for you, let's say rock is our default here.
Now a little adjustment right away,
I want to work with some constants, some global constants here so that when I use rock, paper and scissors
as words in my if statements, I can't introduce typos,
that's a pattern I showed you in the control structures module.
So here I just will introduce some global constants, selection rock which is rock
or maybe just rock actually, we can shorten this and duplicate this
and then also here have paper
and also here have scissors and the advantage of this is that
now here I can use rock, here I can use paper
and here I can use scissors and I can't mistype and we can even use that here in our template literal
and ask for rock,
now of course the user has to enter this all in capital cases,
paper or scissors. Now to make sure that we don't dismiss a choice as invalid just because the user may
be entered rock instead of ROCK,
we can actually also convert the entire string the user entered to all capital case and we can do so by
calling to uppercase on the return value of prompt. Now the return value of prompt is a string as you
learned and as you learned, objects can have functions, can have methods.
Now you also learned that strings are primitive values and not really objects but in that same video
where you learned this, I mentioned that you can still access certain properties and functions on these
primitive values and they're kind of temporarily used as objects you could say. It's a bit more complex,
Javascript does this behind the scenes for us so we can use them like objects but they're not really
objects,
that's how you can think about it.
So a string is a primitive value but it still has this to uppercase method which it exposes to us. So
it exposes this method to us and what this method does is it returns a new string where all characters
have been converted to uppercase characters.
So what we store in selection will be a string with only uppercase characters and then we can use
that here in that if check. So in here, we now check for a valid selection and if selection is invalid, we
let the user know that we chose rock for him or her,
so actually we can use a template literal here as well and output rock here as well, maybe even create
a new constant, default user choice and set this equal to rock,
so that here I refer to that and if we ever would want to change that default choice, we only have to
do it up here and with that, we validated this,
of course I now want to return here.
So here I can return rock or to be precise, default user choice,
otherwise if we don't make it in here, I want to return selection which should be rock, paper or scissors.
So now here in this anonymous function, we can call get player choice and this will return us whatever
the user chose or that default selection and hence I'll store this in a new constant named player
selection which is now a local constant of this anonymous function.
So for now let's just log this here and see whether it works, so let's log the player selection here
and have a look at that.
If we save this and we go back and we reload this page here, click on start game and we get this prompt and
if I enter something here and click ok, I get invalid choice,
we chose rock for you and hence rock is being printed here.
If we reload this and I click again and I enter rock here, I get rock and just to prove that also
something else works, if I enter paper here, I get paper
so that works.
Now before we continue, I also want to make sure that once we started a game, we can't start another game.
For this, I'll add a global variable, game is running and set this to false initially but set it to true
in this anonymous function,
game is running, set it to true but also here before I set it to true, check if game is running and if
the game is running and we don't need to add equal equal true here because there already is a boolean
in game is running or something which can be coerced to a boolean value but it already is a boolean.
So we'll make it in here if game is running is true and then I just want to return so that when we
click the button again and again, we don't start new games.
Of course right now we're not doing too much in our game though, so that's something we'll have to change
but we'll get there.
So we started the game, we allowed the user to make a selection, the next step of course is that the computer
also is able to make a selection. Before we do that
however, let's see how else we can create functions because it turns out there is yet another way of
creating a function.