Hello this is Kirill from for ex-beau dot com.
And welcome back to the course and for X-Trace in today's tutorial we will discuss in great detail the
topic of short selling.
Many traders especially beginners on the market find short selling rather confusing and that is why
I will specifically try to walk in your shoes today and be as explicit as I can when talking about short
selling.
So let's jump straight into it as we've already established there are two types of traders on the market
bulls traders who invest into the grove 4 x currency and bears who invest into the decline of a 4 x
currency.
So today we're talking about short selling and that is applicable to bears.
Let's look at our.
Euro used dollar example in more detail.
So here's a chart.
And how would a bearish type of trader profit from this downward trend.
Well there's a trend and bearish trader would enter somewhere over there where the where we see the
X on the top left.
He would sell at about one point three one for all.
And there's a recall that means that every one euro is worth 1.3 one for all U.S. dollars.
And then he would cause a transaction at about 1.2 4 8 0 meaning that in that point in time every euro
is worth only one point 2 4 8 0 0 U.S. dollars.
So as we did previously Let's simplify this example by talking about apples.
And now let's look at the mechanics of how all this comes together.
Well first of all we don't have apples.
We know that on our account we have American dollars but we don't have apples.
How can we sell something that we don't have.
So how how does that work.
Well this is why this transaction is called not just selling but the proper name for it is short selling
it's because you are selling something that you don't actually own.
And the way it works in the forex market is you as a trader you approach your broker and all of this
is done automatically so you don't have to think about it at all.
But this is what happens in the background when you click that sell button in your trading platform
.
So you as a broker use a trader approach your broker and you borrow apples from your broker.
So let's say for instance you borrowed five hundred apples the amount of apples you can borrow is underpinned
by the actual amount of money you have on your account because you have to guarantee that you will return
these apples no matter what.
So you borrow 500 apples from your broker and you then take these apples to the Forex market and you
sell them at one point 3 1 4 0 0 dollars per apple and then gives you in return for 657 U.S. dollars
.
So now you have that money and you decide to hold onto the 657 US dollars because you've predicted that
the price of your apples will drop and you wait for that to happen as per hour chart which we looked
at earlier.
So once the price for apples drops and it hits about one point 2 4 8 0 0 American dollars per apple
guess what.
You still have those $657 that you got in exchange for your apples.
Couple of days or weeks earlier.
So what are you going to do with these $657 now.
Well are you going to go and you're going to buyback apples.
Now if you're $657 you can buy 526 apples.
So as you remember you still have to return 500 apples to your broker.
And that's exactly what you do.
You return 500 to a broker and that means you still have 26 outpolls of profit in your hands.
Because of this transaction.
You left off an extra 26 apples and now what you do with these 26 apples is you convert them back into
U.S. dollars at the exchange rate at the time.
And that basically means that now you have a profit of thirty two U.S. dollars.
Now if we replace apples with Euros as we did previously you'll see that nothing changes that this whole
scheme works.
Also for Euros just as it did for apples you go to a broker you borrow 500 euros you sell them at 1.3
1 4 0 4 6 157 U.S. dollars.
You hold onto hundred fifty seven dollars until the price for Euros drops.
You use those $657 to buy back euros at the new lower price of one point 2 4 8 0.
You get 526 years in return you return 500 years to your broker.
Your profit is 26 euros because your account is in U.S. dollars.
You convert your euros back in to years dollars and you have thirty two years dollars of profit.
So that's in a nutshell how short selling works you may find slightly varying explanations for the stock
market and that's because you're dealing with stocks and ownership rights to a company.
But in the Forex market these are actual transactions with actual money and this is how short selling
works in the Forex market.
Also as we discussed previously the first transaction over there is called selling.
It's short for short selling but and everybody is so used to just saying selling on the forex market
that they no longer use the combination of short selling so we'll just stick to selling from now on
.
And the last transaction over there is called closings.
So as you can see it's not that complicated.
The concept itself is a bit different to buying but the Forex market has been around for so long and
the procedures in place in any brokerage company are so standardized that you will not even see a difference
.
The mechanics are different but the way you conduct them by transaction is I am tickled to the way you
conduct the sell transaction and the way these things work in the background they don't even charge
an extra commission for boring those 500 euros.
And finally before we finish this tutorial I would like to point out that just as with buying selling
you can use leverage to achieve much better results from traits.
And this is something that we will discuss in the future tutorial when we talk more about leverage.
And thank you for our attention.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy trading