Pips and points.
So this is going to be quite important to Tauriel because a lot of people get these things confused
and are really like to help you get started in the Forex market.
Knowing these things right away so there's no question about it.
So let's look at the four digit system to start with the forged digit system.
Any currency pair has four digits after the decimal point.
So except for Japanese based kind of spares with Japan Japanese yen is a quarter currency.
But we'll talk about that later.
So the four digit system four digits after the point the decimal point and the last digit is the minimum
change.
So the last digit is the fourth digit.
And that means the minimum change that in any currency pair can experience is zero point zero zero zero
one units of the quoted currency.
So the minimum change is always called one point and this value on the right zero point zero zero zero
one is called one pip.
And that's important to keep these things in your mind separately.
The minimum change is one point and one paper is zero point zero zero zero one.
So in this case the minimum change is equal to zero point zero zero zero one.
And that means one point is exactly equal to one pick and that's going to be the case for every single
currency pair.
If it is quoted in the four digit coding system.
So let's go back to our example of the spread we calculate the spread is ask minus bid for Australian
dollar and was zero point 0 0 0 7 Astroland dollars.
So let's Express's now in points and pips this is equal to 7 points because it's seven seven times the
minimum change.
This kind of support can experience and so equal to 7 pips because this is equal to seven times 0.00
0 1