Technical analysis this type of analysis is based purely on the belief that all available information
in the world is already accounted for in the price and therefore you need to do is analyze the charts
because if all the information is there any contained in the charts then there's no need to analyze
news.
Interest rates of countries or even events like wars or very good harvests in different countries that
affect these currencies because youre assuming that all of the information is already reflected in the
price at any given point in time.
Traders who use technical analysis believe that prices move in trends and historical patterns tend to
repeat themselves and that is what a technical trader would take advantage of seeing a certain situation
that he's seen before and knowing how it resolved in the past.
He can make a certain assumption of how it will resolve today and best not make predictions and enter
the market in a way technical trading is more precise and definitive than fundamental trading because
in fundamental trading you have to use your own expertise knowledge and assessment of the situation
you are expressing a subjective view on what will happen.
Whereas in technical trading you are looking at patterns which happened in the past and based on that
information driving certain rules for your trading systems to act in the present day.
Therefore you're being objective.
That's a very big advantage of technical analysis.
It's removes psychology from trading so you're not worried about whether you made the right call or
not.
Because you have taken yourself out of the equation once you've set up these rules.
You only have to do is follow them strictly and precisely if you've set them up correctly.
You should make a profit a very high chance of success.
Therefore you're not worried and staying up late at night or not being able to see another good advantage
of technical trading is that in contrast to fundamental analysis you don't have to develop an intimacy
with the concept of trading because charts are of course different kinds repairers will have different
styles of chards different types of movements.
But as so long that you've learned how to analyze one two three four different currency pairs you will
start seeing consistent themes across different currency pairs and you will be able to easily switch
between analyzing different currency pairs.
You because you're not that invested into the knowledge base of a certain kind of spray you don't have
to keep economic events about it you don't have to know who the he is box people are for that country
and interest rates and so on.
It's very easy to switch between charts and takes a minimal amount of time to adjust yourself to a new
currency pair.
And therefore we have the luxury of trading a much more diverse portfolio of currencies.
When you're using technical analysis