All right so we've already talked about support and resistance trendlines.
Now we're going to talk about support and resistance levels so support levels.
Let's imagine a situation where we have a downward trend in the market and in this case a support level
is a horizontal line which is called support level which represents a barrier for the price.
So when we'll find out how to look for support levels in a few minutes.
But right now let's see what the support level does to the price.
So as the price approaches the support level trade has become hesitant because they don't know what
will happen.
They don't know whether the price will cross it or whether the price will bounce off and move in the
opposite direction.
So generally you'll notice a kind of consolidation on the market.
And then one of the following three things will happen.
Either the price will bounce off the support level and go in the opposite direction or the price might
test the support level a little bit.
Cross-head and then bounce off and go in the opposite direction or the price can actually cross the
support level and there'll be a massive impulse in the direction of the trend.
So now resistance levels are they're very similar but they're the opposite.
They're above price.
So resistance level puts pressure on the price and doesn't act as a barrier for the price going upwards
.
And once again generally speaking it's three possible outcomes.
Either the price bounces off the resistance level and goes down or it can test the resistance level
and then go down or it can cross the resistance level and there will be a strong impulse in the direction
of the trend.
There are two main types of support and resistance levels and these are historical and psychological
.
Let's have a look at the historical type first.
So historical lows look at this chart.
Can you identify any horizontal lines that have been tried and tested by the price of more than one
type.
We can see one of those lines right away.
It's this horizontal support line and the price tested this line over here first and then it came back
to this line here.
And so what can we anticipate from the prices future movement.
Well we can anticipate that if the price does go towards this support line then something will probably
happen over there.
So and that's how you establish support and resistance levels the historical type.
You look at what happened in the past and you see that oh wait a second so the price was hesitant to
cross this level previously or there was some sort of consolidation there in the past.
So maybe that same thing or something might happen when the price approaches is low.
And more often than not that's exactly what will happen.
There will be some sort of abnormal movement when the price gets to this level and that's what we take
advantage of.
The second type is psychological levels.
So they're a bit different in the sense that the price is just in a trend and then we identify a level
which is very often a round number.
So for example 1.5 0 0 0 that is a number that's plays of the minds of traders and because they don't
know whether the price is going to bounce off or across it.
Mathematically speaking there's nothing special about one point 5 0 0 0.
It's no different to one point 650.
But at the same time in a consumer's head in a normal person's head who walks the streets and lives
his life in his head his home currency being traded at above 1.5 and below one point for two distinct
things.
So you might not care whether it's 1.6 or 1.7 but he'll remember if it's one point fifty five or if
it's one point forty five because that kind of difference sits in your head.
Or same thing if it's like 2.0 like you would know if your home currency or somebody somebody sold currencies
trading at $2 per unit of the currency or below or above.
So it's kind of a strong level because it's around number and traders tend to be hesitant when the price
approaches this level because they don't know what will happen where the pressure will go down or up
.
And same thing as with historical levels something happens.
One of the three things that we discussed normally happens over here.
So let's have a look at an example from a real chart here we've got the British pound dollar weekly
chart and I just took this out of my terminal So this is fresh as of today our fourth of February 2015
.
And as you can see the British pound dollar currency pair is approaching or has approached this blue
support line.
And guess what it is it's 1.5 0 0 0.
And let's have a look here closer so as we discussed traders don't know what's going to happen and these
kind of broad numbers play with their heads.
They're anticipating some sort of reaction or action on the market and generally the price goes into
consolidation for a certain period of time.
So traders and I was going to happen.
And here you can see that's exactly what happened.
So before the price reached this level we had six weeks in a row we had bearish candles.
You see those six out white candles going down.
They there were 6000 euro.
And as soon as the price got to the to the psychological level it stopped.
We got to bullish candles so the price went in the opposite direction and that's because it's testing
the level it doesn't know.
Nobody knows whether it's going to cross it or was going to bounce off and so now there's like a balance
of power of bears and bulls and sooner or later one of those three things will happen and we'll see
a strong movement afterwards.
And in this particular case you can see that the psychological level is also a historical level and
that's quite common with psychological levels because they tend to be very significant throughout history
.
So back in January to July 2013 the price tested this psychological level three times.
And as you can see it wasn't able to cross it and that's when a massive impuls happened and the price
went upwards and reached somewhere around 1.7 American dollars per British pounds.
So now it's back here at one point 5 0 0 0 and everybody's waiting to see what will happen.
So to sum up there are two main types of support and resistance lines.
These are trend lines which are diagonal and these are levels which are horizontal and there are two
types of supporters Aston's levels historical levels and psychological levels and all of them act as
barriers for the price.
And when the price gets to them it either bounces off or we see an impulse when the price crosses these
levels