Hello this is Kirill from explode dot com.
And welcome back to the course on forex trading today is going to be a very exciting tutorial because
we will finally get to open our very own first real Forex order.
That's right.
I will be trading with real money right in front of your eyes.
As you can see here I've got a real Forex account opened with Al Pari and I have 500 U.S. dollars on
that account.
On the left in the Market Watch we can see that the market is fired up.
The currency pairs are rapidly changing in prices and in the middle here we've got the Eurodollar for
hourly timeframe.
We're going to open up very first order on the euro dollar.
I have already outlined some things on this chart and we'll quickly discuss them before we go on to
opening our very first real Forex order.
As you can see the price on the your adult for our the time frame is currently in a downward sloping
channel.
So the borders are marked with these outer two yellow lines and middle line marks the middle of the
channel the price first entered the channel over here at the beginning on the bottom border.
Then it hit the border a couple of time and hit the middle.
The top border went down back to the bottom border crossed the mail went to border.
Now it's just touched the middle.
And guess what it's going to go next.
That's right it's going to go down towards the bottom border of the channel.
So a couple of other things right here I've got some prices marked out.
The green price is approximately the current price of the euro dollar.
It's a bit higher than that.
Currently it's at one point 2 4 3 1 9.
So basically you see two pipes above that the blue and the red are present we would want to set out
take profit and stop loss levels.
So you can see here I've said Stop-Loss just above the yellow top yellow line meaning the top a channel
border.
And that's because there's a good chance that the price will butts off and we will give it some extra
leeway in there because just in case it does cross the border a little bit.
So we're on the safe side stop loss.
Also this red horizontal line represents a very strong psychological level of one point twenty five
0 0 0 U.S. dollars per euro.
And that means traders will try to sell at that level which will help us drive the price down.
Also we could potentially put the take profit even lower closer to the bottom border.
But I didn't want to make to take profit much larger than the stop loss in this case.
Our take profit is approximately 140 pips and our stop loss is about one hundred and thirty pips.
So that's that's about about even.
Not not not exactly but about even.
You could if you wanted to set the stop take profit a bit lower but we'll go a bit conservative and
stick to this take profit of 1.2 to nine hundred.
Also an interesting fact that I noticed is if we go on zoom out a little bit you'll see that we are
in a downward trend.
So we are trading along with the trend which is good and an interesting thing.
In fact if we extend this channel line you'll see that the price actually touched this line over here
.
So it is a diagonal resistance line for this trend and that's also a good thing for us that means there's
even a higher chance of the price bouncing off this line when it gets to it.
That's exactly what we want.
So now that we've identified the direction of our trade where we want to set out take profit and stop
loss.
The last thing that we have to do is understand what volume we can we can assign to this trade.
And in order to do that I'm going to quickly bring up a slide that we are already familiar with to calculate
volume over trade which is X in this equation.
We have to divide the risk in dollar terms by 10 multiplied by the stop loss pips value here the Stop-Loss
pips value is at how many Pape's the stop loss has been set and risk in dollar terms is the amount of
money that we are prepared to lose if this is a loss trade.
So in our case let's assume that we won.
We're OK risking 10 percent of our balance.
Ten percent is quite a risky approach.
However in our case we've got a very strong resistance line.
We've got another psychological level on our side.
And so it does look like a good trade and hopefully your dull will go downwards and reach out take profit
.
So I'm quite comfortable at setting this risk level at 10 percent.
Our balance is $500 10 percent of $100 is 50.
So we replace 50 in that equation.
So the last variable that we have to input is our Stop-Loss pips.
And as we discussed a plus pips is 130 so I'll just put that in right now.
And now I'm just going to bring up the calculator so we can work this out.
So again to 50 divided by 10 times 130.
That gives approximate 0.03 8 4 6.
And of course in volumes in lots we can only use two decimal points about actually depending on your
count but in on this count it's two points.
So we're going around that up to 0.04.
So I'll just type that in here he goes point zero for lots.
Perfect.
Now we can go ahead and conduct this trade.
Now we're going to click this new order button up at the top here and in these boxes we're going to
specify all of our parameters so it's 0.04 lots Stop-Loss we're setting at one point to five six all
take profit.
We're sitting at one point two to nine hundred.
That's a blue price over there.
The comment is going to be my very first fix order.
Exclamation mark.
And this is going to be a sell order.
So we click sell and there you go the order has been sent successfully executed and it's got a ticket
number.
It's a sell order or a point or a fall last year or Dola.
That's the price at which it was executed.
Stop Loss and take profit just as we specified.
So that's perfect.
And congratulations on that.
That's a very big step.
Very big first step in your Forex trading career.
So I'm just going to click OK here.
As you can see we've got new exposure to the euro here.
It is negative because we conducted a sell order here.
We've got some information on margin and what's going on with the equity.
Now if we move to the trade tab you'll see order here.
So that's the ticket number of order.
That's the time when it was open.
That's the type of water it's a sell order size volume and lots of points are for Symbol your dollar
price is one point and that's the price at which the order was opened.
Stop Loss take profit as specified.
The price price is the current price.
Commission taxes and swap and our current profits a bit negative.
That is because of the spread here you've got information equity margin free margin and balance.
So that sums it up.
Today we're going to leave the order for a few days and then come back and see how it went.
Hopefully it would have close a take profit by then.
Thank you very much for your attention today.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
And until then happy trading