Hello and welcome back.
It has been a day since we opened our Eurodollar sell order and today we're going to look at the result
.
So right away let's look at the bottom left corner of trend for terminal in the trade tab.
We can see that our current account balance is five hundred fifty six dollars and 19 cents.
And that's great news.
That means that our sell order was close at a profit and we earned $56 in that trade.
So just quickly open the account history tab and here we can see that our order is up at the top here
and on the take profit is highlighted in green meaning that the order was closed at take profit and
you can see the profit is specified so after subtracting swap it's $56 and 19 cents.
So can on that it's it's a really amazing feeling when you see a profitable order on your real Forex
trading account.
So let's look at how everything progressed as you can see here.
I've marked the time where we entered the trade with a vertical red line and that was on the 25th of
November 2014 at around 12:00 p.m. server time and we entered a sell order.
So what happened after that.
I'll just zoom in a little bit out Stop-Loss.
Was it over there or taper off was set here.
So before we continue what I'm going to do is I'm going to take this order I'll drag it onto the chart
and you'll see what will happen.
So as you can see that order got drawn on the chart so you can always do that.
And if you want to see multiple orders and just cold shift and you drag the order and your order onto
the chart and you'll see all the orders for that currency pair.
But this is a handy trick to help analyze orders.
So as you can see the order was open there then the price went back up towards the top of the channel
and it exactly happened to hit the top part of the channel where the channel border crossed the very
strong resistance line of one point twenty five 0 0 0.
Meaning that as we discussed it there was a lot of pressure from traders to drive the price down.
So as you can see the price is zoomed in a bit more.
The price did go over the channel border a bit but it went right back in before hitting a stop loss
and that's that's a good thing.
We set our Stop a bit away from the bore of the channel giving it this leeway given the prices the way
then the price went back down and then it tried to test this level again but it was a very strong psychological
level.
Plus we're in a overall downward trend on the daily chart.
So the price was driven down and it actually went right down to the middle of the middle line of the
channel so if you extend this line you'll see that that's exactly where the price bounced back off.
So it was also a good thing that we've set a quite a conservative stop law.
Take profit rather than setting at the very bottom line of the channel we set it around the middle of
the channel that's exactly where the order closed.
As you can see as the order closed the price went back up and that's like a very ideal situation meaning
that you took most of them momentum of the market that you could so you couldn't place take profit any
lower than that.
And that's just very precise tech profit placing.
So that's something you should aim for in your trades to make the most out of the movements that you're
forecasting on the market.
So that's how it all played out.
And that was all very first a euro dollar trade.
Once again congratulations on that.
And I look forward to seeing you on the next story as well.
We will conduct more trades on this Forex real account.
And until then happy trading.