Hello and welcome back and right away congratulations.
It has been 11 days since we opened our order according to the harmonic parents analysis.
And yesterday the order closed at a profit.
So you can see the profit over here it's the last or all in the history of $41 and seventy four cents
.
So we're just going to drag it onto the charts so we can see how it played out.
And here you can see we opened the order here so we we didn't know any of this part.
We always saw with these three dollar bars and that's where we made our decision to sell.
And we opened the order just for comparison.
I have I'm going to bring up a snapshot of the screen when we made our order.
So you can see it here on the left.
And as you can see we didn't know any of that movement.
It was a purely technical analysis decision.
We saw the harmonic pattern we saw the Gartley butterfly and we decided to enter.
And now as you can see 11 days later we have been rewarded with a take profit.
So that's beautiful just an amazing result.
Let's quickly have a look at how the market played out.
So we're going to zoom out a bit here you can see a bit better what happened.
So we had or maybe even a bit more so we had this downward trend and we had a bit of a consolidation
when we got to the.
This is the zero point eighty level.
Here it is.
So this is a zero point eight to level the market was very unconfident getting to this level.
And you can see how the power price bounced off a couple times.
And by doing so it formed this harmonic pattern which we actually use for our analysis.
Then the price went down at this stage kind of tested the zero.
You got to the zero point a 0 6 level kind of.
There was a bit of pressure for the price to move up.
Words went up a bit.
It was a good thing or a really good thing and we said I'll take profit up top here protecting it with
the zero point eighty three level that's exactly what the price that are here.
So the price tried to cross as a report a three level but it didn't.
Then a bit of consolidation again and then it just started tumbling down and that's where our take profit
was reached.
Beautiful result.
It very well said take profits in the sense that it's really sort of sort of stop lost in the sense
that it's very well protected.
A good take profit as well and let's have a look and see where the price actually went up to.
I think you might be a little bit surprised actually.
So we're going to drag out take the Fibonacci levels and we're going to drag them onto our last movement
of the Gartley pattern and we'll see where they will end up.
So we've dragged them like that.
Now is going to move them here.
And what do you know the price actually just touched the 161 point eight level.
Isn't that fascinating.
That's exactly what we talked about in the previous tutorial we said that the Gartley apparently gives
you targets where to set your take profit and something I mentioned was the can I said at one sixty
one point eight or one twenty seven point two but we're going to set it somewhere in between because
we don't want to cross the Zero Point 79 level we do what we don't want to worry about it because the
0.18 level is strong enough.
In practice what actually happened the price touched the one sixty one point eight level and and and
bounced off.
And it's a it's a resistance line here.
Isn't that just fascinating that we had a harmonic retracement here sixty one point eight percent but
a Fibonacci ratio.
Then we had a harmonic tradesmen here hundred twenty seven point two percent that's the square root
of the ratio.
And now we have a harmonic movement.
One hundred sixty one point eight percent.
Just something to think about how mysterious and yet very effective these Fibonacci levels and harmonic
retracement patterns actually are in in practice.
So that's it for today.
Congratulations on that great trade.
Also it was a good example good good illustration of the usage and effectiveness of harmonic parents
.
If you're interested to find more about them I encourage you to read.
Read on and find additional information because they can be quite useful in your trading.
I look forward to seeing you on the next tutorial.
And until then happy trading