This lecture we're going to go ahead and talk about lines.
Kate O-lines are the first fundamental of drawing.
It's the most important part that you need to understand next to shape but you can't create shapes unless
you understand how to make laws.
So the first thing to understand about lines is there's obviously all different types of landscape.
So we have straight lines.
We have curved lines we have lines we have swirly lines.
We have random organic squiggly lines.
We have all different types of lines k we have lightning bolt lines.
There are all different types lines.
Now what I want you to do is I want you to go ahead and practice some lines just draw all the different
types of lines that you can think of K and there's different things you can do to make your lines look
different.
So first off you can draw a dark going by pushing really hard with your pencil or you can draw a light
one by drawing softly or you can draw one in between.
So you can also create very thick lines by drawing lots of lines together or you can draw the edge of
a pencil like so and you can also combine the lines so I can draw a line like that and then I can draw
another one like that that connects like so and then that creates a shape.
So I want you to play around with this and try to create as many lines as possible and as many variations
of those lines as you can think of the next thing we're going to go over is contour lines.
So what is a quarter a line.
Well a contour line are the lines that make up an object or an image.
So for example with an eye let's redraw I really quick.
So there's the basic shape.
Now I know this isn't going to be perfect.
But I'm creating contour lines right now.
So the first phase of drawing a picture is creating the contour lines you want to create those lines
of where your object is and where it ends.
So the top part of the island is right there the bottom eyelet is there the colored part of the I's
right there.
And my eyebrow shape is right there.
So these are contrat lines.
Let's have a look at another example.
So let's see I were drawing this pen.
I want to go ahead and set that right there well where my contour lines.
Well first off we have the top part of the pen the clicker.
So we'll draw that.
So those are contour lines for that.
Now I know this isn't going to be perfect.
I just want to quickly demonstrate for you what the contour lines are.
The next part is going to be this ring rectangular purry there so I'll draw that the next part is going
to be this middle piece.
So we'll draw that the next part is going to be this rebel rubber finger holding part.
So we'll draw that kind of has a little bit of wiggle to it.
And then the last part is going to be this right here.
So go ahead and draw that.
And then if we want to we could go ahead and add in this clip so draw that.
So these are the contouring lines of our pen now the next thing to take into consideration when you're
drawing line art is the line quality.
Now the quality is is it's just the thinness or thickness of your lawn.
This can be used to make your artwork look a lot more interesting especially if it's more of a graphic
design type of piece of artwork.
And if you're creating more realistic type of artwork it can be used to create more of a realistic look
because it will create more of an illusion of shadow.
So for example on our eye we could change the line quality of our eye from being very thin like it is
now to being very thick.
So if I add in a thicker line appear at the top you'll see that changes that line quality and it differentiates
it from all the other lines.
And what we can do is we can even go ahead and add in there sort of an animator type eyelash like so
and now we have that nice line quality in there.
And the reason why it looks so nice is because now there's contrast not just in values but there's contrast
in the wine quality.
This is one of the biggest things when it comes to creating good looking artwork is you want to have
contrast in everything in your values and your colors and your lying quality and your textures.
If there's no value your artwork is not going to look good.
So make sure you have different types of quality in your artwork and that's going to create that contrast
for.
Now let's go ahead and look open and see where we can add the line quality.
So let's say our pen is more of a graphic type of piece of artwork.
And it's not going to look so realistic.
We can still add line quality in there to make it look a lot more interesting.
So for example on this curve we can make the curve a lot fatter.
And then as it gets to this part it can get a lot thinner.
Same with over here.
And then we can also do the same here so maybe we add a derk edge along that edge and then add a dirt
edge along that edge but we leave that thinner and we can add this edge to be a little bit darker.
Can add a darker edge on this curve.
And same with this curve.
And we can do the same thing on the top part.
So this is just creating different types of wine quality cake.
So like I said this is very important.
Pay attention to your life quality and make sure that it has a lot of variety that when you're creating
that contrast in your life quality.
Next we're going to go ahead and practice drawing contour lines just by studying them.
So I have my boo right here and it doesn't really fit into the whole shop but what I'm going to do is
I'm going go ahead and set that up here and I'm just going to look at my boot the whole time while I'm
drawing the contour lines.
So remember the quarter lines are just the outside lines that make up shapes.
So I'm just going to look at my boot and I'm not even going to look at what I'm doing here.
And so it's going to look very sloppy.
But the reason why I'm doing this is because I'm trying to learn how to study an image and only pay
attention to that.
If you can study an image and then copy it that's what's going to be a great artist.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So I'm first going to start with this bottom area.
And like I said I'm not looking at my drawing at all.
I'm only looking at the boob.
And this is going to allow me to really study those contour lines.
But it's also probably going to make my drawing look pretty sloppy since I can't see what I'm doing
but I'm just trying to create those contour lines and even better practice is to do it in one continuous
line without changing at all.
So I went with my pencil up all.
All right.
So then we kind of have a boot now.
I wasn't looking at all this is just because I've been studying contour lines for a really long time.
And so I can really draw something that resembles a boot.
And I understand where my hand is about on the paper.
So you really want to practice this a lot.
All right.
That brings us to the end of this lecture.
So in this lecture you learn about lines you learn how there's all different types of lines and you
also practice a bunch of different lines and created a whole bunch of your own.
You also learn about wine quality.
You learn about how the thicker the line is and the thinner a line is the more contrast you'll have
in your image and the more contrast you have the better your artwork is going to look.
You also learn about contouring lines which are just the lines that make up shapes the outside edges
of those shapes and you learned how to draw a continuous contour and line drawing without even looking
at your drawing.
So your assignment for this lecture is to find an object in your house or apartment and you're just
going to do what I just did.
You're going to draw a contouring line drawing that is continuous.
So never lift up your pencil.
Maybe you can lift it up once.
It's not a big deal if you do but just make sure that you don't look at what you're doing.
You just want to make sure that you're studying your object following the line of your object and then
drawing it.
I'd recommend that you do this with a few different objects.
Now I know this can seem silly but trust me if you keep doing this over and over again you're going
to get really good at understanding shapes and lines in an object and you're going to become very observant
by becoming observant you're going to be able to become a great artist that observing observing from
real life you're never going to be able to create amazing artwork that looks realistic or even caricature
type artwork that is from another world.
You still need to understand the real world to create your own worlds.
So thanks for watching and I look forward to seeing you in the next lecture.