It in this lecture we're going to go ahead and draw on.
Now the reason why we're going to start off with something so advanced is because we want to test out
your drawing skills.
The reason why we're doing this is because I want you to draw the eye now before you've gone through
the course and then at the end of the Course what I want you to do is I want you to draw the same line
and you're going to find that your drawing skills go up by a lot.
As long as you do all the assignments and go through the entire course.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So the first thing we're going to do is we're going to start by drawing the shapes and lines that will
make up our on now any piece of artwork in any painting or digital piece of artwork.
It always starts out with the drawing that's the base and if the drawing is good then the rest of the
artwork is not going to matter and it's not going to look good at all.
So we want to make sure that we focus really well on the eye before we start adding in all of our detail.
So let's start with the main shape of the eye which is sort of the football shape.
Now it's not cheap exactly like a football but it's pretty similar.
The thing you want to take into account is that it's usually more angled so rather than having a football
where one corner to the other corner of the football shape is on a horizontal line.
It's going to be more at a diagonal line.
So it might be something like so and then we can maybe bring that side down a little bit more than down
here.
We're going to have the cornea.
All right so now we have sort of the basic shape for the next thing we want to do is we want to add
in the basic shape for the actual colored part of the eye.
So let's go ahead and draw that in.
It's basically just going to be a circle right in the center of our eye.
And you'll notice too that I'm drawing very lightly the way I do that is just by not pressing very hard
with my pencil.
But this way I can always go back and erase if I make something up and I can also do a build up of highlights
and values on top of this by doing it lightly the next shape we want to add in there is we want to add
in our eyebrow.
So I'm going to start it right about there and then to go ahead and bring it over like so.
And then it's going to taper off in a down direction.
Just like so perfect.
Now I want to play with the shape of my eye just a little bit more so I might bring that up to there
bring that down a little bit more and I might start this a little bit further out.
So like I said making sure that you have your shape right is very important when youre creating your
drawings so you can also use the eraser.
Like I said to a raceway err is that you don't want any longer perfect.
Next I'm going to go ahead and add in the eyelid.
So that's just going to be a line that starts out like so.
So there's a straight line at the top a little curved.
And then it's going to come down like so and follow the shape of my eye.
And then over here it's going to taper a little bit towards the edge of my eyelid.
The next thing we want to do is we want to add in our pupils so the pupils just the black hole in the
center of your eye.
So we want to sketch that in.
We're going to make her pupil pretty small
or something like that should be good.
Next let's go ahead and Emerton where we want the bottom eyelash to be and the edge of our eyelid.
So on this top area we're looking straight onto the eyelid.
And so we're not going to see the actual edge of the island but down here we're going to actually see
the top part of the island so we want to mark where we want that to be and where we want it to start.
So that's going to be the top surface of our eyelid and this will be the actual bottom part underneath
the eye.
Now let's go ahead and start adding in some detail.
So the way we want to add in detail is we want to start out by shading very lightly.
So I'm going to start with this top part of the eye so slowly I'm just going to darken it and thicken
the line.
And because this is a girl I I'm going to add a little bit of an eyelash off that edge.
Remember don't push too hard the further you get into the drawing the more refined it will become and
towards the end of your drawing you'll be able to add in some really dark lines.
But for now you want to make sure that you're staying very light.
Then I'm going to sort of blend this into this edge like so so that way it's not such a hard line and
it will be look more like a soft shadow on the top of our
then I'm bringing in some light shadow onto the white of my own eye about their.
And then I'm going to add a little bit of shadow along this edge just like so.
Now this area right here has been left Weider because it's cold that bounce light.
Now I won't explain too much about it but it gives our eye more of a wet look when we leave that highlight
on that edge.
Now we can add a little bit more of a dark edge along this edge.
You don't want it to be too dark but we want it to be dark enough that it stands out.
And then I'm just going to continue to thicken this line.
Now I want the top edge of my line to be pretty hard.
But this bottom edge can stay pretty soft.
I'm going to go ahead and add in a little bit of shadow into the corner of my
and then we can also add some darker shadow along the edge of our eyelid since that's where eyelashes
are going to begin.
And we can also add a little bit of shadow underneath this edge because this top part of the eyelet
is actually going to be hanging over this bottom part.
And so there's going to be a little bit of a shadow being cast over that.
So we'll add that shadow right now.
And I'm just going to continue to layer in my shadows.
Now you may be a little bit confused of why these shadows are being cast where they are.
Don't worry too much later in the course.
We're going to go ahead and learn all about this shadowing and highlight and values.
But for now just follow along and try to do exactly what I'm doing next.
Let's go ahead and start adding a darker edge around our eye shape.
Then we can start working this part of the pupil and we want to kind of leave this top edge out because
we're going to put a highlight over that or a reflection if you want to call it.
But we're going to go ahead and start darkening that in and then we can certainly in this outer edge
a little bit more.
Then let's go ahead and start adding some shadow and highlight to our Eilidh.
So this topper is going to be getting hit by the most lights so we're going to leave that bright white.
And then on the edges we're going to Durkan it just a little bit on this edge.
And then we want to add a dark shadow along this edge of the island so that way it stands out.
Now this is being this dark edge of being created by shadow and it's very thin because you're barely
seen into that shadowed area between the Eilidh and the top part of the eye.
The brow area but it's still creating that tiny little crease and crevice.
And that's where we're adding in that dirt edged shadow next.
Let's go ahead and start adding in some more sheeting up into this area.
And this is going to start adding form into the brow of our eye.
So we want to make sure that we add in this edge over here so that it adds some form over here and then
we're also going to add a little bit of form over here.
And what we want is we want this edge to be a hard edge and the edge on top we want it to be a soft
edge that slowly blends in to the top of the brow.
Next we can go ahead and search shading a little bit more on the top area.
As you're working on your artwork you want to make sure that you move around very quickly from place
to place because if you spend too much time working on one area you're going to overwork that area and
you're going to forget about everything else.
And then next thing you know your piece is not going to look correct.
So you want to make sure that you are jumping from place to place so as you're working up here if you
see something down here that needs to be fixed come down and fix it.
Drawing is not necessarily about focusing on one area it's about focusing on everything at the same
time.
Now this can be a little bit difficult.
But the more you practice drawing the easier this is going to become and eventually it's going to become
second nature and you won't even have to think about it next.
I'm going to go ahead and start adding in some darker shadow along this top area.
And I'm going to leave out an area up here because this is going to be my highlight or my reflection
on my own and I can sort of start to sketch that out a little bit.
I can also start to add a little bit of detail onto the eye.
So this part of the eye is an actual muscle that pulls your pupil open and closes it.
And so that's what these lines are is it's just part of the muscle.
Now I'm going to get too detailed with this muscle area but we can add a few lines in there just to
make it look a little bit more realistic.
And we'll come back later and even more detail to that to make it look better next.
Let's go ahead and add in a little bit of detail onto the eyebrowed.
So um OLman to do is I'm just going to darken that area that we have there.
So that's all I'm going to do for later we'll come back and add a lot more detail.
Now I'm noticing that it's not very dark great here so I want to darken out a little bit more because
I'd be a lot more châteaux there.
And I'm also going to blend it in a little bit more on that edge.
And then we can go ahead and add a little bit of shadow along this.
Now we can also add some shadow along the bottom edge because our eye is on top of this plane surface.
And so it's going to be casting a shadow down here.
So we'll just add that in like so the dirt in this area a little bit more.
All right.
So it's looking pretty good in the next lecture.
We're going to go ahead and we're going to further detail this.
Make it look really realistic and also add a lot more value in there.
Add those little details like the hairs on the eyebrows the eyelashes and more detail into the cornea
of the eye.
Thanks for watching this lecture and I look forward to seeing you in the next one.