Hi and welcome to the course.
My name's Jason and I'll be your instructor on teaching you how to draw.
Now let me share a little bit about myself so you know who I am and you know that you can trust me to
teach you how to draw.
At the age of 17 I began a six month internship with an animation studio and eventually that turned
into a paying job with the end of my internship.
Now the reason why I'm sharing the story with you is because I want to point out that the only reason
why I got the internship and then got the job was because I was able to draw.
I didn't even know how to use Photoshop which was the primary program that they used in order to create
their own media.
But I didn't even know how to use it.
I knew how to draw.
So I just want to stress the importance of being able to draw and understanding how the fundamentals
of drawing now really quick.
Let's go over what we're going to be covering in this course.
So the first thing we're going to do in the course is we're going to draw on.
Now the reason why we're going to draw this high is to test your skills and then at the end of the course
you're going to have you draw the same eye and see how far you've come.
After going through this course next we're going to go over the fundamentals starting with the line
we're going to learn why line is so important and all the different types of things you can use lines
to create them we're going to go over a sheet and form to create entire landscape pictures and even
characters then we're going to go over value and contrast and how important it is to have value in contrast
in your drawings go over space and perspective which also is very important.
And then we'll go over how to create still life drawings which is vital if you want to become a skilled
artist.
You need to be able to draw from real life objects that were going to go over creating textures so that
you can add some realism to your drawings.
And then we're going to go over the human face and also how to draw the human figure.
And lastly I've thrown in a bony section where I'm going to teach you how I create animations style
sketches and I'll break it down step by step.
So I hope you're really excited to get into this course.
I know I am.
And I look forward to seeing your work.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.