All right in today's lecture I have a special treat for you guys.
I'm going to be teaching you how to draw animation styled artwork.
Now a lot of you have asked me how to create this self artwork and that's why I've included this lecture
in the course.
So let's go ahead and get started.
First what I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead and just sketch a character for you guys and sort
of walk you through what I'm doing.
Then we're going to go ahead and break it down and we're going to draw second character and we're actually
going to look at how it's drawn in detail and how we can change different things to make it look like
a different character.
So when I draw my characters I always start off with a circle for the head and then I go ahead and I
added my chin.
Now depending on where I want my character looking that's going to determine where my chin and the centerline
of my face is going to be.
So in this case my character is going to be looking more in this direction and a little downwards.
So my center line is going to come right down like so.
And the chin is going to come down like here and there's my jaw line.
So now I have a chin jaw line and the shape of my head.
Next I'll let you go ahead and add in my neck so I'm going to go ahead and add in a neck in there and
then I can go ahead and bring that into my shoulders.
And I'm not going to worry too much about the shoulders for now we're only going to focus on the head.
So next one I'd like to do is I like to go ahead and figure out where my ears are going to be so I'm
a placement years probably right about there and there is going to be basic egg shapes or upside down
egg shapes.
So there's my ear.
The other one can't be seen because it's behind the head.
Next I like to do as I like to find my center line for my eyes and since my character's looking downwards
that means this line instead of being horizontal it's going to be slanted just a bit.
And it's also going to be circular so I like to draw an oval star to create that form through my character's
head like so and so.
Right now at this point we can kind of see through that character's head.
Now also I'd like to note that I'm using a blue colored pencil because this is what animators used to
draw her under sketches which are under sketch will go ahead and go in there with either a darker pencil
or a red pencil to add in the final lines.
So now that I have the eyeline in there I'm going to go ahead and find where my nose will be so my nose
will be a little bit further than one third of the way down from that line to my chin.
So to put my nose right about there and then I'm going to go ahead and add my mouth and right there
between those two lines and my chin then when I go out and add in my eyes.
So for my eyes I usually like to start off with basic circles and this one right here is going to be
a perfect circle.
And this one is going to be more of an oval because we're seeing more of that side of the next what
I like to do is I like to go ahead and shape my eyelids.
So since we're looking at this at an angle we're going to go ahead and shape this in a different way
than this is going to be shape.
So this I get shaped like so and then this right here is going to be shaped just a little bit different
just because of the perspective we're seeing them in.
All right.
Great.
Next one I like to do is it like to go ahead and draw in a little oval for my nose so one at an oval
from a nose just like so and I'm drawing that and pretty lightly but in my estimation style I really
like to use ovals as the base for my nose's then I can go ahead and sort of Durkan in where I want my
lips to be.
And I think my character's going to be smiling just a little bit.
All right.
Great.
Next we want to do is I want to add in a little bit more of a cheek bone there.
Go ahead and curve that back in.
And then I'm going go ahead and add in a little bit more of a brow and a little bit more of a forehead
just like so and I can also add in a little bit more of a cheek bone.
And next one I want to do is I want to add in my eyes are the pupils and the iris.
So in this case my character's going to be looking straight at the camera and a little bit up because
she's looking down.
So we're going to go ahead and it in
just like so now your iris placement on your characters is something that we're going to have to practice
and work on.
So they look like they're looking in the direction that you want them to.
So now let's go ahead and move on to this one.
And in this case she's going to have a little bit of her Iris covered by this eyelid.
And I can go ahead and add in
my eyebrows.
So go ahead and first add in sort of a rectangular box like so then a line that comes off like that.
And I want to add some expression into her face.
So I want to bring this eyebrow down just like so now she has a lot more expression.
The next thing I like to do is to add in my character's hair.
So you have her jawline right there and then we have her ear.
And so then sitting there we're going to her sideburn and I like to just sketch out the hairline first
off and this line up here is going to be a little bit curved.
Now that we have the hair line we can go ahead and decide what type of hair want our character to have.
So in this case I think my character is going to have relatively long hair and I think I'm going to
put a part right about there.
And I'm going to go ahead and start sketching in some really light lines because I'm not sure how I
want this to go.
But what you can do is you can start sketching in some really light lines and just plain with some curves
and whatever you want is trying to figure out how you want the hair to flow.
Then I'll go ahead and add the other side of the purse.
All right.
I'm kind of liking the shape of that hair.
So now what I'm going to do some to go ahead and start Durcan in a little bit more where I want the
hair form to be.
And this Haret here is actually going to come behind that ear and then we'll go ahead and add some more
of this here.
You can go ahead and do this site.
Also you'll notice that I'm really playing with the shape of the hair so it really comes down to the
shape of the hair being the most important part not the actual individual lives.
So as you can see or hear rather than just having the hair coming over like so in a round shape actually
comes up and then occurs in the opposite direction and then it starts to smooth back out and then it
comes almost straight down.
And that creates a very interesting shape for us.
So now what we can do is we can go ahead and start adding in some more detail with our darker pencil.
Real quick.
I'm to go ahead and sketch in a little bit more of her body.
So adding some arms in there maybe a little bit of shoulder
going to go ahead and add a little bit of a collar bone so neck muscles.
Perfect.
Now let's go ahead and grab our red colored pencil.
And I like to use red because I just think it looks interesting.
If you want it you can go ahead and use a normal dark pencil.
But in this case I'm going to go ahead and use my red colored pencil and I'm going to go ahead and start
turning into areas I know dark and so I usually like to start with the eyes because I want that to be
the focal point and I make that the DERKS area by adding in some really dark and thick eyelashes.
So even if this is a guy I always add in really dirt and thick eyelashes
then I'll go ahead and start to Durkan in it the iris of the eye.
And I want to make sure that I leave out an area for a highlight.
So there's a highlight right there.
I'll go ahead and fill in around that.
He didn't seem besides going to get a little bit of a highlight there.
6 so and I can add a little bit more of a Swoope off the edge of that eyelash.
And I'm also fatten up a little bit more and connect it.
All right.
Great.
Now let's go ahead and move on to the eyebrows.
I'm going to go ahead and Durkan those eyebrows in
and then I'm to go ahead and Durkan in her forehead.
No this is a good time to reshape things the way you want them so like that forehead.
I brought that in just a tiny bit more.
Go ahead.
Adding this cheekbone that comes all the way down to the chin.
We can go ahead and that and the jaw line and generally girl characters are going to have much pointy
or chins than many characters.
Next I'm going to go ahead and add in the detail on my nose.
So first off I like to start off with the nostrils of the nostrils just a small little line like so
and then I add the bottom part of the nose and at the edge of the nostril and then I like to draw in
that Oval just a little bit darker with my red.
And then I like to add a shadow on the bottom of that nose just like so and then I can go ahead and
connect from this eyebrowed all the way down to my nose with a little bit of a curved line just like
that.
I'd like to add a little bit of shadow in there also.
Next I'm going to go ahead and add in my lips so these lips are going to be very similar to drawing
realistic human lips which this is why I say it's important to understand how to draw realistically
if you want to draw it like an animation artist because you need to understand how real life works.
If you don't know how to draw humans in real life you're going to have a really hard time drawing an
animation character because you're not going to understand how each part of the human face works that
I'm going to go ahead and add in a little bit of blush in there.
I like to add this in because I think it makes my characters look a little bit more interesting and
charming.
So even if I'm doing the guy I usually add a little bit of blush in their own cheeks and sometimes they
have to come across the nose and onto the other cheek just like so you can also go ahead and add some
freckles in there.
I think that adds a little bit of character to your character but you don't have to add that in.
And you got to add that in every character.
But I generally like to add in freckles because I just like them.
I'm a go ahead and add in the ear.
And if you remember how we drew a realistic here we can go ahead and sort of copy that but we want to
simplify it in this case because it's an animation character.
So that's pretty simple.
That I'm going go ahead and start to add it in my hair.
So starting with right here or adding in hair and I can add a little bit more detail there so maybe
a little bit more on the sideburn
I'll just continue these lines down and try to keep them as nice and smooth and flowing as possible.
And I want to make it too dark as I'm trying to keep those eyes the focal point in the sketch and can
go ahead and my shoulder and her neck and in the background areas of her hair we can go and darken man
since and be quite a bit shadow back there
and her collarbone and her collarbone is just a basic little sort of U-shape.
And then the line coming off that is that arm and we can go ahead and add this side of her hair.
Now if you want to get really good animation are what I recommend you do is find a ton of pictures of
other artists animation art and copy it.
You can even copy mine if you will.
I don't care.
But don't take credit for other artists artwork but just copy it to understand how they draw their pictures
and how they use sheep to create their artwork.
This is going to help you out immensely.
When I first wanted to learn how to draw animation artwork this is what I did.
I spent about four months just sketching out tons of other artists drawings.
And from that I picked up how to create like the eyes the nose.
And I learned a ton of different styles.
And then I sort of matched those styles together and then incorporated my own little flavor.
And now I have a little bit of my own style of animation artwork.
All right.
So now we've created our character and I want to break this down a little bit further for you and take
it a bit slower because that was a little bit quick.
So when I draw my animation characters like I said I like to start off with the hand.
So the head like we said is just a very basic circle so we draw a circle in and in this case we're going
to draw our character from the front.
So next one I like to do as I like to go ahead and add in my chin.
So it's basically going to be like drawing a real sick human head.
So we add in sort of the arrow takes shape at the bottom of our circle.
Next what we want to do is we want to go ahead and find the middle of our line or the middle overhead
horizontal vertically and then we want to find the horizontal ones so horizontal one is about there.
You a little bit lower or.
Perfect.
So now we have a set up for our head.
We can also add in the detail for next.
So the next line should be a little bit further in from the edge of the head.
And we don't want the next to be too long.
That's something that a lot of people make in mistake about is making the next too long.
Now this is a style choice that's totally OK.
But in most cases you want your neck to be relatively shorter than you would probably make it normally.
All right so now we have her neck and her shoulders next.
Let's go ahead and add in the eyes now the eyes are very important when it comes to your character.
And it's mostly the shape that matters.
So how do we create different shape eyes.
Well let's come over here to the side real quick and let's try sketching out a few different eyes.
So the kind of eyes we did on this girl was sort of an upturned.
So if you watched the lecture on how to draw eyes he saw we went over five different styles of eyes.
So we're going to do the upturned eyes.
So if you remember the upturn I is basically comes up blank so when it comes back down like so and so
we have a line going through the two corners of her eye but rather than being straight and horizontal
they actually go diagonally.
And that's the device we have on this girl.
Now a lot of the times this would create a more attractive type character but not always but in most
cases if you want a really attractive type looking looking character you're going to want to add in
an apt turn on like this.
Now what other kind of eyes can we do.
Well we can also do eyes that have a large top like so and have a large bottom like so we can also do
other types of eyes where they're almost just like an oval with a little bit of a tear duck there.
And then we can add in a pupil like so
that a pupil to this one so that I'm like so
then let's go ahead and have people this one
also.
Another thing to take nude on is that the eyelashes and the eyebrows are very important on an animation
character.
So if there are no eyelashes it's going to look really boring and bland.
So let's go ahead and add that in.
So generally I just like to lump it up into one basic shape.
So I like to have a curve off the edge a little bit like so and then I like to draw a line right across
the top like this.
And then I just go ahead and fill that shape in.
And so not to every individual actual eyelash.
I'm just doing one basic shape.
Then on the bottom I like to add a little bit of a dark line like so but I don't continue that all the
way around.
I just want a little area that's darker.
You continue it all the way around.
It's going to look like too much.
Let's go ahead and try to on this one so we can go ahead and add in our eyelash shape so we can go ahead
and fill that in and Durcan a pupil a little bit more.
Now we can go ahead and add a little bit of a darker area on the spot my lash.
And in some cases you don't even have to add a Derline you can just leave that out completely.
So let's try that on this.
So if I go ahead and add in my flashlight so and then I'll just leave out that bottom area and sometimes
that looks really good too.
So now let's go ahead and add in the eyes on our character.
So what we want to do is we want to make our eyes a little bit larger than they would normally be.
Now you can create whatever style of animation artwork we want but in this case I'm teaching you how
I like to draw my style of animation artwork.
And I like to make my eyes bigger.
So whether it's a guy or a girl my eyes tend to be bigger.
So I'm to go ahead and start by drawing a circle like so seam on this side and then I like to find where
my eyelids are.
So in this case I'm going to be using this type of an eye.
So I'm going to go ahead and draw that up like so and so I like to start the corner where my tear duct
would be on the straight horizontal line.
And then I like to end this corner just a little bit above that.
And then we can go ahead and bring that back down.
So same with this side.
So we're good at that and just like so go ahead and bring that back down.
So now we have the basic shape for eyes.
We can also add in the iris.
And we can have the iris looking wherever we want we can have it looking forward or we can have it looking
off in this direction.
In this case have a looking off in this direction because I want to demonstrate to you how the iris
changes as it curves or turns around the eyeball.
So we have it looking up here.
It's actually going to turn into more of an oval shape because it's in perspective.
And so as that circle curves around that silhouette or not so under that sphere you actually get more
of an oval shape.
So let's go ahead and add that in on the other side too you go ahead and Durkan in the eyelashes just
a little bit more.
And the bottom eyelashes next I like to add in the nose so the nose is going to be a little bit around
half way between this line and this line.
You can actually bring that down even just a little bit more if you want.
But then like I said I like to use an oval as my nose and depending on what kind of character you're
doing if you're doing a guy it will probably be a much bigger nose but if it's a girl I like to keep
it pretty small.
Somewhere between these two lines and if it's a guy you can do a really big circle.
It just depends on what you want to do.
You can play around with it.
So then I get that oval in there and next I like to add in my lips.
Now from my lips I usually like to start off with just shading a little bit of an area kind of the shape
of my lips and try to play with where want those lips to be.
So in this case I think that's pretty good.
But I'm actually going to bring it up just a little bit so it looks like she's sort of smirking and
it can go ahead and have a little wine like so then it can go ahead and detail those lips and just a
little bit further.
So I like to just add in the top part of the lip which is darker because the light source comes from
the top.
So it's getting a nice cash shadow.
And in this case we can actually add in some teeth in there to make her look like she's smiling now.
Her teeth are going to stay in the same position and her mouth is going to be a little bit lopsided
because she's smirking or smiling.
But in this case her teeth are actually going to start right there.
And then her other teeth are going to come all the way over here and we'll go ahead and add in the bottom
lips.
So we need to add in the bottom line first and we add in the shadow underneath those lips like so so
now we have some lips and some teeth also next.
Let's go ahead and add in our ears so our ears need to be lined up with the eyes.
So basically the ear starts at the top of the eyes and ends down by the bottom of the nose.
Now she would have some huge years if we did that.
So you can always break rules when you create an animation or work.
So I'm going to go ahead and make my ears half that size.
Her is going to be like so that I have the other ear right over here.
Next we can go ahead and reshape the jaw if we want because I don't really like the way her jaw shape.
So what I'm going to do is I'm a go ahead and round that out a little bit more and then I'm going to
go ahead and round her cheeks out a little bit more holes.
So it's just going to turn into one big round shape.
Then we can go ahead and find where eyebrows are.
So I'm trying to decide what kind of an expression I want this girl have.
And I think in this case we're going to go ahead and have a relatively surprised look.
So I'm going to lift up her eyebrows pretty high so I'll go ahead and do the same thing.
On the other side
gripped.
Then just go ahead and find the hairline.
So I'm going to go ahead and first the curved line like so for the top hairline and then I go ahead
and add in the sides that go all the way down to the sideburns and then we can go ahead and add in whatever
type of hair stout you want.
Now in this case I think I'm actually going to give her an afro.
So I actually want to add a headband in there something to draw a curved line that goes all the way
around the head like so.
And then I'm going to go ahead and draw that headband in there.
So then we can go ahead and at her afro so her Afro was going to be a basic shape that comes around
like this.
And I recommend that you look at reference for your hairstyle that will really help you because I know
I had a really hard time drawing here when I first started drawing animation art.
But once I drew a lot of different characters with a lot of different hairstyles I started to build
up a visual library of hairstyles.
So now we have this hair.
We can go ahead and detail the texture out so we can add a nice textured concrete line for her afro.
All right.
Great.
Go ahead and darken in those ears to maybe add a little bit more detail.
So a little bit of a bump in the curve around.
Perfect.
All right.
So next what we can do is we can go ahead and grab our red and we're going to go ahead and detail that
and further.
But before I do that I actually want to Durkan in this hair because I want to create that contrast between
each part of her character so there's Derocher
so
that we can grab a red one or we can.
In this case I actually use a dark colored pencils only use this one.
It's an eight beat pencil.
So it's relatively darker and then going to go ahead and detail this character in.
So I'd like to start with the eyes.
Like I said before so many go ahead and first draw an oval around those two shapes.
And sometimes I like to leave the actual dirt part of the eyes white because I think it looks really
interesting.
I'm not sure why but it's just sort of my style choice.
And then I like to go ahead and add in those dark eyelashes and in some cases you don't have to have
this curving off sort of a shape you can just add in a dirt line.
Not only could appear like they're not wearing so much makeup or possibly like they're not wearing any
makeup at all depending on how long and thick their natural eyelashes are.
You don't go ahead and add in this other bottom line like so.
And I like to bring this shape down a little bit further all the way to the till.
Then I'm going to go ahead and add and eyebrows.
Now these eyebrows are a little bit off because if you look here this eyebrow is coming a little bit
further than that corner of the eye.
And this one is a little bit further back than that.
When are the eye.
So I want to go ahead and bring this eyebrow back just a little bit like so and then I can go ahead
and finish drawing those in
the same with this one
perfect.
Now let's go ahead and add in the nose.
So for the nose from a front view of what we want is we want to go ahead and first add in a little line
for Nasra on that side and the line for nostril on that side.
And I like to draw two lines coming off like so and then I like to add it in sort of a triangle shape
so to shape the kind of moves up like so.
And then I like to shape that in them what I like to do is I like to go ahead and connect a line from
my eyebrow all the way down to my nose.
But you don't want to add that in.
But if you want you can.
Next let's go ahead and do the math.
So I had in that darker shadow on top lip.
Now I'm going to go ahead and add that dark shadow within the mouth because there aren't any teeth right
there the teeth are only right there.
And then I go ahead and Durkan in the bottom shadow on that lip.
And also the bottom line on the left.
And we could go ahead and further sheep out this head so I'm going to go ahead and Durkan in these lines
like so seam with that side.
And the simpler you can make your shapes generally the better it's going to be.
So if you can round your whole face on in one shape it's going to look a lot better and simpler.
Next I want to go ahead and Durkan in that headband
if we want.
We can even add some detail.
There's a sort of a design so I'm going to add in some sort of interesting stuff on that headband
and then we can go ahead and detail out the next so Durkan those lines in and no shoulders we can get
in a little line for her neck muscles so like so.
And then we can go ahead and Durkan in this country line for our Afro
now real quick before we end this lecture I want to demonstrate to you some different styles of noses
mouths and eyebrows.
So we went over a couple of different styles of eyes but let's go over a couple of different styles
with other parts of the face.
So let's start with the nose.
So like I said I like to generally do a small oval for the girl's nose and then I like to add edges
for the nostrils and then a little hole at the bottom or a little line for the nostrils.
And then I like to add sort of a dark triangle in there and fill that in.
And then I'd like to go ahead and curve that out like so.
So that's a girl knows that I like to create.
But let's say or do any guy.
Well we can go ahead and draw in a large circle like so minute two similar circles begin at the edges
for the nostrils and we can go ahead and add in the nostril holes now we can go ahead and add in the
bottom of the nostril like so that we can go ahead and choose our shape that we want the bottom to look
like so we can go ahead and fill that in like soap with chateau and you wind up there like so maybe
a little bit of lying there.
So there's like in nails type of nose but there's all different types of noses so you can really play
around with this.
And what about the mouth.
Well the mouth you can increase the size of the mouse mouth and you can increase the size of the lips.
You can change the way the mouth is shaped or whether it's smiling or not.
So let's say that we wanted to do a mouth that was completely smiling.
Well what we do is we start off with a straight line like so and a lot of people think that smiles are
curved lines like so but they're not they're actually straight lines are crossed at the top and then
the bottom is curved.
You know we're going to go ahead and add in the shape of our lips.
So we start with top lips.
So
you know we'll go ahead and add the bottom part of the lip.
So the bottom part gets a little bit of some sheep in there.
And then they can out in the bottom lip
size so we can having those teeth.
So generally the further towards the corner of the mouth you get the darker it is going to become and
it can slowly fade into the white teeth.
So and then I like to add.
And the bottom line for the bottom teeth.
And then you can either just shave this in for the back teeth because usually your bottom teeth are
behind your front teeth or you can go ahead and do that and all the way I like to Durkan and all the
way because I feel like it makes it look simpler.
You can also add a little bit of shadow underneath this edge and then you can go ahead and Durgan and
the top part of your lips like sound and you can have a little bit more shading down here on the bottom.
But that would be some smiling lips or a smiling mouth.
Now let's have a look at eyebrows are really quick now with eyebrows.
You can add an all different types.
So we have these really skinny thin ones.
But you can also add in ones that are let's say a lot thicker.
So in this case we can add some thicker ones concur those over like so many fill that in and you can
also add in really thin ones you can almost just do lines like so or if you're doing a guy you can make
them really bushy.
So let's say that this is a guys I know I know the eyelashes are really thick on it but can go ahead
and add in some really bushy eyebrows like so.
And we don't want to taper it off like we did with these ones with Guy ones.
I usually like to just cut it off at a straight line or have a very small taper and then draw some lines
from the bottom.
And I like to just draw those in with really thick dark lines like so now might be a guy's eyebrow.
All right.
So that brings us to the end of this lecture.
So in this lecture I shared with you how I create my animation style styled characters.
So first off I'd like to break it down into the basic shapes and then I like to go in there and add
in detail like the eyes the nose the mouth then the eyebrows.
And then I add in the hairstyle usually last.
And I also like to draw with a blue color pencil and then add a darker colored pencil or a red colored
pencil on top of that to solidify all of my lines.
All right.
Your assignment for this lecture is to go ahead and draw your own animation style character if you need
to look at somebody else's and use as reference.
That's fine.
Definitely use mine as a reference if you need to.
Then I want you to go ahead and post that to either the Q and A section of the Course or the Facebook
group and let us all see what you've created.
Thanks for watching this lecture.