In today's lecture I'm going to teach you how to draw the human eye.
So the first thing I want to show you is I want to show you how the human eye works.
So up to this point we've drawn some ice except we still haven't really gone in-depth with how the human
eye works and what we're drawing.
So first off we're going to create a diagram of the human eyeball and then we're going to layer on the
human eye lid.
So first off we have the eyeballs so this circle I have drawn here is the sphere that makes up my eyeball.
Next what we have is we have what's called the iris.
The iris is the color of the eyes.
Go ahead and draw a circle in like so and that's going to make up my iris.
The next part of the eye is the pupil.
So the pupil is a hole in the eye.
Now the reason why there is a hole in your eye is because this is where the light comes in and hits
the back of your eyeball and basically tells your brain what to see.
Now a lot of you are probably familiar with this but if you're not that's why I want to go over it.
Now the this is a muscle the iris opens and closes the pupil and the pupil can get bigger or smaller.
So the larger the pupil the more light it's going to be letting in and the smaller the pupil the less
light it's going to be letting in.
Now pupils can be all different types of colors or sorry irises can be all different types of colors.
They can be anywhere from green to blue to brown sometimes grey they can have little hints of gold and
there's all different types of irises.
This other part of the eyeball is called the white of the eyeball.
Another thing to understand is that the iris is generally flat on the eyeball and sometimes even indented.
And so that might cause a little bit of show on the top side if the light is coming down from the top.
It's going to cause a little bit of shadow on the top side because it's indented.
So if we have a look at our eyeball from a side view what we see is we see a ball but the front of it
would be cut flat like so and that could possibly be barely indenting and then we have the hole for
our pupil which then comes into our eyeball and that's why the pupil appears to be black is because
you're looking into basically a cave and no light is going into that cave at least hardly any light
at all.
The only light that's coming in is been focused by the lens in front of your eye so it's hitting a small
spot in the back of your arm.
So now that we have our eyeball drawn the next thing we need to add is the eyelids so the eyelids are
basically just pieces of skin that are laid across the top
of her eyeball and then he comes up like so and we don't have the top of the eyelid all the way back
here where the round part of the ball is.
We have about half way in.
So that would be the top of our eyelid like so and then we have the bottom eyelid.
So the bottom eyelid can come around like so.
So you have to imagine like the skin is wrapping around the ball.
When you're drawing your eyelids and then you're going to have a little bit of a bottom eyelid and you
don't have to make it this prominent but just for demonstration purposes on the draw that is really
strong.
Another thing to know is the top eyelid will overlap the bottom isolate it right over here.
Then we have what's called the tear duck.
So this area right here that's the Teer duck and that's where your tears come from.
All right.
Now let's go over a couple of different eyeshades because a lot of the times people will teach you how
to draw eyes but it's a very generic type of eye.
And there are actually lots of different shapes and it's what makes somebody look like themselves is
that their eye is shaped the way it is.
So the first time I'm going to go over is called the almond eye shape.
So the all in shape is basically shaped like an omen.
So we had in the Teer doc then I part of it is just going to be basically shaped like so very much like
an omen.
And then we can go ahead and draw in our iris and pupil.
Then we can add in our eyelid
a lot of the time the eyelet on the bottom is just going to be shadow and there's not really going to
be a hard line like there is on the top.
So there is our own shape.
Another type of eyeshade is the round eyes so the round eye is going to be very similar to the almond
shape except the bottom part of it is going to be different.
So we come over.
So just like we did with our home in shape high but rather than just coming down like this and making
an almond shape it's actually going to swoop down a bit more.
So it's going to start off like the almond shape but then it's going to come down a little bit more
like so and we're going to go ahead and add in our iris and then a pupil can add an Arctic duck.
Now I'm going to go ahead and add in the island
gripped and we might add a little bit of this ledge of the island also.
It's perfect.
Next let's go ahead and move on to the ice that's cold.
The hooded.
Now the ice is basically can be like the rounded eye or the omen.
It doesn't really matter what it is just what happens with the Browns.
So for example if we go ahead and draw an arm in shape by.
So now we can go ahead and drop the iris in the pupil.
Now before we draw in that island on the top what we want to do is we want to shape the brown and rather
than the browbeating way up here it actually sags down over the aisle.
And so you don't get to see very much of that top eyelids so it's going to start right about down here
and then it's going to sag over the aisle like so and then we're going to come all the way over and
around and then we can go ahead and add in the eyelid on these edges where we can barely see it and
we can also add a little bit of shadow underneath there so that it can at this Bottom Eyelet in and
large my iris just a little bit of bottom eyelid to that ledge.
Perfect.
So that's called the hooded I.
It's just wear at the top of the brow hangs down and sags over the eyelid.
Next let's go over what's called the upturned art.
So the upturned eye is very often used when Disney animators are creating girl characters and what it
is is it's basically just the eye at a slanted angle.
So some people actually do have this type of ID.
So it's going to come up like so then it's going to come down like so Bielski it's kind of similar to
the Almon die.
The only differences is that rather than the wind going straight through or is obsolete now it's going
through a vertical line.
So now we can go ahead and add in our pupil
and her search pattern or iris.
And then our pupil perfect and then we'll go ahead and add in
or laid it on the top and we can add another layer on the bottom.
Now the last one I want to go over is called the Monteux lid.
So it's going to be very similar to the almond dye in the upturned.
It's sort of a mix between the two.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So first off we start off with more of an up line like this like we do with our almond die.
But then that kind of turns more into our upturned eyes.
So it comes overling overlength so never to come down like this.
Turducken.
So you'll see the first half of it is very much like our own and die.
But the back half of it is very much like her but it turned out that we can go ahead and add in our
Iris and her pupil.
And with this type of eye the eyelid actually hangs right down over like so.
And you don't actually really see any of that eyelid line.
All right.
Great.
Now let's go over how to create different expressions with pods.
So first off let's talk about the placement of the iris.
So the iris is a big part in telling your viewer how the person or the character is feeling.
So if we go ahead and draw an ivory here
and we put our iris right here in the middle and we have covered just a little bit by the top eyelid
and not really at all by the bottom eyelid the character is going to look very neutral.
If we have it come down even covered a little bit by the bottom eyelid it'll still look pretty neutral.
As long as the top and the bottom of the iris are covered your character will look pretty neutral and
it won't look very surprised or anything like that but let's see we want our character to look surprised
or scared.
Well what we can do is we can lift the top eyelid a little bit higher
but the main thing that you want to do to make them look scared or surprised is you need to show the
white of the eye or the top part of the iris with your eyelid.
So we're going to bring our iris down like so so we can see a little bit of it top area.
We can go ahead and add it in our pupil.
But now our eye looks scared or even excited.
Now what if you wanted your eye to look really tired and droopy.
Well basically what she would do is you'd go ahead and drop this eyelid much more past the top of your
iris.
So let's go ahead and draw that in.
So come in sort of like so and then we'd see a lot more of the actual eyelid itself.
We can go ahead and draw on the bottom eyelid then we can go ahead and drawing the iris.
And at the top half of it is going to be covered.
But that gives us the illusion that our person is very tired or exhausted.
We can also draw a sort of some lines underneath here to exaggerate the wrinkles underneath the eye.
Now we can also change the expression of the eye with the eyebrows.
So for example with this iris here if I want to go ahead and add an eyebrow.
And I really put it towards a down angle and it really close to my eye here.
And I even have some of my brow come down over my eyelid.
So I'll go ahead and finish adding that I can go out in the hairs
Well now that looks really angry with this guy over here.
We can go ahead and make it look even more surprised by adding a very uplifted eye.
So we're going to bring the eyebrow really high and this might be a little exaggerated but that's OK.
There's a very famous artist named Norman Rockwell and he was very famous for exaggerating how high
up his character's eyebrows went and that made his paintings look much better.
Because of that exaggeration.
So now we can go ahead and and and the hair on the eyebrow
can also show a lot more of the eyelid because it's been stretched out as it's lifted.
And then with this irony here we can go ahead and make that look much more docile if we just add in
a straight eyebrow just like so then we can go ahead and add in the hair on the eyebrows.
All right that brings us to the end of this lecture.
So in this lecture you learned how the eyeball works.
So first off we have the eyeball itself which is also known as the white of the eye.
Then we have the iris which is the colored muscle of the eye which pulls open the pupil and the pupil
as we saw here in the side diagram is just a hole in the eyeball and it lets light into the actual inside
or the cavernous part of the eyeball so that your eye can pick up the signal and send it to your brain.
So really that black there is just a hole.
Then we learn how to add it in our eyelids and how it's basically just skin wrapped around the ball
itself.
Then we learned that we need to add a tear duck in there and then after we learn how the eyeball works
we learn how there are different shapes of eyes.
Then we learn how to create different expressions with her eyes.
BI How much of the iris we show and the shape of the eyelid We also learn that by shaping and positioning
our eyebrows in the correct positions can create different expressions.
Also I really hope you learn something from this lecture and I'm really excited to see you in the next
one.
Where we're going to learn how to draw the nose.