All right in this lecture we're going to talk about contrast.
Now contrast is very important in treating artwork into songs that contrast you wouldn't see the difference
between things and that also would not look as appealing if you didn't have contrast in your drawings.
Now what is contrast contrast is just the difference between values so something that has really high
contrast would be black and white.
So if I do a black box right here and I do that right next to a white box.
Well there is a lot of contrast between those two colors.
And so that's all contrast is the more contrast there is the more distance there is between the values.
So for example if I took this mid value between our mid-tone and our darker color and I went ahead and
I put that right here
and then what say I took this light gray wrote here that's in the middle of my white and my midterm
and I added that and right next to it
like so well there's less contrast between these two colors.
So even though there's still contrasts between them and you can tell the difference between the two.
There's a lot more contrast between this White and black.
Now in some cases you might have no contrast at all.
So it might just be one solid color.
And in other cases you might not even be able to see the contrast because it's so subtle.
So let's go for an example of this.
So let's say I took a gray from right here and that was the side.
So go ahead.
So that in
and the say I took a break from this side.
So right next to that green and it's almost going to be in the same color just barely barely whiter
like so.
So you can barely see that difference between those two colors yet it's still contrast but not very
much.
Now this can be applied to any area of the spectrum of contrast.
So it's not just in the middle.
If we came up here to the top and we had white
and white was next to let's say a really light gray
so there's not very much contrast between those two colors and yet it's still up here at the top side
of our chart.
Now what about down here.
It can be the same way.
So if we had black
and we put that next to another color such as this one right here that's right next to it.
So again there's still a contrast there.
You can just barely see it because the two volumes are so close to each other on the value chart.
And so when you're trying to create contrast you want to make sure that your values are far apart on
the contrast chart.
The closer they are the less contrast there will be.
So let's try some more examples of this.
So let's say that I have a gray background.
And let's see.
I want to create a lot of contrast between my background and my foreground objects.
Well the most contrast I can create between a great background and my foreground is by using the color
black.
So let's say we had a black circle here
well that's the most contrast I can create between my object and my background.
Now what if I didn't want very much contrast what I could do it was I could go ahead and create my gray
background like so.
And then I could add in another bowl.
But this one would be a little bit lighter like so it's another less contrast between the background
and my goal now one could also do this with a what.
So let's say we had a white board here and then we had our gray background.
And now that still contrast.
So there are many different reasons why we want contrasts but the thing to note is the more contrast
that you have between an object the more it's going to draw in the viewers eyes in.
So let's say for example we are drawing the eyes of a woman.
Now I know these eyes are not perfect at all but I'm just doing this for demonstration purposes.
So why are women's eyes supposedly so print.
Well the reason is because they put a lot of contrast in their eyes by adding eyeliner and mascara.
And so for example if we just have it like the normal and let's say that they're not really wearing
any makeup at all.
No I'm not saying that older men have to wear makeup.
I'm just seeing why make it look so good on some women.
But the reason why is because they're creating contrast so their eyes are very white the white of their
eyes.
And then this And then their eyelashes are very dark.
And so by adding in those dirt eyelashes against the white of their eye.
Go ahead Phil in covert part of their eye the dark ash eyelashes against the white of the eye makes
a lot of contrast and humans like contrast.
That's why the more contrast you can incorporate into your irk the better it will look.
But getting back to my point.
Your your eyes are drawn straight into her eyes because they have the most contrast and that's a really
important thing that we're going to go over later is finding a focal point for your drawing.
You need to find one focal point and there's many different ways that you can make people's eyes drawn
to that area and focus on it.
And one of those is to create contrasts whatever area has the most contrast and the drawing is where
the viewers eyes are going to be drawn to first really quick.
I wanted to show you a few examples of really good use of contrast.
So first off we're going to have a look at the Mona Lisa.
Now all of you should be familiar with this painting.
It's probably the most famous painting ever created.
Now with Mona Lisa it very well utilizes the use of contrast.
Now the first way that it utilizes it is first off.
It draws you into the focal point.
And if you haven't guessed yet it's her eyes why her eyes the focal point.
They have the most contrast so her eyes the white of her eyes are probably the widest part on the entire
painting and the darkest part on the entire painting are her eyes themselves.
It's darker than any of these other dark colors down here or at least it appears it appears like it
is because it's next to such a bright color.
And remember the more contrast between two colors the lighter or darker color will seem the next way
that it strongly utilizes the use of contrast is by differentiating between different parts of the Mona
Lisa.
So for example we know that this is her face and then we know that this is her neck and chest area because
it's separated by the shadow which is more contrast.
And then we know that this area is her hair because it's the darker area.
And so by making our hair dark and then making the face area lighter and then making her clothing darker.
She differentiates between each separate thing and then her hands are in this dark area but they're
lighter and so they stand out because of the contrast.
And it's the same thing with the background.
So her head of really stands out because this area of the background is lighter.
And then as it starts to get closer down towards her body where he doesn't want you to focus too much
it becomes darker.
And so there's less contrast between her body and that the background.
And so it doesn't stand out as much.
Now let's have a look at another example.
So here's a character design I've done in one of my courses and I've taken all the color out of it so
we can only see the values.
Now you'll notice that it's the same with the Mona Lisa as it is with my character that the eyes are
the focal point because the eyes are the darkest part of the entire picture and the white of the eyes
are the lightest part.
And so we're creating the most contrast right there.
Then the next thing I want you to notice is how every single object of my character is placed next to
a value that is contrast with it.
So we start with the hair.
The hairs are really light great and then that's touching this dark gray end of the sword.
And it's also touching these goggles.
And then these goggles are touching the light skin.
And then this light skin is touching the dark eyes.
And then if we move down to the scarf the DERKS scarf is touching the light skin.
And then if we move down to the shirt the shirt is mainly a dark gray.
And it's darker than the scurf right here and so it's making a contrast.
And I even created more contrast by adding a drop shadow underneath the scarf.
So that way there's even more contrast between this scarf right here and the shirt.
And then we have contrast between the shirt and the gloves.
And then we have contrast between the glove and the sword handle.
And then to make sure that there is still contrast between the sword handle and the blade even though
it's darker down here I created a gradient so the blade starts out lighter.
Since it's a reflective metal we can do this.
And so the blade starts out lighter down here and slowly turns into a darker gray towards the end.
That way we still get contrast with the hair and the skin and we still get contrast with our sword blade.
If we come down to the pants.
There's contrasts between the shirt and the pants.
And then there's contrast between the pants and the boot.
And so what I'm trying to show you here is that when you're creating contrasts in your image not only
do you want to create a focal point but you want to create contrast between every object that you can.
The more contrast you have the better it will look.
If all of these were the same color or all of them were dark Grays it would not look as good.
Let's go ahead and move on to our last example.
So our last example is a drawing of Davy Jones that I did.
And once again the eyes are the focal point because those are the darkest part.
Next to the lightest part and so it stands out the most.
The next thing I wanted to point out is how we differentiate each part of Davy Jones by having contrast.
So first off let's point out how there's contrasts between his face and its tentacles and his hat so
his hat is a much darker value than his skin.
And then his skin is a much lighter value than his jacket and his vest.
And so we're creating a differentiating contrast between those two objects to help us understand what's
going on in the picture.
And then if we keep moving down we create contrasts between his hand and his clothes.
And then we even create contrasts between the belt and his shirt or vest if you want to call it.
And that helps us differentiate the difference between the vest and the belt itself.
So contrast is extremely important in creating good artwork.
And the last thing I'll point out is that we have a lot of contrast between David Jones and the actual
background.
So he sticks out completely.
If we had all other types of things going on in the background that were the same values it would it
would completely distract you from the drawing of David Jones.
All right that brings us to the end of this lecture.
So in this lecture we learned about contrast we learned that the further apart values are on the value
spectrum the more contrast is going to be and the closer they are the less contrast.
We also learn that if you want to make your artwork look good you need to have a focal point and you
need to create that by using contrast.
Then we learned that if we want to create a differentiation between two objects we can do that by using
contrast.
So if you have a bowl sitting on a table and the ball is a light gray color then you probably want to
make the table a dark gray color.
That way you create as much contrast as possible because you're watching this lecture.
And I really look forward to seeing you in the next run or we're going to delve a little bit deeper
into contrast.