Right in this lecture we're going to be going over how to create a reflective texture.
So what exactly is a reflective texture.
Well the texture of a reflective surface is just a very smooth glossy surface.
So if something is really rough it's going to be less reflective and a really good example of something
that's highly reflective and very smooth is if you're in your bathroom.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So the first thing we're going to draw is we're going to draw a sphere that is reflective.
Now this isn't going to be reflective like a mirror but it's going to be reflective enough that it looks
glossy.
So the first thing you need to understand is that reflection is just a copy of everything around it
being projected onto your object.
So with this sphere for example it's going to be reflecting anything that's pointing directly at it.
So the first thing we're going to take into account is that it's sitting on a white surface.
That means it's going to be getting a light reflection onto the bottom of our bowl then our horizon
line is going to be dark and as it moves up it's going to turn into a lighter gradient.
So let's go ahead and get started so I can show you what I mean.
So first off I'm at in my horizon line like so and next I'm going to go ahead and start adding in my
reflection.
So starting with the darker area and this isn't going to be a completely reflective ball it's going
to be has some really microscopic rough areas.
And so that's going to allow us to make this more of a reflection rather than a really sharp perfect
reflection.
So we're adding in this dark area here that's going to slowly transition into a layer value because
that's what it's going to be reflecting back here where we have our background or background is going
to start out darker and it's slowly going to transition into a lighter color.
So we'll have that nice gradient background.
And for now I'm just going to rough this in and we'll add in a lot more detail to make it look more
realistic here in the next little while.
But for now we just want to rough it.
And so you start to get the idea of what I'm doing.
And then our floor or area that the ball is sitting on is going to be white which is why we're getting
this white reflection on the bottom of our ball.
So now let's go ahead and get started adding in some real Falcon so I'm going to start off with this
middle area.
And so I'm going to add in a really dark value and this isn't necessarily a shadow.
This isn't our core shadow.
This is a reflection of this background area that's surrounding our bowl
slowly change that into the next lighter value.
So we're going to start creating that nice gradient from one dark value to a lighter value as we move
up our sphere.
Now as we get up more here to the top let's say that we have a light source right here in front of it
and it's a lamp.
OK.
So that means that we're going to see that reflection on our glossy ball.
So let's go ahead and create a sheeplike So maybe a little bit smaller like so and we're going to leave
that area out right because that's where our light source is going to be coming from.
So I'm going to go ahead and erase away the edges.
So it's not so dark.
Now we can go ahead and start adding in our value right up to that point.
And we can start darkening this in more and the darker the better the more contrast the more it's going
to look like it's reflecting.
All right.
Now let's go ahead and move down to this bottom area so I'm to start off by lately adding a darker coat
or a darker value on top of this white area because as it reflects onto this ball it might be diluted
by the color of the ball.
Next I'm going go ahead and Adam my cast shadow and now my cash it was actually not going to be a very
hard edge and it's going to be behind it.
So it's going to come back it like so rather than to the side of it.
Then I can go ahead and begin to Durkan that
like I said I wanted to be really soft So we're going to have a nice gradual change from one value to
our weight value of our surface.
Great.
Now since this ball is reflecting or bottom surface that means it's also going to be reflecting the
shadow.
So we can add this shadow into the reflection on our ball.
So don't go ahead and bring that shadow way up to this edge like so honorable.
Same with this side.
And then I can go ahead and begin to blend that in.
Perfect now really quick I want to go ahead and come back up here to this top area and I'm going to
Durkan this just a little bit more.
So it stands out more and creates more of an illusion of reflection.
All right now let's go ahead and move on to our background area.
So our background needs to match in this area.
It can be a little bit lighter because remember this ball is going to be a little bit darker with a
glossy coat over it.
So that means it's going to cause everything on it to be a little bit darker so such as this white area
that's reflecting the white surface it's a little bit darker than the actual white surface because of
the fact that the ball is a darker color.
So let's go ahead and start adding in that gradient backgrounds.
So I'm starting with the darkest color which is this color right here.
And then I'm to go ahead and slowly fade into my next lightest color and I'm just going to do the all
the way up and then I'll do the same thing on the other side.
All right perfect.
Now I'm going to go ahead and add in a box around my drawing so becomes a better composition.
Great.
So now we've drawn it reflective texture which Let's go over it again real quick what a reflective texture
is.
It's just a very smooth surface with a glossy coating on it that allows it to reflect the world around
it.
So basically all the reflection is it's the objects surrounding it that are being projected onto your
object.
So right here we have the bottom surface which is this white area which is the surface of the ball sitting
on.
And then we have this black area on her bowl which is just the reflection of this background area that
slowly turns into a lighter gray which is a gradient which we also see honorable here.
And then this a lighter area right here is our light source.
Now let's look at an example of a highly reflective piece of artwork.
So in this example this is created by MC Escher.
He's a very famous artist and he created this drawing by creating a sphere that was highly reflective
exactly like a mirror.
So you can see here that everything around the sphere is being reflected right onto the sphere and being
projected onto it and also being warped into the shape of the sphere.
That's another thing to understand about reflection is that when it's being projected onto an object
it's being warped into the shape of that object.
So how can we do something like this ourselves.
Well let's give it a shot.
So first off what we need to understand is that the sphere can be broken up into a grid system which
is sort of like a perspective system for a linear perspective.
But basically if we have a board here the middle one it is going to be completely straight.
Then if we come all the way to this edge this is the most curve or line is ever going to be is on that
edge.
Same with this edge and then we can find in the middle line that is about the middle of the curvature
of this straight line and this curved line.
So it's probably going to be somewhere about there and then we can find one in the middle of each one
of these sections.
So the next one is probably going to be about there and then we can get this section or here and slope.
So as it gets to the edge of our bowl you'll see how it becomes more and more curved.
Let's go ahead and do the same thing for the other side.
So we're just going to try to copy exactly what we see here.
And we should start with the middle line and then work our way from section to section.
But I've already started from the inner side so that's fine.
So now Arbel has been broken up into sections and we've added added that Kirch perspective in there.
Now we also need to do it in the other direction.
So if we turn to paper like so we can go ahead and do the same thing.
So we draw a line like so and then we're going to go ahead and draw on both sides of this like we did
before.
All right.
Great.
So what this grid system is is it's basically a normal grid system that's sitting in front of it but
it's being projected or reflected onto our actual ball.
And so when we draw an image onto a ball we need it to warp to this perspective.
So let's go ahead and try this.
So if we go ahead and draw another sphere right here
and then in this example we're going to draw the reflection of a room kind of like an MC Ascher's drawing.
So first off we need to keep in mind where each one of our grid system lines are.
And so we can lightly sketch an some some guidelines in there but we don't want to sketch them all in
because we don't want it to interfere with their drawing.
But maybe one right there in the middle between our straight line and our outer curved line.
And I will do the same thing going in the other direction.
And these will just help us guide our lines.
So let's start off by creating a character so let's say there is a counter right here.
Like so.
And then that counter is going to curve along with this line right here all the way to that edge.
And then we can go ahead and add and another thing over here so let's try adding in a table.
So a table is going to be a little bit taller and it's going to curve all the way out to that point
right there.
And then we can add in a leg and the leg needs to curve with this line right here.
So we'll go ahead and add that in like so then let's go ahead and add some walls to her room.
So when I go ahead and add a war here it and I need to follow this perspective.
So I'm trying to follow that line there.
And then I'll go ahead and add in a line for my back wall which will be a little bit curved along with
these lines and then I'm going go ahead and add in this back wall over here and then add in a roof.
So and then I need to add in a window so my window also needs to curve with my perspective.
I can go ahead and draw no lines like so.
And those actually need to be a little bit more curved too.
All right perfect.
Now let's go ahead and add something else in there like let's say we wanted to add a refrigerator.
Well we can go ahead and add that refrigerator in and we just need to make sure we follow these curved
perspective lines.
So there is a refrigerator and it comes back to the wall so it can break that up into two different
areas so we have our freezer and our fridge area of that fridge Raider and we can also add handles onto
that.
And then let's add one more thing let's add a rug in there.
So if we add a rug in right here we just need to make sure that it follows the curve of our ball
and alleged to my counter also.
So then I can go ahead and Durcan the edges of my bill
and then I can go ahead and also add in some light and shadow into my drawing.
So for example on this side of my counter that might be my core shadow side then this might be my highlight
side.
And then this also might be my Halet side so this other edge of my table leg is going to get the shadow.
And then we also might make this table top a darker value altogether like so and seam with our rug.
A rug might be a darker value.
And then our walls might be a darker value too.
So this side it might be a lighter wall in this middle one it might be a darker wall.
That'll be nice too because that'll create a focal point in our reflection which will be this window
because that's where we're creating the most contrast.
Me go ahead and that a shadow to this side.
Also like so and then we can go ahead and add in a little bit of a darker edge along the sphere.
And we might even add a picture frame on the wall here.
Keeping with the curvature of our perspective maybe another picture frame over here maybe even a second
one and the second one is going to get squished a little bit as it curves around the edge of our bowl.
And then we can go ahead and add in a shadow too if we wanted to just to make it look like it's grounded.
All right.
But that's the basic idea of making a really highly reflective sphere.
So when you're adding a highly reflective texture to an object you need to imagine that the surroundings
around it are being projected onto that object.
But also they're being warped to the shape of that object.
I know it can be a little bit complicated and old take a lot of practice and a lot of studying to understand
how this works.
But for now this should be enough information to get you by with creating reflective textures.
Thanks for watching this lecture and I really look forward to seeing you in the next one.