All right in this lecture we're going to go over for it and how to use it.
So what is forming for is just adding a three dimension to a to d object.
So for example let's draw a square.
So this Square right here is A to D object.
It only has two dimensions but we can add a third dimension to that.
Or at least the illusion of a third dimension by creating it into a cube.
So to do that all we have to do is draw lines coming off of each corner like so.
No we just need to connect each one of those lines.
And now we have a simple isometric cube.
So we just added to that.
Let's try another shape.
Let's say we wanted to create form in a cone.
Well what we'd have to do is we need to first draw the base which is going to be an oval because this
is going to be a circle base and it's going to be in perspective if we have a circle like this.
And we're looking at it from this view you see how it turns into an oval.
That's perspective.
So let's go ahead and draw that peek of our come just like so and then we'll draw that rounded bottom
like so.
So now we have a cone and that has some form to it because we can see that bottom edge.
Next let's try a pyramid.
So a pyramid is going to have a square or a rectangular base.
So let's go ahead and sketch out that rectangular base.
So let's say there are bases like so and then we need to draw our first surface.
So our first surface is going to be like this so from one corner to the other and then connect at the
top and then we can connect it at the bottom.
Then the other one is going to go ahead and connect up to the top like so.
So now we have a very basic Pyrenean.
Now what if we wanted to create a random sort of organic shape.
So let's say we wanted a shape like this.
So go ahead and quickly draw a shape.
Now how can we add a form to that.
Well it's just like adding form to the cube.
We just want to draw a line coming off of each one of these corners.
So and then we're going to connect all these lines.
But when we connect them on our line or sheep on this side has to match this edge right here.
So first we'll do this one and then this is a solid object.
So you're not going to see this line continue because it's covered up by this area and but go ahead
draw a line there a line there a line there and a line there.
And so now we just added a form to that shape.
Now what if it was an organic shape so let's say we have a very random squiggly shape like so.
And we want to add some form to that.
Well all we have to do is have a line coming off there line coming off there and then we're not going
have a line coming off over here because we're seeing the top of that over here we're actually seeing
the edge of that shape.
I'm going to go ahead and add a line there and will add a little bit of a line in there.
And then one right there and then whoops I went over a little bit right there.
Then we can go ahead and we want to copy this shape like we did on this.
We want to copy this edge over onto this edge so that sheep right there.
Copy this edge also.
Perfect.
All right.
So now you should have a pretty good idea of how to add form to your shapes but this is very basic form.
What if we wanted to change things up a little bit like let's say we wanted to see these from a different
angle.
So with our cube Let's see if we wanted to see it for more of a top view.
Well what we need to do is we need to stretch this top plane out a little bit more so that we see more
of that top plane and a little bit less of this front plane.
So what we're going to do is we're going to go ahead and draw our front plane first but it's going to
be very very slightly squished.
So a little bit less than a square and a little bit more of a rectangle.
Now we're going to take this form right here and we're going to stretch that out by a lot.
So we'll stretch it out like so and then we can go ahead and draw this edge for this plane like so.
So now we're getting a lot more of a top view on that.
Q What do we want to see more of a top view on this cone.
Well what we need to do is we need to stretch this base out.
So right now imagine if we have a circle and we're looking at it from that view we want to see it more
a top you just need to turn that circle down a little bit more.
So this needs to become a more pull out.
So let's go ahead and draw that sort of draw like so and then let's go ahead and draw an the triangle
part of our cone.
Go ahead and draw a bottom round edge.
And so now you get the illusion that you're getting more of a top down view of this cone.
Let's try this pyramid.
So let's say that we want to see a more top down view of this pyramid Well we go ahead and we draw that
square base but with more of the top down views.
So it's just like the circle if you can take a square with your hands.
Let's say you're looking at it from a view like this.
And then we're going to go ahead and we're just going to move that down so that we can see it for more
of a top down view.
That's all we're doing with a square base.
So next what we want to do is we want to add in that first plane.
MIKE So I'm having that second plane and then we'll have another bottom.
So now we're getting much more of a top down view on that pyramid.
Now what if we wanted to turn something so let's say the shape right here at let's say we wanted to
turn it a little bit more to the left.
Well we're the right.
Well we have to do is we just have to squish the shape right here and then pull these out further.
So let me show you what I mean.
So first let's redraw this base shape.
And we want to like I said squish it.
So we're going to make this parade here skinnier and make this part skinnier
like so.
So now we have a lot more squished type of a shape like that.
And then we're going to go ahead and take these lines and draw these out a little bit longer.
So we're going to draw him out to about there and this one too about there is one too there and I didn't
copy the shape of her perfectly but it gets the idea crossed.
Like so.
So now I'm getting a lot more of a side view of this sheet.
What if we wanted to tilt the sheep forward like this shape.
Well this will be a little bit more complicated but it can still be done.
So let's go ahead and draw the shape but you have to imagine the shape as though it's surface is being
tilted forward like so.
And so it's going to become a lot more squashed in the diagonal angle.
So let's go ahead and draw this.
So first starting with this little loop right here I'm going to go ahead and drop that right there and
then I'll do this loop right here.
And this one is actually going to just get squashed in this way rather than this way.
And then we'll go ahead and do this one.
This one will get squashed like so.
And then this one is going to stay wider like this one over here.
And then we can go ahead and draw our lines but we're going to make them go up more because it's been
tilted forward.
So these lines are going to become more diagonal so they're going to almost be straight up
and I'll go ahead and complete these edges.
So connect those two lines also.
So you get a lot more of a tilted view of this shape.
So I really hope you guys are starting to get a really good idea of how form works.
Now let's go ahead and draw a object from real life and try to capture its form.
So I have my research here.
And what I'm gonna do is I'm going to flip my paper over and I'm going to set my eraser right here in
front of me and I'm going to draw for you guys.
OK.
So first off I'm noticing that there's this bottom line so I'm going to go ahead and draw that bottom
diagonal line like so.
And then the shape of the eraser is the first thing I want to do.
So I want to draw the side view of it so it goes up like this and this side does the same thing.
And then it connects over like so and then connects like this
and this may actually not be the best view of the eraser so when I tried this one I'm going to turn
my razor and try this you so I'm going to start off with my dad and a line and then I'm going to draw
two other diagonal lines like so and create that basic shape of my razor.
Then I'm going to go ahead and draw my lines going off in the opposite direction.
And I'll just connect all these lines and see that is the very basic shape of my razor if I want to
I can go ahead and round off all these corners some silver and a razor usually has pretty rounded corners
because it's all used up
and then I can even take my razor and go ahead and race away these unwanted areas.
Remember not to push too hard if you want to erase.
This is why I always recommend that you start out drawing lighter and then move to darker colors.
So there's the basic form from a real life object.
Now one last thing I want to go over with you guys before the end of this lecture is I want to go over
with you form in a sphere so sphere is just a ball and basically a sphere is just going to be a circle
without any highlights or shadows.
You're not going to know the difference between a circle and an actual sphere.
So let's say that we have a circle right here.
Now there are no edges that you can add to this circle.
So there's no way to really show that this is an actual three dimensional form without having highlights
or shadows to it.
But in the next lecture we're going to go ahead and learn how to add highlights and shadows to our forms
to make them look ten times more realistic.
All right.
That brings us to the end of this lecture.
So in this lecture you learn how to turn shapes into three dimensional forms.
So we learn how to make a cube which can also be translated into a rectangular cube.
If you stretch these lines out in either direction we also learn how to create a cone.
We learn how to create the pyramid of random shape and an organic shape.
Then we learn how to redraw these at different angles.
This is very important when you need when you're drawing out of your head is to understand how to draw
things in different angles.
The more you draw from life the more you're going to understand perspective and how to draw from those
different angles in the next lecture.
We're going to go ahead and learn how to add in those highlights and shadows.
Thanks for watching.
And I look forward to seeing you in the next lecture.