In this lecture we're going to be going over how to draw the human nose.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So the first thing I'd like to say is that when I'm drawing the human nose I like to think of it in
two different ways.
The first one is I'd like to think of it as a boomerang type shape.
So if you come right over here to the corner of my page and go ahead and draw the shape of my nose.
And this isn't the shape of the Internode.
This is the shape of the bottom of the nose and the shadow underneath it.
So if I draw a shape like that now I can go ahead and draw my nostrils and so my nostrils are basically
just going to be sort of raindrop type shapes and then I can go ahead and fill those in with a darker
value.
And then from there we can go ahead and fill the sheep in with a mid-tone of value.
So and then we have the sheep and the shadow of the bottom of the nose.
Now if you're not seen it yet let's go ahead and add some further detail.
So I'm going to go ahead and have an open like so and I'm like so and two lines underneath here and
now that makes up the bottom middle part of my nose.
And then I go ahead and also add in a line on this edge like so that then also comes up into my white
area.
And now I have a very basic nose I could go ahead and take that a little bit further by adding a little
bit more shading and sheep to my nose.
But that's the first way I like to think about the nose.
The next way I like to think about my nose is as three circles.
So let's go ahead and draw three circles.
So first off we have a large circle which is the center of her nose and we have our two circles on the
ends which make up these nostrils.
So go ahead and draw one right here and I'm going draw another one right there.
Now from here I can go ahead and draw my nose.
So if I want I can start off by creating that boomerang type sheep and then feeling that in
then I can go ahead and add in my nostrils
and then I can go ahead and add in some more shading more of a ledge to my nostrils and I can race away
anything up here that I was using as a guide but I no longer want to see.
So that's also a very basic way to draw nerves.
Now at the point of drawing with these three circles is this is how you can create the size of your
nose so if I wanted my nose to be bigger I could go ahead and draw my circle larger.
And then I can draw my two smaller circles larger two and I can change the placement of them to change
the shape of my nose so if I bring my circles more down towards the bottom like so now I have a different
shaped nose so I can go ahead and draw in my nostrils.
First off.
And then I can go ahead and draw in the bottom part of my nose and those can lead into my nostrils holes
then they can go ahead and draw in my boomerang shape.
And I can feel that in my head and some more shading and detailing and also a race the way these guidelines
but that's how you can treat different sized noses.
So I'd really encourage you to think about noses in these two simple shape ways by thinking of the bottom
of the nose as a shadow of that shape like a boomerang and then it's thinking of the main shape of the
nose as a large circle and then the two nostrils as two smaller circles that you can then go ahead and
further detail and add in your nostril holes the edge of your nostrils and in the main middle part of
the nostril.
Now let's go ahead and learn how to draw the nostrils from the front view.
So the knot goes all the way up to the brow of the face.
So first off what we're going to do is we're going to go ahead and start to sketch out our nose.
So we're going to start off with the nostrils them start off with the second nostril and the other side.
And then what we have is we have the middle part of our nose.
So first off we have this bottom area like we drew before over here and then we have the underside of
the nostril.
Now it's really important that when you're drawing the human face that you use the reference while you're
drawn
so there is the basic shape of the human nose.
Next what we need to do is we need to start adding in some valleys and shadows.
So starting with up here we need to add some padding values and shadows to shape the bridge of the nose.
So I'm going to go ahead and start adding some darker shadows down this edge and they start from the
corner of the eye and come all the way down to the bottom of the nose which then start to morph into
the shape of this middle part of the nose.
Now we can start shaping that by adding values underneath the nose and on the side of the nose.
And we'll continue to layer in that shading
then we can go ahead and start to Durkan in our nostril holes in the Nasra holes aren't always completely
black.
They usually start off really dark towards the top.
And as you get to the bottom of the nostril hole they start to lighten up a little bit.
So
next let's go ahead and add the shading on it this side of the nose on the underside.
And also there tends to be a little bit of a highlight on this ledge of the nostril holes will leave
a little bit of white right there to make it look more realistic.
This is why it's very important to use references because you'll see and pick up little things like
that.
Now let's go ahead and add some more shading underneath the larger part of the nose and we can have
some more shading under this part of the nose too.
And this is going to be our cast shadow because the light source is coming from the top.
That means it's going to be casting a shadow underneath the nose.
Now this doesn't have to be a very hard edged shadow we can go ahead and keep it pretty soft on the
edges.
And we'll continue to darken everything in.
So Mansome more shadow on this underside seam of this side.
Let me add a little bit of some light sheeting right crossed here.
Go ahead and add some more shading to these edges and also to this edge or an Austro.
And I think the bottom of her nose needs to be a little bit dark or something to go in there and add
some more shading like so then I need to go in there and read Durkan all of my previous shading.
So it still has that form and dimension.
Or grumped So there's a nose from the front view we can Durkan up here a little bit more if we like.
I'm just noticing in my reference that it's a little bit darker up there.
All right.
Great.
So now let's move on to drawing the news from a side view.
So it's important to know how to draw different parts of the face from every possible view because depending
on what type of drawn you're doing it you may find that you need to draw a nose from a different view.
So let's go ahead and draw one from the side view.
So first off we need to think of it as sort of a number seven.
Like we went over before a lot of people accidentally draw noses as 7s which is relatively close.
The thing is that the nose is actually broken up into much more of a shape than just a number seven.
So we want to draw an upside down Number Seven like so necessarily can do is we can go ahead and slice
off this corner right here and that's going to be this bottom plane of the nose.
So we slice that off.
Next we need to bring this line down just a little bit more of at an angle rather than being a straight
horizontal line and needs to be more angled and then that will curve into the upper part of the lip.
Then we need to go ahead and find out where the edge of her nostrils is going to be and our nostril
hole.
So you can start with whichever one you like.
I usually start with the not for Hole itself.
The noster hole tends to kind of go up just a little bit and then come back down and depending on whose
nose it is this hole could be longer or it could be shorter.
In this case it's going to be a little bit longer.
It's going to be a man's nostril hole and then we're going to go ahead and add the edge of our nose
or a nostril.
So it's going to start pretty close to that edge of the hole.
And as it gets out of here it's going to become wider.
Between that space and that's basically the side view of the nose depending on whose nose it says you
might have in this line or here either curve downwards or you might have it curved up like so or you
might have it a little bit weak.
So in this case we're going to make a little wavy.
So first it's going to come in like so.
So this becomes sort of one of its own shape right there.
And then it's going to come back out a little bit and then it's going to wave back in like so then we're
going to go ahead and add in the sheeting on the bottom part of the nose.
So in this case we just want to basically draw a line underneath this bottom area and we can go ahead
and shoot that in with a mid-tone value.
We can also add a little bit of that cache underneath and then we can go ahead and start darkening in
the shadow underneath our nostril.
Gripped next what we want to do is we want to go ahead and start adding some more shading in along this
edge right here so that we start to get the form of this part of the nose and then we can also add some
shading on this back edge.
And again I'm looking at reference so I have a good idea of where I want my lights and shadows to be
I'm going to add a little bit more of a shadow along this under edge and above my nostril hole.
And then I'm a go ahead and curve this line out a little bit more and soften it.
Sometimes you don't like your lines to be too hard.
Go ahead and it's more shooting underneath here.
Then I might add a little bit of sheeting along this edge
on groups.
So now we have the side view of the nuns.
Now the last thing I want to show you how to draw is a one to show you how to draw a nose from a sort
of 45 degree angle.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So the first thing we need to do is we need to understand that you're going to see more of one side
of the nose than the other.
So basically we're going to break it up into first off our basic three circle so there's the first one
there's the next one and then there's the other one.
But you'll see that this one is a little bit more behind this Surt larger circle than this one.
That's because we're looking at it more from this angle.
So now we can go ahead and start adding in our detail.
So first off we're going to start with the main sheet of the nose.
But since we're looking at it from the side we're going to get a mix between these two views so we're
going to see a little bit of this angle and a little bit of that.
And so we to go ahead and add that in.
So we get sort of that kind of a shape and then that turns into the bottom of our nostril and then we
can go ahead and add in our second nostril like so.
And then this bottom shape is going to turn into our nostril hole and then this bottom shape right here
doesn't actually turn into unalterable or an ulcer hole actually starts up here.
You know we can go ahead and add that in and fill it in a little bit.
Perfect.
Next let's go ahead and finish out the shape of this nostril on this side and then let's go ahead and
add and a little bit of a guideline or here for that side of the nose.
Now this looks kind of funny but once we start adding in our shading it will look much better.
So what we want to do is we want to start off by adding the shading on the bottom side of the nose and
some people's nose are split up into sort of two separate shapes so one on the side and one on the side.
In this case our nose is going to be like that.
So our shadow starts to come up into that sheet a little bit and then we're going to go ahead and add
the sheep on this other side where the shooting on that side we're going to go ahead and add some shading
on the underside of the nose and on this side of the nostril.
Go ahead and shoot all the way over and then we can add in a little bit of a cast a shadow on this side.
Great.
Next let's go ahead and add in a little bit more of the bridge of our nose up here.
So we're just going to add a little bit of the line right there and then over here we're going to add
a little bit of some dirt or shadowing you might bring that wine over a little bit more bring that shot
I mean all the way down to here great then I'm going go ahead and erase away a little bit of that guideline
that I had for the shape and that we can really start determining things.
So starting with my Nasra whole I'm going to Durgan that in scene with the other side.
So then go ahead and d'Argent that in.
And then I want to go ahead and start adding some more sheeting in here and during some of the areas
and adding some lighter shading up here in this lighter area just so we can sort of create some more
fair.
All right.
Great.
So now we have the nose from a 45 degree angle.
That brings us to the end of this lecture.
So in this lecture we learn how to draw the human nose first we learned to look at it as a boomerang
type shape.
Now this boomerang type shape is the shape of the bottom of the shadow of the nose.
I find that this is the simplest way to think of the nose into roughly sketched in the nest when we
learned about to think of the nose is by drawing three circles a large circle for the middle and two
smaller circles for the nostrils.
Then we learned how to draw the nose from the front view the side view and a threequarters view.
Now your assignment for this lecture is to go ahead and draw at least one knows but I recommended that
you draw at least five different noses from reference images.
Then post one of those to the Q&amp;A section of the Course or the Facebook group.
Thanks for watching and I'm really look forward to seeing you in the next election.
We're we're going to learn how to draw the human mouth.