All right in this lecture we're going to learn how to do one point perspective.
Now what is perspective.
Well perspective is just creating the illusion of three dimensional space by using lines.
Now the great thing about perspective is that it can very accurately portrayed this 3-D space by using
this technique.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So the first thing we want to do is we want to grab our ruler.
Once we have our ruler we need to decide where we're going to put our horizon line.
So our horizon line is just where the sky meets the earth.
It's that line.
So if you can go outside right now and look out there if you see the mountains or anything that's in
the way it's not really going to work.
But if you can see all the way off at the end of a street or something at that very point that is the
horizon line.
And so we need to figure out where that line is.
Now the higher our horizon line is the more it's going to look like we're looking down on the object
the lower It is the more it's going to look like we're looking up at.
So for example we're going to put it right about in the middle of our page and we're just going to go
ahead and lightly draw that in.
We don't want it to dark because this isn't an actual permanent one.
And then what we need to do is we need to make one point.
So since this is called one point perspective that's because we use one point to create this perspective.
And what this point is it's the vanishing point.
So everything goes back to this point and vanishes.
So if you go out and stand on the middle of the street and you look all the way down to the end of the
street you'll notice that it all comes down to one point and it's long enough you'll see that the street
just eventually disappears and becomes so small that you can't even see it anymore.
That's the vanishing point.
OK.
And so from this vantage point we can draw any line we want out of it and use that as a guide to try
to draw shapes.
So let's go ahead and try an example.
So if we take a ruler and put on our vanishing point then we can go out and draw a line coming off that
vanishing point.
And we want to keep this line pretty light.
Got a little dark there but make sure you keep your lines light when you're drawing this because you're
going to want to come back and erase it.
So now we have two lines that are going after vanishing point.
The next thing we can do is we can go ahead and draw a vertical line like so.
And this one can be darker because we're actually going to leave that there.
And then we can draw another one right next to it.
So put another one right here.
Perfect.
And then what we want to do is we want to draw a horizontal line coming off of this corner right there
and then we'll do the same thing over here and try to make about the same distance or length.
And I'm going to go ahead and connect those two.
So connectome like so perfect.
And then we can go ahead and draw on this edge right there and we can go ahead and draw on this edge
right there.
So now we have a cube in perspective.
Now if this is still really confusing you can go ahead and draw a line from this corner to that one
and you can draw a line from this corner to our vanishing point.
And then you can go ahead and create a horizontal line connecting this back area right there.
And also this back area right here.
So now you've kind of created.
And we want to make sure we connect these arrays here perfect.
So now you've created sort of a transparent box.
Now what you want to do now is you want to go ahead and race away the vanishing point lines.
These don't really appear in real life.
We're just using those as a guide.
So now we have our clear cube.
And then if you wanted it to be a solid cube that you couldn't see through you can go ahead and erase
these lines back here.
On the other side of our queue.
And then you're left with a solid 1 cube and we can go ahead and draw these lines in a little bit darker
but this can be applied to any area of our page.
So let's say we wanted to make a square cube out here at the top.
Well all we have to do is first off we're going to go ahead and draw our square like so and then we
have to do is draw a vanishing point line from each corner to our vanishing point.
So we'll go ahead drawing from there to there and we'll draw another one from this corner to our vanishing
point.
And then one more from this corner to our vanishing point.
And then we just want to connect a vertical line like so and then from that seemed to me right here
on the corner of a connect a horizontal line.
So and then we just want to draw these lines and Dharker and then we can go ahead and erase away these
lines out here.
Or I can see that now we have two different cues and they're in the same perspective.
They're just in different positions.
And so this one is on the right side of our vanishing point.
And so we see more of this left side of our box.
Now this cube is on the left side of our vanishing point.
And so we see the right side of this box.
And so depending on where it is you'll see different faces.
So let's try one more because I want to show you how if you put one down here you can even see the top
of your box.
So if I go ahead and draw a square just like so I can go ahead and create a cube by drawing my line
from there to there and you can use a ruler.
But I'm pretty confident in my line drawing abilities so I can go ahead and do it by hand and draw a
line from there to there.
They're there with your head and you race away these vanishing point line
and so you can see we can see the top surface of this cube.
But since it's right in the middle underneath are vanishing point we can't even see either sides of
it we only see the front plane and the top plane.
Now I want to show you one more thing.
You can create this perspective with any shape so you can create it with a triangle and can create it
with a circle.
So all you have to do is draw your shape.
So if we draw a circle or a here for example and we draw a triangle over here when all we have to do
is we have to just go ahead and connect each corner of our sheep to our vanishing point.
So we'll go ahead and draw that in.
So went from there there.
And it went from there to there.
Same with our circle.
So on from there to there.
And then another one from that edge all the way to her vanishing point.
And then we just want to create the other side of our shape so this edge over here and all we're going
to do is we're going to copy this Edric here to over here.
So go ahead and draw that in.
And then we can solidify these two lines.
Same with our circles so wherever we want our circle edge to end we can go out and copy that edge over
like so and then we can go ahead and solidify these two lines and then I'm going to go ahead and erase
away my vanishing point lines.
All right.
So this should give you a pretty good idea of how one point perspective works.
In our next lecture we're going to go ahead and actually draw a picture with real life objects so you
can understand better how one point perspective works.
Thanks for watching today's lecture.
And I look forward to seeing you in tomorrow's.