All right in this lecture we're going to go over how to add contrast Sheir drawings.
So we know that contrast is use to create highlights and shadows but it's also used to create contrasts
just to make your images visually pleasing.
And the way you do this is by making sure that you have darker things next to lighter things.
So right now we're going to go ahead and add contrast to this character by adding values.
So I've drawn this character up and I drew him up really quick here.
He wasn't very well thought out but I thought it was kind of a little funny idea that a futuristic boy
on a hovering platform.
And so we're going to go ahead and add some contrast to this.
So we're going to start off with his hair so I know I want his hair to be darker and that means that
his skin should probably be lighter not in every case but just for demonstration purposes we want to
try to create as much contrast in this drawing as possible.
So starting with his hair going to go ahead and fill that and darker
like so and then I can go ahead and re draw those contouring lines back in just so we can see him a
little bit better.
Perfect.
Then we know that since this is darker we want to make as much contrast as possible so whatever is next
to it needs to be light.
So we're going to keep his skin pretty light we might add a little bit of shading in there on the side
of him and underneath his neck.
And then we might even add sort of some rosy cheeks in there like so maybe even as sort of a rosy nose.
All right.
Perfect.
Now let's go ahead and move on to the shirt.
So sensus skin is lighter.
We know that we want his shirt to be darker.
So we're going to go ahead and fill this all in with a darker color but then that brings us to the graphic
on his t.
So we want more contrast here.
And so the graphic want to see he is going to be a lighter color so we're going to leave that point.
You had and add those contouring lines back in.
But even darker so that we can see them
perfect.
And then with his arms there going to be the same color as the skin on his face.
So he can go ahead and add just a little bit of sheeting underneath this underside.
So let's go ahead and move onto the paint.
So since the shirt is pretty dark we want to make sure that our pants are pretty light so they don't
have to be super light.
We just want a contrast between this edge and that edge.
So let's go ahead and fill us in with a light grey.
So go ahead and add in that country line so it's much darker
you know when we get down here to where his his pant legs are rolled up we're going to leave those completely
white because we want to make contrasts between this area and the pants.
And then when we get to the shoes we want contrast between this white area and the shoes.
So let's go ahead and fill those in with a black.
Same with the shoe.
Just like so.
And now I'm noticing we're creating too much contrast down here.
And this is becoming the focal point.
And so what we want to do is we want to make his face the focal points we need to make more contrast
up there.
The way we'll do that is by adding Durka shadow up here.
Like so.
So now we have a lot of contrast between the bottom edge of his hair and his skin and then down here
we can actually go ahead and fill these in with a light gray because it's better that there's no contrast
between this and that and this not become the focal point.
Then this not being the focal point and that being white.
So you want to make sure that you're thinking about what you want your focal point to be.
And that's really the main thing that matters.
Next let's move onto this platform.
So the top surface of this platform can have a little bit of shadow on it from the boy standing on it.
And then this other underside is going to be filled in with a light gray
and then this under here can be filled in with a darker gray
then we can go ahead and add in those contrarian lines.
All right.
That brings us to the end of this lecture.
So the main takeaway I want you to have from this lecture is that any time you can put contrasting values
next to each other do it.
So basically you need to pick something on your drawing that you know what you want the value to be
and then base everything else off of that.
So for example we knew we wanted his hair to be black.
So we knew that a skin should most likely be lighter.
Now we knew because of that his shirt should most likely be darker because it's right next to his skin.
And then we knew that because his shirt was darker that his pants needed to be lighter and because his
pants were lighter we knew that his shoes needed to be darker.
Thanks for watching this lecture and I really look forward to seeing you in the next one where we're
going to be talking about space.
Space is super important when you're trying to create drawings and atmospheres.
So I look forward to seeing you in that lecture.