All right in this lecture we're going to break the face down into simple geometrical forms.
So just like all images can be broken down into simple 2-D shapes like we saw in previous lectures.
We can also break everything down into simple geometrical forms.
So let's go ahead and try this.
So first off we're going to start off with the nose so the nose is basically a number seven.
A lot of people like to think of it that way from the side.
But there's a lot more to it than that.
So first let's go ahead and create sort of a cube shape that will represent our nose.
So this is the first shape that the nose can be broken down into.
So we got one point right there.
Another one right here which kind of tapers off as you get to the top.
And then this one right here.
So it's sort of a cube shape but it has more rounded edges and it has some more tape and so tapers off
towards the top here and tapers off towards the top here and also tapers off.
On this plane towards the top.
Now you may not see where the form of the nose is right here but we're going to take it a step further
and add that form.
So from here you could go ahead and draw your nose.
So you'd put one nostril where here let's say and then you could put another nostril right here.
So maybe like so.
All right.
So there are nostrils.
You can go ahead and fill those in with some shadow and then next you can go ahead and add the top part
of the nostrils so they'd be top hurried here.
And then you'd add the tip of your nose right here
and then you can go ahead and add a little bit more of a shape to your nose.
And more of the rounded bottom here.
All right.
So now we have a lot more form in our nose a lot more organic form.
And now we can go ahead and add some highlights and shadows to that.
Take it a step further.
So on this bottom area we would have a shadow so let's go ahead and add in that shadow.
And this is this is saying that our light source come from the top and hitting it coming down like so.
So we can go ahead and added shadow there and then this round area of the nose is going to be where
our shadow starts to soften into our highlight.
Now we can also add shadow on this side or this plane of our nose.
And then since this is the top area of that part of the nose it's probably gonna be getting hit by a
little bit of light also.
And then we can go ahead and add in a little bit darker shadows in there too.
So don't go ahead and hide in the dark shadow right there in a darker shadow here.
Sake's so I'm going to stretch that nostril out a little bit more.
Same with this one.
And stretch it over a little bit more.
You can add a little bit more shadow over here.
All right.
Perfect.
Then like we said before I explain how News Craig cast shadows.
So we want to make sure that we add a cast shadow to this so we're going to go ahead and add that cache
right there.
And just to keep this simple for now I'm going to only do the nose and to leave the lips out.
But really there should be lips underneath this nose that the cash out has been cast onto.
All right.
Great.
So now we have a nose.
Now that's not a perfect nose by any means but I just wanted to get the point across that there is form
in everything including the human face.
Now let's try something else.
So if we go back to our drawing if you remember we had her eye sir.
I was something like so and obviously there is a sphere and so you can basically add a shadow in like
a sphere.
But what I want to show you is I want to show you the form on this eyebrow piece above the eye.
So we would have her eyebrow probably somewhere about here.
All right.
But then this brow piece it also has some form.
So basically a brow piece comes out.
If we're looking at it from the side it comes out like so and then it goes back into the cavernous part
of the eye where the eyeball is held and then we have the cheek bone.
And so we need to create this form up here right here.
So what does that look like.
In simple geometrical form.
Well it's basically a shape like this so we have one plane like this and it kind of curves around like
so.
That's her eyelid right there.
And then we have a plane like this no draw this really lightly.
And then we have in another plane like that and then that whole sort of smooths out like so let me have
a top surface like this.
So I'm going to go ahead and erase away my eyebrows.
You can see what's going on here a little bit better.
But basically this area right here is going to get filled in with shadow now depending on the person.
This shape can be different but basically this is the basic overall idea of the form of the borowe piece
and this area tends to get a little bit darker depending on where your light source is coming from and
in this case the light source is coming from the top.
In this area will get a little bit lighter
then this surface is going to be our highlight area.
And so we're going to leave that highlight it but then we can go ahead and start planning this all in
together.
So it has a nice nice smooth transition.
And then we can go ahead and just add in our eyelid really quick.
And you see how you can take a organic form and then you can see how you can take a geometric form and
then take it into more of an organic shape which is very important when you're creating artwork if you
don't understand how to do that.
It's going to be very difficult for you to create things out of your head.
We want to get back into how to draw the human eye.
We'll just stick with the brown for now.
But you can see we just created that brow from that geometrical form.
Now let's try one more thing.
Let's try it.
The human head itself.
So the human head can be broken down into a very basic shape.
So first it's broken down into a sphere but then on that sphere you have the front flap part of the
face.
So we can go ahead and abat sheep in like so and it basically smooths into the actual sphere.
So now we can go ahead and erase away that area.
But then we want to connect in this area which is going to be the jaw line into here like so then we
can go ahead and erase that.
And so basically we have a shape like this that's connecting into our sphere and that makes up the basic
human shape of the head.
So let's go ahead and add in some highlight and shadow to this.
So if I have a light right here and it's shutting down like so I can go ahead and add in my core Shanno
so going out and core shadow on this side and right along the edge.
That can be a little bit more of a harder edge but as we get up to our actual sphere we want that to
begin to soften a lot.
So it's going to soften into our mid-tone chateau
like so
but now we have the basic shape of the human form.
You can even add a neck in there if you want two sets of really skinny neck will do that.
So you could add a neck in there.
You could even add the chest area which would basically be a rectangular cube in which then you could
round off and add more form to it to create the correct human form.
But basically what I want you to see is that everything can be broken down into basic geometrical shapes
and usually just like when you're drawing an image where you start with your basic shapes then I want
you to break it down into more of geometrical forms.
So let's say this is our character.
OK.
Well now I want you to break that down into more geometrical forms.
And so what you would do is you would turn the square into more of a cube let's say.
So it's more three dimensional and you can turn this into a cube to
and then let's say his hands were down here and you could turn those into more spheres and add the shadow
into it depending on where the light was coming from.
But I want you to start viewing things as geometrical forms.
So once he starts seeing things as shapes the next step is to start seeing things as geometrical forms.
All right that brings us to the end of this lecture.
So in this lecture you learn how to break the human face down in a geometrical forms in the next one
we're going to go ahead and create a landscape drawing out a geometrical forms.
So you just have one more example of how to break things down into geometrical forms and start from
geometrical forms.
When you began your drawings.
Thanks for watching and I look forward to seeing you in the next lecture.