Here, we have the beginnings of the Crypto Portfolio demo application.
It's a simple Spring Boot MVC application,
not unlike the ones you probably see in many starter tutorials.
Currently, it has one controller and a simple Thymeleaf HTML page that prints,
Welcome to your portfolio.
One of the non‑functional security requirements for this application is
that it must support social login with Facebook or Google.
Now, generally, developers would leave this for a later date.
But with Spring Security and Spring Boot,
we can add Facebook and Google sign‑in right now with only a few
simple steps by simply adding the OAuth2 client
spring‑boot‑starter dependency and then in our application.yml
file or your application.properties file,
we add the oauth2.client.registration for Facebook,
we add under oauth2, client, registration,
facebook, providing the client ID and secret.
The client ID and secret are like the credentials for your application.
You get these when you first register your application with Facebook,
so let's go through the steps of how you would do that.
Now, if you navigate to the Facebook for Developers page,
under My Apps, Build Collected Experiences,
give the app a name, select Facebook Login, Web,
okay, that's it, save these changes, and if we go back to our application,
go to the Settings,
and you can copy and paste the client ID and secret
into the application.yml file.
That's it.
And because the application has the DevOps dependency,
Spring Boot notices that we made a change and restarts the application for us.
Now, we get prompted with Facebook credentials,
and now you can continue developing your application.
Of course, the security implementation is far from production ready,
but neither is our web app and the application security can
now evolve along with the application rather than a Russian
hack job at a later date.
Now, the Spring team have done a really good job here.
If you're like me, however, you're probably scratching your head and wondering,
how is all this working?
How did Spring Security configure all this? OAuth2,
is an authorization protocol, so how does it do authentication? Next, let's answer these questions by taking a closer look at OAuth2.