You can download the latest version of Keycloak from their web page.
Unzip it in a folder of your choice.
To run it, in the bin directory,
run the following command with the following Java
argument to set the port to 8081, as by default,
it uses port 8080, and that clashes with our demo application.
If it's the first time you are accessing it,
you will need to set up an admin username and password.
The Keycloak GUI is very comprehensive.
You can do everything here.
The first thing we need to do is create our realm.
A realm represents a set of users, credentials, roles, clients, and groups.
You can configure many realms, but each one is isolated from one another.
Now, in the new realm, you can set up your application as a client of Keycloak,
giving it a name, protocol, in this case,
we'll be using OpenID Connect,
for Access Type set confidential as our application is a
multi‑page application and runs server side,
hence it can securely store the client ID and secret.
Next, we set the redirect URI.
If you recall, this is the path of the authorization endpoint within Spring,
more specifically,
the OAuthLoginAuthenticationFilter looks out for requests to this path.
It's when the authorization server has authenticated the user,
got their consent, and then redirected the user's browser back to the client,
to this path, along with the authorization code,
which Spring can then use against the token endpoint
to exchange for the access token, you can add multiple redirect URIs here,
but Keycloak will only redirect to a URI white‑listed here.
Now, this is to prevent any injection attacks, like someone trying to change
the redirect URI via a malicious browser plug‑in perhaps, as, if you recall,
the authorization redirect request initially sent to Keycloak from our client
included the desired redirect URI the application wants Keycloak to send the
authorization code to after the user is authenticated, hence this is a kind of
added security measure.
Save. Okay, job done.
We now have our application registered as a client with Keycloak.
In the Credentials tab,
you can see, we have a Client ID and Secret as we selected a
confidential type. We now can create a user,
Victoria, set the first and last name, give her an email,
let's also give her a password, okay, done. Next, let's configure our application to use our new authorization server.