Welcome to Section 8 of the complete web developer course I have you enjoyed working with Wordpress
and you've already started building a shop or a blog or some other site using the platform and this
section will be returning to the more serious coding side of PH P ph pay as I said a language which
means it does a lot more than javascript can.
It can do things like send emails or connect to a database or process a contact form.
We'll start off by looking at the basics of programming in HP.
So that is things like for loops variables and arrays and if statements and then we'll be looking at
some of those specific features.
Moving on to creating a weather scraper where the user will be able to type in their location and get
the weather for that location.
So there's a lot to learn.
It's an exciting section and I hope you enjoy working with HP.