Welcome to Section 13 of the complete web developer course I hope you enjoyed working with a team of
5 and CSSA three and seeing some of the great features that we can use from those in our web sites and
web apps in this section we're going to return it to a server side language and we're going to be looking
specifically at Python.
Python is a great language for new coders to learn because it's so clean and well-thought-out.
We can also use it on a huge range of different platforms that works on a web server but you can also
use it on say a Raspberry Pi or an order window to allow you to build Internet of things experiences
for your users.
So it should be pretty straightforward to get to grips with.
We'll start with the basics of how Python works and how you get a Python script up and running and then
we'll go on to look at some of the specific Python features and we'll be making a fun game with Python
as well.
So enjoy the section and as always I'll see at the beginning of the next one.