Welcome to Section 3 of the complete web developer course I have you enjoyed the last section.
I now understand how a basic web site is put together with regards to HDMI out in this section will
be moving on to CSX or cascading style sheets which is all about styling your web sites and making them
look right.
We'll start by saying what a cascading style sheet is and how we integrate it into our pages and then
we'll look at some of the specific features that styling text images layout and a whole lot more.
At the end of the section we'll be making our biggest project yet which will be a clone of the BBC at
the same time.
I hope you're working your way through my book How to earn $10000 while learning to code.
And once again looking at how you can put the skills that you're learning already into action.
Enjoy the section and I'll see you at the beginning of the next one.