Congratulations on making it to Section 7 of the complete web developer course I really enjoyed working
with bootstrap and managed to make a good looking landing page for your app or business.
At the end of it in this section we'll be looking at something quite different and that is a package
called WordPress.
Wordpress is a content management system or CMOS So it allows you to build a good looking Web site very
very quickly and you can edit and update it without actually knowing any code at all.
So if you're building a web site for a friend or colleague or a client then doing it in wordpress means
that they can update and edit it without needing to come back to you to change the code.
WordPress also has a massive plug in and thene ecosystem which allows you to build a great looking website
with just a few clicks and add powerful functionality like logging systems contact forms and even a
whole social network just by installing a plugin.
We'll see how to do a number of those things and we'll be working with a particular premium theme in
this section.
We'll be making a blog a shop and the challenge at the end of it will be to make a complete Web site
of your own using WordPress.
So a whole new world will open up to you in this section.
Wordpress is a great way to build web sites for friends and family colleagues or clients.
So do be still reading through my book How to and ten thousand dollars will and Kate coming up with
great website ideas.
And then using WordPress to put them together really quickly.
As always tweet me what you've made and I'll forward it to the world.
Enjoy getting to grips with Wordpress and I'll see you at the beginning of the next section.