Light.
So we're now moving on from head of tags to look at paragraph tax.
Now you might be wondering why we need paragraph tags.
If we look at some standard text
just like that you can see it looks pretty normal.
And then if we put paragraph tags around it which you might remember are just a P for paragraph and
then we can manually put in the slash Peter end the paragraph tag.
If we then have a look at that.
It doesn't actually have any different.
The paragraph tag doesn't restyle the text at all.
So what's the point.
Well let's go back to how it is some text and now what if we want to put some text on the next line
down.
Well you would have thought we could just do that and put it on the next line down in our text document.
Let's have a look.
No.
So line breaks as they are known new lines in our text don't actually become new lines on the Web site
itself.
So we have to manually put new lines in.
There are two ways to do that and I'll show you both of them now.
The first one is to surround both of our lines of text with paragraph tags like that.
So there's our first
paragraph and there's our second paragraph.
So if we now save that and refresh then they are on separate lines.
So that's one use of the paragraph tag to give us a new line.
It also makes our code look better because we can see very clearly that we expect these to be separate
paragraphs and we might want to apply different formatting to each paragraph as we'll see how to do
in the next video.
There is another way to put text on a new line and I'll show you that now.
So if we have a third paragraph let's have some text with a line break just like that.
And if we want to put a line break in the middle we use the tag B or like that which is short for Boik
or line break.
And let's just have a look and see what that looks like.
You can see we've now got a line break where the tag is but it's slightly different to the new paragraph.
So it's not a full new paragraph because we don't have that gap in between.
But we do have the text on a new line so they do slightly different things.
The paragraph tag and the tag and you could imagine in different situations you might want new paragraphs
or just a line break like that.
One thing to notice about the are targets the first tag that we've met that doesn't have a closing tag
associated with it.
There are going to be a few more that we'll see along our journey.
So be our is what's known as a self-closing tag because it's just a line break it doesn't surround anything.
You may also see the art with a slash in it like that.
And this is when you're using X HTL mail which you don't really need to worry about at this point but
you can look up if you want to know more about it.
It's essentially a very precise version of aged him that you might want to use in some circumstances
and that would have a slash right there in the tag itself.
But with age DML and HVM are five you don't need to use that.
So you should just use be like we've got there.
So that's how you use paragraph tags and line breaks.
Now you're really getting up to speed with HD M-L in the next video we'll see how to customize our text
to change its look and style within a paragraph.
So you then.