Loops along with if statements are one of the fundamental ways of affecting the flow of your code modern
computer programs simply wouldn't be possible without loops.
And it's pretty easy to imagine where they might be used for example when your G-mail is showing you
all of your emails.
That's a loop because it's looping through all of the emails that it finds in the database and then
displaying them to you.
So loops are definitely something you're going to need to get to grips with.
And I'm going to start by showing you the follow.
So we start off with our FOR loop.
Exactly as in Javascript.
And then if you remember in javascript we start off by creating our counter variable which usually we
call something like I and setting it equal to its initial value.
So we do exactly the same in Page Pate.
We set I is equal to zero.
Then as in javascript we set the conditions for the loop to continue.
So we might want to keep going as long as I is less than 10 for example.
And then once we've got the initial condition and the condition for the loop to be true we set the rule
for what happens to each time it goes around the loop and the usual one which hopefully I remember is
I plus plus which is another way of saying increment I buy one or increase by one each time.
So that's how we define our loop.
And then I'm just going to display each item in the loop separated by a line break.
All right.
So a very quick question for you.
Can you tell me what values will actually be displayed on the page when I run that code.
Did you get it.
Take a look.
So starting with 0 of course and then increasing by 1 each time.
And we don't get the 10 that was maybe the slightly tricky part of the question because this keeps going
as long as it's less than 10.
If we wanted to include 10 then we would have to change that to less than or equal to.
All right.
Another quick challenge can you change this so that we get all the even numbers from 2 to 30 inclusive
all the even numbers from 2 to 30 inclusive different.
Did you get it.
We just need to start at 2.
Keep going as long as I'm less than or equal to 30 and then increase I by two every time.
And the command for that is that say I equals I plus two and that should give us 2 4 6 8 all the way
up to 30 just to change everything around a little bit.
Can you do a count down from 10 to zero.
So all the way down from 10 to 0.
Ten nine eight seven six five four three two one zero.
Go for it.
OK.
So you got that.
So we want to start at 10.
We want to keep going as long as I is greater than or equal to zero.
And then we want to decrease one by eye every time and we can actually do that using minus minus something
like 10 on it's of his ex-wife or three two one zero.
Great.
OK.
So one of the most useful uses of for loops is looping through arrays and that's the couple of examples
that I gave you were looping through tweets or emails.
They would likely be stored as arrays on the server which was providing them to you.
And we can use for loops to do that.
So let's set up our good old family right.
Can't go wrong.
We're up Kersten Tommy and Ralphie.
And in fact also this is a little challenge so can you set up a for loop just like this which displays
each of the values of family in 10 different.
All right.
How did you manage that.
You should have done something like creating and setting it equal to zero initially.
And we want to keep going as long as pie is less than.
So this is going to be 0 1 2 3.
So we want to keep going as long as I is less than four or alternatively we could use size of and family
bonus points if you did it that way because that's more flexible because it allows us to add I add people
to the family or indeed remove them.
And this code will still work.
So well on a few If you did that and then we just increment i each time and then to display them.
We use family and then we want the youth one each time and we have a line break in them as well.
There we go.
So that's how to do it with a for loop.
But there's a really nice alternative method which actually my favorite type of loop in HP and that
is the foreach which basically builds this in so you don't have to write out all those fiddly settings
every time.
And the for loop works like this.
So we take out a right family and we want to loop through it as.
And then we specify the variables that we want to contain the key or the index.
And then this our symbol again equals and greater than
and value.
So what this will do is it will loop through all of the items in the family array and we can do something
with them involving their key and their value.
So if I just want to display them for example then I could say
all right I am and then key is and then follow you.
And that will loop through all of them and give us both the key of the index and the value.
Let's put a line break in the
Geiser array item 0.
Is Robert rafted one is Caston et cetera.
And that's not only a great way to display the items in an array.
You can also use it to amend them or change them in some way.
So if I wanted to pop the surname onto each of these in fact see if you can work out how to do that
can you add Percival to the end of each of these names in one line within this for each loop.
Go for it.
OK.
So all it is is we'd find family
and key and this will get the one that we're working with at the moment and we want to set about equal
to a value and then we append to that Percival
and that's it.
So that we'll get the value as it was and append Percival to it and then save that to the array itself.
Let's have a look.
Great.
So you notice it hasn't appended it up here because this value was what we had before.
But it has appended it when we loop through the second time just like that.
Great.
So we'll be using foreach loops a lot as we go through arrays and especially when working with series
of items in databases for example.
But there is a third type of leap that I want to show you which again is particularly useful when it
comes to databases and that is the while loop.