Or I just need to look at a couple of things before we can do our disappearing circles challenge and
that is how we can manipulate styles with Javascript.
So far we've been manipulating content mostly by changing this in HCM L. var..
But we can do the same with styles.
So let's add a paragraph.
Call it more text and we'll have the very boring.
This is some text.
So that's not going to be styled at all.
Let's create a button with an ID of style text
and we'll have the text style text on it.
Obviously it doesn't do anything yet.
But now let's add some code for that button.
And just the same way document or get element by id and the element that we want to get is the style
text button.
And then we want to add an on click function to that.
So this is going to be a function with Kelly brackets.
And then what we want to do is just add some style to the more text paragraph.
So for example when want go through the process get element by id and then we want to get this time
is more text and then instead of in a HMO we do style.
And then for example if we want to change the color to red we would have dot style color equals.
And then in quites read simple as that.
Now let's have a look.
Style text.
It goes red.
Fantastic.
Changing the font size is very similar but slightly trickier because it's not exactly the same.
We don't use font size because we don't like that hyphen in the javascript we just use font size instead.
So that's using the capitalization similar to get element by id small f but then capital S and let's
say we want to make it a font size of 50 pixels that's how I look.
And again it's massive and so feel free to play around with that but obviously combine several styles
if you want but just having multiple commands like this.
But the particular other one I want to show you which we're going to be using in our disappearing circles
challenge is to make it disappear and we can do that by setting the display property to none.
So as you can imagine that just sets the CSSA display property to none which effectively makes it disappear.
Let's check it out.
There we go.
It's gone.
It's not even just disappeared.
But it's actually been removed from the flow of the page.
And so the button moves up as a result.
So feel free to get creative and play around to see what styles you can affect with Javascript.
But we're going to go on now to our mini challenge disappearing circles.