Now that you're familiar with all the basic programming concepts in Python and hopefully are starting
to love its brevity and clarity I'm going to show you how to create functions in Python to organize
your code and keep it lean and easily updatable.
We've used functions before but not a great deal so here we'll also spend a bit of time talking about
variables and parsing them to functions and getting the values back from functions and also we'll introduce
an idea called scope which is about whether a variable is accessible within a certain chunk of code.
But one step at a time.
Let's define a function first off and to define the function we use death.
So I'm going to have a function called say hello and then we use as we've seen before a pair of parentheses
to define our function.
And later on we might put some values inside those parentheses but not quite yet.
And then as usual we use the colon and indenting to represent what goes inside that function.
And for now we'll just print hello.
Simple as that.
And then when we want to say hello we just call the say hello function.
Sometimes I just can't get out of the habit of writing semi-colons.
All right.
So that's how functions are defined and called what if we want to pass a value to a function.
So by that I mean we might want to have a function say something where instead of saying hello every
time we just print out whatever the program once at the time.
Well to do that we need to accept a string which we could call whatever we like call it something and
then we would just print that string and then when we call the function we would use say something.
If you spell something right and then
we could put whatever we liked in that string
that we get.
So what we're doing now is we're passing a variable from our function call to the function itself which
can be very useful.
It makes it much more useful than a function which only does one thing regardless of how it's called.
We can also define functions that return certain results.
So let's say we had a function that multiply two numbers together.
So let's call it multiply two numbers.
And then if we wanted to accept 2 numbers with the function call then we might call those two numbers
x and y
and then we would return x multiplied by Y.
So returning means we return to the function call a certain value or even multiple values.
In some cases and then to print the result of that we might do something like print
multiply two numbers
for comma six and that would then give us the result 24.
So this is really the full definition of a function.
So the function takes certain values and then does something with them and returns a value.
So a challenge for you then.
While we're in I see mode with our prime numbers.
Can you create a function called highest
common factor.
Which returns the highest
number that divides into two of the numbers.
Exactly.
So what I mean there is if I call this function with 4 and 6 it would return 2 because 2 is the biggest
number that goes into 4 and 6.
If I call that with 8 and 10 it will also return to if I called it with 10 and 15 it would return 5
because 5 is the biggest number that goes into 10 and 15.
That's the challenge you're going to need a definition similar to this and probably a loop and some
if statements as well.
Go for it.
All right.
How have you managed it.
We get them to define our function we'll use death and highest common factor.
And I use the same numbers as before x and y and then I'm going to create a loop which will be a for
loop and we'll have an AI which will start at 1.
So we're going to look at a range of 1 and go up to x
plus 1 because we're going to be using this loop to search for numbers which divide into both x and
y.
So if we go from 1 all the way up to x inclusive which is why we need the plus 1 x we want to include
X because it could be that X is 5 and Y is 10 and therefore 5 is actually the highest common factor
because 5 guys into by five and 10.
So we want to include X itself in our search.
Then we want to check to see if I goes into X which we get to by looking at x percent is equal to zero.
So that's the remainder when X is divided by is equal to zero.
And we want why present I to be able to zero to say if that's true we'll set HCF to be equal to that
number.
And notice we'll always get a result here because we're starting off with I being one and it goes into
every hole number.
So we'll start off with HCF being one.
And then as I get bigger and bigger that might make HCF bigger and bigger as well.
And then we get out of the if statement out of the for loop.
And then within our highest common factor function definition we return HCF.
All right let's take a look.
Say print highest common factor and let's try four and six.
And there we go.
It's got to try a couple of the other examples that we had five and 10
five fantastic and 10 and 15 was the other example we had five as well.
Wonderful.
You managed to do that.
The last thing I want to show you is this idea of scope and that is where a variable is defined.
So to see how this idea of scope works let's go back through and multiply two numbers function and we'll
define a slightly different function this one will have that two numbers.
But this time instead of passing the numbers to the function we're going to define the numbers outside
the function.
So we might have AI is equal to 5 and B is equal to 6.
And then if we define add two numbers
to return I plus B
and then we print had two numbers.
Let's take a look see if that gives us the how put it should it does 11.
So because of these numbers here we're defined outside of the function.
They're still accessible inside the function.
However if we try and change them within the function then they're not changed in the main flow of the
code.
So I'll show you something surprising here.
What we can do is set eye is equal to 10.
I don't know why we'd want to do that but just to show you how the scope works if we set is equal to
10 within the function definition.
Then when we return A-plus B we now get 16 because it's 10 plus 6 16.
But if we then print the value of say outside the function it's still 5.
So essentially functions can absorb variables defined outside of them but they can't change them.
Well is the only way that they can is by returning and then the variables themselves being changed in
the main flow of the program.
The final thing to show you is that if a variable is defined inside a function it generally will not
be accessible outside of that function.
So if we define C here to be 8 for example and then I try and print C outside of the function.
We don't get any results.
So that's the basics of how scope works in Python.
Anything that is defined in the main flow of the program is accessible to a function but that function
cannot edit it at least not permanently.
And then any variable that is defined inside the function is not accessible from the main flow of the
code or indeed from any other function either.
All right.
So that's how functions work.
They're essentially ways to take chunks of code that you need reasonably often in your program and organize
them so that they're stored together so you don't have to repeat the lines of code again and again and
that your program is nicely readable and you can see right.
So this function must be working at the highest common factor of these two numbers.
Why rather than trying to struggle to see what's going on down there.
Great.
So now it's finally time to make our Python game mastermind.