One of the most useful things that we can do with the latest versions of CSSA is select elements in
advanced ways.
So let's just start off by some of the ways that way but used to selecting elements in C S S
so we might have an H1 paragraph
and I link
and we would access the H-1 by simply typing each one.
So if we wanted that to be read for example we just put color red in there.
Similarly we could add a class to the paragraph tag and then we could access that class using a period
or full stop and the class name and then
apply some CSSA to it.
Finally
we can have an ID and we access the ID using a hash selector and the ID name and we might have something
like font size is 200 percent which makes it big.
So those are the selectors that we're used to using so forth but we can do a lot more than that.
So first off let's add a div which surrounds our paragraph and our link what if I wanted to select all
of the paragraphs within that div but not paragraphs outside.
So one way would be to give them all a certain class
but that's a little bit messy.
And we don't really want to do that just so that we can select them.
But we can actually select them using what's known as the descendant selector.
So if we wanted to select all paragraph tags within this div we can just use div P
and then that would select all of the paragraph tacks inside the div.
So we might use font weight.
Bold for those for example.
And then you can see the ones in the day of bold but the one outside is not.
We can also select what are known as sibling elements.
So if we had a certain day if that had an H 3 element in it for example
and we wanted to select all of the paragraphs in the same div that have an H three element in it then
we can use H-3 and then Tilda which is the squiggly line for me shift and then the key next to Zed and
then p.
And for example we could underline all of those
and then that would select all the pieces within a div with an age 3 and went in.
But if we added
another div then it wouldn't select that one.
So this is in the other div.
So it is from white board because it's in a div and it's a paragraph tag but it's not sharing its div
with an H-3.
So it's not underlined but if we put three in the
then it would become underlined.
So that can be a very useful way to have paragraphs on different styles depending on what other elements
are in them we might want to be again a bit more fussy and only select the paragraph tag.
Following the H-3 element you might want to give that a particular styling.
So let's give that a font size of 150 percent so the first paragraph then is bigger but the rest are
not.
We can select elements that have a certain attribute in them.
So if for example we wanted to select all the links which had a target which usually would mean that
we'd say Target
is equal to underscore blank which means that opens in a new tab and maybe we want to make all of those
yellow
then we could do that.
And then if we had another link just put it down the bottom
that link wouldn't be selected because it doesn't have a target.
We could even be super fussy.
I've lost my Atra if they're
say this link goes to Google dot com and then we could select links that only go to Google dot com
and maybe make them bigger.
For some reason
and there we get of course if I change the ref to Dan here then that one would become bigger and these
don't necessarily need to be links either.
We could use any element that has any particular attribute to select for.
We could even select links which go to anywhere on Google dot com using Stuy equals.
Which means that the ATF just has to contain Google dot com.
We could even make that just Google that.
Well in this case do exactly the same thing but this would then be more general and only select links
which had Google in them somewhere.
We can also customize this in a number of other ways.
So if I add this has a comment
if we use
conflict's equals this we'll look for whether the attribute begins with whatever we have in the quotes
then we can use the dollar sign equals to check whether it ends with a particular value.
We can use till the equals to see if it has the value between two spaces.
So if they attribute has multiple classes for example or IDs or be separated by spaces and we could
find them here.
And finally we can use the pipe symbol so shift and then for me the key just above the right shift button
to see if it has the valley separated by hyphens i.e. the dash symbol.
So if you've got a class name that's made up of a number of different names separated by hyphens you
can search for it using that.
So there you get a whole different range of ways that we can select things which mostly have the benefit
of keeping your code more simple or more simple and just styling separated from it.
So it reduces the need for having specific classes or IDs just for styling purposes.
That's just the start of fancy selectors that in the next video will see how to use pseudo classes to
select one or number of elements in advanced and complex ways.