All right with steaming through our e-mail tags now and we're going to move away from paragraph tags
and look at the lists in the next couple of areas in this video.
We'll look at an ordered list.
So basically a bullet point list is what we're trying to create here.
And an unordered list we create with the UL tag.
So the UL tag creates an unordered list and then within our unordered list I'm going to use tab to get
it indented again.
We have a list item
so I'm going make a list of my family members.
I'll start with me.
So that's it.
I've got an unordered list at the beginning.
I'm closing the unordered list.
And then when I went to add a new list item I just do the same thing and then we'll add Kirsten in.
And then we want another list item.
So it had to me.
And finally Ralphy.
There we go.
So let's have a look see what that looks like.
Beautiful.
It's got Rob cast in Tommy and Ralphie.
So that's how you create an unordered list in HD Mel has had a very quick challenge for you.
Can you apply different formatting to each of the four elements in your list you can choose any bit
of formatting that you like but different formatting.
Bold.
It's Halik etc. to each element in your list go for it.
All right I hope you manage it.
I'll do something like this so robe can be strong
cast and can be emphasized.
To me a very unfortunately will be deleted and Ralphie can be inserted.
There we go.
Let's have a look.
So we can apply this formatting to anything it doesn't have to be in a paragraph tag as we did in the
previous video text can be anywhere on our page.
Wonderful.
So simple as that.
That's how we create an unordered list in the next video.
We'll see how to do very similarly an ordered list.