Right now we're getting on to something really powerful.
So far we've seen how to use a query and javascript to interact with our pages and do fancy things like
things change shape inside dating web site content.
Ajax takes all of this to the next level.
It was pioneered by Google when they were developing their G-mail interface and now is very widely used.
So whenever you use any webmail app or Facebook or Twitter or any app like that you're using AJAX and
what it does is allow you to grab content from your server within your web page.
For example when the user clicks on a button and do something with that without refreshing the page.
Now that might not sound like much but if you think about what has to happen when you press the send
button on your email client essentially some information i.e. the e-mail content the recipient etc.
needs to be sent to a server which then sends the e-mail itself and reports back to the website saying
that this has been done successfully and we want all of that to happen without having to reload the
page every time.
But she's hugely powerful technology and one that can make your web sites far more fun interactive and
fast.
One slight downside with that though is that we can't use it on local files.
So Ajax doesn't work with files on your computer like this.
So what I'm going to do is work on it live on my eco web hosting server.
So if you haven't set that up yet you might want to go back to the first section and follow the instructions
to do that.
Alternatively if you don't want to set it up or you can't for whatever reason then don't worry just
follow along.
Bear in mind the final code won't work if you're working on your local machine.
So now I'm in fire FTB within Firefox.
If you haven't seen how to set this up then again go back to the video at the beginning of this course
or ignore this bit.
If you're going to work locally and they want to wire about FCP.
So I've already connected to complete web developer because dot com and I'm currently in the content
folder here.
And you can see I've already uploaded the four folders that we've been working with so far and the Course
I'm on the Jay Querrey section so I'm going to go in there and you can see we've got the file Jey query
Drage DML and then going to control click or right click and click open and that will open.
Jay queery directed him L in my text editor.
So it looks exactly the same as before.
But if we jump over back to Google Chrome we can now go to a live web site so that is a complete web
developer because dot com slash content slash for Dasch Jay queery for the folder.
And then Jay Querrey HCM L and this will then load the same page that we had before.
And just to remind you I got that you Arel from content being the folder men for dash.
Jay Querrey being the subfolder and then Jay querido writes TNL being the file name.
So now we can work in exactly the same way that we have been up until now.
But it's slightly more exciting because we're working on a live web site so anyone in the world could
go to this u r l and see this page.
Note if you do check that out and go to this you Arel now it's probably changed.
But this is what is sharing as of the recording of the video.
So just to make sure that everything is working as desired.
I'm going to save that which will then via a fire FCPA it will save it on the live server.
And when I refresh just as we're used to it changes and updates automatically pretty.
So let's in fact let's just check that the query still works.
Yep.
Brilliant.
Everything is connected up nicely.
OK.
So what we're going to attempt to do here is load the content from another file and use it within our
page.
So in order to do that we'll need to have another file to load the content from.
So I'm going to go back over to the fire FTB and create a file right here.
So I'm going to control click or right click on Windows and create file and I'll just call this info
dark text.
It really doesn't matter at all what this file name is but something fairly generic like that should
work.
And then I'm just going to open that
again and that will open up in brackets.
And
or just save a basic bit of text like that and then clicks.
OK.
So is that content that we're going to try and get hold of in our Web page here.
All right.
Here goes.
As always there's a number of ways that we can do it.
I'm going to show you the simplest one first and then we'll move on to what I would recommend using
in a real life site.
So as we're using Jay queery functions and Jake queery by the way is not critical for Ajax but it does
make using it a lot easier.
And then we use it don't want to call a particular Ajax function.
So what we're doing here we're not selecting a particular item within the page as we have been doing
so far.
We're running a special Ajax function and that function is get.
So it does exactly what you might expect.
It gets the contents of a file and then we put in the file name so info dot text and then we need to
do something when the get is complete.
And this is what I mentioned previously is a callback.
So we're going to create a callback function which will run when the Ajax command is complete and they've
got the information and then we can do whatever we want with it.
So we define that as function.
Now we're very used to just putting
parentheses after our function.
That's usually because we don't have a particular variable that we need to do anything with.
But this time we do we have the contents of that get request and so we're going to save that in the
variable data.
You can use any variable name you like that but data is pretty standard and obviously makes sense.
So this data variable is going to contain the data i.e. the contents of inferred text and then what
we need today is do something with it.
So for now we'll just let it and hope for the best.
Here we go.
And there we go.
So it might not look that exciting but what we've done there is the very basis of every web app that
you've used every web mail client every social media Web site and probably every interactive Web site
that you're going to create.
So I think that's pretty cool.
But there are some problems with this function.
For one it doesn't give us the option to do something else if this request fails and that's something
that could well happen if someone is on their mobile in particular and they lose signal and they do
something on your Web site.
We need to be able to give them a nice message saying sorry that's not successful.
Connect to the Internet or even better just keep quiet and then do it later when they are connected
to the Internet.
So to do that we need a more powerful command and the command that we're going to use is Ajax.
So again string and then dots to access Adjaye query function and the function that we're using is Ajax.
Now Ajax is a little bit more complicated than I get but it is worth getting to grips with.
The first thing that we need is to give the you Arel of the page we want to get.
So just like with the get function.
And that's exactly the same as before.
So in photo text and then we can add extra functions on the end.
So I'm going to add a done function and this will be called when the Ajax request returns some information
successfully.
So as before we can use function.
And then again we want a variable to hold the data that's returned so we can refer to it later on and
then
perform we put what we want to happen when the Ajax request is complete in the curly brackets.
So for now we'll just alert data once again.
So let's have a look.
There we go.
So that does exactly the same thing.
So how then will we use it to let the user know if we can get the data for any reason.
Well we add a second or third depending on your point of view function at the end of this which is file.
And this works in exactly the same way.
So it's a function we don't have any data at this time because by definition it's failed.
So there's nothing to return
but it works in exactly the same way.
So let's say let
could not get data
so this will happen for example if I misspell my file name and now I run this again we'll get the error
message.
Could not get data.
So if we do use the get command here and misspelled the file name or the user's Internet connection
it going down then just nothing would happen.
Whereas here we can let the user know that nothing's happened and ask them to send it again later or
do whatever it is we want to do.
So that's the big advantage of Ajax.
There are lots of other settings that give you extra power and control as well.
If you want to check some of them out then just google Jay Querrey Ajax and you'll get lots of information
on this come out but this is all that we need for now.
So I'm just going to tidy this up slightly.
I'm going to put these on new lines.
So it's a little bit clearer.
What's going on.
And I'm just going to give you a tiny challenge here.
Can you create a paragraph tag which is initially empty and then instead of alerting the data put it
into that paragraph tag so it just appears right there on the page.
Go for it.
All right you managed it.
It was pretty straightforward.
So there's your empty paragraph tags.
And then here instead of alerting data we can access or select the paragraph tag.
And then we're going to set the DML to be data and that's it.
Let's take a look wonderful.
This is some content.
So really it might not look like much what we've done there.
In many ways we've just recreated what we've already done but in a much more complicated way.
But hopefully you can see that there's a lot of power in this and especially when you combine this with
a server side language like HP or Python both of which we'll learn later on in the course you're then
in a position to create a really powerful web apps that are useful and fun to use.
Like Gmail Facebook and Twitter.
All right.
So now you're familiar with AJAX.
We're going to move on to a related but different topic which will prepare us for our mini J quivery
project which we're going to do in two videos time and that new concept is another very powerful one.
Regular Expressions.