So now we've seen how to create unordered lists using ul to create a list and then apply to create individual
list items.
Can you guess how we might create an ordered list.
Have a go.
I hope you guessed right.
All we do is change ul to oh well for ordered list and the same in the closing tag there.
And then if we take a look at that it's exactly the same except we've got numbers instead of bullet
points so it's ordered and we can have a little bit of fun with ordered lists and we can mess things
around a little bit.
So say for example for some reason I wanted to start my list at the number 10 rather than the number
one I can use an extra attribute as it's known in my old tag to set the start value.
So I just use start and then equals and then usually in quotes will put the number that we want to start
at.
So I want to start at 10 for example or just start equals 10 and a bit like the you tag the underline
start was actually deprecated in HD M-L 4.0 1 but it's back in 1985 and it's supported by every major
browser out there so you can use it quite safely.
We can also do a couple of other fun things.
We can use reversed in there and that will do what you might guess.
Four three two one.
So that does everything in the opposite order.
And finally we can specify the type of ordered list that we want.
And there's a few type options and you can see my text editor here is very nicely giving me the options
so I can use instead of one to three which is what I've got at the moment.
I could use type is equal to A and that will then if I save it give me ABC as look at the other type
options.
So we've got capital there which gives me capital Roman numerals as small II as well which gives a small
Roman numerals.
And finally we've got small AI which gives us a BCT.
So a lot of people don't actually know that you can change the type of an order list but you can very
easily.
All right.
So you need to know about lists for now and the next video will go on and see how we add images to our
web pages.