So you have actually seen a few pseudo classes before.
Mostly we've use them when it comes to links.
So for example we've used a Coleman Hulver to perhaps add underlining to a link
when it's hovered over just like that but there's a lot more we can do than just style links.
We can also style inputs when they're focused
say for example I might change the background color see blue when my input comes under focus see how
that works out.
So there's my input and clicking on it then we'll turn it blue.
While we're on form elements.
We can also style form elements on the basis of whether they're enabled or disabled.
So I won't show you an example this time but you get the idea.
So normally that faded out by the browser if they're disabled.
I mean we might want to change that in some way and we can use this pseudo selector to select all disabled
inputs and style them in some way.
We can even look at checkboxes or radio elements and style them in a certain way when they're checked.
So that's a way of selecting form elements based on their status.
But we can also select elements based on their location.
And one common way of selecting elements is using first child.
So this actually replicates something that we saw in the previous video and it enables us to select
the first paragraph in each of them containing elements so in this case the first paragraph in each
div.
So if we add another color to that's that's go for the lovely aquamarine then only the paragraphs that
are the first element will be selected.
We can do the same with last child
so let's make that one bigger again.
Here's a question for you.
Will that match any element in our page.
The answer is yes it will match this one because it's both the first child and the last child.
So it will be bigger and aquamarine.
And of course if I move this paragraph to the end of that div it will match that wanty
they have a set up here is we can look at only child maybe we'll make that one bold on that one as you
can imagine we'll style the elements which are the only elements within that container.
So in this case once again it's that one is that the first child doesn't select.
This paragraph here even though it's the first paragraph within the div because it's not the first element
within the div So if we wanted to select the first paragraph regardless of where it was we can use first
of type
and let's underline that one
so this will then underline all three of those because they're all the first of that type in that container.
So not just that selected this one as well because it's the first of its type in the body element even
though there are paragraph tags that come before it's there not directly inside the body.
So they don't count.
We can also use as you might imagine
last of type
and only of type
to select the last of each type in the container.
And the only type in the container as well I'm sure you can imagine how they work.
So I'll leave that as a comment.
Now here we're going to get really fancy and we can select for example if we look at a table row we
could select every other table we're using.
And child.
And the rule is for any child you have to provide your rule.
So now you're going to need some mats for this I'm afraid.
But if you want to select every other row then your statement would be to N because you're selecting
rows 2 4 6 8 etc..
If you wanted to select every other row starting at the first one you could use two and minus 1 and
that would then select 1 3 5 et cetera.
So let's just quickly see that in action if we make ourselves a table
and then a table where I
it's not going to be a table full of me it's going to be my usual suspects.
There we go.
And then if we wanted to make every other one to have a green background
that's how we do it.
There we go.
So it's particularly useful for styling things like lists or tables where you want to separate out the
item from the one below.
There's a couple of other options here as well.
You can use and last child and that will then count backwards.
So instead of counting from the first to the last it will count from the last back to the first.
Similarly you can use and of type to only count
the elements of that type.
So for example here if we were doing the selecting within this div and of type we'd only select the
piece.
And the child itself looks at all of the children regardless of their type.
Usually that's not an issue because we're looking at either table rows or list items or something like
that so they're not interspersed with other elements but if they were then you could use that instead.
OK.
Few more for you.
First off we could select all the empty divs
so we might for example see just hide them so that there's no styling shade.
If they don't have any content we can use the not pseudo selector to select for example all the paragraphs
that are not of a class of green.
Maybe we want to make those plea
and we could use the C to select on its own to select say everything was not a div.
OK.
Your brain is probably exploding with pseudo classes right now but I'll just show you a couple more
things that we can do.
And one of those is to select the first letter of each.
Say paragraph or maybe you want to make that a little bit bigger.
And that will then select just the first letter.
We can also use fast line
and we're almost there.
The last suit I select I want to show you is actually a pseudo element which is essentially some content
or styles that we can create at the end of an element.
So for example if we wanted the linked location to appear after every link in our code.
I'll just add nature here.
So we get the idea.
Let's use that
we can use a colon after
to add some content.
And this could even be something like.
This is a link and if we look at that you see it's added that content there.
Or we could create some dynamic content
by putting
ITTL for attribute and then Streff
and that would then put the actual link itself after that link to make it make a bit more sense.
You might want to put this in brackets and baps at a space
so that it reads better.
You could even style that part of it different by putting the styles in here if you wanted.
So I think that's probably enough for you to recall for now is hopefully given you an idea of all the
different ways that we can select objects using pseudo selectors.
You can always come back to this point as a reference.
You don't need to keep all of these in your head but it's good to know that they're available when you
find yourself needing something like that.
While building a web site.
OK if all of that was a little bit dry for you we're going to look at something a bit more visual now.
And that is gradients and shadows.