So congratulations on making it to the end of the bootstrap section of the complete web developer course
you've been introduced to bootstrap as an HD LCS SS and Javascript framework.
You've seen how easy it makes creating great looking Responsive Web sites and we've used a number of
the components to see how they work and how easy it is to incorporate them into your sites that you're
going to be developing.
Now it's time to put all of that together in our bootstrap challenge where we'll be making an app marketing
page.
So let me show you what we are going to be aiming towards.
It's something like this.
So it's pretty straightforward really.
But it looks nice and has really clear Kolta actions.
So I've pretended that we're working on an app called my app and we've got a nice nav bar across the
top which should be pretty straightforward.
I then given a background image to our Jumbotron where you get that background is up to you.
But if you do a quick google of free high res photos there are a number of pages out there.
All of these I'd ignore the ads at the top and the one I normally use is called an splash dot com but
you can see there are a number of others out there.
Feel free to try them out.
And there's even a few sites listing for a stock photo site so I don't recommend checking those out
if you need some stock photography.
But I'm going to be taking mine from on Splash dot com which has got a number of really nice high quality
photos which you can use absolutely free OK.
So that's where you get your background image from.
We've then got a nice e-mail sign up form them and we're using some cards to display some more information
about the app and also got some really nice icons in here.
I've just chosen some random ones but I've done that with font.
Awesome.
You might want to jot that down.
It's really easy to use so I'd recommend doing that as part of the challenge figuring out how to get
icons from Funt awesome into your site.
But of course I'll show you when I go through it.
If you have any problems.
And then finally we've got a nice big download button which of course doesn't go anywhere.
But it somewhere for the user to click to get your app.
And you'll notice we're all connected up with scroll spy here.
So as we scroll back up again the links update automatically.
So that's where you got the tape.
Easy right.
Well as always.
Third I recommend doing as much if you can on your own.
And then watching how I get it done.
Good luck.
All right.
So I'm going to start by clearing out
my code here.
So we start off with a nice clean file.
So everything comes out of the body
and we're left with just that.
And then I'm just going to switch over to the beat strap h d m l there again.
All right then.
Here we go.
I'm going to start by going to the bootstrap documentation and I'm going to get that by googling bootstrap
for.
And here we go.
I'm going to start with the nav bar at the top of the screen as usual.
I'm going to start at the top and work my way down.
So let's jump over to the documentation and components and Knatchbull And as you so we're heading for
a fairly standard nav bar.
So that top one should do the job pretty much in its current form.
So let's copy and paste the code there.
And remember we don't need a container because we want this to go all the way to the edges of the screen.
Excellent.
So that's looking pretty good as is.
Obviously we need to update it with some information about our imaginary app.
So I'm going to change the nav bar brand.
That is the logo to just be the basic map and then I'll keep home as it is I replace features with about
are we going to have some information about the app and then I'll just have a third and final section.
Download the app
every day and just check.
Make sure that it's all looking OK.
And there we go.
Excellent.
As I mentioned we're going to have a log in section here.
Not that that's actually going to work because we don't have any server side languages yet although
we will have quite soon.
When we look at BHP in a couple of sections time puffing out we'll just have an email and password option.
So let's change first one there to have a type of email and we'll replace the placeholder with email
then I'll just copy and paste that for the password.
And we'll replace the placeholder with password
and then we don't want to search button.
We want a login button and I'm going to get rid of the outline here for no particular reason other than
I think it looks a little better filled in.
But you're welcome to keep it like that if you like.
Notice that the placeholder is displayed but when we start typing of course the password characters
are hidden.
Excellent so far so good.
Now let's move down to our Jumbotron which is still a word that I love saying
that we gave.
So let's start off with the demo code and work from there.
Great.
So that looks pretty good as is.
But we want of course a nice big image to make that look even classier.
And to find one I'm going to go to splash dot com and let's just have a look down see what would work
where we want one with a lot of space really looks pretty good.
We'll keep on looking.
I'm liking that one.
That part would be a nice non-intrusive background.
So I'm going to go for that.
Of course you're very welcome to try another one.
So I'm going to click on the image and there it is.
And then download there it is now I should be able to save image as and I'm just going to pop it there
on the desktop for now.
I'm going to do a little bit of editing with it.
So I'm going to open it up in Preview.
You can do the same thing in Windows if you open up the image in windows photo gallery which does more
or less the same thing.
And then I'm just going to select the bit that I want says something like that.
And then tools and crop and that then saves to the part of the image that I've selected.
Again if you are on Windows in photo gallery you can do that in the fixed menu and then I'm also going
to have a look at the size because we don't want it to be too big.
And I think that's about right.
It still may be quite large half a megabyte or so I'd probably make it smaller for a production site
but I'll leave it at is as is for now.
And then we can export and I'll save it in complete by develop of course and bootstrap
and oh just Colette's background
that we can and I don't need to say the original.
So back to our Jumbotron
let's add some styles so you set the background image.
So we're working with the class of Jumbotron as you're going to be one
and we want to set the background image to have a u r l of background to J.
Right.
Let's have a look.
Beautiful.
A little bit generic perhaps it doesn't say a great deal about what our app is doing but given that
we don't actually have an app that's fine.
Obviously you want to choose an image which is just as pretty but is a little bit more specific so that
people look at that and they can see straight away what your app is about.
Excellent.
Let's just update the text then to have something fairly generic about apps.
So we'll call it my awesome app.
And here are the top then if you want a simple compelling reason why someone should download the app.
So this is why
you should download this fantastic app so effective landing pages convey a simple amount of information
very very quickly when people are browsing the web they're not going to spend ages reading your sites
they're going to decide usually within just a few seconds as to whether they're interested or not and
you need to grab their attention really quickly get the key feature of the app and make it clear that
they need to download it right now.
All right then we're going to add the code for the mailing list.
So underneath
there we'll have something like 8:59 on join our mailing list
and you might even want to offer a freebie or something for your mailing list.
Really like to get something for free such as a mini course or some information or even a demo version
of the app something like that.
It's always good to offer a great incentive to join your mailing list.
All right then we're going to need our form for the user to sign up to the mailing list.
So let's jump over to forms on the bootstrap site and I'm going to take the opportunity to use one of
the ones that have a fancy add on at the beginning then just because I think they look good and we didn't
explicitly try one else self when we saw them in the forms video earlier on.
So under that that's right in our form let's leave it as a form in line for the moment and see how it
looks.
And then this label is not going to be for example amount anymore.
It's going to be for email and we'll change that to email address.
Remember this is screen reader only so we're not going to be able to see this on our browser but it'll
be great for accessibility.
And then I'm going to use the at symbol to denote that this is an email address and it's not a currency.
So I'm going to get rid of the 0 0 at the end Amban we're going to make this a type of email.
Classes still form Cointreau ideas email and I have a placeholder of your email and then we'll change
the button to sign up.
And then we can get rid of
the old button then.
Let's take a look.
Quite I think that looks pretty good.
I especially like the blue on top of the blue of the background and a couple of minor aesthetic issues.
I think the email input there is a little bit short.
I'd like to make that a little bit longer.
And I think I'm going to send to everything here.
Just personal preference but it's pretty easy to do.
We we just go out to our Jumbotron styles and add text align center and we we've gotten an ID for e-mail
input already
so let's just keep that a little bit of extra with try 300.
See how that looks great.
Excellent silicon Gates.
Let's just see you can see displays really nicely at a bunch of widths and even that have really never
with
like that.
So now we're going to work our way down.
So we're going to have another nice big headline here.
But actually my courage looking a bit nasty.
So I'm just going to do a quick bit of
indenting to tidy that up.
So I just selected it all and press tab
and that already looks quite a bit better.
So after our Jumbotron we'll have a div with a class of container.
And then within that we have a div with a class of right.
We're not going to have any fancy columns or anything here because we just want some simple content
but because we're using backstrap It's good to use the different classes.
Generally it'll make you lay out better if you do that.
So let's attempt an H1 see how that looks.
And once again you really need to press home
why your app is so awesome.
And then we want some quite big text here.
We saw before the class is Leite.
So let's try that here.
So we're going to have summary once again of your apps awesomeness.
OK.
I think that looks good but I do want everything centered here.
So let's give this class a quick ID of app summary like that and then
we'll add a text or line of center to make everything nice and center for us.
All right.
In the next one it's ready that is we're going to have our three cards.
Remember that's the cool new bootstrap for feature that replaces panels and a bunch of other stuff as
well.
So let's click on cards and see which suits us the best.
I think that first ones should suit us absolutely fine.
We will need another image but we can get one of those.
It's not a problem so let's copy that over.
In fact let's just remind ourselves how we get the deck of cards as it's.
One
after the other.
It's down here somewhere.
Groups is not quite what we want because we want them to close together.
We want a deck just like this great.
Remember the really nice thing about this is the cards will all be the same height even if the text
length in each of them is different.
And that's almost always what you want.
When you're doing something like this.
So let's copy that.
Eva
and we'll put it
does it come with a container.
No.
But I don't think we'll need one actually because it has a card deck wrapper.
So let's just have a quick look before we add our image.
And it's going a little too wide I think.
So I will add a container class to that because we didn't really want it going all the way to the edge.
Nice.
That looks just a little bit better.
So now to find out little image that we're going to use We'll get back to you and splashed or come and
so we just want a fairly small one this time.
So let's see if we can find that to be quite cute.
I like the look of that one.
We want one that is just a little bit wider.
So if we crop just that I think that look great.
I may be biased having a five year old son but I think there's something nice about that picture.
OK so once again I'm going to write clerical control click and save image as save it on the desktop
then go back over to the desktop open it up in pre-WWI and I'm just going to drop it to roughly the
right time.
So just something a little bit wider than it is high.
It's trying to get the boys in every game and then tools.
Don't quite like that.
I'm going to undi get a little bit more sky and
try it out.
Great.
So then we'll export that into the bootstrap and I'll call it father and some
and we don't need to save the original
OK.
So let's change remember data SAAC to SIRC and we'll just copy that up to all of these of course you'd
normally have different images for each of these and they would be images that would have something
to do with your app rather than just one that you thought was charming.
OK so that's pretty good but a little bit larger than we'd want I think.
So let's specify a width and but bootstrap is expecting to for one or two for two in terms of the width.
So let's set a card image.
Top
to have you with of 240 pixels
OK.
We're not quite there.
So we've got the right width of course.
The cards themselves change their width so we're going to need to make the image actually the width
of the card and we should be able to do that by just changing the width to 100 percent and then it will
make it 100 percent the width of the container which is the card itself.
Quite so.
It doesn't tell you a great deal of it about the app but it's a nice image.
OK.
I did mention I was going to put in some I can say using font.
Awesome.
So I managed to figure out how to do something similar yourself.
But let's see how we would do it.
So we have a quick google for phones.
Awesome.
Every day and it's just got some really nice icons in there.
So let's see how we would get started.
Mm hmm.
Get started looks like a good option for us.
And then we've got a fantastic CDN link
so let's go for that nice and easy.
Of course you can always download the C S S and restrict yourself if you prefer.
So let's pop that up there.
Great.
And then let's see if it's got basic instructions to how we at and I can let's have a look at the icons.
Themselves.
Here they are.
So I got a huge number of icons.
I'm going to start with an anchor one because we seem to be at the seaside here.
And you can see that we've got the HVM allocate for putting the anchor in.
So let's try that out on our first one just at the beginning of the title there.
Wonderful.
Let's just pick another couple while we're here.
Bicycle looks nice.
I'm going to copy that one
and it's just going to get there.
I'm also going to have a space to space that out a little bit.
And then a birthday cake.
Why not.
Quite sure what features the kids these could possibly represent but you get the idea and I'm actually
going to get rid of the last updated part of the bottom because it's not really relevant for us.
OK.
Excellent.
So I'm not even going to edit this text down here.
The important thing to note is that the cards all have the same height even though they have a different
amount of text in them.
Great.
I'm feeling a little bit more padding is needed for this part here.
Why the app is so awesome.
So let's just add that in.
We've already got a CSA Selecta for it.
It's app summary.
So let's add a bit of a margin top maybe 100 pixels.
Let's try a margin bottom of a hundred pixels as well.
Crates a little too much
so let's try 40 at the top and 50 at the bottom.
It seems to be slightly nearer the top anyway.
And a little bit more at the top I think.
Great.
All right.
So we nearly Then all we can add now is essentially a footer row will contain the link to download the
app.
Let's start here.
We'll have a container div
and a row div
and we'll have an H T
for download the app and I file as if the user wasn't completely convinced I should really.
Why should I download this app
and then we'll have a link to the App Store.
So I'll look on Google images to get the app store link all apps are image I mean
I would get that first one looks pretty Perfect's I don't quite like the shining ness.
I think I'm going to go for the second one when you're looking at these it's worth checking out for
size.
So neither one by 3:12 is a little large but it should be OK for us.
But another more important thing to be aware of is whether they have transparent backgrounds and you
might not be able to see this on my screen here.
But if you look really close you might just be able to see a square there.
A lighter is darker and then another lighter square and that indicates that there is indeed a transparent
background here.
So it will look good regardless of what color our background is.
So let's download that's so it will save image as I just control clicked there.
Right clicking would do it as well.
And App Store icon is a pretty good name for the image so we'll leave it at that.
So you might want to resize it and make it a little bit smaller.
That's up to you.
But I'll leave it as is
for now.
And then here I'll put it in its own paragraph tag.
This is going to be a link
but I'll just leave the draft blank because I haven't actually got an AppStore page.
And then we'll have an image
and you can see there it is still icon.
All right.
That's probably going to be pretty wide.
But let's just have a look.
See how it comes out.
OK great.
A little bit too large for us.
So let's
make a few changes here.
So first of
will give us an idea of App Store icon and then we'll set the
T.
Let's try out 200 pixels.
And while we're here I'm going to give our container an ID of FOTR
and I want to have a background.
So I will give it a background color and let's try Aqua.
We seem to be developing a water theme here.
And a padding at the top of this try 50 pixels and also a margin at the top.
To separate it from the cards above all.
Again let's try 50 pixels and I want to center everything.
So let's try applying that to William.
So this definitely looks a lot better.
You can see that there's no extra white on the corners there so this is a nice transparent image.
The major issue is that our backgrounds is not going right to the edge of the screen and that's because
we've got it set up as a container.
I think probably the easiest fix should work fine for us is just to remove the container class there
which is actually fine for us.
So that's now full with the only thing I'm not happy with is we need a bit of padding at the bottom.
So let's add in
a padding bottom of again 50 pixels seems to be working out well for us.
So let's try that.
Excellent.
OK so you can obviously play around with the styles there but there's only one more thing that I'm going
to do and that is set up these links with scroll spy so that we can link to different parts of the page
and that it will update automatically as we scroll as well.
So first off let's set the links up
so we'll get our Jumbotron an ID of jumbotron and we'll set up that link not there.
All right.
Yes.
That will take us to the top of the screen.
And then about we want that to take us to the card deck wrapper.
So we'll call this about
and link there.
And then we want that one to link to a photo.
So let's just have a quick look at our links work about.
Yes.
Wonderful.
And download the app is at the bottom there.
Great.
So let's just set up scrolls by Remember that we need to add data spy is equal to scroll to the body
and then the data target.
And that's the Nev.
so we could use anything here.
But I think it makes sense to give us an idea of nav bar and then we can set up that data target there.
All right.
We also need to add
a position is relative to the body for this to work.
And of course we'll need our nav bar to be fixed to be able to actually see it when we scroll down.
So at a nav bar fixed top cost of that.
So that's going to cause an issue with our Jumbotron but that's easily fixed as we go.
So you can see that that did update for about but not for download the app because it's not tall enough
to get to the top of the screen so I'm going to change a couple of things then.
First of all I'm going to change the data offsets to be pretty high.
So let's try 150 pixels to see how that looks.
And also at an extra hundred pixels to the top on the bottom
or the padding rather than the margin.
And let's have another look.
So now we do get to download the app that's just on my screen size.
It's not critical but it's a little bit better.
And you can see home is highlighted all the time there which is not what we want.
So let's get rid of the active class
on Hayyim and then it should be active anyway at the top.
But then it will switch to a the active div..
Brilliant.
So finally all we need to do is just move the Jumbotron down
and we can do that by giving it a mountain top of I'd say about 50 pixels.
Wonderful.
So we've got our NAV bar working well without log in.
And as we scroll down scrolls PI kicks in and we get we've got our cards with their nice icons and we've
got our download link at the bottom and of course it's all brilliantly responsive as we get an hour
an hour.
Everything still looks great.
Wonderful.
So I hope you enjoy making them.
I hope you're inspired to make some landing pages of your own.
We're not quite done with bootstrapping because one of the many great bonuses you get with this course
is a collection of three great bootstrap themes which are the official themes from the makers of bootstrap
themselves.
So in the next video I'm going to show you the basics of these themes and how you can start editing
them to make fantastic looking dashboards marketing web sites and web apps.
So you then.