In the previous section we saw how to do gradients using the HCM L5 canvas but if all you want is a
gradient it's actually easier to do with scissors.
So in this video I'll show you how to set up gradients in CSSA And we'll also look at the different
types of shadows that we can create.
So I'll start by getting rid of the code from the previous video.
And then let's create a nice simple Dave
which will give an idea of gradient
and then we'll just select it in the usual way and we'll start off by giving it a certain width and
height.
So we'll just have 300 pixels and a height of 200 pixels and we'll start off with a background color
of blue just to check that everything's looking good that we got.
In fact let's make it 500 pixels great.
So if we want a gradient that goes for example from white to blue top to bottom we just use background
and then linear gradient and then we give out two colors so white and black.
Simple as that.
And then we get a beautiful gradient.
And of course we can put any sort of content on top of that as well.
So that's just our background for a div we can but whatever we like behind that note that I've left
the background color is blue for browsers that don't support the gradient.
So let's see what other options we can put in there.
We can switch it to left to right gradient by simply putting two right as our first parameter.
And then it will become I left to right gradient.
We can even make it a diagonal gradient by making it to bottom right and you see my text that is there
is even clever enough to know what that is before we even run it in the browser.
And now it's top left to bottom right.
And of course you can change these to anything you like say if you want it to go the other way round.
You could change that to top left and then that will start with white at the bottom right and go up
there.
You can even have multiple colors in here.
So if we wanted something that looked pretty horrendous We could use white red green and blue.
And there it is.
That's a bit special.
We can also do radial gradients.
So let's just create a new div
and this is exactly the same.
So in fact I'll just copy the width and the height down from up there.
And then we just use background radial gradient.
And then we might have white and blue like I'm We could of course use HVM l color codes there as well
as the color names.
And then we get a gradient coming out from the middle but there's a little challenge that's just appeared
for you.
So can you recreate this bottom gradient.
And I'll tell you that it's green at this end and the yellow at the other.
Try and do it without looking at this carryed if possible.
Jeffery
All right.
How did you manage that.
I'll just do it by creating ID code challenge gradient
and then forget to close it.
We'll give it a thought.
500 pixels and a height of 200 pixels.
And then the background is going to be
a linear gradient because it's not
radial here.
And we want to go to the bottom left to bottom left and we're getting green to yellow.
Simple as that refresh.
And that's what the code was.
So that's about it when it comes to gradients.
Let's look at how we use C-s as three to apply shadows.
There are two ways to apply shadows in C as three.
And that is with text and box shadows.
So we'll start with some text.
In fact let's have an H T.
This text will have a shadow
and then it's very simple.
What we do is apply text shadow and then the offset to the right and the offset down.
And that means that the shadow will be two pixels to the right and two pixels down of the original.
Now that looks fairly horrendous as it is but we could do a lot more with that.
We can add a color.
So this is my favorite green.
There we go.
So looks pretty horrendous but we've got the shadow at the moment there you can see that the shadow
is completely solid.
It's essentially a copy of the original text.
Generally you're going to want a slightly blurred shadow.
So let's try putting in a bit of a blur.
This will give a 4 pixel black.
And there we go you can see that that looks a lot nicer than it did before.
Still not necessarily beautiful with the black and green combo but it looks a lot better than it did.
We could even have invisible text
by setting the color to white and just showing the shadow a slightly different sort of shadow effect
can be achieved.
As I kind of go by essentially doing a shadow with a zero offset
so we use 0 and 0 for the offset and then say 5 pixels red for the shadow.
And then you get this sort of neon a glow effect.
You can even if you really want to put multiple shadows on a single element of text and you can put
them in different directions.
So we might have a shadow which goes to the left and up with a blur of say four pixels and make it yellow.
And there we go.
So obviously I would never advise having that sort of a look in your web sites but you can do it if
you want to remember to use texturing gracefully.
And it can add a real nice subtle boost to the style of your page.
More commonly used than tech shadowing is books shadowing.
So this as you might imagine happens on Dave's or any kind of box shaped element
so I'll call it shedder
then let's bring it in.
So it will set the width to 200 pixels and the height to 200 pixels.
And the box shadow
initially to let's say three pixels 3 pixels
we again I should probably give a background color to the box as well.
Let's.
Antique white that we get.
So it doesn't look great once again as a completely solid shadow.
But if we choose the blue say three per X then it looks a lot nicer.
And it really does have the effect of lifting the div off the page a little bit.
Notice that that's quite dark immediately around the div..
So you might want to change that to gray to have something a little bit more subtle.
And if you want to really bring this of the page then you just increase the book Shadow to maybe 12
pixels 12 pixels and then perhaps 6 pixels.
And there you go.
You've got a much bigger shadow there and that's pretty much it.
So you now know how to add shadows to divs how to add shadows and glow effects to text and how to create
gradients.
Obviously none of the shadows of the gradients that we've created here look particularly great but used
Sutley you really can add a bit of zip to your web pages.
So use it well.
We're now going to move on to look at transformations in CSSA 3.