Let's take a quick moment out to see how much you've learned so far in this section because we really
have covered a huge amount.
We started off looking at what CSSA was and why it was a good idea and how we could use it to style
our websites.
We then looked at both in line and internal see SS Then we discovered classes and IDs to allow us to
apply those styles to certain elements.
Then we created some divs to contain our elements and then we moved on to look at specific CSSA properties
starting with colors and then looking at floating positioning and margins.
So that really is a huge amount and well done for making it this far and staying with me.
We're now going to look at padding which allows us to do something very similar to margins but inside
an element and you'll be pleased to know that we've got just a few hours to go until we've covered the
basics of S and we're going to do our big website project.
I'll tell you more about that later.
So padding is pretty similar to margins but it works on the inside of an object rather than the outside.
So if for example we wanted to have a little bit of a gap between the green text here and the edge of
the blue div we could just get rid of the margin that we could add a padding of say five pixels.
Let's now have a look.
So that's quite nice.
It gives us a little bit of spacing in between the edge of the div and the content.
So a quick challenge for you then could you set the padding within this blue box to be different.
You can choose whatever values you like but different on the top right bottom and left.
You can probably work out how to do that.
Go for it
all right.
Hope you managed it.
It works in exactly the same way as margins.
So we can use 5 pixels 10 pixels 15 pixels and then 20 pixels.
There we go.
Might not be that obvious but we've got five pixels up here ten down here 15 at the bottom and then
20 on the left.
It's worth noting that if we've specified a whit as we have here the padding is on top of that with.
So we've got our 400 pixels from say they're there.
And then the padding.
So the 10 pixels on the right and the 20 pixels on the left will be on top of that 400 pixels.
So quick question what is the width of this box in pixels.
The total weight
it it's 400 plus the 10 on the right plus the 20 on the left.
So 430 pixels in total and that's definitely worth remembering.
You can get yourself in a lot of trouble if you think that this is 400 pixels and then forget that it's
actually 430.
All right.
So that's more or less all you need to know about putting it just one more thing.
I'm going to show.
You may have noticed that there's quite a bit of white space that we haven't programmed into our page
here.
That's that by default and browsers have default margins and padding built in to their elements and
that can make things a little bit tricky if you're trying to get a really pixel perfect design.
So if you do want to do that and get rid of all of those defaults then I would do something like.
First of all starting off with the body.
So we're now styling the actual body of the page itself and set both the margin and the padding to zero.
And let's have a look and see what effect that has.
So you can now see it stretches right to the edge of the page.
You'll notice as well that we've got this gap between our lives here and a gap up there.
If we wanted to get rid of that then we would actually set the padding and the margin for the paragraph
tags to zero.
So that's what's causing that gap there.
So if we set both of those in then everything kind of condenses up.
So that might not necessarily be what you want but we've achieved the effect of getting everything really
close to everything else.
As a quick aside if you're getting quite excited about this and think you might get really into web
design with CSSA then working with something called a CSSA reset makes these things a lot easier because
these default margins that we saw over here can actually vary from browser to browser.
So using a CSSA reset in your pages makes those the same.
So you can be more sure that your website is going to look exactly the same in every browser.
So feel free to investigate that a little bit more.
And definitely if you're having issues that a Web site that you're making is different in different
browsers putting a CSSA reset in there is probably a good idea.
All right.
So that's as far as we're going to go with margins in the next video.
We'll look at how to add a nice bit of styling to the edges of your device or other elements using borders.
See you then.