So we've moved away a little bit from programming in the last couple of sections of the course looking
at bootstrap and Wordpress which are really useful tools for web developers of all types but now we're
going to very much go back and start coding once again.
And in this section we're going to be looking at a language called HP before I tell you specifically
what BHP is.
I want to give you a quick summary of how the various languages that you have learned and are going
to learn in this course fit together.
So this is how a basic web site works.
We've got the web browser here which works on a computer's machine and all the languages that we've
learned so far work within the web browsers.
HTL is processed by the web browser as is.
C Ss for styling and Javascript and Jay Querrey both run within the browser as well.
So those are great languages but there's a number of things that we can do in the browser.
We can't store users information permanently on the browser because the browser gets closed down and
we want a way to store that data somewhere centrally so the user can access it anywhere on the web.
So the web browser of course connects to the Internet and the Internet gets all its information for
a particular Web site from a web server so you can think of this essentially as a computer we're part
of a big gigantic computer that is sitting in a server farm somewhere.
And every time your website gets sequestered essentially what happens is the server does something to
generate the HD MLC SS and Javascript and then sends that to the user's browser where those three get
processed.
So there are languages that work on the web server and allow us to do web service specific things like
logging a user in overturning their tweets or saving their progress in a game.
And by far the most popular language on the Web today is HP.
So that's why we're starting with that one.
HP actually powers over 80 percent of the web at the time of making this course.
And although it's not the most popular or fashionable language to learn it is a really useful one and
I still recommend it as the first server side language that a web developer should learn.
It's also the language that WordPress is built in learning.
HP will enable you to create WordPress plugins customize WordPress themes and essentially do whatever
you want within WordPress page B is also associated strongly with the my Esky Well database type which
again is the most popular database type on the web and that's what we're going to be seeing how to work
with in the next section.
So a very quick introduction to HP then we're going to be working with the latest version of HP which
is actually HP 7.
And as you can see from this introduction on W3 schools ph stands for PH P hypertext preprocessor.
Essentially that means we're processing the hypertext or the HTL before providing that to the user's
browser.
It's completely free and open source and a page file that we'll see in the next video as the don't pay
HP extension and it can contain ph p h t m l c s s and javascript's so we can use all four languages
together in the one file type if you want to learn a bit more about HP and feel free to just go to this
page on three schools or Google ph introduction something like that.
The last thing I just want to show you is historically ph is a pretty old language.
It was developed in 1994 and that's another reason to learn it first because there's a huge amount of
help for HP on line and anything that you will want to do.
Someone will have asked how to do it before.
Usually on stack overflow and the answers will be right there in Google for you.
So that's reason enough for you to learn HP in the next video.
We'll go on to create our first hello world page in DHP.