So welcome back to the complete web developer course as I mentioned in this section we're going to be
looking at style.
So hopefully you have made a website that looks a little bit like this.
Can see we've got all the kind of cool HDMI elements in there but it doesn't look right.
We obviously want to be building beautiful websites as well as useful ones and for that we're going
to need some style and we create style using Cascading Style Sheets or.
SS So what on earth is a cascading style sheet.
Well we've actually seen one before.
When we looked at the code of example dot com which we get from right clicking or control thing and
then a few page source in crime.
You'll remember that we looked over the style section just then and this is a cascading style sheet
and it's pretty simple how it works.
We get the name of the element that we're styling.
So body Dave that could be in each one or UL or an image or anything.
And then we have some curly brackets and inside the curly brackets we have some style information.
So background color margin padding font family with all sorts of things.
There's a huge number of ways that we can style our page using Cascading Style Sheets.
And the real advantage of them is that they're completely separate from the H TNL itself which is a
very useful job then of keeping style and content separate.
This Jemini makes your code more readable.
It's easier to update and maintain and it has a really useful feature that you could completely restyle
your website without actually changing the TNL of the content at all.
And an example of that can be found if you google CSSA then you can see we've got three schools at the
top here.
If you click on the second results CSSA introduction then they've got a bit more information about CSSA
if you want to know more than you can read that.
But I'm just going to show you this example home page here with a certain stylesheet.
If we then apply a second style sheet to it the page looks completely different even though the TNL
is exactly the same.
We can do that again stylesheet three.
And now it looks like the three school's Web site itself stuff for looks completely different again
and we can even remove the stylesheet and we get back to the web page that looks more similar to what
we created in the previous section.
So to summarize CSSA is a simple and powerful way to apply styling to your websites to make them look
great in the next video then we'll apply a style sheet to our own web page and see in detail how it
works.