All right.
So we're now going to say goodbye to Marge and get rid of our image and we're going to look at how we
can add forms to our web pages forms allow your pages to be interactive and the users to enter data
tick boxes and click buttons.
So they're really powerful and really easy to use.
Let's see how we get started.
As you might guess there's a tag called form and that's what we're going to use to create our forms.
And then anything inside of form will be then part of that form.
So a very basic element to have in your form is an input element.
Now this is one of those self-closing tags again so we don't need a closing tag.
But let's just have a look what input on its own looks like it's very simple.
It's just a box.
So it's a box.
And then you can start typing some text in there if you want to.
So you might have something like name and then a colon and then your input and it looks like that.
Now the input tag here has several attributes that we can use.
And the first one we'll look at is type so we can have different types of input and you can see quite
a few of them being predicted.
For me there.
So the first one I'll just show you is not test but text.
So this is exactly what we've got.
So this is the default type.
But really if you're going to use an input you should use a type regardless of whether you're using
the basic type or not.
Just so it's clear in your code that you want this to be a text input but let's have a look then at
some of the other types of impact that we can use.
In fact we'll put that in a paragraph so that there will be on different lines so let's create another
input with a type of.
And we'll first look at checkbox.
Let's see then what that looks like it's what you might guess a simple tick box.
So quite often you might see that next to for example if you're in a log in form there's often an option
to stay logged in and then you can decide with your checkbox whether or not you want to stay logged
in another type of input.
Is the radio input which is not necessarily so obvious as to what it is.
Let's take a look.
You will definitely have seen them while going round the web.
So it's very similar to a checkbooks But the difference is with each set of radio buttons you can only
select one of them.
So for example you might want to have one that says under-rating and then another that says overwriting
like that.
Of course you could have a whole string of different sets of ages and they would only be able to check
one of those.
Now if you try that however at the moment we can select both.
And that's because we haven't linked these up in any way our code doesn't know that these are part of
the same set of radio buttons and we can link them up by giving them a name.
So we might say age.
So now that they both have the same name if we now see how it works if we click one and then select
the other you can see we can only select one of them.
And again if we had a whole string of these we would only be able to select one of them if they all
had the name age.
And in fact later on when we do more work with forms we'll see that pretty much every form elements
should have a name so that you can refer to it and do something with it when the user submits the form.
But to do that you need a little bit more coding knowledge than we have at the moment.
So we'll get that when we come to the next element We'll look at is the drop down and this actually
works differently it's not an input it's a select.
So let's see how this works.
You can see we've got a select tag there.
And then inside the tag we have our options.
So let's say for example that we want to get the favorite food
of our user.
And yes I am spelling that with you.
And let's just get out tabs looking nice.
This is our first long bit of code.
So it starts becoming more important that we set up our tabs nicely you can see that's nice and clear
now that everything here is inside these paragraph tags.
And then there's the option tags are inside the select tags as well.
So let's pop a few foods in there.
Pizza
we'll have ice cream
and sandwiches.
I sure do.
So let's see what that looks like.
So you can see we've got a nice drop down there and the user can select whichever one they want.
Fantastic.
The last one I'm going to show you is the submit button.
So most forms are going to need this for the user to tell you that they finished.
So that's just another input type and all we need to do is have a type of submit just like that.
And then let's have a look and then we got a nice submit button at the bottom that said this is a really
nice basic form that uses several different elements.
We've got a text input.
We've got a checkbox we've got a pair of radio buttons.
We've got to select or drop down.
And then we've got a submit button at the bottom.
There are of course some other form elements but these are the basic ones that you are using over and
over again.
Before we move on I'm just going to show you a little bit how to customize some of these.
So for example we might not want the submit button to have the word submit on it we might want it to
have a different value or text.
And we do that using value to the value attribute so we might want to have click me something like that
and that then changes the text on the button.
The value attribute can actually be used in most of these as well.
So for example we might want to set a default username for some reason if we wanted to do that.
We just put it in
has a value attribute on the user input like that and then it would appear there and the user can get
rid of it.
If they want to.
Similarly we could add a value attribute to the radio buttons.
So that code will know which one they've checked.
So we might have something like value.
He was under 18 and value equals over 18.
And then later on when we write some code to process that we'd know which one had been selected by the
user.
Now setting the value of username into your username isn't particularly useful because most people are
then going to have to click their select it delete it and then enter their username.
So that's not a great way of guiding your users to do something.
But if you do want to give the users a hint as to what to type in the box you can use the placeholder
attribute.
Let's just have a look and see what that does.
So it still puts your user name in there but you can see it's a bit faded.
And then when you click in the box and you can just start typing Rob.
And that disappears straight away.
So if you want to give the user a bit of guidance as to what to put in the box then the placeholder
attribute is a great way to do that.
All right.
Two more things first off we might want to have this checkbox selected by default and we can do that
really easily by putting the word checked into the checkbox input as an attribute.
It doesn't actually have a value just says checked.
And then we have a list you can say it's checked by default.
And finally we can change which one of the three options appears as the default.
So you can see pizza re-appears because it's at the top there.
But if I want ice cream to appear as the default when the user loads the page I just put an option of
selected in there.
And it's now have a look can the ice cream appears as the default one and that's it there for now.
Obviously your form doesn't do anything when you click before me you can see the page is reloaded but
we haven't written any code to actually process the form in any way and we'll do that later on in the
course.
But you've learned about several different HDMI elements and put them all together to make your first
form.
Congratulations.
We're going to move on now to look at tables in HD M-L.