Now that we know how to set the font of our text we're going to look at styling it in other ways so
this is making text bold underlining it's making it taluk and a lot more.
We did of course see how to do that in the HVM L section but I hope that you're reasonably convinced
that it's best generally to keep styles separate from content.
So rather than using strong for example to have some bold text we're better off putting that information
in our stylesheet so that we can apply it to multiple styles and update it and manage our website much
more easily.
So lets start off indeed with some bold and I'm going to get rid of this Google fonts just to avoid
any confusion.
And so let's see how we make our text bold.
It's pretty easy.
We use font white.
Now we can be really precise with our font white and use a particular number or we can use one of the
standard options.
And I would normally for bold go for bold so that will set our text to be bold.
So what about it taluk text.
Well first off let's just switch this to a class so that we can have a nice reference for you with lots
of different types of text formatting.
So we'll have it Salik there.
It's going to be some taluk text
and then dot taluk to select that class and for a taluk we use font style and we got normal there which
is the standard oblique.
And we're going to be doing it like again.
So bold and italic.
Now I'm going to set you a quick challenge.
I'm going to put an extra bit of text here saying this.
And this is bold and italic and I'd like you to somehow.
Any way you like make that sentence both bold and italic.
Go for it.
I you managed it.
I hope you used some sort of a span
around that sentence.
And then I think the easiest way to do it is just to apply the bold class to that span and then the
span will be both bold and taluk because it's part of the paragraph.
That's it.
There we go.
But if you had a separate class for that one which is bold and italic that's fine but you've kind of
made a taluk twice because it was already a taluk from the paragraph tag.
All right.
The third new type I'm going to show you is underlining.
So let's just copy that and we'll have a class of underline
and we'll have this text is underlined and it's pretty easy to do once again so underlined to select
that and then text decoration and underline
like there you go.
So those are the three major types of text styling that you're likely to use.
As it happens I probably use text decoration.
None more often than I use underline because quite often I want my links not to be underlined.
And let's just have a quick look.
Well have an empty link there.
This is a link.
So by default of course links are underlined.
If as is the style of many web sites these days you don't want your links to be underlined.
Then you would just set an instruction in your CSSA for all links.
That is.
And set the text decoration to none.
That's a really handy thing to do to stop your links being underlined.
But just to confuse things or avoid confusion we'll set that back to underlined.
So this is a non underlined link.
There you have one cheeky trick.
I'm going to show you is allowing a link to be underlined when the mouse hovers over it which is quite
a nice way of just confirming to the user that this is indeed a link and you can do that using what's
known as a pseudo selector which is styling a link in a certain condition.
So this will style the link when it's it's harvest state i.e. the user is hovering the mouse over it.
So we can then bring in text decoration underline for that.
Let's have a look.
Now when we bring the mouse over it's underlined and we could even change the color if we wanted to.
For some reason we could make it underlined and green when the user hovers over it.
OK.
The one last one I'm going to show you is one that we've definitely seen before
which is making text big
and we do that with the font size property and we can make that whatever we like.
Normally I'd go for something like 200 percent to make it twice as big as normal.
There we get a nice big text.
And of course we've seen coloring as well.
So those are the basics.
Those are definitely the ones I would use on a day to day basis but there are a lot more to show you
a few of them are Google something like CSSA dialing text.
And then again W3 schools comes up with the top and they've got a few ones that we're used to so text
color.
We know all about that's text alignment we're actually looking at in the next video and then text decoration.
So this is underlining or not underlining.
And there's a few other options there as well over a line or line at the top and line three you can
transform your text into all uppercase or lowercase if you want to indent the first line.
You can change the spacing between letters.
Change the line height even change the text decoration if you really want to.
And word spacing can be changed there as well.
So you can really completely customize the way your text looks.
Using some pretty basic CSSA great.
So that's how we customize the style of our text in the video.
I mentioned we're going to see how we can align our text very easily to have it left aligned right aligned
centered or justified.