Congratulations on making it to the end of the PH P.S. of the complete web developer course you've now
covered a huge range of different programming structures and variable and array types as well as doing
some pretty advanced things like sending emails including files and getting the contents of other Yawara
else.
You should also be in a position that pretty much anything you wanted to know how to do in PE.
You could find out with a quick Google.
So on that note welcome to the HP challenge.
And this is it.
We're going to create a what's the weather web page whether you can put in the name of any city.
So say Dubai for example and the weather for that city will be returned.
You see it looks nice and pretty obviously using bootstrap here and I've got a nice background image
from an splash as well.
We're also pretty neat if they put in an era.
Then we get a nice error message displaying as an alert as well.
So you may be wondering how are we getting the weather for all of these cities then stored on our database
or anything anywhere.
So what we're doing is we're getting the contents of another Web site and that is whether hyphen forecast
dot com.
And the reason I've chosen this particular site is that if we get the forecast for a particular city
you can see that the name of that city is put directly in the world.
So if we got the contents of this whole you are well as we know how to do then hidden in there.
We've got the weather summary which is what we want.
So what your code is going to need to do is get the contents of this you Arel and then extract this
bit of text from it.
Now that last bit we haven't quite done.
We've done similar things but not quite extracting text from within a string.
So you're going to need to do a little bit of googling there to figure out how that's done or of course
if you have problems you can watch me do it.
One word of warning before I set you off although this is a great challenge for practicing all that
we've used in HP.
It's not a great use case for a real live production web site for two main reasons.
First off you're dependent on weather.
I often forecast dotcom not only remaining live but remaining in the same format that it does now.
If they were to change their code or change the layout of that page that would likely break your page.
So that's not a great system for a live and popular Web site.
Secondly if you if your web site does become popular then weather dash forecast outcome will not be
happy with you because you're essentially taking their data and then displaying it to the user without
giving any credits to weather forecast com themselves.
So they may well block your website if it gets too popular.
So it's a good thing to practice and it can be very useful in other ways if you want to get a large
amount of data from a web page for example that's known as scraping and they use very similar techniques
as to what we're going to do in this challenge.
But if you did want to create something like a Web site you're much better off using what's known as
an API which is set up for this sort of site and we'll look at in a couple of sections time.
All right.
So that's it.
This is what you're creating.
Best of luck hope because well effort.
All right then.
Here we go.
So I'm going to start by setting up my user interface and I'll do that of course by searching for bootstrap
for and then I'm going to get the template
set up K say download bootstrap and then getting started.
Scroll down and here it is number that might be in a slightly different place on the bootstrap website
V.
K. lovely Let's have a look.
We've got our beat strapped.
Hello world.
Fantastic.
So let's just pop in a title this time
because it's always good to have one where the scraper should pop up that lovely
And then we're going to want a nice background image.
So let's go to splash dot com and see what we can find.
Let's have a look.
We're looking for something sort of fairly plain and simple and maybe a little bit Wetherbee
not quite there yet I don't think
that's not too bad.
Let's keep looking.
When we've seen before
it's pretty good.
It's got that big to the bottom or this one that looks good.
Pretty relevant to weather but not too much distraction in the background.
Great.
So let's download.
That's
so I'm just going to control a click or right click and save image as and I'm going to save it in the
HP folder on my hard drive and I'll just call it background.
There we go.
So that's saved.
Remember though that we're working on the server.
So I need to go back over to Firefox and fire of T-P refresh find my background or jpg file and then
upload it just before we upload that if we just check it is three megabytes three thousand kilobytes
which is pretty big for a photo on the web.
So let's just resize it for megabytes.
In fact
again we can do that pretty easily on a Mac in Preview in Windows you can use the photo editor.
I'm just going to go to tools and adjust size.
I mean yeah we don't need anywhere near 7000 pixels.
So let's bring it down to 2000 that's already plenty of pixels for us.
And then I'm just going to say that's as it is.
K and then jump back over to the fire of t.p and we can see you now 300 kilobytes a lot more reasonable
that we get right I have now uploaded that to the service so we should be able to access it in our script.
That stee that
so I'll just do a quick check straight off image S.R. see it coils and a should be at background dot
JPAC.
Just to make sure as usual that everything's connected up right.
And there we go.
So you can see it's definitely plenty big enough.
Might even want to get it smaller than that on a live site.
But this will do it for a test.
Now as I mentioned at the beginning we wanted a full screen but not stretched out background.
That's something that we haven't done before.
So let's have a google and see if we can figure out how to do it.
So something like HMO full page background that day
perfect full page background image fantastic.
That sounds great you've got a nice new methods.
Yes I want a full page background brilliance.
But if CSSA three.
Another advantage of doing this is that you learn some new techniques as well.
OK.
So let's put in some internal styles.
So it's actually just the HTL element that we're going to be editing here.
And all I should need to change there is the file name is now background.
Jay Pech
All right let's have a look.
Just get rid of that image
down here and we'll get rid of hello world as well.
Wonderful.
So that looks really nice perfectly sized to our screen and it doesn't look badly stretched.
All right.
It's going well.
Let's start adding some content.
So I'm going to put everything in sight.
I can take the day of
and I'm going to start with an H1
which will say what's the weather so let's have a little look at that.
OK.
Not bad.
But first I wanted to be centered and I definitely don't want it to have a white background.
So let's set
the background of body which remember we'll set the background of everything within it as well to none.
And that should get rid of this problem.
So now everything is going to be on top of our nice background image.
And let's see if I can to everything in container using text.
The line is sent to great looking good so far.
Let's just move that down a little bit
we'll give it a margin top of 200 pixels.
OK that's fine for now we may want to play around with the positioning when we've got the rest of our
content in but that will do for now.
So under these what's underneath what's the weather that's have a paragraph tag into the name of a city.
And then we'll have our form.
So as we're adding a bootstrap component always good to get the code direct from Bootstrap.
Otherwise we're likely to forget something important.
Not that our form is going to be particularly complicated.
But in fact let's just take the default form we can get rid of what we don't need.
OK great so we actually once is
that first input and
the submit button.
And in fact we could put this as a label.
We'll see if that works out for us.
So this is going to be a label for city that type is going to be text email the ID is going to be city
and the placeholder will put e.g. London comma here to give them an idea of what we're after and when
we're worried about sharing our email address here.
So let's take a look.
OK.
Nice but a bit too wide there I think it's a little bit ridiculous.
So let's limit that fact we can just limit the width of our container.
Let's try something like 350 pixels a little narrower
400 pixels
built in our 450 that we get that looks better.
So we're looking is if I enter a city name however it doesn't actually submit through as you can see
there.
And why is that.
It's because we're missing a name for our input.
So have a name of a city as well.
So now if we put London in them we get London in.
You are right up the top.
I would like to just spread things out a little bit.
So I think I'll add a bit of styling for my inputs which will give it a margin of let's say 20 pixels
on the top and bottom.
We don't need any margin on the left or right should spread things out a little bit more nicely quite.
I'm happy with that.
So now the fun bit as I mentioned at the beginning we're going to use a Web site called weather dash
forecast or come here we go and let's go for the weather forecast for London.
So as I mentioned what we want is to extract this forecast here.
So for now let's not worry about that in the user.
But we'll just get the London weather every time and let's get the contents of this page and take a
look at it so that we can work out how to extract what we need.
A case so we're going to do this at the very top of our script.
And we'll do this if someone has requested a city
then we'll set up a forecast page and this is going to be file get contents and the file that we want
to get the contents of is that one and for now we'll just echo forecast page to make sure that we've
got it and to see what the code is.
OK did I write something wrong.
Yes I did.
I spelt it wrong in the first place.
Aggregate those warnings are really handy.
Great.
So we've got to code.
It's kind of mixing weirdly with our page now.
But let's have a look at the source.
So I'm going to use command.
You can also right click and view source and then if you want to find the bit you're interested in.
We want the weather forecast summary.
So I'm going to use Command F or control f on Windows and we want weather forecast summary Let's have
a look.
OK.
So this is what we want we want to extract that bit there.
So we want to get rid of everything before this selected part and we want to get rid of everything after
as well.
As I mentioned that's something that we haven't done yet.
So let's think of a sensible thing to Google to figure out how to do it.
Remember the AGM is just a string.
And what we're trying to do is split it up.
So let's see if we can get anything as a result for PH P and split up string split a string by a string.
That sounds pretty perfect to us.
Let's have a look.
So the explode functions even got a cool name.
I always like to scroll straight down to an example because that makes it a lot clearer.
Aha ha so it looks like with the explode function I can put in a string and then another string and
it will split up that string into an array.
By whatever I put in the string.
So that seems pretty perfect.
Let's take a look.
Said the bit before.
What we want to get rid of is that but then that looks a bit generic to me.
So I think that might appear in the page more than once so I'm going to select more of them.
That's I suspect this bit will only appear in the page once.
So I'm just going to copy that and just do a search for it as well.
I'll actually appears several times.
So that's no good.
I need to select a bit more so London is going to change because we're always going to be looking for
London.
So let's select up to three day weather forecast.
Surely that will only appear once it does.
So what we're going to do is we're going to explode the string using this as our many string to explain
it with and then then array where the zeroth item is everything before.
What we want and the first item is starting with what we want and then the rest of the page which will
need to get rid of later on.
All right let's give that a try.
So we want say create Let's call it a page array.
And this is going to be explode and then we want to explode it by that string there.
Notice I've used single quotes there because there are some double quotes in the string itself.
So it makes life easier.
I don't have to escape them.
And then the thing that we want to explode is forecast page.
All right.
So now we have a look at page array one should start with exactly the code that we want and there we
go you see we've got some weirdness down there which we're going to get rid of now but it does start
exactly where we wanted to great.
So we're getting that.
Let's now have a look at the beginning of the part that we want to get rid of and that is this end of
span here.
So three span closes.
I don't need to be so careful about whether that appears multiple times in the page anymore because
all I want to do is get rid of the first one.
We don't really care what happens further on down here.
So we need to do another explained.
So let's have a second page.
Right.
And this is going to be explode again and we're going to expose it explain it by that little string.
And the thing that we want to explode is page.
What.
All right.
Now then second page Auray zero should be exactly the code that we want.
There it is wonderful perfect.
So what we need to do is put that in our output and display it nicely to the user.
And let's give it a nice a variable name as well.
So I'll just call it whether weather is equal to that.
And then we're going to display the weather underneath the submit button down here.
So we're going to need to do that
so we'll have I.D. is equal to weather.
And then we can just put some ph P right in that
to say if we have some weather
then we want to display the weather.
And we're going to do that with a nice beat strap as well.
So it looks pretty.
So let's have a success.
Let
again I'm using single quites
so I didn't have to worry about
any double quotes in the string itself.
And then we just want to get the weather right in there.
So let's have a look.
Hasn't displayed that nicely for me.
Not a problem.
We can just spend it.
To the rest of the string there we go.
OK that's good.
I think we need to move everything up a little bit.
So let's change the margin top to 100 pixels.
And also I want a bit of a margin there between the button and the alert so let's style out a weather
alert.
Just checking.
I call that weather
give it a margin of 15 pixels.
Great.
So that looks good.
Let's see if we can change our code to work with any city name
site.
First off let's try just replacing London with
the city that was entered by the use of which is to get it right and then city.
So if I now put Tokyo in them
we get the weather for Tokyo.
Wonderful.
Let's just play around and see what happens.
What if I put a capital T for Tokyo.
Does that mess things up.
No it still works great.
One of the cities that we did think we might have an issue with is San Francisco because it's got a
space in it.
And then things go horribly wrong.
So we get a nasty four or four ERA but we should be able to fix that quite easily by just removing all
the spaces in the string as we saw at the beginning of the video because let's just remind ourselves
why that should work.
So if we search for San Francisco then you can see it puts in a hyphen there but we don't even need
to do that because if we remove the space it'll put the hyphen in for us.
So all we need to do is remove the spaces from our string.
Got to be an easy way to do that.
Have a google page remove spaces from string.
Hey we get how to strip out all spaces from a string.
And here we go.
Oh yeah.
So we've got SDR underskirt replace and it replaces anything we put in there with whatever we put in
there.
So if we want to remove something we just put that in there and then nothing in the second
that looks perfect for us.
So we can change the get variable itself
so we want to replace spaces with nothing in
they get array City OK let's have a look now.
If I now put San Francisco in them and submit it works great.
Fantastic.
What if I put in a city and here it doesn't exist.
Let's see what happens there.
We get a nasty error message.
So ideally we want to do two things.
Want to stop that warning coming and we want to let the user know that their search for that particular
city hasn't worked.
It might also be worth keeping the users city in the input here as well so that they can see what they
search for.
Let's do that last bit.
First it's actually quite straightforward.
We need to do is set a value attribute for the inputs and then without ph P We just echo
the city.
There we go.
So that should work fine.
I've just realized that that's going to remove the spaces from it which will look a bit weird for the
user.
So let's use a city variable up here.
And then we'll leave the gate array unchanged.
So let's just check that's actually him and
if I put something like that in there it doesn't strip out the spaces for the input.
It'd be nice to not have these nasty warnings though.
So to do that we need to check whether or not this page actually exists.
So let's see if we can do that.
HP
something like that check if you are ill exists.
Perfect.
And here we go.
This looks pretty perfect So we're getting the file headers and we're checking to see whether they are
equal to or forfour not found error brilliant.
Looks like exactly what we want.
So let's try that out.
So once with
we'll check this.
We want to get the R L up here.
There we go.
And if
the file headers are for for not found them we want to give the user an error.
Otherwise
we'll do that.
So first off that should get rid of the nasty warnings at the top of the page.
That's excellent.
Although we do have a warning down here now.
Not a problem.
So let's set weather to be an empty string
at the very beginning.
And then we lose that error.
So this is great but we're not showing the use of that anything's gone wrong here.
So let's say if they file head as a 4 4 then let's have an error string
something like that City could not be found.
OK.
And we'll put a string up there.
And initially it's going to be empty and we'll do this here in a very similar way.
So if there's some weather then will display the weather if there's an error then we'll display the
error.
But this time with a danger alert.
So it's nice in red and scary.
All right let's give that a go.
Excellent.
Looking great.
So this is pretty perfect.
The one thing I do want to check for is the possibility that even though we could find that page we
still couldn't extract the weather.
And that's certainly not impossible if the page we're getting our data from changes it's HDMI out which
it could well do then that will break our script and we'd like to have a friendly error message if that
happens rather than some nasty warning.
So let's have a couple of checks in place for this.
And I'll just expand a little so that we can say it all going on.
So for this to work we need to have a pager right being right with at least two items in it so we can
check to see if size of page array is greater than one because it will always have at least one thing
in it.
Because if this is not there at all then it will just return the whole string.
So if it is greater than one that means that something is going well
so we'll carry on.
If it's not then we've got an area.
So we'll just have the same error as before.
That city could not be found and then we'll do the same thing here.
Once we get the second page array we'll do a check to see if size of second page array
is greater than one then we want to set the weather
equal to that.
If it's not then something's gone wrong.
So again let's give that error message.
Great.
Now we can actually make that happen.
Whoops I've got a nasty error there on online 23 What have I done.
Oh yeah.
There we go.
I haven't put brackets around page array.
And I haven't even closed my brackets in the second if statement as well.
Not my finest hour but they would get greater as I was saying we can't test that because all of our
cities should either fully work or not work at all.
But let's just have a working one.
So Paris looks great.
And then we can simulate if we got.
So if they changed three day to four day
Van we get a nice error message.
Now whereas before we would have got some nasty warnings and then just no output.
So when you're using other sites in this way you need to be very careful because they could change the
HDMI at any time and you want your app to not break or at least if it does break to break and a nice
user friendly way.
Great.
So once again congratulations on making it to the end of the HP section of the complete web developer
course.
I hope you enjoyed it and I hope you manage to make at least most of the weather scraper by yourself.
We now have just one piece left of the Web Developer puzzle and that is storing changing user data online.
And for that we use databases and the most popular database used in web development today is Maya school.
And that's what we're going to be looking at in the next section.
And just before I leave you there is one more thing I'd like to point out that we do get a warning with
the code in its current form and we get that if we don't enter a city name at all and that's because
we're checking here to see if they get array has a city variable but we need to check that in a different
way to avoid getting a warning here.
Remember we won't get this warning if we were running on a live site because we would switch off ph
warnings.
But it's always nice when we're developing to avoid warnings wherever we can.
So let's see if there's a better way to check if an array has a certain key
or we get check if the given key or index exists in the array.
Array underscore key exists.
Perfect
OK so that's what we want.
So let's just replace that
we're checking the get array for
the key city.
All right.
So let's just run that again and make sure we no longer get that warning.
Just put a test in safety can be found
here again and we get our Web just to be absolutely sure.
Get rid of the city reload the page and we do get one notice down there in the inputs.
So we'll need to do a quick check again to see if the city key exists and we'll do that here.
Give us a bit of room
if the key exists.
Well to supply whatever it is
to bring that back in OK.
Just check that now.
Excellent.
We get our placeholder and we can still put it in London and get the weather.
There you go.
Hope that helps if you are confused by that warning.
Now on to my ask you El.