All right so now we've seen how four loops can be used to cycle through arrays.
We'll see how we can do exactly the same thing with a WHILE loop and then we'll see a different example
that shows the situation that you might prefer using a while loop rather than a flip.
So I'm going to take what we've got here and just turn it into a WHILE loop.
First off from a follow up should hopefully make it pretty clear how while loops work.
So remember with a for loop we start off with stating that I is initially zero.
And then we keep going as long as I is less than the number of tweets or the number of items in this
array.
And we increased by one every time.
So to do that with a WHILE loop we would set high to be zero outside the loop this time.
And then we get rid of our four instructions and replace that with a while and then always state in
the definition of loop is the condition for the while loop to continue.
So while I is less than and again tweets dot length
so this will now keep going as long as I is less than tweet length.
What we don't have yet is an instruction to increase.
I buy one every time and that is now a complete while League which will do exactly the same thing as
the for loop that we had before.
So let's just check yeah.
There we go.
We get exactly the same output but you can see the logic is a little bit different.
We're defining our count variable first then we're saying keep going as long as our count variable is
less than this.
And then each time the loop goes through we're manually adding 1 to i.
So it's the same thing but structured slightly differently.
I actually prefer while loops generally because they're a bit more flexible but in most cases when you're
using a for loop you could use a while loop.
It's up to you.
So when Mike a while loop be a good idea.
Well to demonstrate that I'm going to go back to how how many fingers app but I'm going to turn it around.
So instead of us guessing how many fingers the computer is holding up the computer has to guess how
many fingers we're holding up.
And essentially I'm going to set it up so we state how many fingers we're holding up.
And then the computer keeps taking random guesses until it gets it right and then it tells you how many
guesses it took.
So I'm going to set this as a optional challenge.
So it's quite a tricky one but we're not going to do any googling.
There's no new information here.
It's just using wild loops in a more advanced way.
So I'll give you a moment to put the video and give it a shot if you're feeling confident.
All right.
Well don't worry if it didn't it was a tricky one as I said.
So I'm going to start by saying how many fingers are you.
That is the user of the Web site holding up.
And then we'll have an input with I type of text.
I had an ID of let's call it my number
and then I button
that says guess and we'll give that an idea of guess that's it.
So the idea is that we'll say three and then the computer will have to guess so as usual we want the
action to commence when the guest button is pressed.
So we'll set that up document or get an element by id
guess and then we want to add an own click to that which is our usual function and then curly brackets.
And then I'm not going to do a check immediately this time because I'm pretty confident about that but
I'll set up a variable my number which is going to equal whatever the user has entered.
So that's going to be document to get element by id and the ID is my number and we want the value of
that.
As we've seen before and I'm just going to let my number just because I don't want to do too much before
we know that everything is set up.
OK William that's looking good.
So now we're going to get the computer to choose a random number between 0 and 5.
So we've done this before.
So we'll call this guess.
And that's initially going to be math to random then we most play by six
and then we use math floor to make it a whole number between 0 and 5.
All right then we want to do a check to see if
the computer got it right.
So if guess is equal to my number.
Then the computer got it right.
So for now I'm just going to put a little comment in there.
Computers correct else
computer is wrong.
So what we want to happen is we want this to go on and on and on until we get to here.
The computer is correct.
And then we want to tell the user how many goals it took.
So what I'm going to do is set up a variable called.
Got it.
And this is going to be a new type of variable that we haven't seen before which is called a Boullion
and a boolean variable is either true or false.
So initially I got it is false because it hasn't got it yet.
And then when it has got it we'll set.
Got it to say this is the clever bit we're going to keep going as long as it is false.
And we're actually going to keep doing all of this until it is no longer false.
So let's end on that so that we can say this is all part of the While loop.
So remember the computer gets it at this point.
If gas is equal to my number.
So at this point we will set.
Got it.
Is equal to true.
And we also want to let
go it
and now if they're wrong we want to just add one to the number of guesses so that we know how many guesses
the computer has had.
So let's set that number of guesses.
So we'll start off one because it's going to take the computer at least one guess.
And then if the computer gets it wrong we'll add 1 to the number of guesses.
So take a moment just to see the logic of this.
As long as it is false We're going to go round and round.
In fact there's a slight problem there.
I closed my curly bracket.
Yeah that's better.
So as long as God it is false We're going to go round and round keep guessing until got it becomes true
and then we won't do it again.
So you can hopefully see one big advantage of this is that while loops can have varying lengths.
Now that is true for Phillips as well.
But while loops are kind of set up for that more naturally.
So this is simply going to keep going until the computer gets it right.
So let's just justify that we've got it right by
telling the user what it was.
So it was I.
And then we're going to we could use either guess or my number here.
They're both the same doesn't really matter.
Or use guess.
And then we need to say it took me and then let's just expand this so we can see it clearly number of
guesses guesses.
Hopefully if that makes sense.
We're going to say.
Got it.
It was.
And then whatever the number was.
It took me a number of guesses guesses.
So let's have a look.
I've done quite a lot there without checking so fingers crossed it work.
So let's try three and guess.
Got it.
It was a three.
It took me nine guesses.
Sounds about right to me two guesses.
Excellent.
So it looks like our system is working.
Fantastic.
All right so that's how a while loop here works and how potentially it can go on until something happens.
We don't necessarily have to state how many times it's going to happen in advance.
It does give me the opportunity for a quick warning though.
And when you use while loops like this we need to be careful that our while loop is not going to potentially
go on forever.
Now we're guessing continue random numbers here that this is a very small possibility we could go on
for ages and ages before the computer gets it right.
But that's pretty unlikely and I'd be willing to let that go.
But as we've got a free input here.
They use a kid and a six for example.
And if we press guess now something very bad is going to happen.
And essentially what we've done is we've crash the browser because the computer is never going to get
it because the computer only guess is 0 1 2 3 4 or 5.
So it's not going to get 6.
So we'd have to have a check in place.
I'm just going to restart that page hopefully it will let me.
But we should definitely have a check to make sure that the user has entered 0 1 2 3 4 or 5.
There we go.
It's even become unresponsive.
Yikes.
We definitely want to avoid that.
So a better option here would be a drop down.
So my final challenge for you for this video is to change the input to a dropdown or select which only
allows the user to enter 0 1 2 3 4 or 5 different.
All right.
You remember how to do it.
I've actually realized that I've forgotten to close the Powerball off as well so let's do that.
So instead of an input we're going to have a select the ID will remain the same but then we'll have
our options.
So we've got 0
1 2 3 4 5 is in
there we go and the select and then have a button.
And I think we slightly need to actually to put the paragraph down there.
There we go.
So let's take a look.
This now is cleaner and there should be no way that they should crash.
One final way that you could be absolutely certain would be to have a check at some point to see if
the number of guesses was bigger than 100 or something like that.
And if that was the case then something's probably going wrong.
Now be a good way to make absolutely sure this thing wasn't going to crash.
All right.
So that's a good use of while loops.
You'll be pleased to hear that you've nearly made it to the end of the JavaScript section.
We've got one more video on functions coming up next.
And then we're going to be making our big javascript project which is a reaction.