OK now we know how to style our text.
We're going to see how we can align it.
So this essentially means having it on the left of the page the right of the page in the middle or justify
it's spread out to fill the whole page.
So let's take just our first paragraph and we'll get rid of the bold class
because we don't going to be bold anymore or not in terms of CSSA any way that we get.
So if I want this text aligned to the right of the page then I simply do text a line and then I can
see the options there.
The one that I want this time of course is right.
And very simple.
I will align it to the right of the page or to be more precise I should say it will align it's to the
right of the parent element.
So this is the element which this is contained in so the paragraph tag is currently contained within
the body tag so it aligns to the right of the body tag which is essentially the right of the page.
But if I put it inside say a DIV tag
and then I set that div tag to have say a width of maybe 300 pixels.
And let's do a background color as well.
Just hope we can see it really clearly then you can see the text lines to the right of the div because
the paragraph tag is now contained within the div.
So this alignment applies to the container element or the parent element.
OK.
I'm just going to set a height for this div as well so it's a little bit bigger and then you can see
what I text is doing.
So that's our right aligned text
left aligned is obviously standard.
You can use text to line is left if you want to but it will be left by default anyway.
So a quick challenge for you can you create another paragraph tag with some scented text in it for it.
All right.
Have you managed it.
Let's have a class of scented and I'm going to spell it here.
Otherwise you get very confused because we have to use the correct or American spellings in our code.
So that's have a sentence and then very simply as I hope you manage to figure out text align center
it is this text is sent.
Take a look.
There it is.
So the re-aligned is officially still right aligned and that is then centered.
OK so that's almost all we need to see but I'd like to show you justified as well.
Incidentally one of my favorite TV programs as well but not one of my favorite spacings I think it often
looks pretty odd on Web sites.
She have a really big chunk of text but that's obviously up to you as the web designer.
So to create justified
text we just use as you might imagine text a line is and then justify
now not to see the difference here we're probably going to need several copies of that sentence.
And let's make it a little bit taller as well.
Let's take a look.
There we go.
So you can see what's happened there is it stretched the text right to the edge of the page and it does
that by changing the letter and word spacing so sometimes that might make your text look a little bit
strange especially if you've got some long words.
So I'd use justified sparingly but if you want to use it that's how you do it.
All right.
So that's where we get to see ends of text alignment.
But at this point there is one more thing I want to show you when you're creating a website for a client.
Quite often they won't have given you the copy for the Web site yet and you'll need to put some web
site copy in there.
You don't generally want to put this text justified repeated lots and lots of times because it doesn't
look very natural and the client will be a bit confused.
So you may have seen something called lorem ipsum.
Now if you really want to know the facts behind Lorem Ipsden you can click that first link.
But I'm going to jump straight to the generator which is a really handy page for basically creating
a lot in text.
I have no idea what that means.
I don't really care.
But what I can do is then just take that text and copy it into my page there.
Let's get rid of the height so that it can change the height automatically and then have a look.
And now I've got a much more realistic idea of how that text is going to look regardless of what text
gets put in there eventually.
So Lorem Ipsum has become the Internet standard for generic text.
If you want to see what your web site's going to look like before you have the actual text.
This will give you a pretty good idea.
All right.
So we're nearly there.
Just one more video to go.
We're going to look at lynx in a little bit more detail.
And those pseudo classes that we saw very briefly in the previous video and then we're going to be on
our big CSSA challenge recreating the BBC News website.