So it's all well and good being able to create and manage our database through ph my admin.
But to be able to do anything useful with it we need to be able to connect to it with a ph piece script.
And that's what we can do in this video.
So I'm going to go back over to fire FGP and create a new folder or directory and I'm going to call
this 7 my su l.
There we go.
And then within that folder I'm going to create a new file which will be indexed top HP and that will
be what we'll be working with for most of this section.
So I'm going to use the command 0 0 controller in windows to open that up in brackets and then I should
be able to access that page at a complete web develop because dot com slash content slash 7 Ifan my
ask.
Well that looks promising we've got a blank page so far.
Let's just add a quick bit of content here and refresh just to make sure we're all linked up.
We are indeed wonderful.
So the main challenge for this video is to connect using HP to our database.
And that's actually pretty straightforward.
We create some new ph code in the same way that we're used to.
And then there's just a single command to connect to a database and that is my Eskew L I underscore
connect the there is short for improved and some of you may have worked with databases before or searched
on line and seen my Eskew underscore connect like that.
That's a very popular way to connect to a database.
But I definitely wouldn't recommend it.
It's officially deprecated now which means it's not supported and it's certainly not as secure as my
as you well I underscore connect if you want to learn more about the differences and why you should
use this version rather than just my ask you will connect.
Then have a quick google.
My is to l vs. my SU ally.
Something like that will give you all the reasons in detail why you should use this version.
But if you've never seen this before then just consider this the best way to connect to a miniscule
database.
It's worth noting that there is third way to connect to a database called PTO.
And again if you're interested in these things feel free to have a google and check out pedia.
But I'm going to go for my askaris lie because it's secure it's supported and it's much easier to use
I think than PDA.
All right so we have to pass three variables to the.
My Ask your ally.
Connect function and the first one is the server name of our database.
Now because I'm running this script on complete web developer because dot com and I set up my database
on complete web developer course dot com as well.
I can use what's called localhost and this is a general keyword that you can use to refer to the server
that is running your scripts.
You'll also be able to use localhost if you're working with an Apache server on your own machine.
If for some reason though your database is on a different server to the script that you are trying to
connect to you can still connect to it but you need to use the server IP address which is this one here.
So in my case it's 79 to 1 7 0 4 4 1 to 5.
So I would just replace that with the IP address.
However if you are running it on the same server I would definitely recommend using localhost because
the IP address can in some cases change.
So I would only use the IP address if you absolutely have to.
All right so that's the server that we want to connect the next we need to give the database user name.
So that's the whole of this thing here.
So C-L 29 hyphen uses hyphen B's at H.
You should put whatever you've got here when you created your database.
And finally of course we need the password
which is in my case that I may well have changed that password.
By the time you're watching this video.
So don't try and connect to this database.
It might not work.
You should definitely connect to your.
All right.
So that's it.
What happens when we run that script absolutely nothing.
That's because it's connected to the database.
But we haven't all told it to do anything with that connection.
So it's obviously very useful to know in our script whether or not that connection was successful and
if it's not then we should give an error message of some sort to the user.
So there's a built in my ask well I connect error function which will be empty.
If there's no error but will contain an error if there is one.
So let's echo that for the moment and let's generate an error by misspelling localhost.
I'm putting an E on the end.
Let's see what we get.
OK.
So you can see we've got an error there.
Get address info failed so it's trying to get the address info for the server and it's failing because
it doesn't exist.
If I correct that then the message goes away.
So that's pretty much it.
Just a very quick challenge for you then.
Can you change this code so that instead of just echoing the error we have an if statement that says
if the connection was successful tell the user that it was successful.
If it wasn't.
Tell the user that it wasn't Durford
all rights.
How did you manage that.
It's pretty straightforward.
We just need an if statement and then we're going to put that in itself in the if statement because
remember I said it was empty.
If the connection was successful
if there is an error then we should echo.
There was an error connecting to the database.
You should never echo the error itself on a public Web site because that may give way details as to
what you're trying to connect to which is never good.
If there is no error that means it's been successful.
So again we never actually display this to the user.
But for now we'll just say database connection.
Successful
All right.
Let's take a look.
Wonderful.
We're now connected to the database and ready to create some interactive data storing Web sites in order
to do that of course.
We've got to be able to take data from the database and be able to edit and update that data.
And that's what we'll do in the next few videos.