All right.
So we're making pretty good progress.
We can now view the latest public tweets.
And of course we've got our logging system working well and we've got our code.
If not the actual functions for searching tweets and posting tweets.
So in this video we're going to see how to set up following and unfollow in specific users.
Let's get the model set up first.
So we'll be creating a new table in our Twitter database.
And this is going to be able to keep track of who's following who.
So I'm going to call it is following
and as usual we'll have an I.D. for each relationship
and we'll have follower and is following and they'll both be integers because they're going to refer
to the user IDs
and then if we look back over on our recent tweets page we've got a follow instruction that.
So that's where we're going to write our code for following a user.
It's all going to be nice and fancy with AJAX.
So let's set up a link here which is not going to go anywhere.
But it will have a class of I'll call it toggle follow and I'm going to add to that a data variable
of user ID.
Which is going to be equal say
the
user id of the post to
which is what I use or Id
like that.
And remember we can access any data variable we like using query
OK.
So let's just check that that's worked.
Here we go.
It's a link and then we quickly view the source.
We should be able to just see that the data attribute is the
data user ID is 7 and 8 that
wonderful.
So now let's write some query to do something when the toggle follow
links are clicked and we'll write that in footer top HP
say let's set up how toggle follow links to have a click function.
And initially I'm going to set up my click function to be alert and I'm going to try and get the value
of that attribute which we do using dot ITTL and then the name of the attribute which is data Dasch
user ID.
So let's just have a look and see if everything is connected up right.
We should get a 7 and an 8 let it in our
excellent.
So then we're going to need to to either follow the user up or unfollow the user depending on whether
the user is currently followed or not.
So let's do that with a bit of Ajax
so I'm just going to copy that down.
As before and we're going to post two actions Doppie HP but this time the action is going to be Tuggle
follow.
And the only data that we need is the user id and that's going to be equal to this attribute here.
There we go and as before
we will do something else with this later on.
But for now we'll just let results
great.
So we're looking for an action value of toggle follow now.
So let's go see the actions that HP check for the existence of that
action is equal to Toko follow them will be as before and just display the post variables again to make
sure that everything is connected up right.
Let's take a look.
Something has gone horribly wrong.
Let's have a quick inspect right in the car so AZT is not defined.
OK let's have a look and fit it up there.
Oh yes that's because I've forgotten this.
Fair enough.
Let's have another go.
That's great.
So I was getting the response from actioned up HP and it's receiving the user ID.
So now the first thing we're going to need to do is to check whether our current user is following this
particular user or not.
So we can do that with a query which is going to be something pretty similar to what we've got up here.
So I'm going to just copy that down.
That by this time we're going to select from the following table
and we want to select where our user is following the other user.
So we want to check that the follower is our current user and is following is the user that we're checking
said the user ID.
So we want
the follower to be our current user.
I'm going to use
my ask you apply real escape string link and then
session id and we want is following to be quilty.
And we want to check that.
But this time we're checking post user ID
and I'm just going to cheat slightly and comment that out I'm just echoing my query which is a nice
trick to make sure that everything is working ok.
I select staff from it's following with fulva is 9 and is following is 7 limit.
1 great
let's get rid of that.
So if the number of hours of the result is greater than zero then that means that they are following.
So we need to follow them.
So let's make that happen.
Essentially we just need to delete the entry from the database.
So we're going to need to get the ID of the entry which will be using Why is my your ally fetch a stock
result and then we're going to my secure ally query link and then delete from
is following
where ID is equal to and then we once
a real escape stirring again.
This time we want ID
and we'll pop a limit one on the end.
Always a good idea when you are deleting
and then I'm going to echo one.
So one in this parlance is going to mean that we've unfollowed the use of
the other option of course is that we're going to follow the user set else
this time.
I'm just going to copy those bits down instead of deleting.
We're going to insert into is following and we want to set the follow up.
And is following
we want to set the values
to
the follower we want to be our current user say session id
and then we want is following a
they post
user ID.
Right now I've done quite a lot.
I'm going to change that to a T.
Let's try this out see what happens.
OK we've got a see.
That's promising.
Let's go back and have a look in the database and say yep we do indeed have our followers and is following
a relationship set up which means of course if I press it again we should get one and that should mean
the relationship has been deleted.
Wonderful.
And then a two and a one etc..
Brilliant.
So the backend part is now working.
Let's just update footed up HP
site if result is equal to 1.
Remember one means they've been unfollowed and what we want to do here is check to see if results is
equal to 1.
And remember one means that we've unfollowed.
So we want to change all the links for that particular user ID to follow.
So I think what we'll do here is update this code to have an ID
which is equal to the user ID that we're being followed and then here we'll find all the links that
have a data user id of
get this right Id
think I need that one there actually.
And we want to set there each team to follow
and
if the result is too we want to do the same thing set then hated him DML to follow.
All right let's take a look.
Say reichlich follow them at changes to unfollowed.
Fantastic.
And if I check unfollowed it changes back to full.
And same with that link.
They're brilliant.
So now that we've got following set up I'm just going to follow one user here and then we're in a position
to set up the timeline.
So if you remember we called that page timeline.
So I'm going to go back over to T.P. and interviews creates a file called Timeline top HP open that
up and then not forgetting an index top page to check to see if
we get a page of timeline
then will include views slash timeline dot page.
And we're going to have a string of those and if none of them are true we'll include the home page
Okay.
So then
I'll just put a little bit of text on timeline that page.
And we should now be able to click on your timeline and see that little bit of text in the middle of
our page.
There it is.
Wonderful So let's
copy over our code from home to APHC to time lined up page.
Because things are going to be fairly similar here.
The only real difference is that I'm going to put tweets for you here.
And I'm going to change display tweets to is following.
So that means we only want the tweets of the people that user is following.
And to do that we're going to need to build a WHERE clause.
So we'll do this in the case that type is equal to is following.
And what we're going to need to do is check the following table for the IDs of the users that our user
is following and then constructs a query string based on those.
So we can grab a bit of code from actions to Page Pate Tabari for that.
And now we want to select everything from is following where the follower is our current user and that's
all we care about.
And we want all of them and then we're going to get the results.
We don't really have a need to check whether there are any.
We're just going to leap through any results that they're raw.
So let's initially set how where clause to be empty.
And then we need to be careful here to construct the right where clause so if where clause is empty
then we'll set it equal.
See
where
user id Senatus with searching tweets.
Now
and tweets stores that has user ID with a small as it happens.
That's not great but it will be fine where user ID is equal to the row and then we want the user ID
that our user is following which is following and if where clause is not empty then we won't see a penny
to it.
All
and then user ID et cetera.
So in fact what the is if it's empty I'll say that the cruelty where
if it's not I'll append all and then either way or add to append
user ID is equal to a and then is following.
So that should construct a potentially quite large string which starts with a where and then has a user
id equal to.
And then one of the followings or it's equal to something else or is equal to something else.
It should essentially generate all the tweets of the users that I use the following.
So fingers crossed something's gone horribly wrong.
Sometimes a refresh fixes it.
OK so it wasn't that bad but it hasn't generated what we want.
I'll tell you what let's cheat again and just echo out the query to see if there's an error in our Escudo
select staff from tweets where it user ID.
Aha I think we're missing a space
easily done.
I have another look.
There we go.
William So now we can get rid of the query.
And we're just seeing that one tweet that.
But that does remind me that we've got the option here to follow.
Which isn't right because we're already following this user site.
We're going to need to update functions dot ph HP to check here whether the user is following that user.
And if they all select follow and if not select on the follow say let's change that see and then and
then we'll have a second echo afterwards and then we want to check the user is following this other
user so we can actually use very similar code to what we had that say select stuff from following where
follower is our current user and is following is this time row.
User ID rather than post them at.
And then we get our results.
But I think we want to rename those.
So we did confuse the main string.
So let's have is following query
and then is following query result.
And that and that and is following query and then so if the number of rows is greater than zero.
We didn't actually need to get the result we just need to write on full light because that means that
they are being followed
else.
I follow it because they're not following that use.
OK.
Let's take a look.
We should now see unfollow appear that and there we go.
Fantastic.
And if we link back to the home page as well we should see that we're following one of them but not
the other problem.
And of course we can choose to follow both if we want.
And that means that they'll buy appear on our timeline.
There we go.
So that's following and unfaltering sorted.
The next challenge is for the use of themselves to be able to post a tweet.
And that's what we're going to see in the next video.