Get our first taste of API is we're going to be working with open weather map and we're going to use
its API to get the weather rather than scraping it from a Web site as we did before.
So as a quick reminder Previously we used weather forecast dot com and we noted that if you search for
a particular location then it puts that location in the U R L and then we load it that you are l using
file get contents in HP and we extract it.
The weather forecast from that HVM page but we said at the time that that wasn't an ideal thing to do.
Partly because we might get banned from doing that by the owners of weather forecast to come if we use
their service too much.
And also because we're vulnerable to weather forecast not comet changing the age DML structure which
would then break our code and our web app wouldn't work anymore.
So a much better way to do it is to use an API.
Let's have a quick look and see how the open weather map API works.
So on open weather map I'm going to click API and you can see they've got a number of different API
functions.
You can get the current weather five day forecast 16 day forecast etc..
We're going for the current weather at the moment so I'm going to click API doc and you're welcome to
read this in a bit more detail if you want to know more about what's going on here.
But essentially what we need to do is to get a particular u r l like this one so API open weather maps
are August like status like 2.5 weather and then we've got a query string.
Remember Mark and then queue is equal to.
And then our location.
So I just open that up in a new tablet see what that you r l actually looks like.
All right.
This is it says not particularly friendly looking but this is in a format that the script that we're
going to use we'll be able to process.
It's actually a format called Jason short for javascript object notation but it doesn't necessarily
have to have anything to do with Javascript.
And we're going to use it in H-P here.
So all we're going to do is grab the contents of this u r l using file get contents process the Jason
and then extract the bits of the weather forecast that we want and display them to the user just as
before.
All right.
You may have noticed that we need to sign up for an API key so I'm going to do that like most API is
this has a pretty big free tier so you can practice and mess around with it.
You need to start paying if you have a large number of users requesting data which is fair enough.
So let's get our free API key.
So I'm going to be first of all Rob Percival.
OK.
Okay.
My last word in here
agree to the terms of service and then create account.
So now I'm all set up and the key thing that I need in more ways than one is the API key here and I'm
going to replace then the u r l the u r l had a default API key.
So instead of using that I'm going to use my own one.
You should use your own one and will get the same results that we did before.
Notice it can take a couple of minutes for your API key to start working.
All right so now we've got our API data.
Let's jump over to fire FTB and I'm going to create a new section so I'm going to create directory and
this is going to be 8 an API.
So we'll get into that folder.
And then I've actually got the PH p.s. from the Course here.
And the file that I need is seven point one three page.
That was the what's the weather app and I'm going to grab the background image as well.
So it still looks nice.
You can get those either from your own version of the what's the weather app or just go back to the
lecture and click on the link to download the code.
All right.
Now I'm just going to rename that
index dot ph p.
And then we should be able to jump to crime and find our new page.
So this is going to be complete web developer because dot com slash content slash 8 API is slash and
we should see the what's the weather app.
There we go.
Wonderful.
And let's just check that it still works.
But Tokyo in them it does indeed wonderful.
So that's great.
Let's now open up using Komando control indexed ph P in our textedit to say I'm going to get rid of
everything.
We don't need here.
So I'm just going to take us right down to the if there is a city variable in the get string and find
out what we'll do is we'll just load the data that we need.
So I've just copied the you are l there.
So there it is.
And we want file get contents and we want to get the contents of that U R L but we want to replace the
city with
the city that the user has entered.
And we want to leave Spidey in that
and find out we'll just echo that so it will display the results just to make sure that we've got some
There we go.
Wonderful.
So we need to then process this data so we can extract what we need.
So I'm going to call this you r l contents
and then remember this is in adjacent format of the moment and we want to get it into an array so we
can extract the data.
Fortunately we've got a built in function to process Jasen in ph P and that is J-Zone underscore the
code does what it says on the tin the code straight on content.
So we'll take you Arel contents
and we'll convert that into an array which I'll call
whether away and then we're just going to add a flag here.
True which will return the data in the form of an associative array which we can then extract the data
that we need from.
So let's have a look
at the contents of whether array
there.
So you can see the same data.
I'm just going to write click and view page source so that we can see it a bit more clearly.
All right.
So this is all the data we can then access the main description.
It's now changed to overclass.
Overcast clouds and we've got things like temperature pressure humidity wind speed all the information
we could possibly want and we just need to extract this and put it into a format that we can use to
give to the user.
So I'm going to start off with this weather description here and be useful to know exactly what sort
of things might appear here.
So I'm just going to jump quickly back to open weather map.
So the org slash API
and take a look at the API doc again for the current weather data and you can see there's a huge amount
of information about how we can get information by zip code by city ID etc. even in cities within a
particular area.
But what I'm particularly interested in now are the parameters and what values they give us.
So you can see we've got caught at the top which we've got up here which is of course just the enormity
of the latitude of the location.
And then in the weather many are right we've got weather condition ID which we're not going to pay much
attention to them have got weather parameters and this one I've been looking at is the weather condition
within the court.
So I'm going to start with that one
and what we'll do is we'll start off with our weather and we'll say the weather in and then
will display the city that they've requested
currently.
And then we can access this variable here the description variable using weather array.
And then we want to get the weather sub array within that so weather up and then we want to get the
0 array within that and then we will to get the description value within that.
So that should get the contents there.
And let's pop a full stop and a space at the end as well.
OK.
So let's have a look see if that's worked.
There we go.
Fantastic.
So the weather in.
We haven't got our I was caught up in Tokyo for some reason rather than city and that's giving me notice
as well which is fair enough.
All right.
Let's just add a little bit more information so we get to get the temperature say the temperature is
currently 291 some things.
Let's have a look at the API documentation to find out what those are.
So this is in Kelvin so let's convert from Calvin to Celsius.
Let's find out how we do that if we scroll down.
We've got a nice question there how do you combat to Celsius.
Here we go so it looks like we can just subtract 273 that will give us a nice whole number.
So let's get the temperature in Celsius.
And so we're going to get the temperature in Kelvin.
That's going to be weather array.
This time we're going to access the main subarray and the temperature within that.
And we want to subtract 273 from that then let's append to our weather text
the temperature is and then temp in Celsius and I want to put degrees C there.
So we're gonna have to put the degrees symbol in.
I suspect we'll need an h t m l character code for that.
So let's work out what it is.
Click on the first list and I'm going to use Command F or control f on Windows and search for degree.
And there we go.
Could possibly have guessed that ampersand deg and then semi-colon and we'll have a C as well for degrees
C All right.
Let's close that down and take a look see if that's work for us.
So the temperature is seven point seven six three degrees C.
Pretty accurate.
Just change that to a capital C
Many challenge for you then can you convert that to a whole number.
Go for it.
All right.
Hope you managed it.
I'm just going to do a quick search
ph.
Convert to whole number get the integer value of a variable that looks good.
So we get a Ph.D. function Val looks like it will do what we want.
So in fact and then our number wonderful.
So let's
put that here.
There we go.
And now we should find that we've got a whole number value.
Fantastic.
I'm just going to take one more bit of information and I'll take the wind speed.
So let's just check to see what that's measured in.
So the wind speed is in meters per second.
That's fine.
I'll leave it as meters per second.
You can work out how to convert it to miles per hour if you like.
Not that tricky.
And we can actually put it just straight in here.
So the wind speed is and we're going to get that from the wind Sabbar right.
And then speed.
So that's where the rain wind and then speed
and is proper full stop on the
all right.
Let's take a look.
Wonderful.
So you can obviously customize that to contain the exact weather that you want to show to the user which
is another advantage of doing it this way.
But really the big advantage is that we're doing it legally as it were we're doing it as the system
intended.
And so our weather is not going to break down.
Simple change of HCM all of website that we don't control.
All right.
So just two little challenges for you to finish this one off.
Firstly can you get the weather app to behave nice if the user enters something which is not a valid
city name.
Different.
All right.
How do you manage that.
So I'm just going to put in some random text and submit that.
OK I may get all sorts of errors notices and a bit of gobbledygook there as well.
So let's have a look and see what the weather array looks like.
When we try and search for an invalid city.
So there we go we've got a code of 4 0 4 and an error message as well.
So we could search for that particular code but it might be worth just checking again.
A valid city and here we can see that there's a code here of 200.
So it looks to me like 200 is a valid code and anything else will not be valid.
So let's do a check here to see if the weather are-I
code or code variable is equal to two hundred and forget your equals.
Then
we'll do all of that.
If it's not then we'll display an error message
so something like could not find a city.
Please try again.
And that just covers us more generally rather than that specific for forever.
We're now going to get a nice error message even if there's a different sort of error.
And don't forget the semi-colon there and that's and give it a go.
So it's still working nicely for Paris.
If I put in some nonsense we get a nice error message cannot find that city.
All right.
So we're almost there.
The last mini challenge for you is to make the weather web app play nicely with cities with cities with
spaces in their names so things like San Francisco or New York go for it.
OK you managed it.
Let's start off by seeing what happens if we search for a city with a place name in at the moment.
We get a nasty error so we're going to need to do something about that.
What we did before was we just removed the space and just sent it through as San Francisco without a
space.
And notice that does actually work fine if I put in San Francisco without a space.
That does give me the correct weather for San Francisco.
Well I've just noticed actually we don't have units on the windspeed So let's put those in.
That's better.
But I'm going to show you another way of doing which is a little bit more powerful and that's using
a command called u r l in code which if you done a bit of googling you might have come across
time or if you haven't.
So you are adding code essentially converts all of the nasty characters like question marks equal signs
space's apostrophes into character codes so that they can be put into a u r l without causing any problems.
So let's just do that right here.
So we just have to u r l encode the city name.
And now if we put in San Francisco with a space we submit and we get the weather there.
So that's just another solution.
If you did it by removing the space then that's a good solution to.
So let's just take out our code there.
And there we go.
So we've recreated the what's the weather app in a much more powerful and safer way.
We can be much more confident that this app is not going to break if a Web site that we don't control
decides to change is HTL and we're doing it within the web rules as well and we're using the API exactly
as it was intended.
So that was an introduction to API.
We're now going to step it up a little and use a rather more complex API.
The Google Maps API.