Well congratulations once again for making it to the end of the first section you've gone from not knowing
how a web site is put together a tool to being able to put together pages containing forms I-frame tables
images HD Mellon's these and a lot more.
So well-done.
We're going to put that into practice now by essentially creating a web page that contains everything
that we've done so far.
So I've got an example page that you can copy if you like but really I want you to go crazy and create
anything you like could be a home page about your family your favorite sport whatever it might be.
I'm sure it's going to be a lot more fun.
You choose your topic if you want a little bit of inspiration.
I'll show you what I'm going to be making and I've got this over here and you can actually get the code
for yourself.
Incomplete web developer calls don't come slash to slash HD M-L challenge dot HVM L.
So just stretching that out you can see I've got a nice image here of the globe.
I've got an on ordered list a link and a table down order list and then a very tiny bit of a form there
just to include it and also a YouTube video aligned to the right over there.
So that uses pretty much everything we've covered so far.
So what I'm going to do is challenge you to create something like this you can bet exactly this page
if you like or can come up with your own design and content.
Best of luck.
What you have done it would be great if you uploaded it to your empty space and then shared a link so
that I can take a look and congratulate you personally.
Don't forget to use all the good DML habits that you've learned so far.
So that's nice.
Indenting spacing out your code etc..
I hope you enjoy this challenge.
Go for it.
All right.
I hope you enjoy that.
I'm going to close that down and start building our web page from scratch.
So this is how I would have done it.
Of course as with any coding challenge there are many ways to build a web page or solve a problem.
You did it differently.
That's absolutely fine.
I'm going to start by going to example dot com and just using example dot com and just viewing the source
as we did so control clicking or right clicking view page source and then I'm just going to copy the
whole of that source code and use that as my starting point and that just make sure that I get the doctype
and everything else in there without having to type it myself.
I'm pretty sure that it's going to be right so don't be afraid to do that when you're building sites.
Obviously don't copy wholesale other sites but be to use them as starting points so that you're not
typing out the same code every time.
I'm just going to get everything nicely indented
and there we go.
So now we've got a basic bit of content.
Mine of course is about the world we live in are Earth.
So I'll call it the good old hello world.
So I will do a quick refresh.
Yep so got no content there at all.
But we've got a title of hello world.
All right.
So I'm going to start with a nice big header so we'll use each one and we'll have a nice big hello world
at the top and you'll notice that as I go through the process of building the page or refresh and just
check that it looks OK a lot more than you might think.
So even though we've just got a very basic bit of code there it's always good to see that your new line
of code hasn't broken anything or done anything unexpected.
OK so now I'm going to pop in a subtitle so HD a few facts about the world we live in.
Full stop.
I think that we get very nice.
Now I want a nice picture of the earth so I'm going to go to
Wikipedia.
And search for Earth.
And there we go.
Lovely big picture then.
And as we've done before.
I'm going to save the image as I'm gonna save it in my HVM folder.
I'll just call it
there again.
So this is a jpeg rather than a P and G.
JP G is the extension.
I'll remember that but it should get auto predicted by
my text editor anyway OK so let's pop in our image.
Nice and simple image SIRC for source and Earthwatch J peg gets predicted that pretty slick.
There we go a little bit larger I think.
So let's make it a little bit smaller so we can adjust that with the width as we saw in the image section
and I'll try a width of 100.
See how that looks a little bit small.
Try maybe 400.
OK that's about right of course.
Not necessarily looking for great style here but it's not hugely big and but I can still see the detail
of our planet there.
Right now I want to get a bit of information about the earth so I'm going to Google Earth facts.
There we go all that first one space fax dot com.
That looks great
lovely.
All right so I'm just going to use this paragraph of content there.
Now this but of course you wouldn't be for any live site that you are working with.
But that's fine for a bit of practice but definitely if you're making a site that you're going to use
publicly then make your own content.
OK let's have a look.
Very nice.
So now I want to have something with an unordered list.
So this bit of information looks good so I'm going to copy that and if I keep the moon in there as well
and they'll give me the opportunity to add a link so I'll copy that over.
Now this is a new section so I'm going to separate it from everything else with a horizontal rule.
I get and now I'll paste in my new data and actually just to keep things simple.
I only have three of them and I want an unordered list so that's a UL
and each of these is going to be a list item
that's pope that's the beginning and end of days and indent them so that the code looks really nice.
Great.
Let's just check.
There we go.
I'm liking that.
Now let's add in our link for the moon.
Now it goes to that you are well at the bottom of the screen that space fax dot com slash the moon.
So I'm going to copy the link address so I Contro clicked or right click and copy that and then to add
an anchor or link.
I use an ID tag with an 8 Tref of what I just copied.
And then we'll have the text the moon and then will close the e-TAG.
I will see if that works looks good have a click Billiam links to the page about me.
Fabulous.
Now I'd like to have a bit of practice putting in an ordered list.
So what I would say is
I'll copy the code for an unordered list.
And just change it to an ordered list.
And to separate that out from the previous list I'll add another horizontal rule.
Now obviously we need some new bits of information there.
So let's have a look facts about the earth.
Fantastic.
So let's make these to make them numerical data.
We'll have an H3 a little heading saying top three facts about the earth.
There we go.
And then I'm just going to copy these in
the Earth's rotation is apparently gradually slowing.
Interesting stuff the earth was once believed to be the center of the universe have that as a fact number
two and the earth has a powerful magnetic field.
So get rid of the link there because we don't need it anymore.
Brilliant let's have a look fabulous looks great.
I think now we need a little header above the previous list to kind of match that out.
So let's put an H-3 and we'll just call that about the
OK great storming three.
So now I'd like to add a table.
So let's separate out the section again and I'd like to have an opportunity to you GM out entity so
let's compare the radius and temperature of two other planets.
Just for fun so I will add in our table and we'll have our table header
and within our table head we'll have a table row and within our table row we'll have a T-H which is
going to be the name of the planet and then another T.H. for the radius of the planet and another T-H
for the average temperature.
OK I just have a quick look.
Yep that's looking good.
I think I might just add in a line break
to make average temperature go over two lines.
All right.
So after the table head comes to the table buddy
and within the table body we have table rows and within days we have table data table cells.
So we'll start with Mars.
So we need to get the radius of Mars.
I think we can get this from our space facts Web site
if we just scroll down here we go because Mars factory is.
Hopefully that will tell us the radius and temperature of Mars.
It's giving us the diameter that little bit of math for you the radius is half the diameter.
So I'm going to divide that by to you say 3400
and we'll rounded up three.
That's three thousand four hundred three kilometers
and then average temperature.
OK shall we find the average of minus 87 minus five.
We'll add them together and you get minus 92 all of that and you get minus 46.
So that's not exactly the average temperature halfway between the maximum and the minimum.
But really for our purposes.
So the tricky bit is with them what a degree sign.
So let's search for him out and the degree symbol that should tell us what we want.
Are we going to make sense and Dagh.
That's another quick hint for you.
If you get the Google search term accurate enough then quite often you won't need to leave Google at
all for your result and you can just take it from the Google extract from that page.
Let's put in and dig and then see
rights.
Let's take a look.
MAS 3400 three kilometers and minus 46 degrees C fabulous.
I think we'll just add one more to our table.
I'll do that just by copying and pasting.
So let's do the same for Venus.
Scroll down to get our facts and Venus facts.
So the diameter is 12 1 0 4.
So we want the radius so we'll have it say six thousand and fifty two.
That's what the come in the right place.
And then it's only giving us a single temperature there.
So we'll take that as the average for 6 2 degrees C
fabulous.
Let's take a look William.
There we go.
Finally then we want to integrate a form into our table.
So let's have another horizontal rule to separate them out and then we'll add in a very very quick form
which in fact is only going to have a button in it.
So we'll have to know more.
Question mark and then a button remember his input with a type of submit
and we'll put that inside paragraph tags as well.
OK let's have a look.
So that's great.
Submit though doesn't really make sense.
So let's change the wording using value equals and then click here.
Let's have a look.
Now this is all well and good but if we actually click there then nothing happens because the page just
refreshes.
So what I'll do is I'll give you a little bit of a reward for making it all the way to the end of this
tutorial and I'll teach you one more thing to get your form to submit to a particular page and you do
that using the action attribute just like that.
And then inside action you put the you r l of the page that you want the form to submit to.
So let's say we want to go back to the earth page facts and we just copy that Control-C all commands
C and control V all command V to paste it in them.
And now when we click on the button it will submit the form.
Not that there's any particularly useful information in the form but we will submit it to that u r l
which just has the effect of redirecting that to the space fax page.
Brilliant.
So almost there.
The only thing that I want to add to this is an I frame it with a YouTube u r l of Earth rotating.
So let's do a quick search for you cheap Earth rotating.
That's what one looks good.
We don't need the sound I don't think but wonderful.
That looks great.
So let's click on share embedded and then just copy that
and initially we'll put this underneath and there it is wonderful.
But in the example that I showed you we had the video on the right at the top.
So let's add that in.
We can actually add that in the same way that we aligned the image earlier by doing a line equals and
then right.
And that will align the I-frame to the right of the page but it will still be at the bottom.
So if I want to align it to the right at the top I need to just cut it so command X or control X and
then put its right at the top here even above the H-1 and then let's have a look.
If we then drag it out it's now aligned to the right fabulous.
So it's not the best looking web page ever but it contains a lot of the HDMI elements that we've seen.
And hopefully it's at least a good step up of what you could have done at the beginning of this section.
So once again congratulations on getting this far.
These do show me your projects and I look forward to helping you make your web sites look a lot prettier
using see SS in the next section.