Excellence so well done for staying with me.
We've done a lot of work here and we're almost finished.
So we've got our nice top bar at the top then we've got our menu bar in two shades of red and then we've
got our main article content over here.
All we need left now is the section on the right watch slash listen.
So I should be fairly trivial.
Nothing too tricky in there are just a couple of images and some links.
So if you have done this whole thing by watching me then that's great but why not take the opportunity
to do this last bit on your own.
There really is nothing fancy there.
It's all pretty straightforward.
Give it a shot if you feel you might be able to.
OK so let's start at the top.
Watch slash listen is what we're after.
And we want to do that in a new day.
So we're still inside any day.
I'm not too sure.
You can see the page content gets the page contained was the full 1000 pixels.
So this is going to be how Watch and listen Dave and I'll use an H for it just for fun.
Watch slash listen we'll have a quick look.
Just to remind ourselves what style we're going for.
It's a pretty big black.
Probably not but old let's take a look.
All right.
So not too bad.
I think one thing I'm going to do is
temporarily clear the flights so that I can see it again without having to
change everything.
That's probably a good idea to clear them before the day that I want to appear underneath.
So let's do a little bit of styling there.
First off we want to style watch listen.
I think all we need is a bit of padding or possibly margin on the left
that we'll find out doesn't really matter which we choose to pop in 20 pixels.
I would get
and then I really want to age four.
So let's have fun.
Whites is normal but font size is maybe 20 pixels try that that looks about right to me.
Unfortunately we are going to have to make this bigger and smaller.
OK.
That looks great.
So let's get these images.
One
I think I'm going to get all three in one go.
Here we go.
So let's copy these.
We'll have Article 1 article t and Article 3.
OK.
Copy them as before.
And then just pop them in images fold up
wonderful.
OK.
So let's get the image up first.
Underneath our age for we're going to have first off our image it's going to an S I'll say of images
slash
Article 1 and we can do this we can style these all the same when we come to think that we're going
to have this image here as well.
So we can't just use all the all the images inside watched watch listen.
So let's give it a special class
or call it article sight image because I think I might have used optical image before.
I'm not sure.
So article Syeed
image we definitely wanted to float left
and we're going to want to play with the size a little bit.
I suspect yet because that's pretty big.
So let's try with Paul.
Maybe 70 pixels.
Little bit small
Let's try out 90.
See how it looks.
Ok then we've got
text there which I copy a.
OK.
If I control click or right click that lets me copy it
that's a link again.
But we don't really care where it goes.
But we wanted to be definitely black possibly bold and pretty big.
So not very much like that
all the links here are going to be the same.
So rather than giving it a separate class that's keep our code lean and mean and just style it using
wash listen.
Oh come to think of it we're going to have separate style links there.
Maybe we should give it a class
bit messy but probably slightly easier to understand.
So I watched Tash listen Daschle
OK so we definitely want no underlining
we want the color to be black.
Well try making the font white Bold and the font size.
Let's try out 18 pixels
OK.
I think that looks pretty good.
We then want to make it go blue on the Hulver which we've done before.
OK.
So always copy and paste if you can
fewer chances of you making mistakes.
Well it looks like I have made a mistake.
So maybe I just need what listen link on Hava have a guy that's been a because of course is not an within
watch lists and link it is Watchlist and.
OK we want a bit of a gap between the image and our headline as well.
So I think we'll do that as a margin right.
On the image itself.
Every guy looks nice.
And let's set the width of our watch listen Dave now so that that wraps up nicely say maybe 300 pixels.
BACS let's give it a little bit more if we can.
OK we'll try that out and see if you've got room to fit in there.
I think we have.
OK so now we've just got the date which is exactly the same as what we had over here.
So we should be able to copy and paste our code which would be nice let's have a look.
Say OK
let's put that inside a paragraph tag
and then we can have another paragraph tag.
So we've got our clock image same as before but we're going to need some styling that so let's create
a class of clock so that we can steal the styling that we had before and make it not limited to images
inside whatever we called it.
The article or I think on the article's summary there we go.
So instead of article summary image we're now going to have clock
shouldn't change anything over that.
It will just allow us to use it in more than one place.
OK.
So here we go we've got our clock.
Now we've got the idea of date.
We're going to want to use that more than once.
Now let's change it from an I.D. to a class
and then I'm going to use Command F or control f on Windows to find out on it because it's not there
yet it's hashed state and we want to change that to date.
OK let's have a look.
Really we didn't actually want the technology this time but we will want to later on.
So let's keep it in for now.
One thing you might have noticed is this technology actually goes below the image but it doesn't wrap
round.
So what we're going to need to do is create a div here on the right so that it doesn't wrap as it's
doing at the moment
underneath the image like that that while I'm looking at that as well I think we might need to get rid
of a little bit of padding.
Oh no that's OK.
Slightly lower down.
That's fine.
OK.
So let's create a div around everything to the right of the image.
So I'll just call this side article
and then all of this can be indented.
And then we want site article
fact I don't know if we actually need any styles all
we certainly need something
that's give its a float all right and a fixed width.
All right we're getting that.
But let's move that up a little bit.
Try 15 pixels
up or down.
That's pretty good.
I'm happy with that.
Let's before we add all the others let's just get rid of our clear.
So it should now be floating right but it's not.
I suspect
it's because it's too wide
so let's have a look at it.
Change that to 150 pixels fast Ok not quite take out much less than
change the way that I can.
That's Clasen.
Let's add a flake right.
Just to definitely get it up there.
OK.
Brilliant.
So now we're in the right place.
We just need to get our wits sorted out.
OK.
Slightly too wide
still slightly too wide.
OK.
There we go.
So now we're in position.
I think we can make side optical part a little bit wider.
We can move it up a touch more.
So let's just get the coloring right here.
We want the span with a class of date so you can command F and search a date to get right them.
And I think it's that color that we want the same as the article summary.
That's great.
And now here we want that to appear just on its own.
And then if we've got a link as we have in the second one we want a pipe there or a bit of border and
then our technology on the next line.
So the wildy that is
will break our flights or clear our flights there and then copy all of this to get a new article just
have a look.
Okay.
Very nice.
So now we can get rid of the topic link from the top one arrogated So that's just nine to the general
2016 now and then we need to edit our code so that this technology appears on the next line.
But we also want the border to appear on the right which is a bit of a pain because we've put the border
on the left of the technology link.
So let's add another class to the link saying no border.
And we'll add another class of the span saying border right
and we'll use this to override the existing classes.
So no border
we want border left to be none.
And let's just check.
We might need an important there.
No that's that's achieved it in itself but it has taken us back to the original.
But that's OK that's highlighted an error actually there should be.
Class is topic link and no border and that should be the same.
Then up here.
Yes.
That should be a class of topic link because we're now using it more than once.
So let's find out what link commando control F and then t takes us on I then topic link.
There we go.
So that's now Clauss
abrogate that's better.
So I've got the class without the border.
We also don't want the padding there anymore either.
So in our no bored class let's get rid of that padding
axiom and then let's add the border in to the right of the span.
So this is the border right.
Class.
Now
and that's going to be
the same as this one.
But on the right
I think it's already got putting right of 10 so that should be OK.
Let's have a look.
OK.
That's great.
We do really want to be on separate lines.
So let's see if we can put in a line break.
In between them.
Wonderful.
All right.
That looks pretty good.
So now it's just a matter of updating
every day the titles and the images for the other articles.
Rid of that and so that's going to be off to go to.
And then we're going to want to clear all of that again
and create another side article.
Article 3
copy the content than
paste that in.
Get rid of that video.
And finally
article for
and what is a VPN service very good question.
OK.
And I think one of those yet has a different topic.
So the second one is science and environment not technology that once very
OK let's have a look and then maybe I only copied three optical images.
That's fine.
I'll stop at the three.
That was the threshold that we wanted to go down to anyway.
And there we go.
I'm sure the perfectionist The monkey or the future of web designers will find lots of small ways to
improve that and get it even closer to the original.
But I think to the layman's eye there's not much to obviously see the difference.
So congratulations.
I hope you managed to do a good chunk of it yourself.
But even if you've just followed along with the videos I hope you've learned a great deal and see how
you can take the knowledge that you've learned in this section and create a world class web site for
many of you that was probably the biggest coding challenge you've ever had.
So welcome once again for making it to the end.
Go and have a nice cup of tea and a couple of chocolate digestives and then come back to do some real
coding with javascript in the next section.