On Windows there are just two pieces of software that I'd recommend you download for this course and
they are the Chrome browser and notepad plus plus.
So let's get chrome first on Windows just open up your browser and then type download chrome into your
browser window.
That should get you a bunch of links which will lead to downloading chrome and that will get you to
this page where you click the download crame button.
It's optional whether you want to set Google Chrome as your default browser and whether you choose to
send the usage statistics as well.
The reason we're using crime is because it has great developer tools which will allow you to look at
the code of your pages and see what the errors are in your javascript or whatever language you're working
in at the time.
So once it's downloaded just click run to download the setup file say yes to allow it to make changes
on your PC.
And then that will go through the process of downloading the latest version of crime and installing
it on your machine as it happens.
I already have chrome running on my machine so I'm actually going to stop it there.
But you should just complete the installation and then you'll have chrome running on your computer to
get crime running.
Just click in the search box and start typing crime and there it will be.
If you're on a different version of Windows then it should appear on this start menu list as well.
So this is crime if you haven't used it before.
It works in the same way as all other Internet browsers so we can use it to download notepad.
Plus plus there are a number of free text editors on Windows so I click download notepad plus plus I
think is the most powerful and versatile and easy to use essentially the best one I think for people
to get started with when they're starting to carry.
So then just click the big download button and that will download it.
For you shouldn't take very long it's only four megabytes and then when that's complete click on the
installer and this time I will go through the whole process with the click OK to select the language
and then next I agree.
Next I'd use all the default options there.
Next And again all the different options you can change those if you want but I'm going to leave them
as they are and then we'll just let the install process do its job.
We get.
And finally it will run notepad plus plus and there we go and get an h t l file.
I'm just going to get you started by using Save As in the File menu.
And then I would just get started by going onto the desktop and choosing a file name like
web page dot h TNL.
And if you use the HDMI extension that will save as you directed him out page and then just clear out
the text and use control s to save and then I'll just set you up with the view that will have for most
of this course which is the chrome browser on the left
if you drag that all the way over to the left.
It'll give you a beautiful split screen there with your HD M-L file on the right and chrome right there
for you on the left fantastic in the next video then we'll see how to set up your very first web page
by creating an aged him file in your text editor and then viewing it in your browser.
I'll see you then.