So we're getting quite close.
The user can now follow or unfollow specific users.
And then when they do those uses tweets appear in the time line and also we can see their tweets on
the main page and see whether they're following or not following that particular person.
So there's not that much left to do.
We need to allow the user to post tweets which is what we're getting today in this video and then we're
just going to enable public profiles and searching of tweets in the final video coming out next.
So posting tweets is actually pretty straightforward.
We just need to call AJ queery method.
When the posting tweets button is clicked and here we need to set
ad ID for that.
I posted tweet button should do and remember we'll need the tweet Content ID as well.
So either in Foote's it up HP set this up in the usual way.
So weve got an ID.
You want to set a click to its
Lets get a little bit further than just letting Halo and this time will put tweet content don't foul.
So just to make sure that we can get the tweet content
and something's gone a little wrong there.
I think first off we might need to switch from a form to a div because once again we're not actually
wanting to submit the form.
And let's get rid of that type submit there as well.
And let's make sure that we've saved fitted up AHP.
OK that should work.
There we go.
It's empty.
I put some text in there we go.
So of course we want to submit that to actions don't pay HP.
So let's grab some code to do that and the action is going to be post tweet
and all we need is tweet content.
And that's going to be
tweet content dot
I came.
Now we're getting familiar with how to set this up so we can just do a check to see if action is equal.
See now actually forgotten what it was let's just go and check and floated up AHP post tweet
then as before we just print all the post variables and then unfits it up here.
Well a alert the result.
OK so now put some alleys in there.
Tweak content is a SDF
so we should probably do a check to make sure that there is some content
say so if that isn't
the content will echo your tweet is empty
and let's just make sure we spell that right and we should check that the string is not too long as
well.
So let's just see how we get the length of a string.
String get length that looks promising.
So as TR Eliot perfect.
I think I've actually started writing my ph P in the wrong place so let's just paste that in.
Copy that and undo all of that deary me.
We'll save that for a pitch P And We should be working actions stop HP here.
OK that's better.
So if there's no sweet content will echo your tweets is empty.
Else if the tweet content
is greater than 140 characters
them will echo your tweet is too long.
And Else we'll post it
say let's just check first off your tweets Dempsey.
Excellent.
And if I put tons and tons and tons and tons of characters in it's to be 140 Surely your tweets too
long.
Perfect.
And if I just put four characters in we get a empty response.
William So what we need today is an insets So I'm just going to copy the code from that and we want
to insert into tweets let's remind ourselves what tweets looks like.
So we've got an idea which we don't need to set tweet which we do user ID and date time
say tweet
user ID.
I think with a lower case i and date time and then some values.
So the tweet
itself is going to copy that.
So the tweet needs need to be in single quotes and this is going to be the post variable
tweet content and then we'll have the user id which is the current user.
So session id and date time
we can actually insert directly using my secure well with now
and then our turn 1
OK.
This is a test
one looking promising let's just go back to the home page.
We should have there it is.
This is the test has now been tweeted We do get this s s effect.
Because I shortened seconds to just X
let's use SCC.
OK that's great so I think all that remains is to show the user a message to say whether it's been successful
or not
say when we display the tweet box we'll have a couple of hidden divs.
So we'll have tweet success which you have a class of let's
let success
and he or tweet was posted successfully.
We'll also have a Dave with an ID of tweet fail.
That's going to have a class of alert and alert danger.
And we'll close the day because we can add the content to that ourselves.
So tweet success and tweet fail.
We both want a big hidden.
So let's advise them to tweet success display none.
You could obviously have all these in a single decoration if you like.
I'm going to keep them separate.
So that we can style them separately if we want to.
And then back that sea footed up here HP
if we get a result of one
then we want to find tweet success and show it simple as that.
I think I will just check to make sure that result
is not empty.
Because we might get an error back or something.
Then in this case we'll be using tweet fail and we'll set the HMO to whatever the error messages.
And then again we'll show it.
We should also hide tweet success
when there's been a failure.
And vice versa we should hide tweet fail when there's been a success
OK.
Well look another test come.
Fingers crossed.
I knew I shouldn't of written so much as a test.
Let's have a look see if something's gone wrong thing in the javascript console
OK.
Let's have a look.
Results.
Just check Yeah we are echoing one that we should get a response of some sort.
OK so we got your tweet is empty.
Is there an issue with.
Tweet fail
Kid B tell you what let's test that by
taking out the display is hidden for Tweet file and we should be able to see it at the start.
There we go.
So empty tweet OK.
That worked.
What if I want to tweet tweet fail we get a one on everything does seem to be fine.
So let's put that back in.
Maybe it just hadn't quite saved
does sometimes get that error if it hasn't saved the file properly.
Tweet fail so we feel we should now
post tweet success Hurrah.
OK and let's just get rid of the alert now that we don't need it.
Brilliant.
So now the user can post tweets.
We're in a position to set up your tweets page which we'll do in the same way we set up the timeline
page.
So back over to T-P and create a file called your tweet stoppie HP.
Open that up before we edit it
at
an if statement for that so your tweets
and we want to open your tweets top.
P which will say our usual greetings high that clicks click your tweets that begin wonderful.
So now we've added that page let's copy over
the home page code and we'll just change that to your tweets
and we'll call the display tweets function again but we'll set the type to your tweets.
So back I have it two functions duppy HP.
And then this is going to be a much more straightforward.
If type is equal say your tweets then where clause in this case is just going to equal where user ID
is equal to a.
And then we want.
Q Well I real escape
string and session ID
and that should find all the tweets from our user that have a look
OK let's cheat again and comb out the query to see what's going wrong.
So it's like stuffing tweets where a user ID equals and then nothing well that's interesting.
Let's just see what they type.
Variable is a type is indeed your tweets
so to make sure we're in the right place I go out
just the where clause
Yep.
Let's get rid of that.
OK.
And
might be very obvious what's going wrong but it's not clear to me.
Let's have a look at the session variable it is empty.
OK so somehow in all of that we've got logged out shouldn't have happened because at the beginning of
functions ph P We have sessions starts it could possibly be that's when we were saving functions or
Ph HP that didn't get opened.
So the session didn't get started.
So we got logged out.
So let's look back in as we're up 3 at Rob dot com
that's looking better.
So now back over to your tweets.
There we go.
So now we do have a session id of nine but it's still not putting it in the WHERE clause.
For some reason
yes.
There we go.
Say being logged out was a bit of a red herring because mostly I'd forgotten to put a link in the
there we go.
So there's Rob three at Rob dot coms.
Wonderful tweets
and we can now get rid of the WHERE clause
great so users can now tweet and view their own tweets if they want to.
There's two more things that are needed then and one is a search and the other is being able to view
public profiles and we'll set up both of those in the next and final video.