So now we're going to move on from our What's the weather app and we're going to look at a new and hugely
important and powerful API the Google Maps API.
You're almost certainly familiar with google maps.
It's a great way to navigate from place to place and it's a really excellent way to put maps into your
web sites and your apps.
So take a moment to navigate to cloud dot Google dot com slash maps hyphen platform and if you want
to have a quick scan of what's available on the Google Maps API essentially you can do anything that
you might want to do with maps including working with navigation and finding specific places like restaurants
parks et cetera within your website might be worth quickly checking the pricing page.
You get a lot on the free tier and definitely as you're just developing it's very unlikely you'll end
up paying for anything.
But always bear in mind that if your website does start getting popular you'll likely start having to
pay for your Google Maps API usage.
OK.
In this video we're just going to look at a few of the basic features of the Google Maps API how to
get started how to display a simple map on your website how to style that map how to add places onto
the map.
And finally how to add the user's location onto the map.
So to get started we tap the get started button and then pick which IPs we want to kick off with we'll
go for just maps for now the routes and places work in a very similar way so you'll be able to extend
the code that we cover in this lecture to those pretty easily and then continue.
And then we need a project to be working with.
If you've already got a project on the Google platform you can use that or we can create a new one or
just call it test maps project.
You can call it whatever you like and then click next and then we'll need to set up billing.
You probably already have a credit card connected to your Google account.
But if you don't you'll need to add one here.
I've got just one billing account at it so I'm going to use that one.
If you don't have one you'll be prompted to add credit card details and do be aware that you will start
to get charged.
If your maps account goes over the for usage limit OK.
Next again and it will now set up the Google Maps API is on your account and give you a API key which
you can use to refer to yourself in your scripts.
There we go.
So I'm going to copy that to the clipboard and then click done.
One thing just to point out before we go on and use the key to build a real maps based Web site is it
is definitely worth securing your key and clarifying.
So if it's only going to be used on one particular Web site what that Web site is going to be to prevent
other people from using Yochi without your permission.
But we'll leave that for now.
We're going to jump back to where we started.
That is cloud dot dot com slash maps and platform.
And then we're going to move on to the documentation.
That's where all the documentation is stored.
And by the way if you can't find that link if it's moved around on the Web site you can go straight
to developers dot Google dot com slash maps slash documentation.
OK.
And then we scroll down to see that there are various ways that you can access the API.
If you're working on apps for example but we want to work through the web so we can choose the javascript
API.
And again if you can't find that link you might just want to go straight to develop a legal com slash
Matt slash documentation's left javascript slash tutorial and then very conveniently we've got a great
Hello World page DML page here which I'm going to copy and paste into my text and get it working and
then we'll have a look through and see what this code is doing.
So I'm going to head over to my finder I've got a test HDMI DML blank document set up on my desktop
I'm going to open that up with brackets and I'm going to paste the code of the sample page in and then
the one change we need to make is we need to replace your API key here with our API key.
So go back over to my Google Cloud Platform console and copy that and then paste it in right there and
that's it.
Let's have a quick look and make sure it works.
So I'm just going to save that file back I have to find and then open it up.
In crime and that we get.
So we have our very own web page with our map up on running and you can say it's got all the basic features
of Google Maps you can switch to satellite view.
Zoom in and out even drag a little man in for street view if you like.
So that's already a very powerful thing to be able to do.
Let's have a quick look at the code and see how it's doing it.
So it's pretty straightforward.
All are basic elements of an aged DML page here a little bit of styling to make it a full page map.
And then we've got an empty div with an ID of map which is obviously where our map is going to be contained.
And then a bit of Javascript here which creates the map so it creates a variable called Map and then
it creates a function called it map which initializes the map using various settings.
So you can see it takes the variable map here and turns it into a new Google Maps map based on the div
with an ID of map which is this one here and then it adds a couple of settings.
So the center gives a certain latitude and longitude and gives a certain zoom level as well.
So let's see what happens if we have the zoom level to say 15 and then refresh the page you can see
with far more zoomed in.
So here's a quick challenge for you.
Can you change this code so it shows us a map of London which is reasonably zoomed out so that we can
see the whole of London.
Good luck.
Go for it.
Did you manage it.
It's simply a matter of knowing the latitude and longitude of London.
Which Google of course can tell us latitude and longitude of London.
There we go.
So the latitude is fifty one point five.
Let's put that in them.
And the long achieved.
Zero Point 1 2 7 8.
We probably don't need to be that accurate but that will work.
And then let's guess the zeem level.
I'm going to be slightly more zoomed in than we started with see if Hazim level of 9 looks about right.
And there we go.
That's pretty good.
You might want to zoom in a little bit more.
Just so that we only have London.
But I think that's pretty close to what we were looking for.
Great.
Just one final note in the code is that of course we have this script down here which is what is doing
the magic.
So this is calling Google Maps API javascript and essentially telling it to run the map function which
is what we defined here.
So really that's the basics of adding maps to your app of course they don't need to be fullscreen.
We can make them
say
200 pixels square just like any other div and that will then appear as part of your website rather than
the whole thing.
But for now let's leave it as full screen.
OK so now we'll just jump back over to the documentation and just see a couple of other things that
we can do so quickly here.
We'll see how to add a marker onto our map which is something common you might want to do if you're
writing a contact us page for example and you want to show where a business is on the map.
You can do that very easily.
So again let's take the carried him
and I'm going to just replace everything which means I'll have to copy my key again and pop it back
in
so again let's have a look.
Just make sure that works.
And then we'll take a moment to look at the code see what it's doing.
There we go.
So we've got a marker at a place called I think I'm even going to try to pronounce that.
But at that place there
and this is created again we've got the same set up as before with an in it map function then.
But this time we're using some different settings to add our marker.
So we've got a variable called louer with a certain latitude and longitude.
And then we create our map and you can see here we are creating a new marker at that location.
So another quick challenge for you.
Can you create a map with a marker on Niagara Falls.
Simple as that.
Go for it.
All right.
Have you managed it.
Again it's just a matter
of getting the location at the latitude and longitude of the place where you want to Adam AKA
and adding it in there.
And in fact that should be enough.
Let's have a look.
And something has gone horribly wrong there.
Hopefully some of you have got this problem.
And so how to fix it this time instead of east.
You can see we've got 79 degrees west and we put that into our web site using minus 79 nine 0 8 4 9.
So if you see South there on the latitude then you'll need to add a minus in there as well.
OK.
Try that again.
And there we go.
So that is now centered nicely on Niagara Falls.
Of course to make your
carried make sense I renamed that variable Niagara.
When you come back to it you're not completely confused as to why you've called Niagara leur.
All right.
So we're nearly there.
The last thing we're going to do is see how to style your map.
So on the left there we've got a link again if the links in a different place you might just want to
get straight to the aerial which is that one there.
Styling maps is pretty easy.
And as before we'll take the code Copia run it and then have a look to see what it's doing.
And because I've replaced the API key need to put that back in again.
OK let's have a look.
And there we go.
So I've got a nice night made map of New York City the let's have a little work.
So once again we're using the function and it map to create our map.
This time we've got a center somewhere in New York City and a zoom level.
And this time we have a Stiles object and all its doing is adding styles to various elements so you
can see we've got some geometry here with a certain color labels text and labels text fill again with
certain colors and you can add any settings you want.
We've got points of interest there.
Parks roads highways et cetera et cetera.
So you get the idea.
You can customize the display of pretty much anything on the map and just one more thing.
The Google Maps API also makes it very easy to get the user's location which can be extremely useful
if you want to create a web site that shows them places near them for example.
So let's see how we do that.
You can see an option here called geo location so I click on that option.
Geo location is essentially working out the location of your users.
So let's see how it's done just as we've done before.
Take the sample code
copy it into your site and then replace your API key with your API key
Okay.
And let's take a look.
We refresh that now and now you'll see that we're asked whether we want to allow this Web site to view
our location say click allow and then it should jump over to your location with a little box there.
You'll notice that it's not super accurate depending on the device that you're on.
I'm actually in Cambridge over here so it's not super close.
If you're on a phone you should use the GPS.
So give you a more accurate location but if you're just on Wi-Fi it won't be particularly accurate.
Let's just have a quick look and see how it's doing that.
So it's a little bit more complicated this time.
But again we're creating the map using the map method.
And you can see this time we've got an info window which is this little box here.
And you can see what it's doing is attempting to get the location and when it does that if it's successful
you've given it permission and the browser gives your location to the script then it processes that
gets the latitude and longitude sets the position for the info window.
So that's a bit of content and puts the info window on the map and that it also sets the center of the
map.
That's if it's successful if it's not then it shows an appropriate error message.
And that's process down here in this handle location error function.
It gives the user an appropriate error.
So there we go.
That's how you get the users location and show it on a map using the Google Maps API.
All right.
So there's obviously a huge amount more you can do with the Google Maps API.
This is just a way to get you started and to see how useful the Google documentation is and how easy
it is to create your own maps from it.
So have a think about how you might add some maps to a Web site you're working on.
And when you've done that come back and I'll see you in the next video.