So how does responsive web design with bootstrap work.
Let's take a look back over at the bootstrap docs which are really good by the way.
And I thoroughly recommend reading if you want more detail on anything that we're covering.
Let's go over to lay out a quick look at the overview.
So first off bootstrap has divs with classes of container and they do what you might imagine.
They contain the content within them.
You can use contain a fluid to use a container which stretches the whole width of the user's screen.
Now this bit here is where the magic really happens.
Bootstrap uses something called media queries to have what are known as break points.
Now breakpoints are device widths low which the layout of the page changes.
So if for example I take my screen and I make it narrower and narrower.
Nothing's really changing but something to change there.
Can you see so we have a breakpoint at that point which as we get narrower increases the margin on the
left eye makes everything a little bit smaller.
If we keep going we should find another bright point.
There it is.
So that's changing the layout yet again if we keep going.
I think there's one more there it is.
So there's a jump just that there it is.
And I think that's the last one.
There's another one even there as well and that's the the thinnest breakpoint there.
So there's a number of breakpoints and the layout is then going to be different for screen sizes above
or below those breakpoints.
That's actually quite easy to achieve in CSSA using media queries.
We have actually seen media queries before.
You may remember them from our good old example the column where we started the H.T. M.S. if we control
the right click and view page source there's a media Querrey at the bottom of the stylesheet which I
did mention but we didn't go into any great detail on it at the time.
And essentially what this says is that this is a media query and these styles will then be applied as
long as the width is less than 700 pixels and that's all a media query is it's a set of styles that
are applied at a certain width and we can see the effect that that has on example domain as I get narrower
and narrower some point round here I'll hit 700 pixels.
And then you'll see the design flip.
Yeah.
So that gray background only exists above 700 pixels.
So you can see below 700 pixels the background color is white.
F f f and we lose the border radius and padding and everything else.
So for example the comb is very slightly responsive.
You've got a kind of mobile version here and a desktop version here.
We can do a bit better than that.
We don't just want to have two versions.
We want to have several different versions.
However you're probably not keen on creating several different designs or layouts in your websites.
That's where something like bootstrap comes in really handy because we can just have a single layout
which then readjust itself nicely.
Each screen size using Gritz.
So let's have a look and see what the P-trap website has to say about griots.
So the grid system definitely isn't unique to bootstrap.
It's become an extremely popular way of setting up a responsive web site.
So I'm going to look at a very particular example first off and then you'll see some more general examples.
So here we've got three columns and this is the code that creates them.
So I'm actually going to copy this code and we'll look at it in our own bootstrapped rechannel file
I think it will be slightly clearer that will leave the hello world H-1 in and then we should really
put hello world inside the container.
Everything on a beach front page would ideally be inside a container.
So what we've got then is a div with a class of row and then another div inside that with a class of
coal S.M. for an F is going on there.
Well call is short for columns.
S-M is short for small and 4 for presents for columns.
So the bootstrap grid system is split into 12 little columns.
So what we're essentially saying here is create a div that is for many columns wide and then another
one that formerly columns wide and then another one that's for many columns wide.
So now if we stretch that out four with we get three nice columns all nicely spread out there a third
of the width of the whole page as we bring things in.
You can see we're seeing those breakpoints already.
The main break point however is going to come in and the moment now and there it is.
So you can see we've shifted from having three columns all the way across to having them stacked.
And that's the key idea of grids that the columns will arrange themselves differently depending on the
width of the user's screen and that's really the key idea of how Gritz work is a little more subtlety
to it.
As you might imagine and I'll show you just a couple of extra features now.
Firstly you might be wondering what this S-M really means obviously for small but what does that mean.
Well there are a number of different breakpoints that you can use within bootstrap and the small is
the first break point.
So that's around here but we've seen that there are breakpoints.
There's one there and there's one there as well.
So if I want to use a larger breakpoint to be the point where this switches from horizontal to stacked
and I would just change that see M.D short for medium.
And if we have a look at that now.
So that will stack at the medium breakpoint.
So it's getting smaller and smaller and there we go.
Now it stacks.
So the medium great point is around that.
So that can be really useful depending on how much content you want to have in each of these columns
to give you the details of what the various options are.
So the small columns all stack at 576 pixels.
So that's about this kind of with the first example that we looked at
then medium will stack at 720 pixels which was the second example and the large 940 pixels an extra
large at 1140 pixels.
Now when you get really fancy you can start mixing the small widths with medium and large to create
really quite complex different layouts depending on screen size.
If you're interested in that then just have a look at some of these examples here.
I think they're quite complex so I'm not going to go into them in great detail right now but we will
be looking more at them later on.
For now though I'm just going to give you a quick challenge and that is to create from scratch a 50
50 with layout or two columns essentially 50 percent of the screen each which then collapse when my
screen size is less than 720 pixels go for it.
All right I hope you managed it.
We start as always with bootstrap with a container div
and then we use I wrote Dave to say that we're creating a role
and then our first column is going to have a class of zero Alpha column.
Now we want this to collapse at 7:20 which is
the container with associated with medium.
So.
So we're going to use Culham dash M.D and we want a 50 50 with that means out of the 12 columns.
Each of our two halves is going to be six columns each.
So we've got CIOL for columns M-Day because we want to switch at 720 pixels to a stacked view and then
6 because we want this to be half the screen
and I'll just call it the first half and then we're going to use exactly the same code for the second
half.
And that's it.
Let's take a look.
So it stacks there which looks promising.
Once we move to 720 pixels which is around here.
There we go.
The switches to
horizontal.
Fantastic.
So I had like give you a basic idea about how we use bootstrap to create responsive web sites.
What we've got so far though doesn't look a lot like a web site and it definitely doesn't look that
beautiful.
So we're going to start looking at some of the bootstrap components that can help us create a professional
looking website in just minutes and the first of those that we'll look at is the nav bar.