So now we've got ourselves set up with BHP.
We're going to look at it is in real programming with it and we'll start by looking at variables.
You'll remember a variable is something that has a name and a value.
So in Javascript for example we would set up a variable using var and then name equals Rob something
like that.
That's how we would create a variable called name with a value of Rob in JavaScript in BHP.
Similar but slightly different.
Whenever we're working with variables in BHP we use the dollar symbol.
So shift 4 on my keyboard and then the variable name so I might want to use dollar name like that and
then I just set whatever I wanted to in exactly the same way as javascript.
And don't forget your semicolon and that's it.
So we don't use var or any other commands to create a variable we just use the dollar symbol and then
whatever variable name we want and then we set it equal to whatever we want it to.
So here's a quick challenge.
Can you work out how to display the value of the dollar name variable on our Web page over here.
Effort
did you manage that.
Hopefully you used some variant of Echo because that's the command that we know for displaying things
on the page itself.
And then we just use dollar and name.
And of course semicolon and that's it.
So let's have a look and say yep that displays Rob some of you may have tried something like that which
actually works as well if we run that.
It does do the same thing because BHP is pretty clever and if it sees a variable name inside a string
it will actually not display the variable name but the value.
So we might want to have something like My name is and then we could just put the variable name right
there in the string.
And BHP will recognise it and replace the variable name with the value.
Another way to put strings together is to say we've got a variable called string one this is the first
part and string t is of a sentence then we could combine those using a string one dot or period string
two and that's what's called concatenate ing.
You might remember we did it with a plus sign in javascript but in BHP it's a full stop or a period
and then we get both of those together.
Notice I'm missing a space there.
So here's a mini challenge for you.
Can you change this line.
Line 11 so that there is a space in the middle of part and of effort.
Did you manage it easiest way I think is to do something like that.
So this means string one dot and then put a space in and then dot and then string two.
There we go.
And of course we can put HDMI all in these as well so
we can make them their own paragraphs so they appear on separate lines.
There we go.
So those are all string variables because they contain a string of characters but we can do things with
numbers in BHP as well.
So let's have a variable called my number.
And initially we'll make it forty five and then we can do all sorts of maths with that if we want to.
So we might have a variable called calculation and this is going to be my number and you can have whatever
you like really multiplied by 31 divided by ninety seven plus for no idea what that is.
But then we can display it
let's have a look.
Every guy turns out to be fat.
Now unlike some languages pee pee is very unfunny about the types of its variables.
So you'll notice it started off as a whole number an integer.
And then when I did this calculation it became a decimal.
But I didn't have to redefine it or anything like that some languages you need to be very careful about
the type of your variable with BHP.
You really don't.
And we can use this variable in exactly the same way we did the strings.
So we might have something like the results of the calculation is and then we could put dot and then
the variable name and BHP will work on that just fine.
All right.
Almost then a couple more things I'd like to show you.
The first is boolean variables which we've seen before in JavaScript and we can use those in exactly
the same way in BHP.
So we might have my bool for example and we could set that equal to either true or false and then
we might have something like
this statement is true.
Question Mark and then
my bool in that and then close that paragraph.
Let's have a look see what it gives us.
It doesn't give us actually true or false.
It gives us a 1 or
a nothing and that's actually how HP treats True and False True is considered to be a one and false
is considered to be nothing or some in some cases a zero.
But mostly nothing.
So that's billion variables.
Lastly I just want to show you one kind of fancy way that you can access variables and that is you can
actually store variable names within variables.
So if for example
I set a variable called variable name to be equal t name I can then echo dollar dollar variable name.
Any idea is what that's going to display.
Have a guess
did you get it bizarrely enough.
It's Rob because variable name with a dollar sign in front of it means name.
So this means dollar and then name.
And that means Rob.
So it's a pretty rare situation that you'd want to do something like that but it's quite nice to have
the option.
OK.
That's as far as we're going to go with variables in P P in the next video.
We'll look at it in the next video.
We'll take it one step further and look at arrays.