Excellence so we can now apply our stylings to multiple HDMI elements with just one instruction at the
beginning in our stylesheet which is usually great but what if you have a certain paragraph that you
want to look different to other paragraphs or this is actually really easy to achieve using classes
and ideas.
So let's start with classes and find out how we use those.
First off I'm going to get rid of all my stylings and then just refresh and you can see the page now
looks completely different even though the HVM out hasn't changed at all.
So let's say I want to make this first paragraph read but not affect the second paragraph.
Well what I do is I apply a class attribute to it and then I can call that class whatever I like.
So if I'm just going to make it red I'll call the class.
Right.
But I could use any description I want there.
So if we want to apply some CSSA to the read class we don't just type red to indicate somehow that we're
applying this to a class and to do that we use the full stop or period.
So this is known as a class selector because it will select everything with a class of read and then
we just apply exactly the same pattern as before.
So the curly brackets and then color colon right.
Segregate them and then that will apply it just two things that have a class of red.
Now that doesn't necessarily have to be paragraph tags.
I could apply
the class to my H-1 tag as well if I wanted to.
And then that one would be read as well.
So it's a very quick challenge.
Could you apply a class of large to this paragraph tag.
The second one and then make it twice as big as the first one ever.
All right happy man is that.
Pretty straightforward.
We just use class.
He calls and then lodge in quites and then up in our stylesheet we use dot large to select the large
class and then font size colon and then whatever number you wanted to base say 200 percent for it to
be twice as big.
Take a look fantastic.
So really easy to manipulate things in this way.
Really nice other feature is that we can apply multiple classes to a single element so if we wanted
this first paragraph to be red and large we just put a space between them and type them both in their
red and large.
Let's have a look.
Fantastic that is now red and large.
So that's how classes work.
I work in a very very similar way.
So let's add another pair of paragraph tags and this time will give them an ID and let's say I'm going
to make this particular paragraph Taghreed.
So I'll call the ID green and we'll just have some very boring essays more text
ok.
We have a look at that of course there's no styling applied to that paragraph yet.
So it's not great.
But if you want to make a green we can do very easily.
The difference is because we're working with ID's rather than classes now instead of the period or full
stop.
We use the hash which are my keyboard is old.
Three years is probably around there somewhere as well but it might be the other side of the keyboard.
And then the name of an ID.
So green and this is then an ID selector and it will select IDs with the name of green and then it's
exactly the same as before color green I will look fabulous.
So it works in exactly the same way.
We use a hash instead of a full stop or period.
So you might be wondering well why do we have classes and ideas then.
Well essentially they have slightly different uses.
And the main thing about IDS is they should only be used once per page.
So you might have different sections of the page for example and you might give them specific IDs because
those sections are unique within the page.
You probably wouldn't.
To be honest use an ID of green because you might want to make several things green.
So essentially that's the difference.
Classes can be used more than once IDs only once and will actually come back to classes and IDs again
in javascript as ways of interacting with and moving around objects.
And then the idea of classes and IDS will become very important once again.
All right so that's classes and ideas.
One more thing I want to show you is how we might style some text within a paragraph tag.
So if for example we want to add and this text is underlined then how would we underline just that portion
of it using internal CSSA.
Well we do that using the span HCM element.
And then this span is simply something that we can put around any chunk of text or image or combination
of several different things and then use that to select it.
So if for example we gave this a class of red then only the latter bit would be red of course we want
it to be underlined So that's have a class of underlined and then we'll add in
Dot underlined to select the underlined class and then to underline something we use text decoration
and underline that we get.
And at this point you don't need to remember any of these will introduce them a lot more familiar with
them as we go through this section.
Let's just have a look there we.
So the text is underlined.
So that's how we apply styles to text within some paragraph text.
So that's as far as we're going to go with classes and ideas.
In this video and the next one I'll be introducing the DIV tag which we did see at the beginning of
the HVM L section but you can be forgiven for forgetting it.
Now we'll find out what its purpose is and how you can use it to apply styles to a group of HTL elements.
See that.