So now I've got a pretty big challenge for you.
Our aim here is to create a simple email client that we could use as a mobile app which allows the user
to send an email to and from anyone they like.
So when someone first uses the app they might send to a new user and then they can put their e-mail
address in there.
They from email
a message
nice and simple.
And then when they click send that links via Ajax to a p p script which then sends the e-mail for them
and returns true and the app interprets this as a successful send.
It also knows if for example there is no field that the e-mail couldn't be sent as well as that the
e-mail addresses that are used automatically appear in the e-mail address list here.
And when the user clicks on them it sets up an email to that e-mail address.
All of those are saved with hate mail.
Local storage.
So they're stored permanently for the user to give you a quick glance at what we're creating on the
server side.
We've got a fairly simple script which attempts to send the email and then create some.
Or more specifically Jason P to allow the app to read the response and know whether or not it's successful.
So there's a lot to cover there.
But I think you should be able to figure out at least most of that yourself.
But of course you're very welcome to watch me give it a go.
If you'd rather.
The way.
Best of luck.
All right.
I love that.
Well I'm going to start with the HVM L side of the app and build up our user interface fast and they
will create our HP API when we're done.
So I'm just going to commands it all the way back to the app J.S.
site that we had
a couple of years ago.
I would say just make sure everything's still working great.
So I think I'm going to go for the blue menu bar at the top.
And I'm going to do that just by adding the class blue to the top bar there and then I'll just get rid
of everything that we don't need.
So we don't need the scroll page.
I'm going to leave the key frames in there might be important for one of these animations and we're
not going to be using the color picker.
So I'm going to get rid of all of that.
So I pretty much all the styles in fact are gone.
So let's get rid of our color picker but we will be using the app section here without buttons so let's
get rid of all of those apart from 1 and we'll change the data target to send e-mail.
That's what I'm going to call the div of my e-mail sending page and then we can keep this section as
well.
But this is still going to go to send email
and I'll just change the text to send to New User
OK.
And then we don't need page 2.
In fact we don't need any of these pages
and
we don't need this code either.
So let's just leave it's an absolutely minimal code base.
Definitely don't want to leave any code in that we're not going to be using
let's just update the title to send an e-mail
click below to send an e-mail.
It's a pretty simple proposition.
Obviously this lists section here is not going to be shown initially but we'll leave that for now until
we add all our local storage functionality.
OK.
Then as I mentioned we're going to need the
page from inputs here which actually contains something pretty similar to what we're going to use to
send email.
So again I'm going to view frame source and I'm interested in inputs.
So that's Command F to search for inputs.
There we go.
It's definitely called inputs.
And here's the code that we need.
And for that Solon's copy that down and we'll have a look at it.
Once we've copied it over.
So this is a page as we're used to it's called a top bar that's renamed that's
to send email we might want to keep that button then.
And then we've got to search.
We definitely aren't interested in any search here.
So I'm going to get rid of
that line but we'll leave the rest because we're going to want something pretty similar to that.
And let's update the data page to send email
OK.
We should now be able to click on these and we get to the send email page.
So let's now look at the Send an e-mail page or ditto.
We're going to want a send and recipient e-mail address at the top there and we can actually leave subject
and message as they are.
So let's
call that send the e-mail address and we'll give it an I.D. of send.
Email and then we'll have another section
underneath with an input of recipient email
OK.
Let's take a look.
Great.
So the first time the user runs the app none of these will be pre-filled in.
But once the user has sent an e-mail we want these to be saved.
So let's add our code to do that.
This is going to be in the send e-mail page.
So I'm going to copy the app control code
and add it for the send email page using the data page attribute them.
And I want my code to happen when the send button is pressed.
So let's first give this send button an id call it send button and then we want to run our code
to set up the click function.
When the page is loaded so we're going to use the send e-mail attribute here.
There we go.
And as always we take one.
And as always we take things one step at a time and just do a quick alerts to make sure it's working.
There we go.
And then we want to do something if it's clicked.
Now we've seen some code from that down here somewhere.
Here we go.
So it's a little bit different to what we're used to but I think it's fairly easily transferable.
So we're looking to find an element again but this time we're looking for the element with the send
button I.D. We're making it clickable.
And then when it's click click we're running some code and again we'll just do a quick alert to make
sure that the on click method is all set up correctly.
All right let's give it a go.
Wonderful.
But of course what we're really going to do here.
Is attempt to send the e-mail but I'm going to add the code for that later on.
For now we're looking at our local storage.
So let's make that happen.
So let's start off by checking to see if local storage is available.
That we look at type of local storage and we want to check that that's not undefined
and if it is for now I'll just put a message
saying that will allow the use of that we couldn't save the data.
It wouldn't cause a problem with email.
It just means that we won't save that email addresses etc. and then either here will start off by saving
the sender email address.
Now that's nice and easy because there's only one of them.
So let's just remind ourselves what we call that sense they send the email ID.
So we're going to set local storage set item and I'll call it the same thing.
So I send e-mail and we want to set that see the value of the Send the email field so send the email
again and found.
Now before we move on to saving the recipient email address I'm just going to check that that's all
working.
So we should be able to set up the e-mail address here.
So let's first check again to see if local storage is available.
And I wouldn't have an else this time this time.
I want to check to see if a particular variable exists and that is the send the e-mail variable.
So I'm looking for local storage to get item send the email and I can check that that exists to see
by checking if it's not equal to no and if it doesn't then I want to update the value of the send the
e-mail input.
And we do that using page to find and then send e-mail
with a hash ID and we want to set the value of that to local storage get item send email.
So all of that should have the effect of when we save our local storage data when the user clicks and
we then load up the page again and we should see the send the e-mail address populated there.
So let's get this again.
Just refresh and then click to open up the email and then I'll put in Roback code styles dot com and
then click send.
So nothing happens there but hopefully the local storage got activated in the background and then I'm
going to refresh again and click back on here and there we get it.
It's been populated wonderful So we're now saving the sender email permanently.
Just to clarify that that is the send the e-mail.
I think I'm going to add a from text to text there.
Let's have a look.
Yep.
Great.
OK so now let's do the recipient e-mail address.
Now this is a bit more complicated because we need to save it in an array.
And we only want to save it if it's not already there.
So first off let's see if that right exists.
So I will check to see if local stores get item and then I'll call it recipient
list.
If that's not equal to.
No.
Then we'll set
recipient list equal to that
in fact what I think all day is all set.
The recipient list to be a new
array outside there and then I'll just update it if it doesn't already exist in the local storage.
So now we've got recipient list as an array and it's either equal to the contents of the local storage
or it's empty.
So now we want to see if the recipient email address is in the array.
That's the sort of thing that's probably a query function for.
So let's have a look check to see if in a race something like that like about an array.
Perfect.
So let's jump down for an example.
So in a way and then we're looking for the item that in the array that K..
So let's do our check.
So we're checking to see if the recipient email which is this they're say if
and we want recipient email foul and we want to see if it's in the array.
So we're going to use Jey query docked in array
and we're checking to see if that value is in the array recipient list and we actually want to check
that it's not in there right here.
And you can see here that the value that we get from the NRA function if it's not in it is minus one.
So we're going to check to see if
that is equal to A minus 1
and because I've written quite a lot of code so far I'm going to do a check at this point that we're
still working and nothing's going to horribly wrong.
So let's just put something in there and we've got a small problem there.
I think it's because we're using Jay query here which was what the example had on our test up here.
But actually the standard for
using Jay Querrey functions is the dollar sign.
So let's try using that instead.
That we get it could be that sceptered doesn't support using a query and dollar.
So if it's not in the array we want to add it to the array.
Really remember how to do this.
We use recipient list dot push.
And then they think that we want to add.
So that is of course recipient email
Vout.
And what I'm going to see next is just look to the console.
Recipient list just to make sure that this is happening.
So now I'm just going to put one and two and then inspect and let's have a look.
We should see that we've got an array.
And yep it's saving each one but it's not saving recipient list each time.
That's not a problem.
That just means we need to save it to local storage.
So remember this is an array that is save it we're going to have to convert it to Jason because we can
only source strings in local storage so we'll use local storage.
Set item.
The item that we want to set is recipient list and the value that we want to set it see is J-Zone string
if I and the recipient list array.
And similarly when we get it back we're going to need to convert it from a Jason string to an array.
And we can do that using J-Zone pass as we saw in the previous video.
So now it should not only save the latest one but save all of them say let's save number one maybe I
can get that saved number two.
Great.
We've got one and T number five for him.
So that's saving very nicely and small thing I'd like to do while we're here is to put them into alphabetical
order so that users not looking down the big list of email addresses trying to find the right one say
see if we can find a way to do that.
And we got a few options here.
But J javascript array sort seems pretty perfect for us.
So let's apply that here.
So the recipient list Daut sort.
So let's refresh and then I'll put in the number for my recipient list.
And there we go.
So not only is it added number four but it's put it in the right places.
Well just try number three.
OK so that's looking good.
Or do you just want to get rid of those numbers so that we can replace them with email addresses so
I can do that just by commenting out this line once and then refreshing
and I'm going to put my friend at exampled up come
there we go.
And that's reset the array.
So if I now bring that back in and refresh the page
I have a friend for example to come and then say that with then got the two e-mail addresses saved.
Wonderful.
So we're almost finished on the front end side.
The only thing I want to add at this point is for the users e-mail contacts to be listed here.
So let's remind ourselves where that is.
It's our pay him.
So it's in app section.
Let's give this an I.D.
of contact list and then we're going to want to do is when this page is loaded.
Want to check to see if the user has any contacts and if so make them appear they're.
So we're going to be doing that on the home page here.
So once again we want to check to see if local storage is available
which we do that way and then we'll also check to see if
local storage get item.
And what we're looking for is the recipient list
is not no
and so if that's the case we want to get our recipient list again.
Let's create our array.
And in fact we can use the same code here.
To pass it convert it from Jason to an array.
Then we're going to want to loop through that array.
You can possibly remember how to do that.
But let's just remind ourselves that we get the jey query each function get ourselves a nice example.
Yep that looks familiar.
So we're going to loop through the the recipient list or array and yeah for now I'll just alert value.
So that should mean that when we load the app it will alert my friend for example to come and then my
other friend and example to dot com.
Great.
I didn't actually want to alert them though I want them to appear where it says lists at the moment
say I want to take the contact list ID and at a number of days to its one for each recipient to get
some indenting first off.
So we don't want to let the value
but we do want see just take the contact list.
So that's that
and we want to spend to that day of which I remember means add on the end
and we want to put the value in that.
All right let's take a look.
And something's going wrong there.
I think it's because we're doing this the old fashioned way and we actually need to search the page
with objects.
So we look in page and then find and that's where we put our ID
site contact list.
So just as we did it there.
Let's try that again.
There we go.
Wonderful.
And I'm just going to add in a little bit of code which hides the contact list.
If there's no contacts in it.
So if the recipient list is empty then we'll find the contact list in the same way and hide it and just
in case we need to we'll show it there as well because it might be that it's hidden and then we get
back to it.
I'm willing to share it in that case.
Great.
So now back here if we click on one of those and at the moment nothing happens when we click those.
And that's because when they were added in this way the code attached to the data Target Field wasn't
activated.
So we're going to have to do that ourselves.
And essentially we want to do two things.
When one of these buttons is pressed to jump to the send e-mail page and you want to set the active
e-mail the active recipient e-mail that is to whichever one has been tapped.
So jumping to another page is not something we've seen how to do yet.
So let's see if we can find some way in the docs for.
To have a look.
So we're familiar with that things to note we're pretty familiar with pages this is where we are.
Aha.
This code looks very promising so that loads the page home wonderful.
That's exactly what we need.
So let's add a new class to these links.
We don't need the data target attribute anymore.
So if we just add a class of direct and then once we've finished this process we'll add our redirect
function to those links.
So we're going to need to look in the page again and find anything with a class of direct.
And as we did down here let's make it clickable and then on click
just check it.
We need print sees that and then on click and we want a function
every day and I'll just put those on separate lines to keep things tidy.
Heasley have the dots at the beginning.
So again just to check that everything is connected.
We'll just have a quick alert.
Things are looking good.
So we want to do two things.
Remember we want to redirect upload.
Let's do that bit first because at the bit where little unfamiliar with and we want to redirect to the
send email page.
So let's have a look.
First off wonderful.
And then the second thing we're going to do is use local storage to save the e-mail address so that
we can access it again on the sendmail page and put it there in the recipient email address.
So let's use local storage.
Set item and I'll call it recipient email
and we want to set that equal to the value of this does which we should be able to get using this and
then.
That will give us the HVM hour of the day that was clique's which is the e-mail address that we want.
Again just to check.
I think I'll do a quick alert that that's going to get it right.
And I think both of those should happen before we redirect the page.
Otherwise it might do the redirect and then not run our code.
So let's check first of all excellent.
We've got the data and then it's doing the redirect.
So now we can get rid of the alert and then we need to do now is add the code to make this recipient
email address appear when they send email page is loaded.
So we've already got a function here to check if local storage is up and running.
So let's add other function inside that.
So now we're looking for local storage get item.
And the thing we want to get is recipient email.
So let's check to see if that is not null and if it's not then we want to update the recipient email
address so we use page again to access the page and then find to find our recipient email which I think
is just recipient e-mail but that's just check.
Then we get an e-mail.
Yep.
And then we want to set the value to
local storage get the item recipient email
beryllium.
So now that's already worked wonderful when the user clicks on one of these.
It will save recipient e-mail in local storage and then if that exists when we send an e-mail then it
will update that other page.
Wonderful.
Just one tiny thing to fix.
If we click send to new user now then that will still remember the recipient emails saved previously
which is not the behavior we want.
So when the new user button is clicked we need to remove the recipient e-mail variable from local storage.
So let's add an ID to that or call it new user
and then we want to add some code for it.
I'll do that once again inside the local storage is defined if statement.
So again we want to page find and then I've got a ready what I called it New User very sensible
and then not certain we need clickable about I'll put it there anyway.
And then on click we want a function.
And as usual I'll do a quick alert to see if we're poor connected up.
We are indeed.
And then ideally we want to remove that item from local storage which is not something we've done before.
So let's see if we can figure out a way to do it.
Local storage remove item ha storage don't remove the item that looks so perfect.
I don't think we even need to click on it.
And in fact we've got the example in the second was out there.
So local storage don't remove item.
So let's try that's
remove item and then the key is recipient email and we do only want to do that if it exists.
So we should do a quick check really.
So if local storage gets item recipient email
is not equal to.
Then remove it.
OK.
So let's just check now if we click send to new user and that didn't quite work.
And that's because the code to remove the item here is actually happening after the redirect takes place.
So if we click done and then send to new user again then we do have a blank email address here.
So in order to stop that from happening there is as is often the case a number of ways of doing it.
But the way I'm going to fix it is to remove this data target from the app button in class and then
do the redirect manually.
And so we'll check to see if we need to remove the item and remove it if we need to.
And either way we won't see hap dot load.
They send the e-mail page and this would just make sure that the item gets removed before the e-mail
page is loaded.
So let's take a look.
So now we've got it in the To field and then we send to a user and the field is blank.
So now our front end is working pretty much as we wanted to.
We've got our local story saving our users contact email addresses in a particular order and they can
click to send to one of those or they can send to a new user.
And either way whatever e-mail address they use last time is going to appear in the From field.
So we're looking at it now it's just the small matter of actually sending the e-mail.
And then of course feeding back to our code here that the email has been sent.
So to do that we're going to need to use some ph.
We can't send e-mail using javascript but we can using a server side language.
So I'm going back over to the fire FTB and I'm going to create a new directory which is going to be
nine mobile apps
and I'll create a new file within that called Send email to HP.
So I'm going to use command control in windows to open that up in brackets.
And then
that's just do a quick save to make sure that we've got it open and then find it online.
So it's going to be complete web developer called dot com slash content slash 9 hyphen mobile Papps
slash send email to HP because you are you're you are l is going to be different depending on your domain
name.
OK.
So we've got two challenges here.
One we need to receive the data from the app to tell us who to send the email to who just end it from
what the subject a message should be.
And then we need to report back to the app to say whether or not this ending was successful.
So we're going to be using AJAX within the app and will need to return our data in Jason format so that
it can be read across domains.
So let's set up our malfunction first.
I think we can lose the app jast tabs.
And I'm just going to do a quick search for HP malfunction and then I'm going to jump to a stack overflow
question and here we go.
So I've got some nice headers there.
So usually getting the code from the web will save us a fair bit of time and get some accurate headers
hopefully as well.
So I'm going to be parsing these as get variables.
So we'll have to forward to a subject for subject
message for message and then
we're using from four from as well.
That we get to now I should be able to do a little test.
I'm actually going to change that to an echo.
So we'll see hopefully a one when this has been successful.
Say two I'll use rope Rob Percival that it you came and from all use Rob at Comp..
Web Developer of course dot com a note when you're testing your e-mails are less likely to be seen as
spam if you use a from address which matches the domain name so that if you can.
So that will help with testing.
If it doesn't appear in your inbox then spam filtering could be the problem.
And then we'll have subject that's just going to be test and message.
This is a test.
All right.
So we've got a one that's a good sign.
And just to show that it doesn't send absolutely anything get rid of the send the e-mail address and
then reload the page
then we don't have a one there.
OK.
So that now seems to be where so all that remains on the server side of things is to Outlook.
Jason P so that we can read it using AJAX in our app.
Again that's something we haven't done before.
So let's see how we do it.
Here we go.
How do I create Jason pay.
That looks pretty perfect.
Have a scroll down.
And here we go.
So we create a callback parameter in the get variable then return that as part of our Jaison.
So let's copy this code over.
So this is what we need but we need to create our Jason first and we'll do that from an array.
So let's
set up a result right.
And we'll have result success equal to the output of the mail function which will either be true or
false depending on whether it was successful or not.
And then instead of using the data variable here we'll use Jason in code
result and we've used the Jason code function before.
But it creates Jason from an array.
OK.
So let's just have a quick look and see what that returns.
So nothing at the moment because I haven't but they call back in them.
So let's just say that equal to something and then we get a response and then our Jason and just in
case there isn't a callback at some output there they're not that we particularly need that because
it won't work without a callback anyway.
But better to have that than nothing at all.
OK so now we can shut down our Send email PSAP and I'm going to put out code for the moment in the send
email page.
So as always before I do anything I'm just going to do a quick alert to make sure we're all connected
up and then I'm actually going to jump over to the septet page to get some code to work with for Ajax
just in case it's in any way different.
To the query approach if you want to stick with stand J query of course then you can get rid of Zapato
and just add the query javascript instead.
But with any luck
we gay should work for us.
So let's add our Kate
there.
So the we're used to the Ajax and get the you are el will start of just being this complete you are
all here with the callback in there.
We'll leave the data as is for now and then we should get a success field in the Jason.
So we should be able to get that by just alerting data dots.
Success and the final thing to check before we run this is to change from Jason to Jason.
Pete.
Now let's say fats and refresh and then we get we've got a full response which is great.
So next we need to send the correct variables to our script so rather than just name is Zip toto.
Yes we need to tend to from subject and content and I'm going to do that as just fixed variables for
the moment.
So I'll send it to Rob.
Well Percival took care of you OK.
I'll send it from Rob.
Complete web developer course dot com.
I'll set the subject to be test on the content.
It's just this is a test
case and now when we run that we should get a true response.
We can bring in.
So things are looking good.
Let's then update our code so that we send the users values of from to subject and content rather than
these fixed ones.
So if you remember those are stored up here.
So we've already got an ID for send the email and recipient e-mail.
So let's just add in an ID for subject and also for content.
And now we can refer to those down here.
So the two variable is going to be
recipient email at Val and then I'll just copy that and the from variable is going to be send the email.
Val subject is going to be subject to Vau and content will be content.
Rationalises from that again make sure we're still getting a true response and there we go.
Actually yes that's correct.
We're getting a focused response because we don't have a recipient email address in there at the moment.
So that's what we would expect.
OK so now I'm going to move this string to send the e-mail down to where it should be.
So on this kickable link i.e. when the send button is clicked.
So let's take a look at an e-mail address in here.
And a subject and a message and then send and there we go.
We get our true response.
All right.
So we're very very close now.
It's just a matter of having a more friendly response to the use of alerting.
True or false.
So we're going to do that in the usual way.
We'll have an S..
Dave
at the top of the page which will initially be empty and we'll give that an I.D. of message
and notice that we do see a little bit of that Dave.
So let's hide it when the page is loaded.
Say a page find and we want a message
right and then we'll just show it when we need it.
OK.
So down here instead of alerting day to success we're now checking to see if data dots success is equal
to true
then
we'll set
the message give content to your email was sent successfully.
And if it wasn't we'll just put a fairly generic error message
your e-mail could not be sent.
Please try again later.
And we'll actually do the same thing down here if we get a jack Zayra as well.
OK.
And for each of those We'll also have to show
that if so that the user can see it.
All right.
So let's take a look.
I'm actually going to go back and this and set that example
hi how are you.
And then send your email was sent successfully.
Fantastic.
So that's actually as far as I'm going to go with this app.
Well done for following all the way through.
I hope you did manage to do a fair bit of it yourself what you've created here could be the basis of
almost any HDMI based app.
That's what we've built is a nice looking and fluid Front-End based in HCM L and we've built a Ph back
end as well which for a more complex app could connect to a database and contain user log in details
or anything you like.
So even though the usage here is pretty simple a structure that we've used is extremely powerful.
I hope you're having ideas of apps that you could make in this way.
There are of course many options for improvement here.
One small bug you may have noticed is that if you attempt to send an email with a blank email address
it will save that blank email address in the list.
I'm going to leave that was a small challenge for you to figure out how to stop that happening.
We also obviously don't have any validation on email addresses here.
So we allow invalid email addresses and we don't give a great deal of information in the error message
as well.
We just said the email could not be sent.
So will be very nice to have some checking here to see that the e-mail addresses were valid and that
they were present and that that was a subject and a message.
We could also do with giving the user the option to delete e-mail addresses from their contact list
if we wanted to.
So plenty to do that.
But also a strong basis for any app that you wanted to make once you've made your app.
The next challenge is to get it onto the app stores.
And that's why I'm going to show you how to do using phone get built in the next video.