Now that we've mastered the bootstrap grid system we're going to take a look at some of the components
within the bootstrap CSX.
And the first of those is Naftogaz.
So if you click on components Let's first have a quick look at these buttons partly because they're
quite nice and pretty but mostly because they give us the standard color scheme of Bootstrap which you
can obviously mess with if you want but it's a solid one to at least be aware of.
So the names for these buttons follow on into almost every other bootstrap component so if you want
something to be green you give it a class of success.
Similarly if you wanted light blue info orange warning danger red primary blue secondary white etc.
and see how that works here you give it a class of PTEN to make it a button and then BGN dash primary
to make it a blue button.
Similarly with success info warning danger etc..
So we're going to be using that again and again when we want to change the color of things.
But let's jump straight on on the right menu here to Nashbar.
So you might be used to seeing something like this at the top of Web sites usually it's got a logo or
something at the top left.
Maybe some links maybe a search bar at the top right.
Something like that has become pretty standard and the bootstrap nav bar enables us to set one of these
up really easily.
And it looks like that so very pretty.
Let's copy the code.
Have a look at it in our bootstraps ranged himself file and then see what's going on and how we can
edit it any way we like.
OK.
There we go.
So there it is in its basic form.
It's obviously an attractive and clear navigation bar for your site which could easily have a logo some
links and a search box and can be styled in any way.
So let's have a quick look at the code and see what's going on.
And this is the first time that we're really investigating the bootstrap class system.
So I will spend a bit of time on that as we go through the code.
So first off we've actually got a new team out element type here and that is Nav..
This was new in HCM L5 and it's essentially a div that's used for navigation.
So it doesn't have any properties other than that a div has but it does tell the browser that in this
section is going to be contained your navigation links for the Web site.
But notice if you replace nav with Divx here it doesn't change a thing.
So it really is just a semantic thing.
It makes your HDMI a little bit clearer.
All right.
Now we've got our string of classes and we'll see this again and again and bootstrap.
You have a certain class to define what this component is.
So in this case and nabû and then you have some customized classes which change the look of the behavior
that element.
So here we've got enough power light and background faded so feel free to experiment.
If we get rid of background faded then we have the same effect but with no background essentially
if we put that back in we might want to change it to background success and that will give us a green
background.
Could you make it a blue background.
Wonder if you managed it there were two options.
Info is our light blue background and primary is our dark Hopley background.
Then we've got our first link which has a particular class of nav bar brand.
So that means it will be considered the logo for the site.
And usually that will be an image.
But in this case it's just some text.
Next we have an unordered list with two classes nav and nav bar now I've just set it up to look and
behave like a nav bar list of links.
Then our first item has a special class of active.
It's a Naveh item but it's active which makes it a little bit darker.
So that's for just a page that we're on.
And then we've got the link itself of a elements and then that has a class of Navesink and hatred of
just hash that means I'll get back to the same page and then text of home.
We've also got a span with a class of S.R. only as our short for screen reader.
So if we want some text or information to be displayed only for we're using screen readers that is devices
for visually impaired people then we can use that class and it will only display on those devices then
we've just got a series of links each of which have a class of Nav. item and then the link itself has
a class of NAV link.
So they form these ones and then we've got a form where we're looking at those in Maudie's out in the
next video.
And it's a form in line which means that each of the input items are horizontally laid out rather than
one about the other and it's pulled to the right and access is one of our options for the screen size
and access if you remember was essentially a zero.
So this means that we pull to the right all the time.
If I change that to M.D for medium then it will only be pulled to write for medium and above sized screens
and below that it's just displaying normally normally are going to want to pull to the right all the
time and you achieve that with an excess.
Then we've got to reform itself will look at that in more detail in the next video when we look at forms
but it's reasonably straightforward.
What's going on.
And then we end the forum and then we end the nav.
So essentially it's a really simple way of getting a nice looking naff pile which we can easily customize
in terms of backgrounds etc. but we don't have to worry about all the floating left the styling the
spacing and the fact that it's responsive for different screen sizes says well if the responsive grid
system the components are much of what makes bootstrapped so useful.
Let's have a look at some of the other options of naff but so our brand.
We've already seen nav we've already seen that contains They have items themselves.
There are a few other color schemes here.
We looked at the background but you can also change the whole theme of the nav bar itself surrogate
for dark at the top and nav bar light.
You can see they've set the background to Inv. which means that the text is white rather than dark so
it's easier to say on a dark background.
Notice I didn't put my Nafa in a container because normally you want your nav bar to stretch all the
way to the end of the screen.
You can do if you want but it will look like that which will be a little bit weird.
We then got some placement and this one is really useful.
The fixed top.
So with just a single class in this case nav bar fixed top you can make it so that your nav bar will
stay at the top of the screen even as the user scrolls down.
So let's see that in action that's really useful.
So let's have a container
and then let's get a bunch of
some
get loads of the stuff
lovely.
So now when we look at events and we scroll down you can see the nav bar stays where it is can be annoying
sometimes on certain websites use it carefully but can also be very useful to keep the navigation right
there for the user should they want it.
Now the last thing I want to show you is quite fun.
Let's say you wanted to have a button on your nav bar which he had or showed some collapsible contents
which maybe had some more navigation links or sign up to a newsletter or something like that.
Then you could use this code.
So let's just try it out.
And see what it does.
I'll put it under our existing nav bar and we'll just comment out.
The original nav bar for the moment.
So it's still there when you want to check Kate and that really works really nicely.
And let's see what code is doing this.
We've got a div with a class of collapse.
That means we're going to collapse this div by default.
So it's not showing by default and it's got a particular ID which will reference later.
It's got a class of a background inverse which means it's got this very dark background and pale text.
It's also got a class of P A1 which is a special padding class.
We can actually get rid of that and everything will still work fine.
But the A-one essentially allows you to add a bit of padding in without doing that manually yourself.
And then we've got to content with another special bootstrap class of text muted to get that to display
a certain way.
We have a look at that.
Without that class you can see it's muting the text essentially
giving that sort of gray gray color.
Then we've got our nabû in the same way that we're used to but now this is the clever bit we're creating
a button with a certain class of nav bar Tugela.
It's got a type of button and it's got some new attributes that we hadn't seen before.
Dator Tuggle and this essentially means that we're going to toggle the collapse class on the data target
which is the element with id x collapsing nabû.
So what we're essentially doing in the background here there's some javascript connected up to all of
this which will find the button with a class of nav bar dash Tugela and then we'll look for the data
toggle attribute and then note that as collapse.
And then you look at the data target and then it will find the elements that matches that.
So in this case the idea of X collapsing nav bar will toggle the collapse class.
So this is the sort of thing that bootstrap is really useful for.
If you need to do something like that and it's quite common that you might want to you can do that really
easily without having to create custom Jake wari or javascript yourself.
Great.
So that's nerf bars.
I'm just going to comment out the collapsible one now so I save it in that form for you.
So looks like a more traditional nav bar is there by default.
One quick thing to note there is that as this nav bar is now fixed it's not in the flow of the page
anymore.
So we need to give the container a bit of padding or margin at the top to move everything down so that
we'd see it.
So I'll do some naughty inline styles just to show you how it might work if we give it a margin top
of 50 pixels for example.
There we go.
And that'll get it exactly on.
Probably we want a bit more than that to bring it down a little bit.
Something like that.
So I'd recommend doing that with fixed nav bars.
All right.
So that's a new HDMI element that we have met before but bootstrapped does a huge amount for the ones
that we're familiar with as well.
And in the next video we're going to look at two of those and that is forms and tables.