So now we have our first Web page up and running.
We're going to look at some specific TNL tags that we can use to make our Web sites look like something
other than just plain text.
And in this video we'll be looking at head attacks so I'm going to get rid of the text that my first
web page and I'm going to do my first head attack.
Now do you remember how we do that from the example dot com that we looked at a couple of years ago.
If so then try putting it ahead a tag go for it.
I managed it.
If not don't worry we open a tag in the normal way with our angle brackets and then the first header
tag we can to use is each one and then my text editor gives me the closing tag as well which is very
handy if yours doesn't then just write it out manually.
It's not a problem.
And I'm going to type.
This is a big head.
And let's have a look.
Will say that.
And take a look.
There we go.
So you can see this is what an H1 tag looks like with no custom styling.
It's a nice big bold header and that's about it.
That's all we can do with an H1 tag with an H2 tag
as you might guess.
It's quite a big header not quite as big as H-1 But let's have a look.
There we go.
So it's bigger than normal text and bold but smaller than an H1.
So you can probably see where this is going.
We can have an H-3
and it's getting smaller and smaller as we go on and I'm actually just going to copy and paste so you
don't have to see me type out each one.
So that's going to be an H for.
Let's have a quick look at that.
So obviously we're getting smaller and smaller every time and we can keep going.
So 5
smaller again we're actually getting smaller than normal text here and we can keep going.
We can have an eight six header as well.
I must say at this point they very rarely use the 8:06 head.
I don't think I've ever gone beyond an H for in any of the Web sites that I've used.
So it's very unlikely you'll use an 8.
But just to point out if we try and use an 8 7 header
we get back to normal text.
So there is actually not an 8 7 header because H7 doesn't exist so we can't use an 87 head.
If we try to do it it'll just give us normal text as if it hasn't recognized the tag so headers go all
the way from 8 1 to 6.
But to be honest you're probably only use H1 H2 and maybe H-3 in your documents and occasionally possibly
age 4.
But as I say I've never used an H5 or an 86 but head attacks are very useful and are also good for getting
your site listed in Google.
If you put your important keywords that is the words that you want your site to appear for in Google
in an H1 tag then they're much more likely to appear higher up the Google search results than if you
just put them in normal text.
So I definitely recommend using H-1 tags on all your pages and probably H-2 tags as well.
If you've got some slightly smaller headings that you want to use.
All right so now you're an expert in head of tags in the next video we're going to look at paragraph
tags which was the other formatting tags that we saw in the example dot com Web site.