So now that we know how to change the content of a web page using HVM l we're going to attempt to do
that using a button rather than updating it as soon as the page is loaded.
We're going to have a button and then when that button is pressed that's when we'll update the interface.
And that of course starts adding some genuine interactivity without pages rather than just running some
code as soon as the page is run.
So try and remember this.
I'm going to get rid of it now but you're going to need to type it in a challenge that I give you in
a minute.
So try and have that in your mind what I'm going to do is off to the hello world paragraph.
I'm going to add in a button
which is going to have the words change text every time.
And this is the button that we're going to press to update the text here.
Obviously it doesn't do anything yet.
But in order to refer to it in our javascript's we're going to give it an idea just as before so we
can call it whatever we like I'll call it my button.
All right.
So that's all we need on the H T M L side.
Here comes the first mini challenge then can you select the button by its ID.
So just in the same way that we did in the previous video when we selected the text paragraph can you
select the button by its ID in javascript different.
All right.
Hope you remember how to do it.
You should have started with document to say that we want to get something within this document and
then get element by ID.
Thats the key commands that we need in this case.
And then of course the ID is my button.
There we go.
So thats what you should have come up with.
You didn't need the enraged DML because all we wanted to do was selects the button and weve done that
now.
So how do we then connect some javascript to this button.
Well we don't want to change the energy of the button but what we do want to do is add an on click so
we do that using dot on click.
And this is effectively the same as writing an on click instruction right there as we did a couple of
videos ago but it's much cleaner because we're using internal javascript rather than in line.
So what we're doing here now is we're setting a function that we want to happen when the button is clicked.
So to set a function we use equals and then we want to create a function.
Now when we define a function we always have a pair of parentheses or brackets after it.
Quite often these might have some variable names in it.
If we're going to pass some variables to this function we're not doing that in this case.
So really don't worry too much about those parentheses really.
Think of them as things that have to come after functions.
We'll see them in a lot more detail in just the next few videos.
So now we've said equal to a function we need to define what that function is and to do that we use
our curly brackets like that.
So what this is essentially saying is when my button is clicked do whatever code I write in here.
So quick challenge number two can you make it so that when the button is clicked instead of changing
the text it alerts button clicked.
So when the button is clicked it alerts button clicked for it.
OK I hope you remember it had to do that.
Very simple.
Just alert.
And then brackets because this is a function and then we want to pass a string to the alert function.
The string is just a collection of characters which in this case we want to say button clicked and then
that's Papau semi-colon at the end.
All right let's have a look.
So now refresh and there we go button is clicked.
So that's our first bit of genuine interaction with our page using javascript.
We've run some javascript when the button was clicked.
That's all well and good but what we really want to do when this button is clicked it's changed the
text.
So this is where you need to remember what we did in the previous video.
So can you write the code that will update hello world 2.
Hello Rob.
Or Hello whatever your name is or whatever text you like.
Go for it.
Did you manage it.
I hope so.
We should have started off with document to say that we want to select something within this document
then get element by ID because we want to select an element by its ID and then the element that we want
to select is the one with the ID of text and then we want to set the in a TNL of this element equal
to whatever we like.
So I'm going to change it to Hello Rob just as we had before finish it off with a semi-colon.
That's it.
So that's exactly the same as the code that we had in the previous video.
So let's say that and fingers crossed it a all work Harrar fantastic So that's some really genuine interactivity
because we're updating our web page based on the actions of our user.
That's a very quick aside here.
I'm just going to remind you of the chrome console which you get by right clicking or control clicking
and then inspects the page and then clicking console because as you start doing more of these challenges
you'll start to get code that just doesn't do anything because remember when you have an error in Javascript
it won't show you the error on the page it just won't do anything.
So had you mis typed and typed document by mistake then had you run it nothing would happen on the page
to tell you that you had an error but it wouldn't work.
And then here in the console is where you'll see the error say Line 21 something about document.
There we get there's the error document.
Much better save refresh.
Click the button.
All is well.
So if you find yourself getting errors during the challenges then memba to look at the console to see
exactly what the areas that will save you many miserable hours trying to figure it out yourself in the
next video.
Then we'll move this along and we'll see how we can change our website content in a much more advanced
way than just updating some text.
See that.