Great.
So now we know how to insert items into our database and how to update them once they're there.
Well we're now going to look at is how to return more than one item from our database and how we can
do some fancy select queries so we can select users in a number of different ways.
All right.
So first off let's just update our output here.
So we're getting the whole of the information in the right and then we actually only need to change
a very small part of this.
We just add in a while loop and this is then a container for our row
like that.
So each time we run the command my Eskew ally fetch array we're actually fetching a new row.
So if we run it several times we'll get all of the rows that have been selected by this query.
So in our case we should get three rows i.e. all the raise in the table so let's have a look
there.
We gain let's have a look at the output.
You can see we've got these three arrays here.
We do have an undefined query.
Oh there we go.
Because I didn't get rid of my query that very
okay.
So that's now returned.
Everything in the database.
And we could do something with that data if we wanted to either display it to the user or update it
or even delete it if we wanted to.
So how do we become a bit more selective about what we're querying from the database.
Well we actually do it in exactly the same way that we updated the data in the previous video and that
is with a where clause at the end.
And what we might want to do then for example we might want to get the users with I.D. equal to one.
But with that return pretty easy.
It would return the user with an idea of one.
I mean so let's change that to search for Kirsten's
use it by email address.
We just put email equals and then put our email address in quotes like that's and that will then return
just kissed him.
There we go.
We can do a lot more than that though.
So what if we wanted to return all the users whose email was at gmail dot com.
Well that's actually pretty easy.
We change our equal sign to a like keyword.
And then if we leave that as it is that actually will return the same thing because it's searching for
where email address is like guest and at guest invisible to critique.
But the advantage of using like means that we can put a variety of symbols in our query for example
the percent symbol and the percent symbol in my school essentially means anything.
So if I put the percent symbol and then gmail dot com this essentially means select everything from
the user's table where the e-mail ends in gmail dot com i.e. it's something and then gmail dot com.
So this should return me and tell me
that again.
So here's a mini challenge for you.
Can you return everyone in our database who has a P the letter P anywhere in their email address different
hope you managed it.
It's just a matter of putting percent and then P and then another percent.
So this just means anything and then a P and then anything else.
So essentially looks for the letter P anywhere in the email address so that returns me and Carsten but
not to me.
We can also use greater than or less than symbols.
So if we wanted to return everyone whose idea was two or more then we could use to staff from users
where I.D. is greater than or equal to to and that should return.
Kirsten and Tommy there we go.
We can also return just a single column so say that we know we only needed the email address then it's
a bit wasteful to return all this other information as well so we could just put email in site these
acute accent then and then that would just return the e-mail address.
That's a rather more efficient way of dealing with databases if you know what you're going to need in
advance.
We can also combine where clauses.
So let's say if we wanted to find everyone with an idea of greater than or equal to two with a T in
their email address then we would put an end statement there and then percent t percent.
And I have put a capital T on purpose there to show you that we are case insensitive here.
So none of these have got a capital T but I have got little T's and therefore they're returned if I
changed that to a G then we should just get too many returned because Carston doesn't have a g in her
e-mail address.
So I think you get the idea to our table and I'm gonna do that in P HP my admin.
So I'm going to click structure and then add one columns at the end of table go and the column I'm going
to add is name and that's going to be a text field that we get.
So now let's browse
and I'm gonna just double click there to update my name.
And for some reason I've decided to refer to myself as Rob O'Grady.
Feel free to search for that name online to see if I've been using it anyway.
But really what I'm interested in is of course that it has that single quote in it so if now I wanted
to select the user with the name Rob O'Grady I might start off storing the name in a variable and then
I might put it in double quotes like that to save me from having to escape the character by putting
a backslash in front of it.
That so now can you update the query string so it returns the users who have a name of Rob O'Grady using
this variable name for it.
Did you manage it.
It was a bit of a trick but what I was expecting you to do was keeping that part of the query and then
changing the where clause to went.
Name equals and then in single quotes we have the name.
So I'm using my concatenate thing full stop or period there to bring the name variable into the string
and it's inside these single quotes.
So that looks like it should work.
But if we save it and run it you'll see we don't get any response at all.
And that's because what my asking well is interpreting the name string as is Rob.
Oh and then a single quote so that single quote is interpreted by my as well as ending this string.
So it says it starts with the single quote and then ends after Rob.
Oh.
In fact if we just echo out the query you'll see that in a bit more detail so starts with select email
from users where name equals.
And then this Rob O is interpreted as a single string.
And then the Grady on the end is just another strange word as far as my school is concerned.
And then is another single quote there.
So this is not a valid piece of my.
Well so it's not processed by the database.
There is however an easy fix to this.
And that is we can use the function my askew Well I underscore real underscore escape underscore string.
So it's a bit of a beast but it's well named because it escapes any nasty characters that might cause
problems in our code.
So we actually have to put the database link in there as well as without other my askew ally functions.
But what this will essentially do is add backslash is where necessary to escape potentially corrupting
characters that it cannot break our rescue.
So let's have a look.
Now we run that.
It returns fine.
So as a general rule of thumb whenever you're putting a variable into a my askew l string I would recommend
just always escaping it using that function.
There's another even more important reason to escape your strings and that is if there's any chance
that the user can edit that string if you don't use this function then the user could pretty easily
get access to your whole database by putting in a malicious string which is designed to end your query
and start a new one which could for example select everything in your database and extract all your
users data.
These are called Eskew l injection strings.
And if you want to find out more about that and how you protect your website from them then just have
a google of Eskew l injections but a very good protection.
It's simply to use this whenever you are taking a variable and putting it into a my askew l string.
Then you won't go too far wrong.
All right I'm going to set you a quick challenge then to put all of this together and try and do it
without referring back if you possibly can.
The idea of this is to get the my askew ally commands in your head.
So this is just gonna be a very simple sign up form where you're going to ask for an email and a password
and then when they submit the form check the email and password have been entered then check that the
email address is not already registered
and if all of that's okay sign the user up i.e. put them into your database doesn't have to look pretty
we're not using Bootstrap or anything here we just want something that works go for it.
All right.
I hope you manage that.
Let's give it a shot.
So I'm gonna have a form with a method of post you could use get but I wouldn't recommend it.
Especially when passwords are involved.
And then in this form we're going to have an input with the name of email and we'll give it a place
holder of email address.
Then we'll have another input with a name of password and a type
of password and a placeholder of password.
And actually we should probably have a type for the first one as well.
It's gonna be text which is the default type but it's always good to have types for all of your inputs.
And then finally we'll have input with a type of submit and a value of
sign up.
All right.
Simple as that.
Let's have a look.
Forgot that we were viewing the source there.
Let's go back and actually view the debate at database base itself.
Excellent.
So there's e-mail a password you can see last pass is trying to predict things for me but I'll just
ignore that.
All right.
Let's now check at the beginning of our script if we have some post variables and we're going to do
that using the function that we saw before power a key exists and we're looking for the key.
Email
in the array post
and we'll add in an all
to see if they've entered a password.
It's pretty unlikely that they will just enter a password but it is possible and
I think I'll just do a print Ah.
If that is the case just a check.
There we go.
So we've got our email and our password and then we'll check to see if the email address and password
fields actually have values are you.
The user has typed something in so we'll check to see if email is empty and if it is we'll echo that
the email address is required
like that's and if it's not.
That means that we have an email address so let's just check for a password and if that's not there
then we'll check.
We'll tell them sorry that the password is required all right so let's take a look at that for now.
Put an email address it tells me that the passwords required if I put in a password tells me that the
e-mail address is required.
If I put in both.
It does nothing which is great.
Okay.
So now we want to check to see if the user exists in our database or not.
That's the third and final error that we might see
so let's start off with our query
and we want to select
and let's just select I.D. from the database.
There'll be more efficient because we don't need everything else.
We just need something to tell us whether or not that item is already there.
And we want to select it from the users table
where the email address is equal to and this is why we need our my ask you.
I real escape.
String
we want to escape
the email address that they've have entered and then closed that and end our query.
All right.
If you did manage to succeed with this challenge but you didn't put that in then a small slap on the
wrist for you because your form was very insecure and open to ask you well injections.
So then let's do a check to see if my SKU Well I query and then we want to check the link and the query
and I've just noticed that I'm defining the link beneath all of this code here.
So I'm going to pop my link in there because we don't need to connect to the database if the user hasn't
tried to log in
whoops.
And let's not forget to put our link in there as well.
And then we run our query
so this is gonna be my s q Well I query and we want to send the database link and the query itself and
then we want to check if there's any results in this query.
So one way to do that would be to fetch the results as we did before.
But I just want to show you one more way that we can do that which is slightly more efficient.
We can use my Eskew Well I am then num rows and results and this will return the number of rows in the
result without actually having to get all the votes themselves.
So efficiency is not particularly important in a tiny setup like this.
But if you've got a massive web site that people are logging into all the time it does make all the
difference.
So we should try and be efficient where we possibly can.
So if we check to see if the number of rows is greater than zero then if it is
we'll say to the user that email address has already been taken
all right.
That makes sense.
Let's take a look.
So I'm going to put in an e-mail address that has already been taken or possibility at gmail dot com.
Put in a password and then sign up.
So that e-mail address has already been taken.
Fantastic.
If I put in one that hasn't been taken yet and a password we should not get that error.
Wonderful.
All right.
So the final thing to do then is to actually sign the user up if they've been successful.
So we'll do that of course with another query and here we're going to insert into the user's table and
the columns that we're going to provide.
Email and password and the values that we're going to give for them are.
I'm just going to copy this bit here so my securely real estate string with the link and the email that's
the email address and then something very similar
for the password
and we'll just collate those parentheses then and then end our command
and then we want to run that query.
So that'll be my squirrelly query link karma query and we'll do a quick check here to see if that's
been successful if it has will.
Okay.
You have been signed up and if not well for now we'll just say
there was a problem signing you up.
Please try again later so that of course should never happen.
But it's always good to check and make sure that everything has worked in the way that you think it
has.
So let's just try submitting that one more time.
Oh good an error on line 34.
Oh yes.
Because we're not actually running the query here.
I don't need a close parentheses I just need to close the string.
All right.
Try that once more.
And there we go.
You have been signed up and we may well have been logged out of HP may have me now but let's have a
quick look.
Yeah we have.
So we'll look back in using the password that we're using in our script
and we should see.
There we go.
We've got a new email address with a password.
So one quick note about passwords as I mentioned before we should never have our passwords like this
in just plain text and in a couple of videos time I'll show you the good way to store passwords in your
database.
Before that though I want to show you two ways of actually logging users in or signing them up because
it's all well and good to tell them they've been signed up and then put into a database but then they're
going to click on another link and we want a way to know on that new link that this user is logged in.
And we should show them some information about their account or whatever it is.
And there are two primary ways to do that.
SESSIONS And cookies and we're going to look at both of those in the next two videos starting with sessions.