Now, this course section is an optional one.
This course section will be a refresher on ReactJS,
and you can skip it if you already have
a solid ReactJS foundation,
for example because you took
my React - The Complete Guide course.
In this module,
I'm going to make sure we're all on the same page
by again exploring what exactly React is and why we use it,
by diving into some Core React Concepts:
Components, Props, and State.
And we're going to build a full project
and explore some advanced concepts like Effects and Context.
Now, we're going to use functional components only, here.
We're going to use React Hooks,
and you're going to learn what that is in this module.
And we're going to use these concepts
throughout the rest of this course.
So don't skip this module,
if you don't know these concepts yet,
or if you're not sure about them,
if it's been some time since you last worked with React.
But absolutely do feel free to skip this module,
if you do know these concepts,
because you won't learn anything about NextJS here.
It's really just about React.
And we're going to start with NextJS,
and its Core Concepts in the section after this section.