Hi, and welcome to this course about React.js,
the most popular JavaScript library
you can learn these days.
I'm super happy to welcome you on board.
My name is Maximilian Schwarzmuller
and I will be your instructor in this course.
Now in this first course section here,
I'm going to walk you through the most important questions.
What is React?
Why do we use it?
And I'll also explain what's inside this course,
how you can take this course,
which content you find in here.
Therefore, my recommendation is that you carefully
go through all those lectures
so that you will get a great overview of both
React and this course.
And then thereafter, in this course,
you're really going to learn all about React
in great detail, step-by-step.
You don't need any prior React knowledge.
You just need basic JavaScript knowledge,
and I also got a refresher on that,
so that we're all on the same page,
and therefore I'd say let's not waste any time.
Instead, let's dive into the most important question first.
What exactly is React
and why might it be a good idea to learn it?