So, what are custom hooks?
And we need to clarify what they are
before I can dive into the why.
So, what are custom hooks?
Custom hooks are, in the end, just regular functions
just as the built-in hooks, like use state, are
in the end just functions, but they are functions
which can contain stateful logic.
You can build custom hooks, these custom hook functions
to outsource stateful logic into reusable functions.
Unlike regular functions, custom hooks can use
other React hooks, including other custom hooks.
And they can, therefore, also leverage React state managed
with use state or use reducer.
They can access use effect and so on.
With custom hooks, you can outsource logic,
which you might be using in different components,
into a custom hook, which you can then call
from all these various components.
So, it is simply a mechanism of reusing logic,
just as regular functions are with the special thing
that in these custom hook functions,
you can use React hooks and other hooks.
And that might, of course, still be a bit abstract.
So, therefore, let me give you
a concrete example which shows you
why you might wanna explore custom hooks
and how you then build a custom hook,
step-by-step and how you use it.