So how do you deploy our React application?
How do you push it onto a real server?
There are a couple of steps involved,
which you can go through whenever you deploy
or redeploy your application.
It all starts with writing your code, of course,
and then with testing your code.
And this might sound obvious
but of course you wanna thoroughly test your application
before you deploy it.
You wanna play around with it,
test different things,
see if you handle errors correctly,
things like that.
You wanna make sure that you're shipping an application
which is ready to be used.
Then, as a next step,
you might wanna explore optimization opportunities.
There are certain things in your code
which you can optimize,
most importantly,
you might wanna look into a concept called lazy loading.
And we are going to explore this concept
in this course section.
So that is another important part
before you actually move your code somewhere,
optimize it.
Now once you're happy with your code,
it's optimized and it's working,
then it's time to build your app for production.
And with build, I don't mean
that you need to write more code,
but instead, we will execute a script
which was written for us already,
which is part of this React project we worked with
throughout this course,
a script which will then output a production ready bundle
of our code,
which is minified and automatically optimized
to be as small as possible,
so that we get an output there,
which we can take like that
and move on to a server,
and will then automatically serve our users
a highly optimized code package
which is as small as possible,
which of course matters,
because we wanna ship as little code as possible
to our users,
because they will only be able to interact with our website
once it's fully loaded.
So shipping less code will load the app faster
and therefore is better,
and will be able to automatically generate
such a optimized minified code bundle with a certain script
which we are also going to see in action
in this course section.
Now, once we got this optimized code package
which is ready for deployment,
we need to deploy that package.
And therefore, the next step is that we take that code
which is produced for us,
which is based on the code we wrote of course,
and uploaded to a server.
Now, there will have different choices,
different hosting providers which we can use.
And I'll show you an example in this course section.
But you can really deploy anywhere.
I'll just leave a couple of notes
on what matters there
and what you should keep in mind
when it comes to deploying your application.
You will definitely need to configure your server
or your hosting provider's offering.
And I'll dive into this configuration
together with you in this course section
to make it crystal clear what matters here,
what you should pay attention to,
and how you do configure
and ultimately deploy your code and your server correctly.