Now let's start with
looking at asynchronous code
and side effects in general,
even if they should be synchronous,
even if the code should be synchronous, and Redux.
Because there is one super important rule.
Your reducer functions
must be pure,
side-effect free, and synchronous.
So your reducer functions should take some input
in the case of the Redux reducer,
the old state and the action,
and then produce some output.
And that's,
by the way not just the case for
Redux reducer function.
The reducer function you pass to use reducer,
is react hook,
works in the same way.
It has nothing to do with redux,
but it just general reducer concept
that you have a pure,
side effects synchronous function
that takes input and
produces some output.
And for the same input,
for the same values,
it will always produce the same output,
without any side effects that happen along the way
without any asynchronous code that blocks it.
No code of that kind must be part of your
reducer functions.
But of course, that brings up an important question
when working with redux,
when we dispatch some action
that would involve a side effect,
like HTTP request that should be sent,
where should we then put
the side effect code?
Where should we put our asynchronous code
when working with redux?
Because the reducer function
is clearly the wrong place
as we just learned.
The answer to this question is
that we have two possible places
where we can put our side effects.
We can put our side effects
possibly asynchronous code
directly into the component
with user fact for example,
so just as we did it before in this course,
and then we only dispatch an action
once that side effect is done
so Redux doesn't know anything about that side effect,
or, and
that will be new
we write our own action creator functions,
so we don't use the automatically generated ones
redux toolkit gives us
but instead we write our own action creators.
And it turns out that
for those action creators
redux actually has a solution
that allows us to
perform side effects
and run asynchronous tasks as part of this action creators
without changing the reducer function
because that function must stay side effect free.
Now we are going to have a look at both
approaches in this course
section,
And
to have a look at that,
We are going to start
by setting up another
React-Redux application.
We are going to do that in the next
two lectures and you can therefore
skip those two lectures
if you don't wanna repeat
what you learnt in the last course section,
though I of course recommend that you don't.
But we are going to repeat that
build a basic react-redux application
in the next two lectures
and there after we're going to
explore asynchronous code
and redux
and all this shiny new things.