So here's our project,
and we already got a list of data there,
but of course this list is static.
It's not dynamic at all at the moment.
So for example, if we filter here
this does not affect the list at all,
and also if we would add a new item here,
you would also see that as we pick this and add this
it's not added to the list because we haven't added
the logic for this yet.
So therefore that's what we're going to do,
and therefore, here in this application
we now wanna continue working on that.
In the expenses JS file we currently render
our list of expenses by individually adding
these expense item elements here in our JSX code,
and that's of course not dynamic at all.
In most web applications we don't know in advance
how many items we wanna render.
I mean, here for example, we don't know how many expenses
the user is going to add and how many expenses
should be displayed when a certain year is selected.
So therefore hard coding the number of expense items
as we're currently doing it is definitely not the way to go.
Instead we wanna render that list dynamically,
and doing that as a standard case,
which you'll face in a lot of projects and applications,
and it's therefore also straightforward to do with React.
So here is how it does work.
We wanna render our expenses which are defined in App.js.
Here we got this expenses array,
and we wanna render this in the expenses component,
therefore, the first step is to pass
our expenses down via props, which we're already doing.
We are passing the items prop,
which points at this expenses array.
So in the expenses component, we do get our list of expenses
but we're currently not using that,
and that's what we wanna change.
On our props we got this items prop,
and the value of that will be that array,
which will be in the end when I render here,
but we don't wanna output the array
as text or anything like that.
Instead, we wanna render one expense item
per element in the array, and that's straightforward to do.
For this, we first of all need single curly braces,
opening and closing, because we wanna execute
a dynamic expression in our JSX code,
and you learned that that's done with curly braces.
Then we can execute JavaScript expressions here.
Now the expression which I do want to execute here
is that I reach out to my array of data,
in this case the array of expenses,
and that then for every element
we wanna create such a JSX element.
For this we can access props items,
that's our array of items, our array of expenses,
and now we can use a built in array method,
which is built into standard JavaScript,
and that's the map method.
You can learn more about this method
if you Google for JS array map,
and what this method does, is that it creates a new array
based on another array, and that basically transforms
every element in that original array.
So here in this example, you, for example,
see that we have an array of numbers,
and with map we multiply every number with two
so that we get this new array as a result,
and for applying this transformation, map,
this method which we can call,
takes a function, which we pass as an argument,
and that function is then executed
for every item in the array on which we're calling map,
and the result of this function is the element
which will be added to the newly created array.
That's how this works, and that's a built in method,
as I said, and we can utilize it here
to transform our array of objects, which we have here,
we got a bunch of objects in there,
into an array of JSX elements, to be precise,
into an array full of expense item JSX elements,
because if you do output an array of JSX elements here,
like a couple of cards, then React is capable
of simply rendering these elements.
So if you had something like this,
an array of JSX elements as part of your JSX code,
react would simply render these elements side by side,
and that's what we utilize here to transform
our array of objects into such an array of expense items,
which then are rendered by React.
So map, as I just showed you, takes a function
as a argument, and that function executes
for every element in the array, and it gets that element
for which it's currently executing as a parameter.
So here we get our expense, for example,
and then in the function body,
so on the right side of this arrow
if we're using our arrow function,
we then have to return the JSX element
into which we want to map this expense.
So in this case, I wanna map every expense
in my expenses array, I want to map every expense
into an expense item JSX element.
So I wanna transform the expense object
to this special kind of object, to this JSX element,
and then we can just configure this as we did it here.
We add a title prop, but the title is now expense.title,
so this expense, which has passed as a parameter
into this function automatically,
because that's how map works,
that expense is used to extract the title,
and we do the same for the amount with expense amount,
and of course we do the same for the date
by setting the date prop to expense date.
Let me reformat this, and this is now how that looks like.
Now we can get rid of the hard coded expense items here,
and we're only left with this map expression here,
where we transform our array to an array full of JSX items.
Hence, if I now save this, and I reload,
we get a warning, which you can ignore for now,
but we also see that we get all these items being rendered
just as before but now it's actually happening dynamically,
which simply means that now it's based on the actual array,
and that of course means that we can now
also change that array and such changes
will be reflected in that list,
and that's what we're going to do next therefore.
Of course, feel free to try it on your own first.
We're going to do it together in the next lecture.