In React we're working with JSX.
We work with JSX all the time here
in this course already.
In this course project
which we worked on in the last course module
which you find attached to this lecture by the way
in case you didn't follow along
you can simply download it
extract it, run NPM install
and NPM start and you're good to go.
In that project we of course used JSX.
JSX is that code you return in your Components
which in the end will be rendered
to the real DOM by a React.
That's what JSX is
and we use it all the time.
But JSX has certain limitations
specifically there is one limitation
which we all has already faced in this course.
If we have adjacent root level JSX elements
like in this example
we'll get an error.
And with root level
I mean that we have two JSX elements next to Java
not wrapped by another JSX element.
And we then return these side by side JSX elements
or we try to store them in variables.
This will not work
because in React in JSX in general
you can't have more than one root JSX element.
So if you return a value or if you store a value
in a variable or in a constant or in a property
that value must only be exactly one JSX element
not two or three or four side by side adjacent elements.
Now that one element which you are allowed to have
may of course have more children
which then also can be adjacent to each other.
But that top most element
which you're storing or returning
must only be one element.
And the reason for that
is actually not that difficult to understand
because this also isn't valid JavaScript.
You can't return more than one thing in JavaScript either
you can return one number, not two
you can return one string, not two.
Of course you could return an array
and there you could have multiple numbers
but an array is already a new value.
An array is just the object
so you still only return one array,
one object, not two arrays at the same time.
So that is really important to understand here
your JSX code translates into React create element
like you see it here at the bottom of the slide.
And you must only have one React create element call
which you return.
Now any nested JSX elements
so inside of that one root element
could be side by side
because into the React create element world
those children of that root element
would be the third and fifth and so on argument.
And that's something I had a closer look
at in the basics module
where we explored how JSX translates into
React create element calls.
But because of that natural limitation
of JavaScript we must only have one root JSX element.
Now how can we work around that?
There is one solution
and actually we can already use
that solution here in
that add user Component in
that provided project which you find attached.
Here I do have a rapping div
and that is a workaround.
You can solve this problem
by simply wrapping the adjacent elements with a div.
If you do that
if you wrap them with a div
then you only have one thing that you return
only one value.
It's a bit like returning free numbers
by putting them into an array.
Here we're returning to nested JSX elements
by putting them into one div which we return.
Now this also doesn't have to be a div
you could be using any element here
you could also be using a custom Component here.
The main thing that matters
is that you only have one value
which you return or which you store it in a constant.
And that's all to what we're doing here.
Now there're actually is always an alternative to that
instead of using a div
we could use a native JavaScript array.
I could remove my opening and closing div tags
and put my card Component here
and that dynamic expression here
into an array, separated by commas.
I just would need to remove these curly braces here
because we're no longer inside of JSX here
we're inside of an array.
That would be valid
but this has a little gotcha.
We can return an array
because React is able to work with arrays of JSX elements.
We did utilize that when we output our list
of users here
or also earlier in the course
you learned about mapping a raise of data
to JSX elements in the lists and conditionals module.
So React knows how to work
with a raise of JSX elements and hence
of course here
we could also return such an array of JSX elements.
If we do that
and we previewed application
we do get a warning though
because whenever you're working with an array
of JSX elements
React wants a key on every element.
And that's no exception here
it wants that key
if you map dynamically through a list
of data and map that data to JSX elements
but it also wants such a key
if you have a hard-coded array of JSX elements
as we have it here.
Now of course we can simply add a key
and since this is not generated dynamically
we can hard-code keys here
error modal for example
and add user a card.
We could add the key prop
with our own invented well use
and we would be fine.
And that would be perfectly fine
but typically you don't use this solution
because adding those keys
wrapping it in an array
is a little bit cumbersome.
It's way easier to simply add a wrapping div here
like we had it before.
So I can just go back to that
add my div here and now wrap this here back
into curly braces
and remove the comma here
because now we have a dynamic expression
instead of JSX again
so we need the curly braces to evaluate this expression.
So that's simply more convenient
and therefore typically we use the wrapping div.
However with the wrapping div
or generally any wrapping element
a new problem arises.
Now we can end up with div soup.
So we can end up with a real DOM that's being rendered
where you have many nested React Components
and all those Components
for various reasons need wrapping divs
or have wrapping Components.
And you have all these unnecessary divs being rendered
into real DOM
even though they're only there
because of this requirement or this limitation of JSX.
And this is not an unrealistic scenario.
In bigger applications
It's a very possible that in your final HTML page
which is being served to your end users
you have a lot of unnecessary divs or other elements
which are only there
because you needed them as wrappers
even though they don't add any semantic
or structural meaning to your page.
Now of course you don't have to care about that
you might be fine with that
but it could break your styling.
If you have a wrapping div somewhere
and you use nested CSS selectors
that div could break stylings.
And even if it doesn't break your styling
it's still not a good practice.
You're rendering too many HTML elements
and ultimately that also makes your application slower
because the browser needs
to render all those elements
and React needs to check all those elements
or at least some of those elements
if content needs to change.
So rendering unnecessary content is generally
never a good idea in programming.
Hence this wrapping div
or this wrapping element approach is okay
but not ideal.