Attached you'll find
a simple starting project
basically a pretty empty React application
with an empty app component.
And once you've downloaded and extracted the attached file,
you just need to run npm-install to install all dependencies
like the React library and thereafter,
once you ran npm-install
which I already did here you run npm start
to start this application
and you'll be greeted by such an empty screen
because currently there is nothing inside of AppJS,
nothing inside of our app component.
Now in the application, which you saw in the last lecture,
I wanna have a couple of different areas,
a couple of different components.
We had that component where we could enter our name
and our age.
We had that error modal,
that error overlay component.
We had a button to submit this and to confirm
that we saw the error in that error modal,
and we, of course. also had that list of users.
Therefore, I'll start by roughly planning
out the components we'll have.
And for that I'll add a new components folder
in which I wanna store those components.
And I'll add a UI folder for general UI components
which will have like the button.
And in components,
I'll also add a second folder
and that will be my users folder
for all the user related components.
And now in there we can start adding component files
and I'll start with that component
that allows us to add a new user.
Hence here in the user's folder,
I'll add a new AddUser.js file
which should hold the logic for us to add a new user.
Now in there I wanna have a React component.
So, of course, we have to import React
from React as you learnt
because we're going to use some JSX code here.
I'll then add my AddUser component
using this function syntax which we can use in JavaScript,
an arrow function stored in a constant.
Of course, as I mentioned before,
you can also add a function like this
nothing wrong with that
but I'll go for this approach
and I'll export this as my default
so that we can import that component,
that function into another file and use it there.
Now, instead of AddUser in the end,
we wanna render something on the screen
which allows the user to enter a name and an age
and have a button to confirm all of that.
Therefore, in here, I will add a form let's say,
and inside of that form I wanna have a label
where I say username
and of course that should all be returned
so let's wrap it into brackets
and then put a return statement in front of it.
So there, I wanna have a label
and I wanna have an input where the user then
is actually to type that username.
And that input will be of type text because well,
expect some text there.
Now for accessibility,
we can also add an ID here username.
And then on the label
we would add the for attribute normally.
Now for just like class is not a name that is available
in JSX because these would be reserved JavaScript names
and therefore it's htmlFor actually,
that's the prop name for assigning
that for attribute to a label.
And with that we connect it to that input,
and that's important for screen readers and so on
so that they understand which label belongs
to which input.
So we got that.
Now, I also need another pair of label and input
for the age in years let's say.
And here the type will be number
because I expect to get a number here.
Something like 31, 18, 25, and so on.
Now I'll name this age,
I'll give it an ID of age and therefore
the htmlFor prop here also has a value of age.
And with that I got these two inputs.
Now, below those I want to have a button of type submit
which will basically submit that form.
And here I have AddUser as my text.
So that's a straightforward form.
Now, on the form here,
I'll add the onSubmit prop to specify a function
that should be executed when that form is submitted
and therefore here I will actually add a new function
inside of the AddUser component function.
Let's say AddUserHandler function.
Now here, I expect to get my event object
and I will call event.preventDefault
to prevent that default which for the submission event
is that a request is sent.
I don't want that default hence I prevent it here.
And now can connect on submit here to AddUserHandler
by passing AddUserHandler like this to onSubmit.
Important as I explained before,
don't add parentheses here.
This would immediately execute AddUserHandler
when this line is parsed.
Instead, I just want to pass a pointer
to that function to the onSubmit prop
so that the form component internally
can use that function when it needs to use it,
i.e when that form is getting submitted.
So with that we get this AddUserHandler here.
Now let's go over to AppJS and let's import it here.
So I import AddUser from ./components/Users/AddUser.
And here in the div we can then add AddUser like that.
That's how we can add this component here.
And if we now save that
and go back we should see this relatively ugly,
but working component.
I can click AddUser and the page is not reloading,
which proves that this forms submission
is effectively handled and the default is prevented.
So that's the start.
Now, some styling would be nice
because that doesn't really look the way I want it to look.
Now, I'll start an index CSS there.
You got some basic styling.
I'll go to the HTML element here
and add a background styling of 1F, 1F, 1F like this
and this will give us a nice dark grayish background.
Now, I also want to wrap this username
and age into a card you could say,
into a container with rounded corners
and with a white background
and that's therefore something we'll build
in the next lecture.
Of course, feel free to try this on your own.
Build such a wrapper and container
maybe already with the right styles on your own.
And in the next lecture, we'll build it together.