Now, when we speak about automated testing,
it is important to understand that there are different kinds
of automated tests which you can have a look at.
For example, there are unit tests and I can already say
that those will be super important.
But you also have so-called integration tests
and end to end tests.
Now, these are the three main categories of tests
which you can write.
Unit tests are all about writing tests
for the smallest possible units off your application.
So for functions, individual functions that you use
in your application.
Or in case of React apps,
testing some components independently
from the other components in your app.
And therefore projects typically contain a lot
of unit tests, since you basically wanna test
all the units, all the functions and components
that make up your application.
And hence this is the most common
and important kind of test.
And the idea simply is that
if you test all the individual units on themselves,
the overall application will also work.
But to verify that the overall application really works
if you put together all those units,
we have integration tests.
Here, we test the combination of multiple building blocks.
For example, multiple components working together.
And projects typically contain
a couple of such integration tests,
but not as many as you have unit tests.
Though as you will also see throughout this course section,
it's not always that easy to differentiate
between unit and integration tests when testing React apps,
since very often, you wanna test a component
that also uses some other component.
But we're going to see that in action
throughout this course section.
So generally, integration tests are also extremely important
but we have fewer integration tests than we have unit tests.
And then we also have end to end tests.
These are all about testing entire workflows
in your application, you could say.
Entire scenarios, like logging a user in
and then going to a certain page.
So these aim to really reproduce what a real human would do
with your website.
Basically what you would also do with manual testing,
just automated.
Now, whilst this might sound like the most important test
it definitely is important
and you therefore typically do write some end to end tests
but not as many as you have unit and integration tests,
because if your a unit and integration tests work,
you can be pretty sure that your overall application works.
And then those unit and integration tests
are simply easier to test.
They often are quicker to run and they are more focused
and it's way easier to test all possible scenarios,
if you test all your units for different scenarios
then coming up with all possible scenarios,
if you look at your app as a whole,
which is what you do typically with end to end tests.
So these are important,
but it's basically all to what you do manually
and therefore you have fewer of those tests.
Now in this course section, since it's an introduction
to testing.
We will focus on those most important kinds
of tests.
Unit tests and also to some extent integration tests.
But at the end of the module, I will also point you
at some other resources, which you can check out
to dive deeper into React testing if you want to.