This is a very simple demo here.
(whooshing)
I have some content on the page
and when I click delete, I get this overlay,
where I can confirm or cancel.
Now both buttons don't do anything,
but close that overlay,
as does clicking that backdrop.
But what you see on this page here,
or what happens when we click delete,
all of that is controlled with JavaScript.
I got a HTML file, with some very basic
HTML content, some styling, which you can ignore.
And then the magic happens in this app, JS file.
In there, I got some code, that in the end
adds a Listener to this main button,
which we got on the screen.
So too this delete button here.
And when that button is clicked,
I fired this showModalHandler function.
And in there we run a bunch of JavaScript code,
to create various elements, divs, paragraphs
and then the cancel and confirm buttons,
to configure those elements
and add text or CSS classes.
And to add EventListeners to those
elements as well, to then fire
that closeModalHandler function,
which in the end removes the overlay,
this modal as we call it.
And then still in the showModalHandler function,
I got some code that combines all those
created elements and brings them onto the screen.
This is the JavaScript code responsible
for opening this overlay here.
Now it works and it's not too bad,
but it's quite some code for this simple action.
And here we only got one Todo,
in this demo application.
If we would add multiple Todos,
if we would repeat this HTML code multiple times
to render more Todos on the page,
or to even render those Todos dynamically,
after fetching them from a database, for example,
this code would become far more difficult,
far more complex.
And for example, I couldn't just select a button
on the page with that querySelector,
because we would have multiple delete buttons,
for multiple Todos.
And we would have to make sure,
that for different Todos,
different overlays are opened.
And when we confirm the deletion,
the correct Todo is deleted.
We're not even doing that here in this demo,
but that would be more complexity,
which we have to add and handle,
if we build a more realistic app here,
a more realistic website.
And therefore just JavaScript works
and can sometimes be a good choice,
but it can also reach its limits.
And one of the reasons is that
with just the JavaScript, you have to write
every single step that should be taken.
We want to create a element.
We want to set its content.
We want to add classes.
We want to add a click listener.
Then what should happen on that click listener.
Every single step needs to be described.
This way of programming and bringing something
onto the screen, is called an imperative approach.
We simply describe action after action,
step after step and that can reach its limits.
And in addition, even if we don't reach any limits,
we as a developer have to take care
about all the nitty-gritty details.
We have to run the low level code
for creating a button, for setting it's text content.
And therefore in the end, we reinvent the wheel,
over and over again, doing repetitive tasks.
Now here's the same example with React.
This works in exactly the same way,
but the code looks very different.
I got a React project here.
And as a side note, you find both code repositories,
both code snapshots attached.
And here in React.js, this might look
a bit more complex, we got more files involved here,
but that's something we're going to learn
throughout the course, why we have multiple files,
but in the end, this is the main code
that's responsible for bringing this Todo
onto the screen.
And what's very interesting here,
is that we have like a custom HTML component here,
a custom HTML element.
And indeed React is all about those components.
React is all about splitting your application
into small building blocks, small components,
where every building block, every component,
has a clear task and therefore your code
stays maintainable and manageable
and React, the library, will do the heavy lifting
of rendering something on the screen
and of combining all your code.
So for example, if we look into the code
for this custom element, which we built here,
which lives in this Todo.js file,
then we here again see that I have some HTML code
for rendering a Todo, but that we have
some kind of placeholder in here
and then some kind of other code,
which we don't fully understand yet,
but which we will understand
and learn about throughout this course.
And in the end, that's the code
responsible for rendering such a Todo
and for rendering the modal, this overlay here,
as well and for rendering it conditionally.
And what's interesting here, is that even though
we don't understand this code yet
and even though it's certainly strange
that we have HTML code in JavaScript files,
even though that's all weird,
we can definitely see that we don't have a bunch
of step-by-step instructions here.
Instead, we kind of define what we want to have
as an end result.
And then we have some placeholders,
some flexible elements there.
And then we have very simple instructions here,
which in the end then will be processed
by React to change what's visible on the screen.
And all these low level instructions
for creating elements and setting text continents on,
those instructions are not written by us
when using React, instead they will be written,
or defined if you wanna call it like this,
by the React library.
We, as a React developer, work on a higher level,
which makes working with React and which makes
building complex user interfaces way easier.
And that is why we want to use React.js,
it makes building modern, rich, complex
user interfaces easier.
And it does so, by giving us
a higher level syntax, where we write code
in a declarative way, in a declarative
component-focused way, we define
what we wanna have on the screen.
What the end goal is.
We create these custom HTML elements
and React will do the rest.
And one side effect, for example,
is that if we wanted more than one Todo,
we could just copy that custom element,
change maybe that text, that configuration
and boom, we got a second Todo here.
And we got up button on that Todo,
which works as well.
And that is why we use technologies
or frameworks like React.