So how could we now update
this expenses array whenever a new expense is being added?
Well for this, we need to go to App.js
because that is where we have this expenses array.
There, we also have this addExpenseHandler function
which we added in the last course section
which has triggered whenever a new expenses added.
And we even received the expense as a parameter here.
So all we got to do is we have to add this expense
to this expenses array.
But of course, if we just edit like this
nothing would happen because you already learned
that just because you change some variable,
React won't update the component.
Instead to achieve that, you need to use state.
And therefore here in App.js,
where we manage our expenses,
we now wanna import useState from React
so that we can register some state here.
And I will actually grab this array here,
this constant and extract that out
of this component function and instead store it here
and name it Initial Expenses
or Dummy Expenses since that's what it is.
So that this actually is just some dummy data
which we can use to initialize our state with.
But then inside of the app component function
we call useState and I'll pass my dummy expenses
so this array full of dummy data
as an initial state value
so that we have some initial expenses to display.
But then here, we can again use de-structuring
as I showed it to you in the last section
to get access to our expenses
and to the set expenses state updating function.
And now that we got this here in the addExpenseHandler
where we wanna add a new expense,
we can call setExpenses to set our expenses array
to a new array which includes this new expense.
So how should we update this?
Well, we could pass a new array here
and then let's say we wanna add the new expense
as the first item in the array.
For that we could add the expense which we're getting here
as an item to this array and then use
the spread operator on the existing expenses
to pull out all the existing array elements
and populate the rest of this new array
with those existing elements.
We can use the spread operator not just on objects
but also on arrays.
And again, that's not a React feature.
That's a standard JavaScript feature.
However, if we would update the state like this
it would not really be correct,
as you learned in the last core section.
Instead, if you update your state
depending on the previous state
or to previous snapshot of this state,
you should use this special function form
for this state updating function.
So it would be passed a function as argument
to this state updating function
and that function will automatically receive
the latest state snapshot.
So here we would then get our previous expenses
automatically by React.
And we would return our new array
where we add this expense which we're getting
as a parameter here and where we then add
our previous expenses with that spread operator.
And that's the clean way of updating our state
when it's based on an older snapshot of that same state.
Now with that, we add our new expense.
And now since we're using our expenses state here
to pass it to expenses,
we should automatically have a dynamic list
which automatically updates when items are added.
So if we now add a book for $29.99 and pick some date here,
we see that being added here as a first item.
So this is working and now this is a truly dynamic list
by using state and by outputting these items
with this map method.
And that's how you output lists of data dynamically
with React.
Now let's have a look at this key warning
and what that is all about.