Now, to get started with hooks,
you find a extra project attached to this lecture here,
which acts as a starting project for this course section.
It's this starting project
which we're going to use
to dive into the different hooks,
to use them, to learn how they work
and to then also write our own custom hooks.
So this is a simple React project created
with Create React app.
It runs on a version later than 16.8.
And that's important, you need to have React 16.8 or higher.
Otherwise you can't use React hooks.
Well, and other than that,
there's nothing special in here.
It's just a normal React application
with a couple of components I already built for you.
So let me quickly walk you through what we have here
before we start working with that
and before we start using React hooks.
With our index.js file, which is pretty trivial,
I'm importing index.css,
which sets up some global styling,
imports a font, sets up some well, global styling
for the font, for buttons, and that's it.
And then here, I render the App component,
which is living in the App.js file.
It's a very simple component.
It doesn't do much.
It will do more later,
which is why I have this extra component.
For now it just returns the Ingredients components,
which we get from the components folder,
there from the Ingredients subfolder
and then from the Ingredients.js file,
which would be this file here.
Now, in there, I, in the end, have a div.
I render a IngredientForm component,
which lives in the IngredientForm.js file.
And then I have a section
where I render the Search component,
which unsurprisingly lives in the Search.js file.
And if we have a look at the IngredientForm,
then we see that this is a component
that uses a custom Card component,
which lives in the UI folder.
We'll have a look at that folder in a second.
And then the IngredientForm here,
I do have my form here,
I have a section, which is a normal form
with a couple of inputs, two inputs to be precise
for a type and an amount
with a button and I'm also using React.memo here
to wrap this component to avoid unnecessary re-renders
so that this only re-renders, this component only re-renders
when the props it depends on changed
and not always when the parent component changed.
So not always when ingredients changed
but only when ingredients changed
and we're passing new props to IngredientForm,
which right now, we're never doing.
So right now, IngredientForm won't re-render
when Ingredients re-renders.
That's just a tiny side note.
You'll learned about React.memo earlier in the course
in the component deep dive module.
Now, that's the Ingredients folder.
Well, almost, we also have IngredientList.
There I'm just rendering a list of ingredients.
Right now we're not getting any ingredients from anywhere
and therefore, well, we're not using this.
We'll use it throughout this module, of course.
And in the Search.js file,
well, there I also use React.memo
for the same reasons I do it in the IngredientForm
and I just output a search box,
this input here in a Card.
And that's, of course, this box here at the bottom.
I've got a couple of CSS files there too.
You can, of course, go through them if you want.
Just a bit of styling to make this all look good
so that we have a nice-looking app to work with.
Now, in the UI folder, I prepared a couple
of UI components, like the Card here,
which simply wraps whatever we pass between its opening
and closing tag and gives it this nice Card look
with these styles here.
I've got the ErrorModal, which I'm right now not using
but which we will use throughout this module.
And this is just using React.Fragment.
Then I render a backdrop there in the modal itself
where we can output a custom content,
like a custom error message.
We've got a button to close that.
Clicking the backdrop should also close the modal
but it'll be up to us to wire up this logic.
I'm also using React.memo here and here I've got some styles
for that modal.
And I have a LoadingIndicator,
which is just a spinner, which we can render
to indicate that we're well, loading data.
So that is what we have here.
These are the components I'm giving you
and right now, this app doesn't do anything.
You can enter something here
but hitting this button won't do anything
because now it's up to us to wire this up.
And if you watch closely,
you'll see that all these components here,
they're all functional components.
There's not a single class-based component in there.
And we'll leave these components as functional components.
So we'll not change that
because as we'll now learn in this module,
we can build an entire React app
with just functional components with the help of hooks.
Therefore, let's dive right in
and let's learn about our first hook,
the most important hook probably.