Here is an example application,
of course you find it attached.
And as you see, this application has in the end
just two counters, one counter counting upwards,
one counter counting backwards
and of course that's not a fancy application.
We're going to see another example later in this module
but this application allows me to explore custom hooks
together with you, show you
why we might wanna build custom hooks
and how we built custom hooks.
So here's the code for it is application,
which again, you'll find attached
and in here, we in the end just got free components,
the backward counter and the forwards counter,
the card component which is just a rapper component
providing some styling and then app JS,
I'm using the forward and the backward
counter components and these components
do just what their name implies.
The forward counter uses, useState and useEffect
to manage a state and to create an interval
which simply starts counting up
and which then sets a new counter state every second,
every 1000 milliseconds.
And in the backward counter, I'm doing the exact same thing
but here I'm subtracting from the counter
but other than that, it's the same logic.
So, therefore it is fair to say
that these two components are fairly similar.
Now, of course, we might be able to create one component
in state and then use props to configure it differently
but it would also be realistic that in real applications
you have different components, which to a certain extent
might do related tasks.
And it is fair to say that we therefore definitely
have some code duplication in the forward
and the back counter.
If we leave that small detail of subtracting or adding
to the counter aside, it's exactly the same code in the end.
And whenever you have code duplication in programming,
you typically wanna take that code and refactor it
and create a function which holds the shared code.
And that's exactly what we're going to do with custom hooks
because the problem we face here
is that the code which we want to reuse
uses react hook like useState
and useEffect, and it updates the state
by calling the state updating function
and as you learned with the rules of hooks,
you are not allowed to use these react hooks
in any random function.
You must only use them in react component functions
or custom hooks.
So, if we wanna outsource that logic
into a separate function,
we need to build such a custom hook
and that's exactly what we're going to do here.
So how do we build a custom hook then?
Well, typically just as with components,
we store every hook in a standalone file.
So I will start by creating a new hooks folder
side-by-side to the components folder
and in there, I will add the use-dash counter js file.
Now, the file name is totally up to you.
You don't have to name it, use counter.
I do name it like this though
because there is a clear rule
which we have to follow
when it comes to the function name
inside of that file
because we are going to create a function here,
either as a concept, which stores a function
or with the function keyword
I'll go for the constant approach, but both would work
and that function which you do create
has to start with a use in its name.
That is a must do.
That is a hard rule which you have to follow.
It will be a normal function in the end
but the use at their beginning
signals to react that it will be a custom hook
and it gives the reacts to guarantee
that you will use stat function by respecting
these rules of hooks so that you will use
this custom hook function just as you use to build in hooks.
And that is a guarantee react needs
because otherwise if you start using react hooks
in your custom hook and you would use your custom hook
in a wrong, in a forbidden place,
you would implicitly also use to build in hooks
in a wrong place.
And that's why we started with us here
because react can look out for that
and actually this project set up will give you a warning
if you have a function starting with use
and you then start violating some of these rules of hooks.
That's why this is a must do.
Start with use is in the functioning name and thereafter
you can name it however you want,
I will name it, usecounter
and then store a regular function in it,
and because of that function name,
I also named the file like this,
but again for the file name, there is no specific rule,
you could name it however you want.
Now of course, ultimately the goal is to use this function
in another file, so therefore I will export
this function here and then inside of this function,
we can start adding that logic which we want to reuse
and in our case, if we started with the forward counter,
in the end we can just copy that code here
from the forward counter that code, where we use
use state and use effect, not the code
where we return JSX, just the Abra code.
Copy that and add it inside of that used counter function.
Now, since we are using useState and useEffect now,
we need to import these things from react
because you always need to import what you use.
So here we imported useState and useEffect like this.
Now we got this logic in this custom hook function
but of course in the end, we still wanna utilize it
in our forward counter
and later also in the backward counter.
How can we do that?