Now because things get easier with React,
and because we can build those
rich user interfaces with React and JavaScript,
when working with React we often build
so-called Single Page Applications.
Because whilst we can use React
to control parts of an HTML page,
let's say some interactive sidebar,
and therefore we add a widget, you could say
to a page where only a part of
the page is controlled with React.
It is more common to control
the entire page with React.
Which means that we use React
for everything we see on the screen
and even for switching pages.
So when we click on a link
and we load a new page
as I did with Netflix when I clicked on my list
it looks to the user as if we switched a page
but we actually don't request
a new HTML file from some server.
Instead we just used JavaScript through React.js
to change what's visible on the screen.
And that often leads to a smoother UI
and a better user experience.
As you see it at the example of Netflix.
It's built with React
and there we never request a second HTML page.
Hence it's a Single Page Application
where after the initial request
to decide React takes over
and controls what we see on the screen.