So let's now convert this Users component
to a class-based component.
For this, we again should import something from react.
Let me restructure these imports.
We should import Component from react
because we now build our users component
by creating a class named Users which extends Component.
That's what I explained in the last lecture
and that's how you always build your class-based components.
In there we can now add a render method
and in that render method we return to jsx code
that should be rendered.
So, I'll copy this return statement
and bring it into my render method.
Now we learned that we can access props with these props
but here I'm not working with props
instead, I'm relying on state
and I am pointing at a function
that should be executed when the button is clicked.
Now let's start by adding that function.
In class-based components,
you now don't add a function inside of the render method
though that would technically be possible
but it wouldn't behave correctly.
But instead, since this is a class,
you group together functionality
by grouping it all in that class.
So you would simply add a method
named toggleUsersHandler like this.
There are also alternative ways
of writing a method in classes
but this is the most default and standard way
of defining a method.
Now we have the method, but we don't have the state.
And managing state worked totally different
in the past with class-based components.
With react16.8 hooks were introduced
and we could use to UseState hook
to manage state and functional components.
And it is very simple to manage state then.
Prior to 16.8 class-based components
were the only kind of component that could manage state.
So you always had to write class-based components
when you needed state.
And there you basically needed to do two things,
initialize and define your state,
like we're doing it with UseState when we first call it
and then updated when needed,
like we're doing it here in the toggleUsersHandler.
Now to define state and class-based components,
you would use the constructor.
The constructor function is automatically called
whenever this clause is instantiated
which happens when react encounters,
your class being used as a component.
And then in the constructor, you can do initialization work
like initializing state.
And this would be done by accessing this.state
and setting it equal to an object.
And this is super crucial now.
With class-based components, your state always important,
always is an object.
With functional components, your state can be anything.
It can be just a Boolean, just a string, just a number
but it can also be an object, but it's flexible
it can be anything.
With class-based components, that's not the case.
Here your state always is an object
because with class-based components,
you always group all the state's license and pieces
you might need in a component into one state object.
With functional components
instead if you have multiple state pieces,
you could use multiple UseState calls.
You could also create just one state object
and group it together there
but that is optional with functional components.
And I do talk about that in the state course section.
With class-based components, this is not optional
there you have to group all the state
that makes up a component into one object.
No matter if these state pieces are closely related or not.
So here we would then have our showUsers state
and set this to true initially let's say.
And if we had moreState
then we would simply add this as a extra property.
You can of course also have nestedState,
you could have a nestedObject.
You can have a eraseState that all works
but you have one state object which groups it all together.
Then if you wanna change your state
like in toggleUsersHandler,
you don't do this by accessing this state
and changing it like this, that's not how you do it.
Instead, you call a special method, setState, this.setState,
and this method on this class
is of course also provided by the component class
we are inheriting from.
This setState then also always takes an object.
And this object now contains the new state, you wanna set,
but very important, it won't override the old state
but instead react will behind the scenes
merge the object you're passing here
with your existing state.
So if I had another state here, which I don't need here
if I had that and I then would set showUsers to false,
showUsers would be set to false
but the old state would be capped.
The other state would be capped
because react merges this update with the existing state
it doesn't override the state.
And that's different with useState,
here when you call the state updating function
you always override the old state
with whatever you pass to the updating function,
unless it is a function in which case
we executes that to derive the new state.
But you override the old state,
it's not merged automatically by react
if you would want merging
because you are managing some state object,
you would have to write the logic for this on your own.
With class-based components and setState that's different,
there react mergers this for you.
Now here, of course I don't always wanna set this to false,
I wanna set it to the opposite of what it was before
and therefore here setState
just like the state updating function from useState
also supports such a updating function.
So here we can also pass a function to setState
alternatively to the object with the new state.
And we should do that
if our new state depends on the previous state.
Nonetheless, it's not enough
to just return a new state value like this,
because here I would be returning something invalid
because our state is an object.
Instead here, we have to change this a little bit
and return a new object
just as you have to pass our object to set state
if you use that function form
you have to return an object.
And there, I said showUsers to curState.showUsers
and invert that.
And again, what we return here will be merged
with the old state.
So this second state piece here will not be lost.
And that's how we update state.
Now to use it, we go down to the render method
where I need my state
and here we can now access this.state.showUsers
to access this state object
and then the showUsers property,
which we set up here and which we manage and update here.
And we do it as in all the places where we need that state.
Now of course, I also wanted to arrive to users list,
therefore I'll grab this constant here
and add to this to my render method
because we still can of course define help
or consents like this in the render method,
that all is valid and works.
One thing, one last thing is missing though
and that's this method here.
I added the toggleUserHandler method,
but you don't call it by using it like this.
Instead, it's a method off this clause here
and therefore we need to point at this toggleUserHandler
to point at this method part of this class.
But even that wouldn't work
due to how this works in JavaScript.
And that has nothing to do with react
that this keyword can simply be tricky in JavaScript.
Attached you find a resource
which allows you to learn more about this.
What you need to do in the end is you need to make sure
that this keyword inside of your method
refers to the surrounding class
and it wouldn't by default,
when your method is called upon any event like to click.
So to fix this, we can for example use bind and bind this
which simply means that this keyword
inside of this method here
is now set to have the same context or the same value
as this keyword when this code is evaluated
and here that this keyword will refer to this class.
Again, this is just related to how JavaScript works.
It is not required in the functional component world
because there we just define a function
right before we point at it.
There we don't use that this keyword at all
because we're not working inside of a class.
With that, we can again remove
the functional component or a commented out
and then save everything.
And now if I reload, we get an error,
Must call super constructor in derived class,
that is indeed true.
When you add the constructor to your class
and you extend another class, you need to call super
which calls the constructer of the super class
so if the class were inheriting from.
And with that, if we reload this works
and it works as before now with class components only.
So as you can tell,
it's simply a different way of writing your components.
Of course, now we can also get rid of the useState import
because we're not using it anymore
and as mentioned before already,
you also can't use it in your class based components.
None of the react hooks can be used there.