So we have a pretty much logical error here
in our code.
We have the problem that we have the hard coded ID
and we already learned
how we can find and fix this error.
Now let's say we didn't use any of the other two approaches.
We overlooked that warning
and we don't know why it's behaving incorrectly.
In such cases,
if you can't find the error otherwise
or if you just prefer this approach maybe,
you can go to the sources tab here
in the browser developer tools
and there you find in the end the source files
that are being used on this webpage right now.
And that includes your JavaScript code.
And the cool thing is
that this React development process,
this NPM start script here,
which runs in the end
is set up such that it,
of course pushes code to the browser
that is executable by the browser.
But it also gives the browser extra information
which the browser developer tools are able to pick up
to allow us to actually debug our code
in the raw form we wrote it in.
so that we are able to debug with that code
we're writing in these files,
even though that technically isn't the code
that's executed by the browser.
So this React development process,
gives the browser a bridge,
between the code that runs in the browser
and the code we wrote,
and we can access this code here
in the sources tab,
by going to that User's folder
which you should see.
Users, your username
and then a source folder.
And in there you find your React files.
The files we actually also have here in our IDE.
Now, if you don't find it here,
you can also check out that Webpack folder
and there you might also find a source folder
with your source files.
You can look around because sometimes it's located
in a different node in a different sub folder
but somewhere here in the sources tab,
in this tree of files and folders
you should find your original source code.
And then you could always dive
into the different parts that you wanna analyze.
You could go into the CourseGoalItem
and there, for example, the deleteHandler
and simply add a break point by clicking
onto the line number where you wanna add it.
In this case, that deleteHandler function
which is triggered when we click on the list item
because that's where the deletion process starts.
So maybe that is where we wanna pause the code
and then step through the code step by step
so that we can find the problem.
Once you add such a break point
if you then execute that action,
that triggers that code part
where the break point is placed.
Code execution stops once it reaches that break point line.
So you see that here,
it's paused in a debugger
and that line is now highlighted in blue here
and you've got surrounding information
in those boxes at the bottom.
For example, you see variables
which are currently available.
You see the Call Stack and so on.
And now you can do something cool.
You can step through your code step by step.
And for example, here we call the onDelete method
on the props object, for example.
So to have a look at what's going on there
we can use this Step into next function call button.
If you click that we're in the deleteItemHandler
which is the function that was triggered
because of that props concept.
And here we see that setCourseGoals function
which is being called
and you can also hover over variables here
to see the values that are currently stored in them.
And for example, if I hover over goalId here
I see that it is goal1.
Now, this might or might not help me here,
but I can see that I have goal1 here
when I clicked on this goal
which was actually the second goal I added.
Now we can use the Step over next function call button here
to finish that setCourseGoals function call.
So now with that,
the deleteItemHandler basically finished
and information we got is that
we have the goalId goal1
for that goal we deleted
which as we of course know,
is the wrong goal to delete.
So now we could resume script execution
because we're done with this debugging cycle
and simply try this again
and click on the next goal.
And dive into the next function call here
and see that here we have the same goalId as before.
So now this should be a point where we see,
wait a second,
if we have to same ID on two different goals
on which I clicked here
that seems to be the problem
why the wrong goal was deleted.
So that's maybe with a point
where we resume script execution
and then dive back into the code
where we actually add goals
because that is where we set our IDs.
And just by looking at that code,
we of course should be able to see
why we have goal1 for every goal.
So that's how we can use the break points
to step for our codes step by step
and even inspect values
which are stored in variables and so on
to find out why something behaves the way it does behave.
So break points,
and you can always clear them by clicking on them again.
Break points are another useful tool
for analyzing your code for understanding it
and for finding and fixing errors like that.
And with that, I'll revert this
to Math.random.toString
which of course then is an ID we can use
without getting that warning.
Now, if I try this again,
you see I don't get to the warning.
If I now add multiple goals,
you see if I click on the first goal,
I delete the first goal.
So this now works,
and that's another important set of tools.
The debugging tools you've got natively in your browser
Here I showed it in the Chrome browser
but you also have similar tools in Firefox or Safari.