Well, you are going to use a custom hook
just as you use to build in hooks.
You are just calling it
like a function because it is just a function.
So therefore we wanna import use counter here
in the forward counter component, import use counter
from going up one level diving into the hooks folder
use counter.
And in the forward counter
we can then just call use counter.
Now that alone will not do everything we need to do
but it is a start.
Now we are calling this custom hook function.
So when this gets called,
obviously, all that code will execute.
So that state will be registered
and that effect will be fired.
Now, if you call a custom hook in one of your components
and that component, for example of registers a state
or an effect as we do it here then this state and effect
will be tied to the component
in which you use your custom hook.
So if I call use counter in the forward counter component
the state created here, in use counter
will be tied to this forward counter.
If we use a custom hook in multiple components
every component will receive its own state.
So just because we use a custom hook does not mean
that we share state or effects across components.
Instead for every component
the custom hook is executed again.
And every component instance then receives its own state.
So it's just a logic which has shared
not the concrete state.
So therefore, in this case, since I call use counter
in the forward counter, this state is set up
for the forward counter and the this effect is set up
and fired for the forward counter component.
But of course now inside of the forward counter
I need access to the counter state, which is managed
by the custom hook, because I wanna output it here.
And how can we do that?
How can we make that happen?
Well, just as we do it with the built in hooks.
For use state this built in react hook
this also does something behind the scenes
and it also creates and manage this state.
And then it does one important thing.
It returns an array, which we are de-structuring here.
Custom hooks are just functions and they afford
they can return things.
So here in the case of use counter to make
that counter state available in the components that do use
this custom hook, we can simply return it.
We can simply return counter.
You can return whatever you wanna return
in your custom hooks.
That could be an array or an object or a number
or in this case implicitly a number
because counter will hold a number.
So now I'm returning this counter state here.
So this state, which is managed or which is set up by
that custom hook, I'm returning it here.
And therefore, in the forward counter component
where I call use counter
I can of course use that returned value.
And here I can set up my counter constant
set it equal to calling used counter
since use counter returns to counter.
I can store it in a constant of this component.
And now we can get rid of all that old code in here
and slim down this component, like this, get rid
of the imports because we're not directly using use state
or a use effect in this file anymore.
And now we got this slim component.
And if we now save that, you will see
that if I reload here, this counter this forward counter
still works as before, but now with a custom hook.
And that is how we build custom hooks and why we do it.
And when it comes to the how, the most important thing
really is just the naming, you have to start with use
and then you can use stateful logic in there.
You can use upper react hooks in there
and that allows you to share this logic across components.
And speaking off that, let's now make sure
that we can use this custom hook
also in the backward counter component.