Now because things get easier with React,
and because we can build those rich user interfaces
with React and JavaScript, when working with React,
we often build so-called signal page applications.
Because whilst we can use React
to control parts of a HTML page,
let's say some interactive sidebar,
and therefore we add a widget, you could say,
to a page where only a part of the page
is controlled with React,
it is more common to control the entire page with React,
which means that we use React
for everything we see on the screen,
and even for switching pages.
So when we click on a link and we load a new page,
as I did with Netflix when I clicked on my list,
it looks to the user as if we switched the page,
but actually don't request a new HTML file from some server,
instead, we just use the JavaScript through React.js
to change what's visible on the screen.
And that often leads to a smoother UI
and a better user experience,
as you see it at the example of Netflix.
It's built with React,
and there we never request a second HTML page,
hence it's a single page application
where after the initial request to the side,
React takes over and controls what we see on the screen.
Now throughout this course,
we are going to learn React in depth,
and we're going to start with this basic dummy demo here
to learn about some core concepts.
And then later throughout the course,
we're going to build this Meetup project,
this mini project here,
where we see more React features in action
and where we can practice all those basics.
And where then, at the end, really understand
how React works, and which features it brings.