Being able to set styles
and classes dynamically is super important.
And you now learned how you can achieve this in react code.
Now let's move to something else
and that would be the styling itself.
Currently we're using just CSS for that regular CSS files
with regular selectors, mostly class selectors
but also sometimes combined with tag selectors for example.
We're importing these files into our component files,
but as I emphasized multiple times,
this does not result in those styles
being scoped to this component only.
So that means that if we had any other element
anywhere else in a dorm
that had a form controlled CSS class on it,
this style for example, would target it and would affect it.
So it's not like we only care
about foreign control elements in this component, no,
every element on the entire page is affected
because by default, those styles are not scoped.
Now that is not necessarily a problem.
You can of course be careful about your selectors.
You can use class selectors or ID selectors here,
it is regular CSS after all, you can use any selector
and you can ensure that the IDs
and the classes you are selecting
are only used in the places
where you want to apply the styling.
But of course, especially in larger projects,
potentially with a lot of developers working on the code,
it could happen that a name is used twice.
That form control, for example,
is used in different parts of the application
and therefore unfortunately
styles spill over to our components
and you might want to avoid this.
And there are various ways of avoiding this
and I will show you
the two most popular approaches therefore.
Approach number one is to use a package
called styled components.
And you can just search for style components
to find their official webpage.
Now, on this page you can learn all about style components
here I will only introduce you to the package
if you wanna use it you can dive way deeper into it
with those docks
but I will give you a thorough introduction no worries.
Style components is a package that helps you build
guess what, components which have certain styles
attached to them
where the styles really only affect the components
to which they were attached and not any other components.
Now to get started,
we need to install that package.
And here you see the command you need to run for that.
Now, if you've never installed packages before,
keep in mind that our project here
already has a couple of packages on which it depends.
For example, react.
And we're just adding one more package here.
For that you should quit your development server
with Ctrl + C
and run npm_install--save styled-components
inside of this project folder.
Notice we'll download this package
and store it in a node modules folder,
and thereafter you'll be able to use it in this project.
So let's wait for this to finish.
Yep, here it is.
And with this finished
you can restart the server with NPM start.
So now how do we use this package?
Of course you can learn all about it on the official page
but I will simply introduce you to it step by step.
Now let's pick a place where we do wanna use it
and let's say we want to style our button.
We actually already have a button component
but we really only created this button component
if we're honest
because we wanted to have some default styling for a button.
Nothing wrong with this approach,
but here we could also use the stalled components package
to achieve this in a bit of an easier way.
Now, how would we do this?
We could rebuild our button here
by creating a new const Button
and now what we store in there is not a functional component
but instead we now import styled from 'styled-components.'
This import is now available
since you installed the package.
We can get rid of the button CSS import,
and instead now we use styled.button
and then we add two back ticks like this.
Now that certainly is a super weird syntax
and chances are, you haven't seen that before.
This is called attacked template, literal.
It's a default JavaScript feature,
it's not specific to this package, not specific to react
you could use it in any JavaScript project.
And now what does this do?
Well, button is simply a method on this styled object.
Styled is an object we're importing from style components
and there we can access the button method.
It's just a special kind of method you could say.
Instead of being a method,
which you call like this with parentheses,
you add these strange back ticks after it.
And again, that's just a default JavaScript syntax
which is supported by JavaScript.
In the end this will be executed
as a method behind the scenes
and what you pass in here
will be passed into this method just in a special way.
If you wanna learn more
about this tact template literal syntax,
you find a link attached where you can learn more.
Here, I don't wanna waste your time,
since we won't need to know the internals here to proceed.
For the moment we just need to know
that what we pass between these two back ticks
will kind of end up in that button method.
And this button method, and that's the interesting part,
will return a new button component.
Actually, that styled package
has methods for all HTML elements.
It has p method for a paragraph h1, h2 and so on
for the h1, h2 tags,
div to create a div and so on.
It's all there and here we need the button.
So this overall expression will return a button
but a button with the styles
we provide between these two back ticks.
The cool thing about the back tick Syntax is,
that you can write a multiline string like this,
so you can split this across multiple lines
without any extra Syntax.
And now we can just copy all the button styles here
and add them in here.
We'll need to tweak them, but that is something we can do.
Now, what do we need to do to make this work in the end?
This will return a button
and this button won't have a class of button
because we have no place
where we would set up this class name.
So instead, the styles will pass
between the opening and closing back tick
will directly effect this button.
You therefore get rid of any selectors like this
and instead just paste in your styles, just like that.
And they will be added to the button element
which is returned by this method call
which extends toward into this Button constant.
Now for a pseudo selectors, you can use the ampersand symbol
that's supported by that styled component package.
This tells the package that you wanna have a special case
special pseudo selector in this case here
for this component, which is created here.
So in this case, we're saying,
"Hey, when this button here has focus,
please apply to style."
We can do the same here for hover
and :hover and, :active.
And this should now give us a button which has these styles.
Now the button which is returned all to by default
applies all the props
you might be passing to your own button component
which we're exporting here in the end.
So we can still add on click prop, we can still set the type
that will all be forwarded by the style components package,
to that core built in button,
which we previously wrapped or used ourselves
which is now used internally by this button method.
We can now get rid of the react import up there
because we're not dealing with JSX in this file anymore.
And if we now save this, we should see that our application
looks and works exactly as it did before.
So this still works, but this is now our style button.
Now we can tell that there's something different
if we inspect it in the developer tools.
Of course it's a regular button,
that's what this button method here in the end returns.
But you see on that, there is a very strange class
two strange classes to be precise.
And these are class names we certainly didn't set up.
These are class names dynamically generated
by the styled components package.
Because what this package does in the end
is it looks at the styles we set up here
and then it wraps these styles into generated class names
where it guarantees that every class name is unique
so that it can spill over to other components of the app.
And it will then add these classes as global CSS.
But now since we have unique class names
for every styled component, the style set up here
will never be able to affect
the number of component in the app
because these unique class names
are really well unique per style component.
So that's how the styling is applied here
and that's how styled components work.
Now, of course we could also use stall components
when we want to set up something dynamic.