Now we know how
we can generally build class-based components
and how we can manage state and work with events, steer.
But what about side effects?
As I mentioned, you can't use these react hooks
in class-based components, so you can't use use effect
but class-based components have a concept
called the component life cycle.
And of course, every component technically has a life cycle.
It, for example, is rendered to the DOM
or remove from the DOM, but there are specific methods
you can add two class-based components to run code
at different points in that life cycle.
And the first, most important life cycle method you can add
to class-based components,
is to componentDidMount() method
like render() that's a built in method,
which you can use as soon
as you extend the built in component
which you import from React.
And then you can add this method and React.
We'll call it for you when the component was just mounted
but more on that in a second.
Other live cycle
methods you can add would be
componentDidUpdate() and componentWillUnmount().
There are a couple of other less important
to lifecycle methods, which will not take a closer look
at here because these free lifecycle methods
are by far the most important and common ones.
Now, as I said, componentDidMount()
is called when a component is mounted.
So when it was evaluated and now rendered to the DOM.
It's basically the equivalent to using use EFFECT like this.
You have your EFFECT function
which I left out here with the free dots.
And then you have the array of dependencies
and every EFFECT function is executed when
the component first is mounted.
But if you have no dependencies
if you have an empty dependencies array
the EFFECT function is only executed in that case.
So adding use of fact with an empty dependency
array is basically your equivalent to componentDidMount().
And we're going to See componentDidMount()
in action in just a second.
You'll also have componentDidUpdate().
This is called once a component was updated.
So when something changed when your state changed
and the component was re-evaluated and re-rendered
this is basically your equivalent to use effect
with some dependencies, whenever the dependencies change,
the use EFFECT function re-executes
and the dependencies are re-evaluated
when the component is re-evaluated
and was rendered again.
Because you'll learn
that the effects are generally re-executed whenever
a component re-rendered, if dependencies changed.
So that's why this is basically your equivalent to
componentDidDpdate().
Now componentWillUnmount is called right
before the component is removed from the DOM,
and here the equivalent is basically the clean up function
from use EFFECT that cleanup function is called right
before the EFFECT function is executed again
and also always again, when the component
is about to be removed from the DOM.
Now again, let's take a closer look at that in action here.
And for this, I altered the project slightly,
attached you find the UserFinder component,
which you can add to your components.
And now we need to go to the users component
and dare get rid of the dummy users here.
And instead here, where we used the dummy users
refer to this props users, because users are now passed in
through props into this users component.
And now we just need to go
to the App component and use the UserFinder component
and import user finder from components UserFinder.
Instead of users.
also add the UserFinder. Module.CSS file,
which you also find attached.
And if you added all of that
and you saved as you should see an application that looks
like this, and here, if you type you now also
filter this list down there with every keystroke.
It's a very simple filter logic, which I added here
into UserFinder, and the UserFinder component
is a functional component using multiple state slices
and use EFFECT to manage the users
and to then filter the users
and pass the filtered users to the users component.
Now let's transform this component
to a class-based component to get an idea
on how these class-based components deal with side effects.