So automated testing is a nice feature.
How does it work?
As I mentioned, attached to the previous lecture
you found this starting project
which is a standard react project,
which I did create with create react app.
Now I didn't really change the component code too much.
I just cleaned up the index JS file a little bit
and I did not delete the app test JS file,
which we did not use up to this point in the course,
and the setup test JS file
because we will need those files now.
Now set up tests JS, as the name implies,
just does some setup work
and we don't need to do anything else in this file.
But the app test JS file is quite interesting.
This is a file that contains some testing code
and it is there out of the box.
Later in this module
we will also write our own tests from scratch.
This is a file which is there to test this app component
because the convention is to name your testing files
like your component files,
just with the word test in the file name.
So dot test dot JS as an extension to be precise.
And in this app test JS file.
We have this test function
which we execute here, which takes two arguments.
The first argument is a description of the test.
This is up to you.
It helps you identify this test in the testing output
which we'll see in a couple of minutes.
And it's especially helpful
if you have an app with more than one test, of course.
The second argument is a function
an anonymous function, which is the point here
which contains the actual test and code.
So that's the code which will be executed
once we run our test.
And in there, we do a couple of things
which we don't fully understand yet
but we will soon understand it.
We rendered the app component in the end with help
of that render function imported from the testing library.
So from that third party package
then we get hold of some element on that virtual screen.
So to say, so in that simulated browser.
So to say, into which this app is rendered,
we get hold of some element in there
and we identify an element
by the text that is rendered inside of it.
Here we are looking for the text,
learn react in a case insensitive way.
This is our regular expression in case you're wondering.
And then we just check
if that element actually is in the document.
So if it exists in the document. And this test will fail
if this element is not found and it will succeed
if it is found.
And in app JS, we do have
this, content here
and we do have this
learn react text in this anchor tag.
And so if we look
for an element with a text of learn react case insensitive,
so casing does not matter, then this test should succeed
because such an element clearly exist here.
But that's all nice and theory.
How do we run this test?
For this, we got a script
just as we got a script for running the development server.
We run the development server.
So that we as a human can preview
our app and interact with it.
We run the automated tests to see if those work and for that
in packaged dot Json, we have this test script here
and we can run this test script from inside the terminal.
And here I'm using the terminal integrated
into visual studio code by running NPM test.
So just as NPM start, started the development server
NPM tests, will run our automated tests.
And here, if I now hit enter
this will start up the testing.
And actually, it does not run the tests right now.
Instead, we now have to press 8
to run all the tests it finds
and it will automatically look
for files that end with dot test dot JS
and then run all the tests that are defined
in there with that test function.
So in this case, this one test, which we have.
So if I now run, 8 here.
If I press 8, you see it executed my tests.
And then we get this test output here.
We see that it ran one test in total.
And that one test passed.
I'll come back to the difference between
tests suites, and tests.
A little bit later
here we see that it ran one test overall,
and that test passed.
And here we then see all the tests also,
all the tests that passed
in this case with the green check mark next to it.
And here we see that description text again
which we entered here.
So that is what helps us identify which test succeeded
or failed.
And for example, if I now go
to app JS here
and I remove this text, learn react
and I instead say, learn more.
You see if I save us the tests automatically rerun
because by default,
it watches your files and reruns the tests.
Whenever you save changes.
And now you see that we get a failed test here.
And if I scroll up, we get more information.
We see that this test failed
we see that by that red cross here.
And we also get an explanation of why it failed.
Unable to find an element with the text, learn react.
Then we get an output off the actual content
which had rendered where it tried to find that text
and where it failed to do so.
Of course, that is the content of app JS here.
Then we see the testing code
and the line that failed in this case get by text.
That's the line that failed.
And that is why desk test failed.
And now as a developer, we could either adjust our test.
If we want to have learned more here
or go back to learn react
to make sure that this test passes again.
And of course that's a rather dumb example.
It's just a basic example.
But that's the idea behind testing and how testing works.
Now, of course, we can always quit this testing mode
by hitting control C here
and then our files will not be watched anymore.
And we need to restart testing
with NPM test, if we want to do that.
So these are the basics.
Now let's dive a bit deeper.