We can make React Memo work for prop values
that are objects as well.
We just need to tweak the way we create
and store those objects a little bit.
There is an extra hook provided by React
that helps us with that.
And that is the Use Callback Hook.
Use Callback is a hook that allows us
to basically store a function across component executions.
So it allows us to tell React that we wanna save a function
and that this function should not be recreated
with every execution.
With that one in the same function object is stored
so one in the same place in memory
and therefore the comparison does work.
Because just to make this clear again as well,
if you have object one,
like this and you have object two, like this,
which looks similar you'll learn
that they aren't similar in JavaScript.
If you however, said object two equal to object one
you point at the exact same place in memory
and therefore now object one will be equal to object two.
And that's in the end what Use Callback does for us,
it will save a function of our choice
basically somewhere in React's internal storage
and we'll always reuse that same function object
then when this component function executes.
And using it is simple.
We just wrapped the function we wanna save with it.
So here we use the Use Callback Hook
and pass our function as a first argument to use callback
and Use Callback then returns that stored function
and when the app function reruns Use Callback will look for
that stored function which React stored for us
and reuse that same function object.
So if we know that this function should never change,
we can use Use Callback to store it.
Now you see I got some yellow squiggly lines here though
which tells me that I did probably forget to pass
an array of dependencies.
Use Callback like Use Effect actually wants
a second argument and it wants it even more so
than Use Effect and just like for Use Effect
the second argument should be an array.
An array of dependencies off this Use Callback call.
And the dependencies here are the same as they are
for Use Effect.
Anything you use in your function
which is coming from the surrounding component
so any state or props or context should be specified here.
Now here we only have to state updating function
and we could add this as a dependency but we don't have to
because as mentioned early in the course React guarantees us
actually with help of Use Callback probably
that this will never change so that this will always
be the same function object.
Hence this is an exception which we don't have to add.
And then in this simple callback we'd have nothing else.
Keep in mind that this code here is just a function
we pass to set show paragraph.
So that is totally contained inside
of our callback function.
So therefore here we have an empty array of dependencies
which basically tells React that this callback function
this function here which we wanna store it
in toggle paragraph handler ultimately will never change
that it has no dependencies
and the data for always the same function object
should be reused when the app component rerenders.
Hence now if I saved that, and I reload,
we see button running once but then you never see it again
because now React Memo is able to do its job
because we ensure that all the prop values
we pass in are a comparable in this case
because this toggle paragraph handler function object
is guaranteed to always be the exact same object
in memory because of Use Callback.