Now as part of this first course section
I also wanna give you an overview
of what you can expect from this course
and which topics will be covered.
Now, of course,
you maybe already had a look at the course curriculum
and you absolutely should take a brief look at least
because this is a huge course
and I can't pack all the contents that's in the course
into this one lecture here,
I don't wanna turn this into a 20 minute lecture
and in addition,
I kept this course updated in the past
and i kept adding new content from time to time,
and i do plan to do that in the future.
So the, curriculum you see on the course page
is always up to date.
The content here in this video is just a summary
of the most important features.
There's way more in the course,
so definitely check out that full curriculum in addition.
Now, with that out of the way,
this course is organized into three main categories
or course sections you could say.
And the first category of sections,
is about the basics,
the foundation of React.
These will be sections
that cover core features
which React offers to you,
which you have to know no matter
which React App you're building.
Now, the second category of course sections,
then is about more advanced concepts.
So this course does not stop after the basics.
Instead, we are going to dive
into a lot of advanced concepts as well.
These are the concepts which you need for real apps
which you really wanna push to production I would say.
These are concepts which you don't need in every app
but realistically you will need them in a lot of apps
and that's why we're also going to dive
into such advanced concepts in depth
in this course.
Now the last kind of course, sections and content
which you'll find in this course
will be sections that contain the summaries
or refreshers on certain concepts
ensuring that we're all on the same page
and that you got a single place to go to,
well, summarize the core concepts you learned about.
But let's now take a closer look at
which kind of content you can expect in detail
for these different categories of content.
We will, of course start with the key basics
that you have to know.
And when you'll learn, React,
those core basics will be about components,
you will learn that react is all about components
and how you can build your own components
and how you can combine them
and how you can build user interfaces
with this component approach React takes.
You will also learn how to work with events
and data, so how you can listen to button clicks
and then change something on the screen,
and you will learn about props and state,
which probably doesn't tell you anything right now
but which are key React concepts
which I am going to introduce in great detail
in this course.
Now, since this course is about
building user interfaces in the end
of course you're also going to learn,
how you can style your react apps and components,
how you can make sure that your user interfaces,
which you build with React look the way
you want them to look.
And I'm also going to introduce you to
another key feature called React Hooks.
You will learn what exactly that is,
and you will learn that it is one of
the most important concepts of modern React
and therefore, of course it's also covered
in great detail In this course.
Now, these four boxes on this slide here
are not four course sections.
These concepts, which are listed here
in this basics category
are indeed taught through a lot more course sections.
This is just a summary of the content you can expect.
And if you simply continue with the next lectures
and sections, you are going to learn
these key concepts step by step.
Because of course I ordered all the course content
and all the course lectures,
such that you are learning
about all those important React features step-by-step
so that everything builds up on each other.
Now, as I mentioned, we don't stop after those basics.
Instead we'll directly move from basics to more
advanced concepts.
And therefore, this course also
contains sections about working with side effects
and Refs and what Refs are
and more React hooks.
And if this all sounds very cryptic right now
that's no problem
This is just an overview,
Some terms you might've heard about before,
which are also covered by this course,
you will learn what these concepts are about
and how they work throughout this course of course.
Now we are also going to explore app wide state management
with Reacts context API and Redux.
React Redux is a third party library,
one of the most important React, third party libraries
and we're going to cover it in detail in multiple sections
in this course.
And you are also going to learn how you can handle
user input with forms,
how you can send HTTP requests
behind the scenes to store data
in a database or fetch data from there,
And you're going to learn how to build your own custom Hooks
and what that actually is.
You're also going to learn how to implement routing
and what routing is in detail,
how you can build a page that gives the user the illusion
of having multiple pages, even though
it's a single page app as you learned.
you're going to learn how to deploy your React App,
and we're for example, also going to dive
into another framework called Next.js
which builds up on React.js,
which will make building production-ready
React Apps even easier.
And that will be another a huge module on Next.js
which is also included in this course
a little bit later in this course
since that will already be quite advanced then.
And there is more,
as i said, this is not exhaustive,
have a look at their full course curriculum
to see all the content
this is just the general structure of this course
and what you can expect from it.
Now, as I mentioned, there also are some summary
and refresher course sections,
and specifically there is
a JavaScript refresher course section,
that's the next course section after this one actually
which is 100% optional
but which you can take to ensure that we're all
on the same page regarding JavaScript,
because in that refresher section I'm going to
refresh some core modern JavaScript features
which we're going to use in this course as well.
And there will also be a React.js summary module
at the end of this course
about which I'll talk in greater detail
in the next course lecture,
because it turns out that for this course,
you actually have more than one possible way
of taking this course.
But again, I'll dive a bit deeper
into that in the next lecture.
Now, all that content in this course
will be explained in great detail
in theory, and web small demos and examples
but then we are also going to have a couple of bigger
more realistic course projects and examples
where you can practice what you learned
and where you see the different concepts come together
and where you see how a React app is built
by using all those React features.
Last but not least,
there also are plenty of challenges and exercises for you,
so that by the end of the course
you can really call yourself a React developer.