So, were are you successful?
Let's try this together now.
And for this in the source folder
next to the components folder, I will add a hooks folder.
This is just a convention, not something you have to do.
You can name it differently,
but I will follow this common convention
and then add a new file in there
which I will name use-http.js.
Again, this name is all is up to you
but since I will create a HTTP related custom hook in there,
I think this is a fitting name.
Now the hook function itself, I will call that useHttp
following this must use pattern
where your custom hook functions
must start with the word use
and I will export this custom hook here,
because of course I want to be able to use it
in other files.
Now, regarding the content of this function,
as I said, there will be more than one solution
and definitely feel free to share your alternatives
in the Q and A section if you want to.
I'm just showing you one possible approach
which I came up with.
And for that, let's have a look at the general logic
we wanna outsource.
In the end, it is the loading and the error state,
but then also the entire code where we send the request,
where we evaluate the response.
All of that should be outsourced.
Also this error handling here
where we then set the error state
that all should be part of the custom hook.
And therefore, I think it is reasonable
to go to the app component
and grab this entire fetch tasks function
and grab these states here
and in the end copy that into useHttp
into this custom hook function.
Now, here we can get rid of this tasks stayed here
because that's a bit too specific.
That's specific to the app component,
that's not something I would wanna put
in the useHttp custom hook itself
because this hook should not just be usable with tasks
but with any kind of data,
but I will definitely keep deloading
and error state in there.
Now, of course, to use useState in this file
as always we should import useState from react
and I will rename this function here
from fetchTasks to sendRequest
so that this has a more generic name
because we will also tweak the logic in there
to be more generic.
This custom hook
should not just be dealing with fetching data,
it should also not just be dealing
with fetching tasks specifically
because otherwise this hook would not be very reusable
it would be basically limited to one operation,
fetching tasks and that's not what I want here.
Instead, this hook should be able
to send any kind of requests to any kind of URL
and to do any kind of data transformation
but it should always manage the same state loading and error
and execute the same steps in the same order.
That's the actual reuse that we want here.
And to make that hook that flexible,
we, of course also will need some parameters here.
We will need some parameters to configure this hook.
And what should be configurable here?
Well, I would say the request logic
that needs to be configurable,
the URL, but also the methods, the body, the headers,
this all needs to be flexible.
So I do expect a requestConfig parameter here
and to disintern then should be an object let's say
which contains the URL
and any kind of other configuration that might be needed.
Now, therefore here, I will get rid of that URL
of the hard-coded string here in useHttp
and instead refer to requestConfig.url.
Since we will be calling that hook,
we then have to make sure that we pass in an object
which has a URL property, which holds the URL.
This hook should also be usable for post requests.
So therefore fetch should take a second argument here
and then there, I pass my object
where the method should be set to requestConfig.method,
where the headers should be set to requestConfig.headers
and where the body should be set
to JSON.stringify requestConfig.body.
So that we perform the JSON transformation
inside of the hook,
but the body itself has passed and from outside.
And again, this is really just my approach here.
You could make this more reusable,
you could expect different parameters, that's all up to you.
This is just one possible solution.
Now this request and how this request is being sent
is a bit more configurable.
Of course, I wanna then check the response like this
and I wanna transform the response like this,
I am assuming here that we're always working with JSON data,
so I will not make this hoax super generic
to work with any kind of data.
I will limit it to JSON data
because everything else would be far
beyond the scope of this course
and therefore I will keep these steps here
but the transformation and so on
and what we do with the data in the end
that of course is then again, highly specific
and not something that should be of this hook.
Instead, I would imagine that we get the data here
and then maybe we execute a function
which we get from the components that uses the hook
and pass that data to that function
so that the concrete transformation steps
can be defined in the component
where this hook is being used.
So therefore here instead of executing this code,
I do expect to get another parameter here
and that's the, let's say applyData function.
The name is up to you.
And then here, once we got the data, we simply call
applyData and pass the data to it.
So that in the hook we just hand the data off
to this applyData function
and the function itself and what happens in there
is provided by the component that uses the custom hook.
So that we have that reusability
and that reuse logic in the hook,
but the specific steps that should be taken with the data
in the components that uses the hook.
This is a split which makes sense to me.
Now, with that, we got to the loading and the errorState
and to sendRequest function in the custom hook,
but ultimately these are all things
which we will need in the components that uses the hook.
That component should to then have access
to the loading and the errorState
and it should have access to the send request function
so that it's the component which can trigger a send request.
Therefore at the end of the custom hook,
not at the end of sendRequest,
but at the end of the custom hook function,
I wanna return something to the component
where the custom hook is used.
And I mentioned before in this module
that your custom hooks of course can return anything,
numbers, strings, arrays, objects,
and here I will return an object.
And there I will add is loading property
which points at the isLoading state constant.
So this is the property name on the left side,
this is the value on the right side,
and that is loading state
which is managed for the component by this custom hook.
And I will also return an object with an error property,
which holds the errorState
just as the loading state and then the send request property
which points at sendRequest.
So add this function here.
And since I'm always using the same property names
as variable names on the right side,
we can also use a modern JavaScript shortcut here
where we write this like that that's the same result
or that will give us the same result
as to code I had a couple of seconds ago,
it's just a bit shorter
and it will be transformed to that longer syntax
under the hood by JavaScript.
So that's a shorthand we can use in modern JavaScript.
And with that, we got our custom hook
at least the first version of it.
Now let's see how we could use this custom hook.