[Maximilian} Now, before we add any logic
let's add some styling.
For this attached you find three files.
You'll find the Checkout.module.css file
which you should use to replace yours with it.
You will find a slightly updated Modal.module.css file
which you can use to replace yours and Checkout.js.
I also attached this file
because there I changed the Returned.js Xcode slightly.
For example, I wrapped the buttons in an extra div.
so you can either replace your Checkout.js file with mine
or at least replace your Returned.js Xcode with mine.
And once you did all of that
you should have a form that looks like this.
Now this is scrollable to make sure that we always
are able to squeeze everything onto this screen.
And of course, as always
you can tweak the styling and change this.
This is just some basic styling
which does the trick and looks okay I would say.
Now with that, if we, again, start from scratch
we can add something to the cart, click on order,
and then we get our form here.
And actually this should not be cut off.
So I will change height
to 19rem here on the form.
Slight oversight from my side.
But with that, we're good.
Now let's make sure
we do get the values the user entered.
We then validate them however we want.
And we then also either show an error message
if something's wrong with the entered data
or we submit it to a server.
Now let's start with getting the entered data.
For this, we got various options,
two main options to be precise.
We can either listen to every keystroke
gets the entered data and store it
in some state and update that state
with every keystroke or we get it once.
Once the overall form is submitted.
Now in the forms section, I showed you both
and I showed you various ways
of handling user input and validating it.
I showed all of that in great depth there.
Therefore here I'll keep it simpler.
I will not get the values with every keystroke.
Instead, I will use a reference
with useRef to get the values
only once the form is submitted.
So imports use ref from React
and then we can create a reference by calling useRef
and we'll get a reference for our name input, for example.
So our name input reference
which we get by calling useRef like this
and I'll do this four times to repeat it
for the street input,
for the postal code input, and for the city input.
And now we need to connect those refs
to the form elements here.
And for that, we can use the special ref prop, which we set
on the input elements to connect this first input
to the name input ref.
The second input here
to the street input ref.
The third input here to the postal code input ref
and the last input here to the city input ref.
Now these refs are connected and now we can use them
to read whatever the user entered
when the form is submitted.
Now for this, we've got our confirm handler here
and here we can then get the entered name
by reaching out to the name and put Ref.current.
It's always .current that gives you access
to the actual value stored
in the ref, in this case to the input element.
And since we now have access to an input element
we can access .value because every input element object
in JavaScript has a value property
that holds the actual value entered in that input element.
And we all repeated this or the entered straight
where we then use the streetInputRef to get the value.
And we repeated, whoops, that should be EnteredStreet.
We all the repeated for the enteredPostalCode
to use the postal code input ref.
And one last time we repeated
for the enteredCity to use the cityInputRef value.
And now we can validate this.