So let's now apply
what you learned about Redux to a React application.
Attached you find a simple starting React application
which will bring something like this onto the screen
once you run the DEV server
and you simply need to download it,
extracted it, run NPM install,
and thereafter NPM starts to bring up that DEV server.
And then in this application, in this simple demo project,
I prepared a couple of components
which we will use throughout this module.
And we're going to get started very simple
by transferring this counter example,
which we saw outside of React in the last lectures
to this React application.
Now for this, actually we can quit the DEV server right away
and install the Redux package
because we still want to use Redux.
And I haven't installed it yet in this new project
but Redux isn't the only thing we'll install.
We will install that.
But as I mentioned, a Redux is not React specific.
Redux can be used in any JavaScript project
and it doesn't know anything about React
and doesn't care about React.
Now to make working with Redux in React applications easier.
There is a second package
which we should install the react-redux package.
This is a package which makes connecting react applications
to Redux stores and reducers ends on very simple.
It will, for example, make it very simple to
subscribe components to the Redux store.
So you should install these two packages
into this React project.
And once that is done, we can continue.
So once that's completed,
I will bring up my DEV server again
and now it's time to get started with Redux here.