Now type inference is great.
And in general, up to this point
we already learned quite a bit
about TypeScript and its core types.
But up to this point, we also always had the scenario
that every variable took just one type.
So we always had just one possible type that could be stored
in a variable,
just a number or just a string or just a boolean.
And often that is what you need,
but sometimes you want to allow multiple, different types.
Let's say here for the course
we might be fine with storing a string in there
but maybe storing a course ID
as a number should also be correct.
It really depends on what you're building.
It's not unrealistic that we could have a variable
where both a string, as well as a number should be allowed
or that you have some variable
which should allow two different kinds of objects.
And for this scenario, that you have more than one type
which you want to allow
you have a feature called union types.
A union type is a type definition that allows more
than one type.
You add it like any other type assignment by adding a colon
after the variable name,
on the left side of the equal sign,
and then your type.
Now I mentioned that explicitly setting string
again here would be redundant, but it's not redundant
if you don't want to use the type inference here.
But if you instead want to specify such a union type,
hence allowing multiple types, you set up such a union type
by adding a pipe symbol after your first type
and then adding another type, like number.
And you can have as many types
which you want to allow here as needed,
but here I just want to have string or number.
And now you see that that error
which we had down here before is gone,
because now we are allowing a number alternatively
to a string value.
And of course you can use such a union type anywhere
where you have a type assignment,
not just when you're using type inference.
I could also use a union type up here
allowing username to be a string or
let's say an array of strings, for example
so that we have first and last name
in an array, for example.
That's also something I could allow here.
Union types are a never key TypeScript feature
which allows you to define more flexible values and types.