Now, wherever you like
styled components or not as an absolutely personal thing
there is no wrong or right here.
Now, when it comes to me personally
I prefer CSS in the CSS files.
I like the separation of CSS and JavaScript.
I like having clean JavaScript files.
And I simply like default CSS.
Now, of course you can absolutely stick
to the CSS approach we used at the beginning
where you had global non scoped styles
and you as a developer had to make sure
you're not accidentally reusing names, class names.
You're not accidentally affecting the styles
of (mumbles) components.
That is definitely one route you can take.
You can also however take CSS to the next level
with a feature called CSS Modules.
CSS Modules is a feature which is only available
in projects that are configured to support it
because it needs a code transformation that needs to be done
before your code runs in the browser.
Now, the good thing is the react projects created
with create react app which we used
are already configured to support CSS Modules.
This is actually an excerpt
from the official create react app docs
where you'll learn how you can utilize CSS Modules.
And it's super, super simple to utilize CSS Modules.
So let me show you how it works
and let's start with the good old button again.
Now of course you can stick to the style component there
but I will comment this out and comment out this import
and instead add the import all for react from react again
because I will comment in my own component again,
this one which uses JSX
and which (mumbles) for needs to react import.
Now we have the button CSS fall in India.
We got the different styles and we can leave that as it is.
There's one thing we now need to change though.
Of course, we need to add the import to the CSS file again,
but instead of importing it like this
you now import it slightly different.
You import classes or styles totally up to you
from the CSS file.
That's a syntax we haven't used before,
but that is actually how you have to import from a CSS file
if you wanna use CSS Modules.
Actually for (mumbles) code transformation,
which is needed behind the scenes to happen,
you also need to rename your file a little bit,
your CSS file.
You need to add dot module in there
so that it's named Button.module.CSS.
And then of course here,
you import from Button.module.CSS.
This is basically a signal
to the underlying compilation process
to transform to code so that CSS Modules work.
And I'll show you how they work
behind the scenes in a second.
So now we have this import and now we need to do something
with this import, that styles thing here.
We use it down there where we apply our class name.
Instead of applying a string class named like this
you apply something dynamic.
You refer to that styles thing
which you're importing from the CSS file.
And that thing turns out to be an object.
And in that object, you'll have every class you defined
in your file as a property.
So if I added a button class here in the CSS file
I now have the button property here.
And that's all we need to do.
This will apply this button class in a special way
to this button element here.
Let's see it an actual let's save this
and go back to our application.
And we see the button looks the way it looked before.
Now we see something interesting
if we inspect this here in the Def tools.
On the button you'll see a very strange class.
This is not the same class as added by style components.
Those classes looked like this here on the div.
Instead this looks a bit like the class we defined, button,
but with more information added to it.
It's basically component name, underscore, our class name
and the CSS file, double underscore some unique hash.
What CSS Modules does
or what this concept of CSS Modules does.
What the build process does under the hood
is it takes those CSS classes and a CSS file
and basically changes those class names
to be unique.
That's the core thing it does.
For every component it changes the class names
off the classes you're importing here.
So off the CSS file you were importing to be unique.
So if you import from the CSS file here
in the button component,
it will create unique classes, unique worshens
of all those styles and classes here for this component.
And for data it generates brand new class names
that look like this.
Inside of these class names, your styles will be
so it will just keep your styles.
It will not touch those
but wrapped into this new class name.
You can see this if you expand the head section here
in the rendered Dom.
There you will see a bunch of style texts.
And if we now search for the one here,
here at this for the button
we see that's this newly generated class name.
Here we have our button styles
and that newly generated class name is also used
on the focus style on the hover and on the active style.
And with that, does CSS Modules concept ensures
that the CSS styles we set up in a CSS file
are a scoped Q and a component
we import this file into.
For (mumbles) we need to work with CSS classes here
because we then access those classes
as properties on the imported styles object.
This is how we basically make the connection
between these dynamically generated class names,
which we as a developer don't know in advance
and our components here.
And that's also what you see here in the official docs.
That's in the end, all that's to it.
This is how you can use CSS Modules.
And for me that's actually the best of both worlds.
We have our styles set up in CSS files
but there's still scoped to components where we use them.
So in the next module,
let's all support the course input back to use the CSS file.
And then I will also show you how to use media queries
with CSS Modules.