One downside
of the validation we added thus far is our code.
Specifically, this line
we have this entered name is valid state.
And we start with true here, which implies
that initially we treat this as valid
and it turns out that that's not really the case.
We just set it to true
to not show does error state here ahead of time.
But actually we're cheating a bit here.
We're setting this state to avail you.
That's not correct because we know that we're not
going to really need that state for anything else.
Then outputting, whether it is this valid or not.
Now, why could this be a problem?
Well, imagine you had some useEffect
call in there where you do something.
Whenever entered name is valid changes
and specifically you do something.
If entered name is valid is true.
So if it's true, you wanna do something you wanna
in this case, log name input
is valid in a real application.
You might want to send an HTTP request here.
So let's say we add this.
And for this, I import useEffect.
If I do have that an open the developer tools
you see that this gets locked right at the beginning
before I did anything because of what I just explained
we incorrectly set this state here to true
and it isn't valid at the beginning.
That's just not correct.
We just did this as a work around,
to correctly show the error feedback.
Now, if you don't have, this useEffect case here,
you of course might be good with that
because then you have no real disadvantage
of using this trick.
But even then, I don't think this code reads nicely,
entered name is valid, is true.
Really? At the beginning,
it might be nitpicking,
but I'm not too happy with that.
I think it makes more sense to set this to false initially
because the input is invalid initially,
hence, we might want to add a third state here.
The entered name touched state maybe
and set entered name
touched
where we basically control
whether the user already did added the entered name,
input field.
And this all's is false initially
because initially this input field is untouched.
The user didn't do anything with it.
So now, we can use entered name touched
in combination with entered name as valid
to show this error message
and to add is invalid class.
Because now we don't just care about
whether the input is invalid or not.
But we also care about whether
the user had a chance of editing it
because if the user didn't have a chance yet
because the user didn't touch any input yet,
then of course there is no reason to present
this error.
For this. I'll add a new constant here.
Name input is invalid.
And for this all check,
if not entered, name is valid.
So that's the check we also have down there,
but I'll combine this with checking.
If entered name touched is true
because only if it was touched
and it's then is invalid.
I wanna treat it as invalid.
And now it's this name input is invalid Boolean
which you can use in this condition here
and also down here.
Though, now we have to be careful
since this is now name, input is invalid.
We of course need to invert,
our logic here.
Here, we don't check if it's not invalid,
but if it is invalid,
hence I removed the exclamation mark
and here I of course want to set this invalid class.
If name input is invalid
and not set it otherwise like this,
with that, if we go back and we reload,
initially, this is not showing this error state
but if I click submit, it's also not doing that.
And of course it's not doing that
because we never changed his touched state.
We now need to do that.
And it's now up to us how we want to change this.
And one change definitely is the form submission.
If the form is submitted,
all inputs are treated as touched.
Even if the user didn't type into them,
the user submitted to the overall form.
Which basically means the user confirms the overall form.
So we could treat all inputs as touched in this case.
So whenever the form is submitted
before checking the validity
just when it's submitted,
I will set entered, named touched to true
because all the inputs
and in this case we just have one input
are touched, are confirmed by the user.
When the form is submitted.
With this additive, we now click submit.
We get this error state once we submit.
And this is now a little bit of a better code.
It's more code arguably, but it's cleaner.
And it allows us to handle more use cases.
And it also allows us to ensure that code like this here
works correctly and doesn't run unexpectedly
just because of some strange work around.