So we got this JSX code here
which is basically HTML code inside of JavaScript.
Indeed, JSX stands for JavaScript XML
because HTML in the end is XML, you could say.
So we got this HTML code in JavaScript.
And again, this is really important.
This only works because there are transformation steps
running behind the scenes because of this process
does NPM start process which we started,
which transformed as JavaScript code
to more browser friendly code
before everything is being served here.
And indeed you can see that transformed code
if you want to.
Simply open up the developer tools
and here I'm using Chrome,
which is the browser I do recommend for development.
Simply open up the developer tools in Chrome
by going to view developer developer tools,
or by using that shortcut.
And in these developer tools here go to the sources tab.
And this shows all the sources,
all the script files for example,
which were downloaded as part of this page.
Now in here, you'll see a couple of folders
but you should see some static /JS folder or something
like that, which should hold a couple of JavaScript files.
Now the exact number and names of these files might differ.
But ultimately, if you click through these files
you should see some code which looks fairly cryptic.
And which is definitely not the code we wrote here.
Or we have here in these two simple JavaScript files.
Well, it turns out that this is this transformed code
and it's quite a complex code, as you can tell
because React supports many features.
And this code does not just contain our source code
but the whole react library source code
and the whole react Dom library source code.
So the code in these files is not just our code
but the entire React package code.
That's something to keep in mind.
Now in these files and the main chunk JS file here
for example,
you see a function named app, somewhere in there.
You might need to search for it
with control F but somewhere in there in these files
you should find your app function.
But of course, this function looks quite different
to the app function we have here.
That's a very lean function.
This function is not so lean.
Well in the end debts is transformed code.
You could say that is that code, which runs in the browser
which is not the code we wrote
but that's what this code is transformed to.
And if you have
a look at this transformed code and even look might change
over time, but it will definitely not look like this.
If you have a look at this transformed code that probably
is not code we would like to write.
And that's why we have these transformation steps
because we can use this special JSX Syntex,
which is not normally supported in the browser
whilst we're writing our code
and still it'll automatically be transformed to code
which does run in the browser so that we have the best
of both worlds code, which works in the browser
which obviously is important and code, which is easy to
write for us as a developer.
And I'm just putting so much emphasis on this
because that can be super confusing.
If you're new to React,
you do know some basic JavaScript at least you should.
And all of a sudden you see code like this
which is not regular JavaScript.
Well, this is just developer friendly code
which we can write, which is transformed behind the scenes.