Now in the last lecture,
we learned about refs
and I showed you that
with refs you have an alternative way
of getting that user input of accessing those input fields.
And I also showed you this
a little bit hacky approach of then
still manipulating the input fields and resetting them
if you want to do that.
Now, this approach of using refs
to interact with dom elements
specifically with input elements also has a special name.
We're talking about uncontrolled components
if we access values with a ref.
So these input components here,
would now be uncontrolled components.
Why uncontrolled?
Because they're internal state,
so to value which is reflected in them
is not controlled by react.
We rely on the default behavior of the input
where a user of course is able to enter something
and that entered value is reflected.
And we then just Fetch it, with a react feature
but we don't feed data back into the input.
When I set a new value to those inputs here
with this work around,
we're absolutely not using react here.
Sure we're using the ref,
but in the end we get access
to the native dom element with that
and I then just use the regular dom API
for setting the value of a dom node of a input dom node.
So that's why this is uncontrolled
because we're not controlling these state
off the input element with react.
Now, you can talk about uncontrolled
and controlled components.
All is in the context of other components,
but most commonly, we have this scenario
when we talk about input components
about form components in general,
because those components
tend to have some internal state natively by the browser,
an input element is configured
to take user input and save and reflect it.
And when we then work with those components in a react app,
we wanna connect our react state to that.
That's why we typically have
this controlled uncontrolled thing
when we work with input components in react.
And when we use refs, like we're doing it here,
we have uncontrolled input components.
The approach we had before,
where we manage our state
and we updated that state on every keystroke
and we feed that state back into the input
with the value prop,
so that approach we had before we added refs,
that would be the controlled approach.
Then we would say
that those input fields are controlled components
because their internal state is controlled by react.
These are simply important terms,
which you should keep in mind for potential interviews
or discussions with other react developers,
because they are typical terms you hear in the react world.