Back in the App component.
I now wanna use my custom hook
and therefore first of all, we have to import it.
So I import useHTTP
from
hooks
use-HTTP.
Then we can get rid of the, isLoading and the error states
because that's now a state which will be managed
by the custom hook.
So we can just call, useHTTP here.
Let me actually call this here after
initializing the Tasks state.
Now the custom hook needs some arguments
because we expect two parameters here, the requestConfig
and a function that is applied to that data
which we get back.
So therefore we should pass that in.
And for the requestConfig we pass in an object
with
a URL property
because inside of the custom hook
we are accessing a URL property here.
And we then also later access method, headers, and body
and therefore for the URL in the App component.
I will pass in this String here.
Now in the custom hook.
We also then expect the method, headers and body.
And the thing is that for App JS,
I just wanna get data
and therefore I wanna send a getRequest
I don't need any headers
and I don't need a body.
And to be flexible enough
and to not force all components to then pass
in some dummy data or anything like that, I will go back
to the custom hook and tweak this configuration here
for the fetchRequest a bit.
And in the case of the method here
check if requestConfig method is set
and only if it is set, I apply it here
and otherwise I set this to GET as a default.
For the headers I will check if headers are provided
on the requestConfig, and if they are
I of course will apply them.
Otherwise I'll set headers to an empty object
and for the body, all check if requestConfig body is set
in which case I will stringify it
so transform it to JSON I mean,
but if we got no body I'll set this to null here.
Now with that, the custom hooks should be flexible enough
so that
useHTTP
can just pass in an object that looks like this.
Now that's not all though.
We also need to provide a second argument
which is that function
which receives the data here in the end.
So therefore I will define a function here.
We could define it in line and the argument list
but to make it a bit more readable
I will define it here before I call useHTTP.
And it will add a function which I'll name
transformTasks,
here
I then expect to get my
tasks object
and inside of transformTasks.
I then wanna apply the transformation logic
which we had in use-HTTP JS before I deleted it there.
But I still have it down here
in App JS because I haven't deleted this code yet.
So it's in the end, this logic lines, 32-36 here in my case
which I wanna copy and add here into transformTasks.
And it's the tasks object through which I wanna loop here
with a for in loop and which I use down there.
And with that, we transform all the tasks from objects
which we get back from firebase
into objects that have the structure and format
we need for our front-end.
And then we set our tasks state
which we can still do since we still have setTasks here.
And we set our loaded tasks like this,
and now it's the transformTasks function,
a pointer at this function
which be pass as a second argument to use-HTTP.
And then this function will be called
for us by the custom hook whenever we got a response
and this is the best of both worlds with that
we have the main logic in the custom hook
but the data specific logic into component
where we need the data
that alone still won't do the trick.
UseHTTP does not just require parameters
it also returned something.
It returns this object with the loading and error states
and the a pointer at the sendRequest function,
which we ultimately will need to call
to trigger that request.
So in App JS,
I
will get back my HTTP
data here.
You can name this constant however you want
and it will de-structure it
by pointing at httpData.
And we can pull out isLoading error and sendRequest.
And of course we can also do the de-structuring right here
and save that extra line.
Now I will also assign an alias here
which is something we can do in JavaScript
by adding a colon here in this de-structuring syntax
and giving this a different name
and I will name it fetchTasks.
So we're still pointing at this sendRequest function
from the custom hook.
I'm just renaming it here
inside of this component function.
And with that, I will delete the old fetchTasks function
in the App JS file.
I will delete it like this
but I will keep useEffect here
where I still call fetchTasks.
Now, here, however, I should add fetchTasks
as a dependency now,
we should have done this before
but before it wasn't really an issue
because in the old fetchTasks function
I was only calling state updating functions
which are guaranteed by React to never change
and React to noticed this and didn't warn me before
but React doesn't know does fetchTasks function
so this sendRequest function at the end.
It doesn't know what's going on in there.
And therefore we have to add it
as a dependency to rerun this effect.
Whenever fetchTasks changes
at the moment this would be a problem though.
And therefore I will delete this dependency.
We will re-add it later because this is not a good practice
but we will avoid this dependency for the moment
because it would create an infinite loop right now.
And we don't want that.
And therefore with that
we now restructured the App component.
We still got access to the isLoading and error states
which we pass on to Tasks
to the Tasks component down there.
And we still get access to fetchTasks
but the logic for sending that request and handling errors
and so on is now part of the custom hook.
And therefore, if we save everything now
this should work again.
And if I reload it still loads all the tasks.
And if I add a new task
that also still works.
So that's now our custom hook being used.
It isn't finished the yet though
because as I mentioned, for example, here
we're not using it in a best practice way.
Let's therefore do that in the next lecture.