Now I wanna start with updating the UI
but before we can do that,
we got to do whenever important thing.
We have to store this token somewhere
in this running react application
where we can use it from all kinds of components
because at the moment we're logging our response here
in the auth form component,
but that's not the only component
we're interested in this data.
Instead, we'll need it in the header here
to update the menu items, which are presented to us.
And we'll probably need it
in other places off this app as well.
So this token should be some app white state
because it matters to a lot of different components.
And the general information that the user is logged in
matters to a lot of components.
Now, you learned that for managing app white state
you got two main options, the context API or Redux.
It's up to you, which of the two options you prefer.
I do explain the differences in the Redux section
in case you wanna dive into that again,
here I'll use the context API
so that we don't have to install
an extra third party package.
The authentication state is also not a state
that will change very frequently.
So we all just shouldn't have any performance issues here.
And therefore, I'll add a new folder,
a store folder in that source folder
which will hold the context code, which we're going to add.
And in there we can add up AuthContext JS file
where I wanna set up and manage
this context for this authentication data.
Now here, I'll add my AuthContext in general
by calling React.createContext.
And for this, we should import react from react here
and then initialize as context with some initial data
which I mainly set here
so that we define the general shape of our context
and get better auto-completion later.
And here I wanna store, let's say the token,
which initially is an empty string.
I wanna store the is logged in information in general.
For that we could simply check if we have a token or not
but I wanna use a shortcut here and have a Boolean here
which is true or false telling us whether the current user
of this website is logged in or not,
and out of the box, the user is not logged in.
And then we can add functions
that allow us to change that state.
For example, we can add a login function
which gets the token as an argument.
And then here does nothing.
We'll add the actual function a little bit later
as we did it early in the course.
And we can add a log out function,
which takes no argument and then here does nothing.
And then just as we did it early in the course,
I'll now add my AuthContext provider component here
which will actually be responsible
for managing the auth related state.
This component will receive props because it will return
AuthContext.provider wrapped around props children.
So that we can use this component overall
as a wrapper around other components
that then will have access to this context.
And it's in this AuthContext provider component
where I wanna manage the state for that auth data.
For this we can import use state from react.
And then here we can have our state for the token.
And initially that's an empty string let's say, or null.
And that's the token and a set token function.
And we can infer the answer to the question
wherever the user is logged in or not
by looking at this token state.
So we don't even need a separate state for this.
We can infer it from this state.
If we have no token, the user is not logged in.
If we have a token, the user is logged in.
So here the user is logged in.
Constant is simply the response or the result of checking
if token is truthy, and for this we can check if
nought nought token, this might look strange
but this simply converts this truthy or falsy value
to a true or false Boolean value.
If token is a string that's not empty,
this will return true,
if token is a string that is empty, this will return false.
That's a default JavaScript trick you could say.
And then we also need functions
for changing that token state, a loginHandler
and a logoutHandler function to be precise.
So we can add these two functions already
in the logoutHandler.
I'll simply set token to null again, so I'll clear my token.
In the loginHandler on the other hand here,
I wanna also set my token,
but I do expect to get the token as argument here.
And then I set a token equal to that token
which I am getting.
And with that, we can then construct our context value
which is an object, which will have that token field,
which is that token state we're managing,
which has this isLoggedIn field,
which is that user isLoggedIn value we are deriving here,
which has this login function
which points at the loginHandler function we defined
and this log out function, which stores a point
at the logoutHandler function we defined here.
And then it's this context value, which we set as a value
for this value prop on the AuthContext provider.
And if that looks brand new to you,
definitely have a look at the dedicated lectures
where I explain the context API from the ground up
because here I'm only using what you learned there.
With that context added, we just need to export it.
So here I'll export the AuthContext as a default
and I'll export the AuthContext provider as a named export
and then here in app JS or actually an index JS,
I'll wrap my context around my entire app.
So here all use the AuthContext provider component
which we import from store AuthContext
as a wrapper around my entire app like this.
So this named export, which I export in AuthContext
is imported here as a named import with curly braces.
And then we can tap into this context
in the different places of the app where we need it.
And we do for example, need it in the auth form component
because dad is where I wanna call that login function
to set my token, because here we get that token.
And therefore we need to tap into the context here
with use context.
And then here, for example, we can call use context
and connect this to the AuthContext,
which we also of course now needs to import
from store AuthContext.
And that gives us access to this AuthContext like this.
And with this access granted,
we can call login on this context now.
So down here where I know that the
sign up or sign in succeeded,
I know that this user is authenticated now.
And I know that we'll have this token
because Firebase returns us this token
on this ID token field in the response object.
And therefore here in this then block down there,
I can call authCtx.login and pass data.idToken as a value
because that will then be that token
which we get from Firebase.
With that we hopefully are setting the token
now to reflect that authentication state on the UI
which is the step I wanna start with.
I can go to the layout
and there to the main navigation component,
because here I wanna change the menu options,
which are displayed based on that login state.
And for dis here, of course, I also wanna
import use context from react
and call use context here
and connect to this AuthContext which we need to import
from store AuthContext
and store that in some a constant here.
And then I get the information
wherever the user is logged in or not
by reaching out to AuthContext isLoggedIn.
And now we can use that information
to conditionally render or not render some content.
Now for example, that link to the login page
should only be rendered if the user is not authenticated
because if we are authenticated
going to the login page makes no sense.
So I'll then wrap this entire list item here
and check if is logged in and only if we are not logged in,
hence the exclamation mark, I wanna rendered this list item.
Now for the profile it's the opposite.
I only wanna show this link if we are logged in.
So therefore here, I wanna check if isLoggedIn
and if we are, then I will show this profile link.
And for the button, I also wanna check if we are logged in,
because logging out only makes sense
if we are logged in, like this.
If I save that and I now reload,
out of the box we should only see the login link.
We can still manually go to the other pages
if we entered the appropriate URLs,
but that's something we'll work on later.
But we see only the login item here.
But if I do now login with valid credentials,
we stay on this page, but the main navigation changed
and that's a huge step forward.
Of course, that's not all we wanna do,
we probably also wanna navigate a way
and we wanna make sure that certain pages
can't even be reached if we are not logged in,
but it is a first important step in the right direction.
And before we work on redirecting the user
and protecting certain pages,
let's instead now focus on sending a request
to protected resources from that profile page
when we try to set a new password.