Now one possible,
better solution is actually totally obvious
once you see it.
Instead of using this approach,
which I implemented in the last lecture
and which I'll therefore now get rid of,
instead of doing that,
and hence I can get rid of this cart selector
and of the useSelector import.
Instead of doing that
we wanna stick to the approach from before.
We wanna dispatch the addItemToCart action
and do all this heavy work inside of the Reducer function.
But if we now wanna sync our new state to the server
so if we wanna update the server
with that new state
which we derived on the front end
we can simply switch the order.
We can first do the work on the front end
and let Redux update its store.
And then in a second step thereafter
we send the request to the server
but we don't necessarily need
to do that here inside of the Reducer function
where we wouldn't be allowed to do it.
Instead, we can, for example
do it in the ProductItem.js file
or in a totally different file.
Let's say in App.js
as our root component.
There we can simply get hold
of our overall cart
by basically using useSelector
and listening to changes to our cart state.
And whenever our cart state does change
we can send the Http request.
So that's what I'll do here.
I'll use useSelector,
which we're already importing
to get hold of my overall cart
and then I'll store it in that constant like this.
And now we can use useEffect
which we import from React
to watch for changes in our cart state,
because you learned
that useEffect allows you to run side effects.
So it sounds like a good choice here,
and it allows you to run an effect
whenever some dependency changes.
So we import useEffect from React
and we can then call useEffect here
in the app component, for example
and we could be doing this in any component.
I'm just picking my route component here
but that's not a must to do.
So here we then define our Effect function
and our array of dependencies.
Now, inside of the Effect function,
I wanna send a Http request with the Fetch API, let's say
and I wanna send it to Firebase.
So we grab that URL from Firebase,
add that here
and maybe target a cart.json node.
The .json is Firebase specific.
This will create a new cart Node in the database
and then store the data there.
And we wanna send a POST request
because that will tell Firebase to store new data
or to be precise,
actually here, I wanna send a PUT request.
That's also allowed by a Firebase.
And if we send a PUT request
we also do store data on Firebase.
But the difference to POST is
that the new data will not be added
in a list of data so to say,
but that it will override existing data.
So when sending a PUT request,
will override the existing cart
with the incoming data
and that's exactly what we want here.
So we can send a PUT request
and then set our request body to JSON.stringify
And now here, I wanna send my cart.
So this cart, which I get from Redux,
I convert this to JSON data
and send it as part of the request.
Now, since we're using cart in here
we should add it as a dependency to useEffect
so that this Effect function re-executes
whenever our cart changes,
which is exactly what we want.
Now, the great thing is
that useSelector sets up a subscription to Redux.
So whenever our Redux store does change
this component function will be re-executed
and we will get to the latest state.
So in this case, the latest cart.
So that means that effect will also be re-evaluated
and it will re-execute if our carts did change
and that is exactly what we need.
So with this simple addition here
we will send this Http request whenever our cart changes
and we can keep our logic for updating the cart
inside of the reducer,
because we simply switched the order.
We first update our Redux store
and we're done with that.
And then we select the updated store to send the request
and that allows us to keep lean components
create a fat Reducer with all the logic
and then perform any side effects
that might depend on our Redux state.
So if you save this
and we go back here,
if I reload
if I open up the network tab
so that we can see Http requests,
if I add something to my cart,
you see a Http request is sent
and that happens whenever I update my cart.
And if we go to Firebase,
we therefore see the cart's there.
And we see that here we have the correct cart reflected.
If I add my other item to the cart
and never request the send
and the cart was updated again.
So that is a very, very nice
and that's a very good way
of having our side effect logic in a component
and keeping all our data transformation logic
inside of a Reducer,
which is where we typically wanna have it
when working with Redux.