Now, to build the chart bar component
we again wanna import react from react in there
and then import the CSS file, of course.
So, that we have two styles available.
And then we can define our component function chart bar
and set this equal to props
and then simply return our JSX code here
and we will definitely need props
because we are already defining some props here
in the chart component.
Of course, we also wanna export chart bar
as a default here.
Now, for this JSX code in the chart bar which we return
I want to have a div here with a class name
of chart dash bar
since that's one of the CSS styles defined in the CSS file
and in there then another nested div
with a class name of chart bar underscore, underscore inner.
And this divs and CSS classes are simply required
to make the provided styles work.
Now, in there I will add yet another div
with a class name
of chart dash bar underscore, underscore fill
and then next to that div so not nested but next to it
I'll add another div with a class name
of chart dash bar underscore, underscore label.
And actually that should not be in the inner div
but side by side to the inner div
so, that this is the structure we have here.
A bunch of divs which will then be responsible
for rendering this chart correctly.
However, like this we wouldn't see much.
For one, I of course wanna output the label
which we receive on the label prop.
And that's why I added this div there
we can dynamically output prop store label
so that the label is visible.
But we also will need to change this chart bar fill div here
this div is required to basically remember
by how much this chart bar will be filled.
And this chart bar fill CSS class
will for example define the background color for that.
But one important piece of information
is missing in the CSS class.
And that will be the height of this filled chart bar.
The overall chart bar has a predefined height
100% of the parent container which is the chart
which has a height of 10rem.
But of course, by how much we fill that bar
depends on the data we're receiving.
So, it's depends on the value
because we wanna basically fill our chart bar
by putting the value in relation with the max value.
So, that if the max value for the entire chart is 100
and the value for a given chart bar is 50
we fill that chart bar by 50%.
And therefore in the chart bar component
we now need to calculate
by how much this specific chart bar instance
should be filled.
For this we can add a variable, which we could name
bar fill height but the name is up to you.
And initially I'll set this to 0% as a text
because this will be assigned as a CSS style in a second.
So, it's 0% like this but then I wanna check
if we got a max value greater than zero
so, at four given data points
we do have a max value greater than zero.
We could have zero later if we filter for a month
that has no expenses.
So, we wanna check if we do have a max value
greater than zero.
And if that's the case, I wanna set bar fill height
equal to math round and then in nested brackets
props value divided by props max value
times 100.
This will basically give us the percentage
between zero and 100 by which this bar should be filled.
And I'm rounding to the nearest integer here.
And we also wanna convert this to a string
with the percentage sign at the end
so I will add plus percentage here, like this.
And now we wanna set this as the height
as the CSS style height for this div
with the chart bar fill class name.
And to achieve this we're going to do something
which we haven't done thus far in this course.
We're going to set the style of an element dynamically
and that can be done by adding the style prop here
which is of course a default HTML attribute as well
but actually that style prop, that style attribute
works a little bit differently
when building a react application.
The value is set here should be dynamic
because it should be our derived fill height here
and indeed you then don't generate a dynamic string
where you set something like height 10% but instead style
and that's the special thing once an object.
So, here we don't have a special double curly brace syntax
but instead we have to single a curly braces
for outputting something dynamically
but then the dynamic value is a JavaScript object
which has also created with curly braces.
That's why we overall have the double curly braces
but it's no special style syntax.
The only special thing here is that style
wants a JavaScript object as a value.
And then this object
you should then use the CSS property names
as key names as properties and the values as well values.
So, for example, here we can then set background color
to a given value or in our case
we can set height to bar fill height.
Now, as a side note, if you have something
like background color with a dash
you need the quotes around the property name
because otherwise it would be an invalid property name
or better you use the camel case version of that name
background, color like this.
We don't need the background color here
but I want to show this to you.
I will come back to this later as well in the course
but that is how you would target such CSS property names
which have a dash inside of them
if you are setting the style prop on an element.
But here we don't even need that, so I will get rid of it
we only need to set the height.
And with that, we also finished the chart bar component.
Now, we just need to use the chart
and pass in the data points.