So now, before we proceed,
let me sum up what we just learned,
so that this is all really clear because it is important.
In React apps you work with components,
typically with function components in modern React.
Those components have one job in the end,
and that is this JSX code, which they return.
This tells React what the output
of that component should be.
Now in your React components,
you can work with state, or with props, or with context,
though props and context as I mentioned,
all come down to state changes in the end,
to make changes to a component
and to make changes to the data that affects this component
or that affects parts of your application.
Whenever you change state in a component
that component where the state changed is reevaluated.
And that simply means
that the component function is executed again.
So all this code runs again,
and therefore we get a new output.
This might actually be exactly the same output as before,
but it could also look different.
For example, if suddenly a paragraph is rendered or not,
or as in the case of the demo output component,
if the text is rendered or not.
React simply takes the result of this latest evaluation
and compares it to the previous evaluation's result.
And it does that for all affected components.
And then it hands off any changes,
any differences it identified to, in our case, React DOM
because we are using React DOM
to render our React app here in the index JS file,
and React DOM will take those changes
and apply them to the real DOM in the browser,
and really only those changes, nothing else.
Now, when React reevaluates a component,
it does not just reevaluate that component,
but since it reruns the entire function
and therefore all the rebuilds,
this JSX code rebuilds the output
for this latest snapshot, so to say.
It will also rerun all components
that you have in this JSX code.
Like in this case, it will rerun the demo output
and the button components.
Now to avoid unnecessary re-executions of child components,
you can use React.memo to tell React,
hey, please only execute this component function again
if the props really changed,
so if we got real new values in there.
If we got no new values,
please don't re-execute this function.
Now since reevaluating a component means
that the entire component function runs again,
that can have strange effects
if you're not aware of the fact that this really means
that everything in his function runs again.
And therefore, if you, for example,
create functions in the function
and you pass those functions through props
to our components, you will indeed get a new function object
and even React.memo will then not be able to help you
because objects are reference values
and comparing them with equal signs,
which is what React.memo does under the hood,
will not work for primitive values,
you will therefore not have that problem.
That's where useCallback comes in and can help you,
because with useCallback, you can tell React
that it should store a function and not recreate it
when the surrounding function runs again,
as long as certain dependencies didn't change.
That is what we learned thus far.
Now there are a couple of open questions though.
For example, if the app function runs again,
whenever the state changes, doesn't this mean
that we all the time reinitialize our state,
because we also execute useState over and over again then,
why is this not causing problems?
Well, it's questions like this
and general state related questions
that we're going to dive in next.