Now for this course,
I got two different approaches
two different options for you on how to take this course
how to go through that course.
The first approach which I have
which is the recommended one, is to standard approach.
With this approach.
You simply start in lecture one in section one
I guess you already did that
but you simply then continue lecture by lecture.
You maybe code along.
You might repeat some concepts
but you go through the entire course.
Step-by-step in order
because I built the course such
that all the modules built up
on each other and you'll learn react.
Step-by-step if you simply go
through the course in the order, I give it to you.
You can optionally go
through that JavaScript refresher section
which is the next core section
but you can also skip that refresher if you don't need it.
And then at the end of the course
I have a react summary module,
which basically sums up all the course concepts
from the ground up
not diving into them as deeply as the entire course does
but giving you a good overview
of what you'll learn in a very concise way.
And you can use this react summary module.
Once you've completed the course to get a good wrap
up off the course and of what you learned
and all to half this module.
If you come back to this course
in a couple of months or years even
if you want to quickly dive into react again
because maybe you haven't worked
with it for a couple of months
and then this summary module can also help you
and you don't have to go through the entire course again.
You can instead just take that summary module
and save some time.
So that's the first approach go through the entire course
step-by-step in the recommended order.
And then at the end, go through that summary module
to get a nice summary of what you'll learn.
Now, the alternative approach is
the summary approach as I like to call it.
And that approach is for you if you are in a hurry.
With this approach if you decide to take this approach,
you simply skip the entire course basically,
and you skip forward
to that react summary module at the end.
Maybe you also go through
that JavaScript refresher module first.
So that next course section
but that's also optional, of cause.
So you then skip to the end
to this react summary course section.
And you go through that summary section first
because that summary section is built
such that you can take it
without going through this entire course first.
It works standalone
and then it will give you a very concise
and compressed way of learning react.
You'll learn about all the core features
that you need to know about react in four hours
and that's of cause way faster than
if you go through the entire course.
Now it should be needless to say
that of course, we're not going to dive as deeply
into react in that summary section as we do
in the rest of the course
and that not all concepts are covered there
but it's a quick overview of all the core features.
And if you just wanna get started with react quickly
going through that summary section is a good idea.
You can then still go
through the entire course they're after
once you have more time.
And that is something I would recommend
because of cause it's this complete course,
which will teach you react in death,
not the summary course section.
There is a reason why this is a huge, very long course
and you can't pack that all into four sections.
If that would be possible, I would have done it.
So that is simply an alternative approach.
And you can go
with whichever approach were expander for you.