So, we want such an error modal.
Now a modal is simply does overlay box.
And for me that's a UI element,
we could be using in different parts
of the app.
This of course is a trivial app
that has only one part,
but we're always thinking
from the perspective
of potentially bigger apps.
Therefore I'll add it into UI folder
because such an error modal,
it could be a reusable UI element.
So I'll add my ErrorModal.js file in there.
And in that file,
we of course import react from react.
We got our error modal here,
which got some props,
and we export this like that.
Now that's the first step.
Now the second step,
is of course to fill
that with some life.
And generally, it's totally up to you,
how you wanna structure your modal.
I actually want
to reuse that card,
so import card from,
card like this,
and use this as a wrapper
for the entire modal,
because I liked
that rounded corners,
look hands on,
I wanna use that therefore.
Now inside of that card,
my modal should have different sections.
I wanna have a header,
with the H two tag,
where we actually can output some title.
Now below that,
I wanna have a div,
which holds my main content.
And in there a paragraph
with DRR message,
I wanna display eventually.
And below that, a footer.
Now in that footer,
I wanna have a button which we can click
to close the modal.
So for that I'll import button
from that slash button
to all the reuse, this component.
And this, shows us this re-usability of components.
We're using the card,
in various places of the app.
We're using the button
in different places of the app.
And we only defined these components
and their styles once.
And we can build our entire UI
with these reusable building blocks.
That's really the heart
and the core idea
or one of the core ideas of react.
So, we got the button here,
and hence the footer.
We can add such a button
and say, okay,
or something like that on it.
So that this is our closed modal button in the end.
Now, between the H two tags here,
I wanna have some title.
And of course
that modal should be configurable from outside.
I don't wanna hard code, the title
and the message into this component.
It should also be reusable.
So that we can use it
in different places of the app,
to show different error messages.
Hence here, I, I'll put something dynamic,
between curly braces
and use, let's say props.title.
Again, it's your component.
You can use any prop name you want here,
but I expect to get a title prop,
which holds the text,
which should be output here.
Now between the paragraphs,
I want to output props.message.
So that we also expect a message prop which,
well, holds the message
that shouldn't be output here.
And I also want some styling.
For data attached
to find the errormodal.module.CSS file.
And you can, again,
just drag that into your UI folder next
to the error modal JS file,
and then import it here.
Import classes from ./ErrorModal.module.CSS.
Because I'm also using CSS modules here,
to have unique class names.
And there are a couple
of classes that should be attached.
For example here,
on the card itself,
I wanna add the classes.modal class.
Which is one of the classes
to find here in the CSS file.
In addition on the header,
I want to have the classes.header class.
And on that div
that's surrounds the paragraph,
I will add the classes.content class.
On the footer,
we'll also add a class,
and that's the classes.actions class.
And these are all CSS classes predefined
in that CSS file.
With that, we'll have a basic modal,
and we can already see
that in action.
The question is,
where do we wanna render it,
as part of which component?
And you can actually argue about that.
You can argue
that it should be rendered
inside of add user,
because ultimately it will be this component
that will trigger the modal.
You could also argue,
that it's a general overlay
over the entire UI
and therefore logically,
it should be rendered as high
as possible in the component tree.
Something like inside
of the app component
or anything like that.
Now, I will go for the place
where it actually is, being cost,
and that would be add user component,
but you can definitely also pick a different place.
You then of course, we'll need
to update your state management appropriately.
I will write state management code,
that ensures that it works here
inside of the add user component.
So here I wanna output my error modal,
and therefore, we have
to import it, of course.
So we go here,
and import error modal
from UI error modal.
Now we also need to configure it.
We need to set a title,
and we'll soon set this dynamically
but now I'll set it to,
an error occurred,
and the message which we can set
to, something went wrong.
But this will not work.
And do you know why?
I briefly touched on it
in the debugging section.
Well, if we try to save this,
we'll get an error.
We'll get the error
that we got adjacent JSX elements,
and that this is not allowed basically.
Indeed react doesn't allow,
two side by side components being rendered,
directly as a root element
of your return statement.
And you therefore need to wrap this,
for example, in an extra div.
We'll later see a different solution for this,
for now we'll just take extra div,
and put our error modal
and our card, into that div.
So that the div has returned
by the return statement.
And then inside of the div,
we can have adjacent elements.
And with that it compiles,
and if you reload,
hey, this doesn't look too bad.
We got our modal here.
Now, of course it's not dynamic.
Of course we can close it right now.
And of course, one crucial thing is missing,
and that's a backdrop for the modal.
So a overlay between this modal overlay
and the actual main page.
So to be calm,
to interact with the rest
of the main page,
which currently, is possible.
So, to make sure we can't interact
with the rest of the page,
back in the error modal,
I'll add an extra div,
next to the card, not inside of it,
but next to it, and therefore,
as we just learned,
we need a general div,
that wraps both,
that extra div
and the card.
And on that extra div,
I'll add a class
and that's the classes.backdrop class.
The device itself is empty
but this backdrop CSS class makes sure,
that we have this grayish,
black transparentish background behind the modal.
If we now save everything,
you can see the background here,
and now I can't interact
with the form anymore, for example.
So with that,
we've got the model in place.
Now, of course, the goal is
to show it only sometimes,
only if we do try
to submit invalid data.
And of course we wanna make sure
that we can also dismiss it.