So now to use the chart
and pass in the data points
I will add a new component
in the expenses components folder
and I'll name it, expenses chart
JS.
And here we don't even need a CSS file
but I will import React from React
to be in line with my other files
and create the component function expenses chart.
There I expect to get some props and we export this,
so basically what we always do.
Now in here the goal is to overall return the chart.
So here we wanna return the chart
and therefore you should make sure
that you also add the import to this chart component
in the chart folder like this.
But now we need to define the data points
which are passed into the chart
because there we are referring to this data points prop.
And to set up the data points here in expenses chart,
I will actually create a new constant here
and name it, chart data points.
And this will be an array, and in this array
I wanna have a bunch of objects
because we expect every data point to be an object.
In the chart JS file,
when we map through data points,
we then access values like label
and value on the given data point.
So therefore we wanna have objects
and these objects should have a label and a value key.
Now the value is simply zero initially for every data point
and the label is something like Jan for January.
But then I'm going to duplicate this
and set up the Feb data point, which also initially is zero.
And I'll repeat this for the entire year
and have a March, April,
May,
June,
July
and so on.
Also have August and September and October
and then have November and December.
So that we have all these data points,
which in their initial state all have a value of zero.
Now, of course we're not done here.
We don't wanna have zero for every data point.
Instead, now we wanna have a look at our filtered expenses
and make sure that we basically go through all the expenses
for a selected year and that we then sum up the expenses
for all the different months
and we assign them here
to our data points.
So therefore I expect to get the filtered expenses
as a prop on my expenses chart component
because we will use expenses chart
in the expenses JS file later.
And there we have the filtered expenses.
So here in expenses chart
I just expect to get that list of expenses.
And then we can add a for loop
where we loop through all our expenses,
which we get via props.
And then we wanna have a look at every expense,
get the month of that expense
and updates the value of the appropriate data point
by the expense amount.
So here we kinda get our expense month inside of that loop
by having a look at expense.date get month.
Date is a date object
and there we have the build in get month method
which returns us that month.
Starting at zero though,
so January
is zero.
But we can then use this month later
to pick the right data point,
since January has the index zero in this array as well.
So we can basically use the month as a index
in that array later.
And later is actually now
I will reach out to my chart data points
for the given month.
Again, this starts at zero
and ends at 11 which is exactly the case
for the index of these data points.
So we can use that as an index.
And I wanna update the value of the selected data point
by adding something to it
with the plus equal shortcut operator.
And I wanna add the expense amount
so that we increase the value of a given month
by that expense amount.
And we go through all expenses to sum up
all the expenses for the different months
and assign the values to the appropriate months,
to the appropriate data points here.
So that after this for loop,
we still have this array
but now the values will not be zero anymore
but instead they will have the summed up values
for the given month expenses.
And now we can pass these data points to the chart.
There we set the data points prop,
since that's the prop we're expecting their data points
and we set this equal to our updated chart data points.
And this should do the trick.
Now we're still not done,
we now also wanna go back to the chart
and there you might remember
that we also need to calculate the total max value.
So we wanna have a look at all the months
and find the biggest value
across all months.
Because that's the maximum value
which should be represented in the chart.
And to do this, we can add a new constant total maximum.
The name is up to you.
And here we can use math max to find the maximum value
but actually max wants a number of arguments like this.
So comma separated arguments, comma separated numbers
for which are then returns to biggest number.
Here we have an array though
and also not an array of numbers, but an array of objects.
And we're just interested
in a specific property of that object.
Nonetheless, we can work around that,
we can get our value array if we wanna call it like this
or our
data point values.
And here we can simply call props data points
dot map to call the map method.
But now we won't map the data points into JSX elements,
but instead simply transformed them from objects to numbers.
So that for every data point
we in the end just return data point dot value.
So that means that
we transform a data point object to just the number.
The number stored in data point value.
And therefore map here on data points
will return a brand new array
which is just an array of numbers.
An array of all these values,
for all these data points we're getting.
So in our case for the 12 months
we'll have an array of 12 values.
And now it's the data point values
where we wanna find the maximum.
But since max wants a list of arguments
instead of an array.
And since this still is an array,
data point values still is an array.
We can use the spread operator here
to pull out all the array elements
and add them as standalone arguments
to this max method.
So now this max method will receive 12 arguments
which are these 12 values
from our array pulled out by this spread operator.
And now it's this total maximum
which I pass in here as a max value.
And with that that's all is updated.
And now we just wanna make sure
that we use our expenses chart component
and I wanna do that in the expenses JS file.
There we can import expenses
chart from
expenses.
Chart like this.
And we now simply add that here
between the filter and the list.
We render our expenses chart.
And of course, very important now
we need to pass in the expenses prop
because that is expected in the expenses chart component.
So here all
set expenses equal
to
my filtered expenses.
Because of course I only wanna chart
the currently filtered expenses.
And with all of that we should be done
except that I'm getting an error here,
cannot read property get month of undefined.
And that's simply happening because
here in the expenses chart component
I'm using a for in loop.
Of course it should be a for off loop
since expenses, props expenses is an array, not an object.
So for all these correct to loop for all the items.
And now this is looking better.
Now what we see though
or what we don't see
is somehow we don't have any fill values.
No matter how I switch
we never see any of the bars being filled.
But the reason for that
is that in the chart bar component
I'm checking props max for being greater than zero.
Well, I actually named the prop max value though.
So we should also check props max value here.
And now this looks better.
Now we see
that
this looks good
and now we got certain bars which are filled
others which are not filled.
Simply depending on what we're filtering for.
And this is now the finished expenses tracker,
of course feel free to play around with it,
to tweak it, to add more features
and experiment with it.
But we're also going to have more projects in this course
and we're also going to dive deeper into React.
For example, we are also going to take a closer look
at styling React components
and how we can scope styles to components.
Because actually right now I can tell you
all the styles we set up,
even though the CSS files
have components specific file names,
all CSS styles actually up to this point are global.
If a class is defined here in the chart bar CSS file
we could add the CSS class
to any element in any component
and the styles would be applied.
Currently, these styles are not scoped
and therefore that's one topic
we're also going to take a closer look at
through out the next modules
but of course also plenty
of other core React features.