So let's now send a request
once the form is submitted.
Now this checkout component is already a pretty
full component with a lot of code in there
and they are for I'll not add the request logic in there
but instead I want to kind of submit
or ascend the submitted data
back to the cart where we then also have the cart data
which is good because we need that
to send it to the server,
to then send both the carts data
so the items in the cart
as well as the submitted user data to the server.
Now, one important word here,
on a server you should typically never trust
the data you get from a client
because of validation
as we built it here can always be circumvented.
For example, I as a visitor
could edit the loaded JavaScript code.
It's not hidden from me
I can edit it attached to find an article
and a video with more information on that.
Therefore, you typically always wanna validate incoming data
on the server as well.
Now here, we only have a dummy backend with Firebase
and whilst we could actually also add some service
and logic to that,
that's simply not the focus of this course
since this course is about React
which is a client side library.
If you wanna dive into service side code,
service side validation, writing your own server side code
I of course also got courses on this, for example
my Node JS course, but that's just a side note
I just wanted to emphasize
that you should not trust client side data like this.
You for example, typically also would want to
validate those submitted cart item prices
with actual database data on the server.
It's not something we do here
but I want to make you aware of that.
So therefore it's the cart component
where that data should be submitted to the server.
And for this I'll add a new function in that cart component,
submit order handler that could be the name
of that function
and in here, I expect to get the user data
as a argument, as a parameter.
We already get access to the cart data
through the cart context.
So that won't be a problem
and therefore, all we now gotta do is make sure
that this submit order function is called
from inside to the checkout component
and that it receives that user data.
So for that, I'll pass it to the checkout component
through a prop.
Let's say the on submit
or on confirm prop, up to you it's your component
where I point at the submit order handler.
So on confirm as the prop name hence in checkout.
In this confirm handler.
Once we validated everything down here
we now wanna call props.onConfirm
so that prop name we're expecting here
in the cart component.
We wanna call props on confirm
and now forward that user data,
which should be an object
because I'm not expecting multiple arguments
for the name street, city and so on.
But I am expecting just one argument here
the collected user data.
So let's group that user data into an object here
where we set the name equal to the entered name,
not the validity but just the name.
Set a street field to the entered street
set the city fields to the entered city
and set the postal code
to the entered postal code like this.
And with that we pass the data from the checkout component
to the cart component.
In there we now wanna send the request to the backend
and we wanna send both the user data
as well as the cart data.
Now for this, we can again use the fetch function
and send the request to Firebase.
So to our Firebase, URL here
and then to a new Node of our choice.
For example, order.json
you don't need to create it in advance
it will be treated dynamically.
And the important thing now is
that this should be a post request.
So we need to pass this configuration object
as a second argument to fetch
and set method to post.
We then also need to add to the body
and set this to JSON.stringify
since we need to send JSON data
and pass in all our data
and that's an object with the user data.
So here we could set a user field
and pass the user data we're getting here
as a value for that field
and then maybe add a ordered items field
and that should then be our cart.
Now for this we have our cart context
where we get our items.
So we can then set cart context items
as a value for the ordered items.
And that's the data we're then sending to the backend.
Now just like this, without anything else
it should already work.
We're not handling the response yet.
We're not handling errors or anything like that
but we are sending a post request.
So this should already work.
If we save that
and I do have some data entered here
I do have some cart data
and I click confirm that should have worked.
And indeed, if we check the Firebase console
you should see an order's Node now
with a new auto generated ID for this newly added item.
And then in there we have user with the user data we entered
and ordered items with the cart data we submitted.
So that is working.
If it's not working, definitely double check your code
compare it to mine
because that should now be working.
Now therefore, as a last step,
I of course wanna change the user experience a little bit.
I want to clear what we see on the screen here.
If we clicked, confirm
and show a loading spinner
and then access message if the cart was submitted
and of course the cart
should then also be cleared thereafter.