The question now is what do we want to do
with that value?
What's the goal now?
And the answer is, well, we want to make sure
that we store it somewhere so that when later
when the form is submitted, we can use that value.
Because of course, we want to gather all the values
for all inputs and then combine them
into an object when the form overall is submitted.
And one way of storing that value
and making sure that it survives,
even if that function would be re executed
for whatever reason,
so this component function, I mean.
To make sure that we store the value and that it survives
if that function would be re-executed
and the component would be re-evaluated,
we can again, use State.
So we can import the useState hook from React here,
and basically just call it here
at the beginning of the ExpenseForm function
and set the State for this input here, so to say.
And initially that's an empty string
because initially when this component is rendered
for the first time, nothing was entered,
but then we can again, use destructuring
to get our two elements,
which is the currently enteredTitle.
Maybe we name it, enteredTitle
and a function for updating the State,
which following the convention
should be named setEnteredTitle.
And here, when we react to this event
where the user enters something,
we can't just call setEnteredTitle
and pass events target value.
So the currently entered value as a parameter,
as argument, to setEnteredTitle.
And therefore this will be stored in our State.
Now, here I'm not really doing it to update this component
though the component will update.
That will always happen when you update the State
but I'm doing it to ensure that we're storing
this in some variable, which is kind of detached
from the life cycle of this component function.
So that no matter how often this component function
might execute again, this State is stored and survives.
There would be other ways of solving this as well
but that works just fine.
And it has another advantage
because we'll need that State for updating
and for re-rendering that component later anyways.
But for the moment we just use a to safe to value.
Now we can do the same for the other two inputs.
And of course, definitely try this on your own as well.
Pause the video and make sure you listen
to these change events for the other inputs as well
and that you also store State for those changes.
So here's your chance to pause the video,
thereafter, we'll implement this together.
So, did you add that?
Let's now do it together.
And I'll start by adding a new function
and that will be the amountChangeHandler.
And the logic is basically the same as before.
I want to make sure
that this function gets triggered
whenever the amount changes.
So on the amount input, we can add a onChange prop
and point at the amountChangeHandler, just like that.
And before I add any code in there,
I will already add the third function
for my dateChangeHandler, like this
and that should be triggered whenever the date changed.
So here I always listened to onChange
and point at the dateChangeHandler.
So now all these inputs are wired up
but of course at the moment nothing is happening here.
Now I also of course
want to store State for changes made here.
And that brings up one important question.
Maybe a problem you also encountered,
how can you manage more than one State?
It is something we have learned up to this point
but it turns out that it is rather simple.
You can call useState more than once.
Maybe you tried that and if you did good job,
because you can do that.
You can have multiple States, multiple States slices
or State pieces per component.
And all of these States inside of one at the same component
will then all to be totally separated from each other.
So you're all called useState again
and extract my enteredAmount
and my setEnteredAmount function with RAD structuring.
And now we've got these two pieces of State
which belong to this component
and we can update and read them individually.
So they work in a totally separated way.
When I update the amount,
this will not affect the title and vice versa.
So for the amountChangeHandler,
we can call setEnteredAmount
and pass in event target value here as well.
Well, and unsurprisingly, we can do the same for the date.
Call useState again
and store an empty string here as well.
By the way, I'm storing strings all the time
and not a number here for the amount, for example,
because by default, whenever you listen to the change event
for an input, if you read the value of that input element,
it'll always be a string.
Even if it stores a number
it will be a number as a string and the same for the date.
So we always get a string here.
That's why I also initialize all States with a string.
And here, therefore, for this third State,
I have my enteredDate and setEnteredDate.
And I now also can update this State here
with setEnteredDate events target value, like this.
Okay.
Now we got these three State slices
and this is really important.
This is absolutely okay
and you will see that quite a lot,
that you have more than one State per component.
You can have these separate States and update them
separately and manage them separately.
That is a key part of this entire State concept
React ships with.
You can, and you often will have multiple States
per component.
Nonetheless, this multiple States
verses one State thing is a concept
I wanna take a closer look at.