So in the last lecture
we added these
handler functions
and we added
multiple state slices.
Now I did
emphasize,
that you can have
multiple such slices
that this is totally normal.
However, there also is an alternative
and it depends basically on your personal preferences
which approach you prefer.
You can have multiple slices,
but you could also argue that
of course, all three States here are related
to our form,
that,
in all three States, we just
store some user input and that it's therefore
basically the same concept repeated three times.
Therefore, you could also go
for one state instead of three states.
How?
simply by commenting this out.
by calling used state
only once
and by passing in an object as a value
and that's important
not a string
or number or anything like that, but an object.
And of course in this object,
you can now group together, your three States
you could have a title key, or
maybe alter it entered title key,
And that holds an empty string initially.
And you have an entered amount key as well
with an empty string and an answer to date.
So,
the logic is kind of the same
but now it's in one state object
managed as one piece of state
instead of three separate slices.
The difference now,
of course is
that whenever you update this state
you need to update all
three properties and not just one.
So here you could then also extract this
and have your user input, for example,
and set user input.
And now when,
the user enters a title, you wouldn't store it
like this,
but you would call set user input.
And in the end here, you then want to pass
in a new object where you set the entered title
in this case to event dot target dot value.
But that's not the tricky part
where you also ensure
that the other two pieces of data don't get lost.
If you would just set your new user input state
to this object, you would basically dump the Abra keys
because when you update your state
react will not merge this
with the old state.
It will simply replace
the old state with the new one.
And if your new one is a object
with one key value pair here
the old state will be replaced and therefore
The other are two key value pairs
for amounted to date would be lost.
So if you go for this
one state approach and you manage such a object
it's all your responsibility to make sure
that the other data does not get lost.
And to do that,
you manually need to
copy
the other values
which you're not updating here.
So if you are updating the title, you also want to copy
in the existing values for amount and date.
And one way
of doing this would be to use the spread operator
which is a default JavaScript operator
in modern JavaScript.
And you copy in user input
like this.
Actually, you do this first and then you just
override entered title.
If you haven't seen this syntax before,
this neon just
takes an object,
pulls out all the key value pairs,
and adds them to this new object.
And then we can still override key value pairs like
in this case enter title.
And by doing it like this,
we ensure that the other values
aren't thrown away,
but are always a part of that new state.
And now we could do this
in all three places here,
of course,
and update the entered
Amount here and
do the same here,
Just that here, we update the entered date
and that would be an alternative
to having the three individual state slices.
It's up to you, what you prefer.
And this code also, isn't perfect yet,
by the way
I'll come back to this in a second
but generally,
you can switch between these approaches.
Now, I tend to prefer the individual state slices,
And I would say you also see that more often out there
in the world, in other react projects,
but ultimately both approaches are fine.
One thing is not fine though,
And that is how I update my state here.
When I also consider my oldest state for copying in values.
And that's something we're going to take a closer look
at in the next lecture.