Now let's continue writing tests
and let's now explore how multiple components can interact
with each other and how we can test that
and how we can work with props and tests.
And for this, I'll stick to this
very simple component I have here.
And what I want to do here
is now I want to create a new component,
the output component
which does what the name implies.
It just outputs something.
So this will be a quite straightforward component.
And of course I'm keeping it deliberately simple
so that we can explore these basic testing concepts
with basic examples.
And the idea of this output component therefore
is just to render a paragraph,
which outputs props.children
or props.text, depending on how you want to do that.
And here I'll say props.children.
And of course, this is kind of a redundant component
but if we could have some extra styles on this paragraph
and then use this as kind of a wrapper component
as we also sometimes did it in this course
for example, with that card component
which we had in some projects,
if you remember that.
So that's the output component and it does use props.
Now here, I got this greeting component
and instead of rendering this paragraph here
I now want to render my output component.
And let's see how that could work.
For this in this greeting component file
I'll import output from dot slash output.
And now we can replace paragraph with output
like this
and like that here.
Now, if I save everything
the nice thing which we'll notice
is that the tests simply continue to work.
So that's the good thing about render
which we use to render the greeting component.
It really renders this entire component tree
that is required here.
So it renders not just greeting
and ignores other components used in that JSX code
but it renders the content of those components
like in this case, the output component as well.
And technically we could therefore call this
an integration test because now more than one unit,
more than one component is involved.
But especially when dealing with such a wrapper component
which doesn't have its own logic,
that's of course not really the right term.
Testing the conjunction of these two components together
is absolutely fine.
And that's why I wanted to show this here.
This is not something that forces you
to split your tests necessarily.
You might want to split them
if the output component becomes more complex
and also starts managing state,
then you might want to test that separately
from the core logic of the greeting component.
But since that is not the case here
we definitely can keep the tests we have here
in greeting test JS to keep testing as we did before.