Let's say we wanna utilize
this provided store not in the app component
but in the counter component which I rendered there.
That's this counter component in the components folder.
We got more components there we'll use them later
for the moment it's the counter component
that matters to us.
Now that's the component you're seeing on the screen here
when you're running your Def server.
It shows us basically a container
where we wanna output the counter value.
We got a toggle counter button for hiding
or showing the counter.
Now here I wanna start by outputting the current counter.
And for this we need to get access to our Redux store
and to the data in there.
And we again do that with help off the React Redux Library.
So from React Redux we again wanna import something
and the something which we are importing is a React Hook.
A custom hook made by the React Redux team.
The use selector hook.
There also is use store hook, which we could use as well
which gives us direct access to the store
but you as selector is a bit more convenient to use
because that allows us to then automatically select a part
of our state managed by the store.
So I will use use selector here.
Now if we would be using a class-based component
and not a functional component as we are here
and as we are in the majority of the course,
then there also is a connect function
which we could use instead.
This function can be used as a wrapper
around our class component to connect that class component
to the store.
I'll come back to that later for the moment
we'll focus on use selector.
So here in this functional component we can now get access
to the data managed in our store by using use selector.
We call this and now we need to pass a function
to use selector.
A function which will be executed by a React Redux
of function which then basically determines which piece
of data we wanna extract from our store.
Of course at the moment we have a very simple state.
Just an object with a counter property.
But in bigger applications,
you will have more complex states with tons
of different properties maybe nested objects and arrays
and therefore being able to just get a slice
just a tiny part of that overall state object
in a easy way is worth a lot.
And that's what use selector allows us to do.
For this we should pass a function to it,
a function of which we'll receive the state managed
by Redux and then we return the part of the state
which you wanna extract.
So here for example, state stock.counter.
Again this function will be executed for us by React Redux.
It will then pass the Redux state
so the manage the data into this function
when it executes it and then basically executes
this code to retrieve the part of the state
which you need in this component.
And then use select or therefore overall gives us
that returned value.
So we get a counter constant
which is the counter managed by Redux.
Now the great thing is that when you use use selector,
React Redux will automatically set up a subscription
to the Redux store for this component.
So your component will be updated
and will receive the latest counter automatically
whenever that data changes in the Redux store.
So it's an automatically reactive
and changes to the Redux store will cause
this component function to be re executed.
So you always have the latest counter.
That's why use selector is a very useful hook
and why it is the hook we use for getting data
out of the store.
If you ever would unmount this component
if it would be removed from the DOM for whatever reason,
React Redux would also automatically clear
the subscription for you.
So it manages that subscription for you behind the scenes.
Now that we got this counter, we can use it down there,
to output the counter value like this.
And if we now save this, we therefore now see zero here.
And that's how we can get access to data managed by Redux.
Of course the question now is how we can change that data?
How can we dispatch actions?