Now, the last feature I want to cover here
before we dive into the demo project is redirects,
a feature that allows us to redirect the user.
And I got an example for this as well.
In our App.js file, we defined routes
for /welcome, /products and /products/productId.
Now, what if I just visit my domain /nothing
then I don't get an error,
but I also don't see anything on the screen.
Now, here, we might want to redirect
the user to /welcome.
Of course, we could always adjust
change this to /nothing exact here
and showed a welcome page for /nothing.
But if that's not what we want
we can redirect and stat.
For this, we can to find another route
where the path is /nothing and where we add exact so
that this is not treated as the start of a route.
Otherwise it would match all routes
because all the routes start with /nothing in the end.
Hence, we need exact here.
And then inside of this route, I don't render J as X code.
I don't render another of custom component.
Instead, we render a component provided
by React router Dom.
The redirect component.
That is a component, which you can render like this.
And if it gets rendered, it will do what the name implies.
It redirects the user somewhere else.
So here we can then redirect to /welcome,
which means if we're just visiting /nothing,
this will be rendered
and this will then change the URL to /welcome.
And then this route will become active.
Hence exact is very important here because without it
every route would be matched here
and we would be redirecting all the time
and we would create an infinite loop there
for so exact matters.
But with that, if we save this
if I visit just my domain /nothing
you see it automatically changes to /welcome
in the URL here.
And that's how we can use redirects
in our application with help
of this redirect component provided by react router.