So in the last lecture I showed you
how you can use one state instead of multiple states.
And I did talk about it there.
Now the way I'm updating my state here
is not entirely correct though.
It technically would work,
but in niche cases it could fail,
and it's simply not a good practice to update it like this.
So what's the problem here?
Here, I'm depending on my previous state
for updating the state.
In this case, we depend on the previous state
because we used this one state
instead of three-states approach
and we need to copy in the other values
so that we don't lose them.
Hence we depend on the previous state snapshot
to copy in the existing values
and then just override one value with a new one.
Now whenever, and that's another key rule
which you should memorize,
whenever you update state
and you depend on the previous state,
so for example, as we do here in this object,
but also if you would be managing a counter
which you increment by one, for example,
whenever you update your state
and you depend on the previous state,
you should not do it like this
but you should use an alternative form
of this state updating function.
Instead of calling it like this,
you should call it and pass in a function to that function.
So you call the setUserInput function
and you pass a function to it,
for example, such an anonymous arrow function.
And this function, which you pass to setUserInput here,
will automatically be executed by React.
And it will receive the previous state snapshot
for that state for which you're calling
the updating function,
so in this case, for this object state here.
So we'll get the previous state snapshot,
and now here, we should return the new state snapshot.
So instead of this function
which we passed to the state updating function,
we return the new state now.
And that now could be,
or in this case, should be, our object
where I copy in the key value pairs from the previous state
with the spread operator,
but where we then also override,
in this case here, enteredTitle with event.target.value.
Now why should we do it like this instead of like this?
In many cases, both will work fine,
but keep in mind that I mentioned
that Reacts schedules state updates,
it doesn't perform them instantly.
And therefore, theoretically,
if you schedule a lot of state updates at the same time,
you could be depending on an outdated
or incorrect state snapshot
if you use this approach.
If you use this approach, React will guarantee
that the state snapshot it gives you here
in this inner function,
will always be the latest state snapshot,
keeping all scheduled state updates in mind.
So this is the safer way
to ensure that you always operate
on the latest state snapshot.
So you should use this function syntax here
whenever your state update depends on the previous state.
That is something you should memorize.
If your state update depends on the previous state,
use this function form.
With all of that though,
I wanted to show this because these are key concepts
which you're also going to see again and again
throughout this course
and throughout a lot of React projects,
but here I will actually comment out
all of these alternatives
and I will switch back
to that multiple states approach instead,
which we initially had.
So let's comment out all of that
and go back to this initial approach.
I just wanted to show the alternative
because it is a valid alternative,
you will see it in many projects,
you will have scenarios where you need it.
And this thing regarding the,
if you depend on the previous state,
use this approach thing here,
that's something you should keep in mind in general,
because you will often depend on a previous state,
not just if you merged state like this
but also in other scenarios,
like the counter which I mentioned, for example.
So that's why I mentioned this.
Nonetheless, let's go back to this multi-state approach now.