Whenever you learn something new,
it is important to practice it.
And therefore, that's what we're going to do now
over the next lectures.
We're also going to dive into more React Router features.
So the rest of this module is not just practicing
but we're going to start with practicing what we learned
because it is super important
that you do understand React Router and how you can use it.
Now attached you find a brand, "you starting project,"
this project here.
You can simply download it, extract it,
run NPM install, and NPM start.
There, you got some starting components
which we'll use over the next lectures.
And you've got an empty App.js file.
I did already add React Router
to the starting project package.js file.
So when you ran and PIM install,
you did already install React Router DOM.
You don't need to install it separately.
You would of course, need to install it
if you work on a project that doesn't use React Router yet.
Now with that, we're ready to dive in.
And we're going to build this demo application here.
An application where we can view some quotes,
dive into specific quotes and add new quotes.
For the moment all without a backend server,
just locally in our client-side application.
The quotes which we add also, won't actually be added
to our list of quotes because we will not use Context
or Redux or a backend for the moment,
that is something which we'll add in a second step
there after.
So let's get started.
And let's get started by defining the main routes we need
in this application here.
Now in the last lecture I showed you the kind
of pages I wanna have in this example application.
And there, we had a page which shows All Quotes.
Then we had a Quote Detailed Page,
When we click on a SingleQuote, we would go to that page.
And we had that page for adding a brand new quote.
So we got three different pages, three different routes
which you want to register.
Now you will get more out of this course
and out of this section specifically,
if you also tried these things on your own,
if you practice on your own.
And therefore before we add those pages together,
and before we then add all the code
for registering those pages as routes,
try this on your own.
Add a couple of page components, and then write all the
routing code to register these page components
as a different routes for different paths.
The paths are up to you and make sure
that you can navigate between those pages
by entering these paths manually in the URL.
So you can add links right now, but you don't have to
but definitely make sure
that you add all those page components
and you registered them.
And then offer a short pause
which I give you to pause the video and try it on your own,
we're going to do that together.
So, where are you successful?
Let's try this together.
And therefore here in this app component function,
we can import route this special route component
from React Router DOM, because you'll learned
that this is the component we use for defining routes.
Now, I also want to import Switch right away,
the Switch component,
because I know that I want to have only one act of route
at the same time.
And then here in this app component, instead of this div,
we can return Switch,
and inside of Switch to find our different routes.
Now every route then needs a path
for which it becomes active.
That's what you'll learned.
And if we have a route that should render a list of quotes,
that path could be /quotes.
And then here, we wanna output the quotes component
which we have yet to add.
Then I'll add another route here
with a path of, let's say,
/quotes/quoteId to render the detailed page for a quote.
Here we have a dynamic route, a dynamic path segment.
That's another key feature we learned about
so that we can load the same component for different quotes.
And we encode the quote identifier in the URL
so that we can get it inside of the loaded component.
Now, we also have to add a component here, which we render.
We don't have one yet, but before I added
I will add my last and third route here.
And that is a route that allows us to add a new quote.
So the path here could be new-quote
Now of course, all these paths are up to you.
It's your page.
And it simply depends on how you want your URLs
to look like.
Now, we have these free routes.
Now we need free page components.
And I do have this empty pages folder here already,
you can add such a folder as well, if you don't have it.
And in that folder,
I wanna create these special react components
which are responsible
for rendering the different pieces of data.
So in this pages folder, I'll add a new file
and that could be named AllQuotes.js
The file name is of course, up to you.
This will then hold my component
which displays all the quotes.
We can also add a SingleQuote or QuoteDetail.js file,
which will be used for that detail page
and a NewQuote.js file
which will hold dev for him for adding a new quote.
Now, for the moment I'll just add
basic component functions in there.
So in the AllQuotes.js file,
I'll add this component function here,
copy that and add it to NewQuote as well,
and then also added here to QuoteDetail
and just change the name.
Now we got these free component functions
and then the AllQuotes page,
we could return h1 tag, where we say, All Quotes Page
and then copy this into NewQuote
and say New Quote Page here
and copy it one more time into QuoteDetail
and hence say Quote Detailed Page here.
And now in App.js, we can use these free components
just as we learned that a couple of minutes ago.
We can import AllQuotes
from ./pages/AllQuotes.
We can import QuoteDetail
from ./pages/QuoteDetail
And we can import NewQuote
from ./pages/NewQuote
and then use these free components down here.
Here, we have the AllQuotes component,
here we have the QuoteDetail component
and here we have the NewQuote component.
And with that, we've finished the definition of our routes.
Now there's one thing missing though.
And do you remember what it is?
Well to use React Router,
it's not enough to just define those routes.
You also need to activate the router.
And you do that by wrapping your route component,
the app component in the index.js file
with this special BrowserRouter component.
So for this, we can import BrowserRouter
from React Router DOM,
and then wrap the app component
with this special BrowserRouter component, just like this.
Now we act away to the BrowserRouter.
And now if we save this,
if I reload my page on local host free thousand,
I see nothing.
But if I enter /quotes here
I see my All Quotes Page.
If I enter /quotes/q1
I also see the All Quotes Page.
And what could be causing this?
Why am I not seeing the Quote Detailed Page here?
Well, because you have to remember
how React Router matches your routes.
I mentioned that it goes
for your routes top to bottom and thanks to Switch,
it will then stop as soon as it has a match.
Now, when it comes to matching,
React Router by default looks at the beginning,
at the start of the path and then matches this here,
with the start of the actual URL path.
So if you are on /quotes/q1,
/quotes is definitely part of that path.
This path starts with /quotes.
So they offer here to avoid this
and to make sure that this route actually becomes active.
This second route, we can add this exact prop here
or we change the order.
That would be an alternative.
Here I'll work with the exact prop.
And if we add to this prop here
now I'm on the Quote Detail Page.
If I enter Q1 or Q2 or anything else after /quotes.
And if we visit /new quote
then I'm on the New Quote Page.
So that's now all working,
and with that, we already applied a lot
of the things we learned over the last lectures.
Now, as a next step, make sure
that you redirect from /nothing to /quotes
so that if we enter just my domain /nothing
we still get to the Quotes Page
and also make sure that in the QuoteDetail component.
So this component, you extract the actual quote ID
which is part of the URL,
and then simply log it to the console
or output that value on the screen.
We'll do it together in the next lecture
but definitely try it on your own first.