So let's now make sure that data can be added
or items can be added to the cart.
And for that, I wanna use context.
I wanna manage the overall cart data
through context because we will need it in different places
off the application.
On the meal items,
we need to update the cart and the cart component,
we need to output it, of course.
And we also will need to manage it
in the future because inside of that cart,
later the cart items can also be added or removed again.
So therefore let's start by setting up that cart context.
And for this, I'll add a store folder side by side
to the components and the assets folder.
The name is up to you
but since we are going to store our application
wide state here, store is kind of a convention
in React world
as a name for this application wide state management.
And in there, I'll add a cart-context JS file.
The naming of this file is up to you though.
In here, I will import React from react
because we can then call React, create context.
And I will initialize this context
with some default data, which will not actually be used
but which will give us better auto-completion later.
And here, we'll have an items array
since we are going to manage a couple of cart items.
We'll have a total amount, which is zero,
let's say initially,
and then we'll have two functions
which allow us to update that context.
And that's the add item function
which let's say receives the item that should be added.
And it's the remove item function,
which receives let's say an ID to identify the item
which should be removed from the cart like this.
Now I'll store this in a cart context constant
and I will export this cart context here.
So that's step number one.
Now we've got this context generally created
but now we will also need to manage that context
in some component with use state
or use reducer as you saw it earlier in this course
so that this context can also change
over time and can update parts of the application over time.
And we could do this in the same file here
but I will trade a new file for this
and name it cart provider JS.
Because in here I wanna add our cart provider component
which receives props and of course
which I export and the goal
of this component is simply to manage the current context
to data and provide that context
to all components that want access to it.
And for that here, I will import cart context
from ./cart-context and then return JSX code
because this is a component where I simply
access cartcontext.provider.
And now we can simply pass props.children
between cart context provider.
And this allows us to wrap any components
that should get access
to this context with this cart provider component.
And we can also add all the logic
for managing the context data to this component,
so that all about that is contained in one component
and no other component needs to deal with that.
Now for that, I will add a cart context
helper constant in this component function.
And that is simply an object with items total amount.
So all the fields we set up for the context itself,
this will be the concrete context value though
which will also be updated over time.
And this also holds pointers
for the add item function and for the remove item function.
And we can already add these functions here
and add a add item to cart handler here
where we get the item and then do something with it
in the future and the remove item from card handler function
where we get the ID and do something with it in the future.
And now it's simply point us at these functions
which are stored as values
for add item and remove item in this card context object.
And it's now discard context object here,
which is set as a value or as a value for the value prop
on the cart context provider component here.
And again, this will be dynamic soon.
It's not right now, but it will be dynamic soon.
And with that added,
we can now use this cart provider component
to wrap all components that need access to the cart.
And in our application,
that's actually all the components which are rendered
in the app component.
The cart of course needs access to render the cart items
and also to edit them later
the header needs access to update this batch
in the header button, this batch
where we output the number of cart items,
so the header also needs access to the cart
and the meals need access to the cart
because there we wanna add items to the cart.
So therefore we can replace this fragment here
with cart provider, as a wrapping component.
And of course we should now also import cart provider
from the store folder and then the cart provider file
and we can remove the fragment import.
Now, we could manage that entire context also
in the app JS file therefore,
since we needed an all the components there.
But by using a separate cart provider component,
we keep the app component lean
and don't have to put all the cart management
logic in there.
Simply imagine that you are working
on a bigger application with different app wide states.
Let's say you have a product state and a cart state
and a user state and anything like that.
If you would manage all
of that in the app component, it would become super large.
So having dedicated store components which manage that,
makes a lot of sense.
Now with that, we provide that context
to all of these components.
Now we can leverage it.
For example, in the header cart button,
there we need it to update the appropriate amount
of cart items in that batch.
And hence, what we can do,
is we can use the context in there.
So therefore, definitely try using that context on your own.
In the next lecture, we're going to do it together.