Now regarding the styling
of our components, we still use CSS,
but there is nothing too React specific
when it comes to that CSS code.
In the end, we can just add a new CSS file.
And typically for the CSS code of a given component
you add that file next to the component JavaScript file
and that would be the ExpenseItem.CSS file here.
Then you want to write your CSS code in there
but since this is no CSS course,
I don't want to bore you with writing a lot of CSS code
and hence you attached find a finished
ExpenseItem.CSS file, which you can simply download
and use or simply download it, open it,
and copy the code you find in there
into your ExpenseItem.CSS file.
Now back in ExpenseItem.js,
we need to do one important thing.
We need to make this overall build process
aware of that CSS file and tell it
that the CSS code in there should be considered
and should be injected in the finished application
because it's not by default browsing all your files
and automatically including everything,
you explicitly have to tell React, you could say,
or that build process that a certain file
should be considered.
For ExpenseItem.js, we did this
with this import and app JS.
For expenseItem.CSS, we need to do that
instead of ExpenseItem.js,
there we simply import ./ExpenseItem.CSS
just like that.
This simply tells the build process
that the CSS files should be considered.
Now instead that CSS file, I in the end,
just prepared a bunch of CSS classes
which can be added to elements to apply a certain look
and they are, for now, on this HTML code
in ExpenseItem in our component
we need to add these classes.
For example, on the wrapping div here.
Now there's one special thing here.
We don't type class here as we would do in regular HTML,
but instead className.
And this can be strange, but you have to keep in mind
that this here is not really HTML.
It looks like HTML, but it's this special
JSX syntex invented by the React team.
And in the end under the hood, it's still JavaScript code,
that's why most attributes are the same, but not all.
And here the class attribute was renamed to className
because class is a reserved word in JavaScript.
Technically it would still work
if you would use class here, but should use className.
Now here on this overall div, which wraps everything,
we then add the expense-item class here
On this div, which holds our title and our amount,
we add another of className,
which is expense-item__.
So here we got two underscores.
Description.
And then here on that div with the amount
we simply add className and then expense-item__price.
And if you now save everything,
it should look like this, which is definitely nicer.
Still not the final look you want,
but definitely nicer.
By the way, I'm super zoomed in here
to make this easier to read,
otherwise it would look something like this
and that's definitely also not great,
but again, it's not the final look.
Again, let me zoom in closer
so that we can better see that though.
Now that is how easy it is to add styling
to your React components though.
It's really not too fancy.
You have to be aware of the fact
that it's className instead of class,
but other than that, it's really just standard
CSS code, which then is added to your elements.
And in that CSS code, you can use
all the selectors you might know,
you're not limited to classes, but again,
I don't want to turn that into a CSS course,
so we'll keep that fairly simple.
This import might be the strangest thing in the end
because that is needed to make
this entire project aware of that CSS file.
And that's how we can style our components.