And that's it for this module.
Now you learned that React is able to talk to a backend
but not to a database directly
for a security and performance reasons.
But you can send requests to backend APIs
very often that will be rest APIs like we see it here.
And then you can, for example, use the fetch API
or a third-party libraries like X,
yes to perform that request.
And to then also get the response, analyze the response
and maybe throw and generate an error if it's needed
and or work with the data you get back
as part of the response.
You learned how you can send both get and post requests.
And you also learned how you can handle different States
which are involved with sending requests.
A loading and an error State.
And the we have no data State
as well as the we do have data State.
All of that is important
and allows you to build rich user experiences
which you want to have in most
of your applications of course,
because sending HDP requests is a crucial task.
And here in this demo, you learned how it generally works.