Now what we learned about funks
and funk action creators,
so these action creator functions here.
Now, did we learn about that,
let's build a app action creator that fetches the cart
when the application loads.
Because at the moment we're only sending data
but we never fetched data when the application load.
And therefore, if we reload, all our state is still lost
and that's of course not the goal.
Now we can ride that code in the component
or as action creator,
but here I now wanna stick to action creators
and hence we can add a second function cart slice.
But since this file is now getting bigger and bigger,
I'm a fan of creating a separate file for that.
Let's maybe name it cart-actions.js,
of course, the file name is up to you.
I'll then copy this sendCartData function,
cut it from cart-slice
and added it cart-actions
and now we need to import UI actions here.
So in cart-slice, I'll get rid of that import, cut that
and add that in cart-actions instead.
And in app.js, we therefore now need
to import sendCartsData
from store/cart-actions.
And then I'll add my app action creator function
in this cart-actions file as well.
So that could be the fetctCardData function
and I'll also export that
because we'll need it somewhere else as well.
And just as before that will immediately return a function
which gets dispatched as an argument
and then does something else.
Now here we could then also dispatch some notifications
if we want to do that,
but actually here I'll not do that.
Instead I'll create a new function, fetchData,
and have nested function which is async
because I'll use the fetch API
and I wanna wrap a fetchData with try catch it after
that's why I'm putting it into a separate function.
So then we await fetch action get a response here
and wanna fetch by sending a request
to that same URL again
but this time it should be a get request.
So we don't need to add this configuration object then
as a second parameter,
because I get request is the default, anyways.
Instead this time I am now interested in the data,
so in the result of calling await
response.Json
but of course, I also still wanna check
if the response is maybe not okay for whatever reason
and if that should be the case I'll throw a new error
where I say, "could not fetch cart data"
something like this.
Now, if we make it pass this line of code here though,
we have the data
and I will then return it here,
I'll return it here because
that is not a separate nested function.
Hence here I'll then try executing fetchData
and catch any errors we might be getting.
And if we get an error,
we still might wanna show the error in notification.
So I'll then dispatch this error notification action again
down here,
but I'll say, "fetching carts data failed."
If we however, are the try block or await fetchData,
I can do this
if I turned this into an async function, which we can,
Redux supports that,
that dysfunction which we returned here is async.
So we can use await here as well
and that gives me my cart data then
because I'm returning the data which we pass here
and there for now I wanna use that cart data to set my cart.
Now, the cart data we're fetching,
we'll have that format which is stored on Firebase
and that's the format which we're sending
to Firebase of course.
It will be this cart, which we're sending there
so it is an object with the items key,
with in an array inside and a total quantity key.
Which is exactly the format we need here
in our front-end as well.
Which is no surprise because we are sending
that Redux state snapshot
as data to the back and at the end.
So we automatically get back correctly formatted data here
and we don't need to transform that Firebase data first
because it has the format, we sent to Firebase earlier.
That's different from other sections in the course,
here we had to transform Firebase data
because there we used post for a sending our data
not put as we're doing here
and hence we let Firebase create a list of data
which turned out to be an object when we fetched it.
You might remember that from the HTTP section in the course
here with put we're sending our data snapshots to Firebase
and Firebase will take it as it is and store it like it is
without changing it.
So when we then fetch it, we also have to correct structure
and hence this cart data is correctly formatted
and therefore now, we can use this replace cart reducer,
which I provided to you earlier in this module
to replace our front-end cart
with the cart we're loading from Firebase
and replace cart expects a payload
which has a total quantity
and an items field which is exactly the data structure
we're fetching from Firebase.
So, in cart-actions, we just wanna import
our cart-actions
from the cart slice,
so these automatically generated actions now.
And here, I then wanna dispatch cart-actions replace,
not remove, replace cart
and pass my carts data as a payload,
which as mentioned has the correct structure already.
Now we could have done all to show to success notification
but I don't wanna do that, I just wanna use the cart data
and we're good to go.
With all that done, we now just need to call fetch cartData
somewhere in our application
to start fetching our cartData from Firebase.
And again, app.js is probably a good place for that.
Here we already have a user fact call
and that we wanna start fetching data here
if this application loads.
We could do that here in this isInitial check
because dad will only run if it's the first time
that this effect runs.
But I think it's cleaner to create a separate effect
which simply doesn't have any dependencies
and which therefore all they will only run
if this component was rendered for the first time
and since it's our main component
this will only render once.
And therefore here we can then dispatch
this new cart-action created, this custom cart-action.
So this fetchcartData action,
I wanna dispatch this here
and dispatch as a dependency for completeness sake
but as I said, that will never change,
so this effect will never rerun
and that will dispatch this whenever our application starts.
Hence if you saved this and reload you'll see
that this gets populated.
But you'll also notice that for some reason
we also see sent cart data successfully here
and we are sending a request to Firebase
for storing the cart data again.
So we're fetching it, as we can tell
we have our cart data here
and if I change it and reload,
we see we fetch that change to data,
but at the same time we seem to be sending it again.
And do you know why?
we are sending it again because in app.js
we have this effect for sending the cart data
which we'll execute whenever the carts changed.
The problem is when we fetched the carts data,
once fetching is done, we replaced a cart, right?
We replaced a cart
here with that fetched data,
that changes the cart inside of Redux.
Now, since that cart then changed
we triggered this app effect and send the cart data again.
So how can we now work around that?