So now we know how to style our components.
And again, we're definitely not done here,
this is not the final look I wanna have.
But before we dig deeper into tweaking the final look
and adding more UI elements,
let's think about one maybe obvious problem.
We will probably not just have one expense
and definitely not an expense
where the data is just hard coded
into the component as it is here.
The date is hard coded here,
the title is hard coded, the amount is hard coded
and it's the only expense we have.
In our final tracker we wanna have
an unlimited amount of expenses if we want to.
We want to have multiple expense item components in action.
And after all
that is one of the core ideas behind components.
It's not just a separation of concerns,
it's also there reusability.
We wanna define a component
and its HTML code once
and then we want to be able to reuse it.
And at the moment
we're not able to do that.
Therefore, that will be the next problem we'll work on.
But before we work on that
there's another problem which we have to solve first.
And that's something I just mentioned,
that all that data is hard coded here in this JSX code.
This is unrealistic, some data may be hard coded sometimes
but here for an expense item,
something like the date and the title
and the amount would typically be dynamic,
which means it's not hard coded in the HTML code.
Instead we receive that data from somewhere,
for example from the user who entered it into a form
and we then output it dynamically.
Now for the moment we don't have the capabilities yet
to receive it from the user,
but we can fake dynamic data
by at least adding more
than just HTML code to this component.
Because after all, we must not forget
that a component in React is just a function.
And that earlier I mentioned
that components are the combination of HTML,
to some extent CSS and also JavaScript.
Now we definitely see HTML in action.
We also saw some CSS being added
but where's the JavaScript?
Other than that being a function.
Well, let's add some JavaScript code in that function
before we return.
For example, let's add a constant,
so a variable which may never change
and in there let's store a date
by using the built in date constructor
which comes with JavaScript.
Let's give this constant a name,
for example expense date, sounds like a fitting name.
And then let's maybe set an initial date value here
which is the year 2021,
March as a month.
And since the month field here starts at zero,
March has the number two
and then there the 28th.
This is how we can create such a date object
and this, and that's really important to me
is just regular JavaScript,
has nothing to do with React.
And we can and we typically do
have JavaScript code like this in our components
here just to create some dummy data later in the course
and in your React applications
that could be any kind of code.
For example to send a HTTP request
and fetch data from a database, to validate user input
or to do any other kind of task.
So here we have our expense date,
we can also have our expense title here
which is maybe car insurance.
So a simple string stored in this constant
and then our expense amount,
which is let's say a number 294
dot 67.
So we have these three constants,
regular JavaScript code.
And we now wanna output these values here
in this HTML code.
And that is a typical task,
typically you don't have data hard coded in HTML.
Instead to output dynamic data
you use a special syntax React gives you
inside of these JSX code snippets.
You can replace hard coded data
with opening and closing curly braces.
Single curly braces opening and closing.
And the special thing about these curly braces
inside of your JSX code snippets
is that in these curly braces between them,
you can run basic JavaScript expressions.
For example, one plus one,
you can execute something like this there
and it's now the result of this expression
which will be output on the screen.
So if I run one plus one between curly braces here,
we see two.
We can also do something like
math random here
and generate a random number with the built in math object.
And we see the number here
and every time I reload
I get a new number of course.
Now that's something we can do.
Now here. I don't wanna get a random number,
I don't wanna add one plus one.
Instead, I want to refer to the value stored
in this constant.
And therefore we can just repeat that constant name here.
This is also a valid JavaScript expression
just pointing at a variable or a constant.
In this case a constant.
And now JavaScript will extract the value
stored in this constant
and basically inject it here
into this HTML code, so to say.
So if I now save that,
we again see car insurance here just like before
but now it's not hard coded in the HTML code
but instead here its output dynamically
and the concrete value is taken from that constant.
There of course it's still hard coded,
but it's just a first step.
Now we can do the same for the amount.
So here after the dollar sign
which I will leave hard coded for now.
We can point at expense amount
and for the date we can do something similar.
Here we can output expense date,
though for the date we have to keep in mind
that it's a date object.
And therefore if we try to save it like this
it just breaks.
Because this being a date object
it can't be output as texts like this.
However, we can call to ISO string for example,
a built in method available on all date objects
to output it as a string
and now we see this at least.
Not super readable
but a first step.
Now we will refine and fine tune
the way this is being output later.
For the moment we just achieved
one important thing.
We now no longer work
with hard coded text in our HTML code
but instead we have these dynamic placeholders,
you could say.
Where the concrete value can be the result of a calculation
of a HTTP requests or as it is here at the moment
the value stored in a constant or variable.
And now with that out of the way
we can move on
and we can take a closer look
at how we can make this expense item more reusable.
So that it's not always the same data
which we're outputting.
And so that we can have multiple expense items
based on one of the same component with different data.