[Maximilian Schwarzmüller] So with useReducer
out of the way,
let's dive into a different problem you might face
in bigger React applications specifically,
but even in this tiny demo here, we already have it,
that can be solved in a more elegant way.
I'm talking about a problem, in quotes,
where you are passing a lot of data
through a lot of components via props.
And a good example here is our isLoggedIn state
and the login functions.
We're managing this state in the app component
because I lifted this state up to that component
because we basically need this state,
this isLoggedIn state and the functions to change it
everywhere in this application.
We use the logged in state in the header
to which I'm passing it through the isAuthenticated prop.
From there, we are able to logout.
So I passed the pointer at the logoutHandler
to my header on the onLogout prop.
And we also need the login state
to render different content here,
either the login or the home component,
and to those components,
I also passed the logoutHandler or the loginHandler.
Now the logoutHandler being passed to the home component,
that's something I'm doing here
so that we theoretically could add a button there
with our button component, for example,
to allow the user to logout there as well.
Not something we need in this app,
but something you could add here with props on logout
since we're getting a pointer to this handler anyways.
And if you do that, once you login here,
you all have the logout button here.
So long story short, we need, or we use this login state
in a lot of different places in the app.
Now, obviously this is a very, very, very simple app,
a very simple demo,
and here passing our state around like this
is not a huge problem.
Now it is quite common that you pass data
to components through props,
but it's always a problem if you forward state
through multiple components.
So if you basically just leverage props to forward data
to another component.
And that's actually something we're doing
in the main header.
Here in the app component,
I'm passing isLoggedIn through the isAuthenticated prop
to main header.
And I'm passing the logoutHandler
through the onLogout prop to the main header as well.
Now in the main header though,
I'm using neither of those two props.
I'm using them only to forward them again
to the navigation component
because it's the navigation component in the end,
which needs the isLoggedIn data
to render different links and which needs the
onLogout prop and the logoutHandler therefore,
to do something when the logout button is clicked.
So essentially what I'm doing here, is in the main header
I'm receiving props,
I'm receiving data through props
which I'm not actually using primarily in the main header.
Instead, I just forward that data.
That's not necessarily a problem,
but in big apps, that chain of forwarding
might become longer and longer.
Consider this example of a fictional app.
We could have an app with an app component,
with, let's say, an auth section,
with a login form,
with a shop section where we have a list of products
in which we render individual product items,
and with a cart.
Now in the login form,
we might have the login event when the user fills
out the form and submits the form,
and we validate the data and find out
that the user is logged in.
And we might need that login data,
So the login status,
the information that the user is logged in
in different parts of the app.
We might need it in the shop.
We might need it in the cart,
to show the cart to avoid that the user can go there
if he or she is not logged in.
It's easy to imagine that we need information
about the login status in different parts of the app.
And we have something similar.
Let's say the user adds a product to the cart.
We need that information in the cart component
to show the product there, for example.
But since the product is a direct child of products,
which is a child of shop, which is a child of app.
And since the login event happens in the login form,
which is a child of auth, which is a child of app,
we don't have those direct connections
to the other components where the data might be needed.
If a user clicks a button in the product component
to add a product to the cart,
the information needs to reach the cart component
but there is no direct connection
between the product component and the cart component.
And the same for the login.
And therefore, what we typically would do is
we would use props to pass a function handler
to the login form, for example,
so that in there we can call it.
But that essentially means
that we're forwarding data through our different components.
And the same, of course, if we add something to the cart.
Now, that means that this function that should be triggered
when the user adds something to the cart
would probably be managed in the app component,
because we lifted the state up to the level
where we have access to both the product component,
indirectly,
and the card component.
And that's only the case in the app component.
Only this component has at least indirect connections
to both components, product, and cart.
And therefore we would forward a pointer
to the add to cart function
through all those other components,
the shop component and the products component,
even though those components probably don't need
that function.
They only need it so that they can forward it
to the product component in the end.
So in the end here,
we have the same problem I described here
just on a larger scale.
Here, it's a very simple app
but even here we are forwarding data
through the main header to the navigation component
on props we receive in the main header
even though we don't really need the data there.
So therefore, in bigger apps,
you could easily build such prop chains,
which are used to forward data through components
to other components.
That's something you can do, and that's not necessarily bad
but the bigger your app gets,
the more inconvenient it is to do that.
Instead, it would be nicer if we could use props
in a component to only receive the data
this component really needs from its parent,
and not to forward our data through the parent
which the parent doesn't ever manage nor need itself.
And for that we got a component-wide,
"behind the scenes", State Storage, built into React.
We have a concept called React Context,
and this then allows us to, for example, trigger a action
in that component-wide State Storage,
and then directly pass that to the component
that is interested without building such a long prop chain.
And that allows us to solve our problem
in a more elegant way here.
So let's take a closer look at this now.