Let's dig deeper into Redux.
Up to this point, we only dispatched simple actions.
They only had a type, nothing else.
In reality, you often wanna dispatch actions
that also carry an extra value.
Let's say we wanna add a new button
to the counter component, which says increase by 5.
We could, of course also had a decreased button
but let's stick to the increase button for now.
Now, even though it has this label
it of course only increases this by one
because I still just call the incrementHandler here
and dispatch increment.
Of course, we could now go to the store
and prepare our Reducer for another action type
which is increaseby5
where we then return our updated state,
where we increase the state.counter by 5.
But that's not scalable.
We can't predict all possible values
we might wanna support.
The counter of course is just a dummy example.
But if you're using this in a real project,
which we'll do later in the course,
and you need to work with any user input, for example,
you can't hard-code those values here in your Reducer.
Instead, the action which we dispatch
and which reaches the Reducer
often needs to carry extra data.
So that, for example, we have a increase action type here
and that action type
does not increase the counter by a fixed number,
but instead we expect to get the value
by which you wanna increase from the action.
In there we could say that we expect
to get the value property or have an amount property
or whatever it is.
And then we wanna increase by that.
That would be a reasonable expectation.
And that's of course, a very common scenario
hence Redux and React Redux supports it.
Back in the counter, we can now add a new function here,
the increaseHandler, and in there we again wanna dispatch,
but now the action which we wanna dispatch
will not just have a type.
It will have one as the type is increase
but it cannot also get an extra payload,
extra data which it carries.
For example, an extra amount property.
And this property name is entirely up to you.
It's your action.
It's your action object.
You can add whichever properties you want.
So here I'll add an amount property
and set amount to 5 here.
Of course 5 is therefore still hard-coded
here in this function, but that's just a demo.
Of course, this value could be coming
from an input field.
Here it's hard-coded
but now we can point at the increaseHandler here.
Now we add this extra payload to the action
and in our store, in the Reducer function,
when the type is increased,
we do expect this amount field on the action.
Therefore, of course, you need to make sure
that the property you're accessing here,
on the action in the Reducer,
has exactly the same name
as the property you add to the action when you dispatch it.
Otherwise you won't be able to extract this data.
Hence now, if we save this and reload this,
we do increase by five, but now this is very flexible.
We can easily change this to 10 and for completeness sake,
change the button text to 10 as well.
And now we increase by 10.
It works just like that because now the Reducer is dynamic.
It extracts an action payload.
And action payloads are very common, often needed,
and as you see, it's super easy to add them.
It's just an extra property which you add
to your action objects.