So, now our cart is working correctly
and we learned a lot about where to put code
how to run async code with Redux
and how to handle side effects.
And we spent a lot of time on that
because it is an important topic
and knowing your options there is extremely important.
I can't emphasize this enough.
It's important to understand how that works.
But besides handling async tasks and side effects with Redux
and understanding where to put our code
there was another important topic
I wanted to have a look at in this module.
And that would be the Redux Devtools.
These are extra tools which we can use
which make debugging Redux and our Redux state a bit easier.
Because in more complex applications
with a lot of Redux state handled
by a lot of different slices
and a lot of different actions going on
it can be difficult to find errors in your debug state
in the order of your actions and so on.
And sometimes it might be interesting to look
into the current state of your overall Redux store
without having to dive into different parts
of the UI to verify that everything works correctly.
And that is what we can use the Redux Devtools for.
You can simply search for Redux Devtools
and you'll find a GitHub repository
about the Redux Devtools
and the Redux Devtools can be used
and installed as a browser extension.
You can always install them as a stand alone app
but I personally find the browser extension easiest to use.
So, here I'm on Chrome
so I'll pick that Chrome browser extension
and here you can install this Chrome extension.
Now, I already do have it installed.
You can install it with a click of a button
and once you did so, you will be able to use it right away.
When using Redux without Redux toolkit
you had to set up some extra code
to make Redux Devtools work.
With Redux tool kit it will conveniently work out of the box
and you should then have access to that extension.
Now, here I have an in cognitive tab open
and there I don't have access to my extensions
so, I'll quickly run the application
in a standard Chrome tab again
and when I do so I have this Redux Devtools icon here
or in the browser Devtools
you also should find Redux here as an option.
And if you open that
it will open this Redux Devtools panel here
and now here, you have insights into your Redux store
into your actions and much more.
On the left side, you for example, see the actions
that were dispatched.
And if I reload, we see that's in it and replace cart.
In it, is this automatically dispatched first action
that applies all your initial states to Redux
so that initializes the store
and replace card was dispatched
because we fetched the card initially.
Now, if I add something to the card, you see
add item to cart was dispatched
and our show notification actions which makes sense
because these are all the actions
which are being dispatched when we add an item.
First add item to cart it's dispatched
and when that card state then changed
user App.js kicks in and dispatches send card data
that's not locked because that itself is not an action type
but instead as part of send card data
we then do dispatch these notification actions
which is why we see them here as well.
And you can click on those actions to get insights
into the data that was transported by that action
and how that changed your state.
You see the data, if you click on action
there you see the payload off the action
and this unique identifier.
Here, we can also see
the automatically created unique identifiers
Redux toolkit gives us
as you see it's basically your slice name.
So, in card it's this slice name
and then the method name of this reducer method
that is the unique identifier created by Redux toolkit
and then here we have our payload.
We also see how the state looks like there after.
So, how the state looks after this action was performed
and we see how it was updated if we click on diff.
Therefore add item to cart
we see that the total quantity was changed from six to seven
changed one set from false to true and in the items
we see that the quantity of that first item changed
and so on.
So, that's super useful to understand the impact
of your actions.
You can even do something which is called time traveling.
You can jump to an older state like this one
by clicking on it and then clicking on jump
and you see now the notification is gone
and we're back to the card with six items.
And we can then start debugging here again if we want to
and we can then also jump back
to a newer state if we want to.
So, that can be really convenient
and therefore the Redux Devtools are a piece of software
I can only encourage you to use and play around with
to get deeper insights into your Redux store
and to debug your Redux behavior
and fully understand what's going on.