Were are you successful?
I really recommend that you have a look
at those last lectures again
to fully understand how you manage entered values, validity
and touched state,
and combine that all with different event handlers,
to make sure that you deliver the user experience
you wanna deliver.
Now, here in this case,
I will continue with that finished custom hook,
which we built already.
I will not build up that entire logic again from scratch
because I feel like I would basically
just be wasting your time if I did that
because it's just what we did in the previous lectures
but I do want to apply to custom hook here one more time
to really show you how you could do that
in a brand new empty form.
And therefore, if we start by importing user input from
going up one level hooks/use-input
and we then of course call useInput here.
And we call it free times because we have free inputs here.
Now, the validation logic for these free inputs
is up to you.
I didn't give you any restrictions or guidance there
but it makes sense to ensure that these inputs aren't empty
and that the email address is an email address.
So for that, for the first two inputs,
I'll check if the value we're getting is not empty,
if we trim it.
And since I'll use the same function here,
wrap it and copy and pasting it like this,
I will create a new function
outside of the component function
because that's not a function that needs to be rebuilt
if the component is rebuilt
and I will name it isNotEmpty,
store my function in this constant
and then just pass this constant here
which holds this function in the end.
So this is really just the function outsourced
into a separate constant
and I can do something similar for the email
isEmail and here I get a value
and check that this includes an @ symbol.
And then I pass his email to the third user input call.
Now the custom hook returns an object as we learned
and that object is full of data which we can use.
For example, it contains the value
and we might wanna use the value here
to be able to reset it once the form is submitted.
So here, this is for my first input,
I'll have the first name value,
then we get IsValid.
So this is firstNameIsValid
and I'm assigning these aliases here
because I'm going to extract the same keys two more times.
So we need aliases to avoid name clashes.
And here we also get to the value change handler
which I'll alias with firstNameChangeHandler.
I get the inputBlurHandler, which I pulled out
which I alias with firstNameBlurHandler
and the reset function,
which I'll alias with resetFirstName like this.
And then I'll copy this here this code
and repeats these here for the second user input call.
But of course here it's the last name value
and the last name is valid
and here it's there for all his lastNameChangeHandler
and lastNameBlurHandler and resetlastName
and then copy and paste it one more time
for the last input and that's the email value
and the emailIsValid
and here it's the emailChangeHandler
and the emailBlurHandler and here is resetEmail.
And now with that all done,
we can go down to the JSX code
and on the first input,
for example bind our firstNameValue,
for onChange we bind firstNameChangeHandler,
and for on blur, we bind the firstNameBlurHandler like this.
Then for the second input,
we bind value to lastNameValue onChange
to lastNameChangeHandler
and on blur unsurprisingly to lastNameBlurHandler.
And then here for this input,
I bind my value to emailValue onChange
to the emailChangeHandler
and onBlur to the emailBlurHandler.
Now, I also wanna show error messages if appropriate
and I wanna show different class names
or add different class names.
And I also want to disable the submit button
if the form is invalid.
So let's start with the class names and the error texts.
For this there's one other field we can extract
and that's the hasError field,
which I'll store in firstNameHasError alias,
and here on the second use input called
its last name has error
and here on the third custom hook you search
it's emailHasError.
And it's this HasError field, which we can now use
because now we can infer those class names for example.
Here I have my firstNameClasses
and for that I'll take my firstNameHasError key.
And if I have an error,
I'll add a class of form-control invalid,
otherwise just form-control
and all I will repeat this error for lastNameClasses
and emailClasses.
And here we then have to lastNameHasError
and emailHasError.
And then here we bind our firstNameClasses
and we'll the second div, we bind the lastNameClasses
and on that last div we bind the emailClasses.
Now for the error messages,
we simply go to the first input
where we might need an error message like,
Please enter first name.
And here we check if firstNameHasError
and if that's the case we showed as paragraph otherwise not.
And I then copied that logic to the second input
where I say, Please enter a last name
and I checked for lastNameHasError
and we copied one more time to the email address
where I check for emailHasError
and I said, Please enter a valid email address.
So now that's all wired up.
Now for the overall foreign validity,
we can again derive that state,
we can add a formIsValid state, which initially is false.
And then we check if the firstNameIsValid
and the lastNameIsValid
and the emailIsValid and all three have to be valid.
And only if they are all free valid,
I'll set formIsValid to true.
If at least one of them is not valid,
the form will stay invalid.
So now we have the formIsValid state
we can use that to disable the button for example,
to set disabled to not formIsValid.
If the form is not valid, the button is disabled.
Last but not least for the form submission
which I also wanna add here,
I'll add the onSubmitHandler
and then simply add a new function here,
submitHandler could be the name where I get an event.
And as you learned, we call event.preventDefault here
to prevent that browser default of sending a request.
And then I check if the form is not valid
and if it's not valid, I return
and that's by the way new,
in simple input I didn't do that,
in the form submission handler
there I was still checking for the entered name only
and that was an oversight from my side
but of course we can't even reach that handler
since the button is disabled anyways.
Nonetheless, adding that extra check here might make sense
because the user could theoretically enable the button
with the def tools,
which of course is not really what the user should do,
but it could be done.
So having the extra validation step in here
still also could make sense.
And then they're after if the form is valid
and we made it past to this check,
I will console.log Submitted
and then all the console.log my values.
So the firstNameValue
the lastNameValue and the emailValue.
And then I will call resetFirstName,
resetLastName and resetEmail.
Now we can wire up the submit handler here
and we should be good to go.
If we save everything and go back here,
the button is grayed out by default.
If I click in there, I get this error
and this error and this error
and the errors are not red
because I forgot to assign the right CSS class here.
On these paragraphs we should add a CSS class of error-text.
So make sure you add this on the firstNameError paragraph
and the lastName paragraph and the emailError paragraph.
Now they are red.
And of course if I enter valid values here,
then this becomes submittable
and if you open the def tools and I click Submit
I see Submitted, I see the entered values and its reset.
And again, it's working as before now.
So this is looking good now
and now we applied our custom hook
and what we learned to this new form as well.