So this was a lot of content about animations in react.
As I mentioned, there are more libraries you can look into and actually you could fill an entire course
with content just about react animations.
The key takeaways are that
you should always think about css animations and transitions.
A lot of things can be achieved with just these and even if you fall back to libraries like react transition
group, as you saw behind the scenes you still work a lot with css transitions,
you just have a javascript layer to orchestrate the addition of these different css styles.
That's the key takeaway I want you to have in this module
and then it's up to you which javascript library you use, react transition group,
the one I presented here is nice because it gives you a nice little javascript layer you can add to
your application to
as I mentioned, orchestrate your css animations. You can look at packages like react motion if you want
a more css independent solution which still behind the scenes uses css but which emulates real
world physics
in the case of react motion and which therefore might give you the look you're looking for. These are the
things I want you to take away from this module,
it's of course as always about practicing these things, maybe adding them to the burger builder or your personal
next react project. As mentioned at the beginning of this module, animations can be very important at guiding
user attention and providing a nice user experience and I hope that with the tools presented in this
module,
you have a good well toolset for building and orchestrating these animations.