Now we practiced those core basics again.
One very basic feature is missing though
and that would be links.
At the moment we can only navigate around
by manually changing the URL.
Now I want to add some navigation
and whilst you can definitely also do this on your own,
I would recommend that we do it together,
because I want to build a brand new component
with a specific styling.
And hence, that will be easier if we do it together here.
But definitely feel free to also pause here
and build your own basic dummy navigation
which allows you to switch between the quotes,
and NewQuote page.
We'll work on getting to the Quote-ID page
a little bit later.
Now to build it together though,
I'll dive into that layout folder,
and here I prepared two CSS files for two components
which we'll add together.
The first component will be a main navigation component
which I'll store in the MainNavigation JS file.
As the name suggests, the job of this component will be,
to render a main navigation bar.
So in here, I'll add a regular component
MainNavigation component function,
as we did it many times before in this course.
And then here in this component, I want to return a header.
And in that header, I want to have a div,
which holds my logo text
which could be Great Quotes or anything like this.
And next to that div, I'll add a nav element
which will then store an onward list
with a couple of lists items,
where every list item should hold a link.
Now we'll need some styling here,
and therefore I'll import classes
from ./MainNavigation.module.CSS.
So from that CSS file, which I already provided to you.
And then on that header,
you should add a className of classes.header,
on that div you can add a className of classes.logo.
And these are all predefined CSS classes
which you find in this CSS file, which I provided to you.
And on the nav element, it's classes.nav.
Now for these list items, as I just mentioned
I want to have links in there.
And you did learn that having an anchor tag is not optimal.
At least not if you add it like this,
because that would then trigger the browser default,
of sending a new request.
And we don't want that.
Instead, we learned that React Router,
gives us specific components
which we can use for rendering links.
And there we have the Link component for a standard link
and the NavLink component for a standard link
which also gets a specific CSS class, if it's active.
And here I'll use that NavLink.
And then in this first list item,
we can add a NavLink,
with a text off All Quotes between the NavLink components,
which leads to /quotes, for example.
And I'll also set the activeClassName prop here
to classes.active, so that this link gets
the active CSS class, if it is active.
And of course that is a class which I use in this CSS file.
Now I'll repeat this entire list item
and add a second list item where we could say,
Add a Quote, and this then leads to /newquote.
And with that, we should have the finished MainNavigation.
Now we could add this main navigation here
in the App JS file, above to Switch statement
but I will actually also add another component
the Layout component, which I'll store
in a Layout JS file in that Layout folder.
This will be a very simple component.
I'll again create it as a Functional Component
and export it like this.
And here I'll also import classes
from ./layout.module.css file using
that existing CSS file, which you find here.
Now, the goal of this component is,
to render the MainNavigation side by side
with the actual page content.
And for this I'll return a Fragment
since I want to have adjacent JSX elements.
Fragment is imported from React of course
and then here we can render the MainNavigation.
And for that make sure that you import MainNavigation,
this MainNavigation component we just worked on,
from that MainNavigation file.
And side by side to it,
I'll add a Main element which gets a class
of classes.main, and here I then want to render
the actual page content.
Now, of course the actual page content is determined
in the App JS file by these Routes still.
But we also learned in this course
what we can do in this case.
I want to use Layout as a wrapper
around this Switch statement here in the end
so that whatever Route is chosen rendered,
it's wrapped by the Layout.
And we can create such wrapper components
by using props and to be precise props.children.
And then we can go to App.JS and import, Layout from
./components/layout/layout,
and then simply wrap Layout
around this Switch statement here.
And if we do all of that and you save all files
you should know have this navigation.
And you see that the active link is highlighted.
It's a bit whiter than the inactive link,
so we can switch and that highlighting changes.
And now if I go to quotes/sum-id,
we also have to quote detail page here.
And if I then add /comments we also have that here.
And now the form isn't as big anymore.
Now that's still all not working,
and that's of course it's not the final page
but it's one step closer.