Now let's talk about the objects
which we are returning in our reducer, in our Redux reducer.
I mentioned in the last lecture that we always
return a brand new snapshot, a brand new state object
which Redux will use to replace its existing state with.
So the objects which we return
in the reducer will not, and that's super important
will not be merged with the existing state.
They will overwrite the existing state.
So if we, for example going set
show counter here when we incremented
because before it got to add it here, if we do this
if I click increment, you see I close my counter.
I closed my counter when I click increment even
though I shouldn't, because I don't set show counter here
hence it's basically removed from the object
and it has a value of undefined therefore
an undefined is treated as false.
So we don't render to counter then.
And that's of course a side-effect, which we don't want.
That's an error.
So we must always set all the other states
when we update a piece of state
because we overwrite the old state.
Now that brings up one question.
Why do we need to return a new piece of data here?
Why can't we just use the state
which we're getting as an argument, access counter
and increment it like this, instead of returning?
Or maybe we do it like this, and then we return state.
And when we do that, we changed state before we return it.
And then we just return it again.
Well, if we do that and we reload, everything works.
So it's not easy to see that this is wrong,
but it is, even though it works.
This is something you absolutely must not do
when working with Redux.
You should never super important never
mutate the state, the existing state.
You should never change the existing state.
Instead, always override it
by returning a brand new state object.
And because objects and arrays are reference values
in JavaScript, it's easy to accidentally override
and change the existing state.
You could for example think that
you can do something like this.
And then you return a new object where you then
do set to counter to state.counter
and show counter to state.showcounter.
We can do this because we changed the counter here.
And then we returned a brand new object.
Everything's good, right?
Well, again, that will work.
If I reload, it works, but it's still super bad
because we still mutate the existing state because objects
and arrays are reference values in JavaScript.
And in case it's not clear to you What I mean by that.
Attached you find a link which leads you
to an article and a video where I explained this in depth.
Now, when working with redux and it's state
you must never mutate state like this
never changed the original state which you're getting.
This can lead to bugs, unpredictable behavior
and it can make debugging your application harder as well.
So even though it doesn't lead to a bug here
it can have unwanted and unexpected side effects
in bigger applications where your state gets out of sync.
And suddenly the UI is not reflecting your state
correctly anymore.
And hence the simple rule is never
mutate your state like this.
Always return a brand new object
where you copy any nested objects or erase.
If you have any and create brand new values
as we're doing it here.
By updating our state like this
we create a brand new object where we don't change anything.
And especially when you have a state
with nested objects and arrays
it's easy to accidentally mutate your existing state.
And therefore you should be super careful
that you do this in an immutable way
that you'd never accidentally mutate your existing state
but you copy any objects which you added.
So you always create a brand new object or array.
Whenever you need to update data
you never just dive into an existing object
and start manipulating its properties.
Always copy and create new objects.
Now, at this point it might look a little bit too early
to emphasize it like this,
because this is a fairly simple state here
but it is super important, easy to mess up
and something you should know right from the start
which is why I am emphasizing it here.