So lets explore the useContext Hook.
For that here,
I will actually remove
this code, I will
remove to Consumer.
Like this.
And therefore I'm back to my
old navigation Component
but of course now
I'm referring to that
CTX object which simply
doesn't exist anymore.
Now we are still importing
AuthContext, and we can
use it again.
Now by importing a
Hook from React,
and that's the useContext Hook.
Another Hook that's built into React.
And it does what the name implies,
it allows us to use the Context,
it allows us to tap into a Context
and listen to it.
Using it is simple,
you call useContext in your React Component Function,
and you pass the Context appointer at
the Context you want to use to it.
So in our case, I'm pointing to AuthContext.
Now what you get back, is the Context value.
So here...
I'll store this in a CTX Constant
to make my code down there worth again.
And with that,
we can save this.
And it will again, work just fine.
Simply, because I'm using the useContext Hook.
Easy like that.
Simple like that.
This is all we need to do
and this, of course
I would say it's a bit more
elegant and a bit nicer
than using AuthContext Consumer,
which you...
However, just to make this clear,
are always allowed to use.
It's not wrong or anything like that.
This is just a bit more elegant
in my opinion.