So we're using useContext
to pass the isLoggedIn state
to my other components here.
That's great.
But of course you will notice
that we're still forwarding the onLogout prop
or the logoutHandler function through props
and that's of course still not ideal.
It would be nicer if we could use the MainHeader like this.
So without passing any data to it
because we don't need to forward onLogout.
But of course at the moment this would not work.
This would mean at the moment
that we're simply not able to log out
because we're not passing our logoutHandler.
So hammering the log out button here
in the navigation wouldn't do anything.
The good thing is we can set up a dynamic context
where we don't just pass data
to our components but also functions,
which technically of course owes this data,
but still you get my point.
Here all we need to do is
in our AuthContext.Provider
where we set up the value
besides passing down isLoggedIn.
We can also pass down,
let's say onLogout
where we point at the logoutHandler
just like this.
If I do that
and make sure you don't execute it
you just wanna point at the function.
If I do that,
then every listening component
every component that listens to Auth context
we'll be able to utilize logoutHandler here
simply through the onLogout context value.
So therefore back in Navigation
where we are referring to props.onLogout
We can now simply do ctx.onLogout.
And then this will work,
because on the context object
we now have the onLogout value.
So if you save that,
now logging out works again.
And of course the rest of the app also works just fine,
as you can tell.
So this now all works again
with the help of context
where you cannot just pass down values
like strings objects and so on
but where you can also pass down functions
and therefore now, we're using this app-wide
or component-wide context object
to manage our state and to manage the function
that changes the state.
Hence we don't need props
in the navigation component anymore
and we can remove it.
And you now have a great example for using context.
Now here in my main section here,
I will still pass down the logoutHandler through onLogout
and the loginHandler through onLogin
because I directly use those handlers
in the Login and Home components.
You see in the Login component
we directly refer props.onLogin
where we're not forwarding it
We're using it here.
And the same into Home component.
I'm directly using onLogout here.
Sure, we're technically forwarding it
to our own Button component
but this is a pure presentational component.
And this here is actually fine.
I don't wanna use context inside of my Button
to always bind Button onclicks to onLogout
because whilst this would remove the need
to pass onLogout like this,
it would also mean
that our Button is now always logging the user out
and not able to do anything else upon a click.
And this all just shows you when to use props.
And when to use context.
In most cases,
you will use props to pass data to components
because props are your mechanism to configure components
and to make them reusable.
Only if you have something which you would forward
through a lot of components
and you're forwarding it to a component
that does something very specific.
Like for example, the Navigation
where this button will always log the user out.
In such cases, you wanna consider context.
And as with everything in programming
with more experience it will also
of course become clearer and more natural
when to use what.
You can of course always rely on prop chains
if you prefer that,
but context allows you to write more concise code
and it often makes managing
such app-wide state simply a bit easier.