Now that we got
our first basic pages in place
before we add more route features,
let's add some data, some dummy data
which we can output for now
and I'll start
in the all quotes page.
In there I wanna output a list of quotes
and a little bit later
in this section,
we're going to fetch those quotes
from a server
for the moment let's work with
some dummy quotes here,
some dummy data
which I just defined here
in a constant.
It should be an array of quotes
and every quote should be an object
with an ID.
Any ID you want like Q1.
Then we also want to have
an author field
and here I'll just use my name
and a text field with,
well the actual text of the quote,
for example, learning React is fun
and then I'll copy that
and create the number code
with a different ID
and a different author,
because that's me with my full name
and the quote is,
learning React is great.
Now that's just some dummy data here.
Now the goal is to output that data
and that starting project,
which I've provided to you
does have a quote list component.
This quote list component
in the end just renders
an unordered list here
and that unordered list
renders a bunch of quote items
and a quote item looks like this.
Now they offer in all quotes.
I wanna output that quote list
and hence we should first of all
import this quote list component
from going up one level,
diving into components,
quotes, quote list
and then here in all quotes,
instead of returning this H one tag,
I'll return quote list
and now this quote list component
in the end wants a quotes prop,
because I'm accessing that quotes prop
inside of quote list
and hence here I'll set
quotes equal to my dummy quotes here.
If I do that and save this,
then on the all quotes page
we should see these two quotes
and we have these quote items
with these buttons,
which at the moment don't do anything.
If we click them, nothing happens
but that is a first step.
Now, if I do click
such a item link here,
if I do click view full screen,
I of course wanna load
the quote detail page for that quote
and we'll implement that
in the next step
before we do that
let's go to add a quote
and also work on this page.
This page should display a form,
a form which allows us
to add a new quote later
and for this I did prepare
this quote form component
in the components folder.
It is a component
which renders a form
and which also then has this
submit form handler function
which doesn't do anything
except for trigger a function
which it expects to get
on the on add quote prop
to which it then passes
this entered data.
So in the component
where we use quote form
we wanna pass a function
to the quote form component
on that on ad quote prop,
which expects this data
hence here in the new quote page
we wanna use that quote form component.
So we can import quote form
from components, quotes, quote form
and then output this year instead,
the quote form
and now here, we need to pass this
on add quote prop
which I just talked about
which we expect
instead of the quote form component
and as a value,
we wanna pass a function,
a function which
expects this quote data.
So here in the
new quote page component
I'll add a new function,
the add quote handler function
for example, where I expect
to get some quotes data
and where we then later
we'll sent this to a server
for the moment
I'll just console lock
the quote data here
and then it's this function,
a pointer at this function
which we passed to quote form.
With that if we save this
we have this form here
on this new quote page.
So as that this page
and this demo project
is slowly taking shape.
Now let's make sure
that clicking on the view full screen.
So on such a quote item
on this link here,
that clicking on this link
actually loads this quote detail page
and definitely try
implementing this on your own.
Try implementing a link here
which loads the detail page
for the different quotes.
So which respects
the different quote IDs in the URL.
We're going to implement this together
and finish this quote detail page
at least the first draft
in the next lecture.