So lots of TypeScript concepts
are already at work here.
And as mentioned before
if you wanna learn about all those concepts in depth
you definitely wanna check out the official TypeScript docs
or some other types of resources.
For example off course,
also my complete TypeScript course which I have.
But now let's dig a bit deeper here,
we got this basic Todos component here
which outputs these TodoItems here.
Now, very often for that
we would now have a separate Todo component
so that this list item here
is in a separate Todo component
because in reality it often might be more complex
than just li opening and closing tack
and some texts in between
even though that is what we have here.
Now, I got a challenge and a little practice
for you at this point.
I want you to outsource this into a separate component
and you should keep the JSX code as it is,
don't make that more complex
but make sure you create a new component
and configure it correctly regarding the type,
it needs the types it receives,
the type of component it is.
Make sure you do that
such that you can continue working with that array of Todos.
Here's a short pause for you to pause the video
and try this on your own.
They're all after we're going to implement this together.
Were you successful?
Let's build this together.
And for this I'll create a new component,
that Todo.tsx file or TodoItem.tsx file.
And I'll go with TodoItem
so that we have no confusion or a clash with the Todo,
class we have here.
Now, in this TodoItem component file here
I wanna create my TodoItem functional components
and I'll write it as an arrow function here
and then export this oops, this TodoItem here,
TodoItem like this.
Now here, we'll get this prompts object
we know that already
because we'll ultimately return a list item
with props.text as a content.
The key will not be added here
because the key should be added directly in the list
so where you call map.
And therefore I will add the key
once we use the TodoItem component here,
in the Todos component.
But the key is not our primary problem at this point
instead of the problem which we've got here
is that we have those red squiggly lines
because props is implicitly of type any.
And it is implicitly of type any
because we have no type annotations here.
Now, when you create a new functional component,
you learned that you should add this react fc,
type annotation
and that's what I'll do here.
I'll make it clear that TodoItem
is a react functional component
by adding this type annotation.
And for this, we can import react
though we don't even have to do that
in modern react project setups.
You can still add the react import if you want to,
but you don't have to.
So now we make it clear that this is a functional component
but now I get an error here
because we now use a text property, which doesn't exist,
because out of the box, a component gets props
but it only has this children prop maybe
and it definitely does not have a text prop out of the box.
That's why we need those angle brackets here
that allows us to merge in
our own prop definitions with those base props.
And here, we now wanna set up an object type
because props is always an object
and we always merge an object with those base props.
And we now wanna make it clear,
which kind of prop can expect here.
And here it's not really up to you
you could expect the entire Todo as a prop
so the full TodoItem including the ID.
So, an object based on this model,
but that is actually redundant here
because in this component, we're not using the ID
we're only using the text.
And therefore, we maybe just wanna get this text
or the Todo text, however, you wanna name it.
I'll go with text here, which will be a string
because that's all we need here.
And if I set it up like this, this error is gone
and this component is ready to be used.
If you came up with a solution
where instead you expect to get the entire Todo,
and you import Todo from your models folder,
that's all the fine,
but here I'll just build a very minimal component
and just expect the text.
And now, we can go to Todos tsx
and here all our import TodoItem from,
TodoItem from this TodoItem tsx file.
And here output TodoItem for every item in this Todos,
in this items prop here.
And I'll set this key we can set this,
even though we're not expecting a key prop here
in our TodoItem component,
because we are using this fc based type
that does not just give us the children prop here
it also actually makes sure that
we can add these special props like to key prop
on our component when we're using it.
So we can add the key prop here to TodoItem.
This key attributes so to say,
and set this to item.id,
and now very important at the text prop.
And I'm also getting all the completion here
if I press controlled space,
you see that this text prop is one that it's suggested here.
And then here, I'll set this equal to item.text
and that's one way of building this TodpoItem component
and using TypeScript for it.
And with that, if I save everything again,
we still get the same output
as we did throughout the entire module.
So that's not too exciting
but now we're using yet another component
which again, embraces TypeScript.
And I'm really emphasizing this, because this
is the bread and butter of using react with TypeScript.