Now that we built a lot of components
that dealt with outputting Todos,
let's make sure our actual Todos
no longer have to be hard-coded, dummy Todos,
but that we instead let the user enter new Todos.
And for this I'll add yet another component here,
the NewTodo component,
which should display a form that handles user input
where we get the, well, Todo as a user add it.
For this header, I'll again, create a functional component
by using const and then the arrow function syntax.
And I'll export this NewTodo component here,
NewTodo like this.
And here, I now wanna return my form.
I wanna render a form
that allows the user to enter a NewTodo.
Now this will be a very simple form, which I build here.
I wanna have a label, where I say Todo text.
Below that I input of type text,
where the user should enter the concrete Todo.
And below that a button for
adding that Todo for submitting that form.
That's the JSX code I want here.
We can refine the styling a little bit later.
For the moment, let's just add it like this.
And let's focus just on React and TypeScript.
Now on that label I'll add the htmlFor,
attribute so to say, this prop here
to point at the
text
input which is this one here.
So I added id text here to connect the label to it
for accessibility. But now with that,
that's the finished JSX code. And what I wanna do now
is I wanna handle the form submission
and prevent the browser default,
as we learned it in this course.
And in addition, I wanna of course then get the user input.
And for getting the user input,
we of course learned about two main approaches.
We can either listen to every keystroke with useState,
or we use a Ref to then get the user input
once the form is submitted.
And it depends on what you wanna do.
If you wanna validate with every keystroke or not,
which approach you wanna use.
And here I'll go for the Ref approach,
because we're going to see useState in action later anyways.
Now let's start with the form submission function.
For this, I'll add a new function
in this component function. And that will be the
submitHandler function, though the name is up to you.
In there, I expect an event argument so that I can call
event.prevent default. But we can already see
that I'm not getting any auto completion
and that we got the red squiggly lines here.
Now we're getting red squiggly lines, because
TypeScript has no idea which type of data
this event thing will be.
We as a developer know
that it will actually be such an event object
which is emitted and passed automatically
when we connect this function
to the appropriate event listener.
But that's not something TypeScript can know.
So we have to add a type annotation here.
And here, since we'll add this function to the submit event
through React. So with help of React. With help of React's
onSubmit property later.
Since we'll do that, the type here will be
the React.
formEvent.
And you can actually omit this import as you learned.
That's a special type
provided by our React package in the end,
which is this event object type,
which we'll get automatically
when listening to the form submission.
There also is a MouseEvent, for example,
which you would get if you add onClick listener.
That's then the event object you get.
But for the form submission, it's the FormEvent.
And then here we can call preventDefault.
You now see I get all the completion, because now
I'm clearly describing which type of data we'll get here.
Now we can connect this here
and pass the submitHandler to onSubmit.
By the way, if I would be using MouseEvent here,
you see I'm now getting an error down there
with a very long message basically telling me
that the type of function I'm pointing at it here
for onSubmit is not the type of function React is expecting.
Because for the onSubmit prop,
React is expecting a pointer and a function
that actually gets the argument of type FormEvent,
not of type MouseEvent.
So that's an extra little check, which we get here,
which is great.
And now with that turn back to FormEvent,
everything is working again.
Now we wanna extract the entered input.
And we'll do that with help of Refs here.