Now, to change the logic
for adding cart items,
we need to head back to the CartProvider
and there to the cartReducer.
At the moment, items are always added
as new items in that array.
Now, that needs to change.
When we're adding a item, I always wanna calculate
my updatedTotalAmount like this first.
That is always correct
no matter if a item is already part of the cart or not.
But then, before I derive my updatedItems,
I instead wanna check
if a item is already part of the cart.
And for this, I'll create a existingCartItemIndex constant,
where I will reach out to my existing items in the cart
and where I call findIndex,
which is a built-in method in JavaScript
which finds the index of an item in an array.
Now, it takes a function which should return true
if that's the item we're looking for, and false otherwise,
because this function will be executed
for every item in the array.
And I wanna return true
if item.id is equal to action.item.id,
so if the item we're currently looking at in that array
has the same id as the item we're adding
with this action which was dispatched.
Now, this will then return us
the index of that item if it exists.
So what we can do now is we can get the existingCartItem
by reaching out to state.items
and accessing that existingCartItemIndex.
This will only work if we have that item already.
Otherwise, we'll try to access an item which doesn't exist,
and hence existingCartItem would be null.
If the item already is part of the array, though,
this item will be set to that item.
And now we can add an updatedItem variable
and an updatedItems variable,
which clashes with this constant, but we'll fix this soon.
And then we add another if check here
where we check if existingCartItem is a thing,
if this is truthy, which will only be the case
if it's already part of the array.
In this case, the updatedItem
will be set equal to a new object
where I copy the existingCartItem
but where I update the amount
because the amount now needs to change.
If sushi was already part of the cart
and we added two more sushis,
then, of course, we need to update the amount
of that existing sushi which is part of the cart.
So here I then access
existingCartItem.amount + action.item.amount,
so the amount which was added by this action.
And updatedItems is now equal to a new array
where I copy the existing items
so that I update this immutably
without editing the old array in memory,
hence I'm creating a new array where I copy the old objects.
And then for that existingCartItemIndex,
I overwrite this with the updatedItem.
So I pick the old item,
which we identified in the cart items array,
and I overwrite it with this updatedItem.
Now, that's what I do
if a item is already part of the cart items array.
Now, we also have the else case
that a item is added for the first time
to that cart items array.
In that case,
the updatedItem is simply a brand new item
where I copy my action.item,
and now updatedItems
is simply set to state.items.concat,
and then here I add this updatedItem.
Or we keep this simpler and we keep on adding action.item,
we don't set updatedItem here and remove updatedItem
in here, therefore, and create this on the fly as a constant
because now we only use updatedItem
in that first part of the if block.
And our else block is very lean now.
With that, we set updatedItems to different things
depending on whether the item is already part
of the array or not.
And either way, we then return our new state snapshot
which picks up these updatedItems.
I hope this logic makes sense.
And with that, if we now reload, I can add sushi,
and if I add it multiple times,
and if I add four sushi at once,
you see we only have one entry here
with the appropriate amount,
and that's exactly what I want.
Now, if I add a second item,
this is added as a new entry, of course,
because it's a different item.
But then, again, if I add more items of that,
it just increases the counter.
So, that is working.
Now, let's make sure that the plus and minus buttons
here in the cart also work.
And for that, we also need to make sure
that we can remove items.