Now a little enhancement to our context.
It is a good idea to also add your functions
like onLogout in my case to the default context
when you create a context.
And there you can just store a dummy function
which does nothing.
I'm doing this for better IDE auto-completion.
Because you will see that if I don't have this here
in the Navigation component,
here if I try to call onLogout,
I'm not getting any suggestion by my IDE.
It doesn't know that there is a onLogout prop.
On the upper hand you will see
that there is this isLoggedIn suggestion.
Now that's simply happening because the way React works
and the way Visual Studio Code at least works.
It's looking at this default context object
to find out what you are able to access on your context.
So for better IDE auto-completion,
it is a good idea to add onLogout here
in your default context object as well
just with a dummy function
because we're not going to use this anyways.
And then here you will see that now
I get to this onLogout auto-completion.
So that's just a tiny hint you might consider
because it can be helpful.
Another thing that you might consider
is depending on your application structure
and how you're managing your data,
you also might want to pull more logic
out of for example App component
and create a separate Context Management component
if you wanna call it like this.
How could this look like?
Well, maybe in our AuthContext store file,
we could create a AuthContexProvider component now actually
where we return AuthContext.Provider
and we accept props and simply pass whatever we got
on props.children between our provider.
And then here I don't just export AuthContext
as the default, but I also export my AuthContextProvider
in addition to the default as a named export.
Now, why am I doing that?
Because now we can actually also import useState here
inside of the auth-context.js file,
and manage the isLoggedIn state and setIsLoggedIn here
inside auth this AuthContextProvider,
add the logoutHandler function here
where setIsLoggedIn to false,
and also add the loginHandler function here now
so that we manage the entire authentication state
in this separate provider component.
And here I set IsLoggedIn to true of course.
And then I set the value here of course
to an object where I have isLoggedIn,
which is equal to the isLoggedIn state
where I have onLogout
which points at the logoutHandler.
And in addition where we now also have onLogin
which points at the loginHandler
and therefore, I will also add this
to my default context here onLogin with a dummy function,
just making it clear
that we there want the email and a password.
We're not doing anything with that data
but technically we would need it in a real app.
And now we have this standalone file
which manages the entire login state
in this AuthContextProvider component.
And which also sets up all the context.
And the advantage here could be, and I'm saying could
because this is something you can consider.
It always depends on your preferences,
the exact useCase, and the size of your app.
But this is something you could consider
because now we can strip that all out of App component.
We of course also though need to move over
our local storage access here.
So, clear data in the logoutHandler,
set our data in the loginHandler,
and of course also add our useEffect code here
that all now needs to go into our AuthContextProvider,
and therefore we also need to import useEffect here.
But with that all we can now clear all that logic here
from the App component, remove these hook imports here,
remove our AuthContext import here, remove all of that.
And therefore of course, bring back React Fragment
like this, and I'm doing this
because now we can wrap the App component as a whole.
So therefore an index component
which is where we rendered the app component
with AuthContext provider.
So with our AuthContextProvider component
which we just created an exported in the auth-context file,
and with that we have one central place
for the state management
for the off state management, I should say.
And that central place is now not the App component
but a dedicated context component
and a dedicated context file.
And this might be a structure you might prefer
because it is more focused
and gives you a leaner app component
which now is not concerned with app wide state management
but which now instead can just focus on
well, bringing something onto the screen.
Of course, since I'm using isLoggedIn here
I need to be able to get that information.
So now in the App component we wanna use useContext,
and pass our AuthContext, not the provider
but still the AuthContext object
which is our default export in the AuthContext file.
And therefore, we now got our context here as well
and hence we can access it here.
And now we could even remove the onLogin
and onLog out props here
because we're not managing the log out and log in handlers
and App component anyways,
and now tap into contexts in the Home and Login components.
So in the Home component we can also import useContext
and get access to our AuthContext
maybe to mix up the naming and make it clear what's in there
to which context we're listing here
by importing AuthContext and passing it to useContext.
Again, use AuthContext here not the provider.
And then here we can use authCtx.onLogout
and do something similar in the Login component.
Import useContext here,
and then in our component function
maybe here we can set up our AuthContext
by calling useContext and passing AuthContext to it.
For that make sure you are importing AuthContext of course.
And then we can use AuthContext when we need to log in.
So here it's not props onLogin, but authCtx.onLogin
to which we forward the email and password.
Now again, this is totally optional.
The advantage here could just be
that you have a leaner app component
which again is now just focused on returning JSX
and bringing something onto the screen.
And you have to actual off state management
and auth-context management all in one file.
And some developers including myself
often prefer this more focused and separated approach
where you have components,
where every component has one job essentially
and not a ton of jobs.
And therefore I'm a fan of this split,
but as often it's not the only way of doing this
and it's also not the only correct way.
It's definitely a practice that is worth looking into
though, a practice you might see in projects out there,
and therefore something that of course needs to go
into a course like this,
which has the job of turning you
into a real React developer.
And therefore you have to know patterns like this
which is why we refactored this.
With all of that out of the way
let's test our application to ensure that this still works.
And that all seems to work to me here.
Let's also check the Logout button here.
Yeah, that all works.
Now with one central context
with one central state management.