So by now we got components everywhere.
We got the Expenses component,
ExpenseItem, ExpenseDate, app, yeah.
A lot of components.
But that really is what React is all about.
Now, obviously throughout this course
we're going to learn about more features,
which we can add to these components
to make them more interactive, to improve their performance,
to send Http requests and much more,
but in a nutshell, and that's really important,
it's all about components
and it's about props for configuring these components
for passing data into them.
And components really just are these custom HTML elements
where you combine HTML code,
JSX code to be precise and styling
and if you want to, also extra JavaScript logic,
as we're doing it in ExpenseDate.
That is really what components are about.
Now I did mention it multiple times already.
We build all these components
to then build a user interface
and we are already doing that.
In App.js we're using Expenses,
in there we are using ExpenseItem,
in there we're using ExpenseDate.
Generally, this approach of building a user interface
from smaller building blocks is called composition.
Now there's one specifically interesting aspect
of composition, which we haven't seen thus far though.
What if we wanted to create a component
which actually just serves as a shell
around any kind of other content.
At the moment, we have highly specific components.
The ExpenseDate component is about outputting a date
in exactly that format and in exactly that look.
The ExpenseItem component is just
about outputting an expense item.
And in your React application,
you will always have a lot of these
very specific components.
All these components are also just configured through props,
through the date prop, the title prop, the amount prop
in the case of ExpenseItem, for example.
And again, that is fairly standard.
You'll have a lot of these components
in your React applications.
Sometimes however, you wanna have a component
where you don't configure everything through props
but where instead you're able to pass content
between the opening and closing tags of that component.
And here's an example where this would make sense.
If we have a look at our current output,
then we see
two kind of
boxes or containers.
We got a container around all the expense items.
It has a light gray background, and rounded corners,
and a slight drop shadow, which might be hard to see.
And we have a container around the overall expenses list,
with a darker gray background
but also rounded corners and a slight drop shadow.
Now, the idea behind all of these components
is to have reusable building blocks
also to avoid code duplication.
And here at the moment
we at least have some style duplication,
also maybe some HTML structure duplication.
Expenses has a div which surrounds our expenses
which applies certain styles, thanks to this class.
And the same is true for ExpenseItem.
Now, of course not all divs have the same look though.
Inside of our expense items we also got divs like this one
which have a totally different look.
Nonetheless, we could extract this surrounding container div
which we have both in ExpenseItem and Expenses.js
and extract the styles they have in common,
like rounded corners and a drop shadow,
into a separate component.
And we could name such a component card
because this is a specific card look.
And this is not a term I came up with.
Instead in general, in web development,
when you hear the term card,
it's typically means some kind of container look
with rounded corners, drop shadows, and elements like these.
So that's why I'm picking card as a name here.
Now, such a card component
is still a regular component here.
So let's create it as such
but such a card component could now do one main thing.
It could return a div
or any other kind of container HTML element
with a class name
of let's say,
Card.
And then we could add a Card.css file
and import that into that card component.
So import Card.css,
and now in the Card.css file we could have, let's say,
the box-shadow and the border-radius from Expenses.css.
Maybe we would be able to extract more styles
but I'll go with these two.
I'll cut them from Expenses.css and add them to Card.css
inside of a card CSS class selector, which I added there.
I will also go to ExpenseItem.css
and here in ExpenseItem in this class selector,
we all defined a box-shadow and a border-radius.
So I will remove these styles from there as well.
Now, why am I doing that?
Just to show this kind of component.
Now we got this card container component you could say,
which should act as a shell around
either our ExpenseItem content or our Expenses content.
And that's the key.
This card component will now not be configured
through some attributes.
Instead, my idea would be that,
let's say in ExpenseItem,
we can simply replace this built-in div
with our custom card component.
And then we get these predefined styles
for the card automatically.
Maybe we then just want to make them extensible
but we get these predefined styles automatically.
And for that of course,
we wanna import Card from ./Card inside of ExpenseItem.
The thing just is if I save that,
you will see that all the expense items are lost.
And the reason for that is that out of the box,
just like that,
you can't use your custom components as wrappers
around other kind of content.
Having content between opening and closing tags
doesn't work just like that.
But of course it does work for built-in HTML elements,
like the div or the h2 tag.
So it would be nice if we could also make it work
for our custom components
to build such reusable wrapper components
like this, for example.
And of course, React has a solution here.
We can build such wrapper components.
In Card.js we again, when I accept props.
But now, as I mentioned we'll not work with some attributes
but instead we will use one special prop
which is built into React, which every component receives,
even if you're never setting it explicitly.
And that's a prop which value I wanna output
between the opening and closing tag of this div,
inside of the card component function.
It's the props
children prop.
Children is a reserved name.
We don't set a children prop on this card.
I'm setting a class named prop
and actually at the moment, this won't do anything.
But I'm not setting a children prop.
Children, as I said, is a reserved name
and the value of this special children prop
will always be the content
between the opening and closing tags
of your custom component.
So in this case,
this content between the opening and closing card tag,
that is what will be available on props children
inside of that card.
And therefore, if I now save this, we got some content back.
However it's also a bit broken.
And the reason for that is that I extracted some styles
which ExpenseItem and Expenses had in common,
but I had more styles to find for expense items
and these styles are important.
But they're missing now.
I am setting a class name prop on card here
but you must not forget that card
is now a custom component defined by you.
All the default HTML components
out of the box supports class name for adding CSS classes
to the rendered HTML elements.
But your custom components only support what you tell them
to support.
So if you wanna make sure that a class name can be set
on your card component and then has an effect,
we have to tweak the code in the card component.
And here we would probably wanna tweak it
such that we add whatever is set as a class name on card
to this class name string, we're setting as a class name
on that div.
So here we could add a classes constant
which is
card as a default class
which is always applied,
white space
plus
props.className.
So now anything we receive as a class name from outside
is added to that string.
And here we can then dynamically point
at this class, this constant.
So with that, we're now making sure
that any value set on the class named prop
is added to this long string of class names
which is then finally set on the div inside of the card.
And with that all, if we saved it,
we get the same look as before,
not yet for expenses, but for the expense items
but now we have this reusable wrapper component.
And we can also use that in Expenses now.
Here, instead of using a div,
we can also use our card component.
We can import Card from ./Card
and replace this div here with that card.
Still setting a extra class name here as well.
And also replace the closing tag.
And if we do that, now we get the rounded corners back
on that expenses container as well.
Now, why would we do that?
What did we gain by doing that?
Well, in this case, of course, not a whole lot
but we were able to extract some code duplication
from inside our CSS files
into this separate wrapper component.
And it's not just a duplicate CSS code.
We also were able to extract this HTML code,
this JSX code, this div here.
In this case, it's just one div
but throughout the course
you will also see more complex wrapper components
which might have a more complex JSX structure.
Things like modals and alerts.
And in such cases, being able to extract that
often allows you to save a lot of code duplication
and it often allows you to keep your other components clean.
And this is another aspect of composition.
We compose our ExpenseItem component
by using card as a wrapper,
by using some built-in HTML elements,
and by then all the putting in the ExpenseDate.
And all these components and elements are composed together
to form the overall ExpenseItem component
which then again, is used in other components
to in the end overall, build the overall user interface.
So composition is important.
You use it all the time when working with React.
Whenever you combine components, you are using composition.
And an especially important part of composition
is this props children feature
which allows you to also create wrapper components
which is a special type of component, you could say,
which you also sometimes need.
Now again, as with all these things,
you are, of course, going to see many more examples
throughout the course.