So with the NewTodo component added
let's go to the App component.
There, I actually wanna use this NewTodo component.
So here I added the import,
and now I'm using NewTodo here in the JSX code.
Of course the Todos array here,
should now be managed with help of this NewTodo component.
Whenever a NewTodo is added there,
it should be added to this array here
so that this array is not hard coded but dynamic.
For this we've got a couple of steps we need to take.
We need to use state to manage this array with state
so that this App component will rerender
when this array changes,
so that the Todos component updates when it changes.
We need a way of communicating back
from NewTodo into this App component.
That's what I wanna start with.
For this and the NewTodo component,
here in the submitHandler,
I actually wanna call a function
which will be stored in App component.
That's of course, a pattern we used a lot in this course.
We learned that we can pass pointers at functions
as props to our components
and that's exactly what I need here.
In NewTodo I want to get my props object
and then here in the submitHandler,
I want to call props.onAddTodo for example,
expecting that onAddTodo is getting a function as a value
so that I can execute it as a function,
and then two, onAddTodo, I wanna pass my enteredText
so my string here which I extract
from the todoTextIputRef.
That's how I wanna write this,
but we now get an error up here,
and that's of course an error
we had many times before already.
I actually never clarified
that NewTodo will be a functional component
and we should absolutely do that.
I should add React.FC here to make that clear
and then if we need our own custom props as we do here
I should embrace that generic nature of this FC type
to define my concrete prop object definition
of my own props, which I wanna add in here,
that will be merged with the brace props.
Here I wanna make it clear that this NewTodo component
will actually get, onAddTodo prop,
which will be off type what?
Well which will actually be a function.
For this we can define a so-called
function type in TypeScript,
and that is actually quite straightforward to do.
For this you can add an Arrow function here
but just as curly braces in this spot
would not create an object
using this Arrow function some texts here
does not create an Arrow function.
Instead, we're here in a part
where we want a type definition,
and this is TypeScript's syntax
for defining the shape of a function,
so for describing a function type.
Here we know that onAddTodo should be of type function
so here I'm describing how this function should look like.
Between the brackets, we would describe the parameters
this function will get and after the Arrow
we describe the return type of this function.
Now here onAddTodo shouldn't return anything
because when we call this function,
we're not doing anything with the return value.
We're not storing it in a constant, we're not outputting it
so we don't need a return value here
hence we can set void as an expected return value
of this function, we get as a value on onAddTodo.
But, onAddTodo should be a function
that gets and argument, a parameter,
because I'm passing argument down there
when I'm calling this function.
Currently we're saying, that onAddTodo
is a function that gets no parameters.
That's my function type definition
up there at the moment.
That's why we're getting the red squiggly lines down there.
This onAddTodo function currently expects zero arguments,
but it gets one, enteredText in this case.
Of course it should get one
so we need to update this function type definition up there.
We should get an argument here
which we can give any name we want,
in this case I'll just use text,
which should be of type string.
Now all the errors are gone because now I'm making it clear
that onAddTodo will be a function,
and that's a function that returns nothing
but takes one parameter, which is of type string.
So now calling it the function like this works.
If I would set this to type number, it of course fails
because entered text is a string and not a number.
But that's okay because here we want a string,
so let's switch this back.
Well, and now with that, just as all the times before,
in the place where we use NewTodo.
So in the App component we now have to make sure
that we pass in this prop which we're expecting.
So onAddTodo should now be added as a prop here,
and the value for that,
that should now be such a function,
a function that has this shape.
Now that's a function which we now have
to define here in App.tsx.
So here I'll add a new constant
and I'll name it addTodoHandler,
and that's now an Arrow function lets say,
and that Arrow function needs a specific shape.
Now that's a concrete function definition here now
not a type definition because here we got
some regular JavaScript code in the end.
Now the shape of this function is
that it shouldn't return anything.
So not having a return statement here is fine,
but it should accept the parameter.
It should get the actual todoText or just text,
you can name it however you want,
which, and that's important now, should be of type string,
because that is the function shape
we are expecting in the NewTodo component.
So if we wanna pass this function
through the onAddTodo to NewTodo,
we have to make sure that this shape is correct.
Here it is correct so now we can pass a pointer
at addTodoHandler to newTodo.
Now it's in addTodoHandler
where we wanna manipulate this Todos array.
So this state managed array as it soon will be.