So it's time for useState because
of course we need to manage this todos array
with state so that when we change it,
this component re-renders and therefore
these todos items also re-renders and is updated.
And for this of course we do what we learned in this course.
We import useState from react like this.
And then todos actually will be converted.
I will get rid of those dummy todos here.
And instead I will call useState here.
And, we now don't just get back todos here,
but we get back in array as you learned,
which we can destructure where we get our todos
and this state updating function.
And thanks to TypeScript we now
for example see that setTodos if we hover over it
is actually of type react dispatch,
which might not be 100% clear
but which is actually that state updating function
which we can call to change our state,
to dispatch a state update so to say.
Now useState of course can take an initial value
and that could be an array.
And empty array initially
because initially we have no todos.
But here we actually now introduced a subtle problem
if you write it like this.
And do you see which problem that is?
The problem is that I'm just passing
in an empty array as a default value here.
But TypeScript is not able to infer which types
of values should be accepted in that array eventually.
That's why todos at the moment is of type, never array.
Of which basically means it always must be an empty array.
No values are allowed in there.
That's what this strange never type means here.
And that's of course not what we want.
But TypeScript infers this type
because it's not able to infer that this
should be an array of todos for example, eventually.
Because the initial value has no information about that.
To make it clear that we initially have an empty array
but that eventually we wanna have an array full
of to-do items here,
we again need to tell TypeScript somehow.
And we can tell TypeScript because useState,
this useState function,
out of the box is a generic function.
It is generic for exactly this reason
so that we can set the type of data
we eventually wanna store in this state.
So we add angle brackets again
and now we wanna make it clear that the kind
of data managed by the state will be an array of todos.
We do this by using our todo type
from that models folder and then square brackets.
That means that this state will manage an array of todos.
Initially it's an empty array,
because that's all define
that does not conflict with this type definition.
But if we do add items to this array eventually
they have to be todo items.
Not strings, not numbers, todo items
which have to shape off the
todo object clause here, we created here.
And now that's the proper way of defining this state.
Now in add todo handler,
we then wanna create our newTodo
by calling newTodo and passing in the todo text
as a value to the constructor.
And then we wanna call a setTodos and update our state.
Now here, I wanna use my old todos state
so the existing array and add this new todo
and you learned that if you wanna update
your state based on the previous state,
you should use this function form of updating your state.
And in this function you get the current state
so to say, or to previous state
depending on how you wanna look at it,
and then you need to return your updated state here.
So in this case,
I'll return previous todos, concat, newTodo.
Concat is a method which we can call,
that will create a new array, which we should do.
We should not mutate the existing array.
We should return a new array here,
which then will be used as a new state by react
and this new array, thanks to concat,
contains this newTodo.
That's how we can properly update the state here.
And with all that in place,
if we now save this and I reload,
I got this unstyled form here,
and no todo list at the moment,
but if I then enter a Learn React here, then this is added.
And if I add Learn TypeScript, this also is added.
So that is working.