Now let's continue, and first of all,
I wanna add some styling.
For this, I prepared free dot module dot CSS files,
which you'll find attached.
The to-do's module CSS, the to-do item,
and the new to-do dot module CSS files.
And we will simply add them
like we did it before in this course.
There is nothing TypeScript specific about adding CSS files
to your component files,
no matter if you use global CSS or CSS modules.
Here I am CSS modules, hence the naming of these CSS files,
since we are in a project created by Create React app,
we got that built in CSS modules support,
and here we can now import the classes,
for example from,
to-do's dot module dot CSS.
So just as we did it without TypeScript.
And then here on this unordered list,
we can add the list class, that's sorry, the to-do's class.
That's the class I defined in
that to-do's module CSS file.
And we'll do the same in the other files as well.
In the to-do item, TSX file, we can import classes from
dot slash to-do item dot module dot CSS.
And then we add class name dot classes dot item
to this list item,
dot item,
because in this to-do item dot module CSS file,
I have this item CSS class
and in the new to-do TSX file,
we also import classes from
dot slash new to-do dot module dot CSS.
And with that imported we can go to the form
and on it, add class name classes dot form.
And if you do all of that and save everything,
you should have that look here
on your screen,
where you can learn, react,
and then learn TypeScript.
And that works just like that.
And that's now the same app as before,
just with some styling.