Now to really conclude this module,
I just wanna show you an alternative syntax
for writing these functions,
any kinds of functions in JavaScript.
A syntax which is not exclusive to React by the way,
but which can be used in any modern JavaScript application.
Instead of writing a function like this
with the function keyword,
you can also write a so-called arrow function,
and attached you find a link with more details
on these arrow functions.
Again, it's not a React specific thing.
To use that arrow function syntax.
You replace function with const to create a new constant
with a given name app in this case.
And then the value which you assigned to this constant
is an arrow function written like this.
A list of parameters then an equal sign
and a greater sign forming such an arrow
and then the function body between curly braces.
And again, that's really just standard JavaScript code.
You can absolutely stick to the function keyword.
This is just a syntax, which I personally prefer
because it's a bit shorter or yeah, I just prefer it.
And therefore I will migrate all my functions to
this syntax like this here in the case of card
but you don't have to do that
if you prefer the other syntax, it's really 100% optional.
And in this case here
it doesn't offer any benefits or anything like that.
It's really just personal preference.
And I want to show this syntax here
since you will also see that in a lot of React projects
and you therefore should be aware of it
that you can write your functions like this,
any functions by the way, not just component functions.
And with that, we're really done for this module.
It was a huge module.
And yet we're still only scratching the surface.
There's way more to explore about React.
And the next thing we are going to explore is how
we can make this a bit more interactive
and reactive because currently it's all static.
This data never changes.
As a user we can't do anything about it.
And we are building modern user interfaces
with React because we typically want to
build user interfaces where things can change.
Therefore, in the next course section, we are going to dive
into another important React concept,
state because that will help us
make our applications interactive.