Now to come to an end in this module
where we learned a lot of important things.
I wanna split up this index JS file into store folder.
It's actually quite a small file
not too much code in it, but of course,
in your typical a React application
where you have multiple state slices,
this can become a very long file.
So therefore it might be worth splitting it
up into smaller pieces.
And when using Redux Toolkit
it could make sense to put every slice into its own file.
So we could add a new file in the store folder
and let's say the counter-slice.JS file
or just counter.JS, the file name is up to you.
And then we want to create
and manage the counter specific state and slice in there.
So we would grab the initial counter state
and the entire counter slice cut that
and add it into counter JS file.
Now to use, create slice.
We of course now need to import that here.
So we import create slice from at Redux JS toolkit
and we still also need to use counter slice
in a different folder after.
So we should export it.
For example, as a default export
we can export counter slice.
Now we can do the same for off.
So I'll add an off JS file and take my initial
off state and D off slice cut debt
from the index JS file and move it into off JS.
And then also import create slice here
from add to Redux Toolkit.
And then also here export this default off slice.
Now in index JS, we want to merge all those slices together.
Therefore we can remove, create slice in there.
We don't need that import anymore
because we're not creating any slices in this file anymore.
Instead, we focus on creating that main store
and merging all the slice reducers together.
Hence we can now import the counter slice
from ./counter, or since we only really
needed to reducer in here, we actually go
to the counter and we just export the reducer.
So we don't export the entire slice
but just it's reducer part by doing that in index JS
we could import the counter reducer here
since that is what we're exporting as a default.
And then just assign that
as a reducer to counter the counter reducer
and do the same for off the JS
just export the reducer year and an index JS.
Then therefore import the auth reducer
from ./auth and assign this
as a value for the auth key in that reducer map.
Now regarding the actions,
I want to export those from there,
from the files into which they belong.
So the counter actions should be exported here
in the counter JS file still by accessing dot actions
and exporting that as a named export
at the same for auth I'll grab that export
and index JS and move that into auth JS.
Now with that,
if we saved this we'll need to fix a couple of imports
in counter JS for example,
where I try to import counter actions from the index file
we now need to import them from the counter file
in the store folder in auth JS, we need to import
auth the actions from the auth file in the store folder.
In header, we need to import
auth actions from the auth file as well
and then user profile or not using anything of that.
But if we now save that, if we reload, it works just as
before all the state works as before
but now we're splitting this up
and in bigger application stat can ensure
that our code stays maintainable and is easier to manage
because now we have a lean index JS file
and then pretty lean files for our different state slices
which are then focused
on one specific type of state,
not required here but definitely helpful
in bigger applications.
And even here, it certainly doesn't hurt.