Now, in this course section,
you learned a lot about React Router,
and you learned it about
React Router version 5
because that is the version that is used
in most projects.
The latest version, however, is version 6.
And therefore, of course,
I also want to make sure that you're able
to work with that version.
And thankfully, if you
learned about version 5,
using version 6 is also super simple
and it's not too hard to switch to it.
Now, to learn about
React Router version 6,
you can, of course, check
out the official website,
ReactRouter.com, and the
documentation you find there.
And specifically, there
also is a upgrading guide,
which I will attach to this video
where you will find
detailed upgrading steps
and where you also learn
what's new and what changed.
And this looks like a super long document,
and if you wanna have all the details,
you should definitely also dive into it.
But in the end, it's
really simple to upgrade,
and not a lot changed
when it comes to the code that we write.
Under the hood, version 6 is a lot better
than version 5,
and therefore, if you can upgrade,
you should, of course,
strongly consider doing that.
Now, to see what changed
and write some code,
I created a little snapshot,
a little project snapshot,
which you find attached,
which does use React Router version 5.
So which does not use version 6.
This snapshot is a snapshot
from that course project we worked on
throughout this course section.
It's not the final state of the project
but a first snapshot
that allows us to dive into the first set
of important changes.
So once you downloaded and
extracted this snapshot,
you should run npm install
to install all the core dependencies
that come with that project.
And once you did that,
you should install React Router version 6.
And you do this by running
npm install react-router-dom,
and that's important.
You want react-router-dom,
which is the browser
version of React Router.
And then add @6,
which ensures that you
install the latest version 6.
Or you add @latest,
which will always give you
the very latest version,
and that's what we can do here.
So with that installed, we
got React Router version 6.
And if I now run npm start,
you will see that this project won't work.
If I try to visit this page,
I now get an error
that Switch is not exported
from react-router-dom.
And that's one of the first changes.
When using React Router version 5,
we used this Switch component,
which is provided by
the react-router package
to wrap our routes
and make sure that only one
of these routes is loaded
at the same time,
instead of all matching routes.
And typically, that is what you want.
You want to define multiple routes
but only one route should be active
at a given point of time.
Now, with React Router version 6,
Switch doesn't exist anymore.
Instead, this now becomes Routes.
So you replace Switch with Routes.
And you therefore import Routes
from react-router-dom instead of Switch.
By the way, what hasn't changed
is that you still import BrowserRouter
from react-router-dom,
and you wrap that around your app
where you then plan to use routing.
That's exactly the same
syntax as you know it.
With that, the error goes away.
But if I click Welcome or Products,
you see that the URL changes
but I still don't see
anything on the screen.
The reason for this is that the way
how we define our routes also changed.
We still have the route component
and it still takes a path prop,
but the component that should be loaded
when a given path becomes active,
so in this case, the welcome
component, for example,
is not longer a child of your route
but instead, on Route,
you add a new element prop,
and then you pass a
dynamic value to element
and that dynamic value
is that to be rendered component as JSX.
That's important.
So you don't pass Welcome like this,
you don't pass a pointer
to that component function.
Instead, you pass the JSX element.
Hence the name element.
It wants a JSX element.
And then this can, of course,
become a self-closing component,
this route component.
And we do the same here for products.
Here we also add the element prop,
and we then move Products into this prop
or as a value, we set it
as a value for this prop.
And we turn this into a
self-closing component.
And last but not least,
we also do this for this last route.
And please note that
this is a dynamic route
and that still works as you learned it.
So you can still have
dynamic path parameters,
like productId as you
could with version five.
That did not change.
With that, once the routes
were restructured like this,
now you see I see this
welcome page content here,
and I can switch to
products back and forth.
If I select a product,
I also do see those product details.
So those detail routes also works
and therefore, a simple
app using routes like this
can easily be updated to version 6
by replacing Switch with Routes,
and moving the two below that component
into this new element prop.
But that's not all you
should know about version 6.
In addition to these changes,
it's also worth noting
that there were some internal changes
with React Router version 6.
Specifically, the internal
logic for evaluating these paths
and then picking a route to load changed.
With React Router version 5,
we needed to add exact here
because without exact,
this would match if a path
started with /products.
With version 6, this behavior is gone
and hence, the exact prop is gone.
It now always looks for exact matches
if you define your paths like this.
So we can remove exact with version 6,
and we still get the
same behavior as before.
If you compare that to
the version 5 behavior
where without exact you would
load the products component
and the product detail
component if you pick a detail.
That, of course, is an improvement
because you don't need
that extra prop anymore.
If you want that old behavior
of matching the start
of a path only,
you can still get that by
adding /* after your path.
Once you add that, this route
will become active if a URL
path starts with /products
instead of being only /products.
However, what you will note
is that even if you do that,
and you go back to your site here,
if you pick a product detail,
you still get the product detail
instead of the products overview page,
even though I'm now looking
for the start of the path.
The reason for that is that internally,
React Router version 6 now
also has a better algorithm
for picking the best route to be loaded
for a given path.
And what it basically does here is it sees
that if your path is
/products/ some other value,
that the best fit for
this kind of path probably
is this route
because you explicitly
declared this route here
where you say that for
/products/ something,
you want ProductDetail.
So unlike with version 5,
the order of routes also
doesn't matter anymore.
With version 5, you had to be careful.
For example, if you also had another route
that should be /products/edit.
Then with version 5,
this kind of route here
would have to be defined
before you have the route
with the dynamic segment
because if you had it thereafter,
this route would always win.
With version 6, this changed
and it's smarter internally.
You could define these two routes,
and if you then visit /edit here,
so products/edit,
React Router would find out
that this last route
here is the best match
for this specific path.
And if you had /products/p1,
on the other hand,
it would determine
that you have no better
match than this route,
and hence, this route would become active.
So the order of routes
doesn't matter anymore
when working with React Router version 6.
And that's another
important thing to note.
I'll also revert this here
because it didn't have
any effect here anyways.
So these are a couple of
super important changes
but as you see, code wise,
there wasn't a lot to change.
Now, let's move from
route definition to links.
The first important thing to note
is that you still have the Link component,
which generally works as you learned it
and you also still have
the NavLink component.
That did not change.
However, what did change is
this activeClassName prop.
With React Router version 5,
you could use that prop
to apply some CSS class
automatically to the link
once it became active.
With React Router version 5,
this prop was removed.
Instead, if you want to
apply a specific class
once this is active,
you have to manually find out
whether this link is active or not.
Doing that is very simple though
because you can use the className prop
or the style prop to
apply dynamic styling.
And both props work in a special way
when applied to NavLink.
className does not just take a class name,
instead, it takes a function,
which you can pass here,
and this function will actually
give you some information
about this link and the
current state of navigation.
So get some NavData here you could say.
This argument is provided by React Router
to this function when
this function is executed.
And this function will be
executed by React Router
when it evaluates NavLink
and whenever your navigation changes.
Inside this navData object,
which you get by React Router,
you then find a isActive property.
And that will be true
if this link is active for the
currently chosen path or not.
So you can then use this to
return a className dynamically
that should be applied to NavLink.
So here, I can get rid
of those curly braces
to use this short form of
this arrow function syntax.
I could then check if
navData.isActive is truthy.
In which case, I can
apply my active class here
and otherwise, I apply no class.
That's what I could do here.
And I can do the same here
for the other NavLink.
It's a bit more verbose
but it also gives you more
customization possibilities
and more control
and therefore, it is a change
that's not too difficult
to incorporate, and you then
still get the old behavior
as you can now see in the navigation here.
So that's an important thing
you should know about links.
I also wanna have a brief look
at the ProductDetail component here.
The ProductDetail page to be precise.
There I'm getting this dynamic parameter,
which is part of the URL.
And with React Router version 5,
we extracted that with the useParams hook
that was provided by the
react-router-dom package.
As you can tell, this
code still seems to work
because we had no problems
extracting that dynamic parameter
with React Router version 6 as well.
So the code here stays the same.
Now, let's move on to a
slightly more advanced app here,
another snapshot I prepared for you,
another snapshot taken
from this course section.
In this snapshot, we also have a redirect,
and we have a nested route
in the Welcome.js file.
Now, here we also got
some noteworthy changes
that come with React Router version 6.
And let's start with redirect
because that's already
causing an error here
because the redirect component
doesn't exist anymore.
Now, you can still redirect, of course.
The only thing that changed
is that now instead of
redirect, it's Navigate.
That's a new component
provided by React Router 6,
and we can use this
here to well, navigate.
And, of course, we then also
should use this element prop
instead of passing it as a child
between the opening
and closing route tags.
Though to be precise, if
we just add it like this,
what we will actually do
is we will push a navigation to this page
onto the navigation stack.
If we truly want to redirect,
so replace the current
page with the new page,
then we would have to add the replace prop
to Navigate as well.
And this would then be
the full replacement
for the old redirect component.
But you could also just
configure it like this
to just push the new page,
instead of replacing the current page.
With that, this error goes away.
And as you see, if I now enter just slash,
I am redirected to welcome.
Now I get another error though.
And that other error is
not related to redirecting
because that works with
Navigate as you saw it here.
Instead this error is now related
to this nested route, which we have here
inside another component.
Nested routes can be useful
because they allow you
to build deeply nested page structures
but the syntax you know from version 5
from React Router version 5
doesn't work like this anymore.
However, updating it is also simple.
The key thing you have to do here,
which you also learn in this error message
is that you need to wrap
your Route with Routes.
In version 5, you didn't need to do that.
You didn't have to wrap your
Route definition components
with the Routes or Switch component.
With version 6, this is mandatory though.
Hence, we should import
Routes here as well.
And wrap this single Route with Routes.
So even if it's just one route,
you have to wrap it.
That's just something you have to do.
Now then, we, of course, also
have to update this syntax
to use the element prop,
and pass our to be displayed JSX code
to element instead of
having it as a child.
And with this update done,
if we now save this,
this works, we don't
get the error anymore.
But it also doesn't really work
if you take a closer look.
We see the welcome page,
which is this title
but we don't see the content here,
Welcome, new user!
Well, the reason for this
is that I haven't loaded new-user yet.
If I do change my path
to /welcome/new-user,
then it also doesn't work.
Now, what's wrong here?
Well, what's wrong is that the logic
and the syntax you need for
nested routes also changed,
and it actually changed to the better.
If you plan on using nested
routes, you, first of all,
have to start at the parent route
that will eventually
hold more nested routes.
In this case, the Welcome route here.
I mentioned before that
you can add this /* thing
if React Router should match this route
for the start of the path
instead of the full path.
At the moment, I don't have this,
I just have /welcome.
And therefore, because of how
React Router version 6 works,
this will always match and
load this welcome component
if the entire path is exactly /welcome.
Now, here it's /welcome/new-user though,
and therefore, this route isn't loaded.
So to load it, we could
change it to /new-user
but that would not be the main idea here.
We want to keep /welcome
and only load this title
if we visit just /welcome
but then we want to be
able to, in addition,
load this content here, this paragraph
if we have the /new-user
part after welcome.
To make this possible,
we have to embrace this new syntax
of adding /* here.
Now the welcome component will be loaded
whenever our path starts with /welcome
instead of having an exact full match.
So therefore with this,
you now see if I visit /welcome/new-user,
we have our title back.
But we still don't see
that paragraph in here.
That's happening because of
another change introduced
by React Router version 6.
When you're working with nested routes,
so with this kind of matching
and then routes defined inside
of the loaded component,
as we have it here,
then the paths of these nested routes
actually are relative to the path
of the parent route.
So that means that this route
here only becomes active
if our path starts with /welcome.
Therefore, the path here already assumes
that we have /welcome at the beginning.
Hence here, we only have
to add the extra part,
the extra elements in the path
that are relevant for this route.
We don't need to repeat /welcome/ anymore,
we can just have new-user here.
And that then tells React Router
that this should become active
if this component is active,
which will be the case
for /welcome/ something.
And then this paragraph should be shown
if we have /welcome/new-user
because this is relative.
Hence now if I save this,
now we have our paragraph here
for /welcome/new-user.
If I just had /welcome,
we would only have the title
because of this relative matching.
And therefore, that's
also not too difficult
to update and it's actually a good change
because we can keep our
nested route paths shorter,
and we don't need to
repeat the entire full path
all the time.
Instead, we can focus on the path elements
that do differ and that are relevant
for identifying this route.
As a side note, if you had a link in here,
then the to prop here
would also be relative.
So in the past with
React Router version 5,
you would have to write
welcome/new-user here
if you wanted to load this route
and then here you would
write your link like this
with version 5.
With version 6, since this
is a link inside a component
that already is loaded through a route,
through this route here,
this changes and that's relative as well.
So links and routes are relative
if they are loaded inside of a component
that is already loaded
because of another route.
So if you're in a nested route, so to say.
So therefore, that's how
you could create such a link
and hence, new-user, this link works
as you would expect it to work.
That's also something worth noting.
Now, with all the changes
I covered up to this point,
I already did cover pretty
much all important changes
you should be aware of.
And you hopefully see
that upgrading really isn't too difficult.
There is another important
change and pattern
that I wanna explore
together with you though.
We can define nested
routes as we do it here,
and there's nothing wrong with it
but you could also write
this here differently.
Instead of defining your
routes in the component
where you want to load
that nested route content,
you could also go for
a different approach.
You could cut this route
here from Welcome.js,
and remove this Routes wrapper
and remove these imports therefore,
and go to your main route
definition file, the App.js file
with the App component in this case.
And then you could also define
nested routes right here
in one and the same place.
So here for the Welcome component
where we wanna have a nested route,
we can now actually use opening
and closing route component tags,
and put our nested routes
between those opening and
closing tags as children.
And that's also the reason why
we have this new element prop
where we point at the
to below that component
because the children
of the route component,
if we have any, are no longer
the to below that components
but instead, possible nested routes.
And, of course, not every
route will have a nested route.
Here in this example,
most routes don't have a nested route
but if you do have a nested route,
as we have it here,
then the advantage of
defining it like this
is that you have all your
route definitions in one place.
And it can simply be easier
to see all supported routes
and to work on this application
if you have all your route
definitions in one place
instead of spreading them
across multiple components
as you did have to do it
with React Router version 5.
That's where you could also define
your nested route like this here.
And what I explained about the
path and so on still applies.
We still have path=new-user here
because it's nested inside
of this welcome route
and hence, this will actually
be /welcome/new-user.
Now, if you use this pattern though,
you have to tell React Router
where this nested content
should be inserted into the DOM
because it was clear when
we had the route definition
in the nested component,
now that we have the route
definition in App.js,
it's not clear where exactly
in Welcome.js this
paragraph should be added.
Should it be added here?
Should it be added here after the link?
How would React Router know?
To let React Router know
where that nested content
should be inserted,
there is another new component,
which you can import
from react-router-dom.
And that's the Outlet component.
You can add it like this,
and this simply is a
placeholder telling React Router
where nested content, nested route content
should be inserted.
So we can add this here in Welcome.
And with our nested route definition here,
this, therefore, will still
work as it did before.
You see I can visit the welcome page
with just /welcome,
and I don't see the nested paragraph.
But if I click this link, I do see it.
And this is an alternative
to defining nested routes
inside of other components.
You could still do that,
as you saw it a couple of minutes ago
but you can also go for
this Outlet approach
with all your routes defined
in one central place,
which might make your
life a little bit easier.
It's up to you which approach you prefer.
Now, to conclude these
updating instructions,
there are two last notes I wanna make.
The first note is about
imperative navigation,
instead of having links
with which you navigate.
Sometimes you want to navigate
when a certain action finishes,
when a button was clicked,
when an HTTP request was sent.
And with React Router version 5,
you could navigate by
using the useHistory hook,
and you could then execute
this hook in your component,
and that would give you a history object.
And then on this history object,
you could push a new route
or replace a route to redirect.
That's the version 5 syntax.
With version 6, useHistory
doesn't exist anymore.
Instead now, we have a useNavigate hook.
This gives us a navigate
object and function
if we execute useNavigate,
and this navigate function can be executed
to navigate somewhere else.
For example, if we would want
to programmatically navigate
to /welcome, this is how we could do it.
And, of course, we would not do that right
in a component like this typically.
Instead, we would do
that in a useEffect hook
or when an HTTP request finished
or anywhere else.
But that's how you could
navigate programmatically.
If you want to redirect,
you can pass a second argument,
which is an object with some options
and there you could set replace to true,
which will replace the current
route with the new one,
which will redirect instead
of pushing the new route
onto the navigation stack.
Now, besides passing a
path here to navigate,
you can also pass in numbers like -1
to, for example, go back
to the previous page
or -2 to go to the page
before the previous page.
Or one to go forward again.
So forward and backward
navigation is also possible
with this navigate function.
You simply pass numbers to it
that tell React Router
by how many pages you wanna
go forward or backward.
So that's programmatic
or imperative navigation
with React Router version 6.
Now, as a last note,
I wanna talk about the prompt component,
which is provided by
React Router version 5.
You could use this component
to prevent accidentally leaving a page
if you have unsaved changes, for example.
In React Router version 6,
at least at this point of time
when React Router version 6 was released,
this component does not exist.
So if you wanna prevent navigation
in case of unsaved changes,
you have to implement your
own workaround for the moment.
So for this reason, you might wanna stick
to version 5 if this is
a super important feature
of your application,
and you're not willing
to come up with your own logic
on how you could prevent navigation.
This component will probably
come back in the future
as it sounds but at the moment,
it's not part of React Router.
And that's just something to note.
But with that, that's it
for this upgrade video
or these upgrade instructions
and I hope this was helpful
for understanding what changed,
and what this means for you,
and how you can update your project.
Attached, you also find a
more complex project updated
to React Router version six,
the final snapshot of our
course section project here.
And that should then also help you explore
and practice how updating works
and how React Router version 6 works.