That's it for this summary about NextJSs.
Now NextJS has more to offer.
There are more configuration options
for getStaticeProps and what you can return there.
There also are ways of optimizing images
with the built-in Next Image component.
You can also easily add authentication,
and add user signup, and login, and logout,
and manage sessions with NextJS.
All of that is possible.
It's very powerful, and all these are things
we're going to take a look at in my full Next Course.
This course here, this tutorial had to goal of summarizing
the core NextJS features.
And had to goal of introducing you to NextJS.
And I hope it's now clear what NextJS is,
and why using it might be interesting.
How it can simplify building complex React apps.
How you can work with pages here,
including dynamic pages.
How pages are pre-rendered,
and how you can fetch data for pre-rendering
with getStaticProps or getServerSideProps.
That for dynamic pages, you also need getStaticProps
to tell NextJS which specific instances of this dynamic
page should be pre-rendered.
And how you can run your own Server-side code in there.
Like here, where we are connecting to a database.
You'll also learn about API routes,
so that it's not just about fetching data all the time.
But that you can include your own rest API
as part of this React project.
And you can add your Server-side code here.
You're own API code, to which you then can send requests
from inside your Client-side application.
Like we're doing it here for storing a new meetup.
And that's NextJS.
A super-powerful framework for React,
which adds many nice features,
which can really make your life easier.
And which can help you solve problems
which you're actually facing in a lot of React projects.