Now that's it for this summary of React.
We had a look at all the core features
that make up react, like State and useEffect,
and Context and Components and Props, of course.
And we built this little demo earlier
and now this demo project here, which uses more features,
including features like Routing and Forms.
Of course, React has more to offer
and you can also dive deeper
into the concepts I touched on here.
For example, useEffect has more to offer
than what we're using here,
but that is why I do have a complete course
with more than 30 hours on this topic.
However, the idea behind this section here
was to give you a summary
of all the core concepts React has to offer.
So that we're all on the same page regarding that.
And with that you are now well-prepared
to continue with this course.