Hey everybody, welcome back to Boost Your
Income with Bootstrap to WordPress, and
we are now in a brand new section where
we're gonna code our resources page.
But first I want to explain to you
the importance of a resources page and
why you should have one in
every one of your websites.
Check it out.
[MUSIC]
Okay, so
this is what the Resources page looks
like on the Bootstrap to
WordPress final WordPress site.
And as you can see it's very simple.
Right now I only have
three resources listed,
I have JustHost, Coda 2 and Dropbox.
You've heard me sing the praises of these
many times, especially Justhost and Coda.
I use them every day, and
they make my life and my business easier.
In fact, they make me money, and
the reason why they make me money is
because they are my affiliate links.
And affiliate links are useful when
you are trying to promote a product
that you stand behind.
Now, there are people who use affiliate
links simply just to make money.
Quick and dirty, and
they've never used the resources before.
However, I don't ever do that.
The resources that I suggest
to you as a student,
are the resources that I would suggest
to my family members, and my friends.
They are amazing, these tools that I use,
I always, always,
always use them extensively before
I even think of recommending them.
Because, I want you to trust me and
the resources that I give to you.
So when I say, check out JustHost,
they're amazing,
I'm saying that because they're
amazing and they make my life easier.
Same with Coda 2, you see it right here.
Coda 2, I use it all the time.
I use it for all my courses, I use it for
my client website, my personal websites.
In fact I'm even making my
mother's website right now.
I'm using Coda 2 and Justhost and Dropbox,
so trust me when I say
these are useful tools.
Now coming back, I digress,
areesources pages are incredibly useful.
Because they let your customers,
your clients, your friends,
your visitors,
your audience know hey these are useful.
And these tools should be tailored
towards your audience and
what they're visiting your site for.
So when they visit my site, for
example right here, BradHussey.ca,
I have a areesources page, obviously.
And I'm listing out my everyday
must have tools, JustHost,
GoDaddy, 1Password, X,
Coda, everything like that.
And then I have code editors,
invoicing and time tracking, so
my resources are tailored to my audience,
you guys, who wanna learn how to code.
You wanna learn how to live like
a freelancer, you wanna live passionately,
you wanna work for yourself.
You kinda wanna live unconventionally, and
so my tools and my resources reflect that.
So when you come to the areesources
page I'm giving you tools that will help
make your life easier,
like they've made my life easier.
And that's what resources pages are for.
So it's very obvious why resources
pages are incredibly important.
A bonus of why resources pages
are incredibly useful and
beneficial is because it's an incredibly
valuable page on your blog, your website,
your client's website, your niche website,
because it can make you money.
And it shouldn't be a surprise to you
when I say you use your affiliate links.
And if somebody clicks on your link,
your product, your resource,
your suggestion,
you can get a commission from that.
Now, they're small commissions,
sometimes they're a couple bucks,
sometimes they could be as high as 100.
But when you have volume and
people visit your site, and
they trust you, and
you give them something useful, and
they click that link,
you're gonna get a commission for it.
In fact just last month, my resources
page, now, I don't make money blogging.
I make money as a web developer,
coding WordPress websites and
building websites, consulting,
things like that, selling courses.
My blog, I don't make money on my blog.
However, my resources page is
the only page that makes me money.
In fact, last month, my resources page,
made me roughly $900.
So it's small in terms of my full time
income, but 900 bucks, that's awesome.
So on top of helping your audience and
listing out useful tools,
you can get paid for having a resources
page, essentially, so good tip.
All right back here to our resources page,
this is the resources page on Bootstrap.
The WordPress, its very simple.
So we're going to code that out,
we're going to use some Bootstrap grids.
And once we get into WordPress I
make it incredibly easy so
that you can add new
resources to your page.
And I think you will find it
incredibly useful, so let's jump in.
[MUSIC]