Hey, everybody.
Welcome
back to Boost Your Income
with Bootstrap to WordPress.
This is a brand new section called,
I don't know.
What is it called?
Environment Setup,
Get Your Project Started.
And in this lecture,
we're going to be downloading Bootstrap.
[MUSIC]
So in this course, we're obviously
gonna be using Bootstrap, so
we're gonna need to download it.
And the easiest way of getting
Bootstrap is by downloading it from
getbootstrap.com.
All you have to do is click the Download
Bootstrap button right in the center of
the screen.
But keep in mind that during the time
of the recording of this course,
I'm using version 3.2.0.
So if you are from the future and
downloading Bootstrap, and
you see that that number is different,
keep in mind that the code
that Bootstrap supplies you,
or the framework itself, or
the CSS classes, the styles,
the JavaScript, might be different.
It might not be that different, you might
still be able to use the exact same
classes and HTML markup that we're
gonna be using with version 3.2.0.
But in some cases,
they make some pretty drastic changes.
And to change component names altogether,
they changed CSS classes,
they removed elements.
So if you're just gonna be
downloading straight from here,
then please keep that in mind.
You might need to make a few changes and
modifications if you are downloading
a much later version.
I do suggest trying it and
having the most up to date version,
cuz that's always the best way.
But if you wanna start by using
the version that I have, or that I'm gonna
be using throughout this course, then
you can download that version as well.
I'll supply it in the download section
of this lecture, and also in the next
lecture where we're gonna download
the full course files with everything.
I'll include the version
3.2.0 in there as well.
So just to wrap up what I just said there,
you could download Bootstrap.
I recommend using the latest version,
but it might be easier for
you during the duration of this
course to use version 3.2.0.
You could download that in the download
section of this lecture, or
wait until the next lecture where you'll
get everything all in one bundle.
So go ahead and hit the Download Bootstrap
button, and I'll show you what you get.
So right here,
they give you three options for 3.2.0.
You just get the Bootstrap version,
you get Source code, or you get Sass.
Nevermind Sass because that's using
a CSS compiler called Sass or less, and
we're not gonna be covering
that in this course.
This right here just gives
you the source less files,
JavaScript font files and the docs.
This also requires a less compiler and
some additional setup.
Skip this one as well.
This is what we're gonna be focusing on,
right here, just the compiled and
minified CSS, JavaScript, and fonts.
No docs or original source files
are included, just the Bootstrap.
Go ahead and hit that button,
and then you'll be given a file,
a zip file that looks like this,
bootstrap-3.2.0.zip.
Again, if you're from the future,
you might have a different version.
This is what the source files
look like if you unzip that.
So you got a CSS folder with a bunch of
CSS, a fonts folder with some font files,
and js with a couple JavaScript files.
That's what we're gonna be using.
And again, you could download it right
from the source at getboostrap.com,
or download 3.2.0 for the duration of
this course in the downloads section,
or wait until the next lecture.
See you there.
[MUSIC]