Hey, everybody, welcome to Bootstrap to WordPress.
I'm your instructor, Brad.
Hey, everybody.
What's up?
Brad Hussie here and welcome to Bootstrap to WordPress.
A little while since I first published this course, but you know what, the numbers don't lie.
We've got a lot of students here, tens of thousands of them with just as many positive reviews.
The only downside, however, is that the course needs a little updating.
Well, that's what I'm working on right now.
It's really interesting to go through these videos and just see the tone and the style and the delivery
that I used to do.
I've done so many tutorials and videos and that, you know, I've I've just gotten better and better
over time.
So it's just funny when I see the intro video and I just kind of cringe to me like.
Hey, everybody, Brad Hussie here and welcome to Bootstrap to WordPress.
We're going to have lots of fun, as you can tell, I'm very excited to do this and I'm using the same
headphones, not even plugged in.
We're going to be learning how to build WordPress websites with Bootstrap as the foundation framework
and under it so that you can build beautiful websites that are responsive in nature.
That doesn't look like a standard bootstrap Web site.
You're going to be able to convert any HTML and Kausar static site into a custom WordPress website,
have a better understanding of piece so that you can build more WordPress Web sites and play around
under the hood.
In WordPress, you're going to understand what's most important about custom post type and advanced
custom fields and WordPress.
It allows you to customize things and kind of create your own content management system within the WordPress
environment.
And that also is a benefit to your clients because you can customize what it is that they update and
edit on their sites.
So while going to bootstrap the WordPress, we're going to have a lot of fun.
And let's do this.