Hey, everybody.
Welcome back to
Boost Your Income with
BootStrap to WordPress.
We're entering a brand new section now
where we're gonna be coding the HTML
templates for the blog overview
page using Bootstrap, of course.
And in this lecture we're gonna be
coding the Basic Markup & Structure for
our blog.html page.
Check it out.
[MUSIC]
All right.
And welcome back.
We're gonna be coding our blog
section here in our static templates.
So, right here, I'm showing you the file
static site that you can also access in
your course files folder in
the final static website section.
And I'm just gonna show you
here what we're gonna build.
It's quite simple really.
It's just a pretty generic but
beautiful blog overview.
You see this,
it's pretty common in a lot of blogs, and
in most blogs actually there's a blog
overview where you see the excerpts of
the blog,
some small snippets of each blog post.
And then you can enter those blog
excerpts to see the full posts.
Right now,
we're just gonna build the overview, so
this is the blog overview page.
We have a nice header here,
with a parallax background and
just the title of the page
right here in the center.
Scroll down, you'll see each blog excerpt.
We're gonna be coding all this,
each of these boxes here with the title.
All this metadata, I guess we can call it.
Post info, comment bubble.
Just some generic text here with
a continue reading button or link, and
then our feature image.
And then we're just gonna copy
that a couple more times because
we just really need to style one of them.
Because in WordPress we're gonna
be using the loop to post and
generate and
display all of the blog posts.
And then we'll also be
coding our sidebars.
But, in this specific lecture, we're going
to just be coding the basic markup so
that we can get going and
hit the ground running.
All right, so jump into your code editor
and create a file called blog.html.
Here in the root of your B2W, if that's
what you called it, static site directory.
I called mine B2W,
whatever you called yours,
make sure to create a file called
blog.html right there beside index.
First thing you're gonna wanna
do is just do the pretty
much what you would always
do with a plain HTML page,
to help you speed up time though,
what I would recommend is
going to your index file and
let's copy everything here
from the body up to the head.
Let's start there.
Paste that and let's get a bit more here.
Scroll down to the very bottom and
grab from HTML all the way up to,
I believe, footer.
Here we go.
In fact, we're gonna grab
this sign up section as well.
So let's grab that, paste that below here.
And let's make sure we got that there.
All right, there's our body.
Good, good.
Okay.
So let's save that.
Check it out here in your browser.
Click on blog.
The blog link and
that should go to your blog.html.
And we've got a pretty
funky looking page here.
I notice there's a couple things missing.
We're gonna need to add our header
because that's pretty global.
So let's go ahead, go back to our code.
And we need to grab, up here in our index,
scroll up,
right under your opening body tag.
We're actually gonna grab
a few of these things.
Header, we're gonna grab the header.
Copy that.
Paste that in your blog
right under the body here.
Make sure it's in there nice.
Good.
Save that.
Let's just check it out.
All right.
There is our header.
Great.
We have our footer down here and
the sign up section which
is global on all the pages.
Let's just go ahead, right away,
first of all just make this tab active.
So just go to your blog.html, make sure to
go down to your nav here and take active,
the class="active" out of the first
list item, which is home.
Add it to the second one.
Now, you don't need to do
this when we're in WordPress,
because WordPress will
automatically do that for you.
But just so you can see what
it looks like, there you go.
Boom, there it is.
So there is the basic markup structure for
our blog.
And basically what we're gonna wanna do
now is make sure we have everything so
that the next lecture we can
start adding our excerpt markup.
I think the first thing I want
to do is go to your body tag.
Add the class of blog because we're gonna
be styling the blog page specifically.
And so, if we can add a class
right up here on the body tag,
we can dive down into some CSS
by selecting class="blog", and
then anything within it, so
we can style those things specifically.
Just gonna make sure
everything's good here.
After header, that's where we're gonna
add our big graphic with the title and
the parallax background.
We'll get there.
And we'll add some more
content right here, basically.
So just get some space and I'll see you
in the next lecture, because that's where
we're gonna start coding the markup for
the header and the excerpts.
And so I'll see you there.
[MUSIC]