Hey, welcome back to Boost Your Income
with Bootstrap to WordPress, and
the selector we're gonna be
creating a resources template.
[MUSIC]
Hey everyone, we're back.
So now what we're gonna do
is create a new page and
template in our WordPress theme for
our resources page.
So here is the resources
page on the final site.
And you can just see it's
pretty straightforward.
We've got kind of a header up
there with a feature image.
Some full width text and
a grid of resources that ideally
will be easily updatable.
And you can add and remove them as
you wish, or as your client wishes.
That's the idea here.
So, in our WordPress site we
don't quite have that yet.
So, what we need to do, before we do
anything, is head back to our dashboard.
And, head to pages.
And we're gonna add a new page, but
first I noticed in the menu there,
we had a sample page link,
which is no longer there.
So just remove that from your menus.
And what I'm also gonna do
while we're here in menus,
is I'm just gonna auto add new
top level pages to this menu.
So we don't have to keep
doing this every time.
The downside of automatically adding new
topical pages is that if you are a little
over eager and add a lot of topical pages,
your menu can get cluttered and
can eventually break.
But if you know you're only gonna have
four, five pages, you should be good.
Okay, back to your pages.
We're gonna add a new page.
And we're just gonna call this resources.
And leave it as is for now.
Just go ahead and hit publish,
because right now we only have
default template and the home page,
so I'm gonna publish that.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna
create a new template specifically for
resources.
Head back to your code editor.
And the first thing you're gonna
wanna do is create a new file and
call that page-resources.php,
kinda like what we did for the page-home.
Go ahead and open that up and
of course it's gonna be blank and empty.
But what you're gonna wanna do is
start off with a php script and
then let Word Press know with a php
comment, what this template is called.
And you just do it like this.
Template mean resources, page.
Now, the comment can look like this.
You don't want it to be so,
take so much space.
It doesn't have to have a specific
formatting as long as it is a comment.
There we go.
So now, if I go back to our dashboard and
I refresh this page,
I should be able to choose Resources
page from the template drop-down.
If I go ahead and update that,
I'm gonna have nothing to view,
it's gonna be an empty page.
But we know it works.
So, why don't we just grab that
static content from the HTML file?
The resources.html from your static site.
And put it into our resources page.
So you only need to
grab from feature image
because we already have the header and
the footer.
So grab from feature image all
the way down until you get to
the end of the container.
So just before sign-up section
cuz sign-up section and
footer, they are included in the footer.
Go ahead and what we're gonna
do is paste that right here.
There we go.
We should have everything now.
Now, it's all static, if I save that, and
just give it a little check here,
I should see some really ugly content.
Great.
Well, it's connecting,
so it's pretty straightforward
from this point.
I'm gonna leave that for the next lecture,
I wanted you to have a little break from
the previous one, and yeah,
I'll see you in the next one.
We're going to start
making this more dynamic.
Awesome.
[MUSIC]