Hey everybody, welcome back to Boost
Your Income with Bootstrap to WordPress.
In this lecture,
we are going to download WordPress.
[MUSIC]
Okay, I thought before we get into
any super heavy duty WordPress stuff,
I wanna keep this intro lecture so simple.
It's probably the easiest lecture
you're ever going to do with me.
Navigate to wordpress.org/download.
Click on Download WordPress.
In my case, I have 4.0.
That's what we're gonna be using for
this course.
If yours is later, feel free to use the
newest version if you are a risk taker.
You might come across some bugs
as we go through the development.
If you want to start off a little easier,
I've included in
the Download WordPress B folder,
in the course files, WordPress 4.0.
Feel free to use that during
the duration of this course
while we're building the site.
But afterwards,
immediately upgrade to the future version
that you might see at this point.
And then do some debugging.
All right, so there's WordPress, or
you could just download it right here.
Make sure it downloaded properly.
There we go, I've got it.
It's right there.
That's all.
See you in the next lecture.
[MUSIC]