Hey everyone.
Welcome back to Boost Your Income with
Bootstrap to WordPress.
In this video we are going to code and
style our comment section in our blog.
[MUSIC]
All right, so
it's time to code our comments section.
Now, one thing to note before we start.
I wanna show you what it looks
like here in the static version.
It's very simple and I,
on purpose, left a few things out.
Because in WordPress, the comments
section, when you add the comments,
it's dynamic, and a bunch of information
is added by default by WordPress.
Such as profile pictures,
the time that they posted,
their comment, reply links, and
all these things like that.
Things that I didn't really want
to code in the static site.
It's kind of a little redundant,
because we don't have to really
code it when we get into WordPress.
Because it's already built out.
And all we have to do is style it.
So just wanted to give you a little.
Something to look at and just to get
familiar with how the comments work.
So I'll show you the blog post
here in the final WordPress site.
And at the bottom you
can see the comments.
They look a little different from
our comments here, as you can see.
So you can see there's a profile picture,
and
then Brad -- says,
the date stamp, comment, reply link.
Things like that.
So
you can see the general styles are there.
And the comments,
they look a little different.
So that's why I'm not going to worry
too much about how they look on
the static site.
Because they will be
different in the final site.
At the bottom,
the form looks essentially the same.
So that's important.
So why don't we just jump in and
start coding.
All right.
Here we go.
Code editor.
Go back to your post.html and
under main, so right here, under posts.
That's where we're going to want
to add our comments section.
So, start off by adding a
with the ID of comments.
And within there, we're going to add
a  with the class of comments wrap.
Okay.
And then we'll have a level three heading.
And I'm just going to say four comments.
Right here is where the text
is basically whatever it says.
Three thoughts on whatever.
You know, yada, yada, yada.
So we're just going to
put generic text there.
So, here's just a little flag
to make you remember this.
These comments will have an image and
more information when we use WordPress.
All right.
After here, let's add an ordered list
with the class of comments-list.
And I'm trying my best here to
use actual WordPress markup.
So that we could style it properly.
We don't have to change our styles
too much, once we get into WordPress.
Now let's add a list item
with the class of comment.
Okay.
And in here we will say.
Let's just go.
For our own sake here.
We're going to add level four heading and
say John Smith.
Let's have a small tag.
We'll have a bullet there.
Let's say August 12th.
Not even today's date.
Just making one up.
And then a  with
the class of comment.
Body.
Make sure there's a dash there.
Great.
Whoops.
Within there, we'll have a paragraph tag.
Well, let's just put some
lorem ipsum in there.
Good enough.
And then within this list item,
these are gonna be replies.
We're going to have another unordered
list with a class of children.
And that will have a list item
with the class of comment.
Okay.
And then we'll have another level four
heading.
And let's say Chris McCooper.
Small tag.
And then a bullet here.
August 12, 2014.
And then we're going to have comment body.
Lorem ipsum.
Just copy this and paste it in.
Remember, it's not really that important.
This section, cause we're going to be
a little bit different in Word Press.
Here we go.
And within Chris McCooper's list item,
we're gonna have another nested,
ordered list.
The class of children.
And we'll have a list item with a comment.
So let's just copy.
Well no, let's just type it out here.
List item with class of comment and
within there,
we'll have another level four heading.
Whoops.
Level four.
This will be Johnny Dee.
A small tag here with a bullet.
Say August 12, 2014.
After that we'll have comment-body.
And then we'll have just
another paragraph tag there.
With some lorem ipsum.
Here we go.
And
after Our, I believe,
list item way out here.
Before the end of comments-list.
Let's just add one more list
item that's not a child.
This will be a top-level list item.
comment.
And this will be level four heading.
This one will be Jane Smith.
And again.
Bullet.
August 9, 2014.
And then comment, body.
In there, we'll have just some
generic lorem ipsum again.
Paragraph, lorem ipsum.
All right.
Save that.
Let's see what that looks like so far.
More comments, John Smith,
Jessica Cooper, Johnny D, Jane Smith.
There we go.
And now, after our comments list.
So we're gonna have our
leave a comment form.
So let's have an ID.
with the ID of leave-comment.
And that will look a little like this.
Level three.
Leave a comment, form,
and a paragraph tag here.
Your email address will not be published.
Required fields are marked.
Span tag with the class of required.
And a little asterisk.
Okay.
After that paragraph,
another paragraph tag.
This one will have the class
of comment-form-author.
We'll have a label.
Let's not add a four there.
You can if you want, but
WordPress does all this.
Name, input with the ID
of author in the type.
We'll do this here.
Text.
There we go.
Copy this again.
Instead of comment-form-author,
this will be comment-form-email.
Again change this to email and
then down here, actually we don't need.
Let's add, because we did an ID here,
I just realized,
let's do a for, might as well,
author, for author.
Again, these don't really matter how
you code this out because it's gonna be
a little different in WordPress anyway.
Label for email and
then this one will be email.
Copy this out.
Paste it below that one.
This one will be comment-form-URL.
Website not required.
This will be for URL.
Type will be URL.
Let's change this type to email
up here cuz, be more semantic.
ID URL.
Another paragraph tag.
Comment-form-comment.
And this will say comment.
Technically that would be required for
comment.
And this will be instead of an input,
textarea.
Let's put the name.
No.
WordPress will do all that.
ID.
Comment, take out calls and
rows, or let's play with this.
Calls 45.
Rows 8.
Textarea, good.
And then one more paragraph tag.
Class of form.
Submit.
And then this will be an input.
The type will be submit.
Name will be submit.
Okay.
Give that a save.
Check it out.
There's our form.
Pretty simple.
Now let's go into CSS and style it up.
Scroll down to your comments section,
right here.
We gave a little spot here.
And we're going to start
down here at the bottom.
And start styling our comments.
So we're gonna select ID comments,
then H3.
Text-align center.
We want to center that up.
Comments H4.
Font size 1.3em.
That means it'll be,
I guess you could consider
that 130% larger than
the default font size.
Font.
The font size,
if you were to say is 12 pixels,
1em is 12 pixels.
1.3em is, I believe that would
count as 30% larger than 12 pixels.
So whatever that equals out to.
It's just a little bit of math.
It's a bit larger than default font size.
Comments ol.
List style, none.
Padding 0.
Margin 0.
Comments ol li.
Background, I'm gonna use some RGBA 000.
And then 0.02.
That's very small,
very tiny alfa transparency.
So, it's basically black but
very, very transparent.
You can change that if you
want to a solid color.
But, I just wanna do this, because I
wanna show you what we're gonna be doing.
It's a little bit of a magic trick.
10 pixels, 20 pixels, margin, 10 pixels,
0 so 10, top and bottom, 0 left and right.
Webkit-border-radius will be 4 pixels.
Let's do moz-border-radius 4 and
straight up border-radius 4.
And then border will be solid one pixel.
RGBA 0, 0, 0, 0.03.
So just a little darker
than the background.
And now let's style comments.
ol li and then ol, the class of children.
So we're selecting those children.
Padding 0.
The style none.
Font size 0.96M.
So just under the default font size.
And the reason why I'm using ems
is because with each child within,
that's nested, so with each reply the font
size will gradually get smaller just by
a little bit, by 4% I believe.
And then we're gonna style,
leave-comment.
And this will say margin, 40 pixels, 0, 0.
Padding will be 20 pixels, 0, 0.
Border top, solid, 1 pixel, EEE.
Now, let me just explain here why I
use RGBA, here, in the background.
And why I'm using this.
Because, with every li that's
nested within another li,
the background is gonna
get slightly darker.
Because we're using a transparent
background that is 2% alpha transparency.
So it's going to slightly get darker and
darker as it stacks on top.
So if we save that,
I'll show you what that looks like.
Here we go.
You can see, hopefully you can see,
that the background is getting
slightly darker with each reply.
So, this has a cool cascade effect.
Like that.
Now,
we're just going to do one more
thing here with the comments.
Scroll back up to the very very top of,
blog.
And in there, we're going to add,
after the widget,
the ID of comments.
And then down here after post body, we're
gonna add comments and then comments-wrap.
Save that.
That will give you this look right there.
Boom.
So now you can see the background
a little bit better,
as they cascade within each other.
Kinda has this cool effect.
And you see the font size
gets slightly smaller.
Same happens on the default or
the final WordPress site.
You can see cascades font size just
gets a little bit smaller, and
the background just gets a little
bit darker with each new reply.
Cool, that is it for the comment section.
You did it.
You did the blog, the overview, and
the blog detail, the full post.
All right.
So hang on tight,
because in the next series of lectures
we're going to be coding a lot more.
Much more, in fact.
But the next few lectures will
be about the resources section.
And I will explain to you why resource
pages are incredibly important for
your blogs, your client websites,
personal websites, your niche websites,
your company websites, if I didn't all
ready say that, and why they will be
beneficial to you, your customers, your
clients, and how they can make you much.
See you there.
[MUSIC]