Guys I gotta tell you about
this contact form plugin.
[MUSIC]
So now we need to add the contact form
plugin which is Contact Form 7 if you do
a quick search here in your plugins.
Add a new plugin and
search for Contact Form 7.
It will show up here at the very top as
the most downloaded content form plugin.
I'm pretty sure it's up there with
22.6 million downloads at this point.
So it's super good, infinitely
flexible and you can keep it simple or
you can go intense.
We're gonna keep it simple but we're gonna
do some custom work within Contact Form 7.
They have a really good documentation
on the website for Contact Form 7,
and you can always follow that
if you have any questions or
problems really good
documentation on the site there.
So we're gonna install that, go ahead and
install and activate that plug in.
And when you're ready jump into the plug
in itself right here under contact.
So you just click on contact,
which will be installed.
That's Contact Form 7 and you can go
ahead and add a new contact form.
Or you can add,
modify the one that's currently there.
I'm just gonna show you
what's currently there so
you can see an example of
how Contact Form 7 works.
So this is basically how it works.
It has its own little syntax
of how you put in inputs and
labels and classes and so on and so forth.
You could see here if I
wanna put in a text input,
you would put it in square brackets,
and you would say text and
if it was required, right after the type
of input you have an asterisk, and
then your-name is basically
what the input name is.
Same here, you've got an email
input to require your email.
That is the name attribute of the input.
And then down here we have text which
is a text field and your subject.
And then we have text area which is
a text area and it's not required.
Your message is the name attribute and
then down here we have a submit
button with a value of Send.
And over here you can generate tags,
and it's really cool what you can do.
You can literally do all the inputs,
and it's cool.
You've got text fields, emails, you got
numbers, you can do spin box, dates,
drop down menus check boxes acceptance.
You can do quiz, you can add captchas,
file uploads and submit buttons.
So it's pretty cool and so
down here you could see
in order to send them an email over
the mail server in this mail metabox.
You could see who its going to so
youremail.com and
from who's it from and
then the subject and additional headers.
Then in the message body, and
this is editable, you can
update how the message body displays
using the, and you can see in the syntax,
to use the score brackets, and
then the mean of the name attribute.
That will give you the value of the input.
So your name If you look up here, the text
box had your name as the name attribute,
which will give you that value and
then that will display an email.
So it's pretty cool.
And then it's customizable down here.
You could do a lot more.
And you could do additional settings
like JavaScript if you wanna submit to
a separate page and blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, it's really cool.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna add
a new contact form, and I'm just gonna say
Primary Contact Form, and down here,
I'm gonna remove everything.
And what we're gonna do now is we're gonna
jump over into the Code Editor because
we're gonna code right in here and
then copy and paste it.
Because there's actually quite
a bit of HTML that we have to do.
Because we have to copy from
our static contact page and
then make that friendly with
Contact Form 7, using their syntax.
So go ahead and open the static
version of your contact page and
then copy the form right here.
Copy that, paste it in your empty page
here and let's start making this
friendly for contact room seven.
You don't need the form tag, because
it's gonna dynamically add that itself.
So remove the form tag and
then we're gonna leave any structural kind
of layout markup, like the rows and the
columns, form groups and so on, so forth.
So right here in the label,
that's fine, we'll leave Name.
But the input,
this is going to be done byContact Form 7.
So right after it I'm gonna do
the syntax for Contact Form 7 and
then we'll remove the R
coded HTML version.
Open and close square brackets and this
is a text field I want it to be required
the name
attribute I want to be your name and
then the class.
If you wanna add a class to Contact Form
7 input, you just say class: and
then you could put your class here,
form-control.
If you want another class, you just say
class again and than input-lg, great.
And then I want an id.
Same deal, id:contact-name.
Obviously, you can only have one id,
so you can't put multiple.
And then placeholder looks like so,
placeholder "Your name".
So that is the syntax.
We're gonna do that for email as well.
Well, after we remove
this hard-coded input.
We got our email input here.
This is gonna be opening and
closing square brackets, email.
It's required, your-email will be the name
attribute, class is form-control.
We have another class,
and that is input-lg.
ID is contact-email
the placeholder space your email.
Great and then remove the input the hard
coded one and we have our text area.
Actually we're gonna put
a subject as well, why not?
So I'm gonna copy this col-sml-12 and
I'm gonna paste it right before and
I'm gonna change this HTML and
this is gonna say label and
we're gonna have class sr only for
screen readers only for contact subject.
And then,
we're going to have to say subject, and
then right here we're gonna
use our Contact Form 7 syntax.
Text* your-subject class:form-control
class:input-lg id:contact-subject,
so that label has something to associate.
Placeholder "Your subject",
you get the idea.
And now we have the text area.
Right here we're gonna say in
square brackets [textarea].
This is also required,
your-message class:form-control
class:input-lg id:contact-words x3,
means it could do rows and columns.
And to do rows in a text area the syntax,
you just have to say x3 because
I want the rows to be three.
Placeholder "Your message" awesome.
And now the submit button, well first get
rid of this text area, submit button,
this is how we do this in Contact Form 7.
Submit class:btn
class:btn-info class:btn-lg.
Another class:pull-right, and
then just "Get in touch" and that is the
value that will display for the button.
And then remove the hard coded one.
Copy this, paste it in the form here.
There you go and down here,
make sure to update the information
where you want the form to send to.
So you could put to your@email.com,
obviously your real one.
And then from your name, and then the
email, you could even do something like,
you can select the email
that it was sent from.
So up here, you have your email,
your-name your-mail.
Now I'll put the person's email so
you can hit reply and reply right to them.
Your subject, this is all good.
And everything looks good on here, your
name, your email, your message, perfect.
And then you go ahead and save that.
Head back to your contact page and
then all you need to do,
to add that Contact Form 7 in there is use
the short code that they provide here.
So just copy, what they give right here
and then go back to the page, paste that.
Contact Form 7, perfect, update.
Now if I go and view that page,
we'll see what happens.
There it is, and it's almost perfect,
something going on here and
I'm assuming it's just
a little bit of an html bug.
It looks like to me I just got a couple
break, I got a break tag here,
and a couple empty tags.
And it's probably just because
when you go back to here and
I think what is happening is I
have these comments here and
I think it's translating them
into break tags or something.
So what we're gonna do is go
back to our code editor and
remove all of those comments.
We don't actually need them and
copy this again, paste it back.
Save, let's refresh this page and
we're good to go.
There it is,
now this should technically work but
if your unlocal host a lot of the time,
the email server won't actually send, so
you'll have to wait until you're
actually live to test this out.
But it does have validation and
everything is all set up, good to
go in your Contact Form 7, awesome.
That's it for this module, for the contact
page and you pretty much nailed it.
The only other thing is,
I just see up here
that the contact tab isn't
highlighted when you're on it.
So when you're on these pages,
these styles should actually be in there.
So while we're here,
let's just jump into our CSS, real fast.
So here in our CSS we just need
to scroll to the menu section.
Let's just go down to 5.2.
We just need to add a couple
WordPress specific styles here and
right here we're gonna select navbar-nav.
Directly under that li with the class of
current_page_item and a tag within it.
And this is automatically added
by WordPress to the markup and
if you just inspect
the element on the live site
that you're working on you can see
when you're on a current page the list
items of the navigation have classes
That are called current page item.
And there are also other
classes that are added as well.
So, like this,
navbar-nav directly under that
I also want to select
li.current_page_parent a and
the color with be white.
I save that.
That should solve the problem,
there we go.
Any page I go to now,
we should be good to go and looking nice.
All right, so that's it for
this module, the contact page.
And basically you did most of the site.
There's quite a bit left
in terms of clean up, and
making it a little bit more advanced,
and extending your WordPress site.
And that's what the next
section's all about,
we're gonna extend the functionality
of our WordPress site.
So I'll see you there.
[MUSIC]