Hey everyone, welcome back to Boost
Your Income with BootStrap WordPress.
This program is called Creating
your "Underscores" Starter Theme.
[MUSIC]
All right,
now that we've downloaded WordPress.
Very simple lecture,
probably my favorite simple lecture.
We're going to start getting
into the heavier stuff.
Although this lecture is a little
bit light weight as well,
it does get pretty intense but
that is great.
No pain no gain when it
comes to this stuff.
Okay, so basically what we're
gonna do is we're gonna use
a starter theme called Underscores,
and the URL is underscores.me.
And basically what they do
is give you just a starter template for
a WordPress theme.
There's nothing in it,
like it doesn't have a theme prebuilt.
It's not like when you go
to themeforest.com and
you buy a WordPress theme
that a developer built.
It's just a skeleton bare bones theme
structure so you can build on top of it.
It gives you all the default WordPress PHP
templates that you need to code.
It gives you a basic style sheet
that you can add your own styles to.
It's just a bare bones
plain starter them so
that you can build your own theme on top.
The reason why you want this is because
it's gonna save you so much time.
Literally hours and hours and hours and
hours and so much of a headache.
I don't know why you
wouldn't start with this.
Most of the developers that I know who
build custom WordPress themes start with,
in fact, Underscores,
because it saves so much time.
And the bigger the project,
the more hours you're gonna save.
So don't reinvent the wheel because
it's already here for you and
you don't need to be a hero.
Basically starter theme called
Underscorers, meant for
hacking, dont' use me as a parent theme,
instead try turning me into the next most
awesome WordPress theme out there,
which is what we're about to do.
Ultra minimal CSS and
well commented HTML5 templates,
404 template, sample headers and
a bunch of other fun stuff that we can
use when recording our WordPress themes.
So, head to underscores.me and
what we're gonna do is just
create our Underscores theme.
So the theme name,
let's call it Bootstrap to WordPress.
Theme slug bootstrap2wordpress.
It could be whatever, but I wanted
to call it bootstrap2wordpress and
if you could keep it the same as me,
it might be easy for you.
So that in the future when we're
doing these lectures maybe
you might see that my code's
a little bit different than yours.
Because you might have called
your theme something different or
have a different slug.
So, keep it the same for now and
in your future WordPress themes
you could do whatever you want.
Author Brad Hussey,
you could put your name.
Author URI that is your website and
a custom WordPress theme using Bootstrap.
Don't sassify because we're not gonna
be using sass, we're just using CSS.
Generate that, and
you will get a download with your
Bootstrap to WordPress starter theme.
Here it is, so
you have all the basic pages and
templates that we're gonna be using,
404, archive,
comments, basic content pages,
footer, functions very important.
We have an includes folder with
a few things if we wanted to
do some stuff like that.
JS folder, some layouts,
basically we're gonna use
this skeleton template to create our
own theme, so basically that's it.
And basically in the next lecture,
we are going to install WordPress,
get it started on our local server and
we're gonna install our starter theme so
that we can actually get started and
get into the good stuff.
See you there.
[MUSIC]