Hello everybody.
Welcome back to Boost Your Income
with Bootstrap to WordPress and
in this lecture we're going to be
downloading the final course files.
[MUSIC]
All right.
So in this lecture I have provided
a link to download the Bootstrap
to WordPress final course files.
Once you've went ahead and downloaded that
asset, you will be delivered a zip file.
And that zip file, if you open it up and
unzip it it'll give you a folder and
that folder will look
a little something like this.
It should have four folders within it.
As time goes on,
I will likely add more folders, so
this lecture might be slightly out of
date in the future, but not so much.
We'll just have, I'll make sure to update
the course files so you can go back and
redownload them if there
are any new assets or
folders that you would need to or
would like to download.
So at the time of this recording,
we have A, B, C, and D.
A is Download Bootstrap and
I provided Bootstrap 3.2.0.
B is Download WordPress and
I have provided WordPress 4.0.
So a little note on that, once we get
into the development of WordPress,
you have to download WordPress
in order to work with it.
So at the time of this recording.
We will be using WordPress 4.0.
I suggest using WordPress 4.0 only for
the duration of this course.
Then what you're gonna want
to do is update WordPress.
If you have newer version of WordPress,
because it is always important
to update WordPress.
Then check to see if
everything still works.
Sometimes when WordPress makes updates,
a few bugs will appear.
And while I'll do my best to be on top of
those major changes and let you know if
there's anything you need to do in order
to make sure your website is up to date.
And when I say website I mean
the website we're gonna be building.
It will also be your challenge to see if
you could squash those bugs yourself.
See we have final static website.
There's a folder in here called B2W-
Static and that is the static website.
That static website has all
of the HTML templates and
assets that we'll be using to start
our Bootstrap static website.
So we have our index we have post,
resources, blog, and contact.
And then in our assets folder,
we have CSS, fonts, Img for image, and js.
You might recognize that the js, fonts and
CSS folders are basically the Bootstrap
files that we downloaded.
There are a few modifications in here.
We have a custom CSS file which is not
included in the bootstrap download.
We have a folder called Font Awesome
with a couple folders within there.
And that is for the custom icon font
we'll be using for this course.
Pretty cool.
We'll get into that a little later.
The images, we have all of the image
assets that we will be using for
the website.
And I recommend just grabbing those
because I don't have a PSD file with these
assets for you and
we are just going to be focusing on
the development not the design aspect.
So go ahead and
take these you'll find them in
the Images folder, look in the assets.
And we'll get to that
once we start coding, js.
We have a main.js,
that's also new and jQuery.
We'll get into that a little bit later.
Don't worry about it right now.
Just trying to show you
what's in our course files.
So recap, A, B, C and D.
A is Bootstrap the version we're using for
this course.
B is WordPress again the version for
C final static website.
That's all the final assets.
And then D miscellaneous.
So right now there's
only one file in here,
the Bootstrap to WordPress information
architecture or wire frames and site map.
You can see here, so go ahead and
just check that out if you're interested,
just to see how to do a wire frame.
This folder will likely be
updated as time goes on.
So at the time of the recording,
there's only one file,
but maybe when you download it,
there may be six files.
All right.
So that is the course files.
So go ahead and download those and
we can get started.
Because in the next lecture we're going
to be setting up our project environment.
So making sure we get
everything sorted out so
once we start development hopefully
we worked out the initial kinds.
Okay, so you there.
[MUSIC]