Hey, new lecture.
Add a feature image and a fallback image.
[MUSIC]
So in this lecture what we wanna do is
first of all hook this in properly,
make it look a little bit nicer, which
is fairly straightforward and simple.
And then, what we want to do
is work on the feature image,
and that's this right here.
So this is a feature image that you
can attach to pages in WordPress, and
the way we wanna go about it is have
the ability to give the user or
your client or yourself,
the ability to upload a feature image.
And if they don't add a feature image
which is a very likely scenario,
have a fallback image.
So that the page layout
maintains it's beauty.
So in your code editor.
The first thing we need to do to just
make this look a little bit nicer,
is get the header.
That's one thing we forgot to do, and at
the bottom we just need to get the footer.
Here we go, and
then that should make the page
look more like the rest of the website.
There we go.
Now, we gotta just make this dynamic, so
let's do this header up here
in the feature image, rather.
Okay, so what we need to do is check
to see, if there's a post thumbnail and
if there is,
add an inline style right here in the tag.
Use a style attribute to pull in
a background image with the dynamic
background URL.
Otherwise, we just need
to fall back to this, so
that looks a little bit like this,
has post thumbnail.
There we go.
And if it has the post thumbnail, let's
just do a little bit more PHP here, else.
Just doing the basic structure first,
and then we'll start
explaining how this all works at the end
here, I wanna close that if L statement.
So basically right here,
check for feature image.
Image, there we go.
Okay.
Whoops, this isn't right.
There we go.
Close that properly.
Okay.
So in here basically,
we just need to copy this.
And instead of having the feature
image default be the class here,
we wanna just get rid of that.
Because that's what gives
a background image to this section,
to this specific tag.
So get rid of that.
We're actually gonna add
a style attribute here.
And then, we're gonna go background,
then URL and
then in there is where we
want to put the actual URL.
And that's gonna be no repeat and then,
we're gonna have background size, cover.
Okay, and then basically,
all we need to get is this background URL.
Okay, so in order to do this,
we can't just use PHP to say pull in
the WordPress function to post thumbnail
because that pulls in an entire image tag.
We need to get the URL for
the feature image.
So what is the actual path to
the image in the database?
Stored on our server and so
the way that we do that is
we need to create a variable
because that's good practice.
Let's just say thumbnail
URL that makes sense.
And then in here,
we're gonna use a couple functions
together to get us that thumbnail URL.
So there is one function, built into
WordPress called WordPress Attachment URL.
And so that returns the URI for
an attachment.
So basically,
that kind of gets us what we need.
So outputs something like this
example.net, WordPress content uploads, so
on and so forth.
But we need to be able to get the ID of
the attachment that we're looking for,
and we could very easily just
hardcode that attachment ID in there.
We could just go find out the specific
image we like, find out the ID that was
stored in the data base and then, just
type this out and say, whatever the ID is.
But that's bad practice
because it's hard coded.
But if we remove that attachment, and what
if we want to change the feature image?
Then this isn't gonna work for us.
So we need to dynamically find
out the post thumbnail ID.
Based on the feature image that
was uploaded to this page.
Thankfully, we can do that with
a pretty straight forward function,
inward press called get post thumbnail ID.
And essentially,
it will return the ID of feature image
attached to the post,
that's exactly what we need.
So we just need to put
that function in here.
So get post thumbnail id and
that requires an argument in here.
And we're gonna grab the post,
which is what we're on and
we're gonna grab the ID from it.
So this will get us the ID and
it will store the URL with
the ID right in this variable.
Then we could just very easily go php,
echo, thumbnail, url.
And that should get us
what we're looking for.
Let's just check.
So nothings broken but
why don't we test to see.
So let's replace the feature image,
cuz right now, it's in the fall back,
why don't we just put,
let's try this hipster stuff.
I'm gonna set that feature image and I'm
gonna update that and see what happens.
And there we go.
There is our background image.
And if I remove it, and then update again,
then that should fall back to our default.
There it is.
Perfect.
All right.
So I saw a couple of things in here,
before we move on to the next lecture.
This should actually be a dynamic title.
So all you gotta do there is just PHP,
use the title function.
Built in WordPress function.
And do the same thing down here.
Excellent.
That's it for this lecture.
We'll see you in the next lecture.
We're gonna move on to
the rest of the content, here.
[MUSIC]