Hey guys welcome back to Boost Your Income
with Bootstrap to WordPress.
This is a cool lecture,
I'm gonna introduce you to an awesome,
free plugin called Advanced Custom Fields.
[MUSIC]
All right, amazing plugin, advanced
custom fields so that's what it's called.
Basically, everything that we
just did in our dashboard for
the custom fields, advanced custom
fields takes that process and
makes it way more intuitive,
way easier to work with.
It's better for you as a developer and
it's better for
your client when they're in the dashboard
and trying to update their content.
Essentially, what advanced custom fields
lets you do instead of just having,
when you add a new page and
you have a new template like we
created our home page template.
Instead of just having our text bar and
our big text box, or our text field and
a big text box and then some custom
fields, you can totally modify
the input that you can have on your pages.
So instead of just text field,
text box, you can have text field.
You can have an image.
You can have custom text fields,
custom text boxes, radio buttons.
All these sorts of things that allow you
to customize what you want to have on
the front end of your site rather than
just using this to put into some HTML.
So you'll see what I mean as we start
going through and using custom fields,
advanced custom fields.
But here's the website.
And the best part about it is it's free.
Totally free.
And I've used the free version
on a handful of sites.
Probably about 15 or
20 sites at this point.
Maybe that's more than a handful.
And I've never looked back, it's amazing.
The only thing is that
if you want even more
power and customization,
you could get the pro version.
And it's really not that expensive, and
like I said it's not
It's not required at all.
I think it's, so
the personal license is 25 bucks,
Australian, so it's really not a lot.
And I've only used
a personal license once.
I bought one personal license on a certain
site, and it lets you do certain things
like repeater fields and gallery fields,
flexible content options pages.
Stuff that you don't need to do yet.
And when you get to that point,
you'll know.
You'll think oh, you know what, it'll be
so great to have the ability to do this.
Like have a repeater section.
But it's not required and it's most
certainly not required for this course.
Although if you want to get it, and you
think, aw man, I'm totally gonna get this,
it's amazing, I know, I'm gonna use that.
Then go ahead.
It's great.
It works seamlessly with the free version.
So you don't need to worry about that.
So basically go ahead and download the
free version of advanced custom fields.
You can do it right here.
You can hit Download & Install.
It'll take you to the plugin directory.
So you can just download it right here, or
what would be better is just
going straight to your dashboard,
going to Plugins > Add New and
search for Advanced Custom Fields.
That'll come up here at
the very top by Elliot Condon.
I think I pronounced that right.
Maybe it's Condon.
Condon?
I don't know.
Go ahead and install that plugin.
And make sure to activate it once
it's unpacked and installed.
And then you will have access
to custom fields right here.
So, if you click on that, it gives you
a section here called field groups.
And then, basically, here's where
you start using your custom fields.
So, we're gonna get into the real world
application when it comes to this site
in the next few lectures.
So I won't go through with how to work
with this now because we're gonna be doing
some really cool stuff
in the next lecture.
So see you there.
[MUSIC]