[NOISE]
Where is it?
I can't find it.
404, lecture not found.
Bad joke.
[MUSIC]
So, what is a useful, and engaging 404?
Well, for those of you that don't know,
a 404 is an error that the server throws
at you, at the browser when you come
across a page that is no longer there,
or was never there in the first place.
So, a lot of the time when you build
a site, you kind of overlook this part.
Or you don't even add this part at all.
But in WordPress you can easily overlook
it, and you get a page like this.
Now maybe, it would look a little bit
better, and it would be in a container.
Like oops, that page can't be found,
search for something, is kind of useless.
You're probably gonna
lose your visitor anyway.
So, what can we do to make this
a little bit more useful, and engaging?
So that,
when a visitor comes across a 404,
which they will at some point,
or some visitor will.
How can you engage them into your site,
and have the keep going, and
maybe give them some value,
to keep them sticking around.
Well, that's what we're
gonna do right now.
And it's really simple.
And we're just recycling parts of
the site, to add into our 404.
In your Code Editor,
open up the 404.php that's built
right in to the WordPress site here.
And then you're gonna get just
a template for displaying 404 pages, and
that's what you already just saw.
But we're gonna make it a lot better.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna start
by adding a feature-image at the very top.
So, if you open your,
let's say, Resources page,
we're just gonna copy just the
feature-image content here, the section.
Don't get the php, or anything,
just the feature-image part.
And right here,
what we're gonna do is at the very top,
under get_header,
we're going to paste that in there.
Now, remove the style, and
all that sort of stuff here.
What we should have done is actually
just copied the fallback feature-mage,
but we can just add those classes here.
Feature-image-default-alt.
Okay.
And then regarding the title,
what we're gonna do here,
we're just gonna type in some text.
And that's just gonna be, Bummer!
That page can't be found!
There we go.
And now, what we're gonna do is we're
gonna clean this stuff up, right here.
So, let's just remove all of these.
Remove everything all the way down until
get footer, and leave get_footer there.
So, this is all we have for
our 404 right now.
We're gonna start off by adding
a div the class of container.
Make sure to close that.
And then in there, we're gonna
add a div with the id of primary,
and a class of row.
Within primary we're gonna add a main tag,
the id of content.
And then class, here we go.
And then in there,
we're gonna have another div, and
that's gonna be div with the class
of error-404, and not-found.
So, a lot of markup here.
And then another div in here,
we got a lot of markup, guys.
Div class of page-content.
Now, we're going to inside
page-content at a level two heading,
and that's gonna say, Don't fret!
Let's get you back on track.
And then what we're gonna do,
is we're gonna have a series of content
that's just all from over our site, and
we're gonna give it to them right there.
So that, they can take action on it,
and give them some value right away.
So we're gonna have Some resources here.
We're gonna spit out our RESOURCES.
And so right here,
I'm gonna have a level three heading, and
say Resources, paragraph tag and
this will just say,
Perhaps you were looking for
a specific resource?
And now, instead of just hard coding some
resources, we can actually loop through,
and get the actual resources.
All the resources that we actually
have stored in our database.
So go to your page.resources.php, and
down where you have your resource-row.
[SOUND] Go ahead, and copy resource-row,
right down to where resource-row ends.
Copy everything inside of it.
This is what's great about this.
All you got to do now really,
is just paste that, and
we're going to simplify it just a touch.
There we go.
They're gonna tap that in, so we're gonna
leave that as is except for right here.
We're gonna have the excerpt instead of
the content because the content is quite
large, and
the excerpt will give us a smaller,
more condensed version of the content.
Let's make sure we have the rest of our
markup before we go, and view that.
I wanna make sure,
you see something good here.
After main,
I want you to add your sidebar.
And we're gonna have an html.comment here.
I'm gonna say SIDEBAR, and then I'm
gonna have my aside tag with a class of
col-sm-4, and then in here,
php get_sidebar.
This would be a great time
to use a custom sidebar,
if you wanted to use dynamic sidebar.
And create a custom sidebar, and
register it in your functions.php, and
then go to your appearance widgets,
add some widgets to that sidebar, and
then it will show up on your 404 page.
Perfect time to use that.
I'm just gonna use get_sidebar for
now, but you're always free
to customize as you wish.
Let's save this, and check it out so far.
Bummer!
That page can't be found.
Don't fret!
Let's get back on track.
Resources.
Perhaps you were looking for
a specific resource?
So, we don't really see anything.
Something broke.
Let's go back, and see why that is.
Well, I know exactly why.
We didn't actually initiate, and
we'll re-initiate the WordPress query.
We need to actually have that in there.
[SOUND] So,
[SOUND] we should have copied this
PHP line here in your page-resources.
You're storing WordPress query in
the loop variable, just right here.
Well, let's put it above
your resource-row.
Save that, now we're good to go.
Here we go.
So we've got our sidebar, good.
We got our resources,
they show up in their specific order.
We've got the excerpt,
continue reading, or
you can get started with that
resource right away, great.
Now, why don't we add some categories,
so let's add, let's say CATEGORIES.
Right here you're gonna add a level
three heading, and say Categories,
paragraph tag, with some text say,
or maybe a popular category?
Great!
And right here we're going
to add some markup for
a widget, cuz we want that style.
So class, widget and
then widget_categories.
And then in here we're gonna
have a level four heading, and
that's gonna say, class widget-title.
This will be, Most Used Categories.
And under here, we'll have a level,
an ordered list.
And then we're gonna be using
WordPress function called,
or wp- or _ list_ Categories.
And then there are some arguments,
you can put in here.
We're gonna start out, with an array.
Make sure they're both closed.
And then in here, there are some
key value pairs that you can add.
So there, first you can add, orderby,
and then that will be count.
And then order,
descending, show_count.
This will just be 1, the integer.
Title_li, no title_li.
And number 10.
And so, where I snagged all this from,
is I just went to the WordPress codecs,
searched up WordPress list categories, and
it gave me all the arguments that
you could put within this function.
And then you can just play around with it.
So, WordPress list category is
basically lists out the categories
that you have on your blog.
So, here's an example.
And there we go.
Or maybe a Popular Category,
or Most used categories.
And you can see them right here.
Awesome.
Now, why don't we move on
to one more section here.
Add just a little bit
more value to the 404.
And let's do some ARCHIVES.
So, the old Archives, level three heading,
Archives, paragraph tag.
And this will say,
You can always sort through our archives.
And then if you wanna snag
a specific widget, so
I wanna get the archives widget.
And right here,
you could use a built-in PHP, or
a WordPress function called the_widget.
And just to show you here how this works,
in the codex,
this is the template tag that displays
an arbitrary widget outside of a sidebar.
It can be used anywhere within templates.
So, the usage is the widget, and then
there are three parameters you can add.
And so for example, for
widget you can choose the widget
by grabbing the PHP class name.
For any of these widgets that
are built into WordPress.
So Archives, Calendar,
Category, so on, and so forth.
I wanna grab WordPress-Widget-Archives.
And then there are other things down here,
so instance, and arguments.
So, if you wanted to customize a little
bit, what displays before the widget,
after the widget, so on, and so forth.
So then in here, I just, in a string,
paste the php class name for the widget.
Let's hit save, and check that out.
And here it is,
got our Archives widget right here.
So if you wanna change the title here,
you could just,
in the parameters of this function,
you can add using title.
Change the title.
So let's say, I wanted to say,
Our Archives.
Then, there you go.
So, you can change it around like that.
And if you wanted to update what
displays before the widget,
like right here, or after the widget,
or before the title,
so currently the default is a level two
heading, but I don't really like that.
So, I wanna change that
to level four heading, so
it matches the rest of the style.
So I do that like so.
Before_title, and
this would be level four heading,
the class of widget title, and
after title, close that H4,
close the bracket here.
Perfect.
Now save that, we should be good to go.
Archives.
Our Archives.
Perfect, and that is the 404.
And here is a useful, and engaging 404.
So, oopps, came to the wrong page!
Bummer!
That page can't be found!
Little bit of humor.
Scroll down.
Don't fret.
Let's get you back on track.
Hey, so now,
maybe I was looking for a resource.
Or hey, this looks cool,
maybe I'll check out justhost.
Or I kind of wanna check
out some coding tutorials.
Or whatever, so on, and so forth.
We can add one more thing here,
just to finish it off.
Let's just add a paragraph tag,
and say, or
just head back to the home page.
And then let's give them
a link to make that easy.
And normally, you could just put a forward
slash to get you back to the root.
But in WordPress,
if you wanna reference the home URL,
php echo esc_url, and in here, home_url.
And then in the string, forward slash.
Close out that with semicolon.
Good to go.
Save that.
And then your 404 page should be perfect.
There you go.
Takes you back to the homepage.
Everybody's happy.
That was the useful,
and engaging 404 page.
And in the next section, or module,
we're gonna be learning how to launch our
final WordPress site,
live on an actual domain on the Internet.
So, you could share with family,
friends, clients.
If you're working on a client site,
you can get it live on their site.
This is a very useful skill to know,
because it's not as easy as click, and
drag, uploading your FTP.
There's a little bit of a skill,
and process involved.
So, let me take you through that.
[MUSIC]