Hey there, welcome back to
Boost Your Income with [NOISE],
in this lecture we're going to be doing
some resources with custom post types UI.
[MUSIC]
Hey, hey, all right, so
what we're going to do now is,
first of all we're just
gonna fix this content here.
We need to actually make this
dynamic right now, static, but
then we're gonna get right into what
the point of what this lecture is.
And that is to make custom post types,
so we can easily add and
remove and
edit resources to our resources page.
Head back to your code editor and
basically down here,
we're in the main content section,
get rid of everything.
Basically inside of main content.
So just the two paragraph tags, actually.
So paragraph tag, paragraph tag
right before the horizontal rule.
So, in here we need to initiate the loop.
So a while have_posts and then we're gonna
use a colon here cuz we're
using the shorthand.
The_post, then we've gotta
end that while loop.
This is the end of the loop.
And then in here,
we're just gonna go php the_content,
and that should grab the content
from the content editor.
We're gonna go ahead and copy this so that
we can paste it in the content editor.
Update and then we should be
good to go on the front end.
There we go,
this is the dynamic test from the editor.
Great, let's move forward and
do this stuff.
So, we need to go back to our Dashboard
and create a new custom post type
and that's gonna be,
Resource for the post type name,
Resources for the label, and
then Resource for the singular label.
You can leave the description alone.
Advanced Options,
I think these are all good.
We're going to leave
everything as is except for
the menu icon which is going to be
WordPress content themes Bootstrap to
WordPress assets image icon-resources.png.
And in here we want to be able
to have access to the title,
the editor, no excerpts,
another rest here, keep feature image,
actually don't use feature image,
author, page attributes, okay.
So basically we wanna keep title and
editor.
And then go ahead and
create that custom post type.
That should show up here in your sidebar.
There it is.
So what we wanna do is go
to the custom fields, and
we wanna create some advanced
custom fields for our resources.
Add a new one.
This is gonna be Resources.
And then add a new field.
Because we already have access to
the title we don't need a title.
We need a URL and
an image for our resources.
Cuz we're going to use the image,
we need a URL for the link.
We need in some content.
And in fact, let's do something cool.
We're going to use a conditional
field that will say, hey,
do you want to add a button to this?
To this resource post, and
if you check yes it will give
you an option to add a button.
And then you need to add the text inside
the button just as like a little practice.
So let's go back here and
we need have a resource image.
The field type will be image,
Upload an image for resource.
Required, let's say yes
to make it look good.
We're going to have the image object.
Preview would be medium
sized on the editor.
Leave it in the normal library, and
we'll close that field for good.
The next thing we want is to
have the URL for the resource.
Resource URL and that will be just text.
Say, Enter a valid URL for
your resource.
Acquired, yes.
Default value, no, let's do a place
holder just to show an example.
So http://www.google.com.
So that's what that would look like.
No formatting here at all and
we will close that field.
Now this is where we're gonna
see if you wanna add a button.
So let's say, add field and
this is going to be.
It's gonna say, Add Button.
And then down here,
you just need to choose True/False.
Field Instructions, Would you like
to add a button to this resource?
And then the default will be, checked yes.
Great, okay so, close that field.
So now, let me show you hows this works.
Button text.
This will be the button text.
All we need is some text.
Enter the text you'd like to
appear within the button.
Required no.
And then no formatting.
And then conditional logic, yes.
And this will show if ad
button is equal to checked.
So now, that should be good.
Now show this field group of
the post type is equal to resource.
Great.
And then we want this to be
standard WordPress metabox, and
we wanna hide any of this on the screen.
Well let's hide everything
except Content Editor,
Feature Image, and I think that's all.
So go ahead and publish that and
then now when you go to Resources,
Add a Resource, you should now
have some extra info down here.
So Resources.
You got image, URL, would you like
to add a button to this resource and
your button text, if I check
this it will remove button text.
Because it's not required if I
don't enter anything, that's okay.
Meaning if this is unchecked that
field is still there just hidden.
But if you don't enter
anything that is totally fine.
Here we go.
So now let's just add some resources.
And then we'll hook
them into our template.
So I'm going to say Justhost.
Basically what I'm going to do here so
you don't have to watch me do it all.
I'll do one for you and
you can do the rest.
And then we'll fast forward.
So I'm going to grab the title.
So the resource title.
I'm going to get the resource
text right here.
We're gonna paste that in the body.
And then, I'm gonna grab the link.
Which is copy link address.
URL, brighthouseu.ca/justhost.
Add button, yes.
The button text will say,
Get started with Justhost and the image.
I'm gonna add an image that
should be in our Assets folder.
We should have the Justhost
logo right there.
I'm just gonna make this
a little bit nicer.
Justhost logo, there we go, and
more accessible, and now if I publish
that I will have that resource, but
it won't be on my template yet,
because we haven't hooked it in.
So go ahead and do that for the other two,
or however many you wanna add,
if you're kinda working on something else
as we go along here, go ahead and do that.
And then when you come back,
or when we come back,
we're going to be hooking this into
our template, so let's fast forward.
All right and here we go.
I've got all my resources.
I've got Dropbox, Coda, and Justhost.
Now what we want to do is
head to our code editor, and
we're going to hook
those into our template.
So right here at the end
of our while loop,
we're going to do another PHP script here.
And that's going to establish
a new variable for loop, and
it will be a new WP_Query, so
we're gonna be resetting this, or
re-establishing the value
of what this function is.
So, we're gonna be grabbing the custom
post type resource, so the way you do that
is like we've done in the past,
but let's just write it out again.
We've got post_type, and
that would be resource, comma, orderby,
and that would be post_id, comma, order,
and that is going to be ascending, great.
That looks good.
Now under our resource row,
we're going to initiate the loop.
So, while loop have_posts and
then colon, loop the_post.
Now we have to do this because
we're grabbing a custom post type.
And we have to initiate the loop.
Now we need to end that while loop.
Great.
Okay.
So now in here we need to
basically add our resource.
One of these resources, the mark-up,
and then we're gonna make it dynamic.
Cool.
So in here we have our image, and
we just need to be able to grab that.
So the way that we do that,
pretty straightforward.
We're gonna have to get
those custom fields.
So let's go up to the top and
establish some variables.
Let's say resource_image, and
that's gonna be
get_field('resource_image').
What other ones do we have?
We have resource_url = get_field.
And that's ('resource_url').
And then I believe we also have resource.
Button.
Text.
Or was it just button text?
Let's just double check.
Button text.
That would just be button_text.
Get_field, button_text.
And we might as well get the add
button to see if it's true or false.
So add_button and that will say get_field.
Add_button.
Great so now we have our variables.
So now we should be able
to just pull these in.
So this is gonna be php
echo resource_image.
That should do it.
And then after that we wanna grab.
The title so this is just php the_title,
and then in here we have that URL.
So that's just going to be php echo.
Resource_url.
And then here all these paragraph tags,
that's just gonna be the content.
Easy enough.
And now down here, we want to do something
about this button, and on second thought,
because we made our backend here,
we said do you wanna add a button?
And then this field would appear,
the editor.
Theoretically, this section right here,
we don't need to do anything
with it in our template.
I added a variable that should technically
store its value, but we don't need it.
The reason why is because
button text is not required.
So it doesn't matter.
What they chose or not.
If they put button text then all we need
to do is check to see if there is a value
in button text.
Otherwise don't show anything.
The add button toggle
field is really just for
the editor just to make it
look a little bit nicer.
So all you need to do is just php if.
Not empty.
And that would be button_text.
Show the button.
Right there.
Now let's close up that php tag and
the endif.
So in here we just need
to make this dynamic.
This is gonna be the php
echo resource_url, and
then the text would go here.
Php echo button_text.
There it is.
Save that and delete the other resources,
the static ones.
Make sure your resource
row is still intact, and
everything's still there, now if you save
that and check it out on the front end.
You should have all of your resources.
Cool so they're kind of there,
but we're missing the images and
the URL and the buttons.
So, what's up with that?
I believe the reason why this isn't
working is because our variables up here
are not being passed into this loop
down here when we loop through the posts
when we're in our custom post type.
So, the solution to that would be
just to include those variables.
Right in here.
Like so.
The alternative solution if
you wanted to just not do this
is just use the functions themselves.
Within the template.
Now if I save that let's see what happens.
So we have our buttons with the links.
And the image is an array.
That's because, silly Brad,
this is passing an array.
What we should have done, is this.
Image source and then alt.
And then right here we would do like so.
Resource_image, and then url.
And then alt would be the same deal,
but alt.
Let's see.
There we go.
So we've got our image and
the alt text should be in there,
we've got our links and the buttons.
Good to go.
That's it for the resources page,
pretty straightforward.
Took a little bit of figuring out and
a few issues here and there, but
that's okay.
That's how you do the resources,
that's how you can add dynamic resources.
Very useful to know, and
this can apply to a bunch of other pages.
Rather than just specifically for
Resources, it could be for team members,
it could be for menu items,
it could be for products and
your imagination is your only limitation.
So in the next lecture we're actually
gonna be jumping to a whole new module,
and we're gonna start working on the blog.
And the blog is WordPress's forte, so
it's gonna be fun working with this one.
See ya there.
[MUSIC]