Hey there welcome back to boost your
income with Bootstrap to WordPress,
this lecture we're gonna code
the full blog post section.
So good, check it out.
[MUSIC]
Hey welcome back, what we're gonna do now
is clean up the full blog post page or
template, which is this specific one right
here, which obviously doesn't look very
good because we haven't done anything
to match our final domain design,
which looks like this,
which is our static site.
And the other thing that we're going
to do is clean up the side bar because,
if you look here on our blog excerpt and
what will be our full blog page,
the sidebar doesn't look very good.
The headers are too big,
and just the margins are a little
too spaced out between the headers.
And it's pretty easy to fix,
so we're gonna do that.
So, let's head back to our code editor.
And you're gonna need
to open two templates.
First you'll need to open single.php.
Single.php is the template for
displaying all single posts.
Now, it's not the content, it's
the template, or wrapper outside of it.
And so this is what's gonna
allow us to add the wrappers for
the main content and the sidebar.
Pretty easy.
So follow along.
So what you'll need to do is open up
your post.html from your static site.
We're just going to grab some
of the market from right here.
Not very much.
We're just going to grab
from the container,
right under the main content comment here.
And end here at call small 8.
So copy that.
Go back to your single, and
replace these two tags.
So remove these ones and replace
them with the ones you just copied.
Make sure they're lined up nicely.
Okay, and we might as well
just make this the tag main
because it makes more semantic sense and
that's what it is usually in WordPress.
I you can use a HTML5 tag, why not?
You can leave it as the div but
let's change it to main.
As long as we make sure
to close the ending tag.
So now what we gotta do is
close these tags up here, so
we're basically going to remove these and
close up the correct ones.
First we're gonna have to close up main.
That's the ID of content.
And then we've gotta close up the primary,
which is the ID of primary, and
then close up the container.
But we also have the sidebar we need
to add, and that is in our post.html.
We just need to get the aside tag,
that's all.
And that's gonna be included after the
main tag, and then close up that aside.
And in between there,
you just have to php get_sidebar.
But make sure to remove the one down here,
cuz we don't want two of them.
So we got our sidebar.
I'm just gonna add a section title here,
an HTML comment, SIDEBAR.
And then up here I'm gonna the same
I'm just gonna tab this stuff in.
All right, looking good.
Give that a quick check here,
and looks pretty good.
It's coming together.
Obviously we have some
things left to do here.
And now, to fix the rest of this,
go back to your code editor, and
jump into content single,
because as you can see here,
we're getting a template part and
its content-single, right here.
And then, content-single, we're
basically just going to copy a lot of
what we did from the previous lecture
where we did the content excerpt, or
not specifically content excerpt, it was
content.php, but it was the blog excerpt.
And that was in content.php.
And go ahead and
grab the entire header tag.
And everything in it.
Copy that.
Go back to your content single.
And then, replace the header
tag with your own header tag.
And then, get rid of the entry content and
the entry footer but
leave the article, closing article tag.
And in here go back to your content
PHP and copy the rest of it,
post image, post excerpt, but we're gonna
change something once we paste it in here.
Instead of post excerpt,
it's gonna be called post body, and
then this instead of the excerpt
will be the content.
Save that, now go back.
And we pretty much have
everything in there.
So what we're gonna do
to fix this is actually,
not necessarily in the styles at all,
you can, you can jump into your CSS and
style the headers of these widgets but
the fact is the default is
that these widgets have level
one headings as their headers.
So we can jump back and style those
headers, but what would be better, and
more semantic is to change the source
code altogether, change the markup so
it's not a level one heading.
So we'll go back to your
functions on PHP and
scroll down to the register widget area.
It should be around line 74.
And then you'll see your sidebars here.
And you can register multiple side bars.
And you can see here before title,
change this from level one
heading to level four heading.
And after title close that tag.
Level four heading, save that.
Go back.
Quick check.
There you go.
Looks exactly like it should.
Okay, that's it for this lecture.
In the next lecture we're gonna jump
down here to the comments section and
style this up so
it looks a lot better than this.
See you there.
[MUSIC]