Hey, everyone, welcome back to Boost
Your Income with Bootstrap to WordPress.
This lecture is called,
Code the "Boost Your Income" Section
using Advanced Custom Fields.
Check it out.
[MUSIC]
All right, and so what we want to do
now is take this section right here,
the How You Can Boost Your Income section.
And convert it to a dynamic section,
that you can easily update
using advanced custom fields.
Super easy.
Check it out.
Let's go to Dashboard.
Click on Custom Fields.
What we're gonna do is click Add New.
And then we need to enter a title for
a field group.
And you'll see what
a field group is shortly.
Basically, it's a group of
form inputs that we want to
create that we can use to enter
information into the database.
Which we then pull that information out of
the database to display it in our template
on our page.
So let's call this
Boost Your Income Section.
And then we're going to add a field.
And then here we can add a bunch
of information about our field.
So the first one we wanna add
is a section for this image.
We wanna be able to have people
upload an image for that section.
So let's say, income feature image.
And then it gives a field name and
that's what we'll use to
grab the information out of
the database in our template.
The field type is going to be an image.
And then you can give field instructions.
So if you'd like you can put
some instructions here so
it makes more sense on the front end.
So let's say upload an image for
this section.
Required let's say No.
You don't have to have that.
Return value, you can have
an Image Object, Image URL or Image ID.
We're not gonna do the ID.
We're basically in between object or URL.
So URL gives you the actual
URL of the image.
Or the object,
which is the actual image itself,
which would be an array of information.
So let's stick with Image Object and
Preview Size.
So the preview size shown when entering
the data, when you're in the dashboard,
do you want it to be a thumbnail,
medium, large or full?
Let's just keep it as, let's say medium.
Library we limit the media
library choice so,
it will be the global library or
library that's uploaded to the post.
Let's keep is as the global library.
Conditional Logic, we don't need to
do this, basically, this would mean
if we added another field, that was
a check box, you could have a check
box that would say something like,
do you want to add a feature image?
And then if they checked yes,
then you could say, conditional logic, and
it would give you a field here
that says include feature image,
and then is equal to true, and
this section will show up.
We're not gonna do that right now.
You don't have to worry about it.
So there you go, that field's in there.
The next one we want to add
is the image section title.
So we're gonna add another field.
And let's close this field up so
it's a bit smaller.
Just click on that there.
Income Section Title.
Income section title, there it is.
Field Type,
we want it to be just basic text.
We don't need a field instruction here.
If you like to then sure.
Let's make it required.
And you don't need to add
any of these other things,
except let's change this to No formatting.
We don't want to have people
put HTML in there at all.
You could put placeholder text if
you'd like just as like helper text,
but you don't need to.
And you could limit the characters
that you want people to add, but
I'm gonna leave that as is.
Close this field up.
Let's add another field.
And this is gonna be
the Income Section Description.
That gives us an auto generated field
name and this will be a text area.
I'm going to put some field instructions.
Enter, Required?
Yes.
And formatting, converting your lines
into break tags or convert to HTML tags,
leave them as break tags.
And then close the field up.
Great.
The next one you want to be able to do is,
we have these two sections down here.
We have two reasons, or two ways that you
could boost your income with this course.
So, we're gonna call that reason one and
reason two and there's a title and
a description.
So we're gonna say reason one title,
reason one description.
Reason two title, reason two description.
So let's go in and do that.
Add a Field.
Let's say Reason One title.
There we go.
It's gonna be text.
Required?
Yes.
And don't convert, so
No formatting at all, no HTML.
Close that up.
Add another field.
This will be Reason One Description.
And this is going to be text area.
Required.
And leave it as break tags.
Close that up.
Cool.
And now we're gonna
duplicate these because we
already have the settings.
We're just gonna rename them.
So duplicate.
I'm just gonna drag this down
below here so I'm not confused.
And edit this.
This is gonna be Reason Two Title,
make sure to change
the subteries int 2_title.
They should have the same settings, great.
And then duplicate the description.
This is going to be
Reason Two Description and
then make sure to change this so
it's not reason description copy.
reason_2_description.
Text area.
We're all good for the settings.
Close that field up and
drag that below the Reason Two Title.
Now, what you can do if you wanna
make it a little bit easier to see
on the front end is you can
organize these into tabs.
Now before we do that I wanna,
I'm gonna show you what this looks like as
is before we start doing any fancy stuff.
I'll just show you how this works.
So technically once you publish this
you'll have this field group but
it's not associated with any post,
page or entry at all.
So, we need to be able to show this field
group when you're on a certain page or
within a location, and that's what
this section is right here, location.
Create a set of rules to determine which
edit screens will use these advanced
custom fields.
So, show this field group if,
and then it gives you a bunch of options
to be able to display this field.
So we want this to
display on the home page.
So page is equal to home.
There we go.
So this will display only on
the home page when you're editing.
Down here are the options.
You can choose the order
field groups that are created
in order from lowest to highest.
So if you wanted to override that and
put a number where you'd
want this field to display.
So if you have a bunch of fields that
are displaying the home page, and
you want this one to be the top,
you'd put zero.
If you have another one and
you wanted it to be in the third position,
you'd put two.
So on and so forth.
Position normal after content,
high after title, or side bar.
So when you're editing
a page you have the title,
you have the text field, and
then you have the sidebar content.
Do you want this to display
after the text fields or
do you want it to be after the title or
in the side bar?
I'm gonna leave it as normal.
The style is seamless, no metabox,
or standard WordPress metabox.
Basically a metabox, if I said WordPress
metabox, it will display like this.
Like this section right here.
We have a big white box that has a title,
which would be the field group title.
And then you have the rest
of it in this white box.
Otherwise, it would have no white
background, it would just have this
content, whatever your field groups
are on this gray background.
And you'll see what I
mean once we do this, and
then hide on the screen select
the items to hide from the Edit screen,
if multiple field groups
appear on an Edit screen.
And the first field group's
options will be used,
the one with the lowest ordered number.
Basically, on your Edit screen, do you
want to be able to show these things,
these are pretty much the default
things that show up on the Edit screen.
So Permalink,
Content Editor those things show up,
excerpt you can have
an excerpt by default.
The excerpt you can have on your
Edit screens, Custom Fields,
we use Custom Fields.
Discussion, Comments, the Slug,
Author, Format, Featured Image in the side
bar, Categories Tags and Trackbacks.
These are all the things that
are available by default
natively with WordPress when
you're on an Edit screen.
And so let me just show you what I mean,
so I hit Edit Page.
You can see the Title, the Content Area,
the Permalink, got the Page Attributes,
Custom Fields.
I can use screen Options to show
Discussion, Comments, Slug, Author, and
you can see all those down here now
Discussion, Comments, Slug, Author.
Now those are hidden by default, but
if you want them totally
removed from the site, or
from the Edit screen to clean up the Edit
screen then you can do that here.
So I can say I wanna hide Comments,
and Revisions and
I want to hide Format, Featured Image.
But I'm gonna leave that for now,
because it's not going to effect me.
So there we go, I'm gonna publish that.
And that should now be
available on our udemy
editor homepage, so let's refresh this.
So here we go, the booster income section.
So you can see our Field Groups,
Income Featured Image, Upload an Image,
you've got an Image Uploader,
Image Section Title, Section Description,
Reason one title,Reason one Description,
Reason two, and reason two.
So this right now is very linear
it just goes all the way down, and
they have these really big form fields.
But I want to organize this a bit better,
and
in fact I do want to remove
this text field right here.
So I could do that by going back
to my Edit Field Group, and
I'm gonna say hide the Content Editor.
I don't wanna see that, and
also I want the reason one and
rReason two to be grouped
in their own little tab,
so it's not a huge linear
layout on the Edit screen.
So I'm gonna add a field I'm just
gonna say Reason number one,
the Field Name, it's gonna say reason_1.
It really doesn't matter
because it's not gonna show,
you're not gonna use this
to input any information.
All you're gonna do is choose layout tab,
so you lose the Field Name anyway.
And conditional logic, so
you don't need to use that for now.
Drag.
So here, let me just explain, use tab
field to better organize your Edit screen
by grouping your fields together
under separate tab headings.
At all the fields following
this tab field, or
until another tab field is
defined will be grouped together.
Use multiple tabs to divide
your fields into sections.
So this is how you do it I'm gonna
put this above Reason one, and
now everything under
here will be in a tab.
But I don't want Reason two to be in
a tab, so I'm gonna duplicate this,
and this is gonna be Reason two,
and Reason two is gonna start here.
Now I don't need these Titles to be,
so because these are what show up
on the Edit screen, and
they kinda look a little silly.
So I'm actually, and because they're
gonna be in group sections here
I'm just gonna say Title.
Keep the field name the same though,
you're going to do the same here for
the description.
That's just gonna say Description we're
going to leave the Field Name the same,
because that's important for
us to pull that in from the database.
Reason two, change this to just Title.
Obviously leave the Field Name,
and same with the Description, so
I'm gonna call that Description, great.
Now if I save that, or
update it, and go back to our
homepage editor you will now see
a different homepage editor.
So, here we go, now we have no Content
Editor, we have the same info here, but
now we have Reason one, and Reason two.
So, you just add your information for
Reason one, add your information for
Reason two.
This doesn't affect the way you
pull it into your template,
it just groups this so
that your editor is a bit more clean.
And then our custom fields
are still down here, and
you can already see now how
this is a way better option.
Because I could have done this
theoretically in Custom Fields,
but I'd have crazy amount of name,
and value pairs.
That would just go all
the way down the screen,
whereas this is a nice little section.
It's very user friendly, and
when your client logs in they can see oh,
I'm updating the Booster Income Section.
And the cool thing is you can hide these
if you're working on a new section, and
you don't wanna have all
these fields in your face.
So basically what we'll
do now is add some info,
and then I'll show you how to
pull that into your template.
So let's start by adding an image.
Now we don't have an image for the Booster
Income Section in the Media Library,
so that's gonna be in our assets
folder in your Static Site.
You have the images and you also have it
in your WordPress site as well in your
assets folder in images you should
have the icon called Icon Boost.
So just go ahead, and grab that and
drag it into your Media Library,
Add a Title and Alt Text,
that's good practice.
This would be boost your
actually this is just a graph,
so we'll just say Graph Icon,
and the Alt Text will be,
An icon of a graph, great, so there we go.
Income Section Title, and
we're just gonna copy this right
from our from our homepage.
Cuz right now it's static, and
we want to make it dynamic, so
let's go ahead and grab that information.
So this is How You Can Boost Your Income
is what the title is.
And copy that, and
go back to your page, the homepage and
paste the Income Section Title in there.
Income Section Description,
that would just be that stuff right here,
paste that in here.
Boom, and then Reason one.
You've got make money on the side.
And we got our description down here
of how you can make money on the side.
And then Reason two,
create a full-time income.
Paste that in the Title, and
then the Description we have our
WordPress folder have option.
Paste that in the description,
now go ahead and update that.
Now currently, this isn't going to do
anything, If we were to refresh the page,
it's still gonna look the same
because this is still static.
And it's not pulling from the database,
but it's actually quite simple, so
let's go into our code and
in our home template, page-home.php.
We're gonna pull that information in,
it's now saved in the database.
We just need to pull it out,
and it's really easy.
So let's create another section
here in our PHP script called
Advanced Custom Fields.
And right here we're just gonna basically
make a bunch of variables with our fields.
So that we can echo that out using PHP, so
first one is the income feature image.
Now this is a variable, and
you can name this whatever, you can say.
IFI or incomeImage or whatever.
But I'm gonna call it
income_feature_image because is the same
as the field name that is
automatically generated, or
that you can custom add here,
income feature image, the field name.
This can be changed to whatever you want,
if you edit in here but,
we're gonna use this, so,
income_feature_image.
That's what I'm gonna call
the variable as well, just so
it's consistent, easy to understand.
I'm not trying to be a hero here.
And, in order to grab that
information from the database,
it's actually quite easy.
There's two ways, and the most common
way is using the get_field function.
And then in here we have a parameter,
we just have to put the field name, and
the field name is income_feature_image and
there we go.
So now the income_feature_image array is
actually gonna be stored in here because
this is actually an array.
So we need to be able to grab the image
URL and everything a little bit later.
Let's keep adding our
variables while we're up here,
we have the income Section_title.
And we're gonna use get_field as well and
that is same deal, income_section_title.
I'm just gonna copy that and paste it in.
Make sure to move the dollar sign.
And then,
we have the income section description.
I'm just gonna say desc.
D-E-S-C, just cuz it's
a little bit shorter.
And then, this'll be get_field.
I'm just gonna copy this, and then change
this to income_section_description.
This one is actually the full length,
I believe.
We'll look in our field group,
income_section_description, yes.
Okay, now we have our reasons.
I'm gonna copy this whole thing, and
this is gonna be reason_1,
whoops, reason_1.
Get_field will be reason_1_title.
Is that correct?
Yes, reason_1_title.
Copy that and this'll be, might as
well make that say reason_1_title.
The same thing reason_1 content,
or description, yes.
reason_1_description.
And maybe we'll make that
short like I did earlier.
Okay, so
reason_1_title reason_1_description.
This will be reason_1_description.
Copy both of those cuz you're basically
just gonna change the numbers now.
Reason 1 and 2.
And then, reason1 and 2.
There we go.
So, now we have some information for
our first part of that section.
So, why don't we go down and do that.
Go down to you Boost Your Income section
that is hard-coded, and let's start off by
doing the image because it's actually
the hardest part of this section.
So, get some space here.
We're going to do some PHP.
And we need to do an if
statement to see if the feature
image exists because it's
not a required field.
So we need to actually check to see,
hey is it empty?
Did it upload an image, or what?
So I'm going to say if
feature image exists,
and maybe it's not called a feature image.
I don't want to confuse you.
If user uploaded an image.
There we go, that makes more sense.
And then in here we're gonna have PHP, if.
So an if statement, this is the basic
skeleton of an if statement here.
Actually, we're gonna do
a shorthand version of this.
It's actually kinda neat, so let's go if,
and then in here, not empty.
And that in here we're gonna
have the income feature image.
So that's pulling the array.
So if the array is not empty,
meaning if the user uploaded an image,
then this is how you do the short hand.
You just go like this.
So I'm just gonna fix
this PHP script here.
Make it a bit shorter, use up less space.
So copy that out.
So here we have,
if income_feature_image is not empty.
And then this is how you do
the shorthand of the if statement.
And the reason why I wanna do this
is because I'm closing the PHP tag.
I could use a bracket here,
like an open curly brace, but
I'm just gonna use the colon because now
I can close it like this, PHP andif.
That's one way of doing it.
I could have also just done this.
Could have done that,
but I wanna do this, just to show
you a different way of doing it.
So, in between these PHP tags,
this is if the user uploaded an image.
Very easy.
So, grab this image here,
paste that in between your
PHP if statement, and
now we need to change this to be dynamic.
So let's get rid of this PHP blog info and
the alt.
Okay so we wanna fill these in,
and we have that information.
So this would be PHP echo.
Income feature image, but
because it is an array,
we need to be able to grab something.
So we're gonna reference
a key within this array.
And that is going to be the URL.
That is one of the things that
is saved within this array.
We have URL.
And so,
I'm going to grab the URL from that array.
And then Alt.
I just wanna echo the income feature image
Alt text that is saved on the image.
So, php echol $income_feature_image, and
then in my square brackets here,
reference the alt key.
That is saved within the image
object in the advanced custom
fields and for more information on
the different keys you can reference
in certain fields,
you can go to the advanced custom fields
documentation which is hugely
extensive and really well documented.
So it's a really great reference.
You just have to go to
advancedcustomfields.com,
I believe is the website and
then just click on documentation.
Everything's there if you are curious or
confused, running into any problems.
So this should grab our image.
So why don't we just see?
Be the first test.
[NOISE] See, if this image is here now.
It looks like it is.
And let's just inspect it and
view the source and see if we have
the alt text in there correctly.
An icon of a graph, and
there is the image.
Perfect, that worked out great.
So, let's keep going.
We have a few more things here,
very easy this stuff.
You probably even already
know how to do this.
We're going to fill in this header.
All I have to do is echo
the income section title.
That's all.
Our text here.
Php echo the income_section_description.
And now we have the first reason.
So this is PHP.
Echo income.
Oh, sorry.
Reason one title.
I'm just gonna copy this so I don't have
to rewrite the PHP script every time and
then paste it here in
between the paragraph tags.
Reason_1_description.
Copy the h3 and p because you can just
replace these now in this second column.
Reason_2_title and reason_2_desc.
Save that out, check it out.
Now these should be dynamic.
There they are.
Now just to prove that they're dynamic and
they're easily updatable or editable.
In here in the dashboard, I'm gonna say,
How You Can Boost Your Income and
then in here I'm just gonna say YAY!
There we go, update and
let's check it out and see if it worked.
How You Can Boost Your Income!
Yay!
There we go, it works.
In here I'm just gonna change
that back to what it should be.
Perfect, so
I'm just gonna update that now.
And that's all,
that's how we use advanced custom fields.
That was a brief overview.
There's a lot more to
advanced custom fields, and
we're actually going to keep going.
There's a lot more that we have to do.
So in the next lecture, we're going to
work on the Who Should Take This Course
section using of course,
advanced custom fields.
Show you a new field.
All right, see you there.