Hey, everybody, welcome back to Boost
Your Income with Bootstrap to WordPress.
This lecture is called Installing Free
Web Fonts with Type Kit and Google Fonts.
[MUSIC]
All right.
Let's add some custom font libraries to
our HTML.
Couple things to take note of,
here is the final WordPress website, and
here is the final static website.
Very subtle difference, but
the difference is there.
If you look the fonts here, just look at
the Bootstrap to WordPress title here.
You could see that the font is slightly
different here in the static one and
in the WordPress one.
Well that is because here I'm using Google
Fonts to serve up a font called Railway,
and here I'm using Proxima Nova.
The font is called Proxima Nova
with Typekit by Adobe.
So the final font we're gonna be using
is Proxima Nova because it's a much
sexier looking font, in my opinion.
Although Railway's not too bad itself.
But I wanna show you how to add both.
So there is Typekit and
there is Google Fonts.
The reason why the static one
isn't serving up Proxima Nova
with TypeKit is because TypeKit,
if I show you here in my kits.
You can see my kit settings.
The domains that these fonts will
show up on are bradhussey.ca,
localhost and bootstraptowordpress.com
That is where the font will show up.
If it doesn't have any of these,
if it is not a part of these domains,
then they won't show up.
So Proxima Nova is looking for
any of these domains here.
But because the static site is
just hosted on my local machine.
File volumes blah, blah,blah..
It can't serve up that font, so
it's falling back to the Google font.
So I'm gonna show you how to do both,
how to add both just for variety, and
you might like some Google
fonts better than Typekit.
Plus, Google Fonts is free.
Typekit is free as well, but
the basic version of it is free.
So, Google Fonts.
We have google.com/fonts, and
all you have to do is just
type in the font you're looking for
here if you already know it.
Or you could just play around with this to
kinda find a font that you're looking for.
I'm already looking for a railway.
So here's what we're looking for.
I'm going to add this
one to my collection.
So here it is down in my collection.
And down here I wan to click Use.
And I think I will add some normal and
let's add bold as well.
Okay?
Here it shows you the page load and
the impact on the page load time.
And then here is the script or
the code you wanna add to your
website in order to reference the CSS.
So you can use the standard,
you can use the @import Or JavaScript.
Let's just use Standard.
Go ahead and copy that HTML snippet there.
And then all you have to do is
add it to your header here in
the index file, or in all of your files,
but in this case we're on the index file.
So I'm gonna add right here, Google Fonts.
And then paste that,
there is our link to the Google fonts.
And in order to reference
the railway font,
integrate the fonts into your CSS,
this is all you need to do.
So when you're typing out the font
family you wanna use in CSS.
Font family in pair of strings, Railway.
So that is all for Google Fonts.
We're not doing the CSS yet,
but that's there.
So when we want to use CSS it'll be there.
And Typekit.
So sign up for
typekit.com account, it's free.
Unless you want to upgrade to
kind of a more fancy version.
And create a kit, a new kit, and
then look for the font Proxima Nova.
I'll show you the Proxima Nova font.
So I'm just looking for Proxima Nova.
And so here is Proxima Nova.
We wanna click use fonts and
then you can add it as Web.
And then add it to the kit
that you want to add it to.
So I already added it
to my Brad's blog kit.
And then open up your kits here.
And I want to open up Brad's blog kit,
you can name yours whatever, obviously.
And here is kind of
the information about this kit.
So, the default weights and styles.
Those will be fine.
This is where you can choose
the styles you want to include and
up here using fonts in CSS.
So you just reference it by
typing proxima-nova all lower
case inside a pair of strings
as a font family like this.
And you're going to need the embed code.
So copy that embed code right there.
And Kit Settings, this is where you
are going to want to name the Kit and
then choose the domain.
So local host would be good,
maybe your website or your blog.
Whatever your website is going to be on.
But, make sure to include local hosts.
Then you're gonna Save those settings, and
then hit Publish to
make sure it's updated.
And then, go back to your code editor.
Go down to the very bottom.
Just below the closing body tag,
paste those two scripts and
these will be your
TypeKit Fonts right there.
For proxima nova.
Save that and that should be it.
So then all you do at this point
we'll get there eventually is for
the font family you just type in either
railway in a string, pair of strings or
proxima-nova all lower
case in a pair of strings.
What we're gonna do is go font family,
proxminova, railway,
sans-serif, so we can have a font stack.
All right.
And that's it for this lecture, and
in the next lecture we're going to be
coding the header and
the navigation bar of our HTML file.
All right, see you there.
[MUSIC]