Hey everybody, welcome back to Boost
Your Income with Bootstrap to WordPress.
This lecture is called
static versus dynamic,
which is better Another hint one of them
is much more valuable, check it out.
[MUSIC]
All right, let me tell you the difference
between static and dynamic websites.
You probably already know the difference,
but if not let me clear it up for you.
Static websites are basically
brochure websites.
They're coded in HTML, CSS,
they're just hard coded,
there's nothing dynamic about them.
They're .HTML pages using
CSS to style the website.
You have hard-coded text it's
literally typed in your code editor,
saved in an HTML file,
thrown up on a website that's static.
Static means it is still nothing changes
about it, unless you manually change it.
Dynamic on the other hand is something
that's living, and breathing.
The information is pulled from a database
that's is updated by a user whether
it's yourself, or
your client,or a friend, a colleague,
team member it's living, and breathing.
It can auto update itself depending
on the type of programming
language you use, and
it's a lot more valuable.
Static websites, if you deliver that to
a client you need to keep updating that
yourself, your client can't have
the convenience of doing that.
Dynamic websites,
your client can update those,
because it's using a Content Management
System that's incredibly valuable.
Your client will see way more
value in that, and it's better for
you because you can charge higher.
Also there are certain things that
static websites simply can not do,
it's impossible.
For example Facebook,
that's fully dynamic there's no way that
there's a team of 1000 developers
always updating the website.
You can't do that, plus you're the one
updating your status, or adding pictures.
It's impossible for a developer at
Facebook to magically know what you
just added, and
then quickly create an HTML page.
It doesn't work like that that's
impossible, that's why its dynamic.
So dynamic websites are way more
valuable than static websites, so
you're gonna wanna know how to do it.
All right, now that we've covered why
you should be learning Bootstrap, and
WordPress.
And how using them can significantly
increase your efficiency in your business,
and increase your income.
Let's jump into a totally new section, and
start getting into more of the details
of developing our website.
So the next step is
Information Architecture, and
why you must start your website
with a sketch see there.
[MUSIC]