Hey everyone!
Welcome back to Boost Your Income
with Bootstrap to WordPress.
This lecture is called Code the "Who
Should Take This Course" Section
using Advanced Custom Fields.
I love advanced custom fields.
Check it out.
[MUSIC]
Now what we're gonna do is add the,
Who Should Take This Course?, section.
Now the last lecture was quite
long at about 25 minutes.
That's kinda at the top end of how
long I like to keep my lectures.
So this one's actually gonna be quite
short because this is an easy section
to update.
We're just gonna have
the image like last time.
The title.
And then we're just gonna use
a text box to display this content.
So you can add whatever text you want.
So let's just go into the back end here.
Into our Field Groups.
Let's go back to Custom Fields here.
And then add a new Field Group.
And this is gonna be called
the Who Should Take this Course section.
You could shorten that if you'd like, but
I'm going to leave it as is
because it keeps it simple.
You know what it means.
There's no confusion.
Let's add a field here.
And we're going to do something
a little different here.
We're going to have a field label be
totally different from the field name.
So this is just going to be section title.
But I don't want to call
this section title.
I want this to be- who_section_title,
and that's going to be Text,
and required, yes, and
then formatting, no formatting.
Close that field.
Let's add another field here, and it's
actually going to be the section image, so
this would be section Image, and
we're going to change this
to who_ Feature_image.
And this will be an image.
And we're gonna grab that image object.
Required, no.
Previous size, medium.
All good to go.
I'm just gonna drag that above the section
titles, since it comes before.
So, it displays like that in the editor.
It doesn't effect how we pull in the info.
But it does effect how the editor
looks to the people editing the page.
Section body.
This is gonna be who section body and
that will be a text area required yes.
Actually, it won't be a text area.
We're gonna make this a wizzy wake editor,
meaning they can do a lot of formatting.
So tool bar, full or basic.
Let's give them basics.
They don't have full Toolbar access,
but they have basic access.
So they can do basic text formatting,
possibly upload an image,
have some links, things like that.
In fact, you can actually decide if you
want them to show media upload buttons.
I'm just gonna say no, so they can't
upload images, cuz they don't need to.
Let's just say that.
Close the field.
So we have the image title in body.
Good.
Show this field group if
page is equal to home.
Good and the order number.
This is, again if you want this to display
before or after the previous field group
which was the,
how you can boost your income section.
I'm going to leave this as zero because
you can actually drag it on the front or
when you're in the editing
screen you can drag that
meta box to where you want it to display.
And it should by default come
after the one we just created.
Position normal, seamless.
I'm going to show you what
no meta box looks like.
I don't prefer it but
I'll show you what it looks like.
And it's already going to
be pulling the settings
from this from the other booster
income section that we just created,
the field group because it
has a lower order number.
Technically this one is zero,
but because we did it first it
should be using those settings.
But maybe let's confirm that before we for
sure say that's the case.
Publish that and go to your edit page.
On your home, your home edit page.
There we go.
And under there we should
have our section image.
There we go.
So do you see what I mean without
the meta box?
It doesn't look as nice.
It just kind of It just kinda fades
into the background a little bit,
it doesn't stand out.
And that way you can't actually
close the section or drag it.
So I'm gonna go back here and
make it be a meta box standard.
Update.
That should be here on
the home editing screen now.
In the boost income section, and
who should take this
course section right here.
So we have an image, title, and body.
Let's go ahead and do those.
So, let's add an image and
that image will be pad.
The title will say,
icon our pad icon and
then the alt text will be
an icon of a pencil and paper.
Here we go.
Select.
There's a section image.
There's a section title.
It is who should take this course.
I'm going to copy that and
then I'm going to paste it in there and
in the section section body,
see how we have the basic tool right here?
I'm just gonna copy all of this.
Paste it right in here and it should
maintain or retain the formatting,
there we go, and
then go ahead and update that.
Of course we haven't done anything in
the template so it won't do anything.
Won't show up on the front end.
So we have to pull that in in here.
So let's go ahead and
add some more variables.
Who_feature_image.
That's going to be get field again.
And this will be, who_feature_image.
This next one will be, who_section-title,
change this to, who_section_title.
And this last one will be, who_section_
body, I believe is what we called it.
Yep.
And this'll be who_section_body.
Great.
You should know what to do now,
scroll down to the who benefits section
down here is what we called it.
The image.
Same deal, why don't we just
copy what we did up here.
If the user uploaded an image.
And we're just going to switch that up.
So put it here.
If user uploaded an image.
This will be who_ feature_image.
And then the source will
be who_feature_image, and
then we who_feature_image here as well.
URL and alt is still good.
This will be, php echo who_section_title.
And then all of this stuff, remove all
of this HTML inside of that column tag.
Or the div with the tag of call.
Php echo who_section_body.
And that's it.
Let's see if it worked on the front end.
And here it is.
It's dynamic pulling in from
the back end and simple.
Pretty straight forward, really easy and
now you can easily change this text or
your client can and it's you
can say how easy it is to just set up
a section like that and it looks great.
In the edit screen right here who
should take this course section.
It's very easy to edit.
Very easy to modify.
And it's also worth noting that by
dragging these on top of each other,
it doesn't affect
the position on the page.
That's something that we'll leave for
a more advanced lecture,
of how you can reposition
those using the dashboard.
Or using the edit screen.
But it's worth noting that if you
drag these in different positions,
it's not actually going to change
the layout on the front end.
Cool.
In the next lecture,
we're going to go down.
And we're going to get started
on the course features.
But first I'm going to
introduce you to a really cool.
Another really cool plugin that's amazing
and I think you're going to like it.
See you there.
[MUSIC].