Hey, friend, welcome back.
We're going to start coding up these little excerpts right here, and that's going to be easy because
we just have to make one and then duplicate it just for, you know, for the template purpose of the
template, obviously in WordPress.
We won't be hard coding each individual one.
We just code one and then that will act as the template.
And it will repeat as many times as we have blog posts.
And then we're also going to code this little snippet up and then just a footer copyright section.
Very simple.
So let's see how quickly we can do this in our code editor here.
We have finished off and in the previous section with the Subscribe bar and I believe the title banner.
Yes.
So now let's let's go down below our section here.
What's that?
A div with the class of contents dash area and then a div with the class of container, div with the
class of row and div, and this is going to have a few utility classes.
This is going to be called Ash M.D. Dash eight four eight column grid that breaks at the medium screen
size Offset Dash, M.D., Dash two.
And so this is kind of like what we did previously where we had our title banner and we had the call
M.D. Tan and an offset of one so that we could, you know, make this section not a full width.
Well, we're going to do that even more with the content area.
We want the contents to only be eight columns, but we want it to be centered in the screen.
So we're going to offset it by two so that there's two empty spaces beside on the left side of the 800.
And then obviously there's two empty spaces on the other side.
We just don't have to write it.
All right.
And then we're going to have a small screen call, Sam Dash 12, Offset Dash Sam Dash zero.
Now I'm going to test something here as overflow hidden as well utility class.
Now, normally I wouldn't write these call Sam 12 and offset some zero.
That's kind of like saying when we break, when we do call Medium 8s, when we get to the small screen
size of below medium.
Then do this.
But I believe the reality is is we don't need to put these.
Because once we get to the medium screen size, the fallback is a 12 column full width anyway, so I
mean, we can test that.
Let's go to the final version right here and we can just like, inspect and just test my hypotheses
here.
And so the idea is as we make this smaller.
And here's the small screen size coming up.
It breaks to 12 right there.
OK, so what I'm thinking is what if we just removed, call us 12 and offset in zero?
All right, so I've removed it.
I just have call medium eight offset medium 12 or two.
And let's just see if it does.
Yeah, so it does it anyway, so because of the medium break point, it goes forwards anyway.
So you can put these if for some reason you wrote suggests that overall, you know this, if you only
had this and you had some success that overall, you know the column size and the small screen, then
maybe this would be valuable.
But honestly, let's take that out.
You don't really need it.
OK, so then inside of that's we're going to have an article, the class of post, and then we're going
to have a dev with the class of meta for like content like date and stuff.
So span tag.
And let's just say, I don't know, let's do today, like September 24 in WordPress, this is going
to be dynamic anyway, outside of the meta and a half inside of that, we're going to have a level two
heading and then blog post title.
So that's so that the full H2 is a link like that.
We can also put the link inside the H2.
I guess we'll come to that when we come to it, when we get to WordPress.
We can always change our markup later paragraph tag with the class excerpt.
And then let's just put some lorem ipsum in there so that we can have kind of something to view.
And after that, we got another attack, and we're going to say class, read more and then read the
full post, and I'm going to say Right, Arrow?
Let's see if that's coming up.
Here we go.
Well, it's pretty decent, actually.
I'm actually, you know what?
I want this a tag to be inside the Level two heading.
I think it's just more proper HTML.
It could work either way, really.
But essentially, we want this H2 to be a link.
So all you're really going to do now is just copy this post, maybe one to say three for like that.
Let's see what it looks like.
Perfect.
Now what we can do is we can use utility classes to give us some margin in between.
We can also hand code the CSC, but it's going to show an example.
It's really up to you.
You don't have to follow this exactly, especially if you know some CSIS bootstrap XSS utility classes.
You really can do whatever you want here, but I'm just going to show an example.
Let's say each post we wanted to have like margin, you know, top and bottom of a certain amount,
just give it some space in between, we could say.
So we say that on each of them and four in my Dash four, and that's margin y axes.
The fourth of the styles.
So it's probably, you know, a certain amount based on the spacer and bootstrap.
So if I were to go to like bootstrap men, dot CC and I went to like M y Dash four to find it.
Here it is my fourth margin one point five m.
Am I five is three RAM?
You can you get the idea there that's that's the utility classes there.
Let's see what that looks like.
So it gives everything some breathing space there.
You know, you can do it that way.
What if we just search and replace them with four, four and y five?
Let's try it.
Little more breathing space.
You could do it that way if you want.
You know, we're going to do this in CSI anyway because this has got a lot of breathing space, but
that's just one way of doing it if you want.
That's just kind of an example.
OK, so those are excerpts.
That's all.
Now we're going to do is put our little foot or call to action.
This is going to be a global section on each of the pages.
So let's go down here and this is the content area.
So outside of the content area, what's nice about Adam is that it underlines the closing div tag so
we could find it and we're going to add a footer tag.
And the footer inside of that is going to have a div with the class of footer dash call to action text
center.
So utility class.
This will be a custom class that we'll use to target later in our casts.
David, the class of container div with a class of row, it's a bootstrap class div and this is going
to have some utility classes for our column.
So call Medium H or call MDA eight Offset Dash, M.D. Dash to perfect overflow hidden.
See Utility Class Bootstrap CSC and see what overflow dash hidden does.
So literally just excess overflow hidden as the style, so that's like if the text like a long link
or something like that overflow outside of the container you can hide it really is probably not that
necessary, but it's kind of a safeguard paragraph tag class of sub dash title during the course and
then level two heading, we can say bootstrap to WordPress 2.0 paragraph tag.
And then just like learn how to design and build custom beautiful and responsive WordPress web sites
and themes for beginners in 2021 and beyond.
Because let's be honest here, you might be looking at this in the future, and this should still be
relevant, whether it's 2022 or so on and so forth.
A HSF class BTN, BTN Primary, those are bootstrap classes.
Join now and then RR, which is unity for the right arrow.
Right Arrow can also do left arrow la ra.
And finally, we'll just add our copyright.
We're going to keep that within the footer outside of the last div here, div with the class of copyright
and text center and then paragraph tag.
Let's just say copyright.
Right side studios ink.
Whatever you want there, you can put your name.
There we go.
And that is the footer.
I believe I got that right.
Actually, I just noticed I want to move this entire footer.
Outside of these debates, so this this last debate here is, I believe, a container.
Let's find it.
Yeah, it's that.
OK, we got something going on here.
We must be missing a closing div tag.
So this is I could edit this part out.
But the reality is, is this is what happens with web development and designing and building websites.
You're going to have the stuff happens.
So I'm going to show you in real, real, real time here.
So basically, I want this footer outside of the last div.
So you know, this is what I would have done.
Like that, but something's up here when I clicked on this last div.
I see that it's saying that the opening one is the top navigation, and that's not right.
That's not what I want because top navigation should essentially close after this.
And I believe that's the problem, so this is this is how we deal with this, so we got our mobile menu.
And we actually want to close.
The We Don't Want Tidal banner inside of the top navigation.
And container.
Should close.
Not way down here.
So there we go.
So let's take these last two.
Just cut them out.
And let's put them after the mobile menu.
OK, so there we go, so now this closing div is going to be the opening div of let's see, let's start
with top now.
Todd, now perfect.
This next one should be.
Container perfect.
And then the rest is is good.
There we go.
Perfect, OK.
And then this section, we can probably indent this whole thing back one.
So that just lines up nicer.
I'm going to hold command and then the left square bracket a couple of times and atom usually that works
with most code editors, so you can move and tab in entire sections.
OK, so there we go now.
Our markup looks good, so we had a little bit of incorrect markup there for a bit where the top nav
was wrapping everything and we would have found that eventually as we were styling.
But it's good that we found it now because it probably will cause some headaches later on.
And that looks good to me.
Space that out a bit more.
That's looking good and not if we check it out.
Looks like this.
So here we go.
We've got markup.
Obviously, the navigation looks like a total horrendous mess, but we'll get there.
Perfect.
OK, so basically we can go a couple of ways here.
We can keep going and and add our code for the rest of these other ones.
But part of me is wondering if I kind of want to jump ahead a little bit and then come back.
Maybe we style it up in our next video.
Make our CSR kind of do some nicer stuff so that we're looking at something a little more inspiring
because this to me makes me want to quit because it's pretty, pretty bad.
Uh, obviously the markups good.
But the styles are bad.
So you know what?
I convince myself just now in real time next VIDEO Folks, we're going to make this look really pretty.