Hey, everybody.
Welcome back to Boost Your Income with
Bootstrap to WordPress.
This lecture is called,
Coding the Hero Section.
[MUSIC]
All right,
first thing's first on the realest.
I mean, open your code editor and
scroll down to your section,
that we titled hero in your index file.
Now in this lecture we're going
to be doing a little CSS as well.
Throughout this whole course throughout
the Bootstrap part especially
we're going to go back and
forth from our HTML to CSS.
Just a heads up, it's kind of my
style I like going back and forth.
So we're gonna be adding some classes and
then we're gonna jump over to CSS and
we're gonna style those classes so
we see them in real time.
Just as a heads up.
All right,
give that section the ID of hero, and
inside, actually let's do that first.
Inside here, let's give an HTML5 article.
Tag div.
And that's going to have
the class of container.
We know what container does.
Container gives us that wrapper
inside of our full width section.
So, right here, section, this is the full
width of the screen because we haven't
given a specific fixed width
on our body of our HTML page.
But, anything with the class
container has a fixed width, or
rather a responsive width, and
is centered in the middle of the page.
So that's where we're going
to be using container.
We'll be using container a lot.
And let's add the clear fix class,
because Bootstrap has a class
in their CSS for Clearfix.
And that will address the issue that
we will come across here when we
have floated elements within a container
or a div, block level element it will
collapse on itself if you don't clear
the elements before the container closes.
So Clearfix will fix that for us,
magic, it's beautiful saves me so
much coding time.
You too.
All right, div class row.
This is a Bootstrap class and this will
basically give us some styles so when
we add our columns in here, we're gonna
have a grid-based layout in this section.
Row is what you to need initially
code to have your grid within it.
There's documentation on
it at getbootstrap.com.
Make sure to check out the grid section,
and
you will learn all about why you need
to use rows to wrap your columns.
Just trust me,
I know what I'm doing, I think.
<div class "col-sm" for small 5.
Let me explain this.
You're gonna see a lot of these col-sm and
then a number.
So in Bootstrap they now have a grid based
system where you can use classes and
it's a way more robust grid system.
Let me just open that up for you.
Get bootstrap.com.
Let's check out the CSS.
Grid system.
Here it is.
This tells you everything you need to know
about the grid system.
Rows must be placed within a container.
Blah, blah, blah, blah.
You can read that if you need to know,
want to know a little bit more.
But here's what you are gonna
concern yourself with, right here.
Call.
XS for or whatever number.
It's also MD, LG and SM.
So here are the Grid options right here,
so extra small devices, small devices,
medium devices and large devices.
Here are the class prefixes that you
need to use if you want the grid
to work on those devices.
So, for example, on a mobile device, if
you don't want your three column grid to
collapse down into
a totally vertical layout,
then use col-xs and then whatever number.
So if you have three columns,
then you'll use cal-xs4,
so on and so forth, and that will
maintain the grid layout for you.
You'll see what I'm talking
about as we start coding, but
if you're unfamiliar with the new
version of Bootstrap, go ahead and
read the grid documentation here.
It's pretty interesting, and
I think it will blow your mind.
Maybe not blow your mind, but
you'll find it interesting.
Okay, col-sm-5,
that means for small devices,
maintain the layout, but on mobile
devices, just stack it vertically.
All right, so
let's just add our columns first,
just so we can see div class,
needs to add up to 12.
So what is 12 minus 5?
I believe that is 7, and
this class will also be hero text because
we're going to use some CSS to style our
hero text, and
we'll get there, don't worry.
Okay so here we go,
inside our container we have a row,
inside our row we have some columns,
these columns add up to 12, 5+7 is 12.
So we'll have on one side five columns and
on the other side seven columns
where our hero text will be there.
Okay, inside our first one let's add
an image assets/image/logo-badge.png.
That is in your image folder,
feel free to check that out.
Bootstrap to Wordpress it's the really
big badge, and this will have
the class of logo, because we're going
to style that, so give that a look.
There you go, there it is.
All right here, we're going to add
a level one heading and say Bootstrap to
Word Press, and then we're gonna have
a paragraph with the class of Lead.
That's a Bootstrap class.
It makes your paragraph tag
just a little bit bigger.
Earn an extra 1K to 5K
a Month by Learning to
Code Your Very Own Responsive Custom
WordPress Websites with Bootstrap.
Go ahead and type that out.
If you don't wanna type out the exact
same thing, write whatever you want, or
use some more.
Why don't we give that a look?
It's there, but something's going on here,
because you can see it's
collapsing in under our nav.
That's because our nav is
a fixed navigation bar,
and we're going to need to use
some CSS to pop that down.
Don't worry about it, we will do that, but
first let's add the rest of the content,
and then we'll style it up.
Okay, nside our div,
we're going to add another div, the ID of
price-timeline.
And here,
we will put the timeline of the prices for
this specific course, price and
active.
So that is a class I'll be using.
So we're gonna have a couple more of
these, but not with active on all of them.
Just price, price and price.
Inside here,
let's add a level four heading, and
say Pre-Launch Price, and
then in a small tag, let's say Ends soon!
Then, after that, we're gonna add
a span tag, and put the actual price.
So, let's say $149, copy this so you don't
have to write up the same markup again,
paste it in the next price,
change this to launch price and
let's just say coming soon and
that price will be $299.
Paste again and this will be Final price,
and that again will be coming soon and
that price, let's make it $399.
Give that a save, check it out.
Okay, so here we have pre-launch and
soon launch and final price.
Great, we have our content.
We'll style it eventually.
And one last thing here,
let's add a paragraph tag.
Inside that paragraph tag, let's add
an A tag with a class of BTN for button.
Button large and button danger.
These are all bootstrap classes built in.
So this is gonna style
this button real nice.
It's gonna be a button.
It's gonna be a large button, and
it's gonna have button with the color that
is associated with danger, which is red.
And that will have an href of,
right now let's just put root,
because we'll put
an actual link eventually.
Role, button Semantic.
Enroll, and then let's put HTML
entity RA quo for right arrow quote.
Save that, check it out.
There's our enroll button and
it looks nice and
it has all the styles pre-built in
we didn't have to CSS that at all.
Gonna stop you right there.
We're getting a little
long with this lecture.
We're at about nine minutes, five seconds.
I don't like my lectures to be too long.
I like them to be bite-sized snippets, so
it's not too much content
to take in at once.
I know I said at the beginning of the
lecture that we're gonna be using some CSS
in this lecture.
Not.
We're gonna be doing some CSS for
this section in the next lecture.
So consider it the same lecture,
just part B.
So see ya in the next lecture where
we're gonna be styling our hero.
[MUSIC]