Hey friends.
Welcome back to Boost Your Income with
Bootstrap to WordPress with Brad Hussey.
Should I call the course that?
Maybe too many Bs.
This lecture I want to introduce
you to an amazing plugin called
Custom Post Types UI.
Check it out.
[MUSIC]
Other amazing plugin for you guys here,
it's free, which is amazing.
And the other part is, it's gonna help you
when it comes to creating custom posts.
And that's what it's called.
It's called custom post types UI.
Post Types UI and
UI stands for User Interface.
And the reason why we're using
this plug-in is it's an admin
user interface for creating custom post
types and custom taxonomies in WordPress.
So what that means is over on our left
side, these are called post types,
Pages Comments, Posts,
those are posts types.
So on WordPress you are limited to
posting pages and posts and for
people who are using WordPress for
the first time as a CMS, they kind of get
a little worried and think like oh,
this isn't like Drupal or Joomla.
Or expression engine where I
can have these advanced and
custom fields that aren't just
limited to blog posts and pages.
What if I want to have
things like team members?
What if I want a team member post type.
What if I want a portfolio post type?
And the good news is, you can do that.
And you don't actually need
custom post types UI to do it.
You could do it in the back end
programming it using your functions like
PHP file, but that's not what we're
going to be doing in this course.
This course is all about efficiency, and
getting it done efficiently and
quickly and the best possible way.
And now for those of you who want to
learn a little bit more about how you can
hand code and hand program custom
post types, then totally go for it.
I know how to do it and I've used it
a little bit, but in all honesty,
I'm a full-time, paid web developer and
I've used custom post types in every
single WordPress site that I build and
I don't hand code them.
It's not efficient.
If I'm just doing it for practice,
then sure, totally, just so
I can get a grasp on how it works.
But if I'm trying to create websites fast,
then I'm not trying to be a hero here.
I don't need to reinvent the wheel.
Custom post types creates
a really simple user interface to
add those to your website.
So it's great.
So go ahead and
install Custom Post Types UI.
That'll show up down here,
once you activate it.
Here we go.
CPTUI, Custom post types UI.
Basically I'll just show you the UI,
you can add a new custom post type.
And here you can create
a post type name like, movie.
The label that'll show up on the side bar,
like movies the singular label movie.
So, basically,
you need to add all this information so
that it creates a custom post type,
and then you can go ahead and
see in the sidebar your
new custom post type.
And then, what you will do is hook
that in with advanced custom fields
to have your own custom field.
So if you had a movie custom post type,
you'd wanna have something like movie
title, movie rating, movie description,
movie link, link to download,
things like that.
And then you do that with
advanced custom fields.
So when you use custom post types and
advanced custom fields together,
you're literally unstoppable.
You can create whatever you want in
WordPress, and that's why I'm so
excited to show you this next lecture.
So, hang in there.
[MUSIC]