Hola, mi amigos.
Welcome back to Boost Your Income
with Bootstrap to WordPress.
This lecture is called Cover Your Assets.
We're gonna be installing our assets
folder into our WordPress site.
Boom.
[MUSIC]
All right, and we're back.
So this lecture is called
Cover Your Assets.
And basically what I mean by that is that
we need to add all of the proper assets,
or more specifically,
our assets folder to our WordPress site.
Because right now, we have no images,
we have no styles, we have no fonts,
we have no JS, all that stuff.
Very important for the overall look and
functionality of our website.
Specifically, Bootstrap.
We need Bootstrap for
this site to work the way that we coded
it when we did the static version of it.
So right here is the static version we
coded, and here's the assets folder.
Essentially, all I want you to do,
is just take that folder, and
copy it over, right into your Bootstrap
to WordPress theme root directory.
So, that's one step.
We're not quite done yet.
So, in there we have the css,
fonts, images, and js.
We need to make sure that we
have everything referenced.
Now, when we coded this section right
here, when we coded the static site, and
we built our assets folder, at least when
I recorded it, I added Bootstrap 3.2.0.
But in the web development world,
things always update, so
now we're on Bootstrap version 3.3.1.
Now at the time of the recording,
I did 3.2.0, but
you probably will have already
downloaded 3.3.1 because
I include it in the course files folder,
right here, Bootstrap 3.3.1.
And that gives us, when you uncompress it,
this dist folder with css, fonts, and js.
Basically all I need to do
Is make sure that my css and
my js and fonts are up to date.
So you might not need to do this but
I'm gonna do it right now
just in case you have 3.2.0.
So right here, css, let's drag in
our bootstrap-theme.min.css and
bootstrap.min.css, pull those over.
Right into our CSS.
And we're gonna replace both of those.
Great, fonts.
We wanna make sure those are up to
date too, so those glyph icons,
we're gonna drag those right in here.
We're gonna replace all of those,
and then we have our js.
We have bootstrap.min.js and bootstrap.js.
Grab those, drag them into your js folder,
replace both.
Great.
Again, like I said,
if you're already using 3.3.1,
you don't need to worry about this.
If you're using any earlier version,
go ahead and do what I just did.
So, drag your assets folder into
the root directory of your theme.
Great.
Now, it doesn't just work that easy.
We need to actually reference these.
So, this is pretty elementary stuff,
but we're gonna do it.
We need to, in under our,
let's put it under here.
You could type all this out.
Or, you could check out
your index file here.
And you can just, basically,
copy all of this stuff.
And we're gonna change
the paths to all of them.
So, copy that.
Paste it right here.
Okay.
Now let's change this up.
I need to reference the assets
folder in our WordPress theme.
And the way to do that is not
the way that you are used to.
Basically, you need to reference
the root directory of the theme,
not the root directory of WordPress.
Take note of that, or remember that.
Because you will run into many
issues if you reference the wrong
path of your assets.
So this is how you do it,
php you use a built in word
press function called bloginfo.
And then we can access
the stylesheet_directory.
That will give us the directory.
This is dynamic and will always update
no matter if we're on local host or
if you're on your website.com or
your website.ca or whatever it is.
The style sheet directory is dynamic and
will always find your Bootstrap to
WordPress style sheet directory, or
whatever active theme you're using.
And then after that,
/assets/css, there it is.
So now your core CSS should be hooked in.
Same thing goes for
the rest of this stuff.
So let's just copy this and
the forward trailing slash there.
And paste this before your
FontAwesome Icons, /css/font-awesome.
Great.
And the Custom CSS.
Basically, this is not going to
be included right here because
it's built in to WordPress, so
it doesn't quite work the same.
You can add a custom CSS style sheet but
if you want to keep it simple and
use the built in styles, the style sheet
that's already in Bootstrap to WordPress.
They just have it simply here outside
of assets and just have it right
here in the root directory of
the Bootstrap to WordPress theme.
You don't need to actually do this.
But you need to make sure that
your styles in your css folder
are copied into this style.css.
So why don't we do that?
Delete this, save what you have so far.
Google Fonts should be good to go.
Now, what you wanna do is,
open up your style.css
file that came with the starter theme.
Go ahead and open that up.
Now, this comes with the theme.
There is a lot of
unnecessary styles in here,
we're gonna clean it up
in the next lecture.
But for now,
basically what we want to do is grab here
in our css folder, open up custom.css.
This is the CSS we coded
in our static site.
Copy all of it, Cmd+A, Cmd+C.
Copy all of that.
And at the end of the style
sheet that's provided with
the skeleton theme, paste it.
Okay, so now it's in there, I'm just
gonna scroll up to the very beginning
of our custom styles here, and
we're gonna make a note of it.
Okay so we have custom,
we have Galleries here,
this is the previous styles, here we go.
Here's where our styles start.
I'm gonna add a comment here.
And this is gonna be I
believe this is number 13.
12.2, yeah we're gonna go number
13 in our table of contents here.
This is Theme Specific Styles.
Not necessary to put this,
but trying to keep organized here in
our table of contents up at the top.
So why don't we just add that in here.
13.0 Styles.
There we go.
So now you know number 13 is
our Theme Specific Styles.
You can scroll down to your theme specific
styles, they're all right here, okay.
Go ahead and hit Save.
Now you could just get rid
of your custom.css file.
You don't need it anymore because
it's now included in your style.css.
However, leave your css folder because we
have our theme.min and bootstrap.min.css.
So this is basically just
external third party things.
So like font-awesome CSS for
Bootstrap, fonts for
Bootstrap, this is gonna be our images,
and we have JS for Bootstrap and
jQuery, and our custom JS.
All right, so you save that.
Let's go back to our header.
One more thing we're missing here
is under our Google fonts here.
In our static, we have the HTML5 shiv and
the IE9 maxcdn links.
So copy those.
And we're going to, under WordPress head,
it's important to do that
because this needs to be
last in our head here.
So the HTML5 shiv and
that will include the less than
IE 9 conditional comments here.
So if you're looking at this on IE 8 or
lower, then we're going
to serve up some shiv and
respond.js that's gonna help HTML5
work on those crappy browsers.
If any of you are using IE,
I suggest not doing that and
using something like Chrome or Safari.
Okay.
So, we're looking good.
We covered our assets, right over here.
We added our updated Bootstrap files and
all of that.
We made sure our styles from our
custom.css were copied into our style.css,
which is a theme specific style
sheet already prebuilt in to our
WordPress head function that comes
with our skeleton underscores meme.
Great, all right.
So, good lecture.
You did a good job.
There's a lot more to do, but
it's gonna get better and better and
better cuz you're gonna start
seeing some really cool results.
Well, before we end this,
why don't we check it out and
see if something's changed.
You know, maybe something's broken.
All right here we go.
You can see a significant difference.
Obviously it looks like crap right now.
But you can see that
Bootstrap's hooked in.
We have some styles that
roughly reflect what we coded.
There are fonts.
And all that stuff.
So we're getting there.
I'll see you in the next lecture.
We're gonna clean up that style sheet and
start making this look a bit better.
All right.
See you there.
[MUSIC]