Hey everybody.
Welcome back to Boost Your Income with
Bootstrap To WordPress.
We're in an brand new section now called
Information Architecture where we focus
a little bit more on the specific blue
printing details of web design and
development.
This specific lecture is called
why you must always start your web
design with a sketch.
[MUSIC]
All right, so let's talk about
sketching or, more specifically,
let's use the proper term, wireframing.
Wireframing is an important step in
web design, and it's often overlooked.
Think of wireframing as
the blueprints of web design.
Let's use a different
sort of analogy here.
When you are building a house,
you don't just start taking wood and
just hammering it together.
If you have house building experience,
you know that's not right.
You don't just do that.
Because you overlook things like
where's the electrical going to go,
where are we going to put the plumbing.
How is the plumbing gonna
run through the house?
Where are the doors?
How are the doors gonna open?
Which direction?
Does that door get in the way of this?
Or is there something
blocking that entrance?
What about windows?
Where are the windows gonna be?
Electrical outlets?
Things like that have been
very important steps.
The layout of the house needs to
be blueprinted and sketched out.
Before you even pick up a hammer and
a nail, the same goes for web design.
The blueprint, or the wireframe,
needs to be laid out and sketched out.
Before you start opening Photoshop or
writing a line of code.
The reason why is,
it lets you work out all the details
before you get too far into the project.
So, if you just jump into designing and
you don't even think like,
this is where we're going
to put the carousel.
This is we're gonna put the contact page,
content, it's fine over here.
We'll throw a sidebar there.
Lots of websites have that.
Great, we're good.
You don't even think about usability.
You don't think about the architecture.
You don't think about important elements
because your head is somewhere else.
You're in a creative process.
This is a more logical process.
You need to see the steps,
you need to see the outline, and
you can work out details before you
even get farther into the project.
The reason why is because you're just
looking at the black and white boxes and
lines that you sketched out on pen and
paper or in Photoshop.
You're just sketching out
just a rough draft, and
it's easy to say, scrap that,
that doesn't look good.
Let's try this layout.
Let's discuss that with the client.
What are we putting a sidebar there?
What kind of content goes there?
Where should we put this?
Where should we put that?
It's easy to modify a wireframe,
cuz you're just sketching something
out on pen and paper or in Photoshop.
It's just,
it's really easy to hash out the details.
A few of the reasons why it's
important to wireframe is because
usability becomes important.
You focus on where the links are,
the navigation structure.
Certain elements.
What is more important?
Why is that placed on the page?
Let's think about the usability
a little bit more.
And that's what wieframing lets you do.
The design process also becomes a bit more
easy because you're just
sketching out your layouts and
your design elements on paper or
on Photoshop.
And once you've kind of worked
through the perfect layout,
you can then jump into Photoshop and
you'll already know what you're designing.
You're not just thinking of something off
the top of your head as you are adding
colors and fonts and background images,
and all this and all that.
So basically, it's an important
process that's often overlooked,
because people think of it as boring,
or not important.
But it works.
Whenever I sketch a website layout out,
I can see, oh, that doesn't make sense.
Why am I doing that?
Or maybe this needs to be in a more
important spot or that's not gonna work.
Or it's easy to have an iterative process
with your team members or with your client
and without jumping into a full design and
having your client say I don't like that.
What if we switch something up here?
Then you're putting way more
work in than you need to.
If you just have boxes and lines.
You can drag and
drop stuff around no problem.
Because you're just sketching stuff out.
It's easy.
It's a very easy and
simple process that is fundamental
in the success of your project.
So now that we've covered that,
let's jump into the next lecture.
I'm gonna show you a couple resources
that you can use to wireframe.
That professional web designers and
developers use to wireframe.
I'll see you there.
[MUSIC]