Hey, everyone, welcome back to boost your income and bootstrapped WordPress, and this lecture is
called.
Let's call.
Clean up your stylesheet and modify your access for WordPress.
OK, so one quick thing that we need to do first before we get into cleaning up the stylesheet is a
fix the brand down here, the Navar brand, the we're still referencing the wrong image file.
And it's been bugging me when I was just getting started on this.
The electricity, we sell a broken image up here.
Not cool with me, not cool with you.
Let's fix this super easy.
All you got to do is.
And then do the good ol.
Blog info.
And reference the stylesheet.
Underscore directory and then slash and then that should get you the correct.
File, let's see if it's there.
Cool, it is there it's kind of hidden under the dashboard, the toolbar up here, but that's what's
part of this lectures about we're going to clean up the CSFs.
So this starts to look a bit better.
Part of it will be making sure that we can see our header and not have our toolbar covering our good
stuff.
All right.
In your code, editor, open up that good old style dot access file.
Now, let me tell you a few things about all this fancy stuff up here.
When you create a new theme, this first comment up here in your stylesheet the style access file is
very important.
It tells WordPress a lot of important information, like the theme name, the theme, you or I, the
author, author, you are description, version, number, license, bla bla bla bla bla bla bla.
Where you would see this in your dashboard, check it out, dashboard head over to appearance and then
themes this year that these guys have information here.
So let's click on theme details, bootstrap to WordPress version 1.0, and then I'm not sure what that's
from.
I'm pretty sure when you downloaded the underscores theme, a tag that on.
So let's just go version one point.
Oh, boom, that'll be good.
The name good to go author, you can change that to you if you wish and save that.
You'll see that now version one point oh.
Now, you're probably wondering, hey, why do I just have a just like a default, kind of transparent,
immature, I want a cool image.
Well, you can do that.
And I actually have an image already.
I will make sure that it is in your miscellaneous folder, in the course files miscellaneous, I'll
make sure that you have the proper screenshot.
Boom.
There you go.
Screenshots.
And this is what we're going to be using as the theme screenshot kind of image.
So that's in your miscellaneous folder.
And then all you need to do is replace the screenshots right here.
This is your transparent picture.
Just replace screenshot in the root directory of the theme with your screenshot right there.
Now, watch this and replace that.
And if I refresh, we're going have a nice image here.
Boom, there it is, bootstrapped to WordPress by Brad Hussie, customer first team using Bouchet version
one point.
Oh Wicken there it is.
OK, that looks good.
OK, so let's get back to what Stylesheet.
Got a little excited there.
Now there is a lot of success that is included in this default style sheet that I don't want because
it's, it's excessive.
There's a reset, lots of typographical things, elements, forms, navigation, some of it's important
like accessibility and certain elements like infinite scroll media captions and galleries, all that
you can remove if you really want.
But I am going to remove what we don't need.
So what we don't need is this entire reset section.
So get rid of that.
We don't need reset because bootstrap already comes with a bunch of reset stuff.
The normalized, I believe so give it a reset, in fact, get rid of typography as well.
Just kind of redundant, because we already have this stuff figured out in our static site or static
site looks great and this is just overwriting all of our hard work and we don't need that.
So elements we don't need this.
Get rid of this two forms.
We don't need that either.
And boom, got rid of that navigation, five point one links, we don't need that and we don't need
that menus.
Let's get rid of almost everything.
Get rid of everything all the way down to.
The small menu right here.
And then.
We're going to keep sight, main content, navigation, stuff like this, because these are WordPress
specific styles and they may come up in our templates as we build our site and as it grows over time.
This isn't specifically overwriting like typography or reset elements or forms.
This is more specifically WordPress style.
So you could see like common navigation, paging navigation.
We want kind of we want that to be we want to leave that there for now.
Accessibility, important, keep that certain things here are important to keep.
So don't bother removing that alignments.
Keep that as well, because the line left, right and center, this is actually when you code or type
something in your WordPress text editor and you just you take a text or like an image and align it left,
center or right.
It tags a class on that element and that class or those classes are these classes and that will help
align those things.
So keep that clearing's.
Keep that as well.
Because certain things will keep the country content, content, content, things like that, not necessarily
remove that widgets as well, keep that content.
Keep this, because these are all WordPress specific styles.
Again, we probably won't use most of this stuff, but, you know, as time goes on and we realize,
hey, we're not using the stuff, you can go, go, go ahead and trim that out.
Same with asides and comments.
Infinite scroll media keep captions or good galleries.
Keep that as well.
This is the when you add a specific or a gallery within your content in the text editor in WordPress,
it adds these styles so that the items, the gallery items are in a grid like format.
And then last but not least, we have our theme specific styles, good Sèvres that we basically cleaned
a lot of it up.
And let's just have a little look to see.
So far, so not really much has happened.
A few margin fixes and not much else because we haven't really run into it.
But we solved this little issue up here.
I want to fix that because it's bugging me.
I want to be able to see what is happening up there.
Pretty simple right here in your stylesheet.
Let's just add a little something here.
Uh, logged in.
Is the class that's actually a class that WordPress adds, you know, you have that WordPress, Dasch
head function.
Well, right here in your site, WordPress.
Adds a bunch of classes to the body right here home, so we know it's the home page.
It's currently the blog page as well, logged in and Midvale, no customer support.
So they add some styles or classes and we can target those.
So logged in Novar fixed top.
We want that to be.
Top thirty two, because it is position relative, we can go top 30 to.
That no fixed will move down 32 pixels, which is the height of this admin toolbar.
There we go.
Now we have our header with our dynamic navigation items.
So this is exciting.
OK, let's keep going.
Let's clean up some more stuff.
In our general here, um, let's fix the background, because this this is not going to work.
This is not referencing the right assets.
And you can't do this in WordPress.
You need to actually be more specific.
So we can basically do this every time that we find an image, uh, you URL image reference.
But there's probably a handful of these in our success.
So why don't we just do a global search and replace if you're not using coded to most code, do this.
If not.
Again, a really good reason why Sugar-coated to it saves you so much time otherwise are going to have
to go in manually and do this.
So not cool time waster.
All right.
So we want to select your URL string, dot, dot, slash image.
And then we want to replace that with.
It looks like this, your URL waps, you are el.
String forward slash content, dash content slash themes, bootstrap to WordPress, slash assets.
Image and make sure you don't put the trailing slash at the end, if you didn't overhear otherwise,
you're going to be adding a double Trilling's and you're going to break your references, your paths.
OK, so you got Web content themes bootstrapped to WordPress, assets, image, what that is doing is
jumping from the root of the whole WordPress site B to W WordPress content themes, bootstrap to WordPress
jumping in the assets were jumping in images and were snagging those images.
Awesome, cool.
Replace all boom.
Nine instances were fixed.
So now all of our background images will be they'll be referenced properly.
Why don't we say that and just have a little chat?
Because I know the background should now have a texture.
Great, I can see it here.
I don't know if you'll see it on your on the recording here, maybe it won't be as high enough quality.
You see the subtle background, but on your browser you should see the subtle background tile.
Let's keep going.
OK, so I went through the stylesheet and there isn't much else that we need to clean up at this point
except for down here in the media queries the when we get to a certain width.
On our site for mobile devices, the toolbar switches.
Watch this.
Right there, see how the toolbar becomes a mobile toolbar, but it's kind of it's now it's taller and
it's tucked under our header here.
So we're going to change that.
We're going to fix that and add a little media query here.
No problem.
Just before five, six to eight.
After seven.
Actually, it's going to be above seven.
Sixty eight.
Below nine.
Ninety one.
And it's going to be specifically to fix the top margin when logged in to media screen and Max with
seven eighty two.
For some reason WordPress chose 702 as the width.
Not really sure why, but that's the specific width that the breakpoint is at.
And in here we're going to say logged in now our fixed top and then that will be top will be forty six
pixels, which is the new height of that toolbar.
And that should fix now.
There we go.
So that swaps when you get down to that 70, 80 to perfect.
Looks good.
And then eventually our toolbar, our neighbor starts working and we go, OK, great.
There's also one last thing here.
Now, if I make this bit smaller, you could see the toolbar then just gets a bit smaller.
I'm assuming they do that just to clean up the toolbar so it works a bit better on mobile devices.
We need to fix that.
We need that to line up better.
So that breakpoint is actually six hundred pixels.
Again, I don't really know why they did that.
Why did they didn't use the standard, um, the standard breakpoints in mobile devices.
Not sure, but they did.
So we need to accommodate for that.
OK, so all you need to do is fix the top marginal logged in media screen max with six hundred.
Put that above the five sixty eight below the seven sixty eight.
And you're all you're going to do here is just select your logged in.
No fixed top and that's going to be top forty two pixels.
Check it out there.
It is fixed so that will adjust.
With WordPress, great, OK, that's really it for this lecture, next lecture, we're going to clean
up the footer in our WordPress theme and add some scripts and all that sort of good stuff.
See their.