Hey, friend, welcome back.
So we've got a mess up here with all of the links hanging out here and the pool dots and allied dots
and this ugly little thing and an ax over there.
We got to make this look more like this and behave more like this.
That's what we want to do.
Let's do it.
Here we go back here in our little line where he said more now.
Styles to come.
Get rid of that and let's continue from where we left off.
And because we've got a big chunk of code to right here, I'm going to try and be real efficient here
and not walk through.
Every single character will write the code out quickly and I'll explain any kind of unusual things that
happen as we go.
So we're going to do.
Main menu navigation L.I menu item has children Child's Locker A..
So again, pretty specific selector.
And that's going to have the padding right of 16 pixels.
And I have the important I don't know what this is called just important with with the exclamation point.
It just overrides any other style that might be styling this.
And we want to just make sure that the padding rate is 16 pixels.
Usually that happens when you're coding and your style is not working, so you just throw an important
in there.
It overrides whatever you're trying to do.
All right.
Next up, we got main menu navigation child selector L.I menu item has children, child selector a before,
before, as a pseudo element.
So we're selecting before, and that's going to have a few things here.
So we're going to have the font family of flat icon.
That's a flat icon font, Emily, that we brought in that flat icon font family we brought in.
And this a little bit of each HTML entity here, like the backslash F1 zero four is actually one of
the icons.
And in our files, I think if we went to like font flat icon HTML four to open that file up in a browser,
we'll actually see what each of them are.
And I believe you can also open CSS.
So yeah, so let's let's open that up in a browser.
So here's our flat, I can file that we that I provided in the project files, but you can also get
it at the flat acorn website.
And right here you can see if you want to use these styles or you can use a class or you can use the
HTML.
What is it called like?
A code?
Simple code.
The entity.
And I believe you'll find those in the course of the flat icons success.
So we've got menu close, right, arrow down, arrow so on, so forth.
See?
So that is what we're grabbing there.
So we're throwing it into here.
So f one zero four looks like we're grabbing the arrow down sign to navigate.
Cool.
There it is.
Position absolute right.
Zero font size 12 line height 34 Font White Font Weight 800.
All right, we're going to keep moving on here.
We're going to select the main menu navigation child selector ally.
You all in there.
We're going to have a handful of styles, one a position on absolute and negative.
Thirty left seventy pixels from the top.
We want the min width to be 150 pixels z index, to be 100 to override kind of be in front of everything
and the opacity to be zero.
We want it to not be visible right now.
And we will change that in an upcoming style.
We want the list style to be none because we don't want those little dots.
We want visibility to be hidden, display to be black.
And now what we're going to do is we're going to transition.
All point four seconds is let's actually change that to our variable VAR.
Dash Dash Transition Dash Dir.
OK, let's throw that in there.
And each of these instances.
Just to be consistent, why not?
Nobody will notice, but why not?
And then finally, padding 20 pixels top and bottom, 15 pixels left and right.
All right.
Let's add a couple more things, actually.
Background color.
That's going to be white and we're going to add a box shadow, which is going to have zero pixels,
zero pixels, 10 pixels.
Ogba GBA zero zero zero zero point one So pretty pretty like non opaque Mr word hard to see.
Lose my word said.
Hey folks, let's check it on the browser.
All right, so we've cleaned up, we've hidden the menu, that's what we did.
Put that down, arrow, we've hidden the menu, the submenu, we can't see it right now because we haven't
done any styles to make it visible.
So let's let's get moving on that.
Let's move, move on.
Next up, we've got main menu navigation, child selector, ally child.
You call child ally.
So again, really specific and we're doing position relative width 100 percent border bottom one pixel
solid F9, F9, F9 So very, very thin and hard to see like hairline, that's kind of the ally in each
of the submenus.
So in under the ally, we want to make it look like this.
So you can kind of see here there's like a thin hairline.
That's essentially what we're making.
All right.
And then we want the last one.
So in the final one here, we want the last item like blog or contact in this case to have no hairline
on the bottom because it doesn't look very good if there is.
And that doing this coming up, if we do main menu, we select that last child navigation, child,
ally, child, URL, child, ally and then colon.
Last child, it selects the last ally, which I showed you in that example.
And we're going to say border bottom.
None.
Cool.
All right.
Moving on, we got some more specific child selectors coming up here, folks.
Main menu navigation child ally child u l child, ally child a.
So basically, this is saying only this a.
Tag that as a child of the of the lie immediately before it, that as a child who you are a child of
the ally child of this, so it's very specific.
So we don't like select accidentally all tags within a list or something, and we're going to make that
position relative.
Display block.
We want the padding to be 10 pixels top and bottom, eight pixels left and right line height to be 24
pixels.
We want the font weight to be 400, font size to be 15.
We want to text transform that to capitalize.
In case you have any, you know, you spell it lowercase, you want to capitalize the first letter color
going to be two to two.
Let's see if we have that anywhere up here.
We don't know.
What we can do is we could just use colored arc.
Maybe we'll do that for our color dark.
We can use our variables.
And now we're going to do some transitions.
Transition all 500 milliseconds is to the Moore's web kit, Microsoft and opera browser fallbacks.
And then we're going to do another big child selector here.
Main menu navigation alive while I hover.
So on hover of this ally as a children of these, these the A.
So for hovering over the ally, we want to style this specific a link.
What we're going to do is we're going to make the color.
FDA zero zero and the padding left to be 10.
I mean, check if we have that as a variable FDA zero zero, it's the color yellow perfect.
So the color yellow save that.
Now let's see what happens in our version.
OK, nothing's happening so far.
That's OK.
It's all happening in the background.
OK, I need to make it appear.
So we still got a few more stores here.
All right, we've got main menu navigation legal ally with the class of menu item has children and then
that child a after pseudo element, big selectors.
Here it's going to be flat icon font and if one zero five is the content.
Position absolute.
We're going to go 15 pixels in the right, 14 pixels from the top.
We're going to do width and height.
The width is ten pixels, the height is 20 pixels display block and the color is going to be 01:58 or
let's use our dark color color dark.
Line height and font size, 20 pixel line height, 12 pixel font size.
Font weight is going to be normal, the text a line is going to be center and then the Z Index five
font weight 800.
OK, we're getting closer.
Closing in on this?
Let's see if anything happens here.
Refresh.
OK, we're not doing anything yet.
That's OK.
It's all happening in the background.
This will appear and once once we make it appear, then and then it will all start to to show all of
our hard work here.
And what I recommend is if any of this stuff is confusing to you because we would have the longest license
in the entire whole wide world if I were to explain every single line of this, I presume that many
of you watching have some CSI experience and if not, like, play around with it once.
Once you follow along and we make this menu up here, take some stuff out just like, you know, take
a whole swath of it out, you know, go Command X to cut.
And then, like, save it, see what happens and then paste it back in and see what happens to isolate
what each style does, that's a great way of learning, by the way.
All right.
So.
What do we got next?
Main menu navigation.
You, Ally menu item has children.
When you hover the child selector after it's thought the same style as this one, I don't know.
Let's check how Lionel Ally.
Menu navigation, this one looks a bit longer.
Oh, OK, well, this one's when we hover.
OK, perfect.
As soon as when we hover, we're going to just make the color of that.
A after pseudo element is going to be our bar.
Color dark.
Now we're going to do is we're going to position sorry, we're going to do main menu navigation, legal
ally you all.
So we're nesting here doing a lot of nesting.
That's going to be position absolute left 120 percent top zero percent.
That could also be zero virtually the same number.
And then the mean width of this element is going to be 150 pixels.
See what happens so far.
If anything's coming up, nothing yet.
It's a whole, very underwhelming so far.
When is that index 100?
List style.
None.
Save that.
OK.
Opacity zero display block.
When do some padding, background color and box shadows of 20 pixels top bottom, 15 pixels left right.
White background color block shadows zero zero 10 Najiba.
All zeros in our igby and then on the Alpha Channel zero point one.
Then finally, some transitions.
All 2.4 seconds is now, as you know, point four seconds.
It's close enough to our to our variable transition, dir.
So we're going to do that.
We're going to change it to VAR Transition Dir in our replace all.
OK.
Say that actually were good and.
Now we're getting closer to making this thing appear.
So what I'm going to do is actually I'm going to make it appear well, we're we're going to jump right
to that style where we make it appear and then we'll go back and do some finished styling so he can
kind of see our work because I have the benefit of, I know what this is going to look like.
And you're just kind of trusting the process here, which is great.
But let me let's let's make it appear, and then we'll come back to where we were here.
I want to jump ahead here.
I see more now, styles to come and I'll go down.
And so we're going to say main menu navigation.
Ally menu item has children hover and in the pool, so any navigation menu ally that has children,
so the class, we're going to select that URL when we hover on the fly that has that class and we're
going to do is do visibility visible opacity one and then display block.
Let's see what that does.
OK, so it made it appear it's looking pretty good.
And we're not getting a submenu here or sub submenu, but so far it's looking pretty good.
Now we need to do is go left zero percent.
Am I going to do border top?
Zero Pixels?
And importance to override any other border styles we have.
We're going to do some transforms.
So we've got to transform rotate x zero degrees and then Moore's Web Kit Microsoft, an opera.
Well, this one at the top.
All right.
So if that did anything.
Kind of more in the animation's camp.
All right.
Actually, this is what we're going to have, this is probably going to change.
Right now, we're rotating in to zero degrees, but eventually when we go back to our more nav styles,
we will probably actually add that rotation and this resets the rotation to zero.
So it might seem like this did nothing, but it will eventually.
OK, now let's select the submenu like the Sub Submenu, Main Menu Navigation Ally, Child URL child
alive with the class of menu item has children hover children, you ll cool.
We're going to another level deep here and we're going to do visibility.
Visible display block opacity one.
Top zero.
Kind of like the last one left one hundred percent.
Let's just see what happens.
It's probably going to make it work real.
Nice.
And it mean in very cool satellite link style, but we're getting there now, what we also need to do
is our transforms.
So we got the Transform Rotate acts, and that's because eventually when we go back, we're going to
have some rotations in there.
And so it maybe rotates in and we're going to do our transition is going to have all 300 milliseconds.
So here's our transform style.
So transition styles save it.
We're going to keep going.
Big Selecter main menu child, you'll fly with the class, the menu item has children.
All right, let's go back up to our more now styles, and we're going to make all that happen again.
All right, so.
Now we're going to do is we're going to add back in here main menu navigation child, ally child, you
child, ally, child URL to class of from right?
And we're going to add left auto right.
Zero.
Main menu navigation.
A child's electors, loyal ally, you'll ally.
And this is going to have position relative width 100 percent border bottom one pixel solid F9, F9,
F9 All right.
From here.
Main menu navigation.
Todd Selecter, all the way through U L L IU, L L I would see the element of last child just like the
last one and we're doing border bottom.
None.
Just want to make sure that I'm not writing this again twice because I know that we.
We did last child up here somewhere.
No, I think we're good.
We're just selecting, I guess, further in the Sub submenu, so if we save and refresh.
Then we're adding the hairlines in under this perfect.
OK.
Now we're going to do is we're going to go into that submenu subsub menu and grab the AirTags.
So we got this big selector here.
I'll read it out.
Main menu navigation L.I, you'll ally, you'll ally a all child selectors.
And then we're going to have position relative display block and we're going to have padding.
Top and bottom is 10 pixels left and right, 18 line height is 24.
The font weight is 400.
Font size is 15.
As usual, text transform.
Capitalize the color.
We're going to make that VAR color dark, then padding left.
So we're overwriting that.
No.
And then some transitions transition all five hundred milliseconds is Mars webcams and oh all the same
for fallbacks.
OK, now save.
Maybe let's have a little look.
Now we're looking real nice now, it's not animating like this, so I think we should maybe take care
of that coming up.
Next.
We want.
Main menu navigation.
We're nesting pretty deep here.
I hover and a.
So we want to change that color to our VAR color yellow.
So when we hover on that submenu, the links in the sub submenu rather.
And then we got our main menu navigation.
We're digging deep into that subsub menu, the fly when you hover to a high.
In fact, I think it's exact same.
Yeah.
And then padding left.
10 pixels.
Came.
Check it out.
That's looking better.
There we go.
All right, so now we're going to do is we're going to dig into the that.
Submenu subsub menu again.
Now, here's another way of writing out that child selector where you have many, many, many, many
child selectors who do something like this.
Main menu navigation and then on a new line child Lee child you call child Lee Child, you will child
play with the class menu item has children, child a after school element.
So you could do that.
And it's just some people like doing that.
Some some designers and developers like doing that.
It's easier to see.
Whereas this is a little dizzying, you know the all in one line to you.
And then we're going to do this is a font family flat icon content backslash F1 zero five.
It's going to be position absolute.
Ten from the top, ten from the right, eleven from the top.
Width and height.
Ten pixels or the width, 20 pixels for the height?
Let's check it out.
See what happens?
OK, I don't see much of a change here.
But.
Believe us icon, yeah, we're we're trying to add this icon there, so let's keep going.
I think it's because we need to go display block now, if we show it refresh and we still don't see
it.
Let's keep going.
Color, this is probably it, 277 to seven.
We could also go like this VAR dash dash colored dark.
And line height, 20 pixels.
Font size 12 pixels, font weight 800.
Text Align Center Z Index five.
Maybe this will make it show up.
I'm not seeing anything.
Main menu, navigation and lie.
Mean, let me just check my code here.
Well, let's keep going, actually, and then we'll isolate to see if this did anything, keep going.
So we're going to do is we're going to select the main menu navigation.
Child IU, L L IU, L L I menu item has children hover A. After pseudo element might be the exact same
selectors up here, let me just confirm.
OK, so this one is with without the hover, and this one is with the hover.
That's it.
OK.
It's always nice to make sure.
OK, so in this, this is where we're going to do a couple of things.
So let's bring this all back.
One.
Clean it up.
OK.
This is going to be color white.
This is where we're going to make some stuff happen.
Let's see.
Main menu navigation child Ally menu item has children, hover child, you all so in this one, right,
this is where we're going to make things appear.
Visibility visible opacity one display block left zero border top zero.
Important or decent transforms that rotate.
So I already did that were there.
OK, so let's check it out blog.
Ta ta da.
All right, well, we did do the styles cool.
So.
I'm thinking.
The suction here, let's just remove it and see if it did anything flat icon menu item has children.
It's possible that we out of these styles, but they're not showing up because we don't have that markup
in there.
So you don't.
All right, let's have a look.
And now it's looking really, really good.
OK.
I just want to show you something real quick here, I was just kind of reviewing my code and remember
we wrote these rotate acts now.
Currently, we actually don't do anything with that.
I think we might have wrote this when meaning we, as in behind the scenes, wrote this code and didn't
have a look.
We meant to use an animation, but we didn't actually incorporate anything.
So what this is saying is when you hover on this submenu, you know, put the rotate back to zero.
But the thing is is we don't actually rotate it anywhere.
We don't have it rotated.
So if you want to do something with this way, you can do is just select this one main menu navigation,
you know, limey menu item has children hover you all right before it.
Take the hover state off of it, and let's like actually transform it to start at, you know, certain
rotation.
So let's say, you know, like.
Forty degrees.
So now this, by default, is 40 degrees, but you don't see it until we hover and it actually is going
to rotate to zero, so let's see what that does.
Very subtle, almost like it kind of squeezes.
You can kind of see that if we would've made it more
drastic, let's say, like 90.
You can kind of see there, it's like rotating 90 degrees on the x axis.
You can also change Rotate X to rotate Y if you wanted to spend another way.
So let's search and replace everything, rotate x and we'll change it to rotate.
Why?
So what happens?
It looks kind of interesting.
You could also rotate.
Z.
Replace all.
So let's see.
That's interesting.
Kind of cheesy, but maybe what we can do is, like make it a little more subtle, so instead of 90
degrees, we can do something like.
20 degrees.
Just a little more subtle.
That's kind of neat, actually kind of think that's cool.
Maybe even more subtle, I'm all about subtlety.
It's like eight degrees, so it's going to hurt to replace.
20 degrees to eight degrees.
Yeah, it's kind of a neat.
Kind of a neat little thing, you could do the same thing with this one.
This one does a different animation.
It slides in from the right.
Maybe we'll leave it.
Yeah.
OK, I'll be I'll be done in three minutes, OK?
No, I'm almost done, buddy.
I'm recording a video, so I need three minutes, three minutes, tell mom three minutes.
Since that time, I'm three minutes.
Illegally and recording video, I need you to go all the up and through the.
Let's see if we could do something with them, because right now we're not doing anything, so here
is that sub submenu.
We're in a place that same thing, but take the hover out so the current, the actor or the standard
state we're going to do like, we'll rotate it again from eight degrees, going to copy that style.
So just to show you here.
Main menu.
This is the sub submenu.
That we're selecting and this is its hover state.
So we're rotating on the z axis from eight degrees.
Let's see what happens.
That's neat.
I think that that's pretty cool.
And when they both like, go away, whoa, I like it, I like it a lot.
Good job on that one.
All right, and not as good for this lesson.
We tidy this up.
We cleaned up the menu.
We did a submenu subsub menu, lots of styles in there.
In their next video, we're going to take care of this mobile menu.