Hey everyone, welcome back to Boost
Your Income with Bootstrap to WordPress.
This lecture is called Add the course
features using custom post types and
advanced custom fields.
That's a mouth full, check it out.
[MUSIC]
All right, so this lecture's gonna be fun.
So it's gonna be a little bit more
advanced than the previous lecture,
because what we have to do for
this course feature section,
is not only add the image and
the title, which is easy.
We have to add each of these items,
these course features, and
we're gonna use custom post types.
You want to be able to have these
be individual custom posts,
because what if we want to
add only three features?
Or what if I have more features as we
go along, and I have ten features?
And if we were to use just
the advanced custom fields,
then we're only going to make room for
six of them.
But if we do advanced custom post types,
then we can keep adding individual
post types and they'll be
individual entries in the database.
The other bonus in this lecture
is we're gonna show you how
we can use custom post types and
advanced custom fields to
decide which icon we're going to use,
by modifying the CSS spread.
So, jam packed lecture,
this is going to be awesome, all right.
So let's head back to our
Custom Post Types UI, click on Add New.
And we want to add a new Custom Post Type,
and we want to call it course_feature.
So it's gonna be lowercase and
we're going to use no spaces, so
we're going to use underscore,
course_feature.
And then the label on the sidebar
I want to be Course Features,
the singular label will be Course Feature.
And then the description, it won't
show up anywhere but this is just for
your own sake.
These are the features you
wanna highlight in the course.
In fact, if you hover over this it should
tell you Custom Post Type Description,
describe what your custom
post type is used for.
Okay, so then now you can go to Advanced
Label Options, which we won't be doing.
It's just that if you wanted to have
different and more advanced options for
how you want the label to display, but
Advanced Options is
worth having a look at.
So usually the default options are fine.
In some cases you don't want them,
so say for example,
exclude from search, do you want to
exclude the course features the search?
If you have a search field on your web
site and someone types in something,
do you want that course
feature to be excluded?
And I'm gonna say true,
because it's not worth an entire page
just to see one single course feature.
Its just gonna be a little icon and
a one-liner description,
it's not worth having its own page.
And Has Archive, this is whether
the post type will have a post
type archive page,
we don't need that as well,so False.
And all the rest is fine.
Show in menu, we do want to show
this in our sidebar menu here.
And the menu icon,
we need to put the full URL for
the icon you want to display in the side.
Otherwise it'll just have a generic tool,
a little gear icon here.
So, we do have the icon, and it is located
in your image folder in your
WordPress site, as icon-features.
So we just need to grab the full URL for
that, so if you were to go to Assets,
and then image > icon features,
I'm just gonna copy that path.
And essentially, I'm gonna paste it here
but I'm gonna have to remove a few things.
So we have icon features which is buried
in image, which is buried in assets,
and then buried in your
Bootstrap to WordPress folder.
So basically all we're gonna do
here is themes, WordPress content.
So remove B2W and everything before it,
which would be desktop, volumes,
Macintosh, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
So we want the root to
be WordPress content,
well the root, and
then jump into WordPress content.
Then themes, bootstrap2wordpress, assets,
image, icon features, that'll do it.
Supports, this is what do we want this
custom post type to support in its editing
page, do we want it to have all of these?
And because I'm just gonna
have a title and room for
an image which we're gonna create in
advance custom fields, we only need title.
So uncheck all of these except for title.
Create custom post type, now it'll
display right here in your sidebar.
Course features, there it is, cool.
So now if you click on that, you'll be
taken to the course features section and
you can see all the course features.
For course features right now,
if were to go add course feature,
we just have a title, and
we need to also be able to have a section
to choose which icon we wanna
use out of our CSS Sprite.
So we can do that by
going to Custom Fields,
Advanced Custom Fields, that is, and
we're gonna Add a New Field Group.
And we're gonna call it Course Features,
and
we're just gonna give one field here, and
it's gonna be the course feature icon.
Field type will be a radio button, meaning
you can select one of multiple options.
And the field instructions will be,
choose the icon you'd like to display
with the feature, is this required?
Yes.
Now Choices, this has a certain syntax
that is required and it's very easy.
It says over here you can either just
put the choices like this, one per line.
Or you can have the name or the value
that would be associated on the back end,
and then a colon, and
then the front end what will display.
So if your front end display is
a little different than what
the choices in the background are,
then you would do this.
And that's what we're gonna do,
because our choices,
they're gonna look a little like this.
So, I have ci space ci-computer, colon,
and then the front end displays computer.
And if you remember or recall,
these are the classes we used for
our CSS sprites, let me just show you.
On our index page here, our home page,
you can see course features, so we have
an icon with the class ci ci-computer.
So essentially what
we're trying to do here
is give people options to choose
which icons they want to see.
So, computer, device, user, so on and so
forth, of all the sprites that we
already have in our CSS Sprite image.
And then if they choose a certain
radio button, then that will select or
tell the database to store this text,
which happens to be the classes.
So we can easily,
depending on what they choose,
update the icon to have
the correct Sprite.
So the other options look like so.
So we have CI watch, and then Calendar,
Community, Instructor, and Device.
So go ahead and
write those down in your choices,
feel free to pause if you need to.
And then after that I'm just going
to go ahead and close the field.
Here in our location we want to show this
field group if the post type is equal to
course feature, because now we have a new
custom post type called course feature.
So this will only show
up on course features.
Down here we want the style and
the look to be normal and seamless box.
So we have all this like it is already,
in fact you could probably hide
everything here, cuz the only thing
we actually need is the title.
So hide all that and then publish.
So now go back to your course features,
and add a new course feature, and so
now you'll see the title, and
a course feature icon option.
So basically, lets just add new posts,
new course features, and
on our front end we have
them all right here.
So lets just copy these out and
choose the correct icons.
So lifetime access, that's computer.
Add a course feature,
gonna do another one here.
And that will be watch,
because we're using the watch icon.
Community icon.
That's the instructor icon.
And then one last one,
we have the accessible content on your
mobile devices with the mobile icon.
And if you were to want more icons,
basically you just add
more icons in your sprite.
And then you just add the icons
here in your radio button list,
and then go to town.
So now that we've added all
of our course features,
you can see them here in the list.
They're in their own section.
We need to be able to pull them in
to our code, so let's scroll up and
let's do some more variables.
Now there's one thing
that we still need to do.
We need to add the image and
the description for
the features, the course features section.
So why don't we go ahead and
do that first?
Let's go back to our custom fields, and
we're going to add a new field group,
which is going to be called,
Course Features Section.
Then we're gonna add field labe,l which
will be the features section image.
And then we're gonna choose
the image required no Image object.
Medium preview size in the edit screen.
Good to go.
Let's add another.
This'll be the Features Section title,
lots of typos there,
section title, there we go.
This will be text.
Required, yes.
And no formatting, close that field,
and then we have one more thing,
the features section body.
Here we go.
And this will be a text area.
Acquired yes.
And everything else looks good.
Okay, cool.
And then do we want to hide
anything on this screen?
Let's at least give it the standard
WordPress meta box style.
And we need to make sure that
the page is equal to home.
Go ahead and publish that.
And then your homepage edit screen,
go ahead and refresh.
There we go,
we have our course feature section.
It looks like it's at the very top here,
above the booster income and
who should take this course section.
Now the reason why.
Is because the position of
the meta box has been set for
these two,
when we manually drag them around.
So I'm resetting the position here, so
it's overriding what
the default positioning is.
When we put that in our field
group using the order number.
And so basically now,
you just need to make sure to drag
this into it's respective section.
Again, it doesn't effect how
it appears in the front end.
But for your own sake, your client's sake.
It would probably be a good idea to just
have it be in order in the edit screen.
So essentially all I need to do now,
is to just have the image, the title, and
the body.
Which is very easy.
We have the image, and
we have the title here.
And I also just noticed that there
is no body section for this section.
But we can leave it, because we can
have the option to put that in there.
But we might need to make a few changes,
so let's go back here.
Feature section title.
The image is going to be In our
image assets folder here,
were gonna be taking the icon rocket.
Drag that in there, and
this will be icon, or
rocket icon,
all to be an icon of a rocket.
Select, so that'll be good, intersection
body, let's make it optional, because
I don't actually have any text for it, and
if you wanted to put in snyyhinh, great.
But we're gonna need to make this optional
so for now, because I need to save this,
let's just put something so
we can actually save or update,
and go back to our field group.
And feature section body,
make it not require an update.
And then we go back to your edit
screen for your homepage here.
Now this is not required,
I can delete that, and then update.
So if you have any text you
want to put there, great.
Let's go to our code editor.
And now we're gonna start
hooking all this stuff in.
So we need to have a couple
advanced fields variables.
And we're gonna have
the features_section_image.
That's going to be the same
as this stuff up here.
This will be features section image.
Then below that we're going to
have our features section title.
And then after,
we'll have our feature section body, and
that will be feature section body.
Great, now we can access those
down here in our course features.
So let's go ahead and change
the content here in the section header.
Again, we're just gonna
copy this PHP if statement,
to grab the feature image
that we have uploaded.
If the user uploaded an image, that is.
And this should not be who_feature,
it should be features_section_image.
And then this should be the same
feature section image URL,
feature section image alt.
Great, and
then now the title we're gonna go PHP
echo feature section title.
And now, if you want to add some text,
then basically
let's just see what it looks like,
because we haven't actually tested this.
Paragraph tag here and let's just
put some lorem ipsum, just to test.
Go back in to the front end
version of the site and refresh.
Perfect.
So,
this is what the text will look
like if we want to add it, in fact,
maybe we'll make it a leading text,
so it matches the rest.
So go back,
give this the class of lead, and
now, because it's optional,
we need to be able to account for that.
So, let's first hook it in.
And say echo feature section body,
but only if the user added body text.
But now we need to add a PHP if statement,
I'm just gonna copy this one and
modify it a little bit.
It's gonna be PHP if not empty
Features_section_body and
then we're gonna close that php
if statement down here, end if.
Great so if the user added body text so
meaning if it's not
empty then there you go.
Otherwise, don't have
anything there at all.
Great!
Save that, and
let's see if it shows up on the front end.
Now it shouldn't, because we haven't
saved anything in the back end.
Perfect.
Now let's add these icons here.
So it's actually quite easy but it's a
little bit different than what we gonna do
in here using the functions
we've been using.
We're gonna be going a little bit more
hardcore but no sweat it'll be all good.
Inside row we just need
to create a new loop and
access through WordPress
query the custom post type.
The course feature custom post type.
So the way that we do that.
As we need to store a variable,
content in a variable, called loop.
Loop equals, and
now hang in there and follow along,
new WordPress so
WP capital letters query like so.
And in here, we need to say an array,
because we're accessing an array.
Post type, that's the key.
The value is course feature.
Now you see what we're accessing.
Comma.
We want to order by post_id so
we want to order them by post_id and
we want the order to be ascending.
Now we gotta put that semicolon.
Okay so
we have this variable called loop, so
we're gonna access that now,
down here in a php while loop.
Php while( $loop ) we're
gonna grab some info out of there.
Have_posts we're gonna check
to see if the loop has posts.
This is how you write that out.
While that loop has posts, remove
that semicolon, that was an accident.
We're gonna have a :$loop the_post.
This is just how you do this in WordPress.
This is how you access
the info in a WordPress query
to get your custom post types.
It's the same way of doing it for
any other custom post types,
So I know it looks a little bit advanced,
and it is.
But once you know it once, you basically
can just use it over and over and
over again, for
different custom post types.
So this is how you do that.
And now, that while loop is open,
meaning we need to close it.
So let's close that while loop.
And then we need to put
something in between it.
So endwhile.
There we go.
In there I'm just gonna grab one of
the cuz they're going to be a template.
Then I'm gonna paste and
it's gonna use the same structure.
But the class, we'll need to grab,
remember how the radio button,
they gave us the class when they chose
the radio button, so php in there.
To access that you just say the_field and
then we're grabbing
the course_feature_icon.
Great.
That should be good.
And now we just need to grab the title and
this is actually a very fun one.
It's nice and easy.
A built in WordPress
function called the_title.
So because we are in posts in a while
loop to grab the info
from the course features.
We just need to grab the title because
the title is the main title in that new
course feature post, and that is all.
So let's get rid of all the rest
of these here, we don't need them
because it's gonna loop through them
all now, no matter how many we have.
Whether we have 1 or
1,000 it will loop through them.
Real quick here before we move on,
you might be curious why I used the field.
I am accessing the custom fields
using advance custom fields for
the course feature.
Remember when we created
the course_feature, custom post type,
and we gave it some
advanced custom fields,
where you could choose the course
feature icon in the radio buttons?
Well this is how you access it, and we're
using the_field, rather than get_fields,
and the reason why, here in
the Advanced Custom Fields documentation.
The_field displays the value
of the specified field.
It's the same as going echo get_field
rather than using get_field alone,
whereas get_field returns the value
of the specified field, so
get_field is a little bit
more versatile function.
So if we were to use get_field here,
it would be returning an array
of the course_feature_icons and
it wouldn't actually display.
And we'd need to add more information,
and more parameters and
arguments within the function.
But the_field echoes that specific icon.
Which is why we're using the_field.
Save that, and
let's just double check it worked.
Go to your frontend and refresh,
and there it is, dynamic.
We have the icon and we have the text and
the title of the feature.
Perfect, and that's all.
That's how you do that.
In the next lecture we're
going to move on to the final
project features where we can just add
some info for the project features.
So, see you there.
[MUSIC]