Welcome back, friends, let's take care of this mobile menu navigation thing up here.
All right back in the code editor, we're going to continue here.
And let's start out by styling out the mobile menu.
That's mobile dash menu class.
Let's just make sure that's the case over here in our markup in the index card.
Hey, HTML.
Don't know.
I just did that.
Where are we?
Menu item is our mobile menu.
There we are.
Class mobile menu service style.
This baboy parade here could change.
All right.
So mobile menu is the class and we're going to style that up.
We're going to start by doing position fixed and it's going to be right zero top zero.
The width is going to be 300 pixels.
We're going to do padding right of 30 pixels and max width of 100 percent.
That's for when we view it.
In mobile view, we want the max width to be 100 percent and padding right 30 pixels.
Want that height to be 100 percent opacity.
To be zero visibility hidden because we don't want to see it right now.
And Z index to some really high number like nine nine nine nine nine nine nine nine.
That many nights and then we're going to do is we're going to say more menu visible.
So this is a class that gets added.
That's going to be overflow hidden.
OK.
Mobile dash menu visible.
So this is when it's added.
And then the mobile menu, we're going to say opacity one and visibility visible.
Target the mobile menu and menu backdrops.
That's the backdrop that we want to appear.
That's going to be positioned fixed, right?
Zero top zero.
The width and height are both going to be 100 percent.
We want that z index to be one.
And then we want the background itself to be R.G. be a so that's the RG B and then a four alpha channel,
zero zero zero and then point nine in the alpha channel.
And then we're going to do a little transform here.
So we want Transform Translate X one hundred and one percent and then have the back back ups their web
kit, transform an MMS transform.
And then we want transition to be all 0.4 seconds ese.
And as I recall, we had a variable for that transition dur.
So let's take care of that.
And instead of point four, we're going to use our VAR Dash Dash transition dash dur.
You.
He's there.
We go back the backups, though the fallback s'mores webcams and oh for transitions and those four seconds
replace those with transition dir.
The way I'll do that is just point four seconds.
Change replace all done.
OK, now we want to keep going with this menu backdrop, so probably won't see anything now perfect.
But we want to now target the mobile menu visible.
So that's one that causes added mobile menu.
Menu backdrop Inside those styles, we want opacity to be one invisibility to be visible.
And we want some transitions, so transition all 0.7 seconds.
So just a little bit longer, maybe we'll check that out after see if it really matters.
Maybe we'll go back to our Our Transition dir, but we'll we'll we'll stick with this for now and then
back fallbacks.
And then we want the transition itself, all we got, the transition, we want the transform.
To be translate x zero.
So this is where it ends up.
Here we go.
And the fallbacks always good to have that.
OK, now we're going to do the mobile menu.
Menu box.
So what is that?
Check it out.
Mobile menu.
Menu box.
I don't know if we see that yet.
Probably because we don't have any.
Anything in here yet?
Well, what will get there?
This is a style that won't do anything for now, but I presume we're going to be adding that afterwards
with maybe Jake weary.
All right, so for the mobile menu menu box, we've got position absolute left, zero top zero width
and height or both 100 percent max height, 100 percent overflow.
Why is going to be is 100 percent.
Sorry, I'm an auto.
The background is going to be white.
Or f f f.
Padding is going to be zero Z Index five.
Opacity.
Let's make that zero visibility hidden.
Border radius.
Zero.
And then transform Translate X one hundred and one percent and then Web kit transform it kind of back
fallbacks.
There you go.
Now, before we go any further because we're going to be doing a lot of styling where you're not going
to see anything and that's not really that fun.
Basically, what's going to happen here is in our navigation and here right now, there's nothing there.
There's no elements, there's no navigation whatsoever in our markup, as you can see here in our mobile
menu.
We literally have just a shell markup shell and there's nothing there.
There's no navigation.
Well, and that's because we don't want to create two separate navigation where there's one code it
up in mobile and one code it up and up.
Here in the in the desktop version, we want to use the same one.
And that's what's going to ultimately happen in our in our WordPress site.
So we're going to use a little jQuery to take what's in this menu to add it into this menu kind of add
into this shell.
So this is the reason why right now you can't see anything.
But in our final markup version, you can see here when we go smaller, our hamburger icon appears and
then we've got the same navigation.
In our mobile menu that is in our desktop menu, so the desktop menu content simply disappears and finds
its way in here, which is what we're doing.
So why don't we maybe play around with a little bit of jQuery and add this in our little mobile menu
so that we maybe have some content to work with?
Let's try that.
So in your.
Assets, we have jobs open up, main script, so main script is where we're going to write our jQuery.
And because we have jQuery added into our index and our head, actually no in the foot, in the bottom.
Before the closing body tag, we have j query right here.
That means we can use jQuery.
We're going to start it by opening up with function in the parentheses.
Put a dollar sign after that.
Make sure this is where you want to make sure you get this code right kind of right out the gate.
Otherwise, you're gonna have some issues.
So this is kind of how you fire up jQuery.
One of many ways there's a few ways of doing it, actually.
This is this way we'll work out here.
So in parentheses, you are opening parentheses here, function and then another opening parentheses.
Dollar sign closing parentheses and then curly quote our curly bracket.
Give it a little space.
Closing curly bracket.
Close parentheses.
Open parentheses.
jQuery close parentheses.
Semicolon.
That's how you kind of fire this up.
We're going to tell it to use strict.
And then this is where we are going to get started.
This we're going to start writing our jQuery ad. The content of the navigation into the mobile nav,
so let's say.
Mobile nav just.
Go from here, and we'll say, if so, make sure you get this code right.
It will be in the final resources if you want to download it and install it and in parentheses here
and then in single quotes or double quotes cost mobile dash menu.
Then what we want to do is outside of this, select its length.
And then inside of here.
We're going to write some stuff, so we're going to establish a variable VAR, call it mobile menu content
like Cell Equals and then we're going to select.
The.
I'd have top dash navigation.
And then the class of navigation, and I'm going to grab its HTML.
All right, so that variable is going to be there with the HTML of this selector, of that element.
Then we want to select.
Mobile menu navigation.
And then we're going to append.
The variable mobile menu content.
Make sure that code is right.
After that, we want to.
Select sticky header navigation.
And we want to append.
Mobile menu content.
Another line we want to select mobile dash menu, a close button, close dash between.
And we want to kind of bind an on function here on Click.
So this means on clicking the closed button, we're going to open up the function here.
Whoa.
That's not how I use my function function.
OK.
And the function is going to be.
Selecting the body tag, remove the class.
Mobile dash menu Dash visible.
OK.
And then make sure you have that closing semicolon, so be very mindful to make sure that each character
is is written properly here because in jQuery and JavaScript, in lots of different programming languages
outside of this, if you simply miss closing semicolon or or closing curly bracket like things will
break and not work for you and will be very frustrating.
So the good code editor will let you know if there's like an error.
If you have might have to turn on validation in your code editor, but that is important.
OK, so this is the mobile nav hide show.
And adds the content as well, so maybe we'll see if something happens.
And we don't have anything in there right now, because I think we need to add our yeah, we need to
add.
Maybe we'll check to see if it's even in our mobile now.
Mobile menu.
We have our content here, as you can see.
So, yeah, our content is there, so maybe we'll go to our styles.
And let's end the.
Styles where we hide.
Visibility.
Let's make it appear just so we can see, so we're going to do is save.
And a high this opacity and visibility, you're going to comment that out and then also menu backdrop,
no menu backdrop right here that's visible, OK?
Menu box.
Opacity and visibility are going to comment that out safe, see if we can see anything.
Yes, so we can.
So now we can start styling this to to look better.
So at least we can see it while we're styling, and then we'll go back and hide those so that we can
toggle it on and off based on the viewport size, viewport size.
All right.
Let's keep going with our styles, and we'll come back to jQuery when we need to.
All right, after the menu box, we're going to say mobile menu visible.
Mobile menu and menu box, so in there are capacity is going to be one.
Visibility is visible.
OK.
And then we're going to do some transitions.
It's going to be transition all 0.7 seconds is ad your usual fallbacks and then we want the Transformers
to be there as well.
So web kit transformers and then the Transform Translate X zero percent.
So now what we'll do is we'll style the close button that little X, so that's a mobile menu, close
button.
Those are both classes.
We want the position to be absolute top and write 15 pixels.
Line height.
30 pixels and the width, 30 pixels.
Text align center.
We want the font size to be 26 pixels.
Color is going to be like a dark.
So let's find a variable.
I think we have color dark.
Yes.
We're going to say the color is vare colored dark.
Well, the cursor to be a pointer, does that an X to be 10, and it would make sure all your transitions
and transforms are in place.
So we're going to say Typekit transition all point five seconds.
Let's use our VAR.
Transition Dash, do you are?
And then our transforms are going to go Web could transform me, transform and then the standard transform
translate, why minus 50 pixels?
OK.
Let's check it out, see if something's happening.
All right, so we made it disappear.
Is do mobile menu mode menu.
Sorry, mobile menu, visible mobile menu and the close button.
Just for when it's visible.
We want the transforms.
Translate why zero pixels, so we want it to go to zero, so that's going to make it rotate?
I believe.
Then we want our mobile menu close button on hover opacity to be point five.
Now let's start styling that navigation to make it look better.
Right now, it looks pretty messy.
Mobile menu navigation that's going to have position relative padding top 50 pixels display block.
And border top one pixel solid GBA is going to be all zeros and the alpha channel zero point one came.
Then we want our mobile menu navigation ally to be positioned relative display block and the same thing
instead of border bottom or instead of border top, it's going to be border bottom.
One Pixel solid TBA Black.
Zero zero zero zero point one.
OK, let's check that out.
We're getting there.
But now, as you can see, there's kind of a bit of a mess here of of borders in this sub menu and the
sub submenu.
We're going to clean that up.
What we're going to do is we're going to select the mobile menu navigation l i child, you l child,
ally, last child.
And that's just simply going to be border bottom.
None.
And then.
Mobile menu, navigation, ally, child, ul child, like first child, and that's going to be border
top one pixel solid.
Zero zero zero zero point one in the RGA, check it out.
There we go.
Now, the reason why we do this, let me just show you, is it's really quite hard to see.
Let's add it back and see if we can see it.
It adds it right here at the top of where it's a single post.
So that's just because we have no and this is the last tiled.
And so we got rid of the border bottom.
So we're just going to say first child on the submenu and add a border on the top.
So that's what we did there.
Team beauty.
All right, moving on.
We're going to like mobile menu navigation ally child selector A, so the tags that are a direct child
of the fly.
And we're going to take that position relative to display block line height 24 pixels and padding 10
pixels on the top bottom 20 pixels left right font size is 15 pixels.
Let's make the color VAR color dark.
Techs, Transformers going to be capitalized and then we want to do our transition to be.
All 0.5 seconds is or if you fancy, make that a variable just for fun transition der ease.
And then make sure you have fallbacks, so that'll be webcast miles, so on and so forth.
There we go.
Now we're going to do is we're going to select the the current the mobile menu navigation ally, the
class of current and then child, select the A and then a comma to combine another selector.
And that's going to be a mobile menu navigation L.I child selector, a hover.
So when we hover over an ailment, we want the color to be.
E f one, f two, two.
Let's see what that looks like.
That's kind of like that pink red.
Color, let's capture that color in a variable.
We're going to say Dash, Dash, color red.
There we go.
And now all we can do is just capture that in a variable and any time we want to change that, we can
do so easily.
Thus far, Dash Dash, Color, Dash Red Save works brilliantly.
Perfect.
Carrying on, we're going to do mobile menu navigation alive with the class menu item has children and
then the drop down button position.
Absolute.
Right, zero top zero width is 44 pixels, height is 44 pixels.
Text align center font size 16 pixels line height 434 pixels color.
You could put a dark gray.
I'm just going to use our variable is going to be VAR Dash, Dash, Color Dash Dark.
Save the cursor pointer just for a user experience z index.
Five.
Save that.
Keep going.
Mobile menu navigation ally with the class menu item has children.
Class drop down button and then the after pseudo element content is going to be just a empty string.
That's what we do, and we want to make the pseudo element appear on the screen and appear like it's
a real element.
Position absolute left is going to be zero.
Top is 10 pixels.
Width is going to be one.
Pixel height is 24 pixels.
Border left?
We're making that one pixel solid our GBA zero zero zero zero point one.
Then, when we want to select the mobile menu navigation i child selector u l comma mobile menu navigation
child u l child l i child ul display none.
OK, that hides that submenu there.
It hides all the sub menus rather.
Now there are a couple of styles that we didn't add and that was nav bar open.
We want that to be position relative display none.
Background color unset padding zero border.
None.
Position absolute right, thirty two pixels, top zero pixels and then nav bar open flat icon colour
white display block font size 30 line height 40 knots pixels cursor pointer padding 18 pixels top bottom,
zero, left and right.
And I'm going to move those actually before all these mobile menu styles.
There we go and say that we were going to need to go back to our JavaScript.
And we've got to add some some dropdown button toggling kind of functionality in here.
So inside of our if statement.
Right here, we are going to keep going after this last bit of code here, and we're going to add,
let's say, drop down button functionality here, and that's going to look like this.
Mobile menu, ally with the class of menu item has children drop down dash button.
And then we went on.
Click.
And then function.
And we're going to select this, which is the very element we are clicking on, engaging with previous
you allies or selecting the previous you you'll slide toggle at five hundred, which means milliseconds,
OK?
After that, we're going to do the menu toggle button.
And we're going to select mobile nav toddler.
On Click Function.
We're selecting the body.
We're going to add the class.
Mobile menu visible, you remember we styled some styles with this class, well, this is where the
class gets added, so now the styles can actually start doing something once that is added.
And then we're going to do the menu toggle button here again.
And we're going to say mobile dash menu.
Menu dash backdrop.
Coma Mobile Dash menu closed Dash BTN.
On, you guessed it, click function.
Inside the function.
We're going to select body.
Remove class mobile menu visible so that we want to remove that class when we click on the close button
so that those styles can then disappear, so we can't really see much because we still need to add some
more styles like media queries to make things display.
And we're making this thing just display right now, but we actually need to hide it for now and then
we can make it appear again properly.
So those commented out styles that we added, Let's find them.
Right here, opacity and visibility hidden under the mobile menu menu box.
We're going to uncomment that and there was another one.
Under mobile menu itself, opacity, visibility, hidden uncomment does so now should disappear.
And now what we need to do is we need to make the that kind of option the hamburger icon up here so
that we can start engaging with this JavaScript that we're writing or jQuery that we're writing.
So in our success before the navar open style here.
We're going to select the main menu child selector you'll ally with the class menu item, has children
dropdown button and their position absolute.
Right, 10 pixels, top six pixels, width and height are both going to be 30 pixels and then text align
center color, white line height 28 pixels border solid one pixel triple f background size is 20 pixels.
Pointer for the cursor.
Z Index five display, none.
We don't want that to appear just yet.
And then big Selectric coming up here.
Main menu class child selector you'll ally with the class menu item has children dropdown button i with
the class flight icon Arrow Down Sign to navigate and then the before pseudo element.
We're going to say font size one hundred pixels.
OK, so now we need to add some.
Media queries now.
You can add them at the very bottom of your styles, but a convention that I learned a little while
back was to just keep your media queries where you have the styles so that you don't have them separate.
It just makes a little bit more sense to me.
You can do whatever way you want.
That's the way I like doing it.
So we're going to do media.
So at media only screen and max with 768 pixels pixels, that's kind of like landscape phones or, you
know.
Tiny tablets or something like that.
Basis, just like a medium sized, small ish screen.
All right, we're going to select Top Dash Navigation I.D. and then top menu class in the same select
of their display, none.
We're going to override or override any other styles that might keep it visible.
So this is going to force the property to override any other declaration.
That's what the important is for visibility hidden just to make sure it's not displaying anywhere.
Then we want to say NAV Bar, Dash Open.
We want the opacity to be one, visibility to be visible and then display inline block.
All right, save that.
Let's check it out.
See if that does anything around here.
Perfect.
See what happens is the nav.
And shows the hamburger icon.
Let's see what happens if you click it.
So nothing is happening on the screen.
But check the code out down here when I click it, see what's happening?
Blog mobile, my invisible blog.
Blogging and many visible blogs.
So it's toggling.
So our classes are working in our jQuery.
So in the final version, if I click this slides out, looks good, but in our version, something's
going on here.
It's toggling the class, but it's not toggling the styles.
All right.
What I just found here is critical issue.
So in our mobile menu.
I noticed that we styled quite a bit this menu box.
But it wasn't quite working.
I thought it was because the have been something I thought, we're going to add the subject, but when
I investigated my email, I realized that our nav element was supposed to have the class of menu dash
box.
That's why our styling wasn't working, so let's just see if something happens when we go back.
Refresh.
Close this.
All right, so we're still not seeing something so.
We're getting there, so I made a mistake in that I didn't add the cost menu box.
So now I just need to do a little digging to find why isn't that appearing three hours later?
OK, so upon investigating spending considerable amount of time debugging my CSC code and referencing
it with the final version, you may have already caught this a long time ago, but I found the issue
was a simple typo.
Right here, mobile menu visible, which obviously is not a class visible.
Now, when I save our menu works splendid, Lee, splendidly.
Look at this, it's incredible.
And if I go back to full size screen, here we are with our nice kind of drop down animations, mobile
menu animation.
It is brilliant.
OK, now that we got that sorted out to back to our script drop down toggle, we're going to say if
and then we're going to go with the pound sign, another opening and closing parentheses.
We're going to select class main dash menu.
Ally with the class of menu item, Dash has Dash children.
You will length went the length of that open curly bracket, close curly bracket inside of that if statement,
we're selecting main dash menu along with a class of menu dash item.
Dash has Dash children and we want to append this HTML so div with the class of and then because we're
using single quotations to open up this section.
Inside of that, we need to use a double quotation.
You always have to toggle between the two.
So if I were using double quotations here, oh my goodness, right here and I added the div with the
class, I need to use single quotations on the inside.
Just a little tip.
You probably already know that, though dropdown dash button.
Or BTN, OK, and inside that div, we have an I with a class of flat icon and flat icon Dash Arrow
Dash down Dash signed Dash to Dash Navigate.
OK, close that I tag and close that div tag.
There we go after that, make sure you have your your parentheses or your semicolon rather.
And then now we want to add the drop down button.
That's going to be selecting the main course of main menu.
Ally menu item has children and dropdown dash button on click function.
This.
Preve private for previous the previous u well, we want to slide toggle at 500 milliseconds and then
we want to disable the dropdown parent link so it stops working when it's in this view.
We're going to select main dash menu navigation ally menu item has children, child selector, a comma
class of hidden dash bar.
Class of side dash menu.
Ally menu item has children.
Todd's lecture a on click function.
Open that up properly.
And then we want to go E for the event.
And then prevent default, so that just prevents the default functionality, which is a click to navigate
the link, but this will prevent that cliff from working.
Save it.
Let's see what happens.
And here is our little down navigation, click it, nice, click it.
Nice.
Now, I believe.
That is working the same, and it's looking the same.
Beautiful.
All right, so we did our header, the nav with our nice animations in the submenu sub submenu and then
when we.
Are in a mobile view.
We have our.
Dropdown navigation.
Brilliant.
That looks so good.
And that is all of our styles for the navigation menu, dropdown submenus and the mobile menu, that
was gigantic lesson.
Let's move on.
We're going to get going into the rest of the content here.