Hey everyone.
Brad here.
Welcome back to Boost your
income Bootstrap to WordPress.
This lecture is called Add the Project
Features Using Custom Post Types and
Advanced Custom Fields.
That's so many words.
[MUSIC]
All right, so here we are in
the Final Project Features section.
And what we're gonna do is basically
just add a title, description.
And we're gonna make custom post types for
Final Project Features.
So we can add these three custom post
types rather than just building them
directly into the Final Project Features
edit section.
If that makes any sense.
All right.
Head back to the dashboard.
We are going to go back to Custom Fields
here and we're going to add a new field
group and that's going to be
the Project Features Section.
I'm going to add a field and that's
going to be the Project Feature Title.
And that's gonna be Text,
yes it is required, and
we're gonna have no formatting,
close that up.
Then we're gonna have
the Project Feature Body,
and that's gonna be Text Area.
Close that field, we're all good.
And that should be good for
that section because now we're
gonna add a new custom post type.
So show this field group if
the page is equal to home.
You got it.
And
this is gonna be standard
WordPress meta box.
And leave the rest as is, publish that up.
Good to go.
Go to your custom post types.
We're gonna create a new,
add a new custom post type.
That's gonna be project_feature.
So project underscore feature.
The label will be Project Features.
The singular label will
be Project Feature.
And we'll say these are the features
of the final project.
Advanced Options.
We don't want this to be in the search.
So exclude from search, True.
And the menu icon.
We want this to be WordPress content.
Let's use the same icon because it's
basically going to be same sort of deal,
a feature.
We got the title.
We don't need the rest of the stuff.
Let's close it all up and
leave the title alone.
Good to go, create custom post type.
Now let's see,
we've got our project features.
Great.
Now why don't we go ahead and
add some project features.
We can actually use the native
built in WordPress stuff.
We don't have to create
custom post types at all.
Because what we'll do here
is use the feature image.
And we'll use the title, and
we'll use just the content editor.
So why don't we just do that.
What we do need to do is in the custom
post types, we need to manage
the project features, so edit
the project features custom post type.
The advanced options,
all the way at the bottom.
Turn on the editor and
turn on the feature image.
We need access to those now.
Save that.
Now if you go to Project Features and
add a new project feature,
we have the title, the description or
the content editor and we do not
have feature image for some reason.
Now, I believe the reason is,
in our functions of php,
we need to enable support for
post thumbnails on posts and pages.
So right here on line 41,
it's commented out so we need to add
theme support for post thumbnails.
Save that and if we go back and
refresh our Project Feature New Posts,
we should have access to our
feature image, which we do.
Excellent, so take note of that.
By default, the support for
post thumbnails is not active, so
you need to turn that on
by uncommenting that line.
Let's add a new project feature, shall we?
So here on the front end, we're just
gonna copy some of this stuff here.
Sexy and modern design, and
then we have our body text.
I'm gonna paste that in here.
The only downside about this is that we
have a full WYZIWYG editor that can edit
this text and, you know, it might not be
a good idea if you want this to be simple.
And the other thing, too, is because
we didn't create any custom fields for
this project feature, we weren't able
to hide the slug, which is useless to
us because this technically is just going
to pull up a really ugly archive page.
With some basic information
that we submit here.
So usually we'd be able to hide
this if you use a custom feed.
Now right now we're using the default
title, body, and feature image, and so
unfortunately we can't
actually hide the permalink.
So if you were to do it a different way
then you can actually hide the slug from
the editor screen, but I'm just showing
you the different options here.
So just ignore this permalink.
Okay, now the feature image.
We want to be able to grab the Design
feature image from your Images folder.
I already pulled that in here.
And I gave it the title Design Icon and
an icon with transparent layers.
Okay.
Publish that.
And we're gonna go ahead and
add another project feature.
And that's gonna be quality HTML5 and
CSS3.
And then the body text will be so on and
so forth, and then the feature
image is going to be the icon code.
And this is gonna say.
Web design icon.
And say an icon with a browser.
Okay, and then I'm gonna publish that, and
then I'm gonna add one
more project feature.
And now it'll be easy-to-use CMS.
Use that text here, and
then the feature image,
we're gonna pull that from our icon CMS.
There we go.
This is gonna be gear icon.
With a gear.
There we go.
And I'm gonna publish that.
So now I'm gonna go to my home page.
Editor.
And the Project Features section should
be right here, again it's at the top.
I'm gonna drag it down below
the Course Features Section.
Project Features,
title will simply be Project.
Final Project Features.
And the Project Feature body will be this.
And I'm going to go ahead and update that.
So now in our code editor, we just need
to be able to pull in the info from
the editor, and
from our custom post-types.
So let's go ahead and do that.
The very top we need to add
a couple of variables first.
Right under here, let's say
project_features_title = get_field.
And that will be
the project_features_title.
I believe that's what we called it.
Project feature title
is what we called it.
So let's say project_feature_title,
and let's update this.
And one more here.
Project_feature_body, is
what we had that be called.
I meant to write body.
Okay.
Now save that.
Scroll down.
We can start editing
the Project Features Section right here.
Final Project Features.
That's actually going to be,
using php echo
project_feature_tile, and
then in here we're going to use
php echo project_feature_body.
And then down here,
we're gonna do like we did right here.
So just copy this whole loop right
here from the previous section,
the Course Features.
Copy that,
we're just gonna change a few things.
Paste that whole section in there.
And we're just gonna change a few things.
So instead of course_feature,
we're grabbing project_feature.
And then the rest of it, right here,
in between the loop,
we need to add one of these columns.
So replace that, and
remove the rest after the loop there.
And let's just work with this.
So we're going to grab the feature image.
And the way that we grab
the feature image is like so.
So within php, we're going to check
to see if there is a post thumbnail.
Which is the feature image, and if so,
the_post_thumbnail, and then that's it.
So, there would be your feature image.
And if you didn't upload one,
then nothing would happen.
So, if you don't want that,
then you could go, else, and then in here,
you can just echo an image,
a static image.
Otherwise, You could leave it empty and
then for
the level three heading we're gonna go
php and this is gonna be the_title.
And we're just using
the native WordPress stuff.
We're not using advanced
custom fields at all here.
And this is php the_content.
And that is the content
in the content editor.
Save that and let's see if it worked.
And there it is.
So we have our Final Project Features,
the text and
each of the custom post types.
Awesome, great job.
You did it.
The next lecture we're actually
going to skip this section.
We're going to leave it static,
just because,
well it would be redundant to do the same
thing over and over and over again.
We're basically doing the same thing now.
I'm just kind of hammering
in how this all works.
We're going to do this again for
the instructor section because
there are a few more details.
A little bit different than
the past few sections.
Like the numbers, the social icons and
things like that.
Where as this,
we just have a title and a video.
If you want, and I totally recommend
you do this, is you try yourself,
that's my challenge to you,
is, create, before you start
the next lecture,
create a custom section on the home page.
Using advanced custom
fields to add a video.
To embed a YouTube video.
That's my challenge to you.
If you can do it,
if you think you can, give it a try.
And if you want to skip that
altogether then that's fine,
just head to the next lecture
which will be the instructor.
And, doing that sort of stuff so
I'll see you there.
[MUSIC]