Welcome back everyone to Boost Your
Income With Bootstrap to Wordpress.
This lecture is called Convert Your
Static Footer to a Dynamic Footer.
[MUSIC]
Open up your footer.php file in your
Bootstrap to WordPress theme file.
So, in the theme directory,
open up footer.php.
Basically, we're gonna simplify this a bit
and make sure that our jQuery, Bootstrap,
and all of our styles, sorry,
all of our scripts are hooked in.
Cool, so get rid of everything here.
So from page, the div of the idea of page,
remove it all the way up here to content.
Wipe that out, we don't want that.
And after WordPress footer,
we want to put the footer info
that we had in our static website.
So go to your index file and at the bottom
and you'll see the section that says,
Bootstrap Core Javascript and all this
stuff, type Git fonts and everything.
Grab this, copy it, go back to your footer
and paste it right under WordPress footer.
I'm just gonna line this up here.
Looking good.
So we've got our Bootstrap
core JavaScript,
jQuery is pulling from Google API.com.
Okay.
Now we have assets, jQuery,
we need to fix that
using our PHP blog info
function built into WordPress, okay.
And then,
you can, basically, what I am about to do
it does the same as style sheet directory.
You know how we use to do what we've done,
stylesheet_directory.
Well you can do template_directory,
and really there isn't a difference,
unless you modify it somewhere.
But the default functionality
is the template directory
is the template right here.
This is the template directory.
Bootstrap to WordPress.
And the style sheet directory,
well, it's the same.
So unless you change it somewhere,
they are the same.
There's really just kind of for
semantic purposes, I suppose.
So you're referencing scripts.
You don't want to say template style sheet
directory just in case you change that
style sheet directory in the future.
Again, like I said, you probably won't.
But template directory makes more sense in
this case rather than stylesheet director.
So, like I said,
this is the same spot by default.
So go ahead and put template directory.
And we're gonna wanna copy that
because we're gonna paste it here for
our Bootstrap main js.
And for our main js,
I'm gonna put these closer together just
because they don't need to be spaced so
far apart.
Type kit, looks good.
Save that and
there really isn't much change.
Now, we just have JavaScript and
we have access to what Bootstrap offers.
Okay.
Great, simple lecture.
I thought I'd keep it simple for that one.
That would be the end of this section.
And in the next section, basically, we're
gonna start jumping in and we're gonna
actually turn our home page into this,
this beautiful beast right here.
That's what we're going to start
doing in our next section.
So, I'll see you there.
Get yourself something to eat, something
to drink, and I'll see you there.
[MUSIC]