Hey everyone.
Welcome back to Boost Your Income
with Bootstrap to WordPress.
In this lecture we're gonna be coding
the testimonial section with custom post
types UI.
[MUSIC]
Hey guys,
I've got an easy one for you now.
We're gonna do the testimonial
section here on the homepage and
basically that is it for the homepage.
So what we're gonna do is just do what
we've been doing the past few lectures.
We're gonna do some custom post types.
It's gonna be really easy and
this one should be quite simple.
Head back to your dashboard and
just prior to recording this lecture,
I updated my WordPress version
to version three, sorry, 4.1.
Previously it was 4.01, I believe.
And at this point you're
probably already updated to 4.1
because by the time I've
launched this course,
I'll make sure that everything is
up to date to the latest version.
So you might even be on a later version.
So I just wanted to let you
know there were no problems.
No functions were deprecated.
Everything's all good.
Usually, when you wanna update
your WordPress version,
you wanna make sure that it's
not gonna break anything.
Have a back up,
just in case you need to revert back
to that while you make some changes.
Massage out the bugs and the kinks.
And that's basically it.
So everything's good.
4.1 works perfect for me,
should be working perfect for you.
Go ahead and add a new custom post type,
custom post type name will be Testimonial,
the label will be Testimonials,
the singular label will be Testimonial.
The description you don't have to put one,
but
if you want to you could just describe
what this post type is all about.
Advanced options, go ahead and
exclude this from search.
Meaning exclude from search, true.
You don't have to, I just thought
it's probably not a valuable search,
when you are searching for something
on the site, if I have a search bar.
I don't really want
the testimonials to come up.
It's maybe not a valuable search result.
Okay down at the bottom
we need our menu icon.
Luckily we already have one in
our assets/images folder and
that will be WordPress content themes
Bootstraps WordPress assets images
icon testimonials.png Looks like that.
The supports feature, we only wanna
support title editor and feature image.
So go ahead and disable everything
else other than those three.
Tittle editor, feature image, keep those.
Go ahead and create that custom post type.
All right.
And when you're done you
should see the testimonials
tab right here with the icon and
all of that good stuff.
Go ahead and hit add testimonial.
And what we're gonna do now,
is use the title field for
this part right here, so the person's
name and their, who they here.
In this case graduate
of all Brad's courses.
Could be so and so client or
CEO of such and such a company.
Use that as the title,
use this as the body, and
the image is available
in the assets/images
folder in your website,
both the static and the WordPress version.
So what I'm gonna do now is just
show you how this person looks, and
then I'm gonna fast forward because you
can do this, you don't have to follow me,
kinda time waster.
I like getting to the good stuff.
Copy this, paste that into the title,
copy the body,
just the body, and paste that in the body,
section here in set feature image
go ahead and upload a file.
Select files and
it should be in your asset/images folder.
You can choose, in this case Brennan,
set that featured image,
and there is Brennan if I hit publish
that will show up on the front page.
Basically what I wanna do now
is publish that and go ahead and
add a new testimonial and
do that for every single one.
And then when you're done we'll be good to
go start adding this to our template, so
go ahead and do that, pause the video.
I'm gonna fast forward now and
just do this.
All right, I've went and added all of my
testimonials, we got Ernest, AJ, Ben, and
Brennan, but
these won't show up on the front end
until we make our template, do so.
So head back to your your page-home.PHP.
Head down to testimonials and right under
your H2 we want to put that loop variable
with the WordPress query function and then
start the WordPress loop, the while loop.
So all you gotta do is just
scroll up a little bit.
We already used this a couple times.
Right here, so
in our project features we have the loop.
So grab the function and
the while loop and
we're gonna have to remember to close
that while loop so don't forget.
Right here, paste that.
And all you gotta do now is first of all
don't forget to close the while loop,
that'll cause some major
issues if you don't.
So, there we go.
Great.
But now we need to change the post type.
The value.
So we got the key and the value pair here.
We need to change this from project
feature to testimonial, because we're
grabbing the custom post type and
we gave that field name testimonial.
So that's how we're gonna grab that.
We're going to keep the order by and
the same.
You can change it if you want,
play around.
Go to the WordPress codex and
search WordPress query function.
You can see all the options
that you play around with.
With all the functions that we're gonna
be using throughout the whole site
forever and ever amen.
So here we go.
In the wile loop just grab one
of your testimonials here and
paste it in there and
let's just make it dynamic.
Super easy.
So the first thing we wanna
do is grab the feature image.
And the way that you can do that is
by starting up a PHP script here,
and then we just want to say if
statement has_post_thumbnail.
Great.
Because that's in the loop it's
checking the ID for this post so
we don't need to add any extra
arguments in this function.
Great.
If has_post_thumbnail so
if there is a post thumbnail,
so check for feature image.
Then the_post_thumbnail, simple.
There we go.
And what you can do in here,
what if the user uploads an image that's
like 1,000 by 1,000 pixels or
2,000 by 1,048 pixels.
Then you're gonna have
a massive image on your site.
You're gonna break something,
it's gonna look bad, and
you're gonna make your users download
massive images unnecessarily.
So luckily in the post thumbnail,
there are a couple of arguments
you can put in this function.
One of which allows you to crop the image,
itself.
And, that would be like so.
Using array( 200, 200 ).
And the syntax for that is height and
width or width and height, I believe.
But anyway, if you go to the WordPress
codecs, the post thumbnail,
it will tell you literally everything
you can do within this function.
It's amazing.
Always use the WordPress codecs.
I always use it.
I have it always open when I'm
working on WordPress sites.
So go ahead and do that.
And then right here we've
got the block quote.
This is gonna be straight up.
It's gonna be php the_content because
we put the text in the content box.
So it's super easy to grab, no extra work.
And then the site tag,
we're gonna leave the em dash and
then we're gonna just grab the title.
So php the_title because
we put the title of who is
giving the testimonial
in the actual title bar.
So then that will give us what we need.
Save that.
Delete the rest of
the testimonials that are static.
And save that.
Give it a check on the front end and
make sure everything's working.
And here we go,
all of these testimonials are static.
Great, that's awesome.
That's really it.
It was actually quite easy.
So in the next lecture,
basically what we're gonna do is we're
gonna clean up our Home template here.
Because it's quite big, it's got
a lot of PHP in it and a lot of HTML.
But we can actually clean it up by doing
a simple little trick that allows us to
separate the content out of each
of these sections into separate
include type templates and
WordPress makes it really easy.
And it helps clean up your template.
Plus the bonus to that is you can recycle
certain sections should you want to
use them again on different pages.
Like for example the testimonials.
If you wanted to grab that content,
it'd be easy to grab that out without
having to do a lot of coding.
Same deal with all this other stuff.
You want to recycle any sections,
you'd be good to go.
So I'll see you in the next lecture.
Rock on.
[MUSIC]