Hey everybody welcome back to Boost
Your Income with Bootstrap to WordPress.
This lecture is called Learn How to
Create a Modal Popup Using Bootstrap.
[MUSIC]
Now let's code our modal window.
Scroll down to the bottom of
your HTML to the modal div.
And there we're just going to start
using the HTML for the bootstrap modal.
Now this is available on
the getbootstrap.com documentation.
You could just copy and
paste their code and play around with it,
that's all I ever do.
But here since you're with me
you could just follow along so
that you can learn a little bit.
So the div will hold the class of modal,
and fade.
That's just something that
bootstraps adds by default and
it allows it to fade in
when it's initiated.
The id will be myModal using camel case.
Within here, we're gonna have to add
a div with a class of modal dialog.
Again, these Divs in this markup,
is specifically copied from
the get bootstrap documentation.
These classes, they're here for a reason.
I won't really explain them.
Because they just work.
Just use what works.
Modal content And then inside here.
This is where we're gonna add
the div with the class modal header.
Modal header.
Inside modal header, actually let's
keep adding that mark up first.
Then after modal header we're gonna
have div with a class with modal body.
All right?
And now let's go into our modal header,
and give a button.
The type of button, the class of close.
This is gonna add our close Icon
in the top right of our modal.
Data, dismiss, boot strap attribute,
dismiss the modal window.
And then in here,
we're going to add a span.
Make sure to close that button.
And inside that span, we're going to say
aria, whoops, aria hidden equals true.
And then we're going to add
the times HTML entity for an X.
Then after that, we'll add another span.
And then class SR dash, only for
screen reader only, and inside your span.
Close.
That's just so
screen readers can read that
that is a close button.
After your button, add the h4 heading,
class of modal title, and
then id="myModalLabel," just for
some semantic assistance.
And then an i tag.
Class fa fa-envelope.
And what this is actually gonna do
is it's gonna grab Font Awesome.
This is how you.
Use a Font Awesome icon.
So the i html tag gives it
the class of fa for Font Awesome.
And then fa dash whatever
icon you're looking for.
And that's available on
the Font Awesome website.
For reference.
And then space,
subscribe to our mailing list.
Save that and let's check it out,
see if it worked.
All right nothing yet.
And that is because we haven't
initiated some JavaScript I believe,
but let's not worry about that right now.
Let's continue our markup.
And then we'll get it working afterwards.
Inside the modal body let's add some text.
And that text will be simply
enter your name and email!
As a thank you for
joining us we're going to give you one of
our best selling courses, emphasis tag,
for free.
All right, after that paragraph tag,
we're going to add a form.
That form is gonna have the class form
inline because it's an inline form.
Rule will be form and
then inside your form.
Let's give a div with
the class of form-group.
These are Bootstrap classes.
It allows you to give some
default styling to the form so
you don't have to do so much CSS.
And then, inside the form group,
label class sr only, whoops.
That is for your screen readers.
For subscribe dash name,
that will be the ID of our input.
And then your first name,
and then add your
input type text.
And then class form-control
id subscribe-name.
And then a placeholder.
Your first name.
All right,
that'll be your first form group.
Copy that form group,
paste it again afterwards so
you don't have to recode
everything over and over again.
This next one will be subscribe email and
then the label will be and your email.
And then this id for
the input will be four,
subscribe email,
placeholder, and your email.
Okay, and
after that we're gonna add one more thing.
Right after the form group we're gonna
add an input with the type of submit,
the class of btn-danger for a red button.
Value will be subscribe form.
All right.
And then after our form we're
just gonna add a horizontal rule.
HR, and then a paragraph and inside that
paragraph we're gonna add some text,
just like a little bit of a disclaimer.
Small tag, by providing your email
you consent to receive and occasional
promotional emails and newsletters,
break tag no spam just good stuff.
We respect your privacy.
You may unsubscribe at any time.
Okay, that should be your modal.
Save that, now that we've got our HTML in,
we should technically be able
to display our modal by clicking
the button, however it's not working and
the reason why is because down here at
the bottom, our Bootstrap core JavaScript.
I actually forgot to add our
Bootstrap core JavaScript
inside of our scripts here
at the bottom of our page.
So that's important, obviously.
So right after your
jQuery add a script tag
with the source of
assets/JS/bootstrap.min.js.
And that's because you're
grabbing your bootstrap min js.
Close that off, and
now your bootstrap should use script for
your bootstrap should be in your.
Website here.
And now your button should
work if you click it.
There's your modal window, subscribe to
our mailing list, enter your name and
email and here's the inline form with
the button, your close icon up here.
You see this is the font, awesome icon
here, and then our text at the bottom.
All right, there's the modal window.
Hopefully that made sense to you.
See you in the next lecture,
where we are going to code the boost
your income section right here.
See you there.
[MUSIC].