Hey, friend, welcome back, this is the blog post single template, it's very simple.
So we're going to go ahead and code up this e-mail template right now and your code editor.
Make sure to create a new file in your folder of the site and call it something along the lines of a
single dot html.
So let's say single dot h html perfect and in a single day HTML.
We're basically going to just copy a lot of what's in the index that each HTML to get things started.
So copy the head posted and you're single.
And then we're going to also copy the footer section all the way from.
Footer down to the closing HTML tag pasted in there as well, and make sure actually after the opening
or the closing had tag, rather we need to add a body tag and that body tag.
We're going to give it the class of single dash post.
Perfect.
Now inside of there, we're going to have to copy the entire navigation, the hero section, all of
this stuff that we got from the home page or the blog index that we just coded up.
So here's our version here.
We need to actually get this whole header section here and paste it into our single post here.
Now, once we start coding this in WordPress, we're going to be using PHP and then these can all be
dynamic template files, so we don't have to code every single one up.
But right now, we're just going to have to do that.
So go to your index and we're going to grab top navigation all the way down.
Past mobile menu, past title banner past Subscribe!
Bar.
And we're going to stop.
At the content area, so like that is a copy that.
Top navigation all the way to the end of subscribed bar paste that in.
Save now, let's just check to see what this looks like so far.
So here's our single template so far you can see we've got the header, the subscriber and then the
footer perfect.
And then we just need to add content in the middle.
All right.
So we're going to do now.
We're going to add this stuff.
It's going to be very simple.
Now let's head back to our code editor after our section closing section tag.
We're going to add a div with the class of content dash area inside of that div.
With the class of content area, we're going to add a div with the class of container.
Another div with the class of row inside of that.
This one's going to have a few utility classes, bootstrap utility classes.
So Div and the classes are going to be called Dash M.D. Dash eight Offset Dash, M.D., Dash two to
offset it by two from the left.
And then we're going to say overflow hidden dash hidden inside of there.
An article, the class of post.
So now we're just going to post some dummy markup in here.
So Level three, heading with just some, you know, leading into next couple paragraph tags.
Let's save that and have a little look.
There we go.
This kind of looks a little bit weird to me, so maybe we change it to a Level four heading.
The reality is this once it's in elementary, in WordPress, like you could do whatever you want with
it.
So for example, when you're on a post, when you're in the blog and you're writing a post like you
can add whatever text you want in whatever way that you want it, we just have to make sure that each
of those elements are styled.
So it doesn't matter what's in here right now, whether it's a level three heading paragraphs, it doesn't
really matter, but there's our template single HTML file.
Onto the next one.