All right, friends, now we're going to try and code these things up and style them so they look just
right.
Head over to that code editor and in widget start each HTML.
We're going to make a little spot for that area of our widgets.
So right after our title wrapper, what we want to do is find the closing div tag to the row that we
opened here because we want to start a new row.
And so we're going to div with the class of row and in there we're actually going to put a div with
the class of call Dash SM Dash Dash four and then we're going to call this div class text dash card
space, let's say style Dash one.
And we're going to have an empty div with the class of overlay, so let's make sure that that doesn't
expand because we don't actually need that opened just an empty div that will style level four heading
and we'll just say, like modern and responsive.
After that, a paragraph tagged with just some text you can put whatever you want.
I'm going to put just a little descriptive, you know, thing there.
And then after we're going to have div with the class of overlay dash image.
And inside of that, we're going to have an image.
And we're going to go into our assets folder.
In a folder called Images, which I do not believe we've set up yet, so we'll go ahead and do that
in just a moment.
Slash well, we need to get the image, so let's check our assets folder.
We have no images right now, but in our final folder, which you should have already downloaded and
if you didn't, it'll be in the downloads section of this course, or at least the section of the course.
I'll make sure that that's very easy to find wherever those assets are stored.
And then in the assets folder, we'll have assets images.
Make sure that you grab those so you can make a copy of them in your finder and put them and put them
in your assets folder.
We're going to grab those images.
We're just going to drag them into our assets folder, a copy of them images.
There we go.
So we need to grab the card dash date Typekit page.
It's always a good practice to put an alt descriptor in there illustration and that will be the markup
for one of these text card overlay type things.
So if we save that?
Check it out in our browser.
It looks just like this, so there's not much to it, there's just the markup with no actual specific
styles, so that will be the first card.
OK, now what we're going to do is we're going to copy this and we're going to do so from the call Sam
for add another one.
And we're going to change a few things.
So instead of style, one is going to be style two.
And you can put different, different text if you want.
So in the H-4, I'll put like hand-crafted code and in the paragraph tag, let's put something like,
you know, something like this.
And then a different image, it will be card and then editor.
Illustration is fine.
We're going to copy this call, Sam four again for another card.
And this is going to be style three and then we'll do something like intuitive seems.
This doesn't really matter what's in this, it's just really for display purposes because it will change.
It'll be dynamic once be added into WordPress.
The editor sorry, the image is going to be Car Dash page, so those are three images in the images
folder.
Now, if we save that, we'll have three two two two.
So they're in there columns, they just don't look like this.
Now, before we move forward in between this closing rotation and this row tag right here, we're just
going to put a date with the class of spacer and we're going to style that to give some space in between
these rows.
And we might use this in elementary later once it's in WordPress.
So if you head over to your styles, then what we're going to do is maybe just after the typography
here, after the age for you, go to everyone.
It doesn't really matter.
It's class of the spacer margin.
We're going to say seventy five pixels.
Zero, so top and bottom seventy five pixels, so that'll give some space right there.
Head to the bottom of your styles there, and we're going to text card style that general style up.
So possession is going to be relative overflow hidden.
Minimum height of the card.
Let's make like three hundred and thirty five pixels padding thirty five.
Thirty one hundred, that means thirty five on the top, thirty left and right, 100 on the bottom.
We want the border radius to be 20 pixels and then we want the box shadow to be zero, 10 pixels, 15
pixels negative three and then be a black and the alpha channel zero point one five.
So if we see what that looks like now, it looks more like this.
So we're starting to we're starting to get there.
Now we're going to style the text card age four and the text card paragraph tag.
The color is going to be white.
And then we're also going to style the text card paragraph tag individually here in isolation, and
the font size will be zero point eight REM.
Text card overlay, these are classes.
Now the position is going to be absolute, and we're going to Z Index negative one.
So that overlay that empty div that we set up, this is we're going to style that.
So what does that that index be negative one.
So that goes back behind kind of the content, the text.
We're going to say top zero left zero.
We want the width and height to be 100 percent of the container.
And then this is where we're going to do like a background gradient sort of thing just to show you where
it is.
You could see like background black and you'll see just kind of an overlay that spans the whole content
and it's black.
You can change whatever color you want.
But we're actually going to do a gradient, a linear gradient.
Let's go 130 degrees.
So from where it starts, the color, the first color stop.
Is going to be up to nine nine for a zero percent, zero percent, so the color stopped right at the
beginning and it's going to go to even be five seven five seven to 100 percent.
And that's the background gradient.
Check it out.
Here we go, looking very good.
Now we're going to style these individual cards, so we have text card.
Also, with the class of style Dash one.
So you see how there's no spacing between this, these styles, these classes.
Rather, it's because we want to select the text card that also has the class style Dash one.
We could just say style Dash one, but we're being more specific.
And then the overlay, we're going to establish a style one overlay as basically the same is what we
have here.
In fact, it's the exact same because that's going to be the style one overlay.
Now we want to style the style to overlay.
So just copy that entire style, duplicate it and change it to style too.
And then this is where we can change the colors.
Five six, cc f two.
And that's going to go to two f eight zero ed, really.
You can just choose your favorite colors or whatever you think looks good or whatever works for the
brand of the site that you're building.
So let's style to check it out.
Perfect.
Now, copy that.
A third one is going to be style three and then again, change the color to something that you like.
We're going to make this one six f c f nine seven two two one nine six five three.
There we go.
So we've got like an orange blue and a green gradient.
Now we're going to do is we're going to say text card overlay image and then select the image within
that.
We're going to say width 100 percent height, auto and then opacity zero point five.
Looking a little bit better, continue on with this style, we're going to select text card and then
overlay image.
We're going to do position absolute transform, rotate negative 15 degrees.
We want to twist it a little bit.
We want the border radius to be 20 pixels overflow to be hidden and the width to be 65 percent.
Let's check it out, Kate.
Now we want to position these to, you know, being a different location.
As you can see, they're kind of hidden off on the side and the enemy.
So we're going to say because this is position absolute, we can move it wherever we want.
Right.
Negative 15 percent and then bottom negative 15 percent and then transition.
Are Variable Transition, dir.
OK.
Perfect.
Now let's do that animation effect.
We're going to say text dash card on hover.
We're going to select the overlay dash image style that and that's going to be transform rotates and
it's like 18 degrees.
So something subtle but still noticeable.
Negative 18 degrees.
Perfect.
Now the font size is a little bit small here, a little bit bigger on the final.
Let's make a little bit bigger.
So that would be the paragraph tag that we started in.
Isolation will say point nine room.
That looks better to me.
That would be the widgets, the little text card widgets with different colors.
In our next lesson, we're going to style this kind of bigger call card with the background shadow and
the same little effect and just kind of an interesting call to action.
So head over to that.