All right, friends, we are going to go ahead and code this bigger call to action box.
We need to come up with a great name for it.
So let's head over to our code editor and in our widget study team, we're going to style up the markup.
So make sure outside of those three four column or one to three text cards that we just created, you'll
see the row.
We need to make sure we're outside of that row, and I'm just going to add a div with the class of spacer.
Remember how we styled that up in our previous lesson?
Now what we're going to do?
Give ourselves a little space in their little room to work.
Work it.
We're going to add a dinner with the class of row your boat and then actually don't write row your boat,
you'll break everything, but you know, little jokes here and there just to keep everybody happy.
Happy little jokes.
David the class of Col., M.D..
12.
We could just assume 12, I mean, it doesn't really matter.
The point here is a dinner with the class of S. Let's call it call to action all one big class and then
Dave with the class of overlay and inside of that overlay, we're going to have a David, the class
of overlay dash image.
And inside of that div, we are nesting.
Image source assets, slash images, slash card dash date dot PG.
Let's say illustration is the alt descriptor there.
OK, now outside of that overlay.
Tag, we want another div with the class of overlay dash bag.
That's an empty tag.
Nothing in there.
So just keep it like that.
This is what it looks like.
A little bit of space.
We're going to add a paragraph tag.
And we're going to give that the class of sub Dash title.
And this is where you have that kind of eyebrow effect.
I was going to say join 49000 students and then a level two heading, say, bootstrap to WordPress 2.0
with Brad Hussey, another paragraph tag tag with just whatever you want.
Again, this is going to be dynamic, but we're just going to put some some text in there.
Whenever he wants a trough, just the pound sign.
Class BTN space, BTN primary primary.
Primary primary and in there.
Join now and then because we're using the interface and family just dash greater than sign, and it
will automatically convert that to a nice, happy little arrow.
Okay, save that, I must say.
Have a look.
Here we go.
We are looking basic.
Let's make it look.
Next level, go to your styles.
That success or style don't ciusss and after your text card styles and that some space here for the
section call to action.
We're going to position that bad boy relative with the text align center.
The border radius is going to be four pixels padding.
We're going going 90 pixels top and bottom and 100 undead on the left and right.
And then the margin.
We're talking 20 picks anada 20 picks not out.
Check it out.
There we go, looking better already.
Next, we need to select the section dash you don't want.
Just copy and paste this so much typing and overlay dash bpg.
What are we doing there?
We're going to position that absolute top zero left zero.
We want the width.
To be 100 percent, the height to be 100 percent and z index negative to you, Americans might call
this Z index, but the trick here with Z Index using the word Z versus Z is C listen a little background
here.
This has nothing to do with coding, just some literal grammar semantics based on geographic location.
As a Canadian, you might think that I would always say Z, I don't.
In fact, sometimes I say Z, sometimes I say Z.
It's not a uniquely.
All Canadians say Z sort of thing.
I say Z when there is a, let's say, for example, a vowel after the letter Z, it's easier to say
Z index than it is to say Z Index.
Z Index is like you're trying to sound like a cheesy French Accent Z index.
When we say Z Index, it's just easier.
Just bounces.
Just a little top tip there for you, folks.
Back to CC border radius 40 pixels and we want that background color to be true.
That's the sound that is the hex code for the sound effect of like Star Wars guns two.
Oh, sorry, folks, just kind of enamored today.
There we go.
Save it.
Let's have a little check, Jackie.
Nice.
So that's a background yellow background gradient there, not gradient the background effect.
Set background.
You know, it's not a shadow, but we kind of pretended it to be shadow.
So that's it there.
So we're calling it the overlay bag.
Well, perhaps we could call it the underlay bag.
Why don't we do that?
Let's call it the underlay, because it's it really is an underlay underlay big.
Change that to the underlay, big works now we have a better name.
Perfect.
All right, now we're going to do is we're going to S. Call to action overlay.
And it's going to be position absolute top top zero left zero.
We want it to be width and height.
One hundred percent Z Index C Z Index, not Z Index negative one border radius 40 pixels.
We want that overflow to be hidden and we want a linear gradient.
So background, we're going linear gradient and it's going to be 100 degrees.
And then five eight five zero zero five seven.
That's the color stop zero percent and then we're going comma maybe six between nine at 100 percent.
Color stop.
Don't forget your semicolons.
Transform, rotate.
Let's go like three fifty eight degrees.
Save it, Kitao.
See how we kind of twisted that front container a little bit.
All right, now, we've got a problem here with some contrasty it's hard to read.
All right, we're going to go S. Call to action, overlay image image.
There's the selector right there.
Feel free to just type it all out.
And we're going to go width 100 percent height auto.
Opacity zero point five.
And that's going to make that image just a little, you know, going to look like that pretty sketchy.
Let's fix it.
S. Call to action overlay image.
So this is without the image specifically, we're going to say position, absolute transform, rotate.
And now it's going to be 18 degrees border radius, 20 pixels overflow hidden.
And we're going with 30 percent left negative, four percent bottom negative 50 percent and the transition.
And you got it.
We're doing our VAR transition dir.
Check it out.
Look at that and just poking over in the corner like a little cutie pie.
Now we're going to select on hover.
We want to give it a little effect.
So the same selector.
But the trick here S. Call to action when we hover over the section, call to action.
We want to select the overlay image and we're going to transform.
Twenty one degrees.
What was transform rotate 21 degrees?
And save.
When we hover.
But you see how it kind of does that little jiggle get finally, just that texts hard to read.
It's make it white, so select all of that text in there section.
Call to action H.
Two S. Call to action subtitle section call to Action P Color White, But there it is.
And I actually want this to be a different color.
That's the subtitle.
So let's go.
Let's make it like section call to Action subtitle.
We're going to say color, VAR Dash, Dash, Color Yellow.
Do we have that set up in as a variable?
We do.
All right.
Check it out.
Boom, that looks nice.
I like it very much.
And that was good.
Good job in the next one, we're going to keep going.
Doolittle quote looks like this needs some styling or make that look a little nicer.
And then we're done with our widgets and onwards and upwards.
Adios.
Bye.
Salu.
Joe it.
There she.