Hey, everyone, welcome back in this video, we're just going to do a couple small things just to make
sure that we're looking good on mobile devices.
Inevitably, there's always going to be something that's kind of out of whack or wonky with your mobile
device, depending on the device that you're using.
But smaller screen sizes, we're using bootstrapped, so it takes care of probably 80 or 90 percent
of the issues, but you're always going to have little things for her to resize this window.
You're going to see.
It's looking pretty good so far.
And I saw something here, so the margin looks not quite right on that paragraph tag will fix that.
This button doesn't look right.
Well, to fix that.
It's a lot of spacing white space here.
It's probably not necessary.
Um, this is an issue that's too tight.
We need those to break sooner.
This is look and find me, find me and maybe on phone font size could probably afford to be smaller.
And then the margin in between each of these text cards can be fixed.
So that's the widgets page for her to go to, maybe just like the blog index.
OK.
The spacing here is a little bit too much white space.
And I don't think we really have any other pages to to take care of.
OK, so let's head back to our code editor.
We're going to start in the widget that HTML and these columns the call small for are those text cards,
and this call Small four says that it's going to be a three column grid.
So four, eight, 12, so 12 divided by four is three.
So we have a three column grid and it's going to stay in the three column grid until the small break
point.
And then at the small break point, anything less than that, it will break and it will stack.
We want that to happen sooner.
So instead of m make it MD for medium break point on those three, save it and now we'll go back to
our widgets.
And try it, the medium break point will happen here.
Perfect.
Alex, good to me.
We need some margin in between these, so the trick for that is simple.
Go to our style desks and we need to find our text cards.
There we go.
We need to add some margin on the bottom, let's say 20 Pexels Alex Ghadami.
It doesn't affect here stocks.
That's looking good.
All right.
Now, another thing I want to fix is the paragraph tag inside of this subscriber.
Something's going on with that, so maybe what we need to do is add some padding in this.
Here we go.
You can even see it.
So the subscriber has uneven top and bottom padding.
So if we fix that, it should solve the problem.
Now, I think it's going to create a new problem with this, but let's let's get to there when we get
to, they're so subscribe dash bar padding some 30 pixels zero.
So that's going to make a 30 top and bottom.
Now you can see there's an issue here.
It's not vertically aligned.
Well, what we could probably do there to fix that is maybe use a little flexbox.
So what's cool about Flexbox is you can do these things like vertically and horizontally aligning things
and grouping things.
It's just a lot easier to align things using and lay things out with Flexbox in this sort of scenario
where in the past we would have had to use like line height or cheat with like position and things like
that.
What's neat is we just basically have to find the container that we want to be vertically centered.
So.
Not this.
Not this, we want this rather the row this row to be.
Vertically, like in the in the vertical center.
Of of the row, we want the content to be vertically centered.
So if we were to select a subscriber container row.
Then we should be able to vertically center it.
We can also create our own utility class instead of selecting subscriber container row.
So, for example, in our CSIS, instead of selecting Subscriber Container Row, we can create our own
utility class.
Now, before we do that, let's see if this will work.
So display flex and then align items.
This will, it says, defines how the browser distributes space between and around flex items on the
cross axes of their container.
So line items center.
Let's see if that worked.
OK, so it did work here and here, but the Subscribe button, not so much.
Let's see why it's a lot of each HTML markup nested here.
And then I found the button and the button looks like it has some bottom margin, which is preventing
it from falling down.
So if I were to remove that margin?
Then that would fix that issue.
So we just basically need to give no margin on that button.
So we'll go to the markup find with that button is.
It's right here.
Button, button invert, so we can do a number of things, we could select this button or we can give
it its own utility class, I believe Bootstrap has a margin utility class, so m dash zero.
I think might remove margin altogether.
And I believe I'm correct, it did em dash zero is margin zero important?
So that worked.
We did the trick there.
Now what I can do.
Is instead of doing subscriber contain a row, what if we just like created our own utility classic
something like.
Flex, and then let's call it a line center or like Flex Vertical Center.
This is just an example.
It might not be the best naming convention, but we could say like Display Flex, a line items center.
And then we just comment this one out and then add this class to what we want to have these styles.
See if it works.
So we want the subscriber.
We want the RO itself to have that.
Let's see if it even works.
Flex Vertical Center.
And refresh now you'll see our Flex Vertical Center utility class did the trick, but in all honesty,
when we fix the padding of the subscriber to be even and the removed the margin on this button, we
kind of solved some problems.
But let's see if it works here.
OK, so the margin bottom on the paragraph needs to be fixed.
And this subscribe, we probably could have this break sooner.
The form should break sooner the input in the button.
And we need a margin bottom on that paragraph tag.
OK, so let's go to our call mad8.
I'm going to say call.
LG aides.
Let's see if that's changed anything.
That break sooner kind of solves the subscribe button issue, kind of.
Maybe we change the padding 12 pixels in 44 pixels on the invert button.
Let's go to the button and make just like the padding more like 12 pixels all around.
That works better for me.
Now looks good, and then the paragraph here needs some spacing, so we can actually use the bootstrap
utility class on that paragraph tag.
We can say class margin.
Dash, be for bottom, not Dash.
It's M B Dash once for margin bottom one, and we added space there, but we don't necessarily want,
although it does work fine because.
We have Flexbox keeping it vertically centered regardless of the size.
And we have a little bit of space there, which I'm OK with, but maybe if we did, maybe Dash X s Dash
three, it will only give.
OK, that didn't actually do anything, I thought that that was an option, maybe not.
Maybe, maybe Dash three, that's better spacing.
Does it affect here?
The margin bottom here actually looks a little gnarly.
Let's go back to meet one spacing looks more appropriate to me.
This is where you can use a media query, so go to the subscriber p and then add a media query here.
So media screen and max width, let's go five sixty eight pixels for that small break point and we're
going to say subscribe dash bar p.
Margin bottom 20 pixels.
And it doesn't seem to be showing up because it's probably being overridden by this and b one.
So remove that and b one class actually change it from five five six eight to like five seventy six.
And that'll be a break point where this breaks here.
There we go.
And that looks good.
Keeps the margin out of it there.
Add some margin there.
Perfect.