Hey, everybody, welcome back to Boost
Your Income of Bootstrap to WordPress.
This lecture, I'm gonna teach you how to
code a circle, using CSS3, not Corel.
That was weird.
>> [MUSIC].
Okay guys, now what we're gonna do
is gonna code some CSS3 Circles, and
what's exciting about CSS3 Circles?
Well traditionally in web design, what
you'd have to do is open up Photoshop,
create a circle at all different sizes,
and colors, and textures, and
whatever it is you were trying to do, and
you'd export it as a background image.
And you couldn't just export it as an PNG,
because not all of
browsers at one point supported PNG,
so you have to have a JPG as well.
You have to have all these
different fall back images.
It was a huge waste of time and
a pain in the butt.
But now you can use CSS3 for
your circles and your shapes.
So we're gonna do that.
I'll show you what that is here.
These are actually circles in CSS3,
they're not images.
Their circles using CSS3,
and the even better part,
is they take hardly any loading time.
Whereas an image, you'd have to
export all the image assets, and
that has loading time, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, crappy, you know?
CSS3 is awesome, let's do it.
Open up your CSS, and
in your global section, we're gonna
go to the bottom here after image.
Now I did realize there's one
thing we haven't done yet.
And this is kind of,
I wanted to include this in this lecture.
Because although this lecture
is about CSS3 Circles,
there is one thing that we
missed in a few lectures back.
And that's cool, that's fine.
It's natural that's kind of the process
of web design and development.
You don't always have everything
perfect and in order.
Sometimes you have to jump back and fix
something that you forgot a while back.
And we're gonna do that together.
So right here in this section,
we just need to select our modal content.
Do you remember the modal
content in that modal window?
Well there's supposed to be
a texture within that Popup window.
Right now it's just white.
We're gonna change that.
And we're gonna give it
a background texture.
The tile.jpg, top left repeat.
So that's selecting the tile graphic.
And now let's just check it out.
Refresh your page, and
initiate the modal window.
There you go.
Now you should have the tile.
There you go, that's it, okay.
Now let's jump back into our CSS3 circles.
Right below the modal content,
conveniently, we're going to select
the CSS3, or sorry,
the CSS class badge and social.
So we're combining those together.
Badge and social.
So this element has two classes.
And we're selecting them together
rather than spacing them apart.
Because it's not a descendant selector,
we're combining those.
Okay, the background will be CCC,
font size 24px, height 40px, width 40px.
So we're making a square here text
align: center; line height: 40px,
that's the height of the social icon.
So, that should technically
center that text vertically.
Margin: 0 5px 20px and 0.
So that's 0 on top, 5 on the left and
right, 20 on the bottom.
Sorry, 0 on top, 5 on the right,
20 on the bottom, zero on the left.
Padding, none at all.
We're gonna,
this is where the CSS3 circle comes in.
So we're gonna do web kit.
Border radius 50px.
The other thing you could do is just 100%.
But because we're height and
width 40px and it's not gonna change ever.
We could just say 50px, just a little bit
larger than the height and width itself.
And then, moz-border-radius, this is for
Mozilla browsers 50px and
then just the good old,
whoops, border, radius, 50px.
Now I wanna show you something.
Something comes up here in Coda2.
The little border radius
dialogue window here.
If I click that, I can actually
style my border radius right here.
So right now this is like
50 pixel border radius, but
if I wanted to change it, and
I want it to look like that.
And maybe I want it to look like that.
Or maybe a little bit like that.
And then this is very ugly.
But see what this does?
Here you go.
How about something like this?
This neat little teardrop shape,
something like this.
There you go, that's cool.
What if you wanted to do that?
Then there you go.
You just add the other values
here in the CSS class.
But we're just gonna go with 50.
There you go.
And then the color of
the text will be white.
So why don't we just check it out and
see what it looks like.
Refresh that and
scroll down to your instructor section.
Here it is.
Hey, so we're getting there.
Now I noticed a small, little detail
that you might not even notice.
I said 40 pixel line height,
but, if you can see here,
the graphics
are just a touch too high
in the center vertically.
There's a little bit too much space on
the bottom and not enough on the top,
not technically centered and that's due
to the fact that sometimes icon fonts
don't match up the line height properly,
because they just, it is what it is.
So, all we need to do is
just a little mini hack.
Instead of line height 40, just add
a couple pixels to that line height, and
now, if I refresh that, There we go.
That's dead center.
So, just a couple pixels
made all the difference.
Okay, now we wanna be able to make
these colors change when we hover.
So back to the CSS.
We're gonna select badge.
That also has a class of social.
That also the class of Twitter.
And the pseudo class hover.
So badge social Twitter hover.
Background the Twitter
brand color by five ACEE.
I didn't memorize that.
I have a reference and I researched it.
And why don't we just keep going.
Badge, social, Facebook and hover.
The background.
So, we'll do the Facebook brand here,
the actual purple blue color
that they use, 3b5998.
And then, .badge.social.gplus, remember?
Hover and then we'll use the gplus
background, the actual brand color.
So we're actually complying with
their brand regulations for, sorry,
that should be four.
No, I'm a liar, that's d, db4b39.
Save that.
Why don't we give it a little check.
Hover over those, see what happens.
Look at that.
So I got the G+ salmon color,
Facebook blue purple color and
the Twitter sky blue color.
Amazing, okay.
So we're getting there.
Okay, now there's something
that I noticed here.
I don't like how this looks.
You can see the instructor,
the h2 here, and
our social icons,
they're not lined up very well.
That doesn't look very good.
They don't match up in the baseline.
By the baseline, I mean the bottom
of this level two heading.
They don't match up.
There's a little bit of spacing here,
and that's because this
level two heading has margin on the top,
and we do not want that.
So let's go into our CSS.
And scroll down past the layout
section here down to the instructor.
There we go.
And just select instructor ID,
H2, margin 00 and 20.
So there's only 20 pixels on the bottom.
And there we go.
So now it's lined, it should be
lined pretty much in the center.
So, we've got just 20
pixels on the bottom.
That gives us just a little
bit of space there.
So, now, the H2 is pretty much
center in between, vertically,
in between these social icons.
Now, why don't we move down,
and style these babies up?
So, go to your code here.
And we're going to select
those have the class of num.
So, we're going to select instructor,
and then class of num.
What we'll do now is,
let's do a few things.
So, font-size, 30px.
Font-weight, bold.
Color: white.
And let's say height: 140, and width:140.
Text-align: center.
Background: we're gonna do
that salmon color, dd5638.
And then we're gonna
do that border radius.
So webkit-border-radius and
that will be 100%.
We'll just try it, why not.
And then moz-border-radius 100% and
border-radius 100%.
Great.
Let's do some sexytext,
just cuz we want it to look smooth.
Save that, and
let's just see what happened.
All right, so the circles are there,
but the text doesn't look that great,
but that's okay.
I'm gonna save that for the next lecture.
And I'm gonna show you the trick
to make sure that the text within
a block level element is always vertically
centered and it's not using line height.
It's actually something you
may not have heard of before.
It's cool.
See you there.
[MUSIC]