Hey everybody.
Welcome back to
Boost Your Income With
Bootstrap To WordPress.
And in this lecture I'm going to show you
the one weird trick to vertically line
your content within any element.
I hate Clickbait.
It gets me every time.
[MUSIC]
All right guys, what we're gonna do now
is vertically align this content here
in our circles, as you can see, here.
Now, what's cool about this is there's
a couple ways to vertically align content,
and it's pretty difficult sometimes
to vertically align your content.
I know when I have been developing
websites and I didn't know this trick.
It's really frustrated me cuz I
would use margin or I'd position
the element absolute and then just use
a pixel value to vertically align.
To make it look like it's
vertically aligned, but
what if I change the height
of these elements?
What if I change the height of
the parent block level element?
And then I have to go and
change the absolute position.
Or what if there's more content?
What if the content, I add more content?
And then, now it's not actually
vertically aligned anymore.
Or what if the font doesn't load
properly on a certain browser, and
then the font is just a bit bigger,
and then it drops on a new line.
And it's so many things that
kind of make it difficult to vertically
align content within an element.
And what I mean by vertically align,
if you don't know what I'm talking about,
is this is vertically aligned.
It's like saying text align center,
but from top to bottom.
Cuz right here,
it's easy to say text align center.
Instead of left or right.
But I want it in the center vertically,
like this.
So when I add my text you could see here,
it's at the top.
Minus a few styling issues, which we'll
fix, it's just stuck here at the top.
But I want it here, and I want it to
always stay in the center no matter how
big or small that freaking circle is.
So, we're gonna use this cool trick that
will solve that issue for you forever.
So please pay attention to this lecture
because when I found out this trick,
I thought why didn't I know this before?
Open up that code editor my friend
right here under your instructor.
We're gonna select instructor and
num and then span.
So we're just gonna do a little styling
to make it look a little sexier first.
display: block.
So span elements are default inline.
You want that to be a block.
And then the font size,
you want it to be smaller.
And the font weight, normal.
So let's just have a look.
Okay.
That looks a bit better.
Perfect.
Okay.
Now back above that.
Select instructor num and num-content.
Remember in our HTML markup
we have the num element and
then inside num we have num-content.
And that's because this is
what we're gonna do here.
We're going to say
display will table-cell.
And vertical align middle.
Now before you go and check anything, in
order for this table cell display to work,
it's parent num needs to be display table.
Right now num is display block.
No no no display table.
We need to make the num
element act like it's a table.
And now that it acts like a table,
we can say let's make its child
num-content like a table-cell,
and we can vertically align
the content within that table-cell.
That's what's neat about this, because we
don't code in tables anymore for layouts.
We lost the access to easily
vertically align things.
Those of you who are old school and
coded in tables,
you might have thought like, oh totally.
Why don't you just vertically align it?
Like in a table?
But for those of us who have
been learning web development
past the time when you would
use tables for layouts.
This trick is kinda forgotten
because who uses tables for layouts?
Nobody, at least you shouldn't be,
but this is the trick.
Make sure the parent is a display table,
and then you need to have an extra element
within that display it table-cell vertical
line middle check this magic out.
Holy moly, that's amazing.
Perfect.
The only thing is,
it looks like there's maybe a little
bit of a line height issue.
So, why don't we go back and fix that.
So, in here,
let's just put it above our height and
between our color and
I hear it doesn't really matter.
But, I'm going to say,
here line height 24 pixels cuz right now,
it's probably at about 30 or a bit more.
So, that should fix it.
Man oh man that looks good.
Perfect.
Well, there you go.
There is the secret trick.
That one weird trick to make sure all
of your content is vertically aligned.
And hopefully you love it and
are excited about it.
Make note of it.
And I'll see you in the next lecture
because then we're going to start coding
our testimonials section.
And then we're almost done and then we'll
start jumping into our other pages.
See you there friendos.
[MUSIC]