Hello and welcome to the course on artificial intelligence ages.
My name is Colonel Reiko and on behalf of I love the West the construction of this course.
I'd like to welcome you into this amazing adventure that we're about to start.
And what's up with this timer.
Well the reason for this cyber is this is my third time regarding this tutorial and I get so excited
about these things and it just goes over like blows over 10 minutes or 20 minutes so I decided to limit
myself to five minutes to get you excited about this course and why it's the best time to be in a job.
So let's dive into a good four and a half minutes left.
Why.
Well we've all heard about applications of artificial intelligence that are popping up around us self-driving
cars medicine heavy machinery.
The of a service the list just keeps going on and on and on.
But why right now why not 10 years ago not ten years later.
Well the answer is hidden in this current which is called Moore's Law.
It was originally identified in 1965 or more and what it says is that the power of the average computer
in like in very simple terms the power of the average computer which you can buy for a thousand dollars
will double every 18 to 24 months.
And that's been as easy as the law has held and through good times and bad.
War and Peace and the recession depressions and nothing stops this.
And we've already surpassed the brain of an insect for another computer was going by for a thousand
bucks.
We're sitting at about the speed of the processing power of the brain of Arat by 2025 will be at the
brain of a human.
As you can see it's exponentially growing.
And so this is a great time to be in artificial televisions.
It's just going to be doubling the power is going to be doubling every time or every three minutes.
So what's some my favorite examples are related to games like chess and go.
So in 1997 deep mind was the first computer to beat Gary Kasparov in chess.
It was a huge thing was like one of the most broadcasted chess games on the planet ever.
And at the same time.
So that was like consider it an impossible feat right now on any phone you can install at chess which
no human player will ever be.
Because computers are that good.
Now you just cannot beat a computer in Chesapeake put on the hardest setting and then just recently
in Marsch doesn't succeed.
A computer won against the 18 World times champion and world champion of the game of Go.
Lisa idole again considered an impossible feat even at the start of the match.
It was considered to have to be impossible that it's only going to happen 10 years from then but it
happened.
And by the way if you'd like find out a bit more about the game.
It's very very exciting very interesting.
It's got 40 media players.
The thousand year old game very popular in China Japan and Korea.
And it's much more complex than chess so it's just that there's many more possible combinations.
So again something I would consider impossible is happening and it's happening now and much earlier
than it's time.
So how are we going for time.
One minute 50 seconds.
So that's what you'll see from this course you'll see that we're using games to train AI Why are we
doing that.
Because games are a confined environment where we can if we can beat a game using an artificial intelligence
then we can use the same principles to apply to business.
And that's the exact same thing that the team at Google deep mine who created Alpha go who want to get
these adult.
That's exactly what they did.
They applied artificial intelligence to Google's warehouse to control the air cooling.
And what they found is that the electricity bill is a consumption you can see like it's going like this.
Soon as they switch on the AI goes down.
And then they switch it back off goes up.
They were able to save 40 percent on their electricity bill and I have one that 40 percent so you can
find the full article on the deep mine blog.
That is insane.
Imagine that for a company of Google's scale which has millions and millions of servers.
So there you go.
That's that's your connection between applying artificial intelligence and games and applying it to
business very very closely related.
And that's what you will be able to do after this course.
And finally one of my favorite blogs.
Wait but why dot com.
Check it out.
Amazing blog by Tim Urban.
This is how he describes the situation we're in.
This is us and technological progress.
We're sitting here.
This is what it looks like looks very very linear but because it's an exponential boom.
This is what's going to happen in the next two years and there's very strong evidence from the things
we seeing to suggest that we're sitting right over here and they can occur.
And that my friends in-shore is why it's so exciting to be alive right now.
Why is so exciting to be and get into and be in the space of artificial intelligence because the power
you have the locations that you will be able to create or the ways you will be able to have what is
going to be intense and insane.
And I can't wait to see on the first of all the scores.
Let's get this started.