Hello and welcome to this tutorial.
All right so today we're going to make a function that will save or model that is that will save the
brain of the car so that we can we use it whenever we quit the application.
Thanks to the Save function will be able to save the model.
Then quit the application and then when we go back to the application things to another function that
is the load function which will make after this one we will be loading the last version of our model
that was trained so that will be very practical and therefore let's make these two functions the same
function and the load function.
So let's start with the same function in this tutorial.
So here comes the new def then save and then it's going to take one argument that it's going to be self.
And the reason is that the thing we are going to say is not the whole model here but our neural network
Selldorf model and our optimizer cells that optimize it because what we want to save is just the last
weights that were dated at the last iteration because whenever we want to reuse our saved more later
we wanted to bring the action to play with the weights that were already trained.
So we need to take this last version of the weights.
And also we need to take the last version of the optimizer because it is connected to these weights.
So let's do this.
We have our cells so we'll be able to take our That model in ourselves the optimizer and we will be
saving these two objects in a Python dictionary and to save these two objects.
We're going to use the same function from the torch module.
So I'm starting here with torche that save and in parenthesis we are going to put that dictionary brackets
in a dictionary.
Bison works like that you have a key which is your identifier.
So that's unique.
And for each you have the value you want to get to that key.
So it's like a mapping function from unique identifiers to a value you want to get these identifiers.
If you take a simple dictionary book well the keys will be the words and the values will be the definitions
of the words.
Well here that's to say we're going to make two keys one key for the first object we want to save which
is subduct model and one second before.
The second thing we want to say that is our self that optimizer and therefore let's start with the first
key.
So we had to give a name to that key and I'm going to call it state on the score dict because then you're
going to see them going to use the function say dict to save our model in the dictionary.
So that's our first key then to give the value we want to attribute for that first key.
Well as you can see I added a little con here and here I'm going to add the object the object I want
to say.
So the first object I want to say is self model so we can just copy this self to morrow and paste it
as the value of our first key cell.
Now then we add that state underscore dict.
Here we go.
The first one.
And then we add in parenthesis and that will save the parameters of your model.
In this first key state dict.
And now let's say our optimizer.
So we're going to add a second key in the dictionary and to do this we have here a comma.
Then press enter and then we go with our second key.
So the second key We're going to call it.
Well we can call it optimizer then call in and then we just need to add the name of the object you want
to save.
And that is self.
That is our optimizer.
So we add here self that optimizer.
And then again to set the parameters of this optimizer we are here again that state.
And then we go we have our model saved with all the weight saved and our optimizer saves perfect and
then we will save all this into a file and to do this I'm going to add a second argument to the Save
function which is going to be the name of this file where we want to have our model in our optimizer
set.
So remember I should do a quick demo in the first section of this first module self-driving car.
You know that was a demo where we just had some random actions.
So that was not yet the self-driving car but then remember I clicked on the save button to save the
model and this created the last brain that PCH found which is the file that contains the same version
of your email.
So I'm going to add here last underscore brain that age so that your moral and your optimizer will be
saved into this created file.
Let's bring that page so you don't have it yet.
But as soon as you said your model on the application this file will be created thanks to this code
we just added.
All right.
And so now perfect.
We have a safe function that will save your model save the brain of your car by saving the weights and
the optimizer of the new network that is in fact the brain of the car so perfect we now have only one
function to create left.
That's the load function and that's because the same function never goes without a load function.
No there is no purpose saving your model.
If you cannot load what you say afterwards.
So that's the last step in our journey before the exciting demo and we will make this Sloat function.
In the last two Toyota section so I'll see you in this next tutorial.
And until then enjoy AI.