[Autogenerated] All right, let's dive in now.
The first thing we're going to look at within Amazon
CloudWatch is what's called metrics.
Now.
Metrics are one of the key components that make up
the Amazon CloudWatch service.
So CloudWatch used to be primarily just a metric
monitoring service offered to us by A W S.
But it's really morphed into a major critical service that offers a lot more.
So let's go ahead and check some of this stuff out.
Now let's go to CloudWatch in the first thing we can see over here
on the left is the abundance of resource is and services that
belonged to the CloudWatch services itself.
Now the primary key components you need to know for your solutions.
Architect exams are alarms, logs, metrics and then events,
and we'll cover all of those here later on.
But for now, we're going to focus on metrics.
So let me go ahead.
I'm going to go to metrics,
and this brings us to a graph screen with some
metrics listed at the bottom here.
Now,
metrics are strictly data about the performance of our
systems that's reporting to CloudWatch.
So it's important to notice here that it's not necessarily.
Only a W s resource is if you have hybrid architectures.
You could also push metrics to CloudWatch.
It just takes a little bit more configuration.
Now to build on that,
there are two main types of monitoring offered to us by a W s.
There's free monitoring.
So it's built in metrics for several different resource is.
And then there's detailed monitoring for specific resource is and that
allows us to also publish our own application metrics.
Okay, so now that we have a better understanding of all of that,
let's go ahead and dig into these metrics.
Now, on the bottom half of the screen here, we can see all metrics.
Now,
these metrics are specific to what metrics we have created
and pushed to CloudWatch in our account.
And keep in mind these error regional.
So there are many more services.
In fact,
let me show you these error all the services that
pushed to CloudWatch for metric data.
You can see it's a lot.
But what we see here is what we have actually used is far as services.
So to demo this I'm going to select E c two and E C two is actually
the name space of the metric that we're measuring.
So if you remember, we discuss name spaces in one of those key concepts,
and that's exactly what that is.
E.
C two is a group or a container of metrics that we can look for.
And if I go back to this services screen,
you can see the name Space is here in the middle column.
And if you notice they all follow the same pattern,
they start with a W s / and then the service name.
So when you're creating custom metrics and custom name spaces,
which you can do this prefix the A W s slash is saved.
You cannot use that.
So just keep that in mind.
Let's go back to CloudWatch and will continue.
I'm going to look at, per instance, metrics,
and you can see we have a ton of metrics in here Now a ton is relative.
There's only 35.
But for a small account, that's quite a bit.
And this can get a little overwhelming.
So what I'm going to do is I wanna look for CPU utilization,
so I'm gonna search for this only and then we narrow that down to two resource
is now This is the instance IDE that I spun up and what I've done in the
background is I spun up in easy to instance and I went ahead and stress test the
CPU to generate some CPU utilization metrics.
And you can see that here in this graphic that I
clipped from my terminal session.
So I'm going to select CPU utilization.
And if you notice at the top of this page, it's populated our graph.
Now, the measurement time is three hours.
So let's go and knock this down to a custom of 15 minutes and there we go.
That's a bit easier to see now,
the default data point is every five minutes and a data point is a period
of time that we're measuring data for these metrics.
So for this graph, we have two data points.
We have one ending at 2.
20 UTC.
As you can see here and then we have another one at 2.
15 UTC that you can see over here on the left and you can see
those both have their own metric measurement.
So if we wanted to we can even specify a finer data point like every minute.
But keep in mind that costs more than using the
default of five or even greater now.
Another tidbit to remember is that your metric data is
going to be kept for 15 months within AWS,
so it allows us the ability to view minute by minute data or we can.
Go back and look at historical data.
It's all dependent on your use case.
So now that we have this graft here,
you'll see that it populates are graft metrics tab.
Now, this is where we can specify a little bit more customization.
We see our label here, CPU utilization.
We see our details so we have the E.
C to name space,
our metric label and then the instance IDE that we're
actually measuring and we have our statistic.
Now the statistic is essentially what we're displaying on our graph.
So right now it's average, but you can see there's several options.
You can do the 99th percentile.
You can do some or we can even do maximum,
so I'll select maximum and you can see the maximum for
the past two data points is 100%.
Which makes sense because I'm stressing the system out.
Let me go back to average, and then the next thing we see is period.
So depending on the service, you could go down to one second,
which is detailed, extremely detailed.
I can go up to an hour, or even if I wanted to.
I give you 30 days within the console, so it allows for a lot of flexibility.
Now that's going to do it for this demo on CloudWatch
metrics and how we can measure those metrics. Let's wrap up and then we'll continue on by looking at CloudWatch dashboards.