[Autogenerated] All right, let's go ahead and talk about CloudWatch alarms Now.
CloudWatch alarms are a very critical component that you need
to understand how to implement and use.
They serve many different purposes within an architecture.
So let's go over to alarms, and this brings us to our alarms list.
Now we obviously don't have any because we haven't created one yet.
But let's go ahead and fix that.
Let's create an alarm and you'll see the first step
is we need to specify our metric.
So let's select metric and I'm guessing you'll recognize this screen by now.
Let's go ahead and set up the same metric as before.
So CPU utilization, we'll keep the line as it is.
But I'm going to switch this statistic to maximum.
So I wanna measure for the maximum CPU utilization every five minutes.
So let me select my metric and there we go.
We now see are Grafana on the left.
We see our name, space, our metric name, the instance, the instance name.
If we specify that we see are statistic that we chose and then our period.
So our five minute period Now the next thing that's present is our conditions.
Now conditions are exactly what they sound like.
They're conditions that need to be met in order for us to trigger an alarm.
Now, the two types of thresholds error static.
So we set a static value or we can have anomaly detection.
So it measures using insights, the normal operating levels.
And then when it sees an anomaly or unexpected one,
it goes ahead and breaches that threshold.
And then we move on to our second piece,
which is our metric that we're measuring.
So whenever CPU utilization is and we define our alarm
condition so it could be greater than greater or equal to
lower or equal to or just lower.
So we'll go ahead,
I'm going to select greater equal to I'm going to set our threshold here,
which is next to 50.
So whenever CPU utilization breaches are static value of 50%
it will go ahead and trigger this alarm.
Now let's look at additional configuration and we can.
See, we have data points to alarm.
So what this means is we can customize how sensitive we want these alarms to be.
So, for instance, if I left it at one out of one,
that's extremely sensitive because it's going to always trigger an
alarm any time a data point crosses our threshold.
So let's say we wanted to be a little bit less sensitive.
We can maybe raise this to, let's say four.
And then let's say we want a monitor on every two out of four.
I'm going to leave this as the default.
So we can speed this demo up and then we move to missing data.
So we can treat missing data differently, depending on our use case.
Now the default is to treat it as missing.
So nothing happens.
But you can see you can switch it to good.
So the alarm moves to an okay state we can ignore it,
which maintains the current state or we can.
Treat it as bad.
Move it to in alarm state.
So depending on your use case, those can be useful.
I'll leave it as missing.
Click on next, and that brings us to our notification.
Our actions.
Now this is where alarms become extremely powerful.
We can set up a trigger that can take action on a notification.
Now, we can see the three different types of triggers we have in alarm.
So whenever a threshold is broken, we have.
Okay, so it's like negation of an alarm.
Whenever our statuses okay,
we'll go ahead and trigger or we can trigger on insufficient data.
So when there's not enough data available, we'll go ahead and trigger.
I'll leave this at an alarm now for the okay status.
This could be useful when Let's say you scale out based on
percentage of utilization on Auto Scaling Group.
And then when you reach below a certain threshold and that alarm moves to okay,
you can actually perform a different action that scales back in.
So similar to this graphic here where we're triggering a
notification and action on an auto scaling group based on
requests now for this demo, I'm going to leave in alarm,
and then we could select an SNS topic.
Now we can create one.
From here, you can specify an arm to use.
You can specify that here as long as you have permissions,
but we're going to select an existing Now I'm going
to send it to my admin alert, SNS Topic and we can.
See, my email is my endpoint,
so it's going to send me an email to my company's email
address whenever this alarm is triggered.
now, The next thing down here is an auto scaling action, so this is similar.
It's the same triggers, except for the resource types are just different,
their auto scaling.
So you can see we have auto scaling and CSS.
So depending on our use case,
we can select an auto scaling group and take a specific
action when this alarm is triggered.
So calling back to that graphic like this right here, this would be an example.
We're taking an auto scaling action upon an alarm.
Triggering.
Let me remove this.
And then the last thing we see is an easy to action.
So the same triggers, except for the actions error different as well.
And these error specific to an E c two instance we can Stop it
terminated or reboot it and you can see great out.
We can recover it, but that's specific to certain e.
C two types.
Now I'll remove this.
We'll go ahead and continue,
and I'll give my alarm a name and after the name of description,
and then I'll click on next.
That brings us to a preview screen,
and you can see here on this graph that it actually laid
out a line that measures are threshold.
So that's at 50% and you can see currently we're underneath that threshold.
So that's perfect.
We can review our conditions, our actions and our name and description.
And then let's create our alarm.
And there you go.
We see it here in the insufficient data state because it just
has not had enough time to collect enough data based on the data
points we selected as well as the time period in order to make a
decision on the state.
So since we selected Treat as missing data,
it's going to just sit here in the insufficient state and not move.
So what I'll do here is I'll pause this clip.
I'm going to start another stress test and then we'll
resume and view how our alarm reacts.
Okay, so I'm going to resume here for a second,
because if you notice, our state has now switched to okay,
and that's because our CPU usage is below that 50% threshold.
So I'm going to pause one more time while the stress test runs in the
background and then we'll resume once this changes.
All right, so I just got an alarm here,
so Let's breathe fresh This And there you go.
We can now see our alarm has switched its state to alarm.
So once it did that, it's semi and email,
as you can see from my phone that I'm recording and it shows us
the alarm that went off and in which region.
So hopefully this gives you some insight and some spike
and curiosity on how you can utilize CloudWatch alarms within your own architectures.