[Autogenerated] all right,
So now that we have an understanding or an overview
of what CloudWatch events are, let's go ahead and demo some of these out.
Now, in this clip,
we're going to look at scheduled expression based CloudWatch events.
So over here on the left, I click on events I'm going to click on Get started,
and this brings us to our create rules screen.
Now, the first thing we do here is we select our type of trigger.
We have Event-Hubs.
Kern, which is next, and then we have schedule,
which I'm going to select for this one.
Now, this brings us to two different options.
And these error the two different types of scheduled expressions.
We have a rate expression where we define an integer and then a rate,
so minutes, hours or days.
So I'll set this at one minute for now, or we can set a Cron expression.
Now,
the Krahn expressions here might differ a little bit from what you
might be used to if you work with Cron's in Linux.
So the first section is the minutes of the day.
The second is the hours.
Then we have the day of month.
So the first, the second the third, etcetera.
We have the month itself.
We have the day of week, day of week, meaning Sunday,
all the way through Saturday.
And then we have the year and you can see CloudWatch actually
shows us what our next 10 trigger dates will be,
so we can see that this is going to trigger every day at the same time.
12.
UTC.
So if I change this third sprechen in, let's say I change it to the 15th.
It's going to trigger this rule on the 15th.
So these error very powerful.
Now for this demo, I'm going to select a fixed rate of one minute,
and that brings us to our targets.
So we add a target for this event,
and you can see we can actually target several different services.
We can do batch jobs we can do easy to instances we can trigger
toward can nested streams or maybe a SNS topic.
It's very, very versatile now for this, we'll do lamb to function.
I'll select my function here and we'll see what this does as it invokes.
You can notice that we can configure a version and alias if we wanted to,
and we can configure our input so we can pass the matched event
we can pass part of the matched event we can send constant JSON
or we can transform our input.
Now I'll leave it at matched event.
I'll configure our details and let me give it a name,
and with that a description.
We'll leave it as enabled, and I'll create our rule.
And there we go.
We now have our CloudWatch rule with a rate based expression.
Now,
one thing to keep in mind here is when you create a rate
based expression in CloudWatch events,
it always invokes immediately when you create it for the first time.
So when we created that, it invoked that function.
And then a minute from that point in time,
it will invoke it again and then so on until we
either disabled or delete this rule.
So let's go ahead and check that out.
Now let me go to Lambda.
I'll go to my CloudWatch event here.
Let's go to monitoring and we can CR metrics and you can
see here we have had an indication, so that's great.
So in roughly another minute or actually a little bit less,
we should have to indications.
Let's go ahead and look at our logs in CloudWatch we can CR Day and time,
which is the one that just occurred.
So if I open this log stream there we go we can see our first
indication at 307 UTC and it prints our rate based event.
And then exactly one minute later, we have our second request.
So it's invoking every single minute.
So now you can see how we can leverage CloudWatch events to trigger
certain services to customize our own workloads.
These CloudWatch events are very powerful and they
meet a broad amount of use cases.
So let's go ahead and clean this up.
And then after I delete this rule will go ahead and wrap up
this clip and then move on to the next one, which is going to discuss event based events.