[Autogenerated] Hello, everyone.
My name is Andrew Estes and welcome to my course Gaining
operational excellence within a W s.
I am an enterprise cloud architect at CSG International as well
as founder of Quick to Cloud Operational Excellence is one of the
five critical pillars that make up the well architected framework
provided to us by A W s.
And in this course,
we're going to learn how we can best implement A W s services to gain
the most efficient operation for our architectures.
Some of the major topics that we're going to cover include
advanced CloudWatch logging scenarios were going to configure
and protect CloudTrail trails.
We're gonna work with leveraging systems manager and parameter store,
and then we're gonna create repeatable deployments
using CloudFormation and ops works.
By the end of this course,
you're going to understand how you can utilize A W s offered
services to optimize your own workloads and handle your
operational tasks before beginning this course,
you should be familiar with a few concepts,
and those include core A W s concepts.
So some of the core services you need to be comfortable with SSH and then it
might help to have an operational background or at least an understanding of
how infrastructure in operational backgrounds work.
After the course,
you should feel comfortable diving into gaining operational
excellence with courses on CloudFormation deep dives,
other courses that are a part of this solutions architect,
professional learning path.
And I have another course called Managing A W s Operations that is
essentially a deep dive into systems manager.
So I really hope you'll join me on this journey to learn how to
optimize our workloads with the gaining operational excellence within a W S course here at Pluralsight.