[Autogenerated] all right, now, before we wrap up everything and in this course,
I just wanted to give a brief course review and
then some recommended next steps.
So if you recall, we used CloudWatch in advanced scenarios,
including pushing custom logs from our servers to CloudWatch
law groups for us to monitor and look at.
We learned how to heavily utilize CloudWatch metrics
for both monitoring and alerting.
And we looked at enabling,
configuring and then protecting via validation are CloudTrail trails.
Fourthly, we looked at leveraging systems manager for ops related tasks.
So our normal,
tedious work that could be done in an automated fashion can leverage
this service in order to speed it up and building off.
Of that,
we looked at getting secret values Using a W s
parameter store within systems manager.
We saw how padding can do work for allowing access,
and we looked at the different types of parameters that error offered.
And then finally,
we just wrapped up creating repeatable deployments using
both CloudFormation and A W S ops works.
So this allowed us to learn how to implement these infrastructure
and config management tools using a few templates.
Now that does it for this course.
Thank you for watching for next steps.
I do encourage you to look at the AWS Solutions architect
professional learning path that they have and follow
through on some of those courses.
Now, I also have another course called Managing A W s Operations,
and that is essentially a deep dive on the systems manager service.
So be sure to check that out as well. And with that, Thank you for watching.