[Autogenerated] Okay.
Welcome back.
Now, In the previous clip, we went ahead and viewed the default CloudTrail trail.
And in these clips,
we're going to create and configure our very own trail for custom uses.
So if I go to create trail here, this brings us to our create trail screen.
Now, the first thing we have to do is give it a name.
So let me give this a quick trail name.
And after that, we see we can apply this trail to all regions.
Now, if you want it to only record data in this region,
you can select No,
but it's a very common and it's a best practice to
enable a trail in all regions.
So you're monitoring your entire account.
So this automates the tedious task of creating the
same trail throughout our account.
Now,
another important aspect of this is that when you
create the same trail to all regions,
it will help with de duplicating data and events that you might otherwise get.
And that's really more specific to global Resource is now.
The next thing we see here is management events and you can see
that management events are simply records of actions performed on
or within resource is in our accounts,
and they allow us to go ahead and configure specific options.
The first one is read.
Write events, so we can either capture all events.
We can capture only right events.
We can capture only read events, or we can capture absolutely none.
Now.
I would never recommend you capturing none.
It's a good practice to go ahead and leave it at all,
because this is going to capture any time someone's logging into your account.
It's going to capture anything security related within your account.
And it captures anytime someone might set up some type of logging,
so it captures those really specific events that you might want to know about.
Now.
The next option is we can Log Kms events.
So if we wanted to we can log any time that someone's
calling Kms within our account and log it to the trail so
we'll leave this it Yes as well,
because we want to know everything that's going on and we can
filter it later and then we have insights,
events.
Now.
This shouldn't be included in the Solutions Architect Professional exam,
and we didn't cover it when we were looking at CloudWatch,
but All it is is groups of records that capture
unusual call volume of right APIs.
So if out of the blue and out of nowhere,
your account starts receiving an enormous amount of right API
calls enabling this will capture those events.
The next thing we see is data events.
So this is event records for actions on or within a
resource and specifically S3 and Lambda.
Now, when we enable it and S3,
you can see that it captures object level activity.
So if we put an object, get object, delete object.
All of those data object related API calls that we can perform.
So we'll go ahead and select that.
And it's a good practice just to select all as three buckets.
Otherwise,
you could specify a specific bucket and we can customize what kind of
events we want to capture over here on the right.
Now the next thing we see is Lambda.
Now for Lambda.
This is going to record function level event,
this tary that's happening within our individual functions
so you can see we can log All current and future or we can
specify a function to log.
I'll leave this unchecked, but I'll leave S3 checked and let's move on.
Now The bottom part here is our storage location.
So this is what I was talking about when I was saying
we can push to a centralized bucket.
If you notice in this graphic here,
we're assuming we have an organization set up in A W s.
We have the master account with the Master CloudTrail Trail.
We have an organizational bucket for security,
auditing and logging in that master account.
And what we're doing is applying the same trail to all
sub accounts within our organization.
Now, we don't see that option up here,
but if this was a master account within an organization,
you would have an option here similar to this one that says,
Hey, I want to apply this trail to my organization.
So if you select yes to that,
it's going to create it in all your current accounts that
error sub accounts as well as future ones.
So it handles setting that up for us.
And that's really what you see in the graphic where we
configured the same trail within our sub accounts.
And both sub accounts are logging back to the central bucket in
our master account for security purposes.
This is a very common scenario,
and it's a best practice for security auditing based around CloudTrail so we
can create a new bucket here and we'll go ahead and do that.
But if we wanted to, we could select no and choose an existing bucket.
So this might be where you enter an organizational bucket.
But I'm going to click.
Yes, and let's just give this a made up bucket name really quickly.
Hopefully, that's unique.
And let's open up advanced and you can see we can
specify a few other advanced options.
We can specify a specific prefix if we want,
which is highly recommended,
especially if you're pushing several different log files to the same bucket.
A best practice is to go ahead and set up a custom prefix,
so it's easier to search through Now.
The default that's going to happen here is listed down here in the gray.
You can see it's going to be slash A.
W s logs, slash account IDE slash CloudTrail and then the region.
Now, if this was an organization account,
we would see the organization IDE within this prefix as well.
So just keep that in mind, it will look slightly different.
The next thing is we can encrypt our log files with Kms.
So this is going to allow us to encrypt all of our log files using a kms key
instead of the standard S3 encryption that this comes with.
So if we have our own customer managed key that we
want to use we can specify that here,
otherwise it's going to encrypt the files no matter what.
But it's going to use a W S s services, IT encryption within S3.
So no matter what,
you're going to have protected logs from an encryption standpoint Now,
the next part here enable log file validation is very,
very, very important.
This is a critical piece of information.
You need to know.
What this option does is it allows us to validate that our log files
have not been tampered with in any shape or form,
and a little gotcha on this option.
If you send your files to a bucket and you have this
enabled and then you move those files, it's going to notify you that Hey,
these error, not the original files.
Even if you move them back into the same bucket,
it will ruin the validation,
and it will flag it for not being a true original copy of the logs.
So if you enable this option,
be sure that you're sending it to the final destination
for your log files within your accounts.
And then, lastly,
here we have the option to send SMS notifications for every log file delivery.
Now, I don't see this option used very much,
but it is possible if you have some type of application,
such as a third-party monitoring service that has an endpoint that we
want to notify whenever log files error delivered.
So maybe that third-party security application could go
ahead and received that notification.
It parses the event that it received.
And then it goes in and collect those log files so it
can do its own custom workflow with, um And then finally,
as with every A W s resource we can ad attack.
So I'm not going to do that.
Let's click on create.
And there we go.
We now have created our trail.
Now,
an important note here is the first CloudTrail that you
make your very first custom trail is free.
Anyone's beside that are going to cost you so everyone
gets one free to customize now what you will incur costs
on is right here the S3 bucket.
So you're going to incur data costs and API call costs for storing
and delivering these objects to your buckets,
so just keep that in mind.
Now, before we wrap up here, Let's go ahead and switch our region.
Let's go to us East one and I want to check my CloudTrail trails in US East one.
And there it is.
It's the same exact trail, and you can see the home region here.
US.
East to is different than the one we're in now, us East one.
So this is already propagated all the way to the
different regions within our account.
And let's actually go ahead and in this clip here, take a short break and then we'll pick up in the next one where we left off