[Autogenerated] Okay, Welcome back.
Now picking up where we left off.
Let's go ahead and open our trails here,
and I want to go in to our trail that we just created.
So within this config screen we can see, logging is on.
So this is enabled.
We see our settings that we set here,
but what I'm looking for here is the S3 bucket.
So let me open this.
And while that loads, you can notice that it says,
Hey, last log file delivered at this particular time.
So if I go to S3,
you'll notice that it actually takes us to this specific
trails prefix that we saw earlier.
So it's our bucket that a W s logs,
theater count IDE and then CloudTrail and then within
here we have our different regions.
So let's go to us East to you can see the date is populating,
so we have year, month,
day of month and then it'll start saving files on a regular basis.
Now, these error gzip files and I actually opened one of these up.
So we can view what they look like and you can see that it's simply a JSON
file with the event that happened So this is exactly what we would see in
our CloudTrail trails under our event history.
It's just captured in a zipped up log file for consumption whenever we want,
and it's stored for a long period of time longer than the default 90 days.
Let me switch back here.
Let me close S3.
And the very last thing I want to touch on is this CloudWatch logs section
down here so we can actually push our CloudTrail events,
too.
CloudWatch.
We create a log group name here so I can call it CloudTrail.
And then, for the sake of this,
lets mimic like it's going to a bucket that's shared
with other CloudTrail accounts, and we'll give it a prefix of our account IDE.
So we should see a CloudTrail a Count IDE CloudWatch Law Group.
I'll click continue, and this brings us to a role creation screen.
So what this is saying is, Hey,
we have to create a role that will be assumed by CloudTrail
to perform these specific operations, and if you look here,
it's simply allowing us to create a log stream as well as put log
events into that log stream so we'll leave this as is,
I'll click, allow.
We get a successful message and it brings us back.
So now, at the bottom, it's validating our role and we actually got an error.
So let's go through this again.
I'll click allow or let me view details first.
Okay, I'll click allow.
And there we go.
So we just had a transient era there.
But it's fixed now.
So what this does?
It should be pushing to CloudWatch within this region.
So let me open up CloudWatch.
I'll look at my log groups and you can see we have our trail Law group here.
So if I go into this,
we'll see we have a log stream now an important note here
since we're only having this single account,
this is what it looks like account IDE CloudTrail us East to the region,
so there'll be one for each region.
But if we were part of an organization and we were
pushing to an organization law group,
what would happen here is each organization would have its own log stream.
So we can see several log streams here,
depending on the amount of sub accounts that we have.
Let's go ahead, open up this log stream and we can view events in here,
so this makes it a little bit easier to manage than downloading it from S3,
unzipping it and then viewing it from there.
And you see, it's literally what we just looked at.
It's a CloudTrail event in JSON form.
Put in as a log message.
Now, one last thing before we do.
If I go ahead and go to law groups, I select this one.
A key aspect of this is under actions.
We can do several things we can export our data to S3 as needed,
which more than likely is not necessary if you're pushing to a
singular as three bucket we can stream to a Lambda to perform
actions based on those events coming in or we can even stream to
Amazon Elastic search service.
Now,
a use case for this might be some type of dashboard that you wanna
build that quickly lays out in a visual form.
What kind of events error receiving and for Lambda
I can talk from personal experience, we have used this based on a metric filter,
so it streams events for a certain IFilter,
and when it receives that event,
it acts on it and sends either an alert or it corrects
the action during the indication.
So just remember that these options are available for you to use.
You can push CloudTrail to CloudWatch.
And then, with those law groups,
you could go ahead and stream to a Lambda Function or ELASTICSEARCH
services and these error known as subscription filters.
So just keep that in mind.
We're gonna go ahead and in this clip here and then in the next one will have a module wrap up and review.