Let's get started. You are going to create the product
presentation as a Microsoft PowerPoint document.
First,
by creating just a blank presentation and then
adding the very first slide to it.
You can follow along coding as you did in the previous modules.
I've opened up the Maven Java project that we've been
working on throughout this course.
You can get the project from the exercise files of this module
and set it up in your development environment.
When you open it up, on the ID,
you will find this class, ProductPresentation, already
created with some unimplemented methods, which we'll be
implementing along this module.
So as the first step, to create a Microsoft PowerPoint presentation,
instantiate the XMLSlideShow class like this. This class resides in
the org.apache.poi.xslf package. That consists of all the API features
required for working with .pptx PowerPoint files. Then open up
FileOutputStream, passing in the path where the files should be saved
in the file system.
Ensure that the FileOutputStream is closed after use by
surrounding it in try with resources.
Now you can go ahead and add a slide to it by calling the
createSlide method on the PowerPoint presentation object, ppt.
It will return a XSLFSlide type object.
This represents a slide in the PowerPoint presentation.
Finally,
you can write the PowerPoint presentation to the output stream
like this for it to be saved in the file system. Then in the
main class, add these lines of code.
This line of code is to load product data that should be passed
to the generateProductPresentation method here. You'll be using
that data in the upcoming clips.
So here, as you can see,
the generateProductPresentation method is called. Now save and run
the application. And you can see that a file with the .pptx extension
is created under the resources folder.
If you open the file, you can see that it has one blank slide added to it. In the next clip, you will see how to set the slide with a title layout.