Let's see what it takes to apply a layout to the
title slide of the presentation.
So what API classes and methods should we use to do this?
The XMLSlideShow class, that represents a PowerPoint presentation.
It has a method getSlideMasters.
This method gives us a list of slide masters.
A slide master is the mechanism used in Microsoft
PowerPoint to create slide templates.
These slide masters hold a bunch of slide layouts.
So by getting the first element of this list,
you can retrieve the default slide master.
So in the XSLFSlideMaster class there's the method getLayout that
can be used to retrieve a specific slide layout from the
available layouts for that slide master.
Then the XMLSlideShow class has the method createSlide
that can accept a slide layout object.
It will result in a slide created with the specified slide layout.
The resulting XSLFSlide has the method getPlaceholder,
using which you can get access to the available text shapes in the layout.
Note that a slide can have placeholders to hold content other than text as well.
These text shapes are represented by the XSLFTextShape class,
and it has a method setText. Using this method, you can set text inside those text shapes.