Metadata can also be set to other objects like PDImageXObject.
Let's say you want to set some metadata to your product images.
How can you do that?
I've added this method setImageMetaData, and in it
written basic code to load the document.
You can simply copy this document loading logic from one
of the methods that you wrote earlier.
Now, we are going to read metadata from an XML File
and set them to the image objects.
This is the XML file that we are going to use.
You can find this in the exercise file of this module.
Simply place it under the resources folder.
As you'll see, we set the title and all the metadata using the creator tag.
So, first of all,
create a File object to represent this XML file, and then open
up an InputStream on it to read its content.
We need to create a PDMetadata object that represents PDF document metadata.
This time,
let's use the constructor, passing in the product
catalog document and the InputStream.
This will read everything in the InputStream and
embed them into the PDF document.
Then the PDMetadata object that we create will consist of
the metadata saved in the XML file.
Now, say you want to save this metadata to the product images in
the first page of the product catalog PDF.
So get the first page.
Now, you saw in the Modify the Already Created PDF Document
module that the way to access resources like images in a PDF
document is to use the PDResources.
So get the resources of the first page. Then looping through the
resources, you can access the images in the first page.
This code is straight from the earlier module,
Modifying the Already Created PDF Document.
Once you get a PDImageXObject,
you can simply set the PDMetadata to it by calling the setMetadata method,
passing in the PDMetadata object, meta, to it. Once again, remember to save
the document after doing these changes to it.
Now when this method is called,
the metadata title and author should get attached to
the product image. There is, in fact,
no way to see this unless you write code to read them.
Let's quickly add this code to read the image metadata that you just set.
You can find the code for this method on the exercise files.
Simply copy and paste it to your ProductCatalog class like this.
Now, add this line to read the metadata of the image.
To read the image metadata, let's create an InputStream on the
metadata object. Then create a new InputStreamReader object for
it, and a BufferedReader so that you can read lines from the
buffer and print them out like this.
Now if you call both these methods in the main class, and run,
you should see the metadata extracted from the three images like this.
This is the title and author metadata that we added to the images using the XML file.