Hi everyone.
My name is Buddhini Samarakkody, and welcome to my course,
Apache API Integration in Java Fundamentals.
I'm a software developer, a teacher, and an independent consultant,
and I enjoy sharing my knowledge with others.
PDFBox and POI are Apache's leading open source Java APIs for working with PDF
documents and Microsoft documents. This course is great if you are a beginner
who's looking to learn how to integrate Apache PDFBox and POI APIs in your Java
applications, and you'll only need to be familiar with the Java language
fundamentals. Some of the major topics that we will cover include essentials of
PDFBox and POI APIs, configure the development environment, create and modify
PDF and Microsoft documents, extract content from documents, and a few advanced
usages.
By the end of this course,
you will have the skills and knowledge of integrating Apache PDFBox and POI
APIs that are needed to work with PDF and Microsoft documents in a Java
application of any scale. Before beginning the course,
you should be familiar with Java basics.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn Apache PDFBox
and POI APIs with the Apache API Integration in Java Fundamentals course, at Pluralsight.