Hello, I'm Buddhini Samarakkody,
and I'll be your guide for this course on Apache API
Integration in Java Fundamentals.
Generating documents from your Java application can be really interesting,
but of course,
if you know what APIs are there to help you and how to work with them.
Welcome, and thanks for choosing to take this course,
where you'll learn how to use Apache APIs to generate PDF and
Microsoft documents in a Java application.
First things first,
let's take a glance at what you're about to experience in
this module and the course as a whole.
Pause for a moment.
I know what's on your mind right now.
You're probably thinking,
why would I want to watch this course? What's in it for me?
I get it.
You need the motivation to go ahead with this course,
and this module will do just that.
Then what can you expect in this course?
You'll soon see what the agenda of this course looks like.
Then the next question, how will you learn them?
Well, I'll tell you the story on which this course is based upon,
the prerequisites,
and about the software tools you'll need to have in place
to follow this course successfully.
Last but not least,
I'll show you how to get yourself started without wasting much time.
Generating documents is a pretty common requirement in any Java application.
You've probably come across that requirement right now,
and that could be the reason why you're here watching
this course in the first place.
The common document formats you'll need to generate from
your application are PDFs and the Microsoft Office
documents like Excel spreadsheets, Word documents,
and PowerPoint slides.
In a Java application,
we are specifically talking about standalone and web applications here.
PDFs can be generated using the iText library or the PDFBox library.
Microsoft Office documents can be created using the POI library.
PDFBox and POI are PO Java,
and open source APIs from the Apache Software Foundation.
Both APIs are extremely popular among Java developers
are used in enterprise applications. I'd say this is exactly why you should be learning how to work with these APIs.