Next up is adding a header, footer, and page numbers to the quotation,
using the Header, Footer, and HeaderFooter classes.
It should be noted that the header and footer will
appear in the Print view like this, and when the document is printed.
To add a header and footer to the quotation,
in the generateQuotation method, create a header object like this.
You can set what needs to be displayed on the left‑hand side of the header,
and the right‑hand side of the header.
Similarly, create a quota object.
Set text to be displayed in the center this time,
and let's display the page numbers on the right‑hand side.
As you can see, we use the Header/Footer class to retrieve the current page,
and the number of pages.
Now, if you run, open the quotation Excel sheet,
and go to the Print view, you can see the header, footer, and page numbers applied.