Once again, we've come to an end of another module,
so it's worth noting some key takeaways.
Remember to use the addTab method of XWPFRun class to add tab
space inside a text run or a range of text.
Then use the addBreak method of the same class to add an explicit
line break in the text run whenever you want.
When you call the createTable method on the document,
it creates an empty table with one row and one column added to it by default.
CreateRow method adds a new row to a table with as many cells
as the number of existing columns in it.
Also keep in mind that the setWidth method of XWPFTable and
XWPFTableCell accepts width as 20ths of a point,
so you need to pass in a value that complies with the fact that
one typographical point is equal to 1440 inches.
Retrieve and use the default paragraph in the table cell using the
getParagraphArray method when you want to format cell content.
To wrap things up in this module,
you learned how to work with an MS Word document using the
Apache POI API by creating a blank document and adding
paragraphs of content to it, adding formatting to paragraph content,
adding an image, a table, and formatting table cell content,
and last but not least, extract text, table data,
and image content from a Word document.
As always, don't forget to pay attention to the key takeaways.
We've almost reached the end of the journey with the Apache POI API by
creating and modifying an MS Word document in this module, and we have the final module of the course next.