Since the slides look boring,
let's format the text content on the product slides by setting the font
type, font color, font size, and make some of the text bold.
Doing that is pretty simple.
Let's see how to do that. Back in the code, go to the place where
you added the product name in the addProductSlide method. That's
right here. Call the setFontColor method on the nameRun. You can
pass a java.awt.Color to it.
Let's pass in BLUE, then set the font size.
You need to pass it as a double literal.
Next, let's format the bulleted list to have red font.
So here, set the font color to RED.
One more thing to note here.
If you want to change the bullet character to some
other character of your choice,
you can do that by calling the setBulletCharacter method,
passing in the required character as a string. Try giving
an asterisk, for example, and see how it looks like.
Then go to the price text.
Let's show the price in a different font. For that, call the
setFontFamily method on the run. Pass in the font family name as a
string, let's say Courier New. You can pass in any valid font name here
as a string, then the font color to MAGENTA.
Make it bold by calling setBold method and passing in true. And the
font size, set to 34 to make it a bit bigger. We need to do one more
thing to make our presentation look better.
Remember,
you created a header slide earlier to be used as a separator. Separator
slides should be added before each new product category and type. For that,
let's set this code in the addContentSlides method right here inside the for
loop. What it does is it's checking for the product category and type, as we
have products belonging to two categories, FURNITURE and DECO. And under the
DECO category, there are product types, Lamp Shades and Wall Clocks.
So in the loop,
when it encounters a product that belongs to a new category and type,
call the addSectionHeaderSlide method like this to add a section
header slide. These flags are used simply to avoid the header slide
from being added after each slide,
but to add them to a group of slides as required instead.
Now save and run the application.
You can see the product slides have the text formatted now with colors,
font sizes, and different font types.
Also,
you can see that the section header slides have been added before the slides,
displaying each category and type of products.
You can see the products sorted by category and type because of the code that
was added back in addContentSlides method when adding section header slides for products based on their category and type.