Coming to an end of another interesting module,
let me summarize what you learned in this module.
You learned why and how to use metadata properties in a PDF document by
setting metadata to the Product Catalog document.
You also saw how to create variations in fonts by setting different
fonts in the catalog PDF document, next, about splitting and merging
PDF documents by splitting the Product Catalog PDF into two separate
PDF files and merging them back together to form one single PDF
document, and last, but not least,
about protecting a PDF by specifying access permissions
and adding passwords to the Product Catalog document using
standard protection policy.
So those are some of the important advanced options that can
be used with the PDFBox API that could be of help to you
when working with PDF documents.
Where are we now in the learning journey?
As I said at the beginning of this module,
you have now reached a milestone where you've completed the
Apache PDFBox API part of the course.
It would be beneficial to recap at this milestone. You started off by
learning the essential API features of the PDFBox API, configured the
development environment by setting up the required JAR files, and then
created your very first PDF document and added content to it. Thereafter,
you loaded the already created PDF,
modified and extracted content from it, and finally, used some of the
advanced features like metadata, splitting and merging a PDF, and
protecting a PDF document. That marks the end of this module. And stay
tuned for the next half of the course where you will be learning about
Apache POI API integration, starting with the module, Outlining the Essentials of Apache POI Library.