Let's go ahead and create hyperlinks for the web and email addresses.
First, add the last slide to the presentation. Then, add hyperlinks
for web address and the email address.
Back in the code, go to the generateProductPresentation method, and here, go
ahead and create another slide using the same titleLayout.
This is going to be the last slide in the presentation.
This slide will have two text boxes.
Let's get the first one, and set the text, THANK YOU! on it.
Then, get hold of the next text box,
set the company name like this on it, and below it, to display the
contact number, add a new paragraph and a text run.
Let's set the font size to be 14, and set the text like this.
Add another paragraph and a text run on it,
set its font size also to be 14, and set this text.
Now to make the email a hyperlink,
create a hyperlink on the run by calling createHyperlink method.
It will return a XSLF hyperlink object. Set the link address
by calling the setAddress on the hyperlink object, passing in
the mailto address, like this.
Next,
follow the same steps to make the web address a hyperlink. Create the paragraph,
create the run,
set the font size to be 14, set the text, create the
hyperlink, and finally, set the address.
That's all it takes to create hyperlinks on a slide.
Now save and run. You can see the last slide added to the presentation with the
content that was created in it, and notice that the email and web addresses are formatted as hyperlinks, and they are clickable.