To add an image to an Excel workbook,
you need to follow these steps. Provided that you already have a workbook and
a sheet added to it, first, open up an input stream to the image file, and
read the desired image data into a byte array.
For this,
you can use the helper method, toByteArray, available in
org.apache.poi.util.IOUtils class.
After that,
you should add the image to the workbook by calling the
addPicture method on the workbook,
passing in the image by data, and the type of image, for
example, Workbook.PICTURE_TYPE_JPEG.
The addPicture method returns an integer,
which is the 0‑based index of the picture, with respect to the entire workbook.
This is required later for you to position the image
in the worksheet of your choice.
Next, you need to create the drawing canvas that will hold the image.
This is called as the Drawing Patriarch,
which is like the parent container that holds all shapes in a worksheet.
In this case,
the shape is the picture. To do that, call the
createDrawingPatriarch method on the worksheet. Thereafter, an
anchor point should be defined for the picture.
Anchor point is nothing but the row and column for the top‑left position of
the picture. You create the anchor point, or in other words,
the client anchor, with the help of a creation helper. Using the
anchor, specify the starting column where the picture is going to start
drawing its cell, and also the starting row,
which is the top‑left corner position of the picture.
Now you can call the createPicture method on the drawing canvas, or the
patriarch, passing in the anchor point and the picture index that you
got before, when adding it to the workbook.
It returns a picture object.
Finally,
you can call the resize method on the picture. This authorizes the picture
relative to the top‑left position specified earlier, to adjust its size to
feed the available space in that area of the worksheet, so that it can correctly render on the workbook.