In this demo, you'll remove the last slide of the product
presentation. For that, first, load the existing presentation,
and then remove the last slide of it, and finally,
save the changes. Back in the code, once again,
go to the removeLastSlide method.
Follow the steps that you just saw.
First,
create a FileInpuStream to the product presentation file.
Then create a new XMSSlideShow object, passing it as usual.
Then call the removeSlide method on the ppt.
Now, since we want to remove the last slide of the presentation,
let's say ppt.getSlides,
which gives the list of slides. Then call size to get the number of slides
and ‑1 to compute the slide index of the last slide.
Open a FileOutputStream to the file. Write the changes made to the
PowerPoint to the OutputStream for it to be saved. Now, call this method
in the main class, save and run the application. You can see that the last slide of the presentation is now not there.