In this final demo of the module,
we are going to see how to read the data in a few
cells of the quotation document.
You will retrieve the quotation date, extract the logo image,
and read the web link.
Let's take a quick look at what it takes to read cell data.
Open InputStream to Excel file, create a workbook,
get the sheet that you want to extract data from,
get the required row object, get the required cell object,
and finally,
you can read the cell values. To read image data, the
first two steps would be the same.
Then get all the pictures in the workbook. Then retrieve the
picture from the list of pictures, if it's just one picture. In
case of multiple pictures in the workbook,
you will need to traverse through the list of pictures and get the required one.
Next, read picture data into a byte array, and finally,
write the data to the OutputStream.
Reading hyperlinks is easy.
Simply follow the first five steps that you saw earlier used to
read data from any cell, and then, read the hyperlink of the cell
by calling cell.getHyperlink method.
Now to demonstrate this, back in the code, add this method,
readQuoteDate. As the first step, open a file InputStream on the
Excel file, like this. Then create the workbook by calling
WorkbookFactory.create, passing in the InputStream.
Get the first sheet of the workbook.
The quotation date is in row index 6, and cell index 10.
Then you can retrieve the cell value as a date
value or string value, as required.
Let's get it as a date value and print it to the console.
Run the application, you should see the date printed like this. Now to
read the logo image, add this method, readLogoImage.
The first two steps are the same.
Then get all pictures in the workbook.
It will be returned as a list.
Since the list has exactly one element, you can simply get it like this.
Read the picture data into a byte array. Finally, create an
OutputStream to write it into the file system, and write
the image data to the stream.
In case if there are multiple images in the workbook,
the list will have multiple elements,
in which case, you will have to traverse through them, and
retrieve the image that you are looking for.
You can filter them by the file extension, mime type, or the picture type.
Now save and run.
You can see under resources, images folder, the logo
image with the given file name, created.
This is the image that was extracted from the quotation Excel document.
Finally,
to read the web address hyperlink, add this method. Then inside,
add the code for the basic steps, and then read the hyperlink of
the cell by calling getHyperlink method.
A hyperlink object will be returned, and you can print out its address like
this to the console by calling the getAddress method. When you run it, you can see the web address printed in the console, like this.