Before all that excitement starts,
we need to look at the basic API features for
creating a PDF and adding content to it.
A PDF document is made of a stream of different object types
This object system is known as the COS model.
In other words, COS model is the low level object structure of a PDF
document. In the Apache PDFBox API, these objects are represented by
the org.apache.pdfbox.cos package.
It contains these low level objects, and it's called the COS model.
The COS model is helpful for developers who want to work
directly with low level PDF objects. Using the COS model, all
aspects of a PDF document can be accessed.
However, since this is a low level object model,
programming with it is quite tedious, and it's not very developer‑friendly.
Therefore, another API was introduced called PD model,
which is a developer‑friendly, high level API built on top of the COS model.
The PD model API is available in the
org.apache.pdfbox.pdmodel package in the PDFBox API.
The PD model is built on top of the COS model as another
layer and another level of abstraction,
which is high level. So you need not worry about dealing with
any of the complexities of the COS model.
The API feature is required to create a new PDF document to add a
page and add lines of text and other basic content to it, all located
in the org.apache.pdfbox.pdmodel package.
It has PDDocument, PDPage, and PDPageContentStream classes to handle all of this.