Here's the roadmap to your learning journey.
In the first part of this course,
you'll learn how to integrate the Apache PDFBox API to your Java application.
As the first step, you'll configure the API in a Java project.
Then go ahead and create your very first PDF document.
Go a few more steps ahead and modify the PDF document that you created.
And finally, you'll spend some time looking at some advanced features of the API.
Hope the journey's quite interesting so far.
The second half of the course is dedicated to the Apache POI API.
Your starting point will be to configure the API,
and thereafter you'll go straight ahead to work with Microsoft
Office documents by creating and modifying Excel,
Word, and PowerPoint documents.
By the end of this course,
you'll have mastered Apache PDFBox and POI API integrations in Java.
Now, let's take a look at the agenda of the first part of the course.
First up is Apache PDFBox.
You will outline the essentials of the Apache PDFBox library in
terms of what it offers you, its components, and common
applications. Configure the development environment to be able
to use it in a Java application.
Thereafter,
you will create your very first PDF document and start adding content to it.
Then you'll see how to modify and already create a PDF by loading,
extracting content, and removing pages from it.
Finally, you will get to explore some advanced features of PDFBox,
like using metadata properties, using different points in your documents,
splitting and merging PDFs and protecting a PDF by encrypting it.
Next up in the agenda is the Apache POI. As usual,
first outline the essentials of the library, and then you'll go
ahead and configure the development environment by using the
library in your Java application.
Next,
you will work with a Microsoft Excel document and a Microsoft
Word document and a PowerPoint document, respectively, by creating, adding formatting to them, and modifying them.