Now let's get to work.
Let's create the product catalog PDF.
In this demo,
you will see how to create an empty PDF document and then
add a page to it. Open up your IDE with the Maven project
that you configured earlier.
Here it is.
Let's first add a new Java class, ProductCatalog.
In this, I'm going to add a method generateCatalog. Inside the method,
we are going to add code to generate our catalog PDF. The
first step is to create an empty PDF document.
For that,
we need to use the PDDocument class that resides in
org.apache.pdfbox.pdmodel package.
You can view this API document from this URL right here.
So let's create an object named catalog of type PDDocument.
Now,
we need to ensure that this document object is closed
after we are done with using it.
We can do that in many ways,
but let's use the try‑with‑resources syntax here. Surround
the document object with try‑with‑resource.
The resource PDDocument implements the AutoCloseable interface, as you can
see here. So we can use the try with resource with it.
And then we need to add a catch block to handle the
IOException thrown by the resource.
So let's add that. Next, let's go ahead and add a page to this
PDDocuments. For that, create a page object from PDPage class.
Let's call it firstPage. Then add the page to the document that you
created by calling catalog.addPage, passing the page object to it. Now
save the catalog PDF in the file system. For that, call the save method
on the catalog document. You need to pass in the file name as a string
to the save method.
Let's save the catalog PDF file inside the resources folder under main,
which I've already added. So let's give src/main/resources and the PDF
file name as product_catalog.pdf, printing to the console that the
document creation was successful. To see the outcome, I will call the
generateCatalog method in the main class. Now run it, and you can see the empty PDF document created as you had expected.