You know, every journey is backed by some story.
Now here's the story for this learning journey.
Here you are, newly recruited as a software developer in a software firm.
You're assigned to work on a project of a new client who's a
reputed furniture and appliance store in town.
They need an ERP system, and in a few modules,
there's a requirement to generate some documents.
In the e‑commerce module, it should generate a product catalog as a PDF document.
The sales module needs a quotation generator,
as both Microsoft Excel and Word documents as required.
The marketing module should generate Microsoft PowerPoint slides for
product presentations for managers to be used at meetings.
Now, your task is to generate these documents using Apache APIs.
The head of technology has decided to use Apache PDFBox and POI libraries.
You've worked on many Java projects before,
but the problem is you have no prior experience using
these libraries in a Java project.
So you're wondering how to get hands‑on quickly with these APIs and be able
to show your colors as a new recruit. To get hands‑on with Apache PDFBox and
POI libraries, you need these as prerequisites.
You will need to know fundamentals of the Java language,
basic knowledge of Apache Maven, and the ability to work with an IDE. I'd
recommend you have these tools in place too, so that you can easily follow
along with this course, Java Standard Edition 11, or it could be a higher
version than that, Apache Maven 3.6.3,
which is the latest at the time of recording this course, and IntelliJ IDEA Community edition, preferably Version 2020.1.