In the final demo of this module, you will display the product price in a box.
To do this,
you will draw a rectangular box and write the product price
within that box. To add a rectangle to the PDF,
you can call the addRect method on the content stream.
You have to pass in the X and Y coordinates as usual,
and the width and the height of the rectangular box.
Let's give a value of 300 for the X coordinate,
and since it should be placed a little bit higher than the
starting point Y coordinate of the image,
which is imageY, let's add 125 units to eat and set 50 and 25 as its dimensions.
Now the box should be filled with black color.
Whenever you want to specify a fill color,
you should set the non‑stroking color.
So let's say content.setNon StrokingColor to Color.BLACK, and
then color it by calling the fill method.
This should draw a black box below the product features.
We need to display the price of the product within this box.
For that, we should start adding text to the stream.
So, add another beginText and endText call, and in between,
set the font. You can set the font and the size to a different one if you wish.
I'm just setting it to be the same. But I want to set the text color to white.
So the way to do that is to set the non‑stroking color to white.
Then to position the text, call the newLineAtOffset method.
I'm setting X to be 300 + 10 more units, and Y to be
imageY + 133 units to be precise.
You will need to play around a bit with these
coordinates to get the exact positioning,
Then the text to display inside the box is the product price rounded and
prepended with the dollar symbol. Done. Now save and run.
Here's the PDF that we wanted to create.
Congratulations! You just created the product catalog PDF document using
PDFBox. Just a thing for you to try, if you would like the rectangular box
to have no fill color, but just an outline color,
instead of setting non‑stroking color,
set the stroking color. Set to red, and then call the stroke method instead of fill method and see what happens.