If you'd like to automatically translate information from
JSR‑303 annotations like @NotNull, @Min,
@Max, and @Size into your Swagger models,
you'll need to add an additional dependency and
import on your configuration class.
The springfox‑bean‑validators library adds this capability.
Add that to your POM and import the
BeanValidatorPluginsConfiguration class on your Swagger configuration
class.
You'll then see information in the Swagger UI that is derived from these
four annotations, without needing to add anything extra.
Note that if you're using the ApiModelProperty annotation along with one of
these four annotations, ApiModelProperty takes precedence.
For example, if department is @NotNull and you just add a description,
then nothing will show up in the Swagger UI to
indicate that this is a required value.
In this case,
you would need to add the required = true value to the ApiModelProperty
in order for the required indicator to show up in the Swagger UI. If
you've added other services and methods,
you can use Swagger annotations to provide additional
documentation in the Swagger UI. For example,
the @ApiOperation annotation allows you to add a value that
appears by the endpoint in the Swagger UI, as well as some notes that appear below the method.