Now that you've added Springfox to your project with the
Swagger UI and default configurations,
let's customize some API‑level attributes. We'll do this using the ApiInfo
object when we create a Docket to add things like description,
version, and contact info.
Here's the Springfox website that has links to documentation
and the source code for your reference.
The ApiInfo object is easier to see in the project itself,
so we'll jump right into the demo. We'll customize the API‑level
information here in our Configuration class when we create the Docket.
We can add a call to ApiInfo, then define a method to create our
ApiInfo object. We'll utilize the ApiInfoBuilder to add some things
like title, version, description, contact info, and email.
If your API has a specific license, you can add
that as well. And we'll build it.
Let's go ahead and restart our application and see how the
API‑level information changes at the top of our Swagger UI. Our
application has restarted, and we'll refresh our Swagger UI. Here
we have our new title, Employee API,
and the version that we set, 1.0. Notice our description,
API for managing employees, and the contact
information that we added, Craig Golightly.
If we check out the website, we'll see globomantics.com, and
the email is going to craig@globomantics.com.
We can also see the license that we put in, the Apache License
Version 2.0. Modifying the properties in your ApiInfo object is a
really easy way to customize your Swagger UI and make it match the
information for your API.
You can now add Springfox to your project with a few easy
configurations and have the Swagger UI display documentation
generated from your Spring Data REST project.
You can also customize some API‑level attributes that display in
the Swagger UI. Join me in the next module where we will look at
additional customizations you can make, including how to document multiple versions of your API.