If you want to have multiple versions of your documentation available in
a single Swagger UI, you can use Swagger groups to accomplish this.
Groups are configured in the Docket object.
You'll simply call groupName and provide a name for the group. From
the Swagger UI, you can then select from groups you have defined to
see the documentation for that group.
If your code is in the same code base,
you can utilize PathSelectors to filter endpoints from each version
into different Docket objects with different groups.
Let's look at an example of using Swagger groups to
create multiple Docket objects,
each with a different group, and PathSelectors to
filter endpoints for a specific version.
We can then see how you can switch from one group to another in the
Swagger UI. Here's an example of a Docket that is using a groupName. In
this particular class we're creating three different Dockets,
employeeApi1, employeeApi2, and employeeApi2.
We've put a different groupName for each Docket,
and we've also put a different path selector for each Docket. We've also
modified to getApiInfo method to accept a version number.
This will set the version number on the title of the Swagger.
UI based on the version that's passed in. If you were
maintaining multiple methods in the same code base based
on different request mappings, this is what that would look like.
Notice the difference between getSchedule1 and getSchedule2.
The RequestMapping value has a different path,
employeev1/schedule versus employeev2/schedule.
We've also defined one for version 3 and the return message is
different in all 3 so we can see it in action from the Swagger UI
when we call this endpoint. Notice now in the Swagger UI there's a
drop‑down box to select a definition.
The three different Swagger groups that we defined all appear here,
and we can switch between the three. For v1, notice the title is
employee‑api‑v1, and our example service has the v1 path.
If we switch it to v2, notice how the version on our
documentation title has changed to employee‑api‑v2,
as well as the URI for the example service method.
And when we switch to v3, we can see the v3. Let's run the GET
method for each of these three services. Notice the response
here, Your v3 schedule is T‑F 8‑6.
Now let's run v2. Your v2 schedule is M‑W 9‑9. And v1. And
finally, we can see the v1 schedule is M‑F 9‑5.
Swagger groups are a good option if you need to host multiple groups on
the same Swagger UI. Congratulations, you've seen how to leverage
annotations for additional documentation like the bean validator library
for JSR‑303 annotations, as well as some Swagger annotations like
ApiModelProperty and ApiOperation.
You've also seen how to handle documentation for different versions of
your API with tools like PathSelectors and Swagger groups. You're now
ready to add great documentation to your API using Swagger and SpringFox
with very little configuration.
The best part is it's based off your code, so it's easier to keep up to date. I hope you have found this valuable, and thank you for watching.