Hello and welcome to the installation Tauriel for Mac OS.
So first thing you want to do in order to install those rescue well and yardman is to open a browser
of your choice.
For me it's Google Chrome so you can see already how it opened up.
And then now all you want to do is to type in a great as well.
Or they need to go to this website.
Alternatively you can just search in Google for download but best Cuil.
This is the same result you will get the top result.
So on the landing page you need to press download.
After that you need to select Mac OS X because we're working with Mac operating system here we need
to say like the interactive installer by enterprise DB click on the modem installer button.
This will load up a new Web site an external Web so of enterprise D.B no worry about that.
Just make sure that when you download the bus ride ask you all you Bresson Mac OS and that that version
does not have Bayda in front of it because then you might run into some bugs.
So as we can see right now version 9 points 6.1 is the newest version and there is no beta.
So that is the most ideal scenario for us.
Just click.
Mac OS X did and will start now.
This will take some time so I'll just beat you up through the process.
All right so not a Darkfall finished to boating.
All you need to do is to click on it or select your Downloads folder and just double click and this
will open this menu.
So just not all they can ask you will not click open until your passport and just give it a second set
of it is being run right now.
So you can see that it is inside of here.
Next remembered this address.
It might come in useful later on.
Then you press yes.
Did you vote for this 5 for free too.
And.
All right.
So us yes.
Next now is Salling.
It does not thing that much time at all.
So you can see the installation is pretty quick.
So in this word it's unloaded the rescue all and began when are installed automatically at the same
time so you don't have to go to that website and from there.
And that's the beauty of this install or so just like one click away from me getting straight into where
easily.
So now you can play on that later.
For now just click Finish close this and now we go for play search and enter Jasmine.
There it is.
It's all loading up so now that we open it we see that there are no mistakes no server errors nothing
bad we have the servers we have to play rescue well being connected to.
And that's awesome.
Congratulations you just installed pgm and for and rescue all on your Mac operating system.