Hello and welcome back.
Today we'll be learning about comments in Microsoft Escudo server as you can see you have Microsoft
SQL Server Management Studio open up ready to go.
As always I have my consumer complaints database and it's over the consumer complaints table.
So let's go ahead and quickly run a query.
So just click the query here.
Select all from consumer and consumer complaints.
Now I'm going to execute it.
Sorry about that.
Just let's say I'm going to actually get to see what data I have inside of it and start working on my
bigger.
So let's say I want to add some more code in here that will say Alster table consumer complaints ad
column
and I want to free one free of data type load updates consumer complaints table set one to free on the
free to be equal to 22 just something like that.
It might make sense to you just like writing down some crazy weird code but basically what we're going
to be working today with is comments.
So there's not that many applications of Commons and ask you all as well as any other programming languages
as far as I've encountered Commins are mostly used in two stations.
The first one is if you're a debugging code and you're trying to understand where exactly the issue
is or what's going wrong or was going actually good what do you want to do then is to comment out different
parts of the code until you find your issue or your animality to us what you need to do is dash dash
star and then at the end where you want to end your comment you could star Bash our star slash.
So now you can see it all lit up in green.
That means it's common.
And that means nothing will happen so we just execute it.
As you can see nothing happened.
This car wasn't even read.
No columns are created on the stakes were given.
Now if you want to go ahead and move forward as you can see if I don't close the star slash then the
comment will be infinite and that will obviously be very inconvenient for us so always remember that
when you open a star you can also close star slash.
Now you can put them in infinite amount of comments inside the same Querrey Just remember to always
close them.
Now there's a second way of using comments and I would say it's more commonly used when it's actually
coming something out.
So this is the second type of comments just by double slash and basically everything right.
Of the double slash on the same row will become a column.
So as you can see update here is not comment.
Then they can write here comment and then I can set a comment here where I want to continue my forte
which will say something like make sure there's no mistakes here and then all I need to do is run it
and everything will run correctly.
Of course if we just get rid of this code and this code just because there was comments so as you can
see these comments work on row level on every line level and they only come in out riffing right of
it.
So double dash is mostly used to leave yourself useful notes or tips or if you have to finish your work
and you're afraid you will remember what you were thinking about tomorrow.
You can always say that hey remember remember to check for null or something like that.
Also very important when you're collaborating with other people and you give them your code for them
not to come to you and ask you all the questions and for you to resolve them you can just leave them
some useful comments to explain what you want to do with your.
Call it what it needs to do and so forth.
So you can see comments are very simple very easy topic and ask you all.
It's definitely not the one that's necessary to know in order to run your queries but it's definitely
a useful tool from time to time.
I hope you enjoy this lecture.
I hope you enjoyed the section.
I hope you enjoyed working with this fundamental basic very important functions.
I hope you have no questions and you had any results.
All of them.
And I most of them are in the hope that you're looking forward to writing more queries later on in this
course because there is much more we need to practice there's much more we need to do and there is much
more you need to learn.
I hope you enjoy this later and I'll see in the next one.