Hello and welcome back.
We hope that you enjoyed the previous section and in this section we're talking about the data attacks
and ask you all through all these tutorials You'll learn everything about integers floats for chairs
and lots of other data types and how to convert between them.
We'll even talk about nodes and how to deal with missing data in your data set data set for this section
is all about console games and console platforms.
It's a very interesting dataset that presents quite a few challenges.
My personal favorite lecture in this section is about working with states.
It really shows you the power base data type.
In today's world I hope to see you inside.