Hello and welcome back.
And today we'll be talking about structured versus unstructured data.
So when you think about structure data what's the first thing that comes to mind for me it's a table.
Just a simple table with different attributes and tuples filled with proper relation.
That does not contradict any rules that you as a user have said or in the rules of database that a certain
database have to be preserved certain primary keys and foreign keys have to be assigned and so on.
Now what do you think about unstructured data.
What was the first thing that comes to mind.
For me it's music movies pictures.
Then it becomes a bit more difficult because if you think about it if structured data is only represented
by Escuela tables unstructured data is everything else.
So you can say that Mac Finder window or Windows Explorer is in fact your data.
And you can even argue that Microsoft Excel is still unstructured data even though it offers such a
high level of data control of data manipulation.
It is still unstructured data just because Eskew all database gives us so much more control gives us
so much more efficiency and gives us so much more space to work with the data unstructured data is rich
data meaning it contains a lot of information that normally can't be represented neatly on a database.
And that is good for users because the Loveridge data would you rather read the script of the movie
or would you rather watch it.
Of course you would rather watch it.
And that's what people prefer.
That's why more than 80 percent of data out there right now is unstructured.
So why do companies still keep using structured data and maintain their Eskew all databases.
Well this is due to the fact that even though unstructured data is so popular it's almost impossible
to manipulate.
It's almost impossible to get results from it.
Almost impossible to analyze.
Now there are more and more services and applications being developed to analyze unstructured data but
the day when we can truly work with rich data as good as we're working we've asked you all databases
right now is not anywhere near this implicity is the power of structured data.
If you put all the data inside of it correctly and then correct drools and restrains you can perform
any sort of analysis on it.
Almost always getting the right results so under that vantages of structure data while the first one
is data consistency because you put in all the data in a simple table with very defined rules it will
maintain that way till the end of your project.
And the other thing that you get from using a secure databases is that you can get more information
from the same data just because all of it is neatly organized.
The amount of tools you can use and the demand of analysis you can perform and that data rises significantly.
What is more you have improved data integrity.
If you define older rules correctly and if you do not make any user input mistakes then your data will
never be compromised.
There will never be a question of it being lost or corrupted.
And then we also have improved security just because database are much smaller working with text based
files rather than movies and music.
You can assign a lot of security checks Movado sacrificing the efficiency of your database.
And finally you have improved maintenance just because your database take Baldwin Hymes less disk space.
It means that your queries can run almost 1000 times quicker and this means you can do regular check
ups on your database anytime you want and you can always know what's happening with your data where
it's stored and you can always perform up to date backups.
So when it comes to data analysis structured data upwards are so much more both in terms of storing
the data and analyzing it that companies will keep using it no matter what users want.
Because even though users want to see movies and they hear music companies will never sacrifice the
efficiency and the integrity.
It's much much much easier to work with a text based table where everything is a sign and everything
is in proper place then to work with very huge files filled with data that you cannot possibly organize.
Even though now more and more unstructured data application and tools are being created on the market
companies will never give up on structured data for both internal analysis and external I hope you enjoyed
today's lecture and understood the difference between structured and unstructured data.
It is a very very interesting topic and it's definitely the one that's evolving up to this day and it
will be changing even more as time goes.
But again as I said structured data will always be needed and ask Will will always be relevant.
However if you ever do decide to get into unstructured data that is a very broad topic we have a lot
of interesting points in it.
So I highly recommend taking out.
I hope you enjoyed today's lecture and I'll see you in the next one.