Hello and welcome back to the course on databases now that we've looked at several different types of
Joines it's time to move on to more complex things.
And today we're going to talk about joining on multiple fields and let's get started.
I'm going to create a new part and here we're going to say joining joining on multiple fields and what
we want to do is we want to take our procedure history table and join into the procedure Details table
so I'll explain why we want to do that so that selects our for all procedure history whoops history
history.
There you go.
Go get your colon and run that.
And so here we've got the procedure history we've got the parody with the procedure date with the procedure
type and the procedure subacute.
Right.
And this table does carry information tells you which pad on which date had a procedure what type of
procedure in the sub code but it is still very very secretive right.
So it doesn't tell you while on the Pet side it doesn't tell you the pet name the owner name the owner
or address and so on and that's fair enough right.
So because not everybody needs to know that information that information doesn't have to be disclosed
all the time.
And moreover these tables are local and so and so that's kind of a privacy protection purposes probably
And also the correct way of setting up a database.
On the other hand you've got the procedure type.
So even if you don't want to know the name of the pet but you want to know what procedure they had you
can't really get to a genome that say this pet had a vaccination on the 16th January of 2016.
But you don't really know what kind of vaccination it was was in a rabies vaccination was it a different
type vaccination.
Pets have lots of different types of vaccination so there was an earth though paid sick procedure for
this pet.
And you AGAIN don't know exactly the code.
And again this could be due to privacy reasons or some other reasons but or more so that it's it's more
efficient way to structure a database.
But regardless of what the reason behind it is how do we solve this problem.
How do we get to the actual description of the procedure that happened for each pet.
Well for that we have another table we have the table which is called procedure history procedure details.
So if I just take this and up here and say procedure details and I run this you'll see that in this
table we've got 41 rows.
So it's a small table but this table is like a glossary.
So here we've got the actual history of what happened.
But then if you want to find out more it's like a dictionary right.
Then you you look up that specific procedure in this procedure Details table and for instance vaccination
type 5 is rabies indeed.
But as you can see there's all these other different types of vaccinations that pets can have an orthopedic
type fire which we saw was a elex patella repair so you know something else and that's these that veterinarians
do for pets.
And here you actually even have the price of the procedure so you can look up not only that description
but the price as well.
And so our challenge for today or in fact this is going to be your challenge so I I propose to you that
we are we are venturing into new territory we're venturing into joining in multiple fields but we've
already spoken about that in theory tutorials and we know quite a lot about Joines.
So my suggestion to you is pose this video and try to join these two tables together and see what you
come up with.
And your hint is that you will require multiple fields right so you can join them in one field but probably
the results are going to be correct since we're going into this topic of multiple fields so if you want
to get some additional hands on experience and I highly encourage you to pause the video right now and
give this a go see see how you go how you can join these two tables and then just play the video again
and see how your result compares to what I'm going to demonstrate in this tutorial.
So now I'm going to proceed.
So three to one.
Let's put this together.
So how would I go about joining these two tables.
So let's figure of sort of where we're going we forget that we're doing multiple fields.
We're just going to look at or know some some obvious way that we would join these and we would say
All right so we've got our parody procedure day procedure type and procedure sub code right.
So how about we join on the procedure sub code.
So it take select everything from procedure history and we will say what type of joint Do we want here.
Well in this case we want a left join and we want to join the procedure details and we want to join
on.
So this is going to be as a as b a dot procedure sub code equals B dog.
So what is this field called in the second table that we're joining on we want to join in this field.
You'll see that it is that description this one is probably called the same thing prestigious upcard
is always good to check.
So the procedure subgoals So now I'm going to put the call on here and if we were on this.
So let's quickly have a look at the procedure history.
We've got 2284 Rose Right.
So all we're doing is to each role we want to add information about this specific procedure that they
had.
And if we do that if we if we just stop for a second to think about if we do that correctly then the
result how many rows should the resulting table have exactly the resulting tables should have 2284 rows.
Because what we're doing is we're adding information.
There can be no duplication of rows right.
If we just find the information about this specific procedure there they can they can it has to be a
one to one match so our There has to be a many to one match so many of the roles from here will only
have always a one role in the procedure Details table so you cannot have a situation where this this
row would have two matching rows and the procedure Details table simply because this procedure should
only be described once.
Right.
You cannot have do a procedure on a pad and then not know what exactly you did.
Maybe you did this maybe you did that.
No.
There it is.
It's a it's an exact match so every one of these rows has to match exactly to one role.
So it's a many to one relationship.
And so if we are now run this we should have 2284 Rose run it.
Going to take a few seconds here we see that we have 8000 179 rows.
So why is that what happened here.
What why did we get way more rules.
Well if you look at the rows here you'll see right away something is going on incorrectly three from
the from the very start you can see that this row looks like Simmons's.
And the same as Rousseau's So these rows got duplicated.
Right so we've got Pead ID procedure date procedure type and and what is this procedure sub code right.
And then they all got matched to the.
So this row got much too much too.
What is this.
If you look at this God must turn in a crop and he got too much.
Elex patellar repair and got matched to rabies vaccination.
Well why is that.
Well because we matched on the procedure subgoal.
And as you can see it did indeed match up the procedure sub code.
So five equals five because five because five and five equals five.
Right.
But what we didn't take into account that we actually should have matched on two fields or should've
matched on procedure type and procedure code because procedure sub code is not a unique identifier of
the procedure.
Right.
So if we look at this procedure details table.
So if you have a look here subgoal one is actually an office call sub code one is actually a bad subkey
one is a vaccination and so on.
So there's lots of procedures that have some code one and that is because some code is not a unique
identifier.
It has to come in conjunction with the type so procedure type has office has three subclause procedure
type grooming has three subclause procedure type vaccination has five or six up because one two three
four five six and only together do they act as a unique identifier.
So that's why here we need to add procedure right.
Oh the Brisas your type.
So I'm actually going to add it at the start because I like to think keep things clean.
I like to it doesn't matter.
You can say here and a dot prissy your type equals VIDOT procedure.
Type but in my view procedure type in high in the hierarchy of things comes before procedure code.
So I just like to put that at the start just to you know remember that OK first when I look up the procedure
type like you would you know in a library you'd first find the right shelf and then you'd find the right
book right or the file right there right.
You find the right shelf and then you'd find the right position on that shelf.
So kind of that type of thing.
But again it doesn't matter you can change these around because this is an and take but the point is
this is how we join on two fields.
We look at procedure type and procedure type equals and then procedure code up code subclause so far
on this.
We have two thousand two hundred eighty four rows exactly so as you can see now everything is matched
up very very well.
All right so that is how we join the multiple fields so if you perform that exercise I hope you've got
the same result.
Don't worry it's ok we're just learning.
And even if you got a different result that's OK.
Now you can see that how we actually do this multiple joint field and you know have a play around with
that maybe add a filter or see how that works.
Just make sure you get comfortable with this concept of joining on multiple fields because it'll definitely
come in handy in your data science career.
And I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.