Hello and welcome back to the course on databases.
So far we've learned so much already.
Right.
We've talked about left joins.
We've talked about tips and tricks.
Totally right.
Joines inner joins full outer joins joining on multiple fields.
Plus you have all this back with the theory of the joins that we discussed earlier.
So this is you're getting quite knowledgeable in the subject of Joines in databases and that is very
exciting and today I've got another exciting step for you today we're going to look at a complex joint
zone example where we don't have just one joint where we have two joins in a row in one statement.
It's going to be quite challenging So hopefully you're ready for it because in terms of preparedness
you're definitely prepared for it.
With all this knowledge in your arsenal in your backpack you're ready to tackle a complex.
So let's get the ball rolling.
We're going to create a new part.
We're going to call it complex joint and we're going to start.
We going just start actually by discussing what we want to achieve.
Right.
So that's always very important to understand.
Well we've already seen that we can connect our pets table to the procedure history table to find out
which of the pets in our clinic have had procedures done.
And that's we were you know how that works.
We used what type of joint did we use for that.
We use an inner join for that.
Right.
And then we've also seen how to connect the procedure history table to the procedure Details table to
find out more specifically what each of the procedures means and you know even the price for the procedures
as we see here.
So now we're going to combine the two.
What we want to achieve is we want we don't want a huge table like this.
For details of all the procedures that ever happened.
All we want is the pets in our clinic or find out of them which ones actually had procedure detail up
actually had procedures.
Right.
So which ones had procedures and then find the descriptions of those procedures and actual costs.
So that's going to be exciting so let's get started by doing this step by step and that's how you approach
these types of problems these challenges you do them step by step you first build one table you can
to the next table then you look at the results you make some notes then you connect to the next table
and so on sometimes you might have lots and lots of tables.
But we'll talk about that later.
So let's get started.
We'll say select star from pets right.
So that's your first step.
Just say that and run that have a look.
So we've got 100 rows 100 pets in here.
Fantastic.
Right now what we want to do is want to connect to the procedure history table to find out which of
these pets actually had procedures done.
And as we discussed previously if you are left join then we will indeed get the procedure details.
But we'll keep all the other pets in the table that never had procedures and that's not what we're after.
We just want only the pets that have had procedures and that's why we're going to do an inner join.
So say Star from pets inner join procedure history
and then you need to specify how you joining them.
You say you're going to say pets.
Well we could say PED's Daut pet idea.
But in this case we're going to create an alias as a as B by the way.
They don't have to be in a and b you could you could say X you could say I said you could say my table
one could say whatever you like and be just short and easy.
And that's why we use them.
A dot PED's IDs so we know that in this table we've got pet ID as the primary key.
And then if we go to if we look at the other table.
So procedure history is have a look at that table you'll see that here we've got parady as well.
So that's the name of the call Notice here that it's not the primary key so there could be several pairs
with the same ID.
This table actually is not identified by parody but still that's how we're going to join to this table
so we can say on a dog pet a equals b dot pet Id call on.
And let's go ahead and run this.
So if I click 5 and I have a look.
Voila 41 rows or pay attention here 41 rows and you can see that we've got the up over up until here
so this is our first table this part and this second table.
So we've got 41 rows meaning that's not necessarily 41 pets in our database have had procedures because
some of the pets as you call here have had several procedures.
There were so this dog has had two procedures.
So but at the same time we know that out of our pets there's a total of on procedures.
Now what we want to know is we want to find out more details on these procedures so we want to add more
information here on the right.
We want to find out the description of this procedure and the cost or the price of the procedure.
Maybe you know maybe this is an audit or something like that and we need to find out how much money
this the paths or how much money was generated from procedures associated with the pets in this specific
facility.
So let's go ahead and do that.
We're going to add on the right so there's nothing scary about it.
We're just going to continue.
So we're going to treat this part you know like this part from pets as we're going to just think of
it as if this was just one table.
Right.
So if this was just one letter right what would we do next.
We say we'd go here left to join if this is one table would say it would say woo left join right.
Because remember we we used a live joint between the procedure history and procedure details tables
right.
Because we want to keep all of this information and then we just add something onto the right.
Right.
And if something doesn't add on that means there there's some some problem but we need to know about
it if we don't find a match.
So we wanted to join and so that's what we're going to do.
So we're going to just return all of that.
And here we going to type in left joins to just keep typing as if nothing happened as if we don't really
have a joint here.
I know it might look a bit complex but in reality you'll see that it all makes sense just in a second
so left join procedure details.
Details we're going to call it as see.
And so maybe get rid of the call for now.
And now how did we perform this joint.
Well here we're used on procedure type equals procedure type and procedure subcortical procedures.
So now we not only have a complex joint because of the three tables we actually also going to have a
joint in multiple fields.
So we're going to just type that up and say on.
So it's important here to understand which table we're taking for the this part which take table we're
taking this information from so now we've got this table is Table A.
Up to here right.
This is Table B where we're here.
So now we're taking from table B we're taking procedure type procedure sub code and we're joining that
table see the say they have the same name there so we're going to be that procedure type calls see Daut
procedure type and the DOT procedure sub code he calls C Daut procedure sub called and colon.
So now if I were on this voice I was still we have 41 Roseberry important so we didn't add did we duplicate
anything and that's going back to what we discussed in the previous tutorial.
But now you can see that we actually have three tables here combined.
We've got Pead ID all the way up to here so up to owner ID then we've got this part where the procedure
is right so up to here.
That's these four column from Table 2.
And then we've got table three we've got the actual information.
So we've got the procedure.
What is this the procedure type.
So this is your procedure type in your procedure subgoal.
And here we've got our table 3 with all of the information here.
So very exactly.
Very interesting and exactly what we wanted.
So we've got our final result and we now know which pets in our database in our tables actually had
procedures and we have details of those procedures so we can actually get to the information on what
they had done and what the price will be.
So there we go that's how we perform a complex joint.
CONAN gratulations on that.
That was quite a task quite a difficult thing to do.
And and you have accomplished that.
So now that is something as you put into your backpack of knowledge about databases and sure enough
there are plenty of situations where complex joins like this will be able to assist you in your work
and I hope you enjoy this or Tauriel and I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.