Hello and welcome to the course on databases and today Sterle are going to upload our data sets into
Microsoft Eskil server.
So the first thing we need is a browser and browser.
Let's go to WW does super size dot com slash S Q L and here if you scroll down to Section 7 you will
see a link called Section 7 MSU all upload code.
So go ahead and download that.
And once you download it what it looks like is this so this is a Word document with some code in it
and we will use this file for the trial.
We'll use this file to convert the raw data that will upload into Microsoft the SQL Server into actual
working tables.
But as a first step would we need to do is actually upload actual data.
So let's go ahead and do that.
We've already downloaded the CSP files previously and now we need to upload them into skills or management
studio.
So let's Right-Click databases create a new database we're going to call it pets and into pets we want
to see if we open it up here you'll see that it doesn't have any tables it's completely empty.
So what do we do and what we want to do is we want to right click the database select tasks and select
import data.
Now this will bring up the skills server import export wizard.
Click next.
Our data source is a flat file source browse to find the location of your downloaded CSFB files.
Select the drop down change to see S V and the start of.
This is golf pedicle least a start from the top owners table.
Now we don't need to change anything here the only thing we definitely need to change is the text qualifier.
This should be a colon so a quotation mark is not not a colon this is a quotation marks so not two separate
quotes but one symbol which is a quotation mark just one symbol.
Everything else should say the same.
Make sure this box is checked called names in the first row is checked.
Go to columns.
Have a look here that is.
There's no errors.
Go to advanced select everything change it from 50 to 5000 So everything fits and we're uploading it
all it's text.
That's the safest way to go.
Click preview.
Again check that everything is working nothing's cut off.
Nothing has changed now looks good and that's it.
So go ahead to click next so that's the import part.
Now the destination dropdown.
Change this to Microsoft.
All only DB provider for secure server use the same authentication as you had when you installed Microsoft
skills or management studio database that's good.
And here in oh in the on the right.
Make sure to change the name of the table.
Put an underscore put Rauh underscore before it so we know that this is just raw data.
This is not something we're going to performing our analysis on.
This is just a way for us to get the data into the studio in the first place.
So there we go.
Click next run immediately click next and click Finish.
There you go.
Everything worked fine.
Click close if you refresh tables now you'll see a real table if you select top thousand rows you'll
see exactly what we got from for this challenge.
And each one of these columns is can contain up to 5000 symbols so it has enough space it should have
enough space to contain our data set and later on we will change it into a working table so we can just
close the script for now.
And now we need to perform the same procedure for the remaining three tables so let's go ahead and do
that.
Right click paths go to tasks.
Import data Wizards next datasource flat file browse.
We're going alphabetically such as this V Pats quotation marks single quotation mark.
Columns advanced 5000 preview quickly check everything looks good.
Next destination Microsoft.
All the DBI for providing for a SQL Server don't need to change anything here.
Put a rule underscore here.
Next run immediately next.
Finish.
All done.
Refresh Sallon is fresh Allen.
Select two thousand rows looks good.
Close next pets tasks.
Import Hoopes pets.
Tasks.
Import data.
You can get good at this.
A couple of practice runs CXXVI procedure is actually a good thing to talk yourself through it because
that way you minimize you reduce the chances of a mistake
otherwise it's easy to forget one of these steps.
Also good to have a checklist of what you need to do.
Microsoft all should be providing first class server.
Next is do wrong.
Wait for or underscore procedure details next.
Run immediately.
Next.
Finish.
Good.
Refresh and procedure details like to tell us.
OK.
You actually can select all of them because there is no there are not that many.
Oh yeah that's right.
This one this I was thinking of procedural history.
We can do that next one.
All right.
And now pets so do that tasks.
Import data wizard next data source.
Flat file source browse.
Change to V procedures history quotation mark columns.
Advanced Search.
All 5000 preview check everything.
Next all the DB provider for a scale server.
Good change this to wrong underscore.
Next thing good thing good and finish close and refresh procedures history if two thousand or she's
Kinslow more because there's more than Feldon here but not too many.
So these girls girls roll 2000 884 excuse crawling.
So looks good everything looks good and that's it.
So we've done the raw import.
Now we need to run that script that we got.
Let's a last step to create those tables.
So let's bring up that script.
There it is.
So just copy everything OK.
And you can run them one by one or you can run the whole thing.
I'm just going to run the whole thing execute because 100 rows in the Pets table while this parts of
it got created and the data types were specified so you can see like there are smaller N is an integer
than 100 rows were inserted owners.
Again the working table owners was created and 89 rows were inserted.
Then here we had 41 rows inserted procedure each other in procedure history 2000 84 rows inserted.
And if you refresh you'll see that we've got the row tables and the tables will be going to be working
with the working tables on here.
So there we go.
Import complete.
You cannot close this window don't need to save it and voila everything done ready to proceed with this
section.
And I can't wait to see on the next tutorial.
Until then happy analyzing.