Hello and welcome back to the course on databases.
So we've talked about all sorts of Joines we've talked about Left-Right inner outer full outer joins
that we've talked about cleaning up your joins with a complex join and joins multiple fields so very
well you're probably very well-versed by now in the topic of Joines and today I have one bonus tutorial
for you.
It's about a specific type of Joines that is not always covered in educational material.
It's and if you will say typical Secret's type of information that you get to find out eventually with
the course of your career.
But I do need to warn you that this is kind of an advanced topic and feel free to skip this tutorial
and get come back to it some time later when you do come across this type of join.
But at the same time if you feel prepared then let's go ahead and check it out.
So today we're talking about something very interesting it's called a cross.
And I personally didn't find out about cross join for at least a year or more of you more.
While I was working with fescue well until I actually needed it in my work and then I had to you know
I thought maybe it's an inner Joyner's an outer join.
I was trying to figure out what exactly I needed and wasn't any of those it was actually specifically
a cross join that I needed.
And luckily Asgill actually has this facility.
So what is a cross doing.
Well a cross join is a is an implementation of a Cartesian product in a scale.
I know it sounds a bit complex but at the same time it actually isn't that bad.
So I went across a Cartesian product is at the Wikipedia page here is in mathematics a Cartesian product
some mathematical operation that returns a set or product set or some product from multiple sets.
That is for sets and being created product is a set of all ordered pairs a b where A's from ABC from
B.
And the best way to illustrate this is to look at this example so if you have just think of it in terms
of table so if you have an all Table A and table B and these are the rows so x y and that are the rows
and B these columns are also rows.
You could call a rose a one two and three.
So the cartesian product is all possible combinations of these two sets.
These two tables all possible combinations of the rows.
So the X1 matches up 1.
So the first rule match up for show Frostrup much second row first row match up third row second row
much of first second second second third third match up with first third of second third of third.
So basically you know how in a join Left-Right inner or outer join we usually match them up so X would
match up to maybe row two and whites row three and this one wouldn't have a match on have a match and
that's what the result would have in a Cartesian product.
There is no on there's no parts there's no criteria for the match it just matches everything.
And that is why that's why this story is a bit advanced is that because now after so many tutorials
on joins in a row we are in the mindset of having this on part of the statement that we are specifying
how to match the two tables.
We want this to be equal to that when the criterion product or in the cross join you're not actually
going to have this part you're just going to grow cross join two tables full stop and it'll do everything
for you.
So let's have a look at that.
We'll start by selecting we'll actually let's talk through this a bit.
We're going to take two of the we're going to take the product prove procedure history table that's
for show which is going to take the owners and pets tables and was that because we want smaller tables
this table has several thousand rows and when you look at the all all possible combinations of two tables
were one to at least one of them is big or large.
You will you'll get a huge resulting table and we don't want that we're not going to break out computers.
So we're going to we're going to just cross join pets and owners so we're going to say select select
start from pets.
And here is sort of inner left outer or right or full outer join we can to say cross joy to owners call
the colon so you can see there's no on statement that comes afterwards.
So when you run this remember we have a hundred pets and about eighty nine owners.
So if you run this is going to take a while to run.
So here we have eight thousand nine hundred so a hundred times.
Eighty nine right.
Eight thousand nine hundred different combinations.
And what does this results show us.
So what we have here is for instance at the start of Ricardo Peterson who got matched to every single
pet so we got Ricardo or starting from here.
Honer ID So Ricardo got matched to every single pet in our database so we scroll down see that he got
matched to 100 different pets.
Then Arthur read he got mice too.
Again all those same pets.
But once again they got mice.
Each one of them so he called Mr. Black rhumba Simba Keller and so on and so on.
Hundred.
And then we got George Donald who are much to again all of our pets all hundred of our pets black dog
rhumba Simba Keller and so on.
And so you can see that that happened for each one of our 18:9 owners.
Each one of them got matched to each of the 100 pets that we have in our dataset.
Now what is the purpose of a cross-train like this makes no sense right.
Why would you match a black to the dog to all these owners when a black dog actually has just one owner.
What's the point of matching a black.
You have all these other owners.
Well the reason for a cross join is there are actually situations sometimes when you might need to see
see all of the possible combinations of two of the rows of two tables.
Right so like for example you have a set of colors like seven colors and you have a set of let's say
a set of tiles that are used in Buffle bathroom floor and you need a resulting table right.
And for example all those columns have certain attributes and all those tiles have certain attributes
or prices attached to them.
So you have seven different types of tiles like made out of different materials and you want to get
a resulting table which will combine which will have a combination of all of those colors and tiles
right.
So then you would do a cross join.
Right.
And another example would be when you have for example a you know five people and or a certain number
of people and they have each one of them has three choices right.
Yeah.
Each one of them has three choices that they can well like three doors that they can go through and
you want to see the results of all possible combinations of like for each person what's if they go through
which door how those parameters will add up.
So you want a table with all of those and then you'll make some analysis based on that.
The example when I need the crows during my career was when I was analyzing some socioeconomic patterns
in Queensland in Australia.
So that's the north eastern part of Australia and there the whole of this region in my database was
broken down into these little Parus which are called S-A ones and they basically each of those statistical
authorities contains about 200 peoples 200 people and in each one of them and then in each other in
each of those statistical regions I knew that there were several levels or civil economic social economic
levels and with different incomes basically several social classes of different incomes and so forth
I knew that I have like for example like five different social economic classes and I have 20000 or
less let's say for argument's sake 10 different social economic classes and I have 20 and like 200000
of these little blocks of
geographical blocks and that means that I need a cross join in my resulting table I need all possible
combinations for each of those geographical little segments I need a socioeconomic one in each of those
sectors socioeconomic classes are assigned to it.
That means I need 10 times.
I mean I need two million rows in my resulting database.
In fact it was much more so than just some numbers of overhead was a long time ago but I remember that
the resulting table had close to 900 million roles.
So as you can imagine like when because it had I think maybe even a couple of Crossroads or something
different it was multiple joins I don't remember how many Cross joins it had but the size of that table
was immense and that was you know a legitimate analysis that I had to do.
And that's my other warning or caution recommendation to you here is that cross-bones are also complex
or advanced not just because the way they're structured and the way they're used but also because of
the amount of resources that they take up so if you were to run a cross join for example with the procedure
history table of itself that's 2000 times 2000 all of a sudden you have a four million road table right
from a not such a big table of 2000 rows.
You're jumping into a four million row table and you caused join that one more time of the procedure
history table and all of a sudden you have a billion rules and if used incorrectly your joint can really
hang your computer not on your computer probably your whole organization's database and hopefully you
know your organization has protection mechanisms against it so they'll they'll just cut your session
and then you'll get a call from the database administrator saying hey you shouldn't do that but just
be careful of it.
And be warned that a cross join does grow very very quickly once you start working with larger tables.
So we go that's what a cross join is.
And hopefully now even if you don't go running into your work and using it right away maybe one day
when you do come across this situation when you need it you'll remember this tutorial and you will know
that what you need might be a crossroad.
And I hope you enjoy this Tauriel.
I'll look for you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.