Hello and welcome back.
Today we'll be learning about inserting that up into our tables.
So let's go ahead.
Open up our own database our own table and create a new query that says Select all from mits movies
free it's whatever you've decided to name your table.
So if we're run it we will see that they return it to us.
Deidre Rose absolutely no information and this is totally fine.
This is due to the fact that we haven't actually inserted or put any data inside our table is just an
empty skeleton so say today will be learning how to do that how to put in some information into a new
table.
Let's go ahead.
Quickly make sure that we have the columns all set up and ready to go and the keys.
Eröffnung is right.
So now all I need to do is type in insert into.
So insert into has two possible variants.
One you already encountered where we say insert into table name from table.
This is very useful when you have the wrong table or you have previous table that you don't want to
work with anymore and you just need to create a new table and you want to save all the data.
But today let's try to make try to insert data manually through the query by writing it with our own
hands.
So what I want to do is insert into and of course another way is using the import data window that we
have learned when you have this pop up menu in which you select flat files or Excel file and so forth.
They will be working with manually so insert into then your table name.
In my case movies and then you want to save values so you save these open brackets and in those brackets
separated by a comma is the values that you want to insert into every column so every column is separated
by a column.
In my case let's go ahead and start filling in my favorite movies.
My first movie that comes to my mind is seven.
So all right.
Capital S lower.
He has 7 pm.
Then I put a comma.
The year that it came out is 1995 the country came out from is USA and the genres are mystic about that
mystic and crime solvers go ahead exit could this as you can see one ROIs effect that you've run the
query which will again select all from movies.
We should see one row of data and that's exactly what we see so done perfect.
We already inserted one roll of data so far.
Let's go ahead and try some more now instead of writing this query a thousand billion times what you
can do is you can just put a comma after the values and type in your second column.
So information for your second row.
In my case it's going to be a movie called interstellar that I need to put in apostrophes because it's
text that I need to put come up the year that it came out and is 2014 country where it originated is
USA and Joyner's of it is science fiction only has one shot or as far as I'm concerned.
So science fiction.
Now if we run this interesting fact will happen it will not run because as you can see it gives us abolition
of primary key.
Basically it tells us because we already have a movie in that table called 7 in the year of 1995.
You cannot run the same movie twice.
You cannot record it twice in there because then the primary key will not be able to do its job.
So basically it saved us from duplicating the data we already had.
So let's go ahead delete this and just put a comma and right and a new fresh piece of data for this
tape.
So you open up your brackets and for me the next movie will be called the Green movie 3.
The Green Mile so the Green Mile the year this movie came out is 1999 the country of origin is again
you say and then genre of the mystic and drama.
So now who run this what will get is actually two rows of data.
So now we have three rows of data in-general all the look very nice.
They look very neatly organized.
So let's go ahead fill in one more roll of data.
I can eat all of this.
Put it in here.
Idlest movie will be the flutter year of its release is 1972 the country of origin is again USA and
the janitor is right now.
Let's say we forget to put the school complete.
We just forget that it exists and try trying to squirty what will happen is it gives us this mistake
that says that we did not put enough columns to satisfy the need of the table.
So basically we've put less columns that there actually are in the table then let's say we're going
to put in just nothing.
We're just going to put Not even the space just we're going to specify that it's of a day type work.
So it fits with our table needs but we're just going to put nothing in it.
So now if we execute it it will let us execute it.
But if we select all we can see that it left it empty and then put a null value in it just let it empty.
So how do we fix this how do we fix it.
Well there is a couple of ways.
First we can go for the right click menu of the table itself or we can write another piece of code in
which we'll say just spaces out of it and say update movies and set country to be equal to USA where.
And here we can just go ahead and say movie name equals the honor.
So now we would run this piece of code nothing would change because as you can see I made a typo here.
So I just have to change this and now it will run perfectly fine.
So as you can see any typos you make any mistakes you make in the put of data will cost you a lot.
Later on it will basically make your life miserable.
Going through all the data you have and imagine the database we worked with the first table 16 Pazner
rows of data.
Imagine you made one or two typos in there and you have to scroll through all of the data there trying
to find a table and then trying to understand what you forgot to input there.
So make sure every time you input data into a database that it's correct its integrity is preserved
and nothing is wrong with it because that way is the most efficient way to work with databases so as
soon as the data is already inside that address then it's all about your skills your logic the way you
operate and your efficiency but inputting the data into a secure well that can be really really hard
and painful.
So another way you can.
You could have done this if you could have Right-Click on the movies you want to script table as and
when to insert two new Querrey at a window.
And here you can see the general syntax that we followed so you could have just used this.
I just prefer the manual way because it teaches you a lot and most importantly teach you do appreciate
your time.
I hope you enjoy this lecture and I'll see you in the next hour.