Hello and welcome back.
Today we'll be learning to delete our newly created table and our newly created database.
There's a few ways you can drop them using the query field by writing a simple drop command but we're
just going to be working with a much easier way because we're working through Microsoft Excel sort of
management studio.
All we need to do is like the tables window right click on the table we want to drop go down and drop
down menu sit like delete.
Click here and just make sure that the right table is like that.
Show dependencies is going to be later on.
If you have more tables connected to one another that might be an issue because you will need to delete
this table of all dependencies or not all the dependencies and then you have to change them for an not
just like this press.
OK Bob there it's gone.
It took us so much time and so much effort to create this table we grew to love it.
But it's pretty much gone at this point with just two clicks and the same goes for a database.
If you had any tables inside the database it doesn't matter you can still drop them or delete them unless
there is active queries open that will just not allow you to do that.
Or this table is being used.
All you need to do again is right click here go to delete menu and your window will pop up in which
you make sure you selected the right the correct database and heroic in nature to the backup.
Just in case you're sure you will not need this database anytime soon.
And also close the existing connections.
If you don't for an hour just leave it by default.
Go ahead.
OK there it goes.
Done.
So all of our work is deleted.
We've left no trace in the system but I hope you've learned a lot.
I hope you understood that it's nothing scary there's nothing scary or hard about creating tables about
editing them about working with them and it's all about logic and just being profound with your naming
conventions being fond of your data integrity and just doing everything correct.
If you Durfee incorrect and follow rules you will always succeed in as well.
I hope you enjoy this lecture and I'll see you in next one.