Hello and welcome back to the course on databases.
So today we want to upload the data dataset for this section.
And let's go ahead and open up.
P.J. admen So here we go it's Jasmine and inside the first thing what's great is the database so let's
Right-Click.
So they create and create a database which we will call.
They just simply call its oil T-P for online transaction processing.
Save there is our database.
Wonderful.
And now we want to upload the data set.
So in order to that we're going to query create a new query and then we're going to open up a browser
again.
And there it is.
So once again go to WWE super day signs that comes as well.
And if you scroll down here you'll see a file called section on postgresql upload code so Dallow that
files a doc X file.
So if you just now minimize that window the file looks like this and it basically has the code that
you need to run to upload this database.
Right so we're going to now go ahead and just copy this code and we posted over here in time and you
query.
So this is are we prepared for you got create table call where you just were just specifying the table
that we're creating which is transactions and basically then all of the columns that we want to create.
And then if you just need to select which version you're using either Windows or Mac.
And then just select the appropriate code and then just modify it you're going to have a look at where
my data is stored and it's stored here so it's stored in databases on my desktop there's a folder called
databases.
There it is.
And then there's a folder in there called Section 9.
So if I go ahead and so I'm on Windows I'm just going to comment on the Mac version which is a Windows
version and I'm going to say here.
Copy transactions from C users curial desktop databases.
And then here it is actually Section 9 OLTP don't see a Svea OK.
And that should do it.
So I'm just going to run this topline first part 5 then just run this part 5 and then you go you can
see that that's how many rows were inserted.
There you go.
So in fact you can just remove this one that you don't need.
And then if you go to schemas public tables you should see a table here or if you've had this or in
the open just click refresh and then just to confirm that it has loaded indeed we'll just say select
star for all transactions and put a semi-colon.
Run that and there is our table.
So everything looks fine just check the columns check the rosemary scroll to the bottom.
Just make sure everything was good.
And there we go.
So you're all set to proceed with this section.
We've got some very exciting stories coming up ahead.
And is going to be good fun.
And we're going to learn quite a lot.
So I look fortune.
And until then happy analyzing.