Hello and welcome back to the course on databases.
OK so now we've talked about why this table is not in the second normal form and today we're going to
find out how we can split this table into several tables to make the design of this database conform
to the second normal form.
So this is the practical part of taking something to a second normal form.
So let's get started.
All right so here's our table and we're just going to start typing up the code that we want to see to
fix fix the situation right.
So the first thing we want to do is we want to separate these columns that we've identified that do
not depend whole wholly or fully on the candidate.
So the first name surname shipping state and loyalty discount those columns for columns they depend
on the customer ID.
So they need to be in a separate table.
So let's go ahead and separate them out first then we're going to do is we're going to create a table.
So we're going to create a new table TNP.
It's going to be the name of our table and here we are going to do an interesting thing so we're going
to create a table team he has and here we'll just type in the select statement for those calls.
So we're going to select the customer id call him as well because we will need the customer ID in the
new table so we're going to like 1 2 3 4 5 corms in total.
So those go hand that select customer id comma first name last name shipping state and loyalty discount.
All right so if we just run or obviously from transactions
so if we just run this part we should just get those five columns.
So OK so last Sundt last name is surname.
So if we run these we should get those five columns.
There we go so we just like to those phone calls two thousand four hundred fifty five rows and now we're
going to run this whole part to create this new tables.
Right so there we go.
Everything is wrong.
We can even put the common here three and three thousand four fifty five.
And here I'll just comment this as separate customer specific columns.
All right.
Wonderful.
Next what we're going to do is we want to make sure that this new table that we've created conforms
to the second normal form right.
So let's first deal with this new table so star from GMP.
So if we look at this you'll actually see that there is a lot of duplicates in this table was that well
because we don't have that many customers what is going on here is the customers have been purchasing
several times.
And therefore there were several there are several entries for every single customer in the Transactions
table and all we've done is we've taken these calls from the transaction table and copied them into
the tempy table.
So it's natural that all of these customers have come across but they're they've got duplicate rows
in here.
So how do we fix that how do we get rid of the duplicate rows.
Well it's pretty straightforward.
That's exactly why we actually use the team table here so temporary table because now we're going to
create the actual table the customer tables so we're going to say create table customers as Select Distinct
star from team Pete.
Right so here we're going to remove duplicates.
We already know what the
slug distinct works how it works if we run this part will tell us that there's only 942 rows.
Right so there's only 142 customers here because every one of these rows is unique.
This information is unique to a customer.
And what we're doing here is we creating a table called customers as this result and the result here
is only the distinct draws from the DMP table.
This is like a little tip for you how to separate the table the columns and then also make it conform
to.
Well right now we just reboot moving duplicates we're making to conform to the first normal form so
this table is not even in the first normal form.
So here's an example finally of a table that's not in first normal form because it has duplicate has
lots of duplicates in here.
But now by removing the duplicate we've got a table that is.
So here we're going to just say 900 for you.
So now we're moving into play because we've got a table that does conform to the first normal form.
Right so so Nexstar from customers on that you'll see nine hundred forty two rows total.
And these are all of our unique customers.
So this table conforms to the well it doesn't have a duplicate rows then we know that it doesn't have
any cells that contain more than one values old values are Tolmach.
That means this table is in the first normal form.
Now we just want to check that it is in the second normal form because for the design of the database
to conform or the schema to conform to the second normal form.
All the tables have to conform to the second normal form.
So let's go ahead and check that this table is in the second normal form.
Well here what is our what is our
candidate key.
Our kind of the key is customer ID here for sure.
Also you could argue that maybe first name and surname of the candidate.
But it really it's not.
It's not the case because you could have two people like Paul Allen and another Paul Allen who are different
people.
And in fact they could both actually even live in the same state and have the same loyalty discount
and therefore no combination of these is actually a candidate key.
The only candidate that we have here is the customer.
And because the customer is the only candidate key.
It is very easy to check the condition of the second roll from that every non-prime attributes all of
these for each one of these depends on the whole of the candidate key on the whole of every candidate.
Well we only have one candidate.
And it only consists of one column.
So you can split it up so as we know by default the condition the second the condition of the second
normal form is met.
Meaning that indeed all of these attributes depend on the whole of this candidate.
And therefore this table is in the second normal form.
So there we go we can just say confirmed
or never confirmed.
Wonderful.
And now we want to move back to our previous table which we still have here so the transaction table
the one we started off with.
Right.
So let's
let's go back to the transactions table now.
So if you run that you'll see that we still have those call them so we never remove them.
We did copy them.
We created a new table from these columns but we never removed them from here.
So that's what we're going to do now.
We're going to remove those calls right so remove customer specific columns but what we're going to
do is we're going to but leave the customer ID field column.
Why is that.
Well because obviously we need that's the customer id call them here is our foreign key to join into
the new table that we have to the customers but otherwise we're going to lose information if we remove
all of these columns.
All five of the columns then we will completely lose information about the customers we have to leave
something and we need to leave the foreign keys something that we're going to use to match up.
And so let's go and do this we know how to drop tables for Kolbe's from our table.
We'll just say alter table transactions and here we can say drop.
Call them first name then we'll just copy that and here will say surname.
Next one is shipping state and the next one is loyalty discount.
I just want to drop those four columns from all transactions table and run this completed successfully.
And now we can simply select OK just run this again.
Let's do this.
If you look at this now there we go so we've got a much smaller transaction stable.
There we go so we've got the transaction ID that timestamped the customer ID right.
So again this is a this is a candidate key and then we've got the item that the customer purchased the
description the retail price and based on our conclusions from the previous tutorial where were we were
investigating if it's in second or not for a normal form or not.
We've already checked these columns so we don't need to check again we already know that these columns
do rely in full on this candidate.
So you cannot just use part of his candidacy to identify the contents of these columns and therefore
this table is an economic forum so we can just say to and have confirmed.
There we go.
Now all we have left to do is to drop this tempy table.
We can either right click and select Delete drop or what else we can do is we can just go and say here
drop table so it's good to clean up after yourself.
Drub table tempy to avoid to avoid further confusion in the future.
So just run that you refresh your and there you go.
So we've got now two tables.
So as you can see what we've achieved now is that from one transactions table we've redesigned our database
to two tables transactions and customers for it to conform to the second normal form.
And already this design is better for online transaction processing scenarios.
So why is that better.
Well because if you look here at so or less of their customers right.
If we look at the customers we now have the customer separated in this table and we have all the information
about them here and that means that when we're actually recording transactions that are coming in we
don't have to record unnecessary information or we don't have to recall information about the customer
name about the customer surname about their location about their discount because all of that is already
stored in that other table.
If we get a new customer we'll just updated once and then as they purchase new items all we're recording
is item and all of this information about the items are recording record recording so more relevant
information to the purchase and therefore we're saving space.
So as you can see these transactions are coming in quite quickly sometimes several transactions per
minute.
We're selling space we're saving processing time we're saving resources.
And overall it's a much better set up for writing information into a database.
And that is exactly what how on OLTP on line transaction processing databases are or should be designed
so that it was our first step.
The second normal form next in this section we're going to discuss this third normal form code next
time.
Until then happy analyzing.