Hello and welcome back to the course on database's Tauriel we're going to continue normalizing our database.
So far we've redesigned the database to make sure that it's in second normal form.
And as you can remember we've got two tables now instead of one we've got the Customers table and the
transaction.
And today we're going to check if these tables are if this database is now in third normal form.
And if we're going to adjust it to make it conform to the third normal form.
So let's have a look at the definition on the third normal form to start off with the third normal form
as we discussed in the theoretical Turris is defined as the table has to be in second second normal
form which we've already checked and also every non-prime attribute is non transitively dependent on
every candidate.
So if we remember that mnemonic it's ever every non-prime Actually it must provide a fact about the
key the whole key and nothing but the key.
So in this case we're talking about the bar which is nothing but the key meaning that any non-prime
Ashmit cannot be dependent on the key.
Transitively through another non-prime attribute or another just another attribute not in that candidate.
And here one thing we do need to remember about the mnemonic is that and nothing but the key here we're
talking about one key but really we have to talk about every candidate.
So let's go ahead and see how this works in practice.
So now we have to remember that we have two tables so to check that the database conforms a third normal
form you'd have to check both tables.
And that's exactly what we want to do.
So here I'm going to add a comment here check three N.F. and we're going to check the customers table
first because it's easier Silex star from customers.
Let's run that and there we go so there's our customers table.
Let's see if all of the non-prime attributes are non-trans to be dependent on all on the candidate.
All right so as we discussed we only have one candidate key here which is the customer ID and we already
know that this table is second.
Norm is in the second normal form.
This is our only candidate key and we therefore this is our only prime attribute.
And these are our non-prime attributes.
So now we need to check that each of these non-prime attributes indeed depends on the customer ID field
or the candidate.
Here we followed a transitive dependencies across other fields.
Right.
So let's get started.
First name does the first name depend on the customer ID directly or maybe through some other field.
It depends on the customer ID direct.
Right.
So first name is not dependent on surname is dependent on state not depend on surname the surname depend
directly on the customer.
Correct so surname is independent of first name first name and surname are not tied up so a person can
have any surname with any first name surname is not dependent on the state on the oil to discuss.
So that's independent.
A ship shipping shipping state is shipping state dependent on first name and the way to think about
it is if if the first name can the first name change and the shipping state will the ship be said have
to change as well so basically does the shipping change.
Is there some sort of relationship between the two.
No there actually isn't a person with any name can be in any state.
Same thing for surname and same thing.
The shipping state does not depend on the oil to discount.
Basically it just depends on the customer ID.
Finally a little to discount.
Does it depend on the first name.
Nope.
A person with any name could have and your loyalty discount surname.
Same thing with shipping state.
It's a bit interesting because the answer is again no it doesn't depend because the loyalty discount
is accumulated by a customer through their purchases through their history through a transaction through
how long they've been purchasing through this online store and so on.
So that's how they get the loyalty discount.
But let's say in a different scenario if instead of loyalty discount you had a state wide discount.
So for every different state there would be a different state the different discount that would be applied
to all the purchases made by customers from that state for example the reason could be that states have
different taxing schemes and therefore the store can offer customers different discounts because they
have to pay they themselves have to pay different taxes different levels of taxes in different states
something like that so there could be a reason for that.
And if you had a situation like that where this was a statewide discount in that case the city the logic
would be different.
Right.
In that case you would say yes the state where discount doesn't depend on a first name doesn't depend
on surname but it does depend on state.
So even though it's the state wide discount is a characteristic of the customer.
Right.
So it's a it's assigned to the customer.
It's knowing you can for every customer I.D. You have a certain statewide discount but really it is
trans. it would have been transitively dependent through the shipping State field because then you would
you wouldn't be able to say that.
OK so if Colorado has 8 percent statewide discount and can we if we change the state.
Will the discounts change and normally we expect the answer to be.
No that's it.
These are independent and therefore if one of them changes this one doesn't have to change.
But in that case if you change the state and you get a statewide discount then indeed the statewide
discount would change as well and that would mean that's an example of the transit of dependency.
And so in that case you would have to split out this them into a separate table and make sense right.
So if you have a statewide wide discount you should have a table where you have all the 50 states of
the US and the discounts applicable to those states.
You shouldn't be replicating the state widescale 942 times for every single customer.
That's kind of the essence of the third normal form why we're doing it.
But in this case it's a bit it's all a much more trivial.
We've got the customer idea and as we discussed because this is not a statewide it is just a loyalty
discount on each one of these fields is dependent on the candidate.
The long transitively so therefore this table is in third normal form so we can say three aneath confirmed.
OK so that's good.
We don't have to adjust this table.
Now let's have a look at the other table that we have which is so Nexstar from transactions.
All right let's check this table.
This is the fun stuff OK.
We're going to make some space.
And by the way we've just had a very heated discussion about a heated monologue by Carol about the customers
table.
So if if you feel comfortable now after this theoretical tutorials and Officer what we how we analysed
the customers table if you feel comfortable giving this a go on your own then I highly encourage you
to pause this video right now and check if the transactions table if this table is does conform to the
third normal form check if it does or not and make your conclusion on that and then just play the video
again or you continue playing the video and see how I would see how I'm going to go about that logic
and that there'll be some very good practice.
So if you want to do that then post a video now.
Otherwise we're going to continue analyzing this table.
All right.
So let's go we've got a transaction ID which we know is the candidate key in this table.
We also know that we've got timestamp in seconds and customer id they are also candidate keys in this
table.
And then we've got item which is the item ID which basically is the code for the item that was purchased.
The description of the item and the retail price of that item and so the customer we've already modified
this table we remove the customer fields and now if we want to get information about the customer we
just join join this table to the customers table based on this customer id field.
So now the question is is are there any transitive dependencies in this table.
And the way to think about it is first of all we have to find the non-prime attributes.
Right so we know that these are our prime attributes because they are parts of at least one candidate
key.
And these are are known non-prime attributes because they are not parts of they're not part of any candidate.
And the question we have to ask is for every single one of these non-prime attributes what we need to
check is is it non-trans a doubly dependent on every candidate.
Right.
So let's go ahead and start start figuring this out.
All right.
So let's sort of item and sort of item and let's start with transaction ID so item the person somebody
purchase an item with this code is it directly dependent on the transaction ID or is it dependent on
the transaction ID through through some other field so it doesn't have to be just the non prime attributes
it could be.
Is it somehow dependent through these fields as well.
Right so basically what we want to check is it directly dependent on this specific candidate.
So item item code.
So basically for this item if it could.
Let's start with timestamp.
In seconds could the timestamp and seconds change right if the Times happened check seconds changes.
Does this item have to change.
No it doesn't because this item could have been bought at any point in time.
What if the customer ID changes.
Does this item have to change this item number.
No it doesn't because any customer ID could have bought any item if the description changes.
Does the item have to change.
This is a tricky one because indeed if the description changes right then the item probably will change
because items have their description.
But the question is here is like the chicken and egg question.
Who who came first.
Well we're going to assume that items is beef out of these two.
Right.
So item we're going to take item as the main call more of the more important call right.
So basically we're not going to say that item is dependent on description we can say descriptions have
been an item.
So for us items does depend on the transaction ID in the case of these two.
And for retail price same thing.
So we're not going to say that items depend on the retail price items upon a transaction or retail prices
depend on the item and it's just the way you think about it like it is logical right.
That price is depend on item so item dictates the price and item the item code dictates the description.
So that's that's the approach we're going to take here.
There are some times like you could come across as attrition where it's a bit vague like say you could
use description as the main out of these three.
And you know stick with that.
But in this case it's quite obvious that that item is the main one because it's a number it's a code
and it's much easier to deal with codes as the foreign key in our case.
Right.
If Wolf what we're trying to achieve.
So we're going to say that item is non transitively dependent on the transaction ID.
It's a transaction id identifies item directly rather than through description or through each retail
price which makes sense.
Then we'll move on to description.
Right.
Or basically we have to check item we have to check the same thing for item.
But with with this foreign key right so timestamp seconds on customer ID is that is item dependent on
this forum on this candidate key is item depend on this kind of key direct.
Right so or is it transitively dependent through transaction.
Well actually no because once you know the time stamp seconds on customer ID you don't really need to
know the transaction ID to understand what item was purchased at that point in time by that customer.
Because it is this is a candidate.
Then is item dependent on this kind of key through description.
Same thing same discussion as we just had with the transaction ID situation so we're going to take item
as the out of these three being the one that is independent or that is directly dependent on the candidate.
Next we move onto the description.
Right so here we've got a description.
Question is is description directly dependent on this candidate.
Transaction ID.
Well the answer is no because description actually depends on item which depends on transaction ID.
Right.
So what that means is basically if we have pillowcase here what if the item number changes we'll pillowcase
have to change.
Yes indeed.
Pillowcase will have to change because they are linked.
There's a link between them this item dictates what the description is and therefore description.
Even though the transaction ID indeed is associated or there is a certain description associated with
the transaction ID or with this combination of these two calls because something was purchased.
It has a description but in reality that description is transitive The dependent on this kind of the
key is transmitted to depend on this candidate key as well through the item.
Same thing for retail price.
So retail price even though yes indeed this transaction has a retail price associated with it.
This transaction happened by the same transaction but if you look at it through this candidate key.
Yes indeed it has a retail price associated with it but this retail price is not directly doesn't directly
come from this candid award.
And as a matter for the matter as a matter of fact it is income very good for this candidate.
Q Either it comes from the item and that's exactly what the third normal form is looking for it's looking
for situations where you've got part of the table that needs to be separated out.
So basically we see here that we need to take these three columns and put them into a separate table
and then also just keep item in the stable and that'll be our way that we will look up information about
the item if we need to.
So basically if you just take your kind and you cover off this part these last two columns This is the
final table that you should have in third normal form of transaction id timestamped seconds.
Customer ID and item number are the item ID and that this information shouldn't be in the table because
we're actually duplicating it right.
So we're actually there's no point in us saving the item id the description and the retail price when
we can have these in a separate lookup table.
And then when we ever need that information we'll just join to it.
So there we go that's how we think about the third normal form and how we check or investigate if a
table is in third normal.
For me it is a real investigation like it's I think it's valid to use the word investigation because
it does take some time and does take some thinking but that is why there is a whole separate professional
database architects or database engineers database designers.
There's these professions exist for a reason because it requires a lot of mental power.
It requires a lot of time and requires a lot of expertise and experience to design a good database.
And what we're doing here is we're actually understanding the thinking process that goes into it and
that will really help us when we are working with these databases.
We will know what thinking went into it.
So that's how we investigate in the next tutorial we'll learn how to modify this database to change
the design to conform to the third normal form.
And I look forward to seeing you then.
Until next I'm happy analyzing.