Now if you've been spending a lot of time looking at other Airbnb properties and looking at their views
you might notice that there are some properties that have much better reviews and those reviews really
really go into depth.
Sometimes you have these reviews that are far you know 300 words describing every single aspect of it
and they are very very positive about the House and the space.
And then other places you look at they might be as positive but they're also shorter listings that have
really really positive reviews.
People are just gushing when they write them they're going to get a lot more people booking because
they look and they say wow this person is an amazing experience.
I want to replicate that if they look and I see only positive views but they're short removes that additional
kind of premium that people will associate with a property that has fantastic reviews that you might
be wondering to yourself.
How do people get those reviews.
How do you get these people that just go on and on and on about how great this space and hosts are.
I call this lecture mastering the warm and fuzzy.
This is something that I'm not the best at.
We have good reviews but they're not absolutely fantastic.
Some of the reviews if you look on the smaller individual spaces in my apartment those are much better.
Typically when I read out my full apartment I'm not going to have fantastic reviews because I checked
out I'm not there when I run out of space.
I have much better reviews because I actually spend time with the guests and you can see that I post
a link.
The reviews of what I have on my other spaces within my apartment.
How do you master the warm and fuzzy some Are you guys going to be much better than I am at this but
I can give you my two cents.
The way that you get better reviews is just going to be how do you communicate with your guests.
How thoughtful are you when you communicate with them constantly remind them that you're there to help
them that if they need anything don't hesitate to ask and then go a step farther.
Make sure that they can communicate with you.
Make sure they have your cell phone.
Send them a text saying just how are you enjoying everything.
Check in with them.
The more of those gift strategies like a bottle of wine the basket of goodies the chocolate things small
things like that those things really add up and people will start feeling more positive about you and
your space and they'll post in your reviews.
You see on some of my reviews a lot of people mention the wine bottle not something they really thought
was great.
I think I found a winner on that one.
Just be as nice as you can.
This isn't a hotel.
You know if someone says your question you can't accommodate them.
Don't just say no I can't do it.
Period.
Always try to cushion whatever you're saying something negative.
You can always say yes it's not this but unfortunately but here's something I can do that might meet
you halfway.
The more you go out of your way to do things for them the more likely they're going to mention those
things.
In general the more time you spend with your guest the more likely you're going to get these types of
reviews.
I know a lot of people.
Their most favorite thing about Aramean be they get to meet people they make friends and they really
do like to spend a lot of time with their guests and so their guests really do go out of their way to
reward them and they post these fantastic reviews.
I think it might be a problem if you later try to like press on the brake a little bit when you want
to pull back and not spend as much time with each cast but it's still an asset to you.
Every good review is something going forward that will make their may be better for you and you'll get
you more bookings and more inquiries and that's what we want you to get to how you get the best reviews.
It really just comes down to a thoughtfulness.
Sarah has very good positive reviews because she's very thoughtful about the guests.
The more you customize and the more you spend individual time with each guest the better your views
are going to get.
Sarah had someone I think it was gluten free or she is vegetarian and she left out food for them when
they came in late because she knew that they were going to be hungry.
Really simple things like that.
I had a guest that really wanted to go to Alcatraz but they didn't have any time.
So what I ended up doing was purchasing it for them and they paid me back and I you know it was easier
for me because I was walking somewhere in San Francisco and I passed by one of the places where they
sell the tickets.
And so it was very easy for me to pick up anything like that that can really make you kind of an accessory
to them having a good experience.
Death really going to pay off really basic things like asking if they have any nutritional requirements.
That's something that really helps and then if you spend a little bit of money getting a couple of things
that they can you know for instance breakfast foods if you know someone is gluten free you might want
to grab a gluten free bowl of cereal.
Really small things like this.
There's one thing you want to come away with this.
Be thoughtful.
Be as warm as you can.
You should really be enjoying this process is something you might get better over time and you'll get
better reading gas and you'll get better at knowing what they need and what they want but eventually
you get to a point where I think you can really elicit the types of positive reviews that you see everywhere
else.
Don't take it personally if you don't get these long gushing reviews from people.
It's a skill.
It's something that you get more comfortable with and once you become a really good host that's when
these things start popping up.