You've probably noticed also on the listing of your property there is the option to add an additional
charge for extra people.
Somebody you might have just cost right or this didn't mean anything to you.
Some of you might have noticed and thought to yourself why is that.
How do I justify to people and charge more for more people of this renting the same space.
Initially I had the same reaction when you're running a space they kind of figured you're renting the
space.
What does it matter if I out another person and used to bother in hotels too and they would do it if
I rent a room for one person and his two beds costs X.
Now if I have two people in the same room it cost more.
I never understood that it sounded like they were just charging more because they could and the case
of arean be it's partially I think helpful to charge more.
And I think partially it's still a little bit strange for the most part people accept it.
It's not something we're going to get a lot of kickback for.
People aren't particularly used to it though so don't be surprised when you notice that they're sending
you the calculations wrong because they didn't factor in the extra costs.
One of the reasons why people don't particularly notice this on Arab PNB is that it's almost automatically
calculated into the first price they see.
They don't ever really see the base price for your apartment unless they are searching for a one person
stay at a base price then they add people and show them incrementally the price going up when you had
Air B and B it ask you how many guests you have very rarely use one say one gas and forget and say Oh
actually it's seven guests.
Most of the time they just think that that is the price.
So I wouldn't particularly worry about that coming off as you know disingenuous.
But I want to help people understand a little bit why if you do get kickback on this you can rationalize
it.
And in my experience what more guests means more utilities especially in the case of a shared apartment
means more flushing of the toilet.
It means more likely to leave the lights on it means you know now you have two people arguing over whether
it's hot or cold in the apartment and messing with the thermostat you know it means more consumption
of breakfast goods when you're in a shared space it means that you have to share space with more people.
And that's just something that you feel like you should be compensated for.
It's not a huge fee for an additional person and it very rarely is the case that people say oh an extra
$100 per person is usually an extra 20 bucks and you definitely make money off of that.
I wouldn't say that the extra flushing of the toilets and the breakfast foods end up being an extra
20 bucks per night it is kind of an excuse to add an incremental cost and it makes sense to me because
I typically feel more comfortable for instance if I'm running up my apartment to for people versus nine
nine people.
It's more chances for things to get scratched up.
It's more traffic in and out we have hardwood floors that has the potential of creating more problems
it's winds up being more of a cleaning job too.
So when you go and get a cleaner and if you're lucky enough to be in San Francisco they have a cleaning
service through FBN be they end up cleaning more and they end up spending more in cleaning supplies
that you have to reimburse them for.
And so it's not negligible it's these are things that you might not have thought about.
But there are definitely things that happen and there is a difference between having four people in
a room versus one person in the room from the host perspective say you're doing a shared room.
It's more noise.
It's generally harder to manage larger groups of people than smaller groups more likely to have miscommunications.
It's all of these things you kind of factor in and that's how you come up with this extra person cause
and you might find that it's not the case that you are bothered by it.
Typically what I do is I say there's only additional costs once you go past the max capacity.
So I would say like for my apartment regularly five people sounds normal for six people and above that
then you're actually creating some strain I think and that's why we charge extra.
Typically I would suggest starting out that you start out with no incremental cost but put a cap and
really do think about your cap.
How many people you can fit in your space.
At first it's going to help people balk when they notice that with my three people I can fit in.
And then as you start getting a review base then you can start charging more and then you can start
getting more and more comfortable and then it'll start working like a well-oiled machine as you start
bringing in the gas and you start you know really going to getting experienced with this.
It all gets easier.
But also in general I think opening yourself to large groups and using this extra person fee.
It's a great way of bringing in extra money.
It really is something that can add an extra couple of thousand per month if you're doing a full time
rental or even if you're you know doing a shared space or an all and you charge extra.
It can make a considerable difference.