Here's a tip that I thought was worth sharing.
This is something that I used that really helped me out of the gate with my Air B and B listing some
of you will laugh a little bit at this but this is an idea around what are the simplest cheapest ways
of getting the best outcome on your arab and B listing earlier we talked about how Airbnb does free
photography and their photography is phenomenal.
If you look at an RV and be photographed it makes the location whatever room they're shooting it makes
it look phenomenal.
The saturation of the image is quite high.
You can notice because the colors are much richer.
They also seem to increase the contrast of their images quite a bit.
So one of the things that was kind of a problem when I started my Air B and B was that when I first
put up the listing I only had the capability to take photographs with what I had on me which was an
iPhone you can apply for their photography but it does take some time for them to come out and take
the photographs.
Depends largely on how long you've been a member.
Obviously it doesn't make sense for them to send photographers out.
If you've only been listed for a day they want to see if you're going to stick around it's quite expensive
for them to get someone to go out and take the photographs even though the photographs do they do them
very quickly they will just run right through your apartment.
So the question is how do you get decent photography.
How do you make your apartment look really good without the air being be photographed because there
is going to be a window where you put up your listing and it's going to be listed with whatever camera
you had.
And there is a huge difference in the air and the photographs and the photographs you have especially
if you're in a competitive area it's really hard to compete with somebody who already has the beautiful
bright saturated images that Airbnb takes and you're trying to compete and you're new and you're trying
to show and your photographs are from an iPhone.
IPhones have a very decent camera but they're not going to capture the same quality high resolution
image that a SLR camera is going to capture.
What I ended up doing is I had my own that certain places that stocked cameras had returned policies
specifically Costco.
I had known it because I've always been a shopper at Costco and if you live in a big city you probably
live near a Costco somewhere even if you live in a mid-sized city you can still drive to one.
They have a lifetime return policy and all their items with the exception of electronics and their electronics
is a 30 day return policy that return policy is any reason any time.
What I ended up doing I went and I bought the nicest camera they had.
And then I went to Best Buy and I bought the fanciest wide angle lens.
This is an important detail wide angle lens.
And they also had a return policy.
There's a little stricter 15 days and I did show the receipt I took those two things the camera I bought
at Costco is something like $4000 you know $4000 in a bank account just put it on a credit card or something
like that because you know you're just going you're turning it the next day.
I did a photo shoot day I took all the photographs that actually bridged the gap between what an iPhone
photo and Airbnb photos going to look like.
The difference in those two are immense.
Huge.
I think that when you first Lister listing a lot of people are going to be timid about booking say paying
a hundred dollars to stay in your living room.
If you take the photograph with an iPhone it just doesn't look professional.
And you're asking for money that implies that this is professional.
So that's how I kind of got around it I just knew that while I can go get a nice camera and I can just
return it.
It did a very good job.
One of the things I would suggest and you will pay yourself over the head when everybody shows up and
takes photographs because you didn't think about this is that they use flash that attached to the top
of their cameras and they point them forward.
And what that does is it shoots a blast of light right at the area that they're taking a photograph
of.
Making it artificially bright.
So if you look at the Air B and B photos you'll notice that they are artificially bright There's just
no way that room looks at that.
Right.
And that's because they use this flash.
I'm sure if you've seen professional photo shoot see something very similar but they shoot it against
like an upside down umbrella.
And that's so they try trying to prevent it from having these streaks from the light hitting whatever
they're taking photograph of.
That is something also you can get.
You can buy that at the same places you can buy that at a Best Buy and just end up returning it.
If you do that it will bring your photographs up to a point where they're actually quite passable and
it's a very good bridge to the point where you can actually get an Air B and B photographer coming out.
When I listed my listing I had inquiries with in something like seven eight hours and I took my first
booking within something like 12 hours.
I believe a large part of that was that my photographs looked really good.
They are not nearly as good as an Air B photograph but they were acceptable.
They were still high resolution.
They didn't have the same brightness because I don't have the technical skill of one of those professional
photographers but it actually ended up working out.
I think one of the things that's really important is that when you first put up your listing to not
get discouraged I believe that if I had put up iPhone photos and I had not taken some time with the
photographs then that might have actually been quite discouraging because I'd magine that I wouldn't
have gotten as many inquiries and wouldn't have gotten that instant validation that I did when I did
end up listing my apartment for real.
The alternative to this.
Just ask your friends.
Maybe one of your friends has a DSL or Seems like it's pretty common that people have DSL.
Now the price has gotten down and even the thousand dollar cameras are still quite nice.
Seems like amateur photographer is a big thing now and if you notice on you Dimi it's one of the more
popular courses how to take user DSL and how to take photographs and travel photography etc..
Chances are your friends probably has one.
So that's another way of doing that.
See if you can borrow their camera you only need it for a day.
Honestly if you plan it out beforehand it only takes maybe an hour later in the course.
We're going to talk about how to take the photographs.
What do you need in the frame.
What do you take.
What's the point of each photograph.
What do you want to highlight.
And that's almost as important as I'd say the quality of the image.
Obviously that feeds into what we consider a good photograph.
That's something not obviously to neglect don't just assume hey I got a great camera I can take photos
of the floor or take photos of every single angle of every single room and that's all I need.
That's not the case.
You need to put some thought into taking the photographs but at the same time you don't need to be a
professional photographer.
It is something I did and I am I have very few artistic skills.
If you guys have any questions post them in the group discussion.
And I am more than willing to answer them and help me through any of the problems you guys are having.