Let's talk briefly about last second hosting last second how is it and what do I mean by that I mean
that occasionally you'll get people who are asked to stay at your apartment or your place and will stay
very late in the day.
Is the second whole thing worth it.
Yeah I think so.
Absolutely.
There are great opportunities to get good reviews because they're only usually staying like that night
or they're very much last second.
They often will give you the benefit of the doubt and they say like oh wow you know Heaven was so accommodating
he let me come in at 8:00 p.m. not last second housing works for you.
It just depends on your space.
How quickly can you have it cleaned.
Typically I say that the best practice is that let's say that you have guests leave you if you don't
have an immediate booking coming up I suggest you clean it after they leave.
This is the case that you don't actually use the space but try to clean it after they leave.
So that if anybody comes and says hey I want to say tonight you can just pull the trigger on that.
Keep in mind also that if you are going to use the N.S. book strategy then you need to clean right after
they leave.
So they always need to have it ready.
Also I want you to keep in mind there's a lot of things keep in mind that a lot of those tips and tricks
I talked about before with gifts and flowers and things like that you might not be able to pull these
off because you don't have enough time so gauge that and you know if it's the case that you're getting
like raving reviews without it then whatever it doesn't really matter.
Just bear in mind you're not giving them your best but I think in most cases less second housing it
works for me.
I'm very flexible and I'm perfectly fine with that the only thing that might happen is they might if
you're sharing a space they might book on a Friday night.
So you have to wait for them to come in and a lot of times you'll have guests that are inconsiderate.
So they say they're coming at 7:00 and then they disappear till 11:00 p.m. that's happened to me before.
But if you have a system set up where you can handle these on the fly then you're perfectly fine.