Want to talk a little bit about one of the metrics in Air B and B that's often overlooked.
It's the response rate percentage.
Now when you look at Air B and B host you'll notice that they're the bottom they're listing it says
response rate.
And typically if the person's trying should be 100 percent.
He also notice that with hosts that have multiple properties and have been doing this for an extended
period of time it's actually not that abnormal to see them have some ridiculous number like 98 percent
or 99 percent.
So what that is when someone messages you air is just going to record every single time you respond
to them.
Now that sounds ridiculously simple but it's actually a little bit more complicated than that.
Now when I first hosted an Arab being B I thought that this was gonna be kind of a no brainer.
So in messages me Of course I'm going to respond.
That's not a big deal.
I was I was concerned with the response time like how long would take me to get to my phone respond
you know for instance a phone message of me at night.
I was a little concerned about that but I did not realize though is that when you're pop when your property
gets popular you can actually run into trouble with this.
A lot of times I will get you know I'll go three days without a booking and query and then on one day
I'll get eight sometimes three at a time and I'll explain later why that is why the air being Bea system
does that.
But that can happen you can just have an avalanche of inquiries and sometimes it just slipped your mind
that you don't you didn't respond.
Every single person now I almost had a little bit of a crisis with this and this is kind of a word of
warning.
When I originally started hosting you know I had one hundred percent up until three months and then
I had someone message me and it was a scam and that scam person messages me I read it and I didn't think
I had to respond.
So I did not respond.
And what ended up happening was that actually tanked my response rate and I CAD to go back find it in
my list of things and then respond to Air B and B and thankfully urban we hadn't removed this person's
account so that I could respond to it.
So I got back up to 100 percent ranked on your response time.
And so obviously it's very very important that you get 100 percent anything below 100 percent is just
not good when you look at other hosts and they're below 100 percent that say you know you have opportunities
and you know the person's not trying the best.
This should be a lay up.
You should always always respond personally the way I like to do it is even if I'm busy I like to send
a message to every single person who sends sends me a message and it's a very basic thing just saying
hey let me respond later.
So at least I know and worst case scenario I've responded to every single person.
So don't let this happen to you what happened to me if you get someone a sentence that sends you a message
you don't you're not taking it seriously at all.
Maybe it's a gas trying to book and you have no interest in what they're trying to book.
Maybe they're trying to ask for a massive discount or maybe it's someone who's just trying to advertise
something always respond.
Don't make the mistake I did even type Hi H I and send that to them.
That's how you get your hundred percent don't ever ignore your messages completely.
That's the worst thing you could do.
And I know if you're hosting a lot of people a lot of properties it could happen.
So the next lecture I'm going to talk about the other part of this which is the response timing and
how you can set up some basic strategies so you can minimize your response timing and how you can do
that once you become a popular property.