All right.
Welcome back.
So in this lecture I'm going to show you how you can quickly add some enhancements to your photos and
try your best to imitate that kind of pop effect that Airbnb photos have.
Now keep in mind when you do editing you're going to be limited by whatever you took the photographs
with.
Right.
When you take you know a photograph with an iPhone or even with your own DSL are the source image is
going to be the biggest constraint on how good your image looks.
However you can use editing programs to make them sometimes look better than they should.
If you go on Airbnb I'd look at some of their top properties and then look at their spaces.
You'll notice that they're all very very bright images sometimes they almost looks surreal.
MVB really has gotten this down to a science where they know exactly how to edit images to make them
really scream you know high quality rent my space.
So I'm going to show you a very quick hack to take photos you've taken yourself and try to improve them
as much as you can.
Keep in mind you're going to get 100 percent of urban bees photos but this is just a stopgap until you
can get the free photography.
If you're not in an area that has free photography I think it's just a matter of kind of waiting for
Irving and me to come out with free photography or follow some of the other tips and tricks in this
course where I can try to help you cheaply take the best photographs you can somebody give me an example
I used a DSL are to take this photograph.
This is my kitchen.
And as you can tell I clearly didn't plan out a lot of things correctly.
You can tell that there is a background foreground problem.
So we have a certain level of brightness here.
But then in the background we can tell that the sun is much brighter and it creates this weird kind
of effect in the back.
You can tell that because of the angle is having to take the shot some of the chairs aren't even illuminated
You can see over here.
This is basically what you'd expect if you took it off of a camera with a flash attachment.
These are this is you know as a source files a raw file is pretty good.
Don't really I would expect you off of your own equipment with no photography skills to get something
better than this.
I really have no photography skills is something I had to learn as I went.
But so now what I can do with this photo to kind of give it the air be and be a fact it's actually quite
simple.
Hopefully you guys on a Mac if you're on a PC I can definitely put some resources in the the addendum
to this course where I can explain to you how you do this with a PC but for Mac users it is super simple.
You're going to use I photo now I photo is free.
It comes with your software or because of their operating system you're using a Mac.
If you can't find it on your computer you might have to download it just go to the App Store search
for a photo.
It's always free.
They're constantly updating it and depending on what package you're on if you're on like Yosemite for
instance you might not actually have it on your system so quick and easy facts just search for I photo
in the Mac store.
You can download it very quickly.
When you do open it up it looks pretty much like any photo editor you've ever seen.
It holds all your photos even like will separate them by faces and whatever.
But that's our interest.
So to get started all you want to do is go up to file and you can go to import to library and then from
import to library you're just going to pick the folder that you use to put all of your camera photos
in.
I'm hitting the spinning wheel of death right now because this computer is a little bit slow but as
you can see here I have set up an image to give you guys an example.
I already have an imported.
But if you didn't have any port it you would look at it at airport and it's in a shop right here.
You just double click it open it up.
OK.
So that is the photo that we were previously looking at.
We can see that there's some kind of problems with it.
You know if you're using an Arab and be photographed you would notice that this area would probably
be a little bit lighter.
Some of the other areas might have a little bit more definition.
I can show you very quickly.
Here's an example of what air and B came across when they did mindspace you know.
So that's a photo they took of my kitchen.
You noticed that from the different street this photo and the other photo.
Look at my cabinets.
There's so much more yellow ish.
You also notice that back here there's a little more contrast.
First of all this is because they took this with a wide angle lens.
They also took it with a flash pointed forward.
When I took my photos I use the flash bulb pointing backwards.
My mistake.
So those are certain things I cannot overcome but I can do some certain things to kind of give this
veneer effect that air being done.
So all you want to do is go to Edit
and it's going to pop up a little side pain on the side.
OK go first it's actually an open up on quick fixes on quick fixes.
You have all of these quick fixes don't honestly touch these.
They're really for people who want to go through hundreds of photos at once and you just want to click
something really quickly and go through effects again.
I don't touch it.
It's not worth it.
So you want to go to adjust and adjust.
You have multiple settings.
One is levels levels.
If you toggle it from the left to the right this little middle indicator what is going to do is it's
going to shift the color spectrum of your image.
Same with these kind of ins.
If I pull this in it's going to actually limit my color spectrum.
And so all of a sudden you might see for instance some color leaving the photo because it's cutting
off the color spectrum so get rid of reds.
Now the Reds are going to pull that guy out.
Exposure exposure.
It just simulates how much exposure your camera had.
It really just ends up being kind of simulates having more light in the room.
Contrast contrast is the detail you'll notice in individual lines.
Saturation is one that and it uses quite a bit and makes the image look richer like the colors have
much more full body to them.
And then there's all sorts of these other kind of secondary ways you can modify it.
But the easiest way to do this honestly is to toggle three different things expose or contrast saturation
levels between the four of these you can usually try to get something that's very similar to air in
these photos.
Now there is no set way of doing this.
It really just depends on what photograph you have.
Typically I've noticed though so for instance in this I want to imitate the way that they made my panels
more yellow.
All I have to do is just take this and move it ever so slightly to the left and just You'll notice you
have the orange in my panels kind of went away.
It turned a little bit more yellow.
They we're clearly getting somewhere exposure.
This one typically what I would say is give it a little bit of a nudge.
In this case I'm not going to give it a nudge because I already have these areas that look like they're
overexposed.
And so you'll notice if I add more exposure somehow it makes it brighter.
But you're also having a problem where this chair is almost about to disappear.
So we can do is we can kind of settle for maybe a little bit of extra exposure.
Again this is a problem right here that I'm never going to get rid of.
I'm sorry.
Contrast the noise and add a little bit of contrast don't go crazy with this.
What happens when I pull it all the way.
Wow.
What in the world.
So you don't want that.
It's going to over contrast images and it ends up changing the colors because it's trying to create
a lot of artificial contrasts.
I just like to give it just a wee little nudge say like five that's good enough saturation.
Again you're just going to have to play this one.
Kind of picture the picture if you give it a little bit of a nudge.
And it's not going make a huge difference but typically M.B.A. photos are oversaturated.
So now if I was doing a photograph that was not as bright as this I might give a little bit more of
a saturation down here are secondary controls.
You can kind of mess with these.
Personally I like to throw highlights all the way up as you can see.
Now it kind of starts to get a little bit of an Arab feel.
Let's try to roll it back just a little bit.
Sharpness is when you don't even really particularly notice depending on what you've done and the other
adjustments up here and also down here temperature.
You can sometimes change it whichever way you want to make it feel if you want to make the image cooler
just throw it down a little bit see how that looks kind of like it's in the middle of winter.
I wouldn't do this because when it does of doing as makes the window light look blue which I don't want
that.
So let's go back to zero.
So all I did here was I gave it a little bit of exposure.
I changed the levels to highlight orange over yellow over orange.
And I just screwed a little bit with the highlights and the contrast.
Don't go crazy with these up here.
If you go crazy I can kind of ruin your photograph but this.
See what I've done now here.
It's really all I've done is kind of I call it adding the MSDE to the photo because all you're doing
is adding a little bit of flavor.
And as you can see a pullback.
The other one.
So now some of you might have an opinion thinking that this image looks better but that's not the point.
The point is to make the photograph look like something you'd see on air B and B.
So if you don't like the fact that Airbnb oversaturate over contrast their images that's not really
the point.
The point is to make it look as similar to the rest of the Web site as possible because they have set
their own kind of design standard.
Personally I think the it looks quite a bit better.
This looks like something that I could throw up Arabic in the logo up here and it look like something
that Airbnb did.
I think that when you guys do this don't spend a ton of time honestly you could sit here for days and
days and days.
I'll make it simple for you.
Try to modify your levels to get a warmer color than you use to add some exposure if you don't have
a lot of light in your shot.
Always add contrasts and always add a little bit of saturation.
Other things you can toggle with you can toggle with your definition and your highlights which honestly
to me I'm not an expert in the difference in contrast and definition but I see as I toggle definition
now you can start to see these drawers stick out a little bit more which is exactly what I want.
So I'm happy with this image.
It's got a little bit the air B and B veneer.
I've talked about this made a huge difference.
When I was posting my listings I took my amateur shots did a little amateur modification with a software
that's free that everybody has.
I spent honestly maybe 30 seconds at Image.
Not a big deal.
All I know is you need to go up an exposure up and contrast up and saturation levels just a little bit.
Don't get too carried away with it and voila.
There you go.
Now you have an image that looks like it's Air B and B quality.
You post that people will think it's an Air B and B photo and you'll start getting a lot of bookings
which is where we want to be.
Thanks for listening.