Here's another tip that I think take into consideration the more face to face interaction you have with
your guests the more likely you're going to get a good review.
I've known this from my own experience and I know this from looking at other people's listings and their
reviews.
Typically in other listings in the reviews you'll notice that the people who give bad reviews do not
meet the host there's always exceptions to this.
A lot of times people give a nastier view and at the very end they'll say like but the host was nice.
What you'll notice is when the person has met the host they typically give better reviews or they're
more likely to give a positive review.
It's another one of those things that I consider a smoothing tactic.
I don't think that it's the case that you necessarily have to meet with them.
I think in a lot and a lot of gas don't necessarily want it but it's never a negative.
If you're running out your entire apartment if you can be available to check them into the apartment
whether or not that takes five minutes 10 minutes or 30 minutes.
That makes a big difference.
You're showing them the space showing how things work and showing you some basic interests in who they
are just giving them some chats or reiterating that they can text you if they need any food recommendations
or whatever that's going to increase the likelihood that you're going to get good reviews if you're
running out your space.
Again you obviously want to have some face time.
They need to be comfortable with you knowing that you're sharing a space or they're running a private
room.
But in general keep this in mind the more you meet them the more likely they're going to give you a
good review.
Think about it the way that people view hotels act as if there is no human element to the hotel.
And in most cases it's just a hotel it's a big chain.
There is no human aspect to the person at the front desk.
Maybe that's different if they give you a really bad review that takes your reviews that could really
hurt your income.
Meeting with them reminds them that there's a human element to this when they see you and see that you
are renting it to them and it's a personal relationship and that's not them struggling with some corporate
brand that will make a big difference.
They're going to give you the benefit the doubt more often.
A lot of times that they have a bad experience they're going to say themselves it's over and there's
no point in me ruining the integrity of their review wall.
It's something to take into consideration if you can fit in an extra 10 minutes 15 minutes and you want
to meet them or you can meet them test it out see if it's something that you like doing.
If you're someone who's a little bit introverted it might be invigorating in the sense that you have
very short interactions with people but it also could be a little exhausting especially if you're running
out for one night fall or one night fall by one night.
It can be a little disruptive to your day if you're in a shared space.
However obviously I think that you're going to need to spend some face time with them.
This is something that you should take into consideration.
More face to face interaction means better reviews more likely to get positive views and less negative
reviews.
Do you need to spend an hour and a half with each one.
Absolutely not only if you want to and only if you know that they are comfortable and they want that
my level of interaction.
The sweet spot I've found is typically between 15 to 20 minutes.
If you do five minutes it sounds like you know you just do this all the time and they mean kind of nothing.
If you do 15 minutes 20 minutes gives the impression that you know you are into this space.
You do like hosting you do like renting but you know you're not selling this as a space that comes with
a friend because a lot of people want to draw the line especially once you get into the range of where
you're charging more.
You it people who are like yes that's nice.
We want our space sooner rather than later.
They're cheaper.
They're probably more interested in spending time with the actual host.
Do you need to do this.
Absolutely not.
But I think it's something that if you are noticing that you're getting negative reviews or you need
more positive reviews really catapult your listing because remember the more reviews you get the higher
up in the search listings you will list.
It's something that I think you should consider doing.