So I got a question from one of the students which was how do I take everything that you've taught in
this course and make it so my Arab can be kind of runs itself and I can leave the country or go off
the grid.
I wanted to explain this and specifically make a lecture for this since it was a question that was asked.
But also I kind of realized now that if you take the entire course you might not realize what parts
of these need to be stuck together in order to be able to leave the country and kind of run it like
I have.
So I've done this as traveling through multiple countries one of them actually I traveled through Cuba
which has virtually no internet access.
Whenever you do use the Internet you have to wait in line to use it and then it's ridiculously expensive.
And I was in Cuba for a month so it is very very doable.
Is what I'm trying to say.
What you have to do though is you need to focus on number one.
You need to identify all of the moving parts in your apartment.
So typically I would never suggest that someone try to do this right off the bat.
I would suggest you do this after you've had a couple for apartment rentals or at least a couple spare
room rentals because when you do that you're going to realize what are the things that can go wrong
and what exactly changes from one listing to another.
We can use my apartment as an example in my apartment.
What are the moving parts.
One of the keys.
So in order to get a guest and they need to have keys to get in and out.
And then they need to get those keys to the next guests.
So that's something that needs to switch over to.
I have a key card to get into the garage for the parking space that I offer to my guests so that key
card also needs to find its way somewhere where the next guests can find it.
3 I have a cleaner and they need to be able to get in before the next guests coming in and they need
to clean it pretty extensively so that it's ready for the next guest.
They also need to do laundry too.
So that's also kind of a something that I have to consider.
So when my cleaner comes after the previous guests they need to have a certain amount of time so they
can do laundry each time.
And so I need to know roughly that there should probably be say a three hour break in between last gasp.
Next guest orientation is another big one.
The next guests need to know how to get in how to get out.
They need to know how to use everything in the apartment and they need to know generally any kind of
rules about the apartment.
You know for things.
Those are the moving parts in my apartment in your place they're probably going to be very very similar.
You might have one extra thing.
But really it's just the keys.
For me it's the parking spot.
It's getting all the information to the gas so they can acquaint themselves and then it's getting a
cleaner in and out with a sufficient amount of time to clean everything and do laundry.
Just take a moment and think to yourself what would you roughly need to swap over.
There might be something extra kind of doubt.
It's usually just kind of the basics OK.
So the way that you would automate this now such that you can be out of the country away from cell signals
away from checking your email constantly is number one.
You need to have a rapport with your cleaner.
And so I previously had talked about the importance of picking a cleaner that's for the long term because
someone who's there for the long term is going to you know not only know where everything should be
in the apartment.
They're also going to know what's potentially missing.
They're going to need to know what's potentially broken.
And they're also going to need to know roughly what the standard of cleanliness is that you expect for
each guest.
Now if you keep bringing in new cleaners every single time you have to hire them them and then have
them clean and then see whether or not they did a good job.
So I would not suggest leaving the country and running this fully on autopilot until you have a rapport
with the cleaner.
If you guys have someone who lives in town and they or somebody who needs extra money and they can clean
your apartment you know they're diligent you know that they're responsible.
It's very easy then because you can just trust that person to know to come clean what you do is you
just send them your cleaning schedule beforehand.
And that's very easy because you're arean busy schedules right there you can even just screenshot your
schedule send it to them and they'll just know they need to clean on the 11th the 15th the 18th and
the 22nd you'll just kind of have a routine going down.
So that's number one.
Number two is you need to find a way of automating the key swap the way that I did this was I actually
just put the key and the map and it's not.
I mean that's not a particularly great way of doing it because things can actually go wrong.
But under the mat someone can step on the mat not realize it kick it out.
I've had several guests pick up the man that can't find it because it stuck to the mat.
It's not a good way of doing it.
So I would suggest doing one of many different things.
One you could have your cleaner have sets of keys.
And so what can happen is when your guests leave your cleaner can come use their key to get in and out
but then leave an extra key and collect the original key.
That's one way of doing it too.
You can use a lock box a lock box is really really simple.
Just stick it somewhere near your apartment and just give the code to your guests.
Obviously some apartments are not going to allow you to do that so this might not be an option so try
any other ones.
Another one you can do is there are a lot of these like fancy locks now where you can like wave the
phone at it use Bluetooth to connect and get in.
I did.
I mean at a lecture later on a Kickstarter that has made a very very interesting lock system called
the lock a Tron.
But right now if you go on Amazon and you look for wireless locks this is a kind of a little intense
in terms of how much an investment they are.
They're expensive but they are also very very useful.
They're locks that you install on your door and then people can get in through a variety of different
techniques.
They can just the door can be unlocked at certain times.
They can use their phone and they can use text messages et cetera.
Another way you can do this and this is popular in big urban cities is if you live near a corner store
or live near a coffee shop you can actually have them hold on to your keys.
In San Francisco there's a service that actually sets you up with coffee shops where they hold your
keys.
And that's actually I think that's pretty cool billing problem is what happens if your guests arrive
super late so they don't really I don't think they think about that a lot of times.
But the point is you need to figure out a way that's foolproof to get the keys to your guests each time.
And it's really not that complicated.
Lockboxes work really well if you have one cleaner You can also just have them hold on to your key.
I use a service called Handey be called handy book and they just have a key.
So worst case scenario they just put their extra key for the next guest.
So number three what you need to do is you really need to go back and read the section on copy pasta
trick.
And the reason why is because this saves you so much time.
You don't want to have to be able to check your e-mail write them a personalized e-mail every single
time they check in and check out.
And now I would suggest taking this one step farther.
Listen to the lecture on using the V.A. trick.
That's one way you can fully automate this if you don't even want to check your e-mail period.
Use a virtual assistant to automate a lot of the messaging kind of process what you do is you would
hire a virtual assistant.
You'd pay them you know a dollar or $2 or whatever and every time they send a message and you'd allow
them to log on to your airbourne B and you would give them the template emails and so they have to do
is pop in the person's name and they just pop in the message and send it to them and you could tell
them for instance you know 48 hours before the guest arrives.
I want you to send them this long block of text that welcomes the Apart welcomes them to the apartment
tells them how to check in tells them how to do everything in the apartment how they can manage the
heat what they can use in the refrigerator etc. etc..
And then what you can do is you can also tell them to post and I called the outro message which is the
day before they leave.
Send them a message saying you know thanks for staying.
I really hope you enjoyed your stay this say you know can you please leave the key under the mat when
you leave or can you put the parking pass on the table.
This way you can manage the way that they exit.
Now you don't have to do this with the V.A. if you are going to be a fraud or just out of town and you
know you're going to be free like infrequently checking your e-mail.
Let's say you're checking it once a day you can still do this so you yourself would just copy and paste
a template.
Introducing them to the space within some given time range.
And then you can send the exiting copy and paste any time during their stay just so they know roughly
what's the protocol for checking out.
OK so the fourth thing that you need to do and this one is really really mandatory so I have to stress
this is you need to start enforcing check in and check out times.
Originally when I started my listing I had flexible check and a checkout.
Now if you listen to my sections on you know minimum days on pricing strategies you can kind of get
the idea that at first you need to be as flexible as possible because you don't want to try to capture
as many bookings as possible.
But when you go abroad and you want to leave this on auto pilot I'm assuming that you have at least
four or five reviews and so you can you can do this you already have a steady stream of inquiries coming
in you're going to do is you're going to set your check in check out times and you're going to pick
something that gives you enough time to have a cleaner come in clean the space and turn it over to the
next guest.
So to give you an example I use 11 and 3.
So what I say is every guest needs to check out at 11 a.m. every guest cannot check in till after 3:00
p.m. That gives me a roughly four hours in-between so that the cleaner can come in and clean the cleaner.
Typically will take three hours with the extra hour gives me a little bit of a break.
Now those two numbers you can modify those you can set it to whatever you need maybe have a small space.
You can have them check out later and then check in earlier.
Doesn't really matter.
Just don't get excessive about it.
Right.
A lot of people are coming to your city and they want to drop off their stuff or they want to check
in because they've been traveling for a long time so don't get excessive with their check in times or
their check out times.
The reason that you want to set up rigid guidelines for this is because one of the biggest headaches
of managing an entire property listing is getting people out and getting the next people in.
Originally when I was doing this flexible flexible times I would have people check out super late.
And I even have sometimes guests checking in all the previous guests were checking out.
So you don't want to have to deal with that.
It's just an unnecessary level of management.
Again assuming you're traveling abroad you're probably got you're listening to a point where it's on
a decent footing so you should be fine it's going to deter anyone if you set checkout times.
And I think actually that's more of the norm.
I think if you look on air being be the vast majority of them have at least a check in or check out
time for main things that you need to do to get this onto into autopilot.
There are two other things that you can do that I think are more or less optional.
But I would strongly suggest doing them one thing is adding a guidebook and there's an upcoming lecture
about the guidebook and how helpful it can be towards helping people kind of integrate themselves into
your space.
The essence of what it is is that you make a little book or just laminated piece of paper or really
anything that you can put in your apartment so that when guests arrive they have just as little book
of information about pretty much what they should do in any type of scenario should it come up.
Now if you have that that reduces the management by honestly 60 percent so many times that I've had
questions from guests or guests call me or guest have to you know use my attention for something it's
because of something in the apartment that they don't know how to use.
And they weren't properly explained.
Now this guidebook goes a little bit farther than your just the copy paste message are you going to
send to them every time they check in.
Because you don't want that to go on for pages and pages and pages.
The guidebook is where you can really put as much detail as you want.
Everything about this space everything about the area popular restaurants things to do how to buy tickets
for events etc. etc. If you have that they'll use the guide book and they'll kind of self-service themselves.
Thing again this is completely optional.
But I would strongly suggest having it is just having a fallback person have someone in your town or
your city that you know that can help you in a pinch because even if you automate every single thing
occasionally.
You know one in a hundred something might happen that you could need someone in in law who's actually
local and in the city to help with.
So things like lockouts you know even if you do have a system where you give them the keys and they
hold on the keys you can't really help it if the guests leave the apartment and accidentally lock themselves
out.
Another thing might be noise complaints if you have neighbors or someone else in your apartment you
could get a complaint so you need to have like a point of contact.
There's a lot of different things that could happen and it's helpful to have someone there who can in
a pinch get something for a guest deliver keys or help make connections that you can't make because
you're not on the ground.
Again that's completely optional.
I strongly suggest doing it.