So let's talk a little bit about what is this going to take up for and to get up on air PNB and to start
making money on your space.
If you want to do this correctly it's going to take a little bit of time.
How much time am I talking about and it takes six months.
Now it's going to take you six months to take you a month now I no it's not going to you know month
in order to get your listing up in a way that is going to solicit inquiries and solicit bookings.
The way I look at it is you know is it the same amount of time you'd spend on building an actual side
business.
No.
No way is it about the same amount of time you'd spend on lunch today.
Now it's going to be more than that.
It depends largely on how big is your space.
Do you have a lot of areas that you need to do photographs of.
Photography is probably one of the biggest things what tools you have available do you already have
a DSL or camera on an iPhone.
What do you have.
Are you good at writing a description of your place.
Are you already familiar with there being be at all help because you're going to spend very much time
figuring out their Web site figuring out a set up the automatic text reminders and things like that.
I think it's important to set your expectations though the more time you're going to spend on this the
more likely that you're going to have a good start.
Let me tell you a little bit about what kind of false start looks like there is a distinct possibility
that if you do not spend enough time on this you just say oh I don't spend 30 minutes on I'm going to
take some photos of my iPhone throw it up put a paragraph.
Don't be surprised if no one asks about your space.
There is a concept that I like to call the minimum assumption of quality when you go to a hotel to a
chain or maybe you're going to a place that you've never heard of before.
Maybe it's a local chain.
There is a minimal assumption of quality because when you tack on the word hotel kind of how does the
assumption that in the worst case scenario it's still going to be this good.
Right.
So we're have a check in desk right.
So get out of bed Datchet minimum assumption of quality means that there's always going to be kind of
a minimum floor that you're going to pay for a hotel.
You always get the same basic bare necessities no matter what their B and B on the other hand is different.
They do not have a minimum assumption of quality.
How is this possible.
When they started out they were literally running out couches.
They were literally running out air beds air bed Air B and B that's kind of what the play on the name
as if you live in San Francisco you can actually go and rent the CEO and founder of couch and it cost
$40 a night.
That's how they started out.
They started out as this convention overflow Web site for people who just wanted a space to sleep and
people do run out futons they do run out air beds they do rent out just a spot on the floor.
Those are on Airbnb those don't make up the majority of listings by any means.
But people know that's the baggage you carry when you think of Air B and B and you go to their website.
So when I book a space I don't automatically assume that I'm going to be sleeping in my own room in
my own bed with my own things and that whether or not the person is going to be available to meet me
or I don't have any assumptions.
When you think about when you're listening your space there's a certain bar to get over.
Think about it from a hosting perspective.
It's kind of crazy right that you can rent out a space in your apartment.
We are in our living room for $180 a night.
That does seem crazy now you're stopping and thinking about and you're looking at that space you it's
even crazier is the fact you think so own pay that amount of money if you just took some iPhone photos
and put a paragraph description.
You need to do a little bit more than that because like I said there is a minimum assumption of quality
if you don't have good photos you don't have a good description.
You don't put a little bit of time into the stuff people are going to assume you're not you're not really
engage in this process they don't want someone who has one foot in the door on the other foot out the
door.
They don't want that they don't show up and not know what to expect.
There is a bar that you're going to have to jump over to get to your first booking and I really don't
want people spent 30 minutes doing this.
Put it up and say Hey Evan I didn't get any inquiries at all.
You need to do a little bit more than that.
You need to write a little bit more about your scription you do a little more thought.
Are you going to spend 40 hours on this.
No way.
And part of this course is that I'm going to show you everything that I did and everything I know so
that you can cut out 80 percent of the upfront costs and the upfront time and to getting your listing
up and starting to make money.
When I first listened MySpace I put a lot of time into it.
I looked at design magazines.
I looked at what all the people around me I looked all my competitors I studied the hotels and what
the offerings were and how they changed their prices and I looked at every single space and I tried
to design each space.
And I went and I refurnished my entire apartment and I did all sorts of things that were in retrospect
I think were probably over the top to get your first inquiry.
But I still implore you that you must put in a decent amount of effort in order to get your first inquiry.
It's realistic to think that you put less effort up front and then as you slowly improve yourself.
But here is the drawback.
The biggest drawback to doing that kind of incremental Lego every listing I get I'll try to all improve
it and then keep going.
The biggest drawback to that is when you first launch your listening is not going to look its best it's
going to be the first version of it.
You might have your first guest leave you a bad review if you did not take the time to think this through.
If you get a bad review and it's your first bad review that could be a game ender that could actually
be such a problem that when people are looking at this they're going to say hey I don't want a book
of his own even one review and it's negative.
I'm going to teach you on this course how to get around that how to deal with negative reviews how to
get good reviews and how to prevent people from saying things you don't want how to avoid that swamp.
I really want it to be something that you take want it to be a point of pride when you do finally hit
the listing button.
And when people do finally come in your space you are comfortable knowing that the quality is going
to be high enough.
Obviously How do you know if a call is high enough.
Taking this course will definitely help you.
And Sarah I'm going to walk you through what we have experienced and what we know as the minimum bar
to getting up here and starting to make money.
Think of the time and effort you put up front like an investment.
Think about how much this could potentially change the game for you.
How it can change your financial situation how it can open up a new way of connecting with your city
that you know you didn't think about before.
Consider what that's worth and then kind of take that into consideration when you then go and put some
effort into making your listing look good before you hit the button to make it public.
Like I said this is not going to be a colossal effort up front but I think it's unrealistic to think
that you getting that done in an hour.
I also think that you're going to have some cost up front but in the long run it's so negligible.
You know the way I think of it it was if I go and I purchased some extra things that might liven up
my apartment or make it look good in photographs.
How much are really spending maybe they spend 100 boxes and 150 bucks 200 bucks.
What does that in terms of a rental.
If that gets me an extra rental Well then I'm broke even.
And that's kind of the thing is that you will break even very quickly if you do decide to spend some
money up front but anyway.
Don't be afraid.
I don't think it's going to take as much effort as you think but it should require some effort if you're
not doing anything when you're doing something wrong.
But anyway throughout the course we'll walk you through pretty much everything we know that will make
you more likely to be successful and make more money.
Any questions throw him in the group discussions and make a private message.
Can you help validating your space.
You don't have a better idea of saying no.
How long is this going to take me or can it.