Here's a tip that I think will make a big difference in how quickly you go from new property to property
that is taking lots of bookings and making lots of money.
I call it hawking your calendar.
Basically what this means is pay more attention to your vacancies.
Something that a lot of people just don't put any thought into is a month's coming up.
They've booked out eight days or nine days out of the 30 days and that's it.
That is generally care about it.
They'll set on a Friday night and that's the weekend.
NO ONE books throughout the weekend.
Well I mean hocking your calendar I mean you need to look and see these vacancies as a problem go to
your calendar and keep lowering the price until you get people to book it.
If you're in a big market this is something that's always the case.
I mean I always use people that are looking at your property.
You can go to your panel and look at your page views to make sure you are in fact getting people looking
at your page views.
We're not getting bookings.
Keep learning your price if it's a day out drop with the price and have dropped to a price that you
think is even just worth it for you because what's going to happen is you're going to get the last second
bidder and you're going to steal the launch and other people who didn't move their price down what you
can do from nesses if you keep doing that and you consistently lower your price as you come up to the
date because you really want to get those bookings.
Now are you noticed like no one's booking this month I need to lower the price.
You're going to get a lot more bookings and you're going to get a lot more fill rates.
And most importantly are getting a lot more reviews.
Building up that review base faster than other properties is crucial.
Once you have enough previews in kind of maximize your price but you have to understand that you will
be comparing yourself to other people in your space and they're also gaining reviews as quickly as you
are.
So focus on what tactics you can use to get more people in and out to get more views so that you can
beat them in the review game you can pick up more per month.
You might actually surpass them if you're coming from behind or in front of them you might put a cozy
lead if this is the case that you're not incredibly competitive about this or you're doing a shared
space.
I think you should consider doing in a shared space Niiler this out when you feel like it or when it's
convenient to you.
I still think that you should identify the dates that it's most convenient to you and try to maximize
that time try to make sure that you do get bookings and even if you know say you know this weekend's
perfect I'm out of town and I want to run out my place and you're not getting bookings.
Sometimes I suggest lowering your price down to cost literally exactly what it costs you to rent it
just because you have the chance of getting a good review from that.
And that review itself will pay its off over time.
You guys have any questions about how to do this.
You know it's pretty easy to just go to air BMB look at your calendar.
Make sure that you check up with it.
You have a smartphone you can use Airbnb app and you can kind of fiddle with it there.
This just requires a lot more time on it.
A lot of people say I don't want to run this where I have a lot of maintenance I would say that this
doesn't take a ton of time.
It's only about 10 minutes a day maybe even 20 minutes today personally something that I find fun.
And so I was doing it naturally when I first started out I was just fiddling with the prices all day
long because it was kind of fun.
It's like watching this light bright board just light up in front of me as I took more booking than
I was clearly doing something right.
And so you guys kind of get in in that same kind of zone that I did have a lot of fun with that.
But I also think it's worth considering if you're only doing this casually as well.