Here's an idea to differentiate yourself from your hosts and mentioned this before just a little bit.
There was a host that I had seen in San Francisco who was doing quite well.
She had one property and then she had two and she had three.
And I think she ended up with four.
So clearly she's making a considerable amount of money.
Not that she can even expand it into other spaces.
Whatever she's doing was working.
One of the things I had noticed from her property was that she took photos of gift baskets that she
makes for guests.
This is a very good idea.
When you think gift basket I'm not talking about a basket full of chocolate and expensive fruit.
I'm talking about flowers or edible arrangements necessarily what I'm talking about would be something
like a small basket full of very small things that you can purchase in bulk assemble and have available
every time a guest comes in.
Imagine if every single gas that came into your space you gave a gift basket to.
Chances are that person's going to mention that in the reviews and it's going to be very hard for that
person to give you a negative review or at least it's going to raise the bar in terms of how bad their
experience must be to get a negative review.
And this is something that I consider a kind of an experience smoother in the sense that a gift basket
for someone else moves out the experience that they have bumps in their stay.
Something went wrong something broke.
I don't know.
And those things happen it has the effect of smoothing out those bumps.
They're less likely to notice them because in the grand scheme of things are going to say well at least
I got this free gift specifically gift baskets.
Here's an easy way of putting this together doesn't seem need to be a guest basket to give me a tray
it could just be something you could wrap up in thin wrapping paper because it looks like a gift.
Everyone loves a gift.
Can you imagine going to a hotel and they have a personalized gift for you.
You don't always want to go to that hotel.
I mean you think I can't do that I rent my space for $75.
I guarantee you you can make a gift basket for $5.
It's very very simple.
Here's one thing you could do.
Put a welcome to my space card.
How do you make a card.
How is that cost effective.
Well you can go to Vistaprint or any of those big print companies and they can literally print free
business cards for you and you can even design it in their app.
You could spend 15 minutes designing this card.
Do it in a little funky cursive font.
And they're free.
You just pay for the shipping.
You can get several hundred for maybe $10 is going to take a very long time for you to get through 100
guests.
Other things you know I live in San Francisco and I live near cheere a deli Square.
They have chocolates that are famous for so I like to include some chocolates in and maybe that's a
dollar per each because I bought them in bulk.
Small Things.
Eminem's those are 99 cents.
You can put a small packet one of those Halloween sized ones in it for you know 20 cents.
Literally anything you can put in it.
Earlier I brought up a tip of making a guidebook.
This is a great place you can put the guidebook in it or on top of it if you give them a tray and you
put on top of the tray the items that you want to give them you can put the guestbook inside of that
the guidebook or guest book and you can buy postcards as postcards if they're a picture of your city.
Think about the reason why they're coming up they're typically tourists you can work with that and put
it inside of it.
There's a lot of things like even tiny little figurines or something like that.
Remarkably cheap $5 even if they run it for 75 bucks or in our case 200 to 300.
What's five dollars.
It's something that would automatically put the beginning of their experience off on a good footing.
If you guys have any tips for this what you've put in your gift basket and I'm going to include a photograph
of one of these gift baskets if I can find the house that I was referencing earlier.
If any of you guys have tips for things that are cheap and easy to put in there you guys are going to
go crazy with it.
It could just be a couple of things that are really nice.
Everybody loves chocolate.
That's a great one.
Popcorn or popcorn.
Now everybody loves a welcome card or just a little piece of paper that gives your contact information
again.
They feel like they're being taken care of.
The more valuable the more likely you're going to get a good review.
But obviously keep in mind that you're running it out for a certain price and so you don't want to spend
too much on it.
If you do it I guarantee you're going to have 90 percent five stars.
Positive ratings.
You know maybe spend 30 minutes thinking about it 30 minutes putting together ordering the supplies
and then it adds an additional minute to your prep before each guest but it will make a huge difference
in terms of the guest experience that's going to translate into better reviews.
That's going to translate into more bookings and a happier experience for you.
Happier guests well make you happier.