Hey guys welcome back to the course in this lecture I'm just going to go over what the Course form is
what to set some expectations what to give you some advice how you get the information out of this course
the easiest.
I want you to be successful at putting your ear be and be the first step is understanding how this course
is going to work.
So we have a wide variety of different types of lectures a lot of them are like this or I'm talking
directly and you can see my face and we can shoot it quite literally in the space that I use.
Some of them are screencast I show you some computer skills.
So later on like for instance I'm going to show you how you can use a basic computer skills to take
photographs and then use that magic touch that Air B and B uses on their photographs.
And so in that case I'm going to show you how to do that on the actual computer.
The majority of the course though actually is just audio with visual representations to reinforce the
learning.
Audio is the most important.
And then I just kind of show images that can help make it stick in your mind.
At the end of each lecture we have these things called cheat sheets.
So if you've already watched all the lectures and you want to go back and review what you've done or
what you've learned you have a cheat sheet and it's just broken down into a very quick simple ways you
can get the essence out of each lecture out of the way.
It's fantastic if you've gone through everything and you just want a refresher.
It's also helpful if you're in a rush and you want to be lazy.
Yeah that's right.
Call you lazy and you don't want to listen to the entire audio.
You're not going hurt my feelings.
But you can use the cheat sheet at the very end of the course so I have attached an entire PowerPoint
that you can download and take with you wherever you want to go and use that as a review.
I've also attached a lot of resources to each section if you guys want more resources posted in the
groups discussion but they're just tools and things that I think are helpful will save you a lot of
time and make you more effective at what you're doing.
Again guys you can message me whenever you want.
I would suggest that you follow this course in a linear fashion.
I think that you're not really going to really get the magic necessarily if you skip huge chunks.
However if you were already a host you can skip a lot of the things about like getting your space ready
and things like that.
I still think they're very important to understand because I can teach you the fundamentals of what
works and what doesn't work and a lot of times you have to go back and change some basic things.
But of course guys you can always skip around.
Feel free to do it whatever way you want.
Now and again make sure that if you have a question you reach out to me I'm there all the time.
Guys I'm really enthusiastic about Air B and B because I think it's a game changer.
And honestly I've seen it change so many people's lives.
That's why I want to teach you this.
So you're having trouble at all.
Please do not hesitate to contact me because I will respond often within an hour we go away.
All right.
I see the next letter.