I want to talk a little bit about what are you going to do in the case that the worst happens the worst
being you have a guest and they leave you a bad review.
So I'm calling this lecture damage control what you can do to minimize the damage from a guest of a
new bad review.
Inevitably I think that if you do this long enough you will have someone that will give you a negative
review and it might be slightly negative or it might be very negative.
I've had a couple where they were making side comments side glances in their review saying it's great
but and I've gone through about 100 guests and only about one or two that had the intention to literally
leave a bad review.
So I want to talk you through what to do and give you a five step plan to turn this around.
If you follow these steps I think you can minimize the damage.
And if you're lucky you can completely remove the damage and completely sidestep this whole kind of
nightmare.
First off this is before you even start.
Need to establish what went wrong.
Sometimes it's not immediately obvious.
Sometimes I just put little weird snippy things in there review and you're not entirely sure what happened
he said.
He said that had a great rapport with the guest.
You know I verified that it was perfectly clean.
What happened.
First you can look at the five star ratings on your listing and see if you've noticed something move.
If someone gives you a significantly negative review you might see something new.
You might see a cleanliness go from a four point five star to a four star or something like that it'll
be pretty obvious meaning that they gave you maybe a one star.
That's her first hint as to maybe what their problem was.
And if you're lucky and they say in the review what the problem was then you know exactly what the problem
is this is how I tackle negative reviews and I try to minimize the damage Step one you need to message
the guest.
You need to message them and you need to apologize for whatever it is that they had a problem with.
You need to be careful.
You don't need to be accusatory you don't need to say that it's you know it's actually their fault.
They never asked for it.
It's OK to mention things like Had you asked I would have fixed it for you but you'd never want to make
it sound like it's their fault.
They're paying you to stay in your apartment.
So that's the last thing they want to hear.
The entire point of messaging them is to see if they can change their mind to only use valid excuses.
Don't really try to make some contrived excuse for you know if they say it was cold or they say that
the heater was broken don't say oh it works fine when I'm there kind of thing because that's too subjective
we don't know we can't verify that.
You probably weren't even there to check it when it happened.
But if it is legitimately the case that you showed them how to change the temperature and they forgot
how to do it you can mention that what I always do is I tell them outright I'm going to fix this.
And you be specific.
Don't just say oh well OK I'll make sure the next guest doesn't have this say I have some coming out
today to fix that or whatever it is you need to show them that they've identified a problem with your
listing and you're going to fix it immediately.
I usually think it helps to try to explain to them that Air B and B is not a hotel you can just say
basic things like you know I do this to help pay my rent or I do this so I can spend time freelance
writing or whatever it is that you do and you kind of say this is a lifestyle thing.
And then you can explain to them how bad you know negative reviews can damage your property because
a lot of times they think that oh I'm going to give them negative view and it's not going to make a
difference.
It really does make a difference so that they understand the actual damage they can actually they can
change their mind.
I to explain to them that OK you brought this to my attention.
I think it's an honest mistake.
And I guarantee you I'm going to fix it.
A lot of times people just say OK well that was the point to begin with I didn't want other guests to
come and you know you know that the heater doesn't work and they're freezing.
So if you stablish that sometimes you can get people that will change the review put some time into
this message make sure that you really actually come off as genuine and make sure that you do understand
what it is they're complaining about because you can't just pretend to address the issue.
It's going to come up in the future if someone goes out of their way to complain about it.
It's going to be something that someone else will find that they can also complain about it.
Guest have I think up to 15 days to modify their review.
So a lot of times I'll just delete it.
Sometimes we'll just modify it saying you know you know if it was an actual misunderstanding a lot of
times people say well we'll change it.
But a lot of times they just won't.
So then you go to Step Two.
Did they violate any of Airbnb review policies and has a lot of review policies that regulate what you
can say and review under what circumstances he can give a negative review.
They don't want negative reviews on their properties if they're not legitimate.
So they're kind of caught in a hard spot because they don't want good properties that make them money
to get unfair review in the same time they don't want to send people who are going to use their service
to properties that just don't produce good experiences.
So take a check and look at the reviews you can just look for eBay and be dot.com and search reviews
on their Web site and they'll give you all the instances where they've removed.
The biggest one is if they say something inflammatory if they curse or they say something derogatory
or they just make something that's completely unfounded.
That's something that could happen if they go to your three bedroom and they say no it is actually a
one bedroom and that's simply just not true.
Air being will strike that review.
Another one that I found in this actually happened to me is if a guest tells you that they wanted a
refund or a discount and they say they're going to give you a bad review if you don't that's blackmail
and B and B has a blackmail policy so you can sell air B and B Hey look at this tax message or threatening
to leave a bad review are being blocked them from being able to leave for review.
Kudos to them.
That's something that happens more often than I know and a lot of hosts just don't know that air being
B will protect you against that.
Most of the time they're being very reasonable about it but it's not going to make a ruling saying oh
the reviews too subjective.
They were not specific enough.
We don't agree because honestly it's he said she said sometimes in these reviews.
So you can't find anything that violates the review policy.
You know step three of you have found something you need to message them.
You can message them to their contacts and or number three.
This is the biggest one.
Make the changes.
If someone's complaining about something and they're compelled to put it in a review identify what it
is that they're complaining about and fix it if they're complaining about your neighbors being loud.
Talk to your neighbors.
Tell them to stop being loud if they're complaining that your fridge later doesn't work fix the refrigerator.
This is a big one.
If there's something in your listing that says you offer something and you don't you need to fix that
you need to make sure that you set expectations because you don't want people coming and thinking you
have a hot tub Jacuzzi getting there realizing you don't have a hot tub Jacuzzi.
Be honest when you say how close it is to other things.
Be careful about the hyperboles and the exaggerations that you use when describing your property because
this will come back to bite you.
So once you've made the changes and is assuming they won't change or review and Air B and B won't intervene
I say respond on the actual review.
And this is crucial if you see someone who has a negative view on their property and the host doesn't
respond.
That just spells out the host is just checked out.
It is important what you say and I think that first two lines of your response are crucial don't come
out and accuse them of being crazy or accuse them of doing something wrong.
Not saying this isn't the case.
A lot of times you just have crazies who just say things that make no sense.
I've had a guest put a negative review in another language and the things they said were just flat out
untrue.
They blamed me for break saying that I blame them for breaking something in my apartment when they did
break it.
I was gone the entire time and I came back and I found the shattered glass from a terrarium on the ground.
And there's nothing I can do with or B and B I can't just say like here's a photo of it.
This proves that they did it.
They're not going to strike that review because of one sentence.
So sometimes you do but you don't ever want to come off sounding like you're defensive sounding like
well that's just not true.
Other people have had a great experience.
Generally the best way of doing this is address the concerns.
You didn't just say I'm so sorry for this.
I did not realize.
And then if it is a legitimate misunderstanding like say the TV and say there is a TV and make sure
that that is the main thing you get across in your spots.
Anybody who's reading this is going to go oh this person says there's no TV.
Followed by her response saying there is a TV.
Here it is.
That will basically make them go oh OK it's just a bad guest.
And typically people are booking or forgiving towards that.
But if it's not a legitimate misunderstanding you just did something wrong.
You just need to address their concerns and then this is the best way of doing it.
You establish that you are going to correct the issue or you have corrected the issue and guarantee
that won't happen again.
The best thing to do is like say if they come in they say oh they said as a private room but it's missing
doors go get doors add them and then say I'm so sorry this is a misunderstanding.
I've updated my listing and I've added doors so any new gas coming in will not have this issue I guarantee
it.
It just caps off that problem someone looks at it and they go oh wow there's no doors and they need
luck and they go.
There are doors.
Case closed right.
They want to make sure that you're improving.
And if you do Consolacion proved the odds of getting a negative review are just going to dwindle and
the one thing that be careful when you do a response please don't drone on and on.
You know don't put a sentence that doesn't look good but don't put two full pages of response.
That just makes you look like you're exaggerating or are you going over the top.
The last step.
Step number five.
Hopefully it doesn't come to this.
Hopefully you have gotten them to remove the review change their review as being gotten rid of it and
hopefully you've changed everything that you need to but what you can do in the case of you have responded
and you do think it's significant it looks bad it does affect your reviews is typically you can respond
by trying to lower the impact of the review on your page.
There is a fall.
So once you've had five new reviews that page that's going to go to the second page you know 90 percent
of people are going to read your first page reviews and probably 30 percent are going to read your second
page reviews so you can kind of minimize the damage that way in order to do that typically what I would
do is I would lower the price for the immediate future.
So over the next week two weeks try to lower the price.
So what you'll do is you all get bookings that are much lower and then spend a little bit extra time
with them.
Previously we talked about maximizing the experience but there's a whole load of tips and tricks in
the section you can use to guarantee that you get a good review.
Try to pull out a couple extra ones make sure that the next four or five are positive because it'll
drown out the other one.
And if it's really causing a problem with bookings try temporarily lowering your price maybe 20 percent
25 percent to get people over that hump you all recover from as long as this is not something that you
repeatedly have problems with.
If that's the case you might run into a slog of trouble.
You guys have any questions let me know if you have any crazy guest stories.
I'd love to hear them if I think of any other worst case scenario guest stories.
All.
I'll post them in the extras section and you guys can laugh at my misery through those.
But if you guys have anything posted in the group discussion I will get to.