Now that we've established what it is that you want to list and whether or not you can list we need
to take a little bit of time to do some background research.
I call this laying the foundation.
I don't think it's going to take a large amount of time on your part maybe an hour or maybe two hours
depending on how into it you get.
But you need to do is start looking at your area on air PNB.
Typically the way you would do this is you just go to or B and B search for your area.
You can search specifically for the area.
My apartment was in an area called Fisherman's Wharf.
You can search for Fisherman's Wharf San Francisco and then set some dates in the future but not too
far in the future.
And then look at kind of what populates the another way of doing this is you can just search for City
and then drag the map towards the area and maybe the area and doesn't have a specific name.
You are not in a big enough city that has a neighborhood title for it.
Or you can search for the specifically the area.
The downside of searching specifically for the area is that sometimes the search engine doesn't specifically
pick up on certain listings.
So sometimes there are areas that are technically Fisherman's Wharf but it doesn't pick up on them Air
B and B also has a centric understanding of what constitutes each neighborhood.
Sometimes as a local you can look at this and say no it's not right that should extend up at least three
more blocks.
But first what you want to do is you look at the space here and now we're not going to do anything in
this lecture in the sense that we're not going to be working towards anything on your list.
We're not going to be building out a listing yet.
This is just so you can get a better mental idea of what you need to compete and what you need to be
successful on air B and B.
Now that you've searched for your area pick a very average let's say pick one person for two nights.
And the reason I'm saying one person is because of the search for one person.
Anyone who can accommodate up to one person.
So that's all the way up to eight people 10 people.
Everyone will show up.
Really what you're trying to do is you're trying to fish out every single listing that's available in
that area and you don't want to preclude any of the larger listings by search terms that are too narrow.
Because we're going to build a complete kind of profile around this to figure out what exactly should
your angle be in the next couple years and then talk about how do you take all of this information.
How do you turn it into a strategy immediately just start browsing the spaces around your area.
Personally I like to pick the first property that's the absolute closest to my property.
This is a generally a good idea to see kind of what an anchor point is going to give you an idea of
what people are running it out for and what other people think about your specific area within your
neighborhood specifically.
Like I said we're in Fisherman's Wharf now.
There's a big difference whether or not you are located on Larkin Street or you are located on Hyde
Street.
These are two parallel streets that are right next to each other.
What's the big difference.
Highstreet has a cable car line on it.
That's a big plus for tourists that's a big plus for anybody who's never been to the city before and
once to get the quintessential San Francisco experience.
Now if you're on Larkin Street which is literally a block away I mean it is a one minute walk.
You don't actually have this.
That street feels like there's not as much attention on it is a big difference.
But in terms of distance it's actually very small.
Now that's why saying look at a property that's close to you and ideally look for a property that's
going to be similar to what you're listing listing a private room.
Let's look for a private room that's physically close to you.
If you're missing a full apartment look for one that's physically close to you.
But then look for one that offers kind of similar amenities maybe of a two bedroom look for a two bedroom
that's closest to you.
This is going to give you a good idea of what is the production quality of the other listings around
you.
What's their popularity and what's the host quality.
Now what do I say about production value.
Look at the listings.
How nice are the photographs.
How many amenities do they offer.
How well-thought out are the actual images.
How long is the description.
How long are the reviews.
That's always something that's worth looking at.
Long reviews mean that the hosts are putting a lot of time into the guest.
Shorter reviews typically means that it's a situation where they probably don't have interaction with
the guests they hand off the keys and they just kind of go.
Typically someone who has very little interaction a host will give a shorter view.
They'll just say great area great space.
I prefer it if the dishwasher worked.
If you have an actual relationship with the gas and people are actually putting effort into it you'll
see those in the reviews very quickly back to production quality.
Take a look at some of the properties around you.
Look at their amenities list.
Are we talking about areas that are clearly college students listing out their separate space or listing
up their apartment while they're gone.
You can tell that there's clutter in the photographs.
You can tell that it was taken on an iPhone they didn't actually take the time to get the Airbnb photos.
Take all of this mentally into account.
Are we talking about apartments that have hot tubs and roof deck or are we talking about spaces that
don't actually have anything they don't even offer laundry it's clean laundry across the street.
They're not going to offer a linen service.
They're not going to offer a stocked fridge.
It's really just you get what you get.
Production quality just take a gander FBN me has a kind of skews this a little bit in the sense that
when you look at their page they have put a lot of thought into their page design.
They are well known for having some of the best industry leading design in terms of tech companies and
Web site.
They do a very good job of making everything look good.
So take that out of your judgment and look at the listing itself.
Let's look at the description.
Does it go below the fold.
What I mean by that is you have to click the More button the More button that means the person really
put some description into it.
They're really planning on this being rented out anything that's shorter than a bold will typically
mean that someone threw this up as an experiment or something that they're just not particularly putting
a lot of thought into.
Now that's only one dimension that you can use to look at the properties in your space.
The next dimension that I had mentioned was popularity.
You're going to use some of the skill set I introduced earlier in the course where you can go and take
a look at each property look at their reviews look at their calendar to figure out how popular are they.
You remember from earlier in the course of an essay in general you want to shy away from the calendar.
But in this case I think it's a decent tool to use to figure out what bookings look like how what is
a fill rate look like the gold standard for telling whether or not something as popular as the review
you want to look at the properties you want to look at the reviews and you want to look at the density
of the reviews.
Did they get the real reviews this month.
That is typically a very good sign.
That could mean that they are booking a lot.
That could mean that they're booking not so much.
You can't always tell what the ratio of guests that stay to guests that stay and leave reviews are in
most cases it's going to be two to one or three to one depending if you host them.
They're typically going to leave or of you more often.
So you do not host them then they're going to leave review less often.
But again the quality of your listing will often necessitate more reviews if you really have a cool
quirky kind of space.
People are going to review that a lot more.
And when we're talking about popularity which was the second kind of item that I listened out you want
to focus on let's restrict this analysis towards the top say five to 10 listings depending on how much
demand is for your area.
And also when I say area you don't have an area title it's the area that you squirrelled your map over.
And what listings show up because it'll it'll create a custom search showing what the top listings for
that space are.
So if you do not have an area title then we're just talking about whatever shows up in your search listing
for your parameters for the space that you're viewing because you know your space better than anyone
else.
That's probably your area.
So now you have your area and you have the top search listings for that area.
You've essentially isolated out the listings that have hosts that are probably more engaged in the general
population on air B and B the population of hosts.
You see people who actually have a track record of hosting typically on Airbnb you'll notice that there
might be five to ten power listings in each area and then you have a trailing end users who try it every
now and then or never really got into AD.
Are they listed in an abandoned.
So you really want to take that second portion those people that are casual users are not particularly
into it out of the equation.
Look at the top five to 10.
So you have your five you have your 10.
Maybe it's three maybe it's even just two that you notice are pretty active.
Take a look at the reviews again.
We use the skills from before how do you determine the general popularity of a listing or just do that
now for that five to 10.
If you have a lot of properties with a lot or abuse and a lot of high density of reviews meaning that
you have lots of people booking within the same month and leaving reviews Typically this is a good sign.
Maybe you're in a hot spot hotspots are good hotspots can command a premium.
Now if you're not in a hot spot it doesn't necessarily mean anything.
You can always lower your prices or you can always find some angle that someone else can't capitalize
on.
They live in an area that's not as central but say you have more space you can use that as your angle
to capitalize on it.
Sure people will come and they want to be in the central area but they might give that up if you have
free parking or they might give that up if you have extra space because they're in an extra large group.
Maybe they have a kid they won't have an extra room for their kid but they want to pay extra for that.
There's always an angle for it.
Take a general look at what your popularity looks like for this spot if it's abysmal.
No one's getting any reviews.
That doesn't necessarily mean anything but that's generally negative indication.
Maybe you lower your expectations for how often you book when you look at the calendars.
And before I said not to do this but you can do this because you're doing it a holistic approach you're
looking at multiple listings look at their calendars let's say next month.
And here's a general rule of thumb in my market and we were a top 10 percent Airbnb hosts we would typically
book out about two months in advance and then a month before if you'll get the month forward generally
popular listings we'll book out farther in advance so that's why you want to look at the next month.
And then the next month thing just get a general idea of how quickly the bookings taper off.
I'm recording this in November.
If you look at the let's say a week they are and now how many of them are full this week.
How many of them are full next week how many of them are full the week after that.
Now look at the next month for all of them.
Is it spotty.
And what I mean spotty are the majority of the spots the dates taken and you just have kind of a hodgepodge
of like two days here three days here.
That generally means this is a good area and it could mean that it's a good host.
That's generally a good indication of the least demand.
And if it's a case that let's say next month that only the weekends are booked out or something like
that that might actually mean that the person turned off the weekends.
But if everybody's doing it that might mean that your spot typically gets more on weekends.
We're going to talk a little bit more about pricing strategies in the future lectures and we can go
over.
How do you adjust your prices for things like weekends or things like weekdays.
There's typically more demand for week ends so you can always raise your price on weekends.
Again here five to 10 you're looking at the calendars.
What does anything stick out to you.
Is it that they're all booked really far into advance.
You know these are some really hot properties in a hot area.
It could mean that it's an area that they turn off their listings a lot.
Generally all five to 10 are doing that.
That wouldn't mean that centricity of the hosts.
It means that there's a pattern going on.
Look at the holidays look at typically the most popular time to run a house or rented Airbnb is going
to be December 24 25 and 26 and then the secondary most popular I've seen as New Year's Eve New Year's
Eve in that little like three day period covering that those are really really popular times.
That's what a lot of people are vacationing.
Thanksgiving is also popular but a lot of people go home for that.
So they're not exactly renting.
Look at those.
That's generally a good indication if those are booked out.
That means that this is a good spot that typically people are doing something right and that means that
you're entering a space where there's plenty of money going around because if they're already booked
out and is make a judgment call if it's two months before Christmas and every single one of the top
listings or rent it out for Christmas that means that this is a good area.
And there's also excess demand.
Surely there's going to be booking for Christmas a month before or even two weeks before so surely someone
is looking for that and you might be able to capitalize on the price by doing that by being able to
raise it because you're the last place that's available now.
The last metric I want you to use when you're taking a kind of a gander around your space is host quality
house quality.
I base this off of a couple of things.
One the actual review quality that's a big one to look at the host metrics and on every air B and B
listing you're going to see metric saying what's the response rate what is the host's average time for
response.
Those are typically things you want to look at look at their profile even sometimes you can get a kind
of idea if they put a lot of time into their profile is their profile picture grainy Graney someone
has a actually a quality professional photograph that typically means they are more invested in it.
But really those are the kind of the only two I consistently gauge and I'm looking at things like host
quality.
Now later we're going to talk about what you can do to capitalize on good host or bad host in your area.
But right now we're just trying to get an idea of what the host quality looks like around you.
Some cities you know a lot of college students are listening out to their host called these lower or
it's the case that it's newer and newer means people aren't putting their full effort forward putting
their full weight into this so the quality is going to be lower.
But the number one thing I want to look at when I'm determining HOUSECALL is look at the reviews the
length of review will typically mean a better host but it doesn't really it doesn't necessarily mean
anything you need to read them don't read years and years of them but read the last couple of months
and see what the general kind of ebb and flow is.
Typically I like to do some digging and actually go back six months and see what the negative reviews
were.
Long reviews don't necessarily mean positive but you have to read them to tell sometimes you can have
a raving negative review and they just go on and on about everything wrong with it.
Here's another thing to look at when a do you get that raving long the review does the host respond.
Hosts are able to post a public response to reviews.
It is always the case that you should do this especially if it's negative.
It's actually a good idea to post when you know positive ones just saying something like Thanks for
staying and then insert some personal detail about the person.
You'll be surprised how few of people capitalize on that.
Even more so you'd be surprised how many people don't even respond to negative reviews.
They're not responding to negative reviews they're not taking this very seriously.
They're not particularly professional about this.
That generally means that there is a space between good hosts and bad hosts and it might be the case
that this host is bad but if they're still getting bookings that's generally a good sign bad quality
steel getting bookings that means there's space it's ripe for a new entrant a new property the space
to be capitalized on.
If you look at reviews this is one thing I like to look for look for consistent themes in the review
there's something about their place that can't change.
And what you'll notice is even the positive reviews they'll mention something like that in our property
when we are doing it private review we inverted a large room into a bedroom and rented that space out
of that space since it was a living room.
It didn't have a door.
And so even in our positive reviews you know I was getting all these postings saying there's no door.
Everything else is fantastic.
Now when you're looking at other properties are going to look for things like that you're going to look
for these themes.
Use this as a general judge of quality but not take a quick gander at the hosting metrics look at general
those five to 10 properties in your space.
Are they all 100 percent response right.
That's typically what you want to see if anything's below 100 percent.
That means that the host screwed up.
This standard is 100 percent you should have 100 percent period.
Anyone who's taken this even remotely serious will have a 100 percent response rate because they know
that arean be judges you based on your sponsor.
The other thing is the response speed.
You don't necessarily have to be within an hour.
It's not going to be detrimental if you respond within two or three on average that if you have some
that says within a day you know that they're getting booking inquiries and they're just getting killed.
That means that people are booking and they're just or they're looking to book and they're just abandoning
the page because they don't respond within a couple of days.
Those original things you want to look at so to kind of bring this full circle.
You want to look at the popularity of your area.
Does it look like there is a lot of booking a lot of action going on.
It look like a lot of people are making a good site and come out of this area.
You want to look at the hosts.
Do you have a lot of low quality hosts in your area.
If that's the case its popularity is a little bit harder to determine because that host will shew away.
But you know potential money and potential booking inquiries.
Maybe it's the case that air space has really good professional or semiprofessional people who really
put a lot of effort into this.
And I think the other thing is the minute lists are you in an area that's going to put you at a disadvantage
in terms of amenities like I said are hot tubs and rooftop bars and you don't.
That's not something you can change a does anybody at parking and you don't have parking.
That's something that's worth looking at.
So look at all the three day Saints this is kind of a mental exercise it's just check out this space
see what it looks like.
You'll get ideas and you'll see what other people are doing.
You know I can do that with my space.
It'll give you a general idea what you're kind of entering and lay the foundation for how you're going
to be successful at listing your air B and B because now you know what you're competing against.
Now you know what bar you have to jump over if you want to be in that top five top three in the search
listings and you get the most bookings.
I know we covered a lot of content in this lecture and I'd love to elaborate more on it if you guys
want me to take any little nugget in here and do a deeper dive.
I'm more than willing to do that.
A lot of these subjects could warrant an entirely separate lecture.
But yeah any questions post them the group discussion.
Send me a private message.
More than willing to help out in the next lecture.
We're going to go a little bit deeper into this how do we do our pricing strategy our listing strategy
with regards to what other people are offering what's their pricing.
We call it the product position because you know I'm a business person I considered a product.
It's your apartment so it's apartment positioning.