OK so what at what point can I actually deduct rent or mortgage if it's regularly and exclusively a
listing on your property.
So for example if you have a three bedroom apartment and it's you have one bedroom that's exclusively
rented out.
And then you could that can be considered tax deductible.
That doesn't mean that it has to be rented out the entire time but it always has to be listed on the
air.
Gotcha.
One one question I know that a lot of people have is if I have a property in a different state and I
live in another state like say I live in California I have a property in Florida.
Do you end up paying the income to Florida or do you end up paying it to California because there's
two different state tax rates yes.
So generally speaking we have to have multiple filings they don't we we file.
So you know if we are if we have a yes hosts who say unreasonable you may have to have an airy rejoicing
I realized how can I have no idea what to do about his tax situation.
And it was really all right something that was really startling and also depressing that Abbie there's
so many kind of separate taxes and opportunities that he could take since is this is just is my job
in corporate America.
Make sure that how are in his green shirt.
Never look back there was a slide that was in between us I know that it is.
But that's the bulk of our climb told I was 8 percent of the gains that we have.
I mean only because everything is pretty good really.
We have a lot more.
And what why does is he.
Or is securely through our going he let it out with him tomorrow.
So I think it's also.
And that's how in a in elections like stuck on various pitches.
So it's that business expenses you need to have the zeem the date the amount and the central business
characteristic of the expense and all that is clearly shown on each of the cards.
So even if you slide over the screen and you want to split the middle yes or no just slide over the
screen shot in if you can press play it.
The screen shot plays Yes.
How fancy.
So you know you can see how much your tax deductions are going to go.
One it was sure the economy and the other one is right now.
So you know this is a great way to make sure that we try to really exceptions where you don't know how
much income it is out on expenses.
You have some money saving opportunities.
So you know around tax time at around the estimated tax filings you know it's never a surprise for you.
OK.
So so just kind of briefly covered.
Tom I realize that no one was talking to third parties you know.
So you're still arguing that you are getting from it's 2015 what you mean.
So it's a one time when I was once asked.
So it's one tool that you made is that specific to you on an artist and Jataka forms of life for two
or independent coping with.
And many who are so quick little snippet to know.
All right so your job is to contact parity of these contacts him Derek.
Sharon you ought to be talking about it.
I don't even try to talk to her.
So I wanted to finish with a couple other questions.
The next one question I had was I know that some Airbnb hosts have multiple properties and they incorporate.
So what point in time do you want to incorporate and when you do it what do you want to do.
Like an LLC and ask for pacy Corp. Yeah.
I mean I'm definitely no lawyer so I'm I can just kind of get general advice on this but I mean personally
speaking from a tax perspective if you have a pass through L.L.C. that's pretty that's a lot less work
from my perspective as you see Corbier S-Corp where we're by if you're Secord press corps you know you
are you're finally in a love in 20 which are corporate Hearn's and 11:29 and loving to us.
And then at what point should you incorporate you know it's really a case by case study.
And I think it incorporation really helps if you if you have a lot of personal assets that you want
to kind of protect.
So so yeah I think you know if you if you see that you'd like to do air B and B for time and you can
you think you can grow and build a business from it.
That might be a good time to think about.
You either incorporate or getting the LLC.
So you don't think there's.
Yeah I didn't realize that but if you're a C corporate S-Corp you'd end up paying corporate income tax
right.
S-Corp has passed through taxation both Secord correct so Secord generally like few if you want to get
an outside investor.
You know you have 100 properties and you want to grow sequent might then be preferred but if you're
just you know a mom and pop and you have one airbreathing be a property and you're funneling a C corp
you're going to have to pay all corporate taxes.
You know personal income taxes going to a certain degree double double.
So theoretically an LLC or an S corp could protect an Airbnb hosts against the worst possible outcome.
I mean I know that some we have some kind of umbrella insurance from Airbnb But does the LLC help a
little bit more.
Yeah.
So anytime you get kind of incorporated or LCD it does provide you know it does provide liability protection.
But in all honesty I don't really know.
I am unfortunately not a lawyer so I can't really speculate on the degree and level of protection that
you would get.
But I do know that you know a lot of hosts who own their property and then maybe another property they
do seek to get LLC.
OK so one other question I had was about the depreciation of your property because airplane be any vacation
rental property depreciates faster than if it was just sitting there being used by yourself.
How do you handle that in terms of tax deductions.
So.
So one quick thing to note on depreciation is you can depreciate the house you cannot appreciate the
old man.
And you know depreciation generally only comes into play if you own your own home.
So if you're renting you wouldn't appreciate it.
So you know it is kind of a case by case study of so.
So yeah there's certainly no real blanket ansaphone depreciating your property.
I know.
So I know that some of the students in the course actually own their own home and they're running it
out.
But do you have any idea how you would even tackle that.
Like how would you figure out how much is depreciated.
Yes.
You want to look for it you know depreciating your home is a little bit more tax technical.
So to try not to confuse your audience you know it just really depends on how much you purchased your
home.
You know what's your basis.
What type of improvements did you make to the property.
You know and then what type of depreciation schedule you know your property goes on that there are certain
different types of depreciation schedules that you'd want to go to.
But in terms of that if you're in Irving be host and you think you are doing your taxes and you want
to depreciate.
That is absolutely a time to go talk to a professional.
I definitely would not recommend anyone try to depreciate their home without seeking professional guidance.
First Ok let's see.
One other question I had was about audit triggers so we've identified that if you have a mismatch when
you're ten ninety nine and what you claim on your taxes that's pretty much an automatic trigger.
What are other triggers that you're aware of.
Yeah.
So the other one that those really popular three years of operating is on schedule C.
So what triggered the IRS is that you're operating.
Is that your schedule C activity is a hobby is hobby income and it's not truly a business.
It's simply operating to make a loss which is what this low.
So you know generally speaking another audit triggers three years of operating losses on your schedules.
Have you run into Be House that have been running unprofitable properties for multiple years.
I'm not.
Yeah I have had a client that had a huge loss in their first year with us because they had to get everything
else.
Gotcha.
Are there any there.
Because Arabs can be is treated differently in every city.
I'm in San Francisco and we just tried to figure out this occupancy tax thing.
Now we have all these rules on how much you can run out for how much and things like that.
Does the rule for taxation different in.
Have you ever noticed any states that make it really hard to claim your Airbnb property or where they
have a central roles that you have to do everything differently.
Yeah I mean I think what we're seeing is just the local news properties are just really trying to catch
up to technology.
I think it's going to be a matter of time before me.
Most of us are paying more taxes and whether that's you know actually factored in the cost.
And after you know so say for example here you're renting your room for $100 they may add on the additional
taxes after after the fact.
But I think it's just taking the cities all time just to catch up though.
Are you aware of any places that you have to pay like hotel tax.
Yeah Assef is collecting it right now and I foresee that you know in the future deploying more cities
are going to start collecting it because you know they're not on tax revenue.
Well so NSF the way they do it is the host doesn't see that tax at all.
We just noticed that if someone goes to our booking page it automatically adds it as another line item
expense on their book.
Have you ever seen it go the opposite way where like the host is now or is responsible instead.
Will the host should be responsible for their occupancy tax just because it's not being collected on
your behalf does that mean that you have to you haven't paid.
And I have spoken to the host who have been paying the local city's occupancy tax.
So you know it just because it's all been blocked it is I mean you don't have to pay and I have talked
to hosts that have been responsible have been paying.
So you know it's important to stay up to date on that.
Gotcha.
Let me think.
No I don't think I have any other questions.
So if anybody has any specific questions they can post it in the group discussion or you can always
email Derek Derek at shared economy CPA dot com.
Did I get that right.
It's hysterical at your Web site.
Yeah.
You know d r d k d r e.
K cool.
Yeah.
All right.
So if you have any questions just let me or Derek know otherwise I hope this is helpful.
OK.
You know I think your to live in.