So I'm going to talk a little bit about the question that I think probably everyone up until this point
is thinking to themselves probably sitting in your chair or maybe you're in your living room and you're
looking at the area or the apartment that you're hoping to rent out yourself.
But it can't possibly be true.
And I could rent this out for a lot of money and I'll be honest that's what I thought at first too and
I think that's what a lot of air B and B hosts thinks of themselves.
There's no way that this is worth anything.
Maybe it's unimpressive to you because you live there you're so used to it it's there's no novelty to
it kind of has that same attitude about your town to wherever you live.
It's not worth seeing or paying lots of money to live here and have the experience I have every day
and I'm going to tell you that's probably wrong.
I want to set expectations.
I want people to be realistic about whether or not they can loose their space.
And I'm going to separate out this lecture into two parts in the next section we'll talk about realistically
whether or not the space inside your home if you're running a side apartment or your full apartment
whether or not that is something that is up to snuff compared to what's available in this lecture I'm
going to talk more about whether or not you can qualify or how to qualify your city your location whether
or not that is something that's going to allow you to do this and take advantage of the benefits of
home sharing.
I think that it's too it's worth looking at this with a tinge of optimism.
When I first started renting out Airbnb it was quite new.
It's one of those things that's like a lot of the Silicon Valley crazy ideas that everyone says that
sounds strange.
And then 45 years later it's just a fact of life.
That's another option.
And the vast majority of people use it or have heard about it.
I think we're kind of in a situation where the majority of people whether or not they're tech savvy
or not whether or not they're in the millennial generation or not they've heard about it.
It's no longer an early adopter thing.
My parents use it.
Most people probably listening you know people who use it or have used it or maybe their parents have
used it.
It has bridged generations so it's becoming more and more of an option everywhere.
It's not just limited to the big cities anymore.
I'm going to be honest.
You have an advantage if you're in a big city.
And the reason you have an advantage in a big city is that hotels are in a higher density.
Prices have gone up more of an opportunity for you to offer your space out but it's the case now that
midsize cities and even small cities.
This is definitely something that's possible and I'm going to help you through a little bit about how
to think about this and when not to validate is it worth going through the effort of posting it.
I going to tell you right now most of the time it's worth it.
I think it's worth considering a little bit about what do you want out of this when you're hearing me
talk about my space you're hearing Sarah talking about her space.
What did you think to yourself do you think.
You know I own my home.
I'd love to rent out the side efficiency kind of room three times a week get an extra 300 bucks a month.
Or are you thinking oh that fantastic.
I'd love to travel for a month and just rented out.
I'm going to tell you a little bit whether or not those options are available to you depends on the
city because certain cities have more density.
They have more bookers coming in and looking at the city.
And so a more popular destination is going to have more bookers which means that Europe the possibility
of running out your space in the second scenario becomes more likely you are always going to have the
option of being able to rent it out sometimes to get some extra pocket money.
That's always going to be on the table to illustrate my point.
This is actually my hometown and two years ago I never would have thought that people use Air B and
B to go to my hometown.
My hometown is only about eighty five thousand people it's a mid size small ish city it's not a New
York City.
It's not a city with a million people it's not a Denver Colorado with a 600000 population it's about
85000 and it's primarily a college town.
And what really shocked me is that in the last year has really picked up in this small city.
People are listening out there space and they're getting reviews what I'm interpreting from this is
that people are booking out.
People are looking to the space and saying hey the city is saying hey Air B and B is an option.
It's something that we can do.
We don't have to stay at hotels and Aramean be as competitive in the space so don't be dismayed if you
live in a small city do be dismayed if you live in a mid-sized city.
Whether or not you can fill out your apartment 100 percent.
I don't know.
Say Lawrence Kansas.
I don't know if that's the case that you can do that I think and this is my intuition saying is that
you might not be able to get a 100 percent fail rate but because rents are lower your going to be able
to make money on top of it because you'll notice that ere being B you still rent out roughly around
what a hotel would charge.
That's like a price of a hotel but you get so much more.
And that's how you get the most bookings and the best bookings in small towns mid-sized towns is the
possibility really anywhere.
And I don't think you should ever rule this out automatically in your head saying I don't live in a
city that wants to go to.
I don't think anyone wants to go to my hometown.
But this is a town that you could get a duplex for $250 a month and people are running out their homes
for $400 a night and they're getting booked.
Is this happening.
And it's not just a once a month kind of thing it's happening multiple times in a month.
People are making money.
I want you to consider where you live.
The first thing you want to think about is realistically whether or not this could happen.
Do you live in an area that has the right demographics for Air B and B.
Like I said before everyone uses Airbnb now but there's a higher density within certain age groups if
you live in a college town chances are people in that college have heard of it.
Kids are those people are going to come back to visit.
Chances are they have friends who are coming to visit.
So it's very possible that area be as popular and you have people searching your location on air B and
B if you have that demographic.
Another way of identifying some demand is what are the reasons why people come to your city.
Do you have conventions.
That's interesting if you have conventions chances are hotels are going to fill up and chance are those
people that come to the conventions travel enough to know what Air B and B is in my hometown.
It's a college town so we have big football games.
We have basketball games and those happen quite regularly throughout the year so we have people coming
to visit all the time.
Maybe you live in an area that has great hiking or great skiing snowboarding.
Obviously this is going to be popular then because anybody and everybody's going to try to undercut
the hotels.
They don't want to go and you know spend $500 a night to stay in a.
Like I said a sterilized lodge if they can stay in someone else's home.
It's twice as comfy and it's just an it's half as you know half the price.
So think about the reasons.
Like I said Why do people come to your area.
Is it a tourist destination.
If it's got tourism just in general maybe it's just domestic maybe it's international doesn't really
matter.
People are coming and spending money and they're staying places and they want to have a good experience
then as possible.
So I guess I'd never rule out Arab and be.
But if you want to know for sure concretely say I don't want to just put up my listing.
You know the time to do that and throw it up there and then realize no one's here yet on the head of
the curve.
You can out pretty easily go to air B and B W W W dog hair b and b dot com and right on the page you
can just search for the city.
Pick a date.
Pick the date way out in the future.
Pick it for next week because it might be the case that everything is booked if there are actual options.
See what's there.
By the time you listen this might have changed but right at the moment they show 8 listings at a time.
So you'll see 8 listings based on your search inquiry and then you go to the next page you go to the
next page.
There are more than 8 listings then it looks like people use Airbnb.
The supply wouldn't be there if the demand wasn't there.
That's typically a good sign if there's less than 8 listings.
Maybe it's not a great sign.
There are some exceptions.
Maybe there's only four listings.
Maybe you live in a really small place you live in a really really small place but there's still four
listings that could actually be a good sign meaning that there's plenty of demand.
Not a lot of supply and there are still people booking.
Someone clearly took the time to put it up and that's the case there's only four.
That also means there's a pretty good opportunity for you to beat out everybody else by doing a better
job beating them in the search rankings because maybe they asleep at the wheel.
So what I would say doing is take the top three that show up on your search inquiry.
Click on the listings.
Did they put a lot of effort into the photographs.
That's usually a good indication that they're getting demand.
But the best way of telling is just to look at the reviews.
Look right at them how they are views that they have to they have 30 they have 20 to 18 maybe they have
10.
Like I said everybody It takes a while for it to spread.
So maybe this is new.
Maybe it's only picked up in last six months so don't discount it.
They don't have 100 reviews my property has 80 something probably had a lot more if I press people and
leaving reviews but I don't.
So check that out.
Here's one of the things I think is most important being me at the moment and they might change us by
the time you are listening to this small disclaimer.
If you go to the reviews you can see when they were posted and so you can see what the frequency of
staes are.
So maybe the case you look at it you already have three reviews for November.
That's a good sign.
Typically use this as a rule of thumb.
One out of three people ever view small towns.
Maybe one out of two.
I think in smaller towns they're more likely to have you on an empty property where they met the owners
more likely in a city that kind of just end up in a bigger property or they kind of shuffle them through.
People are less likely to leave her view but take that in consideration.
So it's November and you see that there's three previews for November already.
If it's a big city you can assume that nine people very state which means that they have quite the DNC
quite the booking occupancy.
Now if it's kind of the case that you only have one November one in October in each month maybe see
just one or something like that that could just mean that maybe they have three bookings a month but
that doesn't necessarily mean that they're just all the time they're empty.
What a lot of things could be happening.
One it could be that factor the host just doesn't like to rent out their apartment that much or their
space that much they only like to do it every now and then maybe they have very restrictive parameters
on when you can book two.
It's one of those properties are not a lot of people review it.
Some places they are more popular for trans..
Guess people are just staying for one night and passing through.
Less likely.
Waiver view.
It could also be that maybe they took a break.
That's another thing to look for.
And you see a break where maybe you see a review in June and then the one before that was in January
might mean that posters took a break.
So it's really hard to weed out what their preferences are.
You look at my property you know some months I just didn't feel like running it out sometimes I didn't
feel like running up more than a week in a week pays my rent and then some months I kind of went crazy
it was like hey I want to make a side income from this so it's really hard to infer directly from just
looking at the reviews I can get a decent idea and always look at multiple listings.
Right.
That's why I say look at the top three the top three are going to be the most popular and have the most
reviews.
But if you can establish that they are in fact getting bookings that's a pretty good show of proof.
I mean it's they are getting people they're getting inquiries maybe it's not a downpour of inquiries
but they're clearly booking people and those people are enjoying this day.
That's a good sign.
You're in an area where not a lot of listings.
And more importantly not a lot of reviews maybe are ahead of the curve.
Maybe it's not something that you should do or maybe it's a case that you want to put it up but you
want to spend less time putting it up and a lot of cases too if you own your own home.
Then you have no fixed cost problem.
You don't pay rent.
You just own it.
You pay property taxes.
But those are less than your rent.
Obviously in that case maybe a booking every two months.
That's good for you.
That is just free money.
It's a good way of connecting and even networking or if you're the kind of case that all people do is
they run out their space and then they go and stay at someone else's house.
Well in that case then it's just again extra money.
Like I said this is the first portion I'm deciding whether or not it's worth living your space.
Like I said more often than not it's worth listing your space and it's getting increasingly so every
day everyday more and more people are doing this as being the blowing up.
It's worth looking into this.
And if you listen my lecture previously about the air Byard room Urana also worth checking them out.
Just see maybe maybe the RBO has a lot of listings where you are eBay me hasn't caught on.
That's a distinct possibility although it's kind of small so if you have five minutes get on and just
kind of dig around look at where you're thinking of listing it.
Look at what other people are doing how are they doing.
Most importantly how many reviews they have.
What's the density of the reviews and a quick bet.
Why don't you just look at the calendar.
Some people have asked me the reason to look at the calendar is like I said before you don't know what
the host preferences are in the calendar will look full even if the host just says I'm not hosting anyone
this month or maybe I don't want someone this weekend.
That doesn't mean that it's booked and you can't tell the difference so the most popular properties
might just not be open for bookings.
That's why we don't look at the calendar and don't usually typically say that's a good reference point.
One other quick thing to keep in mind and this is a quick calculation you run in your head when you're
looking at your space.
Look at what people are running for.
That's also a decent indication of roughly how popular demand is and Judah's quickly in your head just
think what does a one bedroom cost for rent.
What does a two bedroom cost for rent.
And then look at the prices.
Multiply that out by say 10 days 15 days.
If it's a big margin you can tell people are able to post a premium.
They're really doing well if that number is closer to what they pay every day say you know the average
one veterans a thousand dollars but they're on average running out for $40.
Now these are a day after and every single day to catch or to meet their rent and utilities.
So that means that maybe there's not enough demand to insure a premium.
This obviously doesn't concern you if you just want to take the edge off your rent or to make some extra
money.
But if you are trying to turn this into a full time business that's generally a negative sign.
Any questions again post them in the group discussion send me a private message I can help you out too
if you're not totally sure I am.
And I looked at the reviews and it's really hard to tell.
I don't know what's going on.
Sometimes it helps with an experienced eye to look at it.
In the next section we're going to talk a little bit more about qualifying your space determining whether
or not this sick good host opportunity and determining whether or not you want her out of your apartment
or you are there or not you want to run out just a space.
And realistically what to expect to get out of that.
And what's the requirement to do that.