Let's talk about the description portion of your listing I don't want you to look at this section and
get overwhelmed.
I think a lot of times people when they're making their listings look at other people's properties and
see that they have listings that are well-thought out and long really don't worry about that one.
They're very easy to write and to in my opinion they are the third most important thing on your listing
and there aren't that many things on your listing to begin with.
Number one thing for someone who's booking are your photos followed by reviews.
Don't sweat it.
It's not particularly hard.
You know this is something that I don't think should take longer than 15 minutes 20 minutes.
It's also something that you can write kind of in a modular sense meaning that you can write one paragraph.
Use that as your description and come back when you thought of something to add and then add another
paragraph and then another and another until you have something that is somewhat comprehensive.
Don't shy away from writing a long description.
The longer really the better.
I mean they don't really put any limit on how much information you can put.
So this is your time to explain why your space is good why it's great and why everyone should come so
we should really take this opportunity to be enthusiastic about your space.
Don't be matter of factual.
Don't just say you know this is what it is is what it is.
Period.
Also you know I typically say shy away from being outright negative in your descriptions.
That seems obvious but I think what I'm talking about more so are situations where you know they write
a paragraph and the second paragraph they start talking about the things you can't do.
You can't use the kitchen.
Please don't smoke things like that it seems odd when the second paragraph you've already run out of
nice things to say about your space.
The best advice I can give you from when you're writing your description and this is what I did was
copy other people.
It's as simple as that.
You know you don't even have to do this with other properties in your area.
You can do it from other cities or other state pick popular properties you think have done a good job
description and use their format.
You can quite literally copy and paste their description and then just use it as a template.
First sentence it appears that they open up with a kind of a zingy one liner that tries to bring out
something interesting about the city itself and not the space so they try to cram in as many adjectives.
It's a cozy comfortable and quaint room and it's in this place with warm and fuzzy adjectives.
People do a very good job of this making their descriptions see what they do see what they mention and
then convert it for what you're doing.
So you know if someone says I live five minutes from this place or five minutes from this place you
can do the same exact thing in the same exact format just say you're five minutes from something that
you were actually five minutes from doing all these you just copy and paste that wouldn't work but just
generally look at the format that they use and say that's how I used it.
I first tried to write it and I just kind of clueless and then I started looking into other people were
doing it and I just found someone I said I like how they do it.
And there's another section on here I talk a little bit about how you should try to create a rambling
text in the sense that you'll keep running with the hand.
Here's another thing and here's another thing and here's another thing in terms of your bullet points
for why you should be interested in this space.
More on that later so I brought up my description from MySpace and what we can do is we can actually
just go through this and I can read it out loud and tell you kind of what I was thinking and why I kind
of wrote it that way.
Air B and B has changed recently so they change it now.
So you're actually putting smaller descriptions in some headers so they have a header called like the
space and they'll have a header guest access interaction with guests over a view that's another section.
It used to just be you just had a big block attacks but you have to understand that the way that comes
out now it's the same way.
You can literally write the same block of text you just know that there are always going to display
in the same order.
So like the space is always going to be the first thing that shows with the exception of the overview
which shows at the top of the listening to the overview is not going to let you display more than two
sentences or three sentences that keep that short and you also don't even necessarily have to do the
overview.
If you see on my listing this is actually because I haven't updated it since they changed their interface.
I don't actually plan on updating that overview.
Maybe in the future I will you're looking at my description.
It starts off and says Come stay in are huge.
And I put in parentheses there 200 square feet apartment right by the waterfront.
Come stay in our huge I mean come stay it's welcoming it's a persons are getting it.
It's pulling out to them it's like literally kind of talking to them.
That's a strategy that I like to use like I'm talking directly the person who's reading this.
It also sounds kind of professional at least in a sense that you would hear a hotel say that I put huge
because that is a key differentiator of my space.
It's much larger than other places spaces and I put in square feet terms and this is something that's
virtually meaningless because no one else is going to display their square feet.
Partially that's because in San Francisco everyone's apartments are so small.
No one's going to say Come check out my space 300 square feet.
When you hear 300 You probably think it's like a prison cell.
Who in their head knows exactly what that looks like.
But it does sound large and I'm not being dishonest or disingenuous.
It is actually large.
And I say it right by the waterfront.
That is a big thing about my apartment we are right by the waterfront you can literally walk to it.
When people think of San Francisco they do actually think about waterfront scenes and that's something
that I was kind of harping on and that's just kind of like an attention grabber when I say like copying
other people you could copy this and say come stay at our.
And you just fell out.
Come stay at my cozy apartment in the mountain whatever it is.
You're not going to have to hire someone to go.
Right.
This is this is something you can honestly type out very very quickly as it's devoid of typos.
The grammar I'm sure is wrong in my listing and it's something that people really don't care.
It's about readability.
It says right next to all the great tourist hotspots.
Comma the apartment is ideal for seeing the city.
That's what I was kind of angling my apartment after I wanted it to sound like English at first tourist
because tourists are typically the ones who are going to accept me acceptable a larger premium.
You know I said the apartment is ideal for seeing the city.
That's something that people are very worried about especially in tourist cities.
They want to make sure that they don't make a mistake getting an apartment that's near one thing but
far away from the other 10 things that they want to do and a lot of people are pressed for time.
And so it's very important to them that they you know when they want to stay somewhere they want to
be close to it and be like within walking distance so they don't have to spend a lot of time in transit.
And I put two feet from our doorstep you can see Alcatraz in plain view.
That's true.
I mean that's just something that some people can't really compete with that actually is a very cool
feature of my apartment.
And five steps away you can hop on the iconic Hyde Powell cable car.
That is true we are right next to the cable car that runs past our apartment.
Another very big point.
Those are two things that I think are very unique and I think it would help you know if you can think
of at least two things that are unique in your space.
You can add those.
And then I said within five minutes walk to some of the most popular and photogenic spots in San Francisco
what I'd done is I went to Google Maps and I knew roughly what top five things people want to do.
And if you don't know good at Trip Advisor type in your city and I'll give you the top five things or
Lonely Planet dot com those I'll tell you the top five things you want to do.
And then you can you know typed those into Google Maps plus your address and I'll give you a walking
calculation.
The walking calculation is always slow.
So in some cases I used my walking speed which is much faster but it's not double by any means.
In actuality if someone's new to your city it's in to take them much much longer because they can be
wandering especially if they're tourists sightseeing and then I list all the things that I'm with in
five minutes too.
That's just something that gets in their head it says you know I'm literally right next to all these
things and a lot of times people don't even know what these are.
When I say I like Pier 39 Beach Street guardedly square Lombard Street Fort Mason and North Beach if
they've done their homework they know what those are if they haven't or maybe they've done limited research
and know what a couple of the things are but the point is I listened to everything that I could possibly
think of that 20th in five minutes and that's something that the city can say oh you know if all else
fails we can do these five things because they're very very close.
This is one sentence that I thought was interesting but why pay $300 a night at a hotel when you can
rent our entire three bed three bath for the same price.
Earlier we talked about pricing strategies.
I was mentioning that one of the strategies you can do is find the price for a hotel and make sure that
you're under it.
My apartment is under the pricing for a hotel or a comparable space that would house the same amount
of people.
So that's a very good point a lot of people are coming Air B and B and this is something I suggest you
put in your description you can kind of dissuade people from doing hotels.
You can say this is why we're better than a hotel.
Don't be afraid to compare yourself because that is the default option and it's going be a long time
before Airbnb becomes the default option.
And so that was a pretty easy calculation.
You can actually stay down the street and you're going to pay $3 a night for one hotel room that fits
two people.
Our apartment is roughly the same price.
And the next thing I put was walk score the Walk Score is a Web site you can go to it's just walk score
dotcom all added in the extras for the course.
You can find in the resources section what it does is it calculates how close you are to things like
coffee things like groceries points of interest bars things like that.
So some people have an walkable space as some people have very high walk scores.
So this is kind of a loophole in the sense that every single intersection in San Francisco is going
have a walk score or 90 because it's a very compact urban environment.
Everywhere you are you are close to the necessities that walk score can centers on they're taking it
in you know creating this calculation to determine how walkable your spaces.
And 91 in relativity to San Francisco that's actually kind of low.
But again that's kind of the thing is like if the host showing off their walk score that probably means
that walk score is good even if that means nothing to you.
This is something that you know I suggest updating when I had just started listing this.
I said we're only one point five blocks from the wharf and less than five minutes walk from Marina Green
Fort Mason Crissy Field and there is an event called America's Cup.
And now something that was actually very very close to our space and so I put a little paragraph saying
this is a great spot for events because a lot of people were looking for that.
If you are listing a space and you think you're going to be capitalizing on events a lot of times this
is what happens if you're missing a space and say Austin Texas you're going to be making a large amount
of money in a short period of time during South by Southwest and then the rest of the time you're really
making a very modest amount of money.
So it's very important that in some of these cases you put a description saying that this place is pre-qualified
for this event.
I've already decided this is great for an event.
I don't think it's a great idea to put that is the first thing unless you really think that's the only
thing people are looking for.
I thought it was good in the second sentence because even if people aren't interested in the event they
can see oh this is something that's close to a very popular event.
And then the next paragraph is actually the bulk of my description and honestly I just pick three adjectives
that I thought fit the space.
Take that three that I think fit the best I said Sunny spacious and warm which is true it is sunny it
is spacious and because of the sunniness it's warm.
And I said you have the entire space all yourself.
It's classically San Francisco in the building was built a little over 100 years ago after the great
quake.
Always take if you have the opportunity insert some local cultural reference.
If you don't have this then don't worry about it.
Then you would.
You'd heart more in like the convenience of your spot or the amenities or spot if you do have a home
that is quite cool and does have some quirkiness and some uniqueness to it.
Definitely mention these things say something about the architecture or say something about make a connection
to the history of the area.
And that's great boutique hotels.
They command a premium over say regular hotels or hip boutique hotels and a lot of times hip boutique
hotels are places that have a connection to the history of the area they're in they're in nice buildings
they're in historic buildings they're in apartments that are quirky and different and only a way that
your area could kind of essentially wait if you have a loft in Brooklyn.
There's a Brooklyn style to that loft that's something that you would want to talk about in the rest
of it.
I just kind of focused on anything I could think of.
You know I think it's helpful to go in your head and make a quick one through five.
What are the top five reasons you should stay at your apartment and make sure you get all five of those
in there and then pass that you're really just covering all the bases making sure that you don't leave
anything out where someone might notice oh something's missing and that might be a problem.
So they spend their time asking you about it as opposed to just booking.
And I just talked about how his newly renovated.
I talk about how large the living room is.
I talk about how close we are.
How you guys can't read the screen.
Make sure that you can actually grab the in the resources section I have this description up then just
kind of went into a sentence where I just listed out all of the things that were nice like back patio
custom cabinetry and you furnish new refrigerators central heating huge windows things like that so
you should know your space pretty well you should know what the positives not the negatives are.
You don't list the negatives.
The only time you list something is negatives if it's something that would create a problem if they
didn't know before they came.
We purchase a monthly parking spot for our guests so I Blissett that is a big thing.
And that's something that I'll talk about later.
You'll see it in one of the tip sections.
Discuss how that's actually an effective strategy in some cases and it's something you should definitely
evaluate.
And I said you know I know I try to qualify how important that is by saying how expensive the parking
is otherwise.
You know this says $400 a night but also and getting free parking which otherwise would have been $40
a night.
And then I just did this little quick thing that I found helpful I took all of the main things that
people would be consider would be interested in buses.
People were interested in mass transit.
People are interested in points of interest.
People are interested in like dry cleaners where they're going to go to walgreens.
What are things that are open late where they can get their groceries.
What are the things that are very quintessentially San Francisco where is a gym things like that.
And I kind of just listed them out in terms of walking distance and I just made a list and just said
two blocks to this two blocks about five minutes to ten minutes of that eight minutes of that.
And I listed them in descending order.
The entire idea behind that was just so that I could list this.
Look at this and see.
It just gives the impression that everything is close to me.
Look at all of the things I can do.
They don't know what's missing obviously but it just it's some token.
I taken the time to think about all of the things that you could have and you could be close to and
even things like mentioned like I'm next to U.P.S. and then I made a quick bet saying hotels hotels
across the street charge at least blank you know if you live in an area that has really expensive hotels
feel here to steal that little bit.
That's always a fun one.
You can always take the average cost of a hotel Mexi or the highest cost you've seen.
And say they can charge this much.
What that means is hey look I'm getting a great deal versus a hotel but also it says that this area
is nice enough to warrant a hotel that expensive.
The rest of this you can read through on your own.
And if you have any questions you can ask about it in the group discussion.
I'm just going over what does everything we have you know what's our kitchen have invented and mentalists
list everything that's in the kitchen.
Here are the things I can help you with.
That's one thing people really like that he say how helpful you can be to them.
And I was just saying like I can help you with basic like tours and things like that.
And even if you don't know how to do these things you can learn them in five minutes and sometimes you
have to learn it.
Your guest will tell you how they did it and you just have to remember that.
So I just try to think about every single reason why someone would be coming to this space and try to
get a little bit in there for them talked about who will turn the areas to eat food and talking about
like we're flexible and Chacun that that is something we are usually flexible on.
That's that's great.
Let's go over what are bad descriptions and what are things that you shouldn't do.
You'd be surprised how often people have bad descriptions.
And when I say bad 90 percent of time when a bad description is It is a description that just kind of
conveys that it didn't put any effort into it.
You know if you have two sentences and a paragraph it just does not come off well it doesn't make me
think the put any time into my day it makes it feel like it's going to be awkward when I do come and
stay.
And it just makes it feel like you're not really putting a lot of time and there's kind of a revert
back to that initial problem people have with Airbnb which is I'm I'm paying to stay in someone else's
space.
And if they're really not taking this seriously it's very hard for you to take it seriously.
Here's a description I just found in my area better him in a five bedroom house with living room and
kitchen all recent college grads semi-private room.
Capital P separated from adjacent bedroom doorway and curtain and then great place to crash in the heart
of Nob Hill explanation point.
That was it.
That was literally all they said for their listening and they want to charge $80 a night.
That probably took him maybe 30 seconds to write.
It's very matter of fact earlier I don't write.
Matter of fact don't just say this is what it is.
Try to make it sound appealing say you'll enjoy yourself in this.
Come stay with us.
There's many different ways that you can kind of spin this to make it sound positive inviting all recent
college grads.
That's going to kind of eliminate probably 75 percent of the people are going to come and stay.
25 percent of people say oh great.
That's my demographic.
And the other 75 percent of those who say no I don't want that.
Also you're charging $80 a night semi-private room that is just sounds incredibly weird.
What is semi private.
I mean like there's someone else in your room.
But don't worry there's a screen in front of him and that it says separated from adjacent bedroom a
doorway and curtain.
It just seems a bit odd especially the doorway Plus a curtain that says great place to crash in the
heart of Nob Hill Nob Hill is a proper noun.
He didn't capitalize it.
You know that's the only thing he said that was positive.
Like I said before try to be grammatically correct to take away obvious typos were not all grammar freaks
but it really does help if you don't have glaring problems.
Not necessarily that it comes off.
It doesn't say anything negative about you it just says that you didn't put time into it.
Do a proofread don't spend a ton of time proofreading but do read it over at least once.
It would help a lot if you guys post in the group discussion about anything that you kind of ran into
or things that you thought were really helpful to add any other sections.
I mean my description I wrote very quickly and I added more later and added more later and I'd come
in every couple months and add little bits or take out little bits so don't expect it to be perfect
right off the bat.
Have someone read your description and see if they can think of anything that you didn't think of.
That's great about your space.