Tip Number nine I call this one uber I'm So I mean by this this is something that only applies if you
live in a big city.
Sorry if you're in a little city you should probably just tune out.
This applies if you've ever heard of these ride sharing services like lift an Uber and sidecar San Francisco.
Everybody uses them if you're in Chicago or New York or Boston or Atlanta or you know Miami then you
all have it smaller mid-size cities sometimes have typically it's going to be in cities that are at
least half a million while you can do.
And I love telling this one because I use the services you have to share code in your uber account and
your left account.
Typically the way that these work is they say you give 20 bucks to someone else and you get 20 bucks.
And that's how you get new people on the system.
Well what I used to do is I always message people and say Here are the options for getting to our apartment.
And then in my listing I made it the obvious choice that they take Oubre.
So I would say as one you can take the mass transit it costs this much and it takes this long to.
You can rent a taxi and it cost this much amount of money which is an insane amount of money.
Or you can take an Uber and then take the price and deduct the $20 from it and I go you can do it this
way 80 percent of the time that people would just say whoa let me use that one instead because it makes
sense right.
From San Francisco International Airport to my apartment taxis and it costs you about 75 bucks an Uber
is going to cost you 40 bucks.
Mass transit is cheap but it takes longer if you multiply like four people.
Do you actually end up spending 25 30 bucks anyway.
So it actually ends up being more expensive than nuber.
And then with the coupon.
Depends if they're doing $10 or $20 or whatever it would end up being 20 bucks right.
And it makes so much sense and then I get 20 bucks so every time I have a guest coming in they use this
I get this like four or five times a month.
So I get like an extra $100 and tribal credit so it was actually kind of a win win.
It makes sense right because you want to get them there cheaply.
They feel great because you got them there cheaply you found a loophole for getting them there.
And then if they didn't actually use that or didn't do that what I would end up doing is I'd typically
just write my share code on the wall because previously we talked to the white board.
I would write down the wall and say You guys need to go anywhere there's this new crazy service it's
very San Francisco.
Insert this into your smartphone and you get to take a free trip so maybe you'll even get an uber you'd
really get two free trips in San Francisco which is awesome.
So a lot of people take you up on that and then it just kind of feeds back to you.
But it's one of those ones it's like you benefit they benefit it's just a win when.