Let's talk a little bit about thumbnails those tiny little square images of your apartment that someone
sees and they search for a property.
Yes they are immensely important.
Anyone who's taken a course on any type of display advertisement or anything even like an eBay course
they're done now is crucial.
What do I suggest you do with your thumbnails.
Well number one you want to have a photograph that looks professional.
So chances are you're going to use the air B and be photographed when you do a thumbnail on air B and
B if you pick a high quality photograph or at least make it such that other properties don't stand out
against yours.
You want your thumbnail to stick out as much as possible but in a good way you don't want to put a picture
of Google image of a cat or something like that.
I don't think Arab and me would except that you want yours to be slightly different just enough that
when they look at six thumbnails they see yours first what I ended up doing for my thumbnail was I picked
the one thing that differentiates my property from all the other ones in the area.
One of the biggest ones and that was that I have a back yard and a patio.
Never mind the fact that in San Francisco you rarely get to use that patio because it's too windy or
it's too overcast.
It's something that when someone is booking they want to see that they have the option for it and that's
something that other people can't compete with.
You can't go and get a new property simply because it has a backyard.
San Francisco has very high urban density so it's not as common that you would have something like this.
Also everyone seems to make the mistake of taking a photograph of their living room or something that
is inside their space.
That was a big differentiation for me.
I took a photograph of the backyard.
It's green and it's bright blue.
That's different than taking a picture of the inside of your apartment so that stands off against everybody
else who took photos of the best looking bedroom in their apartment.
Do you have something like that that could make a huge difference.
Maybe it's the front of your house.
You would take a photograph of the front of your house if you wanted to emphasize.
And you were the first thought someone has this is a house that I'm renting and that's somehow different
than the other places that I'm renting.
One of the big no nos thumbnails I've noticed is people will take a photograph of say their living room
and there's too much going on in the shot.
So when I look at that and the image is scaled down it doesn't look like anything.
I can't make out everything in the photograph.
It's actually a kind of a waste.
Earlier in the course I talked about someone who took a picture a gift basket that they made and they
showed that as their number one thumbnail is the first thing you see.
And let me tell you that sticks out you see apartment apartment gift basket.
They did it with professional photography so it kind of had that aura of color and saturation that you'd
associate with an energy and be photo.
In my experience those are the best things you can do.
Not really worried about you know if everybody hears this course everybody makes these off the wall
kind of photographs or photographs of things that are old normal nontraditional because like I said
earlier in the course Airbnb hosts they're just not nearly as competitive as you think.
If you put 10 percent more accurate than them you can make a property that's twice as good.
What else can we say about thumbnails.
If anybody has any experience with thumbnails post in the group discussion and glad to hear what you've
had and what works in my experience things that catch their attention are good.
So take a picture or something that's different from anything different going on your apartment maybe
take a picture of a nice painting on the wall.
Tested out like everything but in general you don't want to pick a low quality photo that you took yourself.
You want to pick something as lots of light because they want to be in a good mood and they come to
your listing you know want to pick something that's a picture of a closet or the darkest room in your
apartment.
Pick something that's going to get their attention it's going to stick out and it's going to exude a
positive vibe.
I would love if you guys would post what your experiences are thumbnails because I think we can kind
of crowdsource together and figure out you know this is work this doesn't work.
Lots of people like this people don't like.
So anyway questions experiences posted in the group discussion send me a private message.