Let's talk about how you can turbocharge your listing this is something that I did not realize at first
when I listed my property on air B and B but over time I realized there's actually something to how
many booking inquiries you get and how many bookings you get in relationship to each other.
Now what I mean when you go into Arabic and b you go to your Administration panel it's going to show
you how many booking inquiries you have.
It's also going to show you how many bookings you have and they're going to compare them right next
to each other so you can see maybe you got 10 inquiries per booking maybe you got two inquiries per
one booking.
In my experience and this is something that Irving has never admitted but guys feel free to test around
with this.
This is something that I've noticed repeatedly and I've noticed and I've talked to other hosts who have
noticed a swell.
The more often you book off of each booking inquiry the more likely Air B and B is going to feed you
more page views.
So now if you think about it when you search on air B and B and you see the listings what goes into
the search listings.
A lot of it is reviews.
A lot of it is the popularity of the listing.
A lot of it is how many people have Wish listed your listing how many people have favored it.
And those are things that you would think that they use in the search results.
But there's one key ingredient that I've noticed that actually is almost bigger than those three things
so that is just how many bookings you are taking at first a lot of people are really careful about who
they take into their apartment and they might be really picky and so they you know they get three inquiries
they only take one that might actually be a detriment to you.
And I know you're just trying to be careful at first but if you want a turbocharger listing and get
a ton of bookings I suggest you actually do the opposite and it's actually difficult.
You really have to put a little bit more thought into how you list your listing what are the possible
problems with hosting a wider variety of types of guests.
It's really something that I only suggest people try to do this if they are really comfortable with
hosting people and they're really dedicated towards making a lot of money on air being be what you want
to do is you just want to make sure that you book as many people as possible.
You want to make sure that if you get an inquiry you try to fit them in.
And if you absolutely can't make sure it's because you have another booking for that time.
If Airbnb sees that every person they send to you is more likely to end up booking and who is more likely
to make them money.
They're going to send you a lot more page views they're going to push you up in the search ranks if
you want to stay a golden property on air B and B make sure that you do everything you can to book each
inquiry you get.
Try not to be too picky when someone says something you don't like if someone asks you a question can
you been some of your rules except us try to say yes if they say can we have a special discount on the
price.
Try to work with them within reason.
You don't necessarily have to give them everything they're asking for.
But I always suggest give them something even if it's very small.
They'll feel like they're getting a deal they're going to want a book with you.
The point is if you really really want to do this or you rent it out 100 percent the time or you really
want to maximize how many people you get try to book every person that you get.
Obviously this is impossible because a lot of people you just cannot book but Air B and B is going to
take that into consideration.
You're going to have a higher booking percentage per booking inquiry and that's going to kind of shoot
you up to search results and that's how you get into types of situations where you put up your listing
you've booked out Christmas before the other five properties in your area have even booked out Thanksgiving.