Here's another bonus tip this is cater towards differentiating yourself from the pack.
But it also you know it could fit this into the how the guest experience this was huge for my apartment.
It's parking Why is parking so important in San Francisco.
There's not a lot of parking but there are plenty of people trying to drive their car into the city.
That's largely the case in a lot of other places.
Any big city is going to have parking problems.
People really don't want to have to deal with the option of not being able to park.
And a lot of times they want to come visit your city but they do and are in a car.
But the idea of parking bothers them so much that they don't.
And that actually hurts their experience.
What I did was I went and found parking my apartment doesn't have parking we have street parking but
it's a two hour parking and they will tow you if you stay for two hours.
What I did is I went and just looked at Monkley parking spots.
If a monthly parking spot cost me $150 a month how many guests do I need to book to break even on that
for me that was half a guest ought to do is give me a half agast booking with me to break even where
one guest in my living room and all of a sudden now is a good investment.
When I first originally listed my apartment I did not parking and I noticed this and this is something
that you might have noticed when back when we were doing the looking for gaps and looking for things
that people can't offer in your area meetings were things I noticed was no one could offer parking and
because no one is offering parking no one even thought to offer parking.
Parking was huge.
Once I added parking I got double the booking inquiries that I had before and the way I noticed this
was people were asking me hey I'm interested in your space.
Do you have parking and it's say no parking obviously.
I'd say a lot more than that and make it a little more gracious but didn't they respond or they'd really
be on the fence and was really having trouble booking because people really wanted parking.
What they ended up doing is getting a place out in the suburbs that they could park at.
Consider this strategy does this work for you.
Do you not have parking.
Can you add parking.
No I can't add parking of course you can add parking.
You can find someone who has a parking spot they don't use.
You can find a parking garage that offers parking you find a lot that offers parking.
Doesn't really matter doesn't matter if it's that close to your apartment doesn't need to be a block
from your space.
Mine's four blocks away four blocks and sound like a lot in San Francisco.
It's almost like a ten minute walk but that's enough I mean it technically counts as parking.
And once they see that you have parking they're not going be considering how far away it is because
it's included and you can put in your listing saying this is the cost of what it would cost to park
otherwise in a cheaper city maybe it's only 10 bucks or something.
Here I was like $40 $30 so this is how much I'm saving you for free.
If you come and stay with us and it's something that no one else has really capitalized on literally
in my listing it put at the very end of it in the header title of the listing parking.
Capital P A R K I N G.
Something really does bring in interest.
It's one of those hacks that I've found that really really made it a big big difference.
Look into it if you offer parking and that's something the other people aren't offering.
Then you make sure that you really make a focal point out of this that you don't have parking.
No one else is doing parking see if he can go get to space.
It might be worth it.
Probably will be worth it.
Try it for a month if it doesn't work and no one uses it.
Throw it away it doesn't really matter.
It's another service you can add.
You can offer to tear gas and like anything else it has a return on investment.
A way that you can tell whether or not it's worth it to the $100 for a parking spot and you charge $100
a night.
One person uses that hundred dollars you can probably conclude that without the parking.
There's a good chance they didn't book with you and you didn't get that hundred dollars.
Think of a lot of strategies that can differentiate you from other people but parking was a big one
so please consider it.