In this module,
we're going to be talking about the JDK support and enhancements that
Spring has made around the most recent versions of Java.
Until now, the Spring framework has supported deprecated Java releases,
but Spring 5 has been liberated from that legacy baggage.
The code base has been revamped to take advantage of Java 8 features,
and the framework requires Java 8 as the minimum JDK version now.
The entire code base is based and it's also compatible with Java 9,
but Oracle had delayed the release of Java 9.
So although it's compatible with it, 8 is now the minimum requirement.
Key features being using in the Spring code base now are lambdas,
method references, and default methods in interfaces,
and Spring has exposed the use of the Java util optional class to better
handle the creation of objects and deal with non-null classes.
Spring 5 has also upgraded to Java EE 7.
This bumps our servlet specification to 3.
1, and it also sets the messaging API to JMS 2.
0 and the JPA version to 2.
1.
Much of this may seem somewhat insignificant as you have already been
using these versions before the official 5 release,
but this version helps to push us out to that standard.
The Servlet 3.
1 specification is notable if you're on an older version of the Servlet API,
such as 2.
4 or 2.
5, because by default now you don't have a web.
xml and are now dealing with more straight Java configuration.
That's not to say that you can't use a web.
xml, but they are not the default by now.
This is a welcome change if you're one of the people that doesn't
care for the XML-based configuration approach.
Spring 5 included support for Java 9,
but it was not the minimum support because Java 9 hadn't been released yet.
One of the more significant features of Java 9 that
Spring supports is the notion of modules.
With Spring and the supporting jars that it utilizes,
the scope of various libraries can be confusing at best.
Let's run through a small example showcasing modules and how they isolate dependencies.