Reactive programming is centered around the Reactive
Manifesto for application development.
The Reactive Manifesto is basically a statement that apps will
try to adhere to all of these properties.
They are responsive, meaning that they respond in as timely a manner as possible.
They are resilient in that they stay responsive in the face of failure.
They are elastic.
They stay responsive under varying workloads.
And they are message driven in nature.
Personally, this is where it gets interesting to me.
They are asynchronous by design,
which means that they are loosely coupled and isolated
from other components in the system.
At this point, you may be already writing off reactive programming,
thinking that it's only to be used with extremely large systems.
And this is not true.
Large systems are comprised of smaller systems.
These properties of the manifesto need to be applied to all scales of
systems that could be comprised of other systems.
Let's talk about how Spring 5 helps us by developing applications that are reactive using WebFlux.