In this course,
we're going to cover JDK versions and the enhancements to
Spring because of the JDK upgrades.
We're also going to look at the latest changes to Spring Core.
Spring Core was almost a complete rewrite, and we will discuss why.
Next we'll dive into functional programming with Kotlin and the
latest language that Spring supports for use and configuration and
whether or not it's a good fit for you.
Then we'll dive into reactive programming and using streams,
and finally we'll look at the testing enhancements
and changes brought by JUnit 5.
Although this is a what's new course and not necessarily a step-by-step course,
let's cover the prerequisites and what we will use for displaying the examples in this course.