Now that we have our build file configured, let's set up our application file.
And this is the file that contains our main method,
as well as what defines our Spring application.
This should look pretty similar to what you've done using Java before.
We signify our file as a Spring application by annotating
our class as a SpringBootApplication.
Let's add an application class to our project now.
As I mentioned previously,
I've already created the three empty Kotlin files out there,
Application, Greeting,
and GreetingController just so I had a placeholder for them.
I'm going to go ahead and open up that Application.
kt file, and we can go ahead and start entering our code in there.
I'm going to paste the code in here as I've already written it
and walk through each piece that we have.
We have our package just like we would in Java.
Notice there's a lack of a semicolon on the end of the line there.
We also have our import statements just like we would.
And then we have our annotation for our SpringBootApplication,
and that's what tells this file that it is the class
that runs our entire application,
but notice we just have this function standing alone by itself.
It's not inside curly braces.
It's missing the public static void declarations.
And it takes an array of strings in, and then it runs our Java application.
It says SpringApplication.
run, and this is kind of an interesting syntax where it says Application:class.
java.
So the Kotlin source code is getting compiled down,
but it's telling it to run it as a Java file on the JVM
and pass in any arguments that we have,
and this is how our SpringApplication starts up.
This is everything we need to signify that it is a Spring application and a main method inside of a Java application.