We can now add our greeting class that's going to return the
JSON message to our UI or our calling client,
but you'll notice the simplicity of this class,
and that's one of the things that draws people to Kotlin and other languages,
like Scala.
On this slide, you can see the entire class definition.
Notice there are no getters, no setters, no curly braces.
There aren't even semicolons.
Let's add a greeting class to our project now.
I've already opened up the Greeting.
kt file that we had created before, and I'm going to just paste in that code.
And you can see that it's about as simple as we could get when defining a class.
We have our package statement in there, and then we define what our class is,
that it's just a data class, and its name is Greeting.
It has a variable val id that's of type Long and a variable
that is a name of content of a type String,
and that's it.
No getters, setters.
We don't have to define constructors.
No curly braces, no semicolons.
This entire class defines a simple POJO that we would normally be
right-clicking and generating to have all of those boilerplate
methods produced for us so a lot tighter, a lot cleaner code in this POJO.