To demonstrate the logging configuration,
I went ahead and copied the default methods example that we used
previously into a logging project just called LoggingExample.
And just as a reminder, all of these projects are in the exercise files,
as well as the GitHub repo that we mentioned in the first module.
To start the configuration, I went ahead and added to the pom.
xml these five dependencies, the log4j-api and the log4j-core,
which if I was just using a properties file configuration,
this is all I would've needed to have added,
but I decided to mix it up since you've probably already seen a Log4j
configuration for XML and one using the properties files,
I went ahead and used a JSON configuration.
And in doing so, I had to add the jackson-core,
jackson-databind, and jackson-annotations dependencies.
The next thing I had to do was create a log4j2.
json file.
And this file looks very similar to the XML or properties files
configurations you've probably seen in the past.
I added a configuration section in here where I
defined the Appenders and the Loggers, and then I just tied those to the System.
out.
The other thing that I had to do was just go in and create a private
static final Logger in the class and begin saying logger.
trace.
And you'll notice that it's tied to trace and that our log level and
our JSON configuration is set at trace as well.
Let's run this,
and I'll tell you right off the bat we're going to see one
problem with this inside of our application.
If I right-click and Run As, Java Application,
you're going to see a lot of information logged to the console now.
So now we have all of this trace debug information
dumped out to our application.
We clearly don't want that all the time,
so we can easily tune our logging, and this is why I like Log4j.
It's really simple to do.
Other ones are just as simple.
You may be even more familiar with one over another.
I just think that the Log4j configuration is very simple to do this.
I'm going to go ahead and add another logger inside of here.
And I already have the code written, so I'm just going to copy and paste it in.
And you'll see that I've defined a logger.
Its name is org.
springframework.
Well its name ties to the package that I want to tune that specific logging for.
And you can see I've set the level there on line 14 to level: error,
and then I've tied it to the appender for the console.
So I'm still going to log it to the console,
and I honestly could have it log out to files,
to emails, to rolling file appenders, whatever I wanted to.
This isn't a course on logging.
That's a separate course.
But I can now tune and tweak this in here using this configuration.
I'm going to go ahead and save this.
Now all of the Spring console messages that are logged to trace here down
below are going to be tuned to only show if there is an error.
Let me go back to our application and run that again.
And you'll see that we've lost all of that information and only show our traces.
So we have our trace for our application starting up.
There's a warning message.
This is actually a Spring configuration problem.
It's not ours.
It's a known logged bug inside of Spring.
And then our post construct and our test message and
then our trace for the shutdown.
So really easy to configure that logging level inside of our application,
as well as to tune logging for the entire application and all the
different APIs that are used inside of our app as well.
So it's really easy.
They've cleaned a lot of this up and allow us to tune it all
using just one tried and true logging mechanism,
Log4j.
You can also use Commons logging or the Java util logging, but they recommend either Log4c or Commons logging for your own applications.