Running a unit test with Spring changed as well.
We used to use a runner and load our configuration from there.
Now we can use an ExtendWith annotation,
as well as the SpringBootTest helper annotation to configure and run our test.
To see a more real-world example of this,
let's look at a client that will run a test to get a value from the
reactive service we did in the previous demos.
If you'll remember from our previous module,
we had a call to a Mono web service that would return one
Person object by just passing in an id,
and you can see that we've built that request here on line 22.
We're asking to go against our localhost.
On 24, we're going to call the person API,
and we're going to pass in a variable of 1 into that first placeholder.
We're going to tell it that we're going to accept
JSON back as a response on line 25.
And then we map that response on line 27, and 28 we grab the actually name back.
Now a lot of this has more to do with how we handle a
Mono object than our actual test, but you can see on line 30,
we're going to do an assertion,
and I'm going to compare the string that comes back from that Mono object
to the name of Bryan and see that that runs correctly.
And I've gone ahead and set this test up.
Our Mono server is, in fact, running.
And I want to just right-click on this object and Run As, a JUnit Test.
And it will run successfully and complete,
and this is how we can do a real-world test against the Mono web
object that we created earlier and assert that that test does bring
back the response that we would like it to.
There's a handful of ways we can do this with a Mono object,
but this gives you the idea of how to run that SpringBootTest,
use that @ExtendWith(SpringExtension. class) and do a roundtrip against our server.