The last bit of code that we need to add to our application is the controller.
And this is probably the most complex file out of all the ones that we have,
but it's still pretty simple all things considered.
This controller takes advantage of the greeting class that we just created.
Once we have all of this in place,
we can also run our application and see the results.
Let's go ahead and add this code in our GreetingController
and then run our SpringBootApplication.
Like our previous demos, I've gone ahead and opened up the GreetingController,
and I'm going to paste in that code for our controller.
You'll notice it looks pretty similar to what a Java-configured controller
would look like in Spring with a few things just being relaxed.
Our class definition is more relaxed.
Our variable names don't require a type and our
obvious lack of use of semicolons.
And our function down below here on line 14,
we don't have to define a return type.
We don't have to define that it's a public, a void, or whatever it is.
We can just say it's a function, its name is Greeting,
here's the parameters we're going to pass in,
and then you can see that it's returned as signified by the equals sign and
saying that it's going to return the Greeting object.
And this will automatically figure out that we're
going to return that file as a JSON,
so that Greeting object is going to get returned as a JSON request.
Let's switch over to our command line and run this,
and we run this command by just typing in gradlew bootRun.
And just like before, if you haven't ran this before,
it's going to download a few things.
It'll take it a few seconds to start up,
and then our application will be up and ready to run.
So now our application has started like a regular Spring application has,
and I can switch over to our browser and hit that
service and see what it returns.
And I can hit that service by typing localhost:8080/greeting?
name=Bryan, or whatever name you want to pass into it,
and this ties to the parameters that we had passed into our GreetingController.
When I hit Enter, it'll return back a JSON response with an id of 1 and Hello,
Bryan.
If I change that to another name, so we'll do Steve,
it'll have an incremented id of 2 because that atomic
counter is still in our session and alive,
and I've changed the name, so I've made multiple requests.
You get the idea.
it's a pretty basic application,
but it only took us three files and a Gradle configuration
file to have a complete application up and running using this
syntax and this configuration.
Pretty straightforward and pretty simple.
It's a lot less code than if you were to just do
this in a regular Java application.
SpringBoot does a lot of that heavy lifting for you,
but if you're tired of that Java syntax,
you can go ahead and use Kotlin to make that a lot lighter and a lot simpler.
And if you're doing Android development,
you want to be a full stack developer,
you can keep them in the same languages and exercise some of that flexibility in your whole stack.