Going back to our controller,
I'm going to stop our application and give ourselves some room in
between the repository declaration and the findById method that we
just created and paste in here some code that I've already written
on dealing with a Flux object.
Import the classes that we need here.
And you can see to do a GetMapping for all of the people under the Person URL,
so a standard RESTful syntax.
If I just ask for /person,
it will return all the persons or people that we have inside of our database.
And you can see on line 28 here, we do a repository.
findAll,
and you can see on line 30 here that I can use the helper method
fromIterable that I pass in an Iterable object or a collection,
and it will go through and stream those through a Flux object back to my UI.
That's all I have to do to create a Flux object that responds with a collection.
Now one thing that caught me off guard when I first started using this
is that notice I'm returning a Flux of type person,
not a Flux of type list.
So this will stream back those requests, but it's doing it as the Person object.
May make sense to you, may not.
The Flux object itself is handling the iterable
underneath the hood of that object.
So under the covers, there is a list,
but all you care about is the Flux of type person.
Let's go ahead and save this and exit our full screen.
We'll start our application back up.
I'm going to switch back to my browser.
And now rather than requesting a person with the id of 1,
I can change that URL to just /person and hit Enter,
and you'll receive a stream back with all of those objects in there.
So I have bryan, dan,
and alex that all get retrieved from that database
and displayed through a stream.
Really easy for me to use this stream and not have to
iterate through those individual objects.
And if for some reason it takes a while to build that,
it will retrieve those records one at a time.
If you're wondering why that request may take a long time,
if you've ever dealt with Hibernate for very long,
you've ran into the N+1 select problem.
And if that doesn't make any sense to you,
it's not a big deal,
but that's where I have to go retrieve data from multiple
data stores based off of each request,
and those can take a long time to stream back.
If I do that as a stream, I can respond with these as I get them,
and my UI will still be responsive. Let's now dive into what some of the problems are with using streams.