Hello and welcome back to the course on artificial intelligence.
So we've talked about the Belman equation and we've analyzed our little maze.
Let's have a look at the plan.
What is the plan.
Well here is our main analysis.
And we know that we can see actually the states the values of each state we can see what the value of
being in every single state is.
Therefore the AI can or the agent can navigate this maze.
So what is the plan.
Well the plan is simply like a treasure map for artificial intelligence instead of looking at these
values that just replace them with arrows which indicate in which direction the agent should go.
Because of those because it knows those values.
So an ideal scenario after it's explored this environment.
It knows the value of being in each state and therefore you can come up with this map.
So let's have a look again.
We know that your values one so if you are here out of the two the better one is this Once you go right
from here out of the two this one is a better one this one is a better one.
This one is a better one.
Or actually from here you have two options right.
So he was kind of like a tie so just pick one at random doesn't matter which one because the value in
these in either case is the same and more so even if you look through it will take the same amount of
steps same number of steps to get to the end.
From here you've got three options but this one is the better value from here.
This one is a better value from here.
Obviously this was a better value because you're you know you just get it minus one reward right away.
And from here you have like three actually but this one is the best one of the best value of the state.
And so therefore if we replace them with arrows it makes sense that this is how the agent would go if
it stars here or solve for some reason it ends up in this square.
It knows how to get out of here.
Stars and this square knows how to get on here and so on.
So that is what a plan is.
And don't confuse plan with policy because we're going to be talking about policies for Iran poses a
very similar to plans but they have a little trick to them because the environment's going to be a bit
different.
It's going to be stochastic and that's what we're going to talk about in the next tutorial.
So Conway to you on the next one.
And until then enjoy.