Hello and welcome to the site and to talk to.
All right a very quick tutorial today to make this core function.
And so basically this function will just compute the score on the sliding window of the reward.
And so basically we will very simply compute the mean of all the rewards in the reward window.
So this will be very simple let's do this now we're going to make this new function that we're going
to call core and this core function will just take the argument itself because basically we don't need
anything.
We need to take cells because of course we will take self-talk.
We were winda so just self and then Cullin and there we go.
It's going to take one line of code.
So we want to compute the mean of all the words in the window.
So that's basically the sum of all the words in this window that are between minus 1 plus 1 divided
by the total number of elements in this window.
So let's do this.
We are directly going to return that.
So in starting with we turn and so we need to take the sum of all the words in the window and to do
this we simply need to take the we were Windu itself and so on inputting here self that reward window.
All right.
And so very simply this will sum all the elements inside we were window.
That's pretty practical.
And then to get the mean we need to divide this sum by the number of elements in then we were window
and to get the number of elements.
Well we need to take the len function and then we say are we were window again.
There it is.
But now we just need to be Yahoo with something that lends itself.
We were window is a denominator and this must absolutely not be equal to zero no matter what we need
to avoid this and to make sure that the denominator here is not equal to zero.
We are going to add this safety trick.
We're going to add here a plus one so that Lancefield that we won't win window plus one will never be
equal to zero if the denominator is equal to zero.
This will crash your system.
So we must avoid it and that's totally fine.
Our plus one will still get a good measure of the score.
All right perfect.
And so that's all we have.
Our school function which will give us the meaning of the reward in the sliding window.
All right.
Now let's move on to the next function which is the same function that will save your model that is
said the brain of your car so that you can then be able to reuse it by loading it with another function
that will make after this a function.
So that's really practical to have this save trick safe function to save your miles in case you want
to reuse them for any kind of purpose where they can be useful.
So that's what we'll do in the next tutorial.
And until then enjoy our.