Hello and welcome to the third module of discourse the H-3 sea as synchronous active critic agents.
And so now I can really say welcome to the State of the art machine learning.
Well at the time I'm saying this because maybe some of you will take the course in one to two years
but at the time I'm saying this in 2017.
Well you are about to work on one of the most powerful model in artificial intelligence but there is
more that is not the only special thing about this module.
Not only we're about to work with the most powerful model but we are going to implement the most powerful
version of this algorithm that is the most optimized version implemented version of the A-380 model
because you can imagine that there is the heart of the algorithm.
But then there are a lot of tools that we can use to optimize the whole model.
And so not only are you going to have the heart of the way through the algorithm but are also going
to implement all these tools around it to make the model super powerful.
And why did I want to do that.
Well that's for two reasons.
The first reason is that we are approaching the end of discourse.
This course is the highest level course between the three courses and they'll deal in AI.
It is that now I think you're ready to take it to the next level.
And the second reason is that solving breakout is actually super challenging.
Remember in the promo video we wanted to put break out as the first module because we thought it would
be the easiest challenge but not at all it was actually the most difficult challenge and easier way
of explaining this is that well in doom the monsters are big and therefore easier to detect and therefore
easier to kill or avoid.
But in Breakout we have this tiny ball that the eye has to detect as well because the eye will still
have eyes.
You we're still going to do deep reinforcement learning.
So it's actually super challenging and that's why we don't really have a choice to implement.
The most powerful version of the A-3 see now why do I say this is the most powerful version.
That's for a particular reason.
It's not like I'm saying that I'm going to implement the most powerful version of the A-380.
No it's not this.
The reason I'm saying this is that the version we were about to implement and this is something very
special we're going to do is actually a version of the 3 C that was implemented by somebody but corrected
by one of the most influential people in machine learning today who happens to be the creator of Pi
torch.
His name is Dan Pashka.
Now what we're going to do.
We're going to go on get have on the main page and if you scroll down down to the end down to the bottom
you will see the team the team fight arch creators and contributors.
And you can see here that my torch is currently maintained by Adam Pascal.
That's the person who we should really be grateful for because there are very few versions of the three
things that work well for breakout and he corrected one of the code for the A-380 to make breakout work
perfectly well.
So Pascal is not only maintaining By towards But also he is one of the creative by torch and as I said
today he's in the top 10 most influential people in machine learning.
So we can feel confident that the version we are about to implement is probably the most powerful version
of the A-3 see today.
And so what is this implementation.
Well originally it comes from a developer called iliac history of.
And so as you can see he did a by towards implementation of the A3 C which originally didn't work well
for breakout but then somebody made a pull request.
If we go to the pool request here we can see in the close one that we go we have this one a cleaner
solution to Gretchen problem.
And guess who this pull request was made from.
It was made from Adam Pashka created by torch and that solved the problem that makes the A-380 work
very well on break out without waiting for days and days.
And therefore if we go back to this implementation we can see the four contributors of this most powerful
implementation.
And here are the contributors.
So thank you very much to all of them and we can say a huge and special thank you to Adam passion for
fixing the thread sharing problem.
He started by doing a fork which is a subbranch of the code.
And then he did a pull request to the developer to fix this problem.
There wasn't a code which is a great and sharing problem and that's how he became a major contributor
of this implementation making the whole thing work perfectly well and trust me I did a lot of experimentation
on the AC DC model actually implemented five models.
I was even desperate that it didn't work well so I made my own breakout and cavy to have a bigger ball
and therefore an easier pre-processing of the images.
Then I went back to the eye and made my own implementation of the 3C.
But that took ages to run and train on a pretty powerful computer.
So I wanted to find a better way.
And that's the way it is.
Very powerful implementation of the Silmaril of which one of the major contributors is the Creator by
torch.
So what we're going to do in this Mudgal I think you're ready for that is implement this highest level
code for the implementation of the A3.
So we're basically going to reimplement all these files and we will mostly insist on the files that
are directly related to the three C all the parts that are directly related to the we see.
We will implement the code line by line for the others.
I will just expand the code so we should be able to tackle this without finding it too overwhelming
so that we go quite a special module.
Not only we work in a state of the art model of AI but also at the time I'm speaking and highly confident
we are implementing the most powerful version of the A-380.
So let's do it.
Let's go back to Python and let's start all this before we start.
We're going to do the most simple thing we're going to do in this module.
Setting the working directory folder.
Let's go to our AI is that template folder modules we break out most challenging one.
And there we go.
That's all our files.
So let's see which ones are directly related to A-3 C.
And so let's see which ones we're going to implement.
Line by line and focus our energy on.
So there are actually two files.
The first one is not all the way which is this one so we will re-implemented line by line because that's
the most important that's where we make the A-3 see brains.
And the most important thing to understand here is that we will have a shared model which will have
the same data of the weights for the actor and the critic.
That's a part of this special version of the A-3 see the shared model with the shared data the weights
and then the other most important founder to implement.
Line by line is the trained up wildfowl of course right after we made the brains of the see.
Well we have to train them and we train them in this train that I wife.
So this is quite a long code but this is what contains the heart of the A3 C model which will have to
Lass's to reduce the value in the US which is the last related to the predictions of the critic and
the policy last which is the last related to the predictions of the atom.
So this is quite new but you know that's because the A-380 were basically working with several agents
each one having their own copy of the environment.
We also have this fully connected layer that outputs a value of the function and that basically is a
common vision of what's happening in the game.
So this will be quite challenging.
So make sure be in good shape and for the rest of the fellows Well I will just explain them in detail
but not by spending too much time on them believe me you want to keep your energy for this.
This will be already a lot.
So these fellows are ants ducky Y which is an improvement of the gym environment thanks to universe.
So basically that just improves the gym environment with universe and that allows us to have an optimal
pre-processing of the images and also to normalize all the values of the environment like the colors
intensities or the rewards intensities.
Well all the values of the environment this file normalizes all these values and also make sure we have
enough to not keep processing of the images.
And as you can see this is taken from this opening I get her page where the universe story agent.
So we will not spend too much time on this we will actually stop here.
You just need to understand that we improved the gym environment with universe to get enough to not
be processing of the images.
The rest is not that important especially for the PC.
Then we have main that P Y which is the code that will execute the whole thing.
So you know the code that will run the whole thing create the brain train the brain and output the video.
And that's because it will run all these codes here.
So more we saw where it was then may have turned up.
Why is the special optimizer.
That's basically the atom optimizer but adapted to this shared model that we're implementing.
So we will explain all this code in one tutorial.
Then we have test W-why.
It's actually the last one to test.
Q Why is basically the file that will implement a test agent.
So there is an agent that will play break out without updating the model.
So that's totally independent from the training.
And we will also expand this code in details.
Besides the good news is that you will have two codes one code which will be the code we implement in
the tutorials but without any comment.
And one of the code that is one of the code folder with all the codes commands it.
So with all these six fouls all well connected.
So that if you miss something and tutorial Well you will be able to look at the content of the code
to understand what's going on.
So there we go.
I hope you're excited to implement this.
You're really at the top of the mountain now or just below the top because you need to understand this
first but you're getting there.
So take a good breathe of oxygen.
And there we go with a super exciting journey.
Until then enjoy.