As we learned at the beginning, brute force is a type of attack in which an intruder makes tons of
tries to, for example, gives the password the secret token or the URL of an unpublished page.
This is possible because it's never a person doing these tries, but a computer program often using
powerful CPU or a recent invention GPU, the graphics processor, which does certain operations much
faster than CPU.
There are obvious solutions, like using strong hashing algorithms or not hiding anything on the side,
and there has to be a path.
But apart of them, you can apply some additional security measures, particularly targeting brute force
attacks.
First of all, you can apply rate limits for certain actions that is logged a resource for some time
after some number of invalid accessories.
For example, if the password was incorrectly typed more than five times, log the account for one hour.
This is very effective because the attacker can do nothing after those five tries.
Changing IP, erasing cookies, etc. will not help.
The mechanism is quite easy to implement.
This is an example of data structure where you have log in details, plus a column that counts invalid
drives and another column that stores a timestamp to which the user account is logged.
The first user here is obviously locked and the second is not.
And this would be the PDP code to handle the rate limiting.
In this simplified code example, we first check two things whether the user is logged, which means
the log and date is greater than zero, and whether the log is active, which means the lock and the
date is greater than now.
If this condition is true, it means the user is logged and we don't do anything further.
We just tell them that the account is locked.
In either case, it means the account is either not locked or the lock and the date has passed so we
can accept log in tries first in case there indeed was a lock that expired.
We should reset the log and the number of trace so that the user can again have five attempts.
We need a similar if condition as at the beginning, but this time we need to reverse the comparison
operator so that we see the specific scenario in which there was a log and it expired.
Then we check the password.
If it's correct, we continue as normal.
But if the supplied basalt is incorrect again, we need to see if the number of invalid tries did not
exceed this specific threshold.
In our case.
Five.
If not, we increment the invalid trace counter by one.
If yes, we applied the lock by setting up its expiration date in the locked anthill field.
You can use the UNIX timestamp function of my iscsi well.
The rate limiting can be made progressive.
For example, after five tries, the account would be locked for one minute after another, try for
2 minutes, then for 4 minutes, 8 minutes, etc. The rate limiting method is very effective for security,
but may unfortunately severely impact legitimate users.
Of course, many users would rather try to reset their password.
Then it's tens of times, that's for sure.
But after someone else who wants to break the parcel blogs the account, the legitimate user will not
be able to log in as well.
And in case of progressive logging, after enough number of tries, the account can become locked for
days.
Another prevention method for brute force attacks may be to slow down this sensitive process.
Let's stick to the looking for an example.
The brute force method is sufficient when you can quickly make thousands or millions of attempts by
only allowing one attempt per second.
You can make even the average passwords very, very hard to crack, of course, unless the attacker
has lots of luck or nearly knows what the password is so that they need a few dozens of tries only.
But if you just thought of simply applying the sleep method to the verification process, let me tell
you straight away, it's not the way to go.
It will have performance implications because the script will not actually sleep.
It will just keep the process running longer, which can quickly lead to site outage and actually can
help carrying out the US denial of service attack.
Also, it would be just enough for an attacker to open a large number of simultaneous requests to bypass
this delay.
Instead, you would want to apply a short timeout in the database in a very similar way.
We applied logs before, but this time the database would only need to have a column for the log time
out as it had in the real limiting example.
And here the timeout will be very tight.
Something between one and 3 seconds, which should be less than the time needed for a quickly typing
user to execute legitimate strikes.
This code derives from the area example.
The first thing we check is whether there is a lock and whether it's and the date is greater than now.
If this condition is true, then we don't do anything as the account is locked.
If there is no lock or it already expired, we verified the password and then if it's invalid, we add
a log for 2 seconds.
This code is much simpler than before because we don't need to count in drives and we don't need to
reset the number of ever labeled tries.
After the timeout passes.
And using this method, a legitimate user can try tens of times and will not get locked out for any
longer period, even if someone else tried to attack their account and the brute force tries will be
slowed down enough to make this kind of attack vastly inefficient.
CAPTCHA is a feature that asks users to complete a task which for humans is trivial but for robots is
theoretically impossible.
It was invented to fend off robots from completing a sensitive process and to mitigate brute force attacks,
which always include robots.
In its original form, the task was to rewrite a set of characters from an image.
But now it can be to choose photos that include some particular object or to arrange simple puzzles.
Whatever the mechanism is, there is a number of problems with it.
First, it's not the most user friendly feature.
It's actually very annoying for people because then it's legitimate users who need to make an extra
effort to protect the whole service.
At times it's not clear enough even for a healthy, educated adult.
And it may be tricky for people with disabilities as it is for robots.
And it's not unbreakable either.
With the growing popularity of A.I. Solutions, the relative simplicity to create neural networks and
the growing number of people are trying to break whatever they can.
Not a single capture mechanism can be safe.
There are also companies that hire people from less developed countries to break up just manually.
Having that in mind, I discourage from using CAPTCHA as a basic and brute force method.
If you really like this solution and desperately wants to implement it, consider creating a mechanism
that will allow a number of requests from one person before the CAPTCHA comes in.
In case of a login form, it would be easy because you could adjust the previous example to require
CAPTCHA if the login attempts number is greater than the maximum number of attempts allowed.
However, having to answer reCAPTCHA in such a frequently used thing like login form is well, super
annoying.
Of course, none of the mentioned techniques will prevent anyone from cracking passwords when the database
leaks.
If they know the hash, they can crack it locally without any limits.
And CAPTCHAs.
This is why it's very important to protect your database, protect your server, and use strong hashing
algorithms for passwords.
For example, decrypt.
And you can use the discussed methods not only to secure a log in forms, but also for every identifiable
resource for which you can determine a legitimate and illegitimate request.
Let's say you have an online store.
The order summary page needs order I.D. and the secret token, of course.
You should look out the summary page for the given order and whenever there's too many attempts to access
it with an invalid token.
If your tokens are not trivial, you can use the slowing down method and lockouts that last only a couple
of seconds.
Such short limits will make the brute force attack completely inefficient.
But at the same time, your illegitimate users will still be able to view those pages when they need.
The brute force method can be also used to find files or directories on your server which exist but
are not linked from anywhere.
Or to discover URLs that rewrite to publicly accessible resources which were not meant to be accessed.
This way an attacker can gain access to all unprotected files and pages which someone thought they are
safe just by not linking to them from anywhere.
This particular threat can be, of course, mitigated by properly protecting files on the server, which
we talked about in one of the early chapters.
And not publishing any website content that is not meant to be public.