Allowing users to upload files poses a big security risk for your site.
If you don't thoroughly examined the files, you'll receive.
Similarly to how attackers can try to run Ezekial or JavaScript on your site by entering comments into
your forum fields, for example, they can try to attack your site or server by uploading files that
are not what they seem to be and which would run code when uploaded and then opened in the browser.
Let's see how we can mitigate these risks in BGP when the file is being uploaded.
Its data is available in the file.
Super global.
The entry index file in this example is the emails field the name.
You can see the file Super Global contains an original file name as opposed to mine type a temporary
location from which it should be moved to be permanently saved on the server.
Error code where zero is no error and size in bytes.
To save the file on the server from the script you need to move.
Upload the file, function like this.
This is the most basic and highly, highly insecure code.
Any file type will be accepted of any size and with any name that opens a whole bunch of vulnerabilities.
To mitigate them.
During each final upload, we need to perform a number of checks.
First of all, check if the file size doesn't exceed your maximum allowed size.
The maximum uploaded file size can be set in various places.
For example, in P2P configuration with the upload max file size directive.
In this case, it limits the uploaded fight to two megabytes, which is the default value.
It can be changed per directory with the user INI file or access file.
This is the fundamental setting which cannot be bypassed.
You can also combine it with apertures limit request, body directive.
Putting this line in the access file will limit the size of requests body, which is data coming to
the server to two megabytes.
You can also set your own monks file size in the code and check the incoming file against your own limit.
In this code.
If there is one, then it means the server maximum size has been exceeded and the second condition checks
to calculate its size against our own custom limit.
The beach.
B Dogs also say that you can set the max file size in an A.T.M. form by using an input.
But because anything on the front end can be manipulated.
Don't rely on this setting to keep uploaded files within the limit.
It's only useful for legitimate users for a quick check on the backend.
If a file they uploaded is larger than Mark's file size value, some data transfer will be saved.
And for that file, BHP will return the error code number two.
So if you use this hidden field, you can combine this condition with the earlier check.
Then check if the uploaded final name has a valid whitelisted extension.
You can use their regular expression for that.
In this code, we look for a literal note character followed by any of JPEG, GIF or PNG.
Just remember to always validate the end of a string by adding the trading dollar sign.
Because if you wanted the dollar sign or just validate the name against the jpeg in a string, not requiring
it to be at the end of the string, someone could upload image dot jpeg, dot BHP and the filter would
allow it.
When setting up the white list.
Definitely avoid allowing any executables or potential executables like html xml as vague js as w,
f, BHP, ISP and Apex CGI, BSL or GSP.
In the chapter about cross scripting, we discuss the way images in SVG format are too dangerous to
be accepted as user uploads and definitely don't skip this part.
Every uploaded file must have the proper extension that is on the whitelist.
You don't want to let in a file named Dot Access, right?
Finally check the mind type.
This time also against a white list of allowed types.
In this code.
I used a file info module to read the mime type from an actually uploaded file rather than reading mime
type that comes in a file super global s upload method data and which can be potentially fooled by an
attacker.
When saving a file never street under original name, it can contain malicious characters, a reserved
name like easy to access or be bene or be very, very long with an intention to break your system.
Use the randomly generated name.
In this code, we first get the information, then build file path with path info function.
We needed to get the file extension.
Then we generate a random name and append the dot and original extension to it.
You can also combine the random name with heavily filtered and truncated original name.
Let's build a function for that.
Here.
First we get the file, but the info works separately on file name and extension.
Then we change all whitespace to hyphens.
Then we remove all characters, which are not letters.
Digits, underscores and dashes.
And then we truncate the name to 40 chars to avoid any excessively long file names.
Finally we generate the random string.
Join it with dash with the filtered original file name, append the dot and the original extension and
this is the result.
But we should do one more thing.
Check if a file under the same name doesn't already exist.
To prevent overwriting files.
In this example, the new file name is generated by a recursive function that keeps generating the final,
final name with preceding random chars until there is no file under the same name.
So first it generates a final name just like we did before, but then it checks if there is a file under
the same name in the target directory.
If yes, it calls itself once again to generate a new name with the new random string.
If not, it returns the final name to the parent function, which then returns it to your final upload
script.
Started the uploaded fires in a pre-defined place in a designated folder.
You can also limit the potential danger by storing files, and there are different domain to mitigate
any potential cross-site scripting attacks coming from uploaded files on the different server to mitigate
any potential shell code execution from an uploaded files in a write only directory.
If you don't want anyone from the outside to be able to open the files after uploading.
Or in a directory with disabled script execution, you can easily disable BHP execution per directory
by putting this line in your HD access file in the uploads folder.
But there are other scripts out there in Python, Petal, etc. to disable them all.
Use this at the beginning of your HD access file.
Don't worry about the image in the media files.
They will work as usual.
Be careful though, because if the user is able to create some directories in your upload directory
or upload zip packages that are unpacked into directory trees, it may be possible that they smuggle
their own HD access file that will override this protection in a directory will get to handling zip
files in a while.