We already discussed some security concerns regarding cookies.
Let's now sum it up and talk about other cookies properties as pretty much all of them have some impact
on security.
But first, let's discuss what you can store in the cookies and what you absolutely shouldn't.
Cookies and any other mechanisms that allow you to store anything in the user's browser, like local
storage or session storage, are a convenient way to hold some data between your requests, but they
can be entirely manipulated by users, which includes changing its values, properties, creating and
deleting them.
They store all the data in plaintext and they can be stolen with a cross-site scripting attack.
So not only it's unsafe to store anything critical or secret there, but it also can't be trusted.
A secure application should depend on the minimum of browsers storage.
Ideally, it should only set the cookie with this session.
I'd never store any log in financial or any other critical information in the browser.
It is not saved there in the way it can be stolen.
And also you can't trust this data once you stole it there.
A part of that.
Feel free to use cookies or web storage for any insignificant data like users language choice indications
that they some pop up or some other preferences.
Where to store all the other critical information always on the server in this session?
Data.
As the syntax for creating cookies is essentially just how atypical others are defined.
You need to take extra care when setting the name and value for a cookie.
For example, a semicolon or equal sign have special meanings in the syntax.
So if you pass an input with those characters directly as the cookies value, the syntax goes completely
wrong.
This is an example of a raw HTP header, but usually you would rather create a cookie with set cookie
function in BGP or with document cookie property in JavaScript.
So let's see how it works there.
When you use set cookie function in B2B, the cookies value will automatically be encoded like you would
pass it through or url encode function.
So even if it contains some cons equals signs, spaces and other special channels, it will not break
the syntax.
This code would set the cookie named model with the properly encoded value.
Which after decoding is what we originally wanted.
You don't need to do the decoding by yourself because the value in the cookie super global is already
well decoded.
And you can see the max age was correctly a part of cookie value, not the actual cookie parameter,
but because cookie name cannot be encoded, BHP will not let you use any of the reserved characters
like whitespace.
Single quote equals sign, comma or semicolon.
You will get the page B warning instead.
That's why you need to keep cookie names free of any of those characters.
JavaScript, on the other hand, will do nothing for you when setting cookies with document cookie property.
You pretty much have to follow the HTP header syntax.
This code would set the cookie named model with the value of that's the cookie and the max eight parameter
5000 seconds from now because the value has not been encoded.
You need to do it by yourself.
And in JavaScript, the corresponding functions to be raw.
You are in code and the raw you are the code are in code.
You are a component and the code you are a component respectively.
But let me remind you that JavaScript and code, you are a component and each piece of all you are in
code are not 100% equal in which characters they encode.
We discussed the these differences in this chapter about cross-site scripting, and I showed you the
methods suggested on MDM that fixes the JavaScript function.
It runs the original method on the string and then encodes the five remaining characters that encode
you are a component, leaves out exclamation mark, single quote left and right, parentheses and then
asterisk.
Using this method, you can safely exchange your AI encoded cookie data between JavaScript and BHP,
for example, creating a cookie with a JavaScript.
And reading it with BHP.
There are certain cookies which you don't want to be alive for too long.
Cookies that hold authenticated user session are a great example.
However, in BGP, the parameters are controlled by PDP configuration.
You don't set the manually, but still you can have other session related or privacy related cookies
that you might only wants to store for a limited time.
The cookies lifetime can be set using either of the two parameters expires or max age.
The expires attribute sets the absolute expiry date and it expects a full date and time in UTC string
format like in this example.
Of course it's easy to create this very specific string in BHP set cookie function, you just pass the
timestamp and BHP internally generated the correct date and time string.
BHP 7.3 introduced a new signature four set cookie function, which allows you to set the attributes
you want as an array rather than setting all the optional ones before the one that you actually wanted
to set.
In case of expires attributes, it is the first of the optional attributes, but using array is very
useful for other attributes that we'll be talking about.
And in JavaScript you would use two UTC string method of date object.
Here in the first line, we create a new date object and past with the current timestamp plus 86400
seconds, which is one day in the second line where we define the cookie.
We just use this date object to UTC string method.
The max age attributes sets the expiration time relative to current the date and time.
In other words, the length of the cookies life in seconds.
So it only needs a number of seconds from now.
This is an example in JavaScript.
It's much simpler than before because we only pass the difference in seconds rather than creating a
date object and converting it to UTC string.
For P2P.
I don't even have an example because the cookie function doesn't allow you to set the max age attribute,
although setting expires is effectively the same.
And one note, if both expires and max age are set, the max age has precedence.
You can also deliberately not set the expires or max age attributes.
Then the browser theoretically deletes the cookie after session ends, which in general is when the
browser window is closed.
I underline the word theoretically because it's not something you can relate for 400%.
First.
This is up to the browser to determine whether this session has terminated or not.
It's out of your control so the cookie can be stored longer than you would like.
Second, browsers now have methods for restoring sessions, so again, the cookie might not be deleted
when you thought it was.
Better to either set the expiry date or maximum age.
Or just make your app delete the cookie when you decide it's time for it to go.
To delete the cookie from your application, you need to set it expiry attributes to a past date.
Unfortunately, it's a little bit awkward.
This is how to do it in JavaScript.
In BHP, you need to set both the past expiry date and an empty value.
Another caveat here is that you need to call the set cookie function with exactly the same attributes
as you did when creating the cookie.
Otherwise, it will not work.
Of course not.
Counting the value and expiration date.
When creating a cookie, you can set the domain attributes, but you need to be aware that any subdomain
of your domain can now read the cookies from your domain.
So if you control the site under example dot com but have no control over local example dot com.
It means that your cookies are unsafe because for example dot com can access all cookies.
That example dot com sets.
To overcome this, you would need to, once again, awkwardly and counterintuitively, all meet the
domain attributes when the domain attribute is empty, only the origin that the cookie can access it
and subdomains are excluded.
So you would need to use the same protocol domain and port as when you created the cookie.
So when to use the domain attribute, when you explicitly want to share cookies with some domains,
for example to share the cookie from example dot com with payments example dot com.
But you need to ensure that you have the control over all some domains.
This is an example of that domain attribute in BHP.
As you see in BGP versions earlier than 7.3, you need to specify both expires and path to be able to
set the domain.
And this is an example in JavaScript.
You can further restrict their cookies availability with the path attributes.
This will only send a cookie when users accessing a page inside an admin directory.
The cookie will not be sent to requests outside the admin section.
However, it does not make it impossible to access the cookie from other paths.
If your site has an existing vulnerability and an attacker could manage to insert their own script.
It would be enough to add a frame with their requested path and on the front page read the cookies from
that iframe.
Impeach be if you are on 7.3 or higher, I recommend that you use the functional signature with attributes
array because otherwise you need to specify all preceding optional parameters.
So the first line for be less than 7.3.
We need to specify the third parameter.
The third one is the value for expires.
Here we set a default value of zero because we don't actually wants to set it.
In the second line, we can comfortably use an array and set the path in an array element under the
path key.
And this is the code to set the path attribute in JavaScript.
The HTP only attribute indicates that the cookie can only be set red and deleted on the back end.
It effectively protects the cookie and its content from JavaScript.
If your site had an exercise within our ability, a malicious user might be able to read.
For example, this session cookies and hijack user sessions, which could have fatal consequences.
Session.
Cookies are one example of cookies that should always be asked to be only in general.
Use this attribute always when you will not need to read the cookie on the client side.
So there will be no code example in JavaScript.
In BHP you set the cookie to be only like this.
Here in the first line we need to set a bunch of default options to be able to set the HTP only attribute,
which is the sixth.
You see, the new syntax in 7.3 is way more comfortable to use.
A similar attributes to ATP only, which is also often used together, is secure.
It ensures the cookie will only be sent over the HTTPS protocol by setting this flag.
You can prevent leaking cookie data like session ID if an attacker would be able to create a non HTP
s request.
This is how to set this flag in BHP.
Unlike HTP only this flag can be set when creating a cookie with JavaScript and secure cookies are readable
by JavaScript as well.
This is the JavaScript example of creating a secure cookie.
And there's the last attribute.
Same site.
It prevents sending their cookies with cross-site requests, and it can have one of the three values
strict, lax or non.
If you didn't watch the chapter about cross-site request forgery, I strongly recommend you to do it
because in that chapter I discussed the details of how it actually helps to prevent those kinds of attacks
and what these three values actually mean.
This is how you said the same sector tribute in BHP 7.3 and higher.
Unfortunately in P2P versions before 7.3, there is no option to set this attribute within said cookie
function.
One more reason to upgrade whenever possible.
Alternatively, you can send the cookie by directly sending the said cookie htp header using the header
function.
And this is how you said the attribute in JavaScript.