Okay.
Let's first try to organize our thoughts.
What does make a website secure or not, in my view?
A secure website is the one that doesn't use outdated and insecure software and technologies resides
in a work configured environment which protects all of its components, uses encrypted connection for
data transfer, thoroughly verifies any data coming from the outside, also from its users before processing
it with methods that can be fooled.
Protects any sensitive data and functionalities from unauthorized access, doesn't reveal too much information
about itself, how it's constructed and how it works.
Doesn't let any external environments influence itself and is able to fend off any automated attacks
that are carried out to break the security systems or disrupted.
As you see, the list is quite long and the terms are very broad indeed.
In this course we bring up a number of different areas on which a web developer can improve the safety.
All of these are involved server configuration, frontend code, backend code, selection of third party
components, configuration of quantum management systems if used, and adoption of certain processes
targeted at specific types of attacks.