Before we talk about security holes in the actual code and preventing attacks on your sites, let me
start with something fundamental.
Protecting the files and resources on the server.
You should always be aware that everything that you upload to your server, especially within the root
folder, which is typically public HTML or w w w is publicly accessible unless you're directly protected.
There are ways to do it, of course, but people often forget to do it or don't care about it.
An example would be a database snapshot hosted along the WordPress files or a folder with backups.
Anyone entering the correct URL in their browsers will now be able to download the school or zip file
and therefore gain full access to the database structure in the contents and the code base.
You'd say, I'm not going to share this link with anyone and I'm going to name the file in a way.
Hard to guess.
I would say it really doesn't matter how you name the file and how much effort you will make to keep
its you are a secret.
The problem is that millions of bots are scanning the web all the time.
Some do it to provide us with the best search results, but others may do it for other purposes.
For example, to find something interesting and it might happen that boss will somehow find your files.
Try this link if you don't believe me.
I don't think many of these fires were deliberately linked.
So any secret subdomain folder name or file name will not give you much security.
This is a classic example of security by obscurity, which is not going to provide much protection on
its own.
And the other problem is that there are certain file types which are executable like BHP and those which
reveal their contents or first download like squirrel zip or once popular EMC for BHP include files.
So if you put your theme back up as a zip package, anyone who downloads it will have a complete code
of your theme.
And if your theme have any exploitable security holes, you're lost.
So how to solve the problem?
The first idea would be to avoid storing anything on the server beside your website.
If you need to have files stored online, you can either store them outside of the root directory so
that no browser could reach them and you would only be able to get them via FCP connection or host them
on the external encrypted cloud storage services where only authorised people would be able to read
them.
The second idea would be to password protect the folder that is not meant for public access, at least
with basic authentication.
Is that generic logging and password form handled by the browser?
It's very simple to set up.
There are, however, some risks.
First, if you don't use SSL, the log in and passwords you entering the browser will be sent to the
server as a plaintext without any encryption.
This is really basic authentication system and as such it can be picked by someone having access to
the network traffic.
So using SSL will greatly improve the security of this basic protection.
Second, the log in and password are sent by the browser with each single request, which means more
opportunities for the potential attacker.
Third, if you share the log in and password with someone else, they might store their credentials
in their browsers, either for convenience or by accident.
And it might cause unauthorized access to the files by someone else using their computer.
Anyway, how to set up basic authentication.
If you're on Apache, you need two files, not a password placed anywhere on the server which will store
the username and password pairs and dot the access place within the folder you want to protect, which
will turn on the basic authentication for that directory and its subdirectories.
H t password can really be placed anywhere, even outside the neighborhood, like on the example because
in HD access you will have to provide the full path, though it will get to that.
You can generate a password file in various ways.
If you're comfortable with Common Lane and you have a cell access, you can use the password command.
That C flag is for creating a new file.
Then you provide the file name and then the first user's name after hitting enter.
You will be prompted for password and asked to retype it to add more users around the same command.
But this time without C flag, you can also type a password generator in your search engine.
You will get lots of pages that can generate different contents for you.
Copied the generated content and paste inside the blank XD password file on your server.
Remember though as anything you type in might be locked somewhere, so you're pretty much giving out
your credentials.
However, the generator owner most probably will not know where to use them.
Another method would be to check out with your hosting provider because you might find the password
generator in your server's control panel.
When you're done with creating a password file, you'll need an SD access file in a directory that you
wants to protect.
In this file, you will actually turn on the basic authentication mechanism.
If the file doesn't exist, create it, and put their record like this.
The first line is a message that will be prompted to the user.
The second one defines the basic authentication mechanism.
It turns it on.
The third line is a full path to your password file, but starting from server route and not your side
route.
The fourth line specifies which users are permitted to log in.
In our case, it's any valid user, but you can explicitly allow only Matt or Bob.
Note there is no comma between usernames, only a space.
The third idea would be to simply deny access to the folder for anyone in aperture.
It's done with the access file like this.
The first part of the code is dedicated for apart version 2.3 and higher.
And the second part is for the legacy versions.
Now anyone trying to access the folder or its contents with a browser will just receive deferral through
forbidden status.
With this configuration, you are limited to accessing the files inside with FTP client, but you can
choose to whitelist any apps on which you have full control.
That means if you have a static IP and you are sure no one will have it assigned to them in the foreseeable
future.
Now people from these apps will be able to access the directory contents with their browsers.
Not that in the first part for aperture 2.3 or higher, the apps are separated by a space without any
commas.
You can also protect the files or directories by setting proper permissions.
In case you don't know how file permissions work.
Here's a short explanation.
There are three types of action read, write and execute and three access levels owner group others.
Each action can be permitted or not to each of the access levels like in this table in which group and
others are not given the right permission.
The two usual notations are symbolic notation in which you have ten chars and the shorter numeric notation
in which you have usually three digits in symbolic notation.
The first chart can either be D for directory or dash, which means not a directory file.
Then you have three times three channels for each access level, user group and others.
First of three can either be our which means can read or does which means can treat.
Second can be either w which means can right.
Or that which means can write.
And third can be either eggs, which means can execute orders, which means can't execute.
So the first example is the directory with all access enabled.
And the second example is a file which can be read by everybody, but only the owner can write to it
that is at its contents.
In numeric notation.
Each digits represent the permissions for each access level, and these examples have exactly the same
meaning as the previous ones.
How do we know the number?
Here's the key.
Four is read.
Two is right.
And the one is execute to set multiple permissions.
For example, read and write you just some the values.
And because the key values are one, two and four, the sum of any of them will always produce a unique
number one and two is three.
Four plus one is five.
Four plus two is six and four.
Plus two plus one is seven.
Okay.
So what needs to be said so that a file or folder would be protected from the outside world to protect
the single file?
You need to set the others read permission to zero.
For example, set it to 6420.
To protect the directory and all its contents, you need to set the others execute permission to zero.
The 640 setting that we use for files will work just fine.