Third party components are all pieces of code that build your project, which you or your team didn't
write all frameworks, libraries, plugins or scripts released by people outside of your organization.
It's virtually impossible to code everything by yourself in any medium to large project either when
you build a site on the CMS.
Use a framework to speed up development or just don't want to reinvent the wheel.
But I always try and I encourage you to minimize the number of third party components.
Placing a ready piece of code often seems like a fine idea to save some time and have the job done.
But there's a lot that can go wrong.
Third party components are often open source projects used by many websites.
Attackers will search for potential security holes in popular libraries and scripts to be able to carry
out the same attack on lots of websites.
Some scripts available on the Internet are simply poorly coded, and they can have obvious security
vulnerabilities.
Also, some people will stop maintaining their projects at some point and any potential security holes
will not be fixed anymore.
Also, you need to monitor all your dependencies for upgrades, especially those related to security.
And when the new version is released, you need to integrate it in your project and test if it will
still be compatible.
So the more third party components you choose to put in your project, the more potential vulnerabilities
you introduce and the more effort it will need from you to maintain it.
Having said all that, I will encourage you in this course to use some third party solutions for certain
highly complicated and really difficult tasks where any in-house solution would be simply insufficient.
Finally, let me give you a couple of hints how to choose a good third party component, a part of checking
if it fulfills all your requirements and has a proper license.
See if it's actively maintained and have an active support when it's free, then at least a decent forum
or community board would definitely help.
Verify the latest release date.
If it's not within 12 months, it might have been already abandoned.
See if people are using it or talking about it.
On PM see the right column.
On GitHub.
Check the issue step.
Download it only from trusted sources like author website or unofficial GitHub repository and try to
analyze if it's of a good quality security wise, performance wise, etc..
This may be very hard to verify on your own, but if you are about to use a renowned popular library
which has a lot of active users, then you can assume it's at least of a decent quality.