Some people think that using local storage or session storage makes the data more secure just because
it's not sent anywhere out from the browser.
In fact its otherwise whipped storage offers no protection to the data at all.
It's a simple and pretty much public storage mechanism.
Of course, under normal circumstances it's impossible.
That site a read something from site B's web storage.
But a single access vulnerability will make it almost trivial.
Also, if a device is used by multiple users or someone gains access to the device, the storage data
can be pretty easily accessed by a malicious person if only they know how to find it, which is not
too complicated at all.
Both of these are true for non HTP only cookies as well, so simply using cookies instead of storage
is not more secure.
That's why I always encouraged to store all the sensitive data on the server and only store a session
ID in their cookie.
When you protected with HTP only and secure flags, it will be impossible to read ID with JavaScript
addressing threats coming from existing vulnerabilities and it will be encrypted during exchange with
the server.
Up to this same St Anne's tribute with the value of lax or strict.
And you pretty much did everything you need.
In other words, don't store anything important neither in local storage nor in non htp only cookies.
You have to store decision it somewhere in the browser, but if you do it as described above, the damage
is vastly limited.
The assertion that it cannot be stolen using JavaScript.
And even if somehow the attacker will gain access to the victim's computer and manually read the HTP
only cookie.
Their only hope is trying to attack this session, which you can also make pretty much impossible.
As you can learn in the chapter about session management.
Last.
Storing data on the server protects the integrity of data.
The session data on the server cannot be easily manipulated contrary to the data in the browser, which
is trivial to change, not with ease.
If only you can use browsers dev tools.
In other words, to the data from storage and cookies as any input data coming from user strict validation
and sanitization is required.