Now is the time to take a look at the actual data validation methods, how to make sure what the user
sent is what we expect.
Whenever your language has a built in validation or sanitization methods, you should probably use them.
A language is created by teams where people have shared their expertise and the code base is frequently
monitored and improved, which basically means we can count on these functionalities.
Also, some of them may be simply faster than equivalence written as a custom code.
BHP has a built in filtering system which offers a set of validation and sanitization methods.
It works like in these two examples.
Usually this particular filtering system works well.
However, some of the filters may not always work.
How you expect.
For example, an email address valued according to P2P filters may not look like you think it should.
Also when sanitizing data, you must remember that these filters sanitize data for a given context.
For example, the filter sanitize email would not sanitize the email in a way that would make it safe
for direct use in the query or for direct output on the front end because according to the commendation,
it doesn't remove these characters.
Not the single quote character which is allowed in email address syntax but can be pretty dangerous
when not escaped either in school or in HTML.
So that filter only sanitize the e-mail address to be used within e-mail operations, not in other contexts.
Before you use filters, you need to carefully study what they actually do and what particular filters
are for.
Anyway, as I mentioned earlier, the built in methods are usually the way to go.
But in this chapter, I'd like to show you instead the manual methods to validate data first, because
not all types of data have corresponding filters and PDB.
Second, because for usability, the equal validation process should work on the frontend, which means
we need 100% compatible methods in JavaScript.
And third, in case you need more granular control over the validation process.
For example, in the aforementioned case of email addresses, the P2P validation would have to pass
through an email like test at best because it is technically correct email address according to standards.
But if you expect a public email address, you definitely need at least one dot after the ET sign because
any public domain must contain at least one dot sign.
One of the initial checks you will have to perform is whether the input data actually exists for any
required field or parameter.
If there's no value, there's no point to do any other checks and it can be immediately rejected.
In BHP, one of my favourite functions is empty, which will return true whenever a variable doesn't
exist or has a value which evaluates to false.
When you expect a string.
It's also a good idea to dream it, to make sure it doesn't contain whitespace only, which would be
a multi-character representation of an empty string.
It may be useful to make a helper function.
In the same manner.
You should always trim the string when you check its length to catch situations in which the string
is just padded with whitespace to the expected length.
When using empathy function.
Beware that for numeric values, zero might be a perfectly valid and meaningful value despite evaluates
to false.
In case you might need to deal with numerical values where zero is not considered empty, you shouldn't
use empty function but rather is set.
And then cut the value to string three meet and only then check this string length.
Even after casting two strings we need to use and beat string length.
Not empty because empty will treat string zero as empty value to watch out for such surprises when validating
data.
So to sum up before any further validation, check the existence of mandatory fields.
The first check is for old string values, which should not be empty or contain whitespace only.
The second check is the same, but with an exception which allows string zero.
Both examples use functions which we just defined.
In JavaScript, you can simply do this and it will work pretty much the same as empty in BHP.
To check for an empty or white space drink.
You can use this function.
In JavaScript, you don't need a solution for the case of string zero.
It will not be considered empty, but the number is zero.
Of course will be treated as empty in the code.
Snippets coming next.
I assume this initial non empty check is already done, so we will be able to focus on specific validation
methods for different data types.