Whenever you decide to include on your site any external resources that is hosted on the server, you
don't control your site effectively depends on that server security.
So if you use CDM for convenience or for performance and load scripts or web fonts from Sydney and that's
Sydney and gets hacked, your site also gets hacked because it may then includes resources you didn't
want.
So for security, the best approach would be to store all scripts, styles, fonts and similar resources
on your own server.
But there's one neat method that allows you to have a cake and eat it to this method called sub resource
integrity allows you to ensure the externally stored files are exactly what you expect and it is currently
supported by all major browsers.
It works by simply passing the integrity attributes to script ordering tag, and that attribute should
contain a base64 encoded value to check some of the linked file prefixed by hash algorithm and the dash.
If you wonder how we can obtain this checksum, you can use your common lane tool with this instruction
or use the three hash that or website.
If you don't feel the command line.
Note that because we used SHA 384 algorithm in the integrity attributes, we prefix the hashes that
it generated with sharp 384 and the dash.
In the integrity attributes.
The hash always needs to be prefixed with the algorithm, name and the dash.
Note also that the browsers will check the external file against its cross origin resource sharing policy,
which means if that external server wants to share the file with our site, hence the mandatory use
of cross origin attribute.
Now you can get into trouble when the external file changes for legitimate purposes because the checksum
will not match.
For this to work, your CDM should never change the file contents and the when they provide a new version
of a resource.
It should come with the new file name.
For example, if you build a j query from the CDM, each version has its own.
Finally, so you don't need to worry your site or app will stop working on the next release.
Even if you load the latest version, the file name will always include the version number.
You will have to manually update your site to the most recent version and during that process, update
the checksum in the integrity attribute.
You are probably not aware.
And I also wasn't aware for a long time that if you redirect a user to an external site by opening it
in a new window or tab like this, these external site four dot com in our example has now some control
of the window object of your page, which the user still has open in their browser.
This is also a case whenever we open a new window using JavaScript window open method.
See the live example.
This is an example with an external link.
Let me click that link.
A new page opens in a new tab and when I go back to the previous tab, bam!
So now we've seen this is really the case.
Let me explain how this is possible.
Any page that is open in a new window or tab has a window open their property in JavaScript, which
points to the window object of the page that opens this new window, the current page.
And then it's really simple to do a redirect in the open window.
In the example shown, you clearly see that the page is different, but it could be as well.
And if your page looking just like the original one, but doing some malicious stuff like phishing,
changing the login button link to as we're monitoring what you type forms, etc., etc. and because
the user would most likely be focused on the newly opened window word tab, the changes that happen
in the open their window, for example, the redirect will happen unnoticed if it's that easy and we
open links in new tabs all the time, then how come you're all still alive and most people never got
hacked?
I don't know.
Anyway, there are of course, options to solve.
The problem first would be to not open links in the new windows.
If you open a new page in the same window, there will be no open page on the target page because it
stopped existing when the new document was loaded in the same way in the word tab.
But I really like the idea of opening some links in new tabs for example, external links.
So lets see other options.
Use the rule attribute with no opener value in all linked tags which open in new windows or tabs.
This will make the window open there unavailable on the destination link.
If you would like to support some older browsers, for example, Edge only recently added support for
an opener.
You can combine it with no referrer, but it will also clear the referrer header so the destination
site will not know where the traffic came from.
Which is worth noting if you care about it.
It's not too elegant because you need to specify this attribute on every external link, which can be
rather annoying.
Luckily for WordPress users, WordPress does it automatically for links in post content so your editors
don't need to care.
For links open with the JavaScript window open method.
You can clearly open their property right after calling the open method.
Anyway.
I'd rather like to have it done with this single HTP response header with which we could define the
behaviour once for the whole site like we can do with other security features.
For now.
Recently, browsers started to implicitly disable the open their property for links that open in new
windows that these which have a target attribute set to underscore blank.