Let's start with the most basic context in which you may need to put some data, a HTML element content.
It's difficult to whitelist allowed characters if we expect an arbitrary text like a user's full name
post content or a message.
And as we discussed in the chapter about the validation, stripping tax can be quite difficult and is
often faulty.
So instead of removing tags or everything apart allowed characters, you need to escape the potentially
dangerous ones.
In this context, you definitely should escape these five characters ampersand, left and right and
glue brackets, double quote and single quote.
We need to escape them.
Or in other words, and code, because an escape they can form an email code, which we don't want.
So if we don't expect any markup, we just escape these five characters instead of trying to strip tags.
This way the page will display any potential tags in plaintext rather than trying to interpret them.
And the page will be safe.
In BHP.
This is done by a special function which converts these five features into corresponding A.T.M. entities.
So when we want to render some user data on page in the element content context, we just need to pass
it to this function before we print it.
In this example, the script tag and its contents will be rendered on page as the visible code.
Rather than being interpreted, the script will not execute.
The East Timor special charters function will be your best friend in excess as prevention because it's
useful in other contexts as well.
But please note that by default it doesn't escape the last character of the five that they pointed out,
which is a single quote.
The function accepts up to four arguments.
The input string of course, flags and encoding and the double encode parameter.
The second argument flags is really important.
See this?
When used without the flag, the function will not escape.
Single quotes.
When used with the end quotes flag.
The function will escape both double and single quotes, which is what we usually want.
So this is how you would normally wants to run this function?
In this context, it doesn't make much difference, but it will make in other contexts.
Finally, you can opt out from escaping any quotes by explicitly setting and no quotes flag which means
only English brackets and ampersand will be escaped.
This may only be used safely in the time of element content context, but they don't see practical reasons
not to escape quotes.
So by default, I always use and quotes.
It's a good habit.
Also, the third argument is important.
If you need to escape a string which is encoded in the charge set other than the one set in default
charge set configuration in BHP by default, this is UTF eight.
So if you use something else on your site or if the specific string is encoded with difference, Char
said you must specified in a third argument.
Ideally, use UTF eight everywhere on your site.
It can handle many characters and should suit your needs.
BHP functions by default.
Use UTF eight other like JSON decode.
Accept only UTF eight input.
So any data coming in another encoding must be converted first.
In this course, I assumed the use of UTF eight everywhere.
HMO entities is a similar function, and these two are sometimes confused.
The difference is that each team of entities converts all characters that give entity equivalence,
which means not only dimension five, but also those like copyright or a registered trademark symbol.
To protect your site from cross-site scripting attacks each time a special jars is enough.
The last two functions to mention just in case are a team of special chairs, the code and HTML and
the code which can be used to reverse the convention made by encoding functions.
What about the front end code vulnerable to DOM based access?
Unfortunately, in pure JavaScript there is no team of special chars nor entities equivalent, so you're
left with doing it on your own.
The simplest way to do that is to run the replace method on the target string.
In this function, we first create an object with character and entity pairs and then run the replace
method on the string.
The replace method accepts a function as a second argument which returns and encoded entity from a collection
of character entity pairs with defined at the beginning.
And this is how to use it.
This code will print inside the node element, the HTML code rather than execute it and the display
and alert.
The other way to safely place the plaintext user input on page would be to use a text content or an
inner text property of an element.
Both methods will exactly what have been passed in a string John Doe left and grew bracket, AMG, etc.
instead of trying to place an image so both will not allow any HTML to run.
But note they are not identical.
The differences are mostly visible when getting the text from a note, but setting a note content will
give pretty much the same output with both properties.
How do you think which approach is better?
The team of special charges function that we created or using text content or in their text properties.
Both are fine, but the function can be used more often.
For example, using the function you can combine your own HTML with the user input.
Whereas when using text content or inert text properties, the whole node would have to contain plain
text only because even your own HTML would be saved by the browser and print it out.
And those properties can only be used to put user data in the HD element content context, not for anything
else like attribute values.
When putting user data inside each team attribute values using the very same HMO special charts function.
But note that it will only protect your site when you are very strict with quoting attribute values
and remember about the second argument of the function.
In other words, this is safe.
But these are not.
See the difference.
In the first example, we surrounded the value with double quotes.
In the second example, we properly use the team of special jars function but failed to enclose the
attribute value with quotes.
So the attacker can easily break out from the attribute value context, even with a space which is not
escaped here.
In the third example, we used a single quote, which theoretically is fine, but we failed to add the
end quotes flag.
So it's also possible to break out from the context with a single quote that would remain on the escaped.
You see, you can get a false sense of security here if you don't keep your estimate clean and consistent
by either not using quotes or sometimes using single and sometimes using double quotes and without consistent
use of and quotes.
Flag for most special features function.
Mixing single and double quotes is frequent when printing H.M. with BHP.
In this code someone used single quotes to avoid having to escape a double quote.
In reality, in this example, we could just add and quote, flag instead of changing the quote type.
But because it's so easy to make a mistake in such situations, I recommend you to develop your own
coding standards here, always and everywhere.
Use double quotes for attribute values and always use and quotes flag for each html special chars function.
Be consistent.
Make a habit of it so that you don't accidentally forget the flag when it's needed.
There's no harm in encoding the single code always, but there is a harm to fail to encode it when necessary.
Don't give yourself more opportunities to fail by randomly using single and double quotes for attribute
values.
You might wonder why would they let a user decide on the old tag name?
Well, one use case would be to allow user to select a heading level.
Then on the beach, you might want to use the form data this way.
Of course, that's highly insecure.
We know we can't trust that such incoming data is what we expect because any user can alter values in
this select form element or just send an arbitrary post request.
But even more special jars function will not help in this context.
See this?
The user can send this drink script as their heading level and it will only container letters, so theoretically
only super safe characters and nothing that would be escaped with most special charges.
And then the user can send something like alert one as heading contents and will end up with this.
Instead of something like this.
Of course, other one is nothing wrong within the proper heading element and can be a correct heading
in the real world.
So we should totally accept this.
What we need to fix is dog names.
The only secure way to let the user choose a tag name is to compare the incoming value with the white
list.
Luckily, the list of HDMI of tags is limited and well defined and also usually used, only let users
choose from yet further limited number of tags.
In our example, we don't need to whitelist all HTML tags except script style and other potentially
dangerous.
We only whitelist heading tags.
So first we defined the array of allowable tags, then changed the input string to lowercase for sake
of comparison, and then check if the input string can be found in the array.
If not, we override it with a default value.
This is the only way to safely let the user choose tag name.
You would do exactly the same in JavaScript.
First defined the array of allowed values.
Then get the field value and change it to lowercase.
Then compare it against the white list.
And fall back to default if it's not on the white list.
In a similar way, you might want to allow user to choose the attribute name.
For example, you might want to let users choose the event type.
Or for some reason to arbitrarily set the data attributes name.
These two examples are very different, but I can already tell you that again, East Timor's special
task function will not give us the required level of protection here.
Yes, it will not allowed to enter the dug with Anglo bracket instead of choosing attribute name, but
it will allow to choose whatever attribute the attacker wants or put more attributes in the tag.
One example suppose the attacker would change contact methods to x on most over.
And the contact field would be alert one.
The resulting code would be this
The data attribute becomes an empty data X attribute, and after space the attacker successfully introduced
an on mouse over attribute that will run.
The script passed in a contact field whenever the cursor that's on top of the element.
This is why we need another solution than HTML special function.
And there are two.
What we need for the first case is also a whitelist.
The HTML attributes are well defined and limited, just like HTML tags.
So we just need to whitelist them in the same way we did with HTML tags.
In our first example, we further limit ourselves to only two event attributes on click and on mouse
over.
Not.
We don't need any more.
The special chairs function here as the waitlist list does all the job in JavaScript you to do it exactly
the same way.
The second example where we use the user data to form a data attribute is not that easy to deal with
because data attributes are not well defined.
You can set any data attribute you wish as long as it contains the valid characters.
And according to the standard, the syntax is very relaxed.
But let's face it, usually it's only alphanumeric characters, dashes and maybe underscores.
So you can simply filter out any other character.
We only need to do that for the contact method field, which will form a part of an attribute name because
attribute value, the contact field only needs time of special chance function because it's properly
surrounded with double quotes.
In JavaScript, do the character filtering with the replace method.
And here we use our customised team of special task function that we created earlier for data value.
The other way to deal with the problem of arbitrary data attribute names would be to change the concept
here, and instead of forming data attribute as an attribute name and the value put both as data attribute
values and use a special chance function.
It may not be a good solution for certain scenarios, but definitely is the way to make your app safer.
Text re is a special HTML tag in which we often need to put user input but which will display the code
instead of executing it.
Or at least we think it will do that.
This code will show the demo code inside the text area field.
Browsers are intelligent enough to just render the code as text inside the exterior field, but it's
enough to prevent the malicious code with ending text the real target to actually run it.
So you can't just leave the input as it is and rely on the browser.
Luckily for the area element, it's enough to use HTML special charms function to be safe.
The closing text.
The real target will not execute now, but will be visible as text inside the field.
And what about inputs?
Tag values?
This we already know.
It's simply the attribute of value context.
Always use a team of special features and quote tag attributes when you fill in form data programmatically.
I showed you earlier in the theory part an example of how to break out of the context of a HTML comment
by presenting the string with two dashes and the right angle bracket, which is the sequence for ending
the email comment.
Here again, we are lucky that we can just use the most special chance method and we are safe.
The attacker will not be able now to break out of the comment context with the right angle bracket.