A part of configuring the server behavior you can set or unset certain HTP headers within your SD access
file when any request to the server is being made using HTP protocol.
There always need to be sent a couple of extra information.
For example, what type and coding and language variances expect that these are?
Accept, accept and coding and accept language headers.
What's relevant cookie the broader case and what the browser and operating system is?
That's user agent Heather.
The server also sends back a bunch of information, a part of the actual request at the final data,
content type, caching instructions, server software, information, etc. These are all HTP headers.
The first group those sent by the browser to the server are request headers and those sent back from
the server to the browser are response headers.
The response headers can be entirely manipulated by the site and there are certain response headers
that are not sent by default and should be added to the list to improve security.
But some of the request headers can also be influenced.
The HTP headers must be sent before any actual content that is before a payload.
You can define the HTP headers for example in Texas file using this syntax.
Cather always said instructed the server to always, for all the responses, send the particular response
header.
Then after space you need to provide the headers name.
In this case, it's ex content type option and after a space the headers value in case of simple alphanumeric
values.
You can provide them as they are, but you must use double quotes for more complex values.
For example, when there's a space character.
The aced it because they're defined in the Xs file will be sent with each single response not only for
HTML documents, but also for images, scripts, styles, fonts, etc..
You can also said the header directly within your application, which allows to make it conditional
in BHP units to use the header function, remembering that it must be called before any output has started.
In this case you don't need the header always set towards anymore and you need to type a column after
the headers name.
Also, any complex value doesn't need double quotes.
Any header defined in the PDP script will only be sent along the response for this particular document
request.
Their referrer policy.
HTP header tells the browser how much information it should reveal to the other side that your user
would navigate to from your site.
Let's see the example first.
The user is on your side on an article page.
The user then clicks along.
That goes to a third party site.
This third party site will receive the user of your page from which the user click the link in the referrer
request header.
And this can be manipulated.
You might want to do that in case you have something in your view, URLs that you wouldn't want to reveal.
The links can be clicked by logged in users or users with special privileges, revealing the paths to
admin panel features, for example.
URLs can also have query strings, including values passed with get methods, hopefully not including
session IDs, but something else that you simply don't wants to share.
And an attacker may want to intentionally place an attractive link on your site to exploit the data
from referrer headers.
It's a nice example in which using the response header you can influence how the requests are potentially
sent later will look like.
So there are several options to choose from as a referrer policy.
Empty string, no referrer same origin origin.
Strict origin origin when across origin strict origin when cross origin.
No referrer when downgrade.
Or unsafe.
You are a.
That's quite a long list.
But in reality, it's not too complicated.
The first setting empty string is an instruction that says you intentionally let the brother decide
what to put into the referrer had there.
The rest I have ordered from most restrictive to less restrictive ones.
The no referrer means you never wants to send any referrer information which is the most secure, but
can, for example, break analytics even on your site, the referrer will not be sent between your own
sub pages.
You may stop getting information about how users traverse your own site.
The same origin means you only wants to send referrer info when the user navigates to the same origin.
In other words, when they are browsing your site.
So this kind of helps with the problem with analytics, which you may encounter when using or referrer.
The origin and strict origin will start sending referrer info to other sites, but it will only include
the origin.
So in our example, the referrer will be the protocol domain and port instead of full URL.
The strict origin differs in that it will not send any origin info.
One user goes from HTP s to HTP from secure site to unsecure site.
Note that with both settings we permit the referrer info to go outside, but once again we may break
our analytics because the referrer will always contain only origin.
Also within our own site.
So we may stop receiving valuable information about actual the paths the user take on our site.
This is where the next pair will help.
Origin when cross origin and strict origin when cross origin vs doesn't sound too friendly at first.
I know the settings will send only the origin when the request goes to the other origin.
But the full you are well within the same origin.
So our analytics will be happy with the full information and the rest of the world will receive only
the protocol and the domain name.
The strict prefix once again will not send any origin info when a user goes from HTP as to HTP from
secure site to unsecure site and that includes your own site.
If you link from HTP example dot com slash something to htp example that becomes something else.
The referrer will be known.
Then near the end of the east we have no referrer when downgrade which will send the full u r l to any
site with this same or higher protection that is from HTP as to htp as from htp to HTP and from htp
to HTP s.
And finally unsafe u r l will always send the full u r l to any other site.
This is the least secure setting which always reveals your full path and should be generally avoided.
Okay.
The list is long.
So what to choose for most sites?
I'd go for strict origin when cross origin that will keep the full URLs within your site and sent only
the origin the domain name to other sites.
But there are cases when you may not want to either disclose fully referrer URL to your own analytics
or when you don't want to disclose even the origin to the outside world.
In these cases, use strict origin or just origin for scenario number one and same origin or no referrer
at all.
In this case.
The same policy can be said for any A-frame that you have on your page with the referrer policy attribute
for the iframe tag.
It expects exactly the same values as we just discussed.
To control how much information the embedded page receives in the referrer HTP request header, which
is also sent to pages within frames.
This attribute will override the referrer policy set for the embedding page.
So in this code, despite we said that no referral policy for the whole page, the referrer will be
sent to an iframe given that its security level is not weaker than of the embedding page, meaning it's
htp s or HTP if the original page uses HTP as well.
Content type sniffing was the feature introduced years ago by Microsoft for Internet Explorer.
It enabled the browser to sniff the content of each resource by looking inside the file and changing
the way it is processed when the inner data seems something else done.
For example file extension.
That, of course, meant an attacker could rename a malicious file to something that looks safe.
And if sniffing could discover that it's not what it looks like, then browser, it could potentially
handle the file in a different way, which is of course very dangerous.
Using the X content type options, however, you can disable any potential browsers sniffing on your
site by setting it to the only possible value.
No sniff.
It's strongly recommended to use it.
The extreme options is the htp.
Heather that will protect your site from click jacking.
Let's have a look at this page.
I enter my login and password and enter the dashboard.
But I didn't realize that my in credentials just got stolen.
Why I wasn't actually on my login page.
I was on a page which had my log in page embedded in a frame which spanned across the whole viewport.
If I were a little bit more attentive, I should have spotted the wrong URL in location bar.
But honestly, who's looking there all the time?
If you do ask yourself if your parents do.
So what happened is that when they submitted the log for the parent page, the one that embedded my
log in page, read the form data and send it to the attacker.
Now they know my log in and password.
Of course, they could do much more with my admin panel running within the frame they control.
They could do anything with it.
There are many, many cases how this kind of attack could be used.
Catching foreign data is one of the most dangerous.
But even if you don't have forms on your page, an attacker could be also catching clicks.
For example, a user who thinks they are on your website could click a contact link, and if that click
is shared, they could be redirected to a similar page, but controlled by an attacker with a phone
number or email of another company effectively stealing the client's.
A simple method to prevent this kind of attack on your website is to ensure your server is sending an
X frame options header with the value of denial to prevent it completely.
Or same origin to allow embedding your pages only within your site's origin.
We'll discuss in more details in the chapter about front end security.
X Power BI is another non-standard HTP header.
It may be propagated by the server and it contains some additional information about the backend technologies
like BHP version.
As it's better to hide any non important information, you can simply remove this gather by putting
this line in your HD access file.
Know that now we use they're always unset instead of they're always set.
X Axis Protection is an HTP header, which was invented by Microsoft for the Internet Explorer eight
browser.
The intention was to allow developers to ask the browser to run the built in access as filter that aims
to prevent cross-site scripting attacks.
The similar approach and the header itself were soon adopted by other browsers, but it never became
an actual standard.
With time, it finally became the predated and now has been removed from most browsers.
So do not set these header.
Or if somehow you can't commit it in your configuration, set it to zero.
Content Security policy is a powerful HTP header that allows pretty granular control over what resources
are permitted on a given site and from which origins.
For example, using this header, you can only allow web fonts to be loaded from a defined CDM.
You can disable inline JavaScript or disable external CSS files.
For example, this instruction will block all external resources and inline scripts.
But of course, usually this is too strict.
We will discuss the content security policy and details in the chapter about cross-site scripting.
Strict transport security is an active behavior that instructs the browser that it should use the secure
connection, which means connection over HTP as for any subsequent request to that domain.
Its value is the maximum time for which the browser should remember this instruction since user's last
visit.
I will talk about it in details in the next chapter, which is about using SSL TLS.