When you have the certificate already installed, just navigate to your site typing htp as first.
This is a preview of how your site will work on the SSL.
Before you officially start using and enforcing the school connection, you need to make sure everything
works.
That is, everything looks and works as expected.
The padlock in the URL bar is not crossed out, which means there are no mixed content warnings and
you can log into your admin panel if you have one.
When you protect your site with SSL, there's completely no sense to have parts of your sites protected
and parts unprotected.
First, do not mix the encrypted and unencrypted content on one page.
Using encrypted and unencrypted content from the same domain can, for example, lead to leaking information
from cookies like session IDs or when using secure cookies.
These cookies will not be sent at all to those resources which may be causing errors.
Second, don't protect only selected pages on your site.
Let's say you protect the log in form only if you don't protect the rest of the site, then you don't
protect anything because you effectively let the session I.D. travel through network in plaintext and
anyone monitoring the network can act as the logged in use their third.
It simply doesn't make any sense and the whole system is pretty much as weak as its weakest component.
If you already have the certificate, do use it.
Sitewide.
Especially if you have an already life site before forcing the use of SSL, you first needs to get rid
of any HTP you are.
As for all the resources on your site images, scripts, styles, iframes, etc. for all the resources
that you keep on your server, ideally switch to relative paths and for other resources from external
domains you need to change HTP to HTP s.
So if you had this change HTP to HTP s and of course verify if that works, it must work.
Otherwise, your site will constantly have mixed content errors.
You can optionally make your protocol a relative by starting with two slashes.
This will perform HTP s request on HTP site and HTP request on HTP site.
But since the city is expected to work well on HDP s, there's absolutely no point not to reference
just HDP as you are.
Even if you are still on ATP.
If you are not sure which resource is causing the mixed content warning, you can use the network tab
in developer tools to see which resources were requested with unsecure protocol.
In WordPress and possibly in other cases too.
If you have any images or internal links in post content, they are absolute URLs.
Meaning instead of being a relative path to the post or image, they are absolute with your domain name
and unfortunately the protocol.
Those needs to be fixed as well.
Because otherwise you will keep getting the mixed content warnings.
Doing it manually would be a tedious job on the side with lots of content already published, so you
can automate it.
But if you just thought of doing a search, replace on your WordPress database dump, please don't.
The reason for that is that part of the content and settings sits in the database in the form of a serialized
objects or serialized arrays.
It looks like this.
You are probably well aware about the purposes of serialization.
It is to store a non simple type like array or object in a database field which is capable of storing
numbers or strings but not be to be arrays or objects.
In this case we have a B array.
The key thing about serialization that makes it impossible for us to successfully perform a simple search
and replace is that it stores the length of each key and the value.
See, the title is preceded by semicolon five semicolon, which means it's a string SW letter with five
characters.
The same goes for a URL which is a string with 29 chars adding s to change HTP protocol to HTP s will
make the word a 30 characters long, so this serialized array will most likely become corrupt.
Now I will discuss the WordPress specific solutions.
So if you don't use the platform, you can skip the rest of this video.
To deal with the problem of legacy protocol.
In post content, you can either upgrade to WordPress 5.7, which offers a one click migration mechanism.
Use a plugin.
However, I am an advocate of using plugins only as a last resort.
Or use a WordPress.com online interface which makes the search and replace very easy.
Let's first explore the last option because it's useful anyway.
Some hosting companies have CLIA already installed and you can use it on your existing WordPress sites
if you have shell access to the server.
If you don't have shell access, you can install and use the CLIA on your computer.
It works well on the UNIX like environments, Mac and Linux and unfortunately has limited support on
Windows.
Installing WordPress CLIA needs you to use command line of course, but it's easy and you don't need
to install any package managers first, like with many other useful tools.
You only need to download the far file, make it executable with smolt and move it to your path.
Please refer to installation guide on the wordpress dot org or WB dash CLIA dot org.
There is a couple of scenarios in which you can use CLIA directly on the server with Shell locally on
your computer, on local copy of your site and database or locally on your computer, on local copy
of your site, but directly on the remote database.
The first scenario is obvious.
In the second scenario, you need to of course, have the web server software running on your computer
map, samp, etc. make a local copy of your site files on your local server, import your site's database
dump to your local database server.
For example, using PDB, my admin and finally change the database settings in WP Config PDB so that
it will point to your life site's database dump the one that you want to work on.
In the third scenario, you can skip step three and just change the database settings in WP config BHP
so that it will point to your remote database.
But note that not all servers allow remote connections to database server, so you may not be able to
work in this scenario at all.
When you're all set up, here are the next steps to run this search to replace Common.
First make a backup copy of your database, whether it's a local copy or the remote database.
In case you make a mistake or something goes wrong, you will be able to quickly recover.
If you work on your remote server with still access, connect to your server.
If you work on your local computer, open the command line tool, CMD terminal or whatever you use.
Then navigate to your site's root directory is the one where your site's WP config file sits.
You do that type CWG and the Path or Sydney and the path.
If you're working on Mac, it's important because the site relies on the database settings provided
in the WP config file.
Database name.
Log in password and the host.
Now run the WP search dash replace command like this of course changing example dot com to your sites
you are a.
This comment will replace all non-exhaustive tips URLs to 80 tips URLs taking care of serialized objects
and updating the character count.
And it will process all tables with matching prefix that is not only WordPress system tables but also
those created by plugins if only they have the correct prefix.
We were working on a copy, but if you are still afraid of doing the search, replace immediately.
You can add a dry run flag.
It will not do any changes to your database and only return the report.
What it is going to change in a normal run and you are done.
If you were working on your computer and local database server rather than on the remote database export,
the database would just work on and import it to your server.
There are other options to the search replace tool, including exporting the result to a skill file
which you might choose to do instead of working on a copy.
The documentation is available on WordPress sites.
The search replaced.
All will help you also in the future to not only ease transition to IDPs, but anytime you need to change
this site.
URL For example, in staging environment, I usually build a site locally using some custom local domain.
Then when I'm about to show it to the client, I need to put it on my server on a publicly accessible
domain like site one dot example dot com and is the time to use search replace tool.
Then when it's ready, we can publish it under the final domain.
W w w example dot com.
Once again, using search replace to change all URLs in the database.
As you see, I need to change the site.
You are a twice during development of a single site.
The search replace tool makes it super easy.
But I also mentioned that after upgrading to WordPress 5.7, you can use a built in one click migration
mechanism.
This is a really great new feature because as you just saw, the process of changing URLs in a site
that already have some content desperately needed improvement.
So after you get the certificate, you simply need to go to the diagnostic screen and after a while
you'll see a notification that the site doesn't use HTP.
S protocol with the button that allows you to make a switch.