BHP is configured with a special file called BHP ENI.
It's part of server configuration.
So without route access, for example, on the shirt hosting, it's most likely you will not have access
to it.
However, some settings may be overridden like it's possible to override aperture config with the access
file.
There are different methods for that and access or dot user dot in your file or an INI set function.
The first method lets you change some of the configuration entries per whole directory and the other
option only for the script execution.
But whether you need to use a user INI file or Texas file depends on how BHP runs on your server as
an Apache module.
Or as a CGI script, you can find this information of course running BHP informative, which near the
very top should print out at server API entry.
If it's something like Apache handler, then your appearance as Apache module and you can change the
configuration with the access file.
If it say something like CGI.
Then you will have to use a user any file.
Please note it's very important that you delete the script showing BHP info right after opening the
page and finding out the necessary information because it exposes the detail configuration of your server
and having it online makes the attacker's life much easier.
They know all your setup.
Nothing from this file is a download vulnerability, but it helps to determine what attacks can be performed.
For example, if BHP or some modules are not up to date or it can help carry out a successful attack
by revealing local paths, code, parameter, values, etc..
The syntax of user ini file is identical to any configuration syntax.
For example, this is how you would change the configuration in your directory to log errors to a log
file.
But if your server runs up as Apache module, you would need to use the access file and the diferent
syntax.
There are two key directives BHP flag and BHP value.
The first one is used to set the boolean settings like log errors in this example.
The second one is used to change values.
For example path for error log entry.
The last method I mentioned is an easy set function.
It's useful for temporary changes in the running code, but in particular scenarios call for any set.
Might be too late for the setting to make an effect in your script.
Although the setting will be changed, so better to use the config files anyway.
This is how you would use any set to achieve the same effect as before.
Now each configuration setting has the limitation to where it can be set and overridden.
Some can only be set in the main page.
Any fail available to server admins and can be later overridden at all.
Others may be set per directory in user or HD access file, and others can only be set within set function,
which means directly in the script.
This is the smallest set of config entries.
Let's now see the list of HP configuration entries that are important for the security of your app.
There's generally no need to override the entries that already have the values you need, but if you're
on the shared hosting, you may want to actually do that.
In case the common configuration will change in the future.
Unless otherwise specified, you can change the following directives everywhere in a user in the file,
access file or by any set function.
The syntax is for user your file.
Display errors off will prevent errors from being displayed in the browser and the error warning etc.
will only belong to the error log if that is enabled.
In case of any serious error, the page will just fail silently.
Display startup errors off will prevent startup errors from being displayed in the browser.
It's off by default, so only change it if it somehow set to on.
Log errors on will save errors to log file.
This is turned off by default.
Error log defiance BHP error a log file location.
Remember that this file must be carefully protected as it will contain fragile data.
Keep it off the website directory and ensure it has minimal permissions.
Read and write for owner write.
Permission is necessary so that the application can put the log entries.
Error reporting defines the types of error messages you want to see, either in the log or on page.
If display errors is somehow set to own, the default value is what you see, which means it will log
everything except notices and alerts about coding standards and use of deprecated code.
Note the tiled character, which is a negation.
Logging errors is a good idea, and by periodically reviewing the log files, you may spot potential
attack attempts because attackers trying to break your site will often cause lots of errors.
And as long as you keep the display errors setting to off and properly secure your error log file,
there's no point to limit the error reporting level for security reasons, so you might as well use
it all.
But on production servers there is no need to load the log file with notices and coding standards warnings.
So the default value should be totally fine if you want to use all usage rather on development servers
only.
There's quite a lot of configuration entries related to session handling.
Let's first see those that we might want to change from the default values.
Cookie recipe.
Only one will save the session cookie to be htp only, which means it will not be accessible to JavaScript.
This way you can protect session cookies from being stolen through accesses or CSR if attacks.
Cookie secure one will Wilson the session cookie over secure connection only use it if your site runs
with SSL.
Cookies.
Same site, strict or lax will ensure decision cookie will not be sent along with cross-site requests
which will greatly help to reduce CRF cross-site request forgery attacks.
The values are strict or lax.
And for now, you can just set it to LAX.
We will talk about the differences between those two values in detail in the chapter about Caesar of
protection.
The same site attribute for cookies is fairly new, but the browser support is already pretty good.
It's generally supported in all modern browsers, but it's also backwards, compatible and incompatible.
The browser will just ignore it so you can use this setting safely.
And one more thing this setting is only available as of 7.3.
Use strict mode.
One will not accept an initialized session id if BHP received an initialized session, ID and U.S. I.D.
will be generated and sent back when this is set to zero.
An attacker could generate their own session.
ID trigger the victim user to join that session and when the user would log in, for example, the attacker
would gain the access as well as a member of the same session.
This type of attack is called session fixation.
By default, it's set to zero, so it's off for maximum compatibility, but it's recommended to set
it to one.
See the length and see the bits per character allow you to set the length and complexity of session
ID.
Default values are 32 characters of length and the four beats per character, which means that the string
will contain only numbers and lowercase letters a to F.
The maximum setting is 256 characters and six bits per character, which means a string will contain
numbers lowercase and uppercase.
Letters, dashes and commas.
The longer and the more complicated such an idea, the harder it will be to get it using brute force
methods.
These two settings are only available as of 7.1.
Now let's see the list of session settings for which the folder values are secure and we just need to
ensure they have not been overridden.
Put any insecure value cookie life time sets to zero will make the session cookie valid only until the
browser is open it zero by default.
These two use cookies and use only cookies are on by default, so only override them if somehow they
are turned off meaning sets to zero, they will prevent storing such an idea in your URL, which is
very insecure way of passing it.
So when this is set to zero, your app is exposed to all kinds of attacks.
Some sessions like session fixation or session hijacking.
This, of course, will prevent any user with cookies turned off from being able to maintain a session
but is strongly recommended.
After you force session ID to be stored in cookies, you can make sure that use transit is set to zero
as well.
This is a feature that helps dealing with session IDs anywhere else.
It's off by default.
Cash limiter knockers will ensure the content is not cached for authenticated sessions.
It's non-cash by default and for maximum security should not have any other value.
Upload max file size will limit the uploaded file size in this case to two megabytes, which is BJP's
default value.
This setting can be set within a set function only in user ini or access file or in global configuration,
of course.
Finally, there are some settings which can only be set in the global P2P file.
If you happen to work with root access, you may want to review them as well and overwrite if needed.
Exposed.
BHP off will prevent exposing the fact that BHP is running on the server and disclosing its version.
If this is on then this information will be visible in HTP response headers.
Allow you to include of will prevent including remote files.
If the include path for a file is based on the incoming data.
User input, URL, uploaded files, etc. It will prevent an attacker from including a BHP file from
their server.
It will also prevent you from deliberately including BHP files which are not under your control.
Which you absolutely shouldn't do.
Allow u r l f open off will prevent vital functions like f open file, get contents, etc. from being
able to work with remote files.
While this can be securely done and more secure and less error prone method would be to use curl.