In earlier implementations of password hashing API, there was also an option to use as salt.
Salt is a randomly generated string that is appended to the original password.
The idea behind it is to protect the hashes of weak passwords from being looked up in the rainbow tables
without a salt.
If a user's hashed password is this or this depending on the hashing algorithm.
Then it takes a little time to find out that the original password is Apple because it's so popular
word that finding it by hash is super easy.
But when we append to the string apple, something like this before hashing it, then it will not be
that easy to find the original anymore.
There are two uncertainties regarding the assault.
So let's clear it up.
First, some people believe the cells should be secret.
But in reality, it's not that important because it's not meant to be the second passport.
The salad's general purpose is to complicate the original password in a way that makes the rainbow table
look up useless.
For example, if the same password would be used on different sites that implement the same hashing
mechanism without salting, all of them would simply store the same hash.
And it means that having stored in multiple databases, an attacker would be able to break multiple
accounts just by working out a single hash.
So and that's the second thing that people often get wrong.
Even a super secret sauce that will be used to hash passwords for multiple users will not do its job.
Imagine that two users had the same password.
I love Alice without a per user assault, hashes for both passwords will still be identical.
So the attacker will only need to break one password to gain access to two accounts.
To conclude, every bastard should be salted with a different random value, which doesn't need to be
secret.
In fact, this salt is often just appended in plaintext to the password hash anyway, since BHP seven
is deprecated to use your own salt and instead it's recommended to rely on the salt which is generated
by the password hash function.
Okay.
So all we know about the South, but there's also a paper on the table.
The paper in this context is also a random string, but this time is the opposite of what we learned
about the salt.
It's secret, and it's the same for every user.
Now, because of that, pepper without salt makes very little sense.
The assault on its own would likely do a good enough job.
And salt with pepper may improve the system's security.
This is how you would implement the pepper.
You need to define it in a secret place and protect it like you protect database credentials.
And when you create the password has you need to append these constants to the value provided by user.
Because contrary to salt, the pepper is not stored with password in database but in application code.
The passwords are safer in case only the database leaks, not the whole code base.
One of the problems with this approach is that the paper is hardcoded in every password.
So whenever your application is already running and have some users, it's tricky to introduce it.
It's tricky to change it, and it's tricky to get rid of it.
You could create a migration script that would do any of the above with the paper whenever user looks
in.
But when the user logs in in some circumstances it might be too late.
With all that said, consider assault as a must have and pepper as an option.
You use a strong hashing algorithm like grit or argon to even without pepper.
The passwords should be safe enough.