Let's see how to create a simple, token system that would greatly help to mitigate sea serif attacks.
But first, if you use any framework, consult its documentation.
There's a good chance it will have some built in A.C. SRF mechanisms.
For example, Symphony and Laravel do have them.
If you don't use the framework or have whatever reason, you need to do it by yourself.
Here's a basic working example.
First we start off by creating a session book and for the current user.
Not that the tokens should be generated using a secure random value generator.
If you follow the earlier part of the course, you already know that using the once popular MD5 and
empty round method is not considered secure anymore.
If only you are on BGP seven or eight, use the bin to hex and the random bytes method.
You can more tightly bind the token with the user by combining the token with the user's session ID,
user name or user id like in this code.
Now you have two new variables in session.
The first one is a rookie is a secret, fully random string that will never be displayed anywhere on
the page.
The other.
A rough token is what you're going to use on your page to prevent CSR attacks.
It's constructed from a token as we did before, but also user ID and the current session ID.
This construction is just an extra layer of security to avoid having totally random CSR if token.
The hash function creates a key hash.
That means a hash that will not be resolved without a key, which we pass as a third argument.
So we have the NTC SRF token further protected by the key.
Now you need to implement the tokens in forums, AJAX requests and when doing any other request that
permanently changes something in your app.
These are called status changing requests.
For forums, you just need to add the hidden input if you'd like this.
For Ajax requests in JavaScript, you can either make it another parameter for the request or send it
as an HTP header.
Often developers put the NPC SRF token in a metal tag and the reference these tags value in the script.
At the beginning of the script, we have a function that checks whether the NTC SRF token is needed
or not.
In this case, I excluded the get head and options methods which according to standards, are not meant
to be used for state changing operations.
But be aware that this effectively disables the CSR if protection for those requests.
I will explain in a moment why get method is excluded here and why it should not be used for such sensitive
operations.
Then we have a normal AJAX code.
We create an example CTP request object.
We open a post connection and we form data we wants to send.
Then we add the token if the method actually token exists and if the token is needed for our request
method both we add a request header with the value of the token.
Here.
We named the header x a.c. srf.
We can choose any name for the heather we want, but need to be careful about not using a name that
is already in use either as a part of the standard or some widely used custom.
Heather.
No.
Heather in the HTP specification will ever start with x prefix, but there are some widely used that
do.
For example, in this course we used x frame options or x content type options.
If you don't want us to use the HDTV head there for some reason you can include the token in request
parameters.
In this example, I just added the CSR if token parameter to the post data string.
If you send data using form data or JSON, the parameter would need to be applied in a slightly different
way.
So I think it's just easier to use the ATP header.
Additionally, you can create a common mechanism for all your requests to not repeat the same called
over and over again.
One way would be to create a function that will read the token and said the appropriate header when
needed.
Another way would be to create a wrapper for the send method that would do the same and also send the
request straight away.
In January, there's the Ajax setup method that is intended to set some defaults for all AJAX requests.
Not that this will influence all Ajax calls made with the j query that is using all methods like Ajax,
get post etc..
But in this code we run the need to see a serif method as in other examples which will skip the talking,
forget CAD and options requests anyway.
Okay.
So we prepared our forums and schools to send the intakes, our F token, and now we need to verify
it.
It's as easy as comparing the HTP headers and with the request or the request param with the token stored
in session data.
This is an example.
If we use the ATP header, we can get the token from the server super global by its name.
And if we send the token as their request parameter, that is, for example, using hidden form field,
we need to use the appropriate super global to find it.
Know that we use the hash equals method rather than equals operator which is double or triple equals
sign.
This is because hash equals method is safe for timing attacks, which means a malicious user will not
be able to guess if he or she is close to guessing the hash or not by analyzing the server's response
time.
This is the same case as with password to verify function in password caching API.
So far we used a single token per whole user session.
This is fine and does a good job, but it could be made more secure by generating a new token after
each successful validation.
This offers much better protection in case the position taken would leak.
But note that per request tokens may hurt the usability of your site.
Each request will invalidate the previous token and generate a new one.
So doing operations on multiple dapps may not be possible, and this will probably irritate some of
your users.
To combine both approaches you could use per operation tokens.
For example, there could be two different tokens to delete user with AD one and the user with ID two.
The difference is that we don't use the global C SRF token from session variables, but we generate
the hash for a unique string using the sessions.
See your serif key, which we have set up at the beginning.
That way for the phrase delete user one we will have a totally different token then for the phrase delete
user to.
And if one of them leaks, it can be used to complete the other operation.
And to verify the token, you need to recreate the phrase and compare the generated hash with what you
received as a token.