Let me now describe a couple of concepts and terms which are needed to understand the topic of website
security and which we will be using constantly in this course.
Vulnerability is simply a security hole.
For example, if your site lets people upload files but doesn't filter out executable scripts, then
the upload system has a vulnerability because allowing executables is a security risk for the website
and server.
Such vulnerability can be exploited, which means used to carry out an attack.
If someone discovers that the final upload feature can be used to put some malicious script on the server
and they do it, they are exploiting the vulnerability and such act is called an exploit.
Validation is the process in which you check if the incoming data matches what you expect it to be.
If you expect a quantity or a numeric ID, then you need to make sure the input is a number.
And in some cases, and number other than zero less or greater than zero only integer, etc. when you
expect a country or city name, given that they usually don't contain numbers, parentheses, semicolons,
quotes, etc., you could just reject any input with such illegal characters.
But there's another validation method to check the value against the complete list of possible entries.
That's doable in case of countries, but unfortunately way too complex in case of cities.
However, with whitelisting approach, we will always end up with the correct value if the validation
process fails, which means there was something wrong with the expected input.
The input should be rejected with the detailed feedback about what is expected, because during validation
we assume the input comes from a legitimate user who just made the mistake and should be assisted to
provide the correct and complete data.
This is why it's important to get back to them with an explanation of what is expected.
But validation alone is not enough to make the data safe for our application.
Sanitization is a process that comes after validation.
We already validated the data and we think it makes sense.
But because the data is not always as simple as a number postal code or city name, we need to make
sure it can be safely used in the application.
For example, a single quote or a double quote characters have special meanings in many languages.
Syntax is if an input string containing these characters is passed directly to the database query or
they are left as they are in a string that's going to be displayed on page, they may alter the application's
behavior in an unexpected and dangerous way.
And it also doesn't necessarily mean the input was meant to be an attack.
Legitimate input, including special characters which will not be escaped, can break the application
behavior as well.
So sanitization is a process in which you escape or encode these special characters to strip any special
meaning from them, to safely transmit the input stored in the database displayed on page, etc..
In this example, we escape five characters which have special meaning in HTML so the incoming string
can be placed on the page.
Some people just filter out risky characters.
That is, remove them from the input string before using it.
But be careful with that approach because it may completely change the original input and its intention.
Authentication and authorization are two very similar words, which are sometimes incorrectly used as
synonyms.
In reality, both concepts are very different.
Authentication is the process in which you confirm your identity, for example, providing correct username
and password.
By doing so, you provide your authenticity that you are you.
Authorization, on the other hand, is the process of verifying if the person is entitled to do something.
For example, if a user logged in as John Smith, that is, who authenticated himself as John Smith
is capable of, for example, removing users, adding posts, etc..
If you are not native English speaker to remember which word is for which concept may be really tricky
at the beginning, but you may have heard a lot of times about someone being authorized or being not
authorized to do something.
It means this person can't do something.
It's out of their power and not that the person is unknown.
Also on the construction sites, you can easily spot the signs saying do not enter authorized personnel
only, which doesn't mean that anonymous people cannot enter.
The entrance is forbidden for people who are not granted access to enter, even if they are known.
Both authentication and authorization are essential parts of the access control system, which is a
set of methods and processes that is meant to ensure that only allowed people are admitted to data or
functionalities with limited access.
Cryptography is a science or study that aims to protect confidential data from being read by unauthorized
parties, either when it is stored or when it is being transmitted.
Encryption is a method of putting the data through a mathematical cryptographic algorithm which produces
an and meaningful string, which can then be decrypted to obtain the original content.
Encryption often uses keys the secret values used to encrypt and decrypt the data, which are known
only to the parties that exchange the information.
It prevents someone who broke the encryption mechanism to read the content because they would also need
to know the secret keys.
This is called the symmetric key approach, as the same key is used to encrypt and decrypt the data.
The problem with these keys is that they have to be securely exchanged before any communication begins.
This is why asymmetric encryption has been invented in which multiple keys are used.
For example, each party has their private and public key, which are mathematically related data encrypted
with public key of person A can be decrypted only by private key of that person and vice versa.
So if Bob wants to security communicate with Alice, he uses her public key to encrypt the message,
and then she uses her private key to decrypt it.
Alice's response is then encrypted with Bob's public key, and he needs to use his private key to read
it.
In fact, anyone can now encrypt information using aliases or books, public keys, but only they respectively
will be able to decrypt it.
There is no way to decrypt the data using the same public key that was used to encrypt it.
This is a very important step during SSL or TLC handshake.
That is when the browser is establishing a secure connection with the server.
There would be no way to secure the exchange.
A symmetric key with each website you would like to visit prior to visiting it.
So your browser uses the public key from the certificate to encrypt a secret random string, which,
because it's encrypted with the server's public key, can only be decrypted with its private key.
This secret random is then used in combination with other values to generate a signature key on both
ends.
Only the browser and the legitimate server will know that secret random.
So they will end up with the same symmetric key without having to transfer it over the network.
You might think of caching as a one way encryption.
What is hashed cannot be discussed or decrypted because getting the original data from a hashed string
is much harder than from an encrypted string.
Hashing is the solution to storing user passwords into databases, for example.
Even knowing the hashing algorithm would not let the attacker decrypt the passwords because by design
they don't have decryption methods.
And when the user logs in what they enter as a password is hashed using the same algorithm as during
registration.
And this is compared to the hash stored in the database.
So you really don't need to store the actual password.
This snippet is not an actual code, but the code illustration of the logic that I was describing.
There exist many hashing algorithms from which most popular are MD5 security hash algorithms.
SHA which is actually a family of hashing functions that divides into several groups SHA zero, SHA1,
Satu and SHA three where Qatari is of course using the most recent and advanced algorithms.
To and shut three groups divided further into for example SHA256 or SHA 512, which represent the number
of bits in a hash string.
In other words, SHA 512 will give longer, stronger hash than the SHA256.
There's also rape MDR, which also comes in different hassling versions like rape MDA 160, 256 or 320.
There's wearable typically if to decrypt a script or are going to some hashing methods are not considered
secure anymore.
Many of them were invented in 1990, and at that time they were impossible to break.
But with the computational power available nowadays, it's turned out that some of them produce their
resolvable output.
Also, algorithms like MD5 fell into the trap of their popularity.
So many services used them that some people started to release the hashes and corresponding values,
so it became trivial to decrypt the hash that is just search for the corresponding value.
Also, some methods can produce the same has for different input data, which is known as collision.
It's especially dangerous as in case of a password.
An attacker might enter a wrong password and get inside, if only what their input produces the same
hash as a real password.
From this list, the algorithms in the end are considered the most secure and are recommended these
days.
Especially be gripped script and are going to are the way to go for hashing passwords.
Hashing passwords is the special case of hashing in which it's good if the operation is made intentionally
slow to prevent getting too many passwords in the shortest time.
All of those three algorithms have caused parameters that can be increased over time to raise the hashing
complexity in response to increasing computational power in future computers.
Let me also warn you straight away that combining multiple hashing methods can do more harm than good
and is generally considered as weakening security.
No hashing algorithm is designed to work with another hashing algorithm, and the variety of problems
could emerge when combining them.
It's enough to choose a single strong enough method like one of those three mentioned above, and enforce
a reasonable password security policy, which we'll talk about later in the course and never create
hashing algorithm on your own.
Even if you think you can come up with some neat secret algorithm, you will not even realize the potential
weaknesses in it.
Do use the proven methods.
When talking about web security, often you might come upon the term origin in contexts like same origin
policy or across origin resource sharing, abbreviated to course.
You can think of it as the base of your science address.
It specifically consists of scheme host or domain and port.
In this context, such set is called a couple.
For example, if your site run said east https example dot com slash my site your origin is htp example
dot com but not htp.
Example dot com because the protocol doesn't match htp as w w w example dot com because the domain doesn't
match htp as example dot com port 81 because the port doesn't match.
Origin is the base for same origin policy and across origin resource sharing mechanisms.
The former exists to protect sites from unauthorised interaction by scripts hosted on other domains.
Or we could say at another origin.
The latter's purpose is to allow cross origin requests by explicitly defining which external origins
can have access to selected resources on the server.
For example, if the Origin A wants to access something from the origin b b needs to explicitly allow
A to do so.
And while B allows a request from C can still be rejected.
You don't really need to worry about what the origin is as long as you don't access external resources
at all, or only embed external images, videos, styles, scripts and iframes.
However, things start to complicate.
For example, when you need to run an example http request also known as Ajax to request to another
domain.
Security by obscurity is the method of securing a system by using confusing or enigmatic names for the
system components so that it's difficult to understand how it works and to find out certain information.
An example would be a JavaScript code in which variable and function names make no sense.
You have no idea what this code does, right?
But after inspecting the rest of script and the team code, you start understanding the application's
logic and you can find out what this particular code is doing.
So because it doesn't actually add much protection, only makes the code analysis a little harder.
It's widely considered as ineffective, and I agree.
But to some extent, this technique might help to fend off some part of potential attacks.
The more traps you put in both big and small, the greater the chance that someone wanting to break
your app will abandon their tries.
For example, a large amount of attacks target some defaults, typical elements on pages like logging
screens of popular applications or traditional usernames like admin.
So changing the default URL of admin panel might keep some part of automated attacks of your site.
The panel itself is not more secure when you change its URL.
The form and processing methods are the same.
But because it's harder to find it, some attackers might just go on to find another target.
The same with admin username.
If you change the default admin username to super admin load, the log in mechanism itself doesn't get
more secure.
But anyone trying to exploit the typical usernames will be fended off.
So while this concept doesn't harden your mechanisms, it may still be useful as an additional security
measure and a way to keep of some bots and script kiddies.
At least.
Having said that, never use this concept to obscure anything to a point in which you are getting lost
in your own code.
For example, if you want to obscure your JavaScript file by setting and meaningful names for your variables
and functions, do it with an automated tool.
Keep your development file clean and tidy and then run it through some obfuscate or before deploying
to the server.
This, of course, will not prevent your code from being read and understood by anyone who really wants
to do that.
It will only slow them down.