We finished with 18 more contexts.
So let's add on to the JavaScript context.
Sometimes you need to use data from back end in JavaScript.
Of course, this opens another bunch of possible security holes.
Let me give you an example.
We have a function that, for the sake of example, only logs the past value to the console.
Then we have a button that runs this function with some text that comes from the backend.
Of course we use East Timor special just function so that nothing could break out of the function argument
context which is within single quotes.
Is that safe?
You would say yes.
But in reality it's not.
Suppose the string is this.
It looks completely innocent, right?
No single quotes, only escaped characters.
Great.
But when it's rendered on page, it produces this.
And we were screwed.
Why is that?
JavaScript is designed in a way that it allows and coded entities in language constructs.
So browser evaluates JavaScript and coded entities to their corresponding characters, and the code
can be injected with simple alphanumeric, chars and backslash.
So simply using html special java function will not help here.
This is a huge trouble when you need to pass data from backend to JavaScript.
But you will now learn how to do it safely.
Let's see.
In general, I can see three ways to pass data from the backend to JavaScript.
First, directly within a script, either with a script code block.
Or in a JavaScript context within an attribute like event attributes.
The only safe examples that I can think of of putting data this way would be either for numbers casted
on the back and side to appropriate types.
Like in both examples where we used the interval function, it will return an integral number.
Always let it be zero, but nothing else than the number or using the whitelist.
The second method is to put the data in an HD mode.
Data attribute which content can then be read by a script.
Now because the kind of encoding that led us into trouble just before with only work when placed directly
within the JavaScript context, you can safely put it in the data attributes and then really like in
the example above and it will not execute.
Then the string will be decoded to actual characters but not executed.
To safely use data attributes, you need to wrap the attributes value with double quotes and escape
a special charges.
You should also keep doing all necessary validation like type casting, etc..
But using data attributes all the time might be tedious if you need lots of values from the backend.
Don't be tempted to put them directly into a script to save time and hope this vulnerability never gets
exploited.
Use Jason to export large portions of data from the backend, either by printing the JSON object directly
on page or by asynchronously loading the separate JSON final.
Let's assume we need some author data on page to be used within JavaScript.
It could be a couple of fields like name, age, skills, description, etc..
You can have your JSON generated in place.
In this example, we get some values from CMS and assign them to an associated array.
Then we encoded as JSON and print inside an invisible diff element with proper escaping.
Of course, in case the data included some HTML.
Do not use the script element as this would put the data within the JavaScript context straight away
and we wants to avoid just that.
The idea is to put it as a text inside the plain diff and then read this text back and pass it as JSON.
So to use the values within JavaScript, we need to pass the JSON from the diff elements, text, content,
property, and we do it with the JavaScript JSON pass method of course.
As a result, we get an object with all our data.
The second method is to generate a JSON file with BHP.
Pretty much the same way as earlier.
But remembering to set the correct mine type application slash adjacent and UTF eight encoding.
Then this file can be retrieved, for example, with Ajax on the front and part.
This code makes an asynchronous request with both method to the Jason file generated with BHP and on
success it stores the person JSON object in the author variable.
Finally, let me just remind that with all these methods, we tried to prevent any user code to be run
on page.
If you're, however, willing to accept an actual executable JavaScript code, then you will always
be susceptible to access to attacks.