Let's start with something really easy.
If you expect an integral numeric value like quantity, you can cast the input to an integer and you
are done.
To see if it really was an integer compared the result of casting with original input.
The interval function will always return an integral number.
If user enters 100, it will become an integral number 100, which then converted back to string will
equal to the string 100.
Exactly like the original one.
If they enter 105, the function was three by the decimal part and after converting back to string it
will now be 100 and will not match the original value.
And if the user enters hello, the result will be number zero.
And what's more important, if they enter something like one or one equals one to try ask you will injection.
The final numeric value will be one as the function will return whatever seems like an integral number
from the beginning of the string and skip the rest of the string.
It's not a number.
In JavaScript, you can cast the input to an integer with pass in function.
And this would be the code to check how the customer value compares to the original input.
In the first snippet we passed the form value to integer, and in the second snippet we converted back
to string to compare with the original form value.
If it's identical, then we know the original input was a valid integral number.
The burst in function returns values very similar to interval in BHP with a difference in the last but
third line.
When the input doesn't seem like a number at all, it will return nine, which means not a number.
BHP is interval.
The function returns zero in this case.
And when you finally have the value as an integral number, you can put it anywhere, including the
database query with an numeric value.
You will not get any ESC, you will inject that and the no cross-site scripting code will run.
It's one of those scenarios where a properly validated value does not need to be further sanitized.
So now the data is technically safe to use in your app, but is it really safe for your app?
Well, it can still cause troubles.
What will happen if a user enters a negative number, for example, a negative quantity in the shopping
cart or way to large number like 2000 as persons age?
If that's not allowed.
You may want to add some extra logic to prevent users from entering numbers less than zero.
Or within a reasonable range.
And do the same on the front end.
If you use 80 mil five input type of number, you can use Min and Monk's attributes and remember to
amend your JavaScript validation mechanism to.
Just remember the front and the validation is only for usability purposes.
These attributes can be manipulated in the browser and the whole mechanism will be bypassed.
It's only to help legitimate users provide a valid input.
The final validation must be done on the server.
If you expect floating point numbers, you can use float value or typecasting to float the same way
as with integers.
However, not that we thought numbers, it may be a little bit more tricky.
So this method will not always work well.
First, in some cultures, people use comma to separate the decimal part, not the dot, which is expected
by programming languages.
Some people separate thousands.
Also, floating point numbers have limited precision.
So if you need a lot of digits in the decimal part, simply casting two floating point number may produce
unexpected results.
So instead of casting to float, you can try to treat a number as a string and simply remove illegal
characters, which is would be BP's filters.
Sanitize number.
Float does.
Regular expressions are ideal for that.
And in BJP there are two very important functions or replace that you can use to filter out the illegal
characters and then compare the result with the original string.
If you need and break match that you can use to see if the original string matches the pattern.
This function will return true or false.
See the example.
It will return true if the string contains only digits, commas and dots, but it still doesn't yet
mean we'll have a legitimate floating point number, because if user enters this, it's still unusable
in calculations.
That's why we might need to create a slightly more complicated procedure to transform the string to
get what we need, let's build the function.
We'll start with removing all illegal characters from the string using bread replace method.
Illegal characters would be everything apart of digits, comma and the dot.
Then we replace all commas with dots because we eventually need a dot as a decimal part separator.
Then we need to remove any potential trailing duds, which wouldn't make sense for which we'll use our
trim function.
Then we remove all dots, but last with their regular expression.
The expression syntax is as follows a literal dot and then the group with positive look ahead operator
that looks for any character followed by a literal dot.
At the very end, if we end up with a string that starts with a dot like dot five, which might actually
be a short term for 0.5, then we precede the string with zero.
Now we pretty much have a valid floating point number.
It is now a valid floating point number that can fit the decimal food in database or can be used in
calculations.
But it's worth pointing out that because we transformed it, it's not necessarily what the user actually
wanted to enter.
If it's only possible, it would be very good to confirm with the user the transform number.
But that's the characteristic of such numbers.
The same would be if you use typecasting the initial idea it will return 100 because comma is not a
valid character in floating point numbers.
So the comma and the rest of the string is trimmed specifically in beach B, your best bet might actually
be the filter, which will correctly output 100,000.99.
But this solution is not portable to JavaScript, unfortunately.
So on the front end you would need the custom function anyway.
So let's start to put to JavaScript our validated float function.
In JavaScript, the functions corresponding to be preg, replace and break match are simply string replace
and string match.
The difference is that we don't surround the regular expression with quotes, only with MM as less character.
So this is how the function goes.
First we check if the pasta value is an actual number, if its type is number and if it's finished.
Because that would mean there's no point invalidating anything because we already have a flawed number,
so we can simply return it.
If it's not yet an actual offload, we go on, we explicitly convert it to string in case it came as
some other type.
Then we replace the illegal characters.
No, the g flag in all the regular expressions in this function which was not needed when using B2B
break replace.
Then we replace all commas with notes.
Here we use regular expression again because otherwise it would only replace the first occurrence and
the replace all method in JavaScript.
It's not yet widely supported.
Then we had to change the stream call to regular expression as well because there is no equivalent to
this function in JavaScript.
The regular expression says the character one or more at the end of a string.
And such occurrences are simply removed.
Then we use the same regular expression as in BHP version that removes all dots.
But the last.
And finally we use a handy start with function to detect if a string starts with dot and if yes, we
prepared it with zero.
Also on the front end, you can help your users to enter a valid floating point number by using a step
attribute for a number input type.
This setting would not let through any number with more than two decimal places.
Finally, your requirements may vary, so you may need a slightly different approach to what we just
did.
And often you may want to ask the user to confirm the input data after you transform it to ensure it
reflects the user's intention.
See how much attention it needed to ensure a number is the number.