An attacker who knows the filesystem structure of your site could try their luck directly executing
BHP files, which are only meant to be included in your site.
Such files executed out of your site's intended context could disclose some valuable info oracles errors
to ensure something like that doesn't happen.
You can define a global constant in your app before any inclusions and check for its existence at the
beginning of each include file.
The constant name can be pretty much anything
now.
Anyone trying to directly open the included file will get that direct execution not allowed the message
as a response from the server.
Also, if someone would tried to remotely include your BGP file, don't worry as they would only be
able to get the final output of the script, not the script itself.
So your variables, constants, functions, etc. are safe.
They are executed on your server and only what they generate as the output can be read this way.
Even if the attacker defined the necessary constant in their file, it will not be transferred to your
script.
In order to completely block remote access to your include files, you should either move them out of
the document route, move them to a folder where you deny any external access.
Or set strict permissions.
For example.
6400.
See the protecting files on the server chapter for more information.