Well, let me now describe a couple of attack types.
Of course, there are tens or hundreds of them, many also having their unique names.
But these are the most common, the most related to web developers.
Job not server administrator.
The easiest to prevent by your web developer.
Those which you probably have heard about.
So you decided to take this course and those which we will indeed be talking about.
A school injection happens when an intruder manages to run their own.
Eskew will code on the target site.
Sounds hard to achieve.
Oh, it might be very simple.
See this code?
In intended circumstances, victory would look like this, but the UUID parameter is busted directly
as it came from the outside of the script, so a malicious user could argue read to be something like
this and the final query would be this.
Now because they were closed will always be true.
Because one is always one.
It will return all names and balances for all users.
If only the script would not limit the result.
Count to one the rule.
In a similar manner.
Someone might want to inject the ESC with code in, insert update or delete queries which are not any
worse as an attack target.
Anyway.
Attackers will often try to append such clauses to any query.
The cross-site scripting is a type of attack in which an attacker is able to run their own script.
Typically, JavaScript on the target site, the abbreviation is not seen as S because CSIS is obviously
something else but exists for all wondering why x in English, the letter X works great as a replacement
for the word cross.
Exercise can be either reflective or persistent.
When we talk about reflected existence, when the vulnerability is based on the specific request containing
unexpected code, which is then run on the target page.
For example, if a site displays the contents of the get parameter without filtering it.
In this code example, we obviously expect a name like John.
So the output is a paragraph saying Hello John, but we need to include some estimate code.
This code would then run on the target site.
Instead of a paragraph saying, Hello, John, we have a paragraph saying hello with a comma.
And the piece of JavaScript that is not visible to the user but executes.
In this case, it removes the whole document body so that the page turns blank.
It's called reflected existence because the page reflects what it receives.
It's usually requires that the victim user is tricked to click the malicious link or visit a malicious
website.
A phishing campaign can be used to make people click a malicious link.
The other type of cross-site scripting attack is the persistent existence or stored existence.
It happens when an attacker manages to place their script permanently on page, for example, storing
the malicious estimate code in the database in a field which contents are displayed directly on page.
This is called persistent or stored existence because the malware code persists in the database, it
gets stored there for a longer time.
This type of attack has much broader range because unlimited number of users can get attacked and it
doesn't require to track every one of them to visit a malicious link.
In both example, as I just shown, the attack was pretty kind.
It didn't do much harm.
The page got blank.
But after removing the malicious script and of course patching the vulnerability, it will return to
normal operation.
And the damage is over.
But the same excessive vulnerability can be used for much worse things.
With cross-site scripting, it may be possible to redirect the user to another website controlled by
the attacker.
And the other piece might be just a competitor site, but it also might be something worse.
A phishing page, which looks exactly like the victim page, but is designed only to steal users access
credentials.
It may also be possible to get access to victims accounts by stealing cookies, reading documents,
cookies, objects.
And it may be also possible to run operations on behalf of a logged in victim, which is known as cross-site
request forgery.
All of these can have serious consequences.
Cross-Site scripting is unfortunately a widespread vulnerability and the one that poses real threats
for different parties.
The cross-site request.
Forgery is the type of attack in which an attacker performs an unwanted action on the target site,
acting as a logged in user without the user's consent and knowledge.
For example, John is logged in to his account on example bank site.
Without logging out, he visits a malicious site that would send a post request to the example bank
domain.
Let's say a request that's normally used to make a bank transfer.
The malicious site could try to send such a request, for example, with an iframe.
If the example of Bankside would complete such operation, John would fall victim of a cross-site request
forgery attack.
Something would happen on his behalf without him even knowing that to mitigate the risk of seizure if
attacks a website or web application should implement a token system for all sensitive state changing
operations.
A new token should be generated with each request so an attacker will not be able to steal them in advance,
and only a valid token should permit the operation.
The HTP protocol, which is used to exchange the requests and responses between browsers and servers,
is a stateless protocol.
It means it doesn't bother to link multiple resources with a single client.
Every request is treated as unrelated to others.
Session is a mechanism that allows the server in the browser to maintain an identified relation for
a defined time so that the server knows that the sequence of requests comes from the same client, for
example, and identified user.
It's made possible by exchanging the session identifier between both parties.
There are two elemental attacks that targeted sessions.
Session hijacking means stealing the session idea from an already locked in user and using it in the
attacker's browser.
If the stolen session idea is valid, an attacker pretty much gains access to the victim's account without
having to know the log in and password.
To mitigate this type of attack.
You need to protect the session ID in the user's browser and during transmission and usually introduce
sessions.
Maximum lifetime.
Session fixation is carried out when an attacker generates the session on their own and triggers the
victim to join that session.
This way the attacker doesn't need to steal it because they know it's to mitigate this type of attack.
You need to ensure that your site doesn't accept incoming session IDs and that the the original is the
ID in certain scenarios.
Click jacking is a simple type of attack in which your website is loaded within a frame on the malicious
website.
The frame occupies the whole viewport, so a victim user sees only the frame content, which is your
legitimate site.
But because in reality, a user is on the manager of websites, they can track everything user does
on the victim page, catch clicks, reform values, etc. So it's possible to steal the data user entries
in the form.
It can be logging credentials or other confidential data.
It's also possible to intercept clicks and, for example, redirect the user to phishing sites.
Path traversal is a type of attack in which a malicious user gains access to files in other location
on the server than intended.
See this example.
We have a page which displays an article based on an ad coming from where a string at t variable when
t is zero one, the included file will be zero one.
Page B from the article's directory.
In the second example, someone exploited the system by preceding the file name with a dot, dot, dot,
dot slash and the final name is config instead of an article ID.
In effect, the contents of the config PDP file is displayed if only it exists there.
This way a malicious user can traverse your file system and access any file they want, including those
outside the web root.
By the way.
Path traversal is of course, only one security hole in this very basic, extremely vulnerable example.
The same type of attack can be conducted when uploading or deleting a file.
In other words, something might be put in a place where it shouldn't be.
Or something unintended might get deleted if only a user will be able to somehow influence the target
path.
Brute force is a method of guessing an unknown value, like a password or a file path by trying numerous
potential values until a match is found.
Brute force, especially when used to guess a password is often combined with a dictionary attack in
which popular words, phrases or characters outright first before trying random and meaningful strings.
The usual brute force protection is to limit the number of allowed trees, limit the rate in which a
certain action can be done, intentionally delay or slow down the sensitive process, or to implement
a capture mechanism if really needed.
The last type of attack to mention is the U.S. denial of service.
It's a type of attack in which an attacker sense more requests at the same time than the server can
handle until the server stops responding to further requests coming from anyone.
D d us with double D stands for Distributed Denial of Service and is a name for a situation in which
these numerous requests come from multiple computers and IP addresses, which makes it impossible to
react by simply booking a single hyperactive IP or a range of IP.
Actually, I'm only mentioning it here to explain the term.
There is no simple way to protect from these kinds of attacks, and because it's rather an attack on
the network infrastructure than the particular site's vulnerability there, there's little a web developer
can do to protect this site from them.
But what the developer can do is write the very well optimized backend code and the highly effective
rescue worker is a part of that.
I recommend to use a powerful hosting.
And then, if needed, a well-tested and the US solution like Cloudflare did the US Protection Service.