When you accept zip packages, you can treat them like previously mentioned files, store them separately
and process manually upon downloading or verify them with anti-virus on the server.
However, at times you may need to unzip a package on the server.
This is quite dangerous because zip can contain everything and the checks we did earlier will only apply
to the zip file itself, not to its contents.
If you simply extract the package contents into your uploads, the directory and the package would contain
a malicious SD access file with this inside, then the whole directory and all uploads would be effectively
locked out.
So you definitely need to sneak peek the package and filter the contents to look inside.
You would need to use PS Zip Archive class and here's how it works.
In this code, we first create a zip archive object and use the open method of this object to look inside
the uploaded file.
We can use the for loop limited by the num files property of our zip object to get information about
each file in the package.
We use that index method to get the details of each file.
So let's create a zip verification tool.
First we define arrays of allowed extensions and mine types.
Plus, we instantiate the file info object, which we will use to verify the mime type of each file.
Then we create a zip archive object and use the open method.
Just like in the earlier example.
In the loop for each file.
You should perform all the jigs that we discussed earlier.
This goat first gets the final details with that index method.
Checks if the file size doesn't exceed the limit.
Gets the file name with base name function checks.
If the file doesn't start with a dot.
This would mean there is a hidden file in the package like dot the access.
Get the path information with path info function checks if the file extension is on the white list.
Gets the actual main type of the file with file info object.
And checks if the mime type is on the white list.
This code after developing the actual prediction functionalities could be used to discard the whole
package, but if all checks will pass, we finally can extract it.
You have to methods to extract files from zip.
The first is the extract two method.
It unzips the whole package under a specified directory.
If you choose this method, then if anything looks suspicious inside.
During the validation we did before, you have to discard the whole package because once we extract
it, all files will be saved on your server.
Also with this method, I would extract the advice to a separate directory with a randomized name.
The second method is to save the files one by one in a loop.
Getting their contents with the get from index method.
And saving them using, for example, filesystem methods.
Of course, under his safe generated final name, not the original one.
Of course, it's easiest to save the files in the same loop in which you validate them.
The big disadvantage is that this will work much slower.
So you might encounter performance issues and recommend to first check the number of files inside to
avoid running the loop on the package, which has more files than you expect.
And keep the single file size limit very tight.
Otherwise, your app can start hitting memory or timeout limits.
On the other hand, the advantage is that if you choose to extract files one by one manually, you can
pick only those which you think are safe enough.
And already during the extraction, you can immediately process each file.
For example, if it seems like you are dealing with an image, you can run them through a library and
only then store them on the server.
Remember when a mining phase from the zip package.
You must check every file the same way.
We were checking single file uploads.
And there's one more thing you can do to disable any potential easy access file in that directory in
your upload folder.
But it's only possible with root access to your server when you can modify the global server configuration
file.
It's an allow overwrite directive which lets you disable any potential access file in a specified directory
or its subdirectories.
But you can't put this directive in your easy access file.
It needs to be put in the global config.
Having said all that, let me remind that if you want to receive multiple files from user, you can
simply add the multiple attributes to your input field and you will not have to sneak peek the zip archive.
Each file would be processed within normal procedure.
In this case, you need to add square brackets to the fields name and adjust the logic of your file.
Upload script because each entry in files super global will now be an array.