In early days, BHP had an extension with a set of functions for handling connections with MySchool
databases.
Names of all those functions were starting with my as well.
For example, MySchool, Connect, MySchool query, etc. This extension has been removed from B7 in
favour of to better, more sophisticated and thus secure techniques MySchool A and B speed data objects
video.
If you are used to the old MySchool extension, MySchool II would be a good choice for you because to
some extent it follows that syntax.
In all examples.
In this course I will use DBC variable as the database connection handle.
As you see, first we have an eye to function names as they are almost identical.
To make the transition easier.
Also, we select the database in the MySchool Connect function instead of having to call another function.
And in the MySchool I query function, we need the first argument which is the database connection handle
the rest in this simple example remains unchanged.
But I personally got used to use PDO, while MySchool eight supports both object oriented and procedural
programming style.
Video supports only the object oriented one.
For more detailed comparison between MySchool and BDO, see the BHP documentation.
But don't worry if you don't feel comfortable with OLP, which stands for object oriented programming.
If only you can understand how it generally works.
It will not be much different from procedural style.
The general idea of Obi is that we create a so-called object based on the class, which is simply a
template for objects.
The object has some characteristics.
We call them properties and there are certain things that we can do with it.
These are methods of this object.
In other words, they are functions defined in the object that can do something.
Once the object has been created, the object methods are called very similar to normal function calls.
So the procedural MySchool, an example can be easily converted to old code.
Instead of calling my school, I connect function.
We create a new object of my escuela class.
My escuela is a class a template for our object and DBC is the object we are creating.
We passed the database credentials directly during object creation.
Then, instead of calling my school a query or my school, I fetch us doc functions we call query method
of the object we created and the fetch ask method of the query result object which is returned by the
query method.
In query method we don't need to pass the database connection handle anymore as the method will use
the one from the object.
And this is how PDR looks like compared to object oriented mice.
Scuola di.
Not too different, right?
In the first parameter, when creating the PDO object, we specified the database type Michael and then
after column the host and database name.
PDL has only one method for fetching a single row fetch and to get the associative array we use a PD
l fetch as a constant.
When setting up a database connection with either MySchool II or PTO.
There's a couple of things to remember for security reasons.
First, it's a good idea to catch any potential database connection error.
Remember that it can be a completely separate server, so something may interrupt the connection.
When using PDO, you can simply wrap the connection set up with a tri card statement.
In this code, everything we wrote so far has been put in a tri book and after it we are catching any
potential PDO exception.
If it was thrown, we print out a message to the user, write the detailed database error message to
the error log and quit the script.
So now your site will not spit out errors when the connection fail, but rather display something user
friendly that does not disclose too much information.
BDO can provide even more information if we ask it to do so.
When creating a video object, we can add a fourth attribute the settings array and set the error remote
to error mode exception.
If we don't use this setting video will only log the error code.
But when we do, we'll get also more detailed error information with stack trace.
That could be really helpful in finding the bug to have it quickly fixed.
One more reminder.
Remember to properly protect your log file.
Use permissions not higher than 60400.
Please refer to the chapter about protecting files on the server.
If you need to know how permissions work.
Second, to mitigate the risk of squirrel injection attack, you should always defined the character
encoding, even if it's the standard UTF eight.
There are documented injection methods that take advantage of non Unicode character sets.
In PDL, it should be done during object creation in the same place where we specify the host and the
database name.
In my work.
You allow the unit to run this function right after creating the connection.
Prepared statements is a method of building a school query that is safe against SQL injection attacks.
The idea behind prepared statements is that the query structure and input data are kept separate, so
nothing in the input data can affect the query structure.
We'll be talking about it in details in as index and chapter, PDO as a feature which is on by default,
which emulates the prepared statements in case the database engine behind or does not support it.
It's generally means it will use a kind of the old might ask you whether the real escape string method
to build the whole query on b level, which of course may not be equally safe as using prepared statements
on database engine level.
So when using PDO, it's strongly recommended that you disable emulation of prepared statements by setting
the emulate preparers attribute to false.
Now PDL will always try to use the database internal methods of preparing statements and only fall back
to emulation for those queries.
The database engine cannot prepare.
When using a minus.
Q Ally, you don't need to do anything as Mike.
You allow he doesn't emulate prepared statements.
Last in BiDil, there's a feature called Persistent Connection, which is meant to improve the script
performance by creating only one connection with database server and maintaining it for the time of
script execution.
So the connection is reused for multiple queries to avoid calling the database server again and again.
However, this feature can cause you some troubles and be a source of errors in case your script would
die for whatever reason with an open connection.
So your recommendation is to use it only if the database connection is the main performance problem.
And I really mean connection, not a database query, because usually it's asking with a query that
needs to be optimized.
Not that the connection itself.
Contrary to PDL, MySchool has built in methods to cope with tight scripts and it will automatically
do the cleanup for you.
So when using my skill with I, in most cases you can leave the default setting, which is persistent
connections turned on.
In fact, in my SKU array, this behavior can be changed in any file only, which means in the main
configuration file you cannot switch it on or off on demand with per directory, config files or any
set function.
So you may not be able to change it at all.
Anyway, if you are able to manage the INI file and want to change the default behavior, this is what
you need there.