Because we tried validating floating point number is a string.
We already touched the topic of validating a string, but because there are millions of uses for student
values, it's impossible to give a universal bullet proof validation method titles, names, addresses,
phone numbers, email addresses, URLs, email post contents, serialized arrays, or JSON data.
These are all strings depending on the strings purpose.
There are different methods to validate and sanitize them.
Let's see some common examples.
Starting with those that can be treated more strictly.
You will have the easiest job if you expect input value to be either an identifier of an existing resource,
for example, a number or a machine friendly name, which in WordPress is called slag.
An example identifier is one tool or Premier Bash league for a Premier League tag.
Or if you expect a value from a set of predefined options, for example, selected by user in a dropdown
select box or from a set of checkboxes or radio buttons, the most beautiful part here is that you can
perform a very effective and secure validation.
Compare the receive the value with the actual list of identifiers or options that you defined.
Such whitelisting is the most secure way of validating data.
It allows only values which are in the range of expected values.
See this example.
The user is presented with a select box to select a category.
The options values are machine friendly identifiers.
The labels are normal human friendly names.
Then in PDP, we have the array of permitted label categories where keys are the expected matching friendly
names and the values are human friendly names.
And we simply use the array key existing function to check whether there is an entry in the array under
the given key, which means the user selected a valid option.
If we only had machine friendly names in our array, we could just use in array function to check if
the provided value is within the array values.
Suppose your waitlist is stored in the database?
The approach I mentioned first gets the list of all available options and then compares the values submitted
by user in memory in the script.
But especially for large wait lists, like a list of countries or a list of cities, you could do it
in a different way.
Instead of fetching all possible values, pass the value to the query to see if there are any matching
results for it and when there will be no results.
You will know the value is not valid.
Beware that to mitigate the risk of equal injection, you must not directly pass the input value to
the school query.
This, of course, is super vulnerable.
If you expect the in value, simply casting it to Integra would do the job.
But if you expect a string, these of course, will not work.
You should then use a regular expression to filter out illegal characters.
This one would not allow any Google injection and allow all characters used to generate the machine
friendly identifiers, letters, digits, underscores and the dashes.
However, this will not protect your query if identifiers or options can include characters like a single
quote, double quote, backslash as or other of a special meaning in as good a language.
In this case, you will need to use prepared statements, something which we'll be discussing in the
following chapter.
You could also say that the checking value against the database waitlist hurts performance because every
time we need to query the database either to fudge the list of IDs or options or to search for the records
stored under the provided ID.
That's of course, true, but I wouldn't really worry much about it unless the amount of data for comparison
is really huge or unless this validation is going to run very, very often.
But then you just might catch the white list to limit database calls divided in parts or improve the
performance some other way.
However, in 99% of cases, I would sacrifice the performance to secure the system.
Whitelist validation is one of the situations in which you may need to do the logic validation, which
I mentioned earlier.
Often, not every user is entitled to use any value from the whitelist.
For example, in the web service, a list of possible operations might be read, insert, update or
delete, but an anonymous user is of course not permitted to use the delete operation.
So even if the operation type string is valid, it's on the whitelist.
You may need to verify if the logic of the request makes sense.
In this case, check if the user is authorized to select this value from the whitelist.
Another type of student content would be the one where we expect a strict or narrowly strict format.
For example, a phone number.
When you ask for a phone number, you expect primarily digits.
But depending on your requirements, you may want to accept some optional characters, like a SpaceX
dash plus sign, etc. because people might enter the phone number formatted differently.
The second Morelos validation will accept the following entries as full numbers, which I think you
agree look all legitimate.
But this will not be a valid form number despite it matches the pattern.
I would fix this by also verifying how many digits are there.
Assuming you need nine or more, you could write this code.
And here also you would rather help your users on the front and side.
You can do that by not allowing illegal characters in the input fields and by validating its value after
the user is done with it.
This time you can use an input type tell.
It has the pattern attribute in which you can define the regular expression to match.
But this, of course, is not enough.
Our example here allows only digits and require at least nine of them.
So it's quite strict and that's fine.
But only part of users would like to enter numbers only, so the field will often show errors without
enough explanation.
The second example is more loose pattern, but now it's difficult to ensure we will get enough digits.
We can only set the minimal number of all characters in the field.
A user could want to enter a valid number like 100200300, but they will miss the last digit 10020030.
The final string has only allowed characters and at least nine of them.
But it's not what we expect and not what the user wanted to enter.
Also, the generic feedback from the browser may not be descriptive enough to help users feel the validation
error.
So to help users, instead of using the pattern attribute, we need to JavaScript functions one that
will prevent user from entering illegal go characters and the other that will validate the field when
the user is done typing.
The first function is an even list and there are the key down events attached to the phone field without
even the list in the of method.
So it runs.
Whenever the focus is inside the field and the user presses a keyboard key, it quits if the user is
using a keyboard shortcut.
We know this by inspecting the meta key property of the keyboard.
Even next, we define an array of allowed keys which are numbers.
Some special characters like Space, Dash Plus, sign, etc. and some control keys to allow user delete
content, navigate through it, tap out, etc..
We don't want to make this field a keyboard strap.
Some users are using primarily keyboard, nor that the range of characters must match the range used
in the backend validation.
Of course not counting control keys like backspace arrow keys, etc., because the whole point of this
function is to not allow user to enter something that will be later filtered out or rejected last.
If the character is outside of the allowed range, we prevent it from being placed in the input field.
The second function does the same validation as we do on the backhand side to give user an instant feedback
if they need to fix the data.
In our case, we only check if it matches the pattern and if there are at least nine digits in the full
number.
But you can check here whatever it is you need and whatever else you have in your back and the validation
method.
This function should be called either after the field loses focus, which could mean the user is done
with it.
Or during complete form validation when the form is being submitted and when the following is incorrect,
preventing the form from being submitted and display the error to the user.
The error should point out the phone field which needs to be fixed and clarify what is expected there.
You can do exactly the same sort of validation for postal codes.
Just remember that different countries have different postal code patterns.
For many, many countries it's four or five digits.
But for example, in my country it's five digits, but often they're written as two digits.
That's three digits.
There's a non-exhaustive list of postal code formats on Wikipedia.
And looking at it, you can assume that it will need to allow digits.
The letters, space and dash character, the string length, the exact pattern, etc. vary too much
for any strict regular expression.
In this code, we simply verify the input against the pattern which allows only digits, letters, spaces
and the dashes because some countries do not use postal codes at all.
We accept the zero length string and the longest pattern they found on the Wikipedia had 12 chars.
So this is the maximum length.
No.
The use of carrot and dollar symbols to ensure we are testing the whole string against the pattern.
In JavaScript, the solution is almost exactly the same.