Now let's raise the bar a little bit and let's try to validate the email address field.
This is much more complicated because of two reasons.
First, the actual standard for email addresses as described in privacy may differ from what you would
expect.
For example, an email address full at the bar is perfectly fine according to that standard, but in
most cases will be unusable because every public domain name has at least one dot.
So you'd rather expect something like foo at bar dot com.
Second email address is often used in automated tasks where no real person actually even looks at it.
So proper validation is crucial to have these tasks completed.
Apart from that, for those wanting to use BHP filters, the filter validate email seems to actually
do a really good job because it bases on privacy standard with small exceptions.
It rejects domain names without at least a single dot and rejects comments and whitespace folding,
which is not something you would actually need in the vast majority of cases.
Note also that according to standard single quote and angler bracket characters are permitted in an
email address.
And these are the most dangerous characters when it comes to rescue with injection or cross-site scripting
attacks.
Still, don't expect an email address that passed validation to be safe for database query or direct
output on the page.
Let's create our own email validation function that will give us better control over the allowed email
structure and allow us to ported to other languages.
We will need the JavaScript validation for the front and part of the role.
I would choose one of two strategies accept the RNC standard or set your own standard to insure yourself
that you will get addresses in the form that you expect.
Let's see.
The first method would likely allow plainly useless addresses which can result in junk entries in your
database, and such loose validation could lead to poor usability as well.
For example, if a user enters me at example com, it's a valid address, but they clearly just miss
the dot.
You could develop a pre validation function that will check things like that which are theoretically
valid but practically not.
And as the user, if they are really sure the address is at example.
Com, without any doubt.
But that would have to be a very complicated function.
And remember, usually an email address is needed to complete an automated task either confirm registration
or confirm purchase or receive newsletters, etc. etc. So because no public domain name can currently
exist without at least one dot, those will never complete successfully and you will have a useless
record in your database.
Also with this strategy, you will have to be very careful and remember to escape the e-mail address
all the time to avoid excuses, injection or cross-site scripting.
If you choose the second part, though, with your own more strict validation, you risk that someone
who happens to live with the fancy address will not be that true.
But frankly, people rather use only letters, digits, dots, dashes, and their scores and sometimes
classes.
So you could create this averagely complicated, regular expression that will probably not make any
trouble for 99% of your users.
I know it's lengthy, so let's break it down into parts.
The carrot and those are symbols, of course, represent the start and end of this drink so that we
verified the entire string against the pattern.
And for example, don't accidentally let through something like this.
In a local part that is before its symbol.
We allow all letters, numbers, dots, dashes, underscore and plus one or more.
But the dot is particularly complicating our lives here because it cannot start or terminate this part.
So either we have a one character local part or a non dot character optionally followed by a character
ordered and followed by a non character.
Then we have a little symbol to split the local part and the domain part.
Then once again, we need to do something a little bit more complicated for the domain part.
But let's start from the end.
Here we have a dot character followed by at least two letters.
This is a tilde top level domain, for example, dot com, dot net, etc..
And we're left with the part between act and the top level domain.
It's once again in alternative, either a one character domain or a letter or digital character, optionally
followed by a letter or digit ordered or thus and followed by a letter or digit character.
This is to support domain names with dashes or more than one dot.
For example, those two.
And because neither Da'esh nor DOD can start or terminate the domain name, those would be rejected.
However, this will still slip through.
And here are the results.
So using this regular expression, you can be pretty sure that you get a valid email address which can
do its job.
Of course, it's so easy to still enter some fake address and the above rejects can also be fooled in
some cases.
So it's still not guaranteed that the task will be completed.
But at least you can say you did quite a lot to ensure the best quality input that could do its job.
And the great benefit is that with this rigorous pattern, your app will be safe even if you fail to
sanitise the email address.
At some point, no SKU will index and no excess will happen if you do such student validation on the
provided value.
To ensure the email address is working and the user has access to it.
It's common to send a single use time limited verification link to the provided email address, which
the user has to click before being able to continue.
The unverified records can then be automatically deleted after a certain time since they have been submitted.
Just know that someone may have gained access to victim's mailbox and tried to act as this person.
So depending on your business requirements for certain critical operations, clicking such a verification
link might still not be enough to confirm the user's true identity.
And here once again do the validation on the client side using the same regular expression.
But if you'd rather use validation method and portable tool JavaScript, for example, BHP filters or
any other languages method, you can do some simpler validation on the clean site to ensure, for example,
that the string has at least six characters and then add sign.
Validation on the back end is the one that must be unbreakable.
The front in the validation is only to help users.
Violating URLs will be somewhat similar to validating email addresses in that they also allow a limited
range of characters, have a defined structure and finally shared the domain part.
Now the URL can be represented differently.
These are all valid URLs.
Obviously not all of those types will fit your needs.
So how you validate it will depend on what you actually need the world for.
There are different examples of regular expressions on the web, both easy and complex, so you can
just search for them and quickly get inspired.
But suppose you expect a website address.
Your regs can look like this.
Let's break it down.
We have a carrot and those are symbols representing the start and end of the string, like we did with
email validation.
Then we check whether the string starts with ATP or ATP s, which is followed by a column and two slashes.
Then we essentially copy the domain validation part from our email validation rejects.
So we expect one character domain.
Or a letter or digit character, optionally followed by a letter or digit ordered or dash and followed
by a letter or digit character.
Then we verify if we have a property l.D that is a dot character followed by at least two letters.
And then because your roles can be very, very different, we simply check if the rest of the string
includes any of the allowed characters letters, digits, dash, dot, slash and other allowed characters.
Some of them need to be escaped with the backslash because of the special meaning in regex syntax.
So we don't validate if the query string syntax makes sense or if the hash doesn't come before query
string, which would be incorrect.
Such complex validation would need an enormous function.
As you can see, this regs doesn't accept the IP addresses.
If you want to allow them, you can, for example, other alternative formats in the domain part, allowing
either an expression that matches the IP address.
In this case, we only allow IP version four or what we already have after the pipeline.
The IP part is so complicated because it can accept a value greater than 255 in a group or a number
preceded by 001.
And here are the test results.
But there is an alternative method.
You can first break up the URL into parts with partial function and run simpler regular expressions
on each of its parts.
In this code, we first break up the you are a string, which in this case gives us an array with scheme
that is protocol, host path, query and fragment that is cache.
Then we check the scheme against the wackiest of protocols and host against the part of regular expression
that we worked on earlier.
Similarly, you can verify other parts.
In JavaScript, you can apply exactly the same regular expression to the string match function.
And there's the quasi equivalent of pass u l function as well.
There you are, an object.
There's a couple of differences, though.
The protocol is taught in the protocol property not scheme, and it contains the trading column.
So before comparing it with the array of allowed protocols, we need to remove that trading column with
the replace method.
Also, the path becomes the path name and query becomes search, the fragment becomes hash and it contains
the preceding has signed to.
So remember about the.
This whole checking of course, still doesn't guarantee that you were at least correct works or is what
you there wanted to enter despite it helps improving the input quality.
If you need a working l, you could try to test the connection for example, with kernel.
In this example, we make a request to a given URL with the following flags no body because we only
want to check if the were in the works.
So we don't actually need the response body for the location to follow redirects.
Max to reduce to limit the number of free drinks to three and time out to avoid waiting longer than
5 seconds.
Then using a get info method, we ask for last transverse htp code.
So if the provided you were redirected as successfully to another URL within the max radius limit and
that finally were LS response would be 200, the last transverse response would be 200.
Which means that you are the works.