Now is the time to dedicate some attention to your oral context, which kind of sits across all contexts,
because it can be found as a sub context within HTML, CSS or JavaScript contexts.
In DML, it's usually within an ADF or source attributes for links, images, frames, etc..
Hopefully you don't let an arbitrary user input for resource attribute off script tags.
In CSIS, we find useful context when setting background image URLs with the URL function.
In JavaScript, we can enter URL context, for example, when constructing DOM elements or when reading
or changing the location object.
In case of images or style sheets.
It's obvious you are starting with JavaScript is not expected.
No developer will ever need to do this.
This is why usually browsers will not run any script placed this way.
But there are legitimate use cases for a link with a script in the nature of attributes, and it's very
common scenario.
So these scripts will definitely run.
Although it is a best practice and there are much better ways to run scripts, for example, using buttons
and even listeners.
It may be a little bit more of code, but using buttons instead of links is more semantically correct
and helps accessibility while using even this than allow separation of HTML and the JavaScript code
and makes the code maintenance easier.
Anyway, the whole point is that browsers will not be able to proactively filter the contents of each
attribute.
In such cases you need to pay special attention because even when you encode special charges in the
string, a script still can slip through and get executed when you click on the link.
This code contains escaped single quotes but will actually work and the document body will disappear
when the link is clicked.
In CSIS, you enter your context when you need to place an image in background.
For example, there are design cases in which it's easier to put the image in background rather than
as an image element.
The problem here is, of course, the JavaScript protocol similarity to image, source and link.
If in HTML such you are mixed completely no sense for background images and could only be a source of
problems.
So usually they will be ignored by browsers, but some older or less proactive browser might actually
execute the code that follows.
Interestingly, here, in this context, it would not be enough to check whether the user doesn't start
with JavaScript because someone can type in the middle of the empty comment section and it will pass
the check.
It would also not be enough to check whether the you were starts with slash in case of reductive URLs
because the common section could be as well starting the string.
So whenever you need to use your URL coming from user in an HDMI tag or as a C says bigger than the
image, you need to do a number of checks first.
If you expect absolute paths, validate the protocol and the should the URL start with htp semicolon
slash slash or htp s semicolon slash slash.
Don't validate only for a heartbeat, but because it doesn't mean it will be the protocol.
In this example, the user would need to exploit another vulnerability on your site and upload this
file in the page directory, but it may be entirely possible.
If you allow relative balance, make them absolute by depending with your st origin and if needed a
base path.
In this code we join all the parts using employed function protocol host based path, which is simply
the current page directory here.
Then we use connecting slash and append the user provided URL.
To avoid a path traversal attack, which we'll discuss later in the course, will remove any potential
chips to parent directories in the form of two dots and slash.
Also via the URL to see if it meets your business logic, which means check if it appears to make sense
where it is placed.
For example, if you expect path to the static image, you might want to verify if the URL ends with
the JPEG or something like that.
Finally, ensure the URL is placed on page within quotes and most special chars are escaped.
And if you place it as a background image and sure the value in say, the URL function is also quoted.
Because you will often need to validate the URL on the frontend.
Here are the corresponding code snippets in JavaScript.
Here in this code.
In the first snippet, we use match method on the string to check it against the regular expression,
the joint method on the array.
And the estimate, especially the charts which we defined earlier in this chapter, to escape the most
special characters in both Estimable and Caesar's contexts.
I intentionally don't want to give you a complete ready to use function because your requirements may
differ.
For example, you might want to accept mail to DEL or FTP protocols.
You might want to use something else as a base path when changing the relative path to absolute path.
You might need to do some additional checks.
A totally different story is when you need to put some data in the URL, but in a query string like
as a get parameter of value BHP role, you are in the code and you are alone called functions are meant
to be used just in that case.
Their purpose is to encode this string to make it safe to place in the get parameter.
In our example, by using roll your own called method, we protect ourselves from a malicious delete
parameter which would otherwise be appended as a query string parameter and possibly do some damage.
What's the difference between those two functions?
You are a land code and codes all non alphanumeric characters except dash, underscore and dot with
a person sign followed by two hex digits.
It also encodes spaces as plus signs.
Roll your alarm code, on the other hand.
And codes all non unfathomably characters except dash underscore dot and piled with the person sign
followed by two digits.
Spaces are also encoded to hexadecimal entity.
Better to use rule your land code because it's compliant with RF C, which defines the generic syntax
of your ice.
The JavaScript corresponding method to roll your encode is encode.
You are a component.
However, those two are not exactly equivalent.
To be more precise, speeches and coding leaves out only dashes underscores loads and styles, while
JavaScript encoding leaves out also exclamation mark, star, single quote and round brackets.
You can either fix the JavaScript function or the page function on the end.
They suggest this code to fix the JavaScript function, and I'd rather go this way as the pitch b1 is
RF C compliant.
It runs the original method on the string and then using replace method, it includes the five remaining
characters, exclamation mark, single quote left and right, parentheses and an asterisk.
Using this method, you can safely exchange your encoded data between JavaScript and BHP and this is
how you would use it to safely put the data in a get parameter.