Finally keep an eye on updates.
Of course, constant updates of the core and every component is usually a utopia, and simply turning
on automatic upgrades of everything on the life site can cause big trouble because certain components
could change over time to a point when they will not be compatible anymore with the rest.
Luckily, you can get security and maintenance upgrades automatically for older versions too, but only
for WordPress core.
So definitely what for plugin and theme updates?
They do not have a separate QB for security fixes like coders.
All versions do not receive patches.
If a vulnerability was found, you need to update the whole component.
At some point you may realize that the new plugin or theme version will not be compatible anymore with
the WordPress version that you have.
Then you will need to upgrade the core as well or switch to another plugin.
It's a good idea to subscribe to WordPress Vulnerability Database.
It's a service that scans WordPress core plugins and themes for security holes.
They offer free and paid plans in the free plan.
You have limited access to API and in premium plans you can get more API calls and also instant notifications
whenever something is found.