BHP has two functions that let you encapsulate complex data like objects or arrays into a string and
then revert the operation to get an object or array back from that string.
That could be used, for example, to store the object or array in a database where it obviously can't
be stored as a plain PDP object.
The problem is that if your serialized data could be manipulated by any of the attack types, for example,
as fuel injection and serializing, it could lead to direct execution of malicious code.
If an attacker could modify or exchange their serialized object, they could potentially insert their
own code, which will then run when you unsterilized it.
Even BHP documentation advises to rather use JSON for converting complex type to strings by using JSON
encode and the JSON decode functions.
In many cases, that should work just fine, but if that's not an option for you, make sure you set
the second optional parameter of unsterilized function allowed classes.
In the first example, we don't allow any BHP class to get unsterilized, so this will work for arrays
and simple objects only.
And in this case we could as well just use JSON.
The second example allows us to answer relies on the instances of my class and trusted class and the
other potentially injected will be instantiated as BHP in complete class object.
BHP has a set of very useful super globals, most frequently used being get post request files, cookie
and session.
So they include data coming with get methods, data coming with post method all the request variables,
file upload variables, cookie data and session data.
First of all, you should always wait for input in a proper super global.
If you expect data sent with get the method use get.
If you expect data with post method use post.
Don't use request super global for convenience.
Because someone may use an alternative methods to what you expect in order to bypass protection measures.
Also, from all these super globals, you can put some trust only in data coming from one of them session.
Why?
Because session data is stored on the server, not in the browser, so it's not possible to alter it
on the client side.
In other words, only you put data there and it's only risky when you put there some data coming from
the user without proper filtering.
And the only think about sessions that should be stored in the browser is the session ID, but playing
with it doesn't allow users to directly modify any data stored in sessions.
Super global.
Of course, fiddling with session IDs is a risk, but of other kinds.
It may allow someone to steal this session or arrange a session with known ID.
We'll talk about securing sessions later in the course.