This was a pretty long chapter.
And as you just saw, with such a great number of contexts, it's quite easy to make a mistake.
So let's sum up what we have just learned.
Four Element Content Context in Part B, always use HD email special chars with end quotes.
Plug in JavaScript use our custom HTML special terms function or send the element content with text
content or in our text properties.
For estimate attribute value context.
Use the same estimate special shares in both BHP and the JavaScript.
Plus remember to surround the value with double quotes.
Four estimable tag name context always checked the value against the whitest allowed tags for estimate
attribute name context check the value against the white list of allowed attributes of his very strict
rejects like letters, numbers underscore and does.
For estimate text area or input value.
Always use estimate of special tariffs in both B2B and JavaScript.
Plus, remember to put the input value in double quotes.
For HTML comment context also used a special chance in both BGP and JavaScript.
When putting values in JavaScript context, use one of the following methods.
Put the values directly in the script when the value has been casted to integrate or float, or when
you have a value checked against the white list.
All other values.
You should put in the data attribute of a DOM element and read them from their.
To export large portions of data.
Use JSON.
In serious context when you are putting user input as property values, use very strict regs.
For example, only numbers and letters eight to F four colours or only numbers.
Letters dot and person sign for distance values.
And whether you were using their input to form property names also tested against a very strict regex.
For example, only letters and a dash or even better, a white list.
Finally, when dealing with URLs, when the user input is going to form the URL or its part, require
absolute paths, convert any relative paths to absolute paths by preventing them with protocol, host
based path, etc. Use the estimate special charts function in both B2B and JavaScript and always put
the URL in quotes.
When you need to place the user input as a query string, get parameter, use the URL and code function
in BHP or our fixed and code URI component function in JavaScript.