When learning how to code.
I hope you were told that there's nothing like a randomness in computer science.
Even us humans can think of a truly random number from 1 to 10.
If you ask two, most people will never pick one, five or ten because these simply don't seem random
to us.
Unlike, for example, three or seven.
Computers often base their random number on something that they know.
Usually a time stamp, which is called the seed.
The problem is that if this base, this seed, can be guessed or imposed, for example, by tricking
the number generator to start in given circumstances, the final random number can be predictable to
some extent.
So the random number generator, based on something trivial like a timestamp, can produce predictable
number of sequences and may not be unbiased that these would generate some results more often than others.
This is why for a more random, random number, we need a method that generates a cryptographically
secure, pseudo random numbers.
They still will not be entirely random, but will be both hard to predict and unbiased.
This kind of proper randomness called entropy is achieved by taking into consideration some unpredictable
data coming from hardware like fan noise, mouse movements or temperature, rather than only from an
algorithm.
So in BHP, the initially provided round method was superseded by empty round.
But despite the improvement, both are not enough cryptographically secure.
That's why P seven introduced a new random int function, which from the developer's perspective works
exactly like the former too.
But it uses the entropy, the source of randomness from the operating system, which often involves
already mentioned physical conditions and which is considered random enough.
To generate the random string of a given length, you could simply use the sub SD error and SD or shuffle
functions.
But then again, the steer shuffle function is not cryptographically secure.
It relies on the same mechanisms as the round and empty round functions to get the truly random strings.
You'd have to use the random in again as BHP doesn't have the built in string shuffle method that would
rely on properly generated randomness.
The code which I wrapped in a function could look like that.
This function takes only one argument, which is the final string length.
Then it divides the characters to choose from, which, by the way, could also be an argument.
If you'd like to be able to change the range of characters per each call to this function.
Then we only need the number of characters in our range, which will be the maximum number in a random
function.
After that, we simply get the single character from the position calculated by the random end function
and appended to the output string.
As many times as the output strings length should be a little longer solution SD or shuffle but more
dependable.
The random string function we built has an option to specify characters range.
You can add or remove the characters to either limit them, for example, to only zeros and ones or
whatever else you need, or add as many different as possible, for example, to generate stronger passwords.
But if you simply need a random alphanumeric string, for example, to generate a token, you can use
this simple code.
The random base function will give you some random binary data which you can then convert to a hexadecimal
string using bean to hex function.
The result will be a hexadecimal string of a length twice as big as the number of bytes.
In other words, each byte will be converted to a two character hexadecimal representation.
The character range here is obviously limited, but for things like tokens, it's usually enough.