One important note at this point, my IDE changed slightly here.
The only reason for that is that I switched the IDE because I had to re-record these modules where you
see the new IDE, which does not mean that the other modules are old or outdated,
it just means these modules here needed an update to be up to the quality standards
I want to enforce and to teach you the latest of Angular. If you see videos with a different IDE, then
these videos still are perfectly fine,
that's the only reason for that change.
I hope it's no big problem,
the project of course is exactly the same,
the folder structure is exactly the same,
you will only have some tiny visual changes.