Welcome back to our recipe book course app,
we already added a lot of features to it,
now I went to add forms.
We have two places where we need to add forms, when we create a new recipe or edit a recipe in the
recipe edit component and in the shopping list here.
We already are able to add elements to the shopping list but we can handle this in a better way through
a form and then I also want to make these other buttons here work.
The form for the recipe, as soon as we can create new ones,
I also want to make that delete button work.
Let's start with the shopping list form in the next lectures. Here
I want to use the template driven approach and certainly feel free to go ahead and try implementing this
on your own
but there are a couple of different approaches of implementing it, so probably we won't have the same
solution. In the next lecture,
we'll start together and I will show you my approach.