Welcome to a new module in this course. This module is about services and dependency injection,
now what is that?
Let's start with services,
what are services? Let's consider this application, we get an AppComponent, an AboutComponent, a
UserComponent and a UserDetailComponent.
Now we might have some methods in those components,
let's say we want to log some data to the console in the AboutComponent and in the UserDetailComponent
and somehow this log statement is pretty similar,
so pretty much the same text, so we're basically repeating ourselves here, we're duplicating code in two different
components.
Let's say in the UserComponent, we also want to access some data, some array of users maybe and maybe we
also don't know if we will later use that in some other part of our application.
Both use cases, duplication of code and data storage, providing data are typical use cases for a service
because a service is basically just another piece in your Angular app, another class you can add which
acts as a central repository, as a central business unit you could say, something where you can store, where
you can centralize your code in. So we could create a log service for example to centralize our log
statement,
we could create a user service to manage the data storage here.
Let's see this in a real app so that it becomes more clear though.