One thing we haven't covered thus far in this cause is authentication.
Now of course a lot of modern web applications require users to authenticate,
that means to sign up and login, at least to use certain features of these applications typically
and it's also something we can add to our application here. Thus far in the course project, in the recipe
book,
we're not using authentication.
We always interact with our back-end where we store our data in an unauthenticated way,
there is no feature in our application that would require authentication.
Therefore in this module, you will learn how you can add authentication to an Angular application,
how it works and how to make sure that you lock down parts of your application or the entire application
with authentication.