So we learned so much about Angular throughout this course
and by the way, there still are some bonus modules to come after this module here, so definitely continue
thereafter
but at this point of time, I now want to show you how you can take your application as you build it locally
and deploy it onto a server, so that your application does not just run on your machine which is nice
for development but not that useful for your potential users but that you instead really ship it onto
a server, that it has its own domain and people can visit it from anywhere in the web.
Now for that,
we'll first of all dive into the necessary preparations and then I'll show you how you can host your
Angular application in the web.