We're about to get started soon,
but I did mention that we're going to use Typescript in this course.
We already did use it when we changed the first app. What is Typescript? Typescript, really is just a superset
of JavaScript.
It offers more features than vanilla JavaScript, like classes, interfaces and, very important, which
gives it the name, types; strong typing.
So, you define in Typescript if a certain variable is a number, a string or something else.
You don't do this in vanilla JavaScript.
There, you have dynamic typing.
You can have a string variable and then you can assign a number and that's totally fine.
That won't work in Typescript.
It will give you an error and therefore it allows you to write much more robust code which gets checked
at the time you write it;
and not just at the time you run it. This is
a great enhancement.
However, Typescript doesn't run in the browser, so it is compiled to JavaScript in the end.
This compilation is handled by the CLI; one of the reasons why we need the CLI, why we need a
project management tool like the CLI.
Now, this compilation is really fast and therefore, in the end, in the browser JavaScript is going to run.
We're not writing the Angular app in JavaScript though because, whilst technically possible,
that wouldn't be much fun.
A lot of the features really only exist in Typescript and Angular is meant to be used together with Typescript.
That being said, you don't have to learn Typescript
for this course.
You should be able to pick it up along the way.
I do have a whole section giving a brief introduction into Typescript at the end of this course,
so feel free to jump ahead.
Go through that section right now if you feel like you need it
or, throughout the course if you feel like you need some deeper dive into some of the features you see
there and you should be fine,
you should be able to follow along just fine.
Of course, if you feel like it, feel free to pick up another course or tutorial focused on Typescript so that
you have something to look at
if something is unclear in this course. Generally though, Typescript is an addition to JavaScript; not
a complete replacement,
so a lot of the commands will look really familiar.