Let's now output our data
now that we're fetching it. For that when we're getting the data instead of logging it,
since we now transform this into an array of posts, we can set this loaded post, which is a property
I created earlier, where we now also can be more explicit about the type it will store because that will
be an array of posts of course, we can set this loaded posts here equal to the posts we fetched.
Now we just have to use loaded posts in our template and for that, of course in this area where I say
no posts available, I only want to say that if we really have no posts, so I'll add ngIf here
and check if loaded posts length is smaller than one, which means we have no posts. If it is longer than
one, then I want to output an unordered list with a class of list group which is a Bootstrap class which
has list items with list group item as a class and in there, we'll have a h1 tag for the title and a
paragraph for the content of the post.
Now, I want to only show this of course and hence I'll add ngIf on the unordered list if loaded posts
length is greater or equal than one,
so it's the opposite of this condition here.
If that's true, we'll show the list and now I want to loop through all the loaded posts and recreate
a list item for every loaded post.
So here, I'll add ngFor to go through all my posts, so I'll name this post of loaded posts and then
here, we can output post title and for the paragraph, we can output post content. Let's have a look at
whether this works, if this now reloads, it fetches the posts and you see thereafter, these posts appear
here. Now maybe the heading is a bit big, let's maybe use h3 here but the important takeaway
is that our data loads of course. Now that is super awesome and this shows us how we can make the step
from loading the data to outputting it in our front-end.