Let's start with the loading spinner and for this, you can enter CSS loading spinners to find loading.io
which is a page where you find a lot of beautiful loading spinners and I will simply grab this
one
but of course you can grab whatever loading spinner you want and I will just copy all that code here
which is the CSS code and create a new file in the shared folder here, a new folder first of all which
I'll name loading spinner and in there,
let's add the loading-spinner.component.ts file and important, also loading-spinner.component.css
file and into that CSS file,
copy that CSS code you just wrapped and change that white color to a color of your choice because
this is the color of the spinner and white is something you won't see it.
So here, I will simply change that let's say to a nice dark blue color but of course, you can take any
color you want and replace white in all places where it occurs with that color, which should only be
two here, for this spinner at least.
Now in the loading-spinner.ts file, in the loading-spinner.component.ts file, let's
export a class, loading spinner component and let's give that the @component decorator which is imported
from @angular/core,
give it a selector of app-loading-spinner and then a template which could be a URL
pointing at an external file but here we'll have a very short template and I'll just grab that HTML code
from the loading spinner page, which is the HTML code you need for the spinner to work and I'll add this
as my template here, looks quite unstructured but this is all this spinner needs to work and thereafter
more importantly, I'll add style URLs and there, add one URL to my array of URLs which
points at my loading-spinner.component.css file I just added. With that, we prepared
that loading spinner component, of course as always with all components we need to declare that.
So in the app module, let's add the loading spinner component to the declarations array and make sure
you also add an import path at the top of this file pointing at that loading spinner file in the shared
folder. So that's the loading spinner component,
we can now use this in the auth component here because here, I essentially want to hide the entire form
if we are currently loading.
Now to find out whether we are loading, here in the auth.component.ts file, we can add a new property,
isLoading and we'll follow a similar logic as we did for isLogin mode, we'll change this isLoading
property dynamically and update the UI based on it.
Initially we are of course not loading but in onSubmit,
as soon as we made it past this if check and the data extraction, so right before the requests get sent,
we can set this isLoading to true because now we clearly are sending a request and we are loading and
I'll set this back to false as soon as we're done,
so both here for the success case as well as the error case,
in both cases, we should set isLoading back to false because we're not loading anymore,
we got a response
even if it should be an error. Now the isLoading property can be used in the template to hide the form
simply with ngIf. There we add ngIf to the form element and by checking for isLoading or for
the form here actually, for not isLoading,
we ensure that the form only shows up if we're currently not loading. If we are loading, I want to show
that spinner and for that, I'll simply add a div here and in that div, I'll add my app-loading-spinner
component and that entire div will only be shown if we are loading.
Now let's give this a try and let's save that,
go back to our application, enter our data, switch to sign up and here's our spinner,
of course I still get my error thereafter but the spinner works.
Now obviously, it would be nice to center that spinner
and here we can do this quick and dirty on that div by adding an inline style and setting text align
to center,
of course you could also manage this through a CSS file if you want to.
This however should do the trick here,
if we now try to sign up again,
this was centered as you saw. Now that's the loading spinner
but I also want to show an error message, an alert in case we got an error, in case we had a problem
with logging in and therefore the error should be handled as well.
Hence let's go back to the auth component and we already manage whether we are logging in or whether
we are loading,
now I also want to store an error here and initially, that is null because initially we have no error
but in theory, that will be of type string because it should hold an error message let's say. Now you
can get as sophisticated as you want and store more information in here,
have a more complex error object but for the UI, I only care about the message and I either have no message
or I do have a message.
So therefore, let's now go to onSubmit here, to the error case and instead of logging my error message,
I will simply set or I will still log it but I will in addition also set this error equal to an
error occurred and we'll add a more specific error message in a second.
So here, an error occurred is set and in my auth component therefore, I'll now add another div using the
bootstrap alert and alert-danger classes to give us a nice alert view and in there, a paragraph
where we output that error text because keep in mind that the error property of this component is just
a string.
Now when should this div be shown?
Of course only if we have an error.
So let's add ngIf and check for the existence of error here to make sure this only shows up if
we do have an error and therefore now if you go back, you see nothing here
but if you try signing up for a user that already exists, you now see an error occurred here.
This of course is better because we now give the user a hint about which error occurred or that an error
occurred
to be precise but we don't tell the user which error occurred.
So that's the thing we'll do in the next lecture.