Well that was a lot but I want to mention two more things or show two more things.
One is a more detailed control over the individual steps.
You are in the animation process year.
We always saw that we can defy multiple faces but each face gets the same importance.
It would be nice if we could define some key frames to specifically say okay you any enemy over one
second after 200 Second you should have stayed off for 500 seconds you should have this state and so
on.
Well we can do this.
I'm copying my trigger your final time.
And here I want to set up a list to which in my template I bind to my second list year which uses the
same data source.
So here at least two sets up to trigger to binded and then we can set up the animations here.
Well leave d in stage here.
But for the transition when coming in I want to change this here.
I don't want to specify a normal array as I did before to have these different equally weighted phases
.
Instead I'll pass an argument which is still an array but they're in the animate function.
Let's say one second.
I use the keyframes method as the second argument.
This needs to be imported from an angle or core.
Now the key frames method here in the animate function allows me to be more precise.
Which part of multiple styles I can now set up should occur as to which timing the overall animation
will take one second but I can control which state in sight of that animation should take how long.
So here keyframes therefore it's all an array with now the individual faces.
And there I simply apply a couple of styles of the style method again.
So let's for let's say when we let it enter it should transform and at the beginning we have it on the
left as before minus 100 pixels.
We also said that about your past two years before to zero.
Now let's say we want to have a number stall during that flight in animation.
Here we want to have transform.
Set this to translate x 50 pixels minus 50 pixels.
So halfway there because we want to end at zero trancelike x zero at the end that's our final state
up here that we want to animate the opacity to already be at zero point five.
And then we have yet another style let's say where we want to say OK the transform function is now also
almost there.
So translate X is now minus 20 pixels.
But importantly opacity is one.
So we're done when it comes to opacity but we're not completely at the position we want to be.
This will work like that.
I can now save this and if we let this reload you should watch the bottom list you always saw it upon
the initial fly in and should see if you watched the compression to the top list.
If I add a new item this is much slower and it starts fast and then takes very long for the last bit
.
The reason for this is that by default all these steps here take equally long I have free elements here
in my key from an array.
And then every style is triggered after a third for the third of a second.
I can override this by passing the offset property.
I can't say as to which timing of these 1000 milliseconds in this case should you be at the state sort
of first status at the beginning offset zero.
Then here let's say you want to be at this not after half of the time which it would make sense because
we are half way in and half way the opacity.
But we want to be at this point after point three of our animation time.
So 30 percent of our animation time so 300 more seconds in this case.
And we want to be almost done after let's say Dot 8 and then I will add a final style here
with an offset of one where I'm done.
This is my final key for him so that it doesn't snap at the end.
Well with this if I let it reload we saw it year up on initial loading and if I add a new item it stat
starts fast
but then smoothly finishes does how we used keyframes to control precisely which state we want to have
.
At which time during the transition that's important key for EMS are for the time during the transition
So over the time of such or any made function and of course you could still have multiple animated functions
as we had before it in that array you passed through the transition.
You could have multiple any made in functions and each element functions could have multiple key frames
so unlimited possibilities here