So were you successful using our recipes array here and replicating this part in the code as often as
needed and fill it with the data for the recipe?
Now clearly, we need ngFor for this.
So let's add ngFor, this is the directive which allows us to repeat code in our template
and here, I want to loop through all the recipes.
So I will actually create a local variable named recipe,
this name is totally up to you,
that will simply store the recipe of each iteration in our loop and I will loop through all the recipes,
so through this recipes property we created here in the TypeScript file.
Now with that, I'll also bring this into new lines here to make it a bit easier to read. With that, everywhere
inside this ngFor loop,
so everywhere here, we can use this recipe now.
So let's use it to output the name,
we can use string interpolation for that.
String interpolation as we learned allows us to output some text anywhere in our template.
Now we got the single recipe but that's going to be an object looking like our model because remember,
the recipes array simply holds an array of our recipes,
so a single item simply looks like this,
it has a name, a description and the imagePath. Well with this information, we can of course access the name
here, like this
and for the description, we can replace this with recipe description.
So we're going to use the property names
we set up here in the model and important, you have to use the ones here at the top of course because
down there, these are only the constructor argument names,
they are not available outside of this model.
So that's the name and description,
now about that image. First of all for that alt-text, here that's a normal HTML attribute of course,
I will use string interpolation to output some text here, the recipe name maybe
but regarding the image source itself and I'm just splitting this over multiple lines to make it a bit
easier to read, regarding that source, we can follow two approaches.
You can either use string interpolation here to output recipe imagePath here
and that should work fine
or as an alternative, you cannot use the attribute plus string interpolation but you could bind to the
source property itself
and now here, you don't add curly braces,
instead just recipe imagePath
because now we're using property binding and not string interpolation anymore.
So here is a great example of where you may use both, string interpolation with the normal HTML attribute
or not using the attribute but directly binding to the source property of the image and then just putting
in a valid expression, returning what this property expects, in this case a string between the quotation marks.
Now I will go with the property binding approach here and since I can't comment this out in here without
breaking the element, I'm going to remove it
but I want you to keep in mind that both approaches would work.
With that, let's save and see if we see something and actually that looks pretty good but looks like
the image I chose does not support deep linking, so that's nice,
probably good for them,
let me quickly pick a different image then.
So I ended up with picking this image here then,
so you can see it here
and now we get the list working.
This is the style I want to have,
of course it doesn't do anything if I click it
but that's something we can add in the future. For now,
the recipe-list component is taking shape,
I want to add one more thing though, I don't want to have this button sit directly on top of this list.
So what I'll quickly do in my recipe-list component here between the button and the list, I can simply add
a horizontal line to have a little bit of a spacing in-between and this nice separation.
So that's the list and you should see that if you add more items to that list, that it automatically
grows,
so if I simply duplicate this because I'm lazy, you should see the same recipe twice here.
So that's working great,
now let's work on the details section next.