So in the last section, we created the HTML code for our form,
now let's initialize our form and we will use the reactive approach as I already said.
Now for this approach, it's important to understand if we are in edit mode or new mode and we do get
this information here. Why is that important?
Well of course because depending on this, we need to prepopulate the fields or not.
So I will create a new private method in the recipe-edit.component which I'll name initForm because
it is responsible for initializing our form.
The form itself shall be a property here,
so I will name it recipe form and it will be of type FormGroup
as you learned, to be imported from @angular/forms. Now we can build this recipe form here in
initForm.
Basically I will reach out to it and assign a value and this value will be a new FormGroup, to give
us the outer shell of our form so to say, the frame. FormGroup takes a Javascript object where we have
key-value pairs for the control we want to register.
So the first control I do want to register here is the name, the name of the recipe.
This will be a new FormControl, so we should import FormControl from
@angular/forms too and here,
now as I said it's important to decide whether we are in edit mode or not because that will determine
whether we want to assign an initial value or not.
Well, we could simply create a variable at the top here which holds our recipe name and let's set it
to an empty string by default,
then let's add some logic which decides what the value should be if we are in edit mode,
so let's check if this edit mode.
If that's the case, then recipe name should probably be something else and it should probably be the
value of the recipe
we can load with the ID we got here,
we do have the ID stored up there. So we can simply inject our recipe service,
let's do this here,
recipe service,
make sure to add the import at the top here
and now we can fetch our recipe here,
the recipe we're currently editing. So I will fetch it right at the beginning, the recipe, reaching out
to the recipe service and then with get recipe and passing the ID of the recipe we know we are editing,
I can get it. Actually, I shouldn't do it here because I will try to get one if we don't have an ID because
we are not in edit mode,
I should do it in here.
So now we got a recipe,
now we can simply access the name of the recipe and assign this to our variable here.
Now the same will be true for the imageUrl, the recipe imagePath.
It's an empty string by default and the same is probably true for the description, so recipe description
is also an empty string by default and the ingredients,
I'll come back to these.
So for now, let's overwrite all these variables if we are in edit mode,
so recipe imagePath will be set to recipe imagePath and recipe description will be set to recipe
description here
and with that, we can simply assign recipe name here for the name as a default value because it will either
be an empty string that's the default or if we happen to be in edit mode, it will have the name of the
recipe we are editing as a value.
So with that, we got the name,
now let's also assign the imagePath, here I'll
also add a new FormControl and set this recipe imagePath. As a side note, we'll take care about validation
later and let's assign the description here, a new FormControl again and we should assign the recipe
description.
Now again, I'll take care about the ingredients later.
That is our base form created,
now when should we call initForm,
this method here? We should call it whenever our route params change because that indicates that we reloaded
the page,
so that is where we should call this initForm.
Now with that, we are creating the form and it probably will work,
however now we need to synchronize our form to our HTML code.
We'll do this in the next lecture.