So we already reorganized our code quite a bit,
what's remaining here in the app module is the auth component
and we also got a couple of imports here which we might not need
in the app component anymore because our app component already got pretty lean.
Now the forms module is still required because the auth component needs it
but we can definitely drop the reactive forms module.
We need the HttpClient module because it turns out that this is a module that only sets up some
global services, the injectable HTTP service and we need that,
so we will keep that. We need the app routing module, we need the recipes and a shopping list module and
all these modules but the reactive forms module could be dropped
and I also want to drop the forms module and get rid of the auth component here because we can simply
create a new feature module for that.
I analyzed at the start of this module that this is our third feature area and therefore, creating a
separate module would make sense. Again, definitely feel free to pause the video and try this on your own
here, outsource the auth component and its route into a separate feature module.
Were you successful? To do it together here in the auth folder,
I'll add an auth.module.ts file and as before, export a class, auth module which receives our normal
@NgModule decorator.
Now here, we as we learned, need to declare whatever we're using in this module and in the auth module,
that is the auth component.
So let's cut the auth component from the app module and move it here into declarations of auth module.
Now for that of course, we also need to add the missing import.
Now the auth component is using certain Angular features which we should import. We need the common module,
in case we're using ngIf or ngFor and you need to add the import to that as well.
We also need the forms module, because we're using the template driven forms approach here in the
auth component. That allows us now in the app module to get rid of that forms module.
Now we can also import, maybe here, our auth module and make sure to add that import path of course but
I also wanted to outsource my routes, so in the app routing module, let's grab that auth route here, remove
it from the app routing module and go to the auth module and in here, simply add router module which you
import from @angular/router and as you learned it, forChild and add this route and if you put this
into a separate routing file, into a separate routing module and import that separate routing module
into the auth module, that would have been correct as well.
So now I have my auth module, that focuses on all the auth related stuff. The auth service still is provided
like this
and if you would provide it in a module, you would still keep it in the app module to have it available
application-wide but other than that, this is looking good. Let's now save it all and see if that works
and I'm getting an error, the app loading spinner is missing in the auth component or in the auth module.
Now do you know what the issue is here?
Well, the app loading spinner, the loading spinner component is defined in our shared module and as I mentioned,
you only have access to what you declare in a module.
So if we need the loading spinner component in the auth module, we could add it to declarations but double
declarations are not allowed,
so declaring it here and in the shared module is not allowed.
Therefore the solution is to simply import the shared module to get access to its features
and now with that, everything seems to work.
If I now logout and I test the login flow again, first of all with invalid credentials, that works
and now with valid credentials, that also works.
So now we also outsourced the auth related things into their separate feature module.