In the last lecture, we improve the user experience by taking advantage of the form state handled by
Angular.
Now let's improve this even more and let's say we want to output some help text below this input to assist
if there is an invalid value in there.
Now we can use a Bootstrap class here, help-block, to make sure that this has the appropriate styling
and then we could say please enter a valid e-mail.
We only want to show this if an invalid value has been entered into the control
associated with this input though.
Well, a quick and easy way of getting access to the control created by Angular automatically as we added
ngModel to the input is by adding a local reference to this input element here,
for example e-mail, any name you like and associating this now not with ngForm as we did for the overall
form but with ngModel.
So just like the form directive automatically added by Angular when it detects a form element, the
ngModel directive here also kind of exposes some additional information about the control it creates
for us on the overarching form by accessing ngModel.
So with this, we could simply check or say that we want to attach this span here
if e-mail is not valid, so add an exclamation mark at the beginning.
Now with this if this reloads, you'll see that help text
and of course you can improve this by also chaining another condition
that e-mail should have been touched to give the user a chance of changing it.
So now you don't see the warning but if you click in there and click out of there and it is invalid,
you see that warning
and if you now enter a valid data, it disappears.
So this is another way of taking advantage of the state managed by Angular
but this also shows you how you can get a quick and easy access to control added by Angular.
And with that, you should have tools to really provide a pleasant user experience showing the right errors,
the right warnings and styling the form correctly depending on the state of the form.