To Raptor's animation introduction up there are a couple of callbacks you can listen to so that when
an animation finished you might want to execute some Abaroa code.
So here in EPK component let's say on that day of element here we can listen to you these callbacks
here.
We set up event binding.
But then again with the sign to indicate that we're in the animation world like here with the proper
keybinding But we also used the sign we set up the trigger here.
So Dave stayed for this death and then we got the start and the Done trigger.
This method will get executed whenever the animation starts.
So here we could say animation animation started execute this method and let's pastie when exposed spangle
to see what's inside of it.
And I also want to listen to you.
Finishing with done you went on our trigger animation and it an old past event there and then the app
component.
I want to set up the two methods here so animations started which received some event and here I want
to simply lock this event so that we can see what's inside and then animation ended with the wind and
also log this he went here with Dad let's save this and reload this application here.
And now if I click any made you see we had the starting and the ending animation fired.
And here you see what's inside the wind.
We see the starting state to state and timing and the same is true for the same data is part of the
animation ended event object Englad to give us.
So these callbacks might be useful for you if you have some code which animate something but after the
animation finishes you want to execute some other code and you can do that by listening to these built
in starred and done events on your trigger I hope with that you feel a bit more comfortable using animations
you get a nice introduction to how you might create your own animations and what you how you can ANY
made things you your Englad to application.
And with that play around with it set your own challenges take your existing projects maybe the recipe
book and any made some things.
This is a challenge.
This is where you'll learn the most.
See and other modules by