Now to manage the editedIngredient here, we need new actions, to be precise,
we need actions for starting the editing process and also for cancelling or stopping it.
Hence I'll export new constants,
START_EDIT which holds a value of start edit and also an exported constant, STOP_EDIT
which holds
stop
edit as a value. Now these are just the string types as you learned,
we need classes as actions or for our action objects and I'll name the first class StartEdit
and of course it implements action and then I'll copy that because obviously we also need a
StopEdit class.
Now let's start with the StartEdit,
it needs to be readonly type property which of course is referring to start edit and StopEdit
needs that as well
but of course here we refer to stop edit.
Now stop
edit actually can stay as it is,
it needs no payload because if we want to stop, I just want to reset the
editedIngredient and the editedIngredientIndex to their initial values, so we don't need to change
anything.
Start edit however needs a payload,
I need to know which ingredient we're editing. So I'll add a constructor with my public payload and that
payload can just be the number of the ingredient I want to edit,
again stop edit doesn't require anything.
Now just as before, these new actions should be added to this union action type here at the bottom so
that TypeScript is aware of these actions as available actions inside of the shopping list reducer.
So with the pipe symbol, let's add StartEdit and let's also add StopEdit here.
Now that's the actions,
next on to the shopping list reducer, there we got two new cases to handle,
we got start and stop
edit. So the first case which we get from shopping list actions is START_EDIT, take the string, so all
uppercase and the other case is of course from the shopping list actions file, STOP_EDIT.
Now in start edit and in stop edit,
in both cases we of course return a new object and in start edit, I want to set my editedIngredientIndex
to the index
I'm getting as a payload and the editedIngredient to the ingredient that belongs to that index. So if
we go down to start edit here, first of all I copy the existing state and this is now where this is
important by the way. I mentioned all the time that I would recommend that you do this all the time,
now it's more important than ever because now our state is more than just ingredients or than just
editedIngredientIndex and
for example here where we only edit the ingredients, if we don't copy the state first, we lose the
editedIngredient and the editedIngredientIndex information,
we don't want to lose that, hence copying the state is important.
Now here, I am copying the state and now I want to store the editedIngredientIndex,
now that's part of my action, it's in the payload because the payload for start edit is just a number,
the index of the ingredient I want to edit and of course the editedIngredient itself should also be
stored.
Now that's not part of the payload but we can get it from our state because in this part of our application
state,
we're storing all our ingredients, so of course we can also get our ingredients from there and I get
this editedIngredient by accessing my state ingredients for the action.payload because that's the
index of the ingredient
I want to edit. However if I would return the ingredient like this, this would not be that good,
why?
Because this is a reference to the ingredient in my ingredients array and objects and arrays are reference
types,
so if I now pass this on to let's say the shopping-edit component and I start changing properties on
this ingredient, I do it right in my store because this data is right from the store.
I instead need to create a new object which can then be edited without problems by using curly braces
and the spread operator
and this now copies that ingredient which I'm getting from my ingredients array,
this is then what I store here in editedIngredient. Now for stop
edit, I again copy all existing state and then the idea here simply is to reset editedIngredient
to null and editedIngredientIndex to minus one,
so to the initial values we had before.
All right.
So now we got these two cases set up in the reducer,
they should work correctly,
now of course we also need to take advantage of them by dispatching the right actions.
So first of all in the shopping list component, there in onEditItem,
let's no longer use the shopping list service but instead the store which we already have injected
here
and let's dispatch a new action and for that,
we need to import these actions first,
so as shopping list actions from store, shopping list actions.
So there I access all my actions,
I create a new action here based on my StartEdit class and StartEdit takes the index which I'm conveniently
getting as an argument here,
so now we're dispatching this action. In the shopping-edit component,
we can of course cancel editing here with onClear and I want to let my store know about that.
So besides resetting the form and resetting edit mode,
I here also want to reach out to my store and dispatch a new action, a new action from shopping list actions
and that would be my stop, not start, my stop
edit action
and here we don't need to pass in any data because stop edit requires no payload.
Now I'll also copy that and dispatch the same when we destroy our shopping-edit component so that if we get
rid of that page whilst we are editing an ingredient, I also reset this
otherwise we'll get strange behaviors the next time we revisit this shopping-edit components,
so the next time we try to edit an ingredient.
So I'll dispatch this here in ngOnDestroy as well
and also here, onClear and with that, the only missing thing is that we adjust how we fetch our data
when we start editing up here in ngOnInit.
There, instead of using the shopping list service and listening to started editing,
we should use our store and select the shopping list slice but now instead of using the async pipe in
the template, I'll set up my own subscription which I can of course because it is just an observable
and what we get here is our state data for this part of our store.
So the shopping list relevant state, to be precise, the state defined here,
this is the type of data we get. Now in that subscription here,
I then want to use this data.
First of all, I want to check if in my state data, the editedIngredientIndex
and here I'm getting nice auto completion because TypeScript understands this entire type setup,
if this editedIngredientIndex is greater than minus one, because if it's not, then I have some kind
of weird setup.
So in the else case, I haven't really selected anything and therefore we should set the edit mode to false
here.
Now if we do have a valid index, then the edit mode should be true
and I also want to set my edited item equal to my state data editedIngredient.
Now last but not least, then I also want to update my shopping list form as I did it down there in my old
subscription of which I now can get rid by the way.
So now we're initializing the shopping list form with data from that edited item which we get from
NgRx,
so now the NgRx flow is complete.
We dispatched the start and stop edit actions and we now also get the data for editing from NgRx and
then once we're done, we also dispatch our update
action back to NgRx and now we got everything managed with NgRx. Now one remaining thing, the subscription
here, I would recommend that you also manage this on your own, so store it in this subscription which we
used for the shopping list service subscription before and therefore, this is still managed here in
ngOnDestroy and unsubscribe from when we don't need it anymore. With all of that, let me save that,
let me go back to the application and reload it and now let's try editing the apple. It's not really reflecting
my changes back to NgRx, so something is still wrong.