In the last lecture, we learned how we can pass parameters and fragments,
now let's make sure we can also retrieve them.
So we're loading this edit-server.component in the end, so that is probably where we want to retrieve that
information. We can easily do this by going there, edit server component
and you see there already is a lot of code in there,
well everything what's happening here however is it's using our serversService to get the server with
the ID one and to be able to update it and definitely dive into this serversService file if you want
to learn more about what's happening here.
It's super simple though, we simply are able to get this array of servers, get a single server or update
a single server,
so overwrite it.
So that's not the interesting part,
the interesting part in the edit component here is how we can get access to our query parameter and
the fragment. We need our ActivatedRoute for this,
so let's inject it just like we did before, ActivatedRoute needs to be imported from the
@angular/router package,
so make sure to add this import at the top and with this added and let's say ngOnInit, we can retrieve
our query parameters and the fragment
and just like before, there are two ways of retrieving it. For the first approach, we can simply access
the snapshot of our route and access query params here or our fragment, just like that.
Now this might bring the same problem as with the params,
this is only run or updated at the time this component is created.
So if there is a chance of changing your query params from the page you're currently on, you might
not want to use this approach because it won't be reactive, it won't display or allow you to react to
any changes which happen after this component has been loaded.
So for now, let's use the snapshot though
and let's watch the console, once this reloads, notice we already have a query parameter and a fragment
and we see both here.
This is our query parameter object where we have this key-value pair mapping again, allowEdit to one
and this is just a bit broken
but here you see if I make my console a bit broader, you see the loading hash fragment.
So this is how you can retrieve it.
The alternative of course is to use the route and just like we had params as observable,
we also have query params as an observable we can subscribe to, like this
and of course we also have fragment as an observable we can subscribe
to. So just like before,
this will now allow you to react to changed query parameters.
Now that's something we'll use later in this module,
for now nothing will happen here but it is important to keep in mind like for params, you do
have the same for query params and fragment.
You don't need to unsubscribe here, Angular will handle it for you just like it did for params but this
is how you can now get access to these extra features and how you can make sure that you don't miss
that data.