Let's start by forwarding the user to a different route once the user is logged in. Now since we always
want to redirect the user once we authenticate it,
we of course can do this in two different places -
we can either do it here in handle authentication or we do it in the component, here inside of subscribe
in the success case only of course.
Now it's up to you when you do that,
if you prefer redirecting in the component or from inside a service. Both is valid
and if you need no data from either the service or the component and you have no strong reason for doing
it in one place or the other, it's totally up to you where you do that.
Now you could argue that you want to keep your service a bit cleaner and don't interact with the user
interface in the service, so don't directly influence the user interface and therefore, you maybe don't
want to interact with the router in here, though
I see no problem with doing that
and we did it before in the course as well.
Nonetheless, to mix things up, here I will do it in the component and I will inject the router, the Angular
router which is injected from @angular/router and with the router injected in the auth component, here in
subscribe but only in the success case of course, I want to use the router and navigate to
/recipes, like this.
This is a great example for programmatic navigation now where you couldn't use a link in the template
because you want to navigate once some action is done and you don't want to navigate when a user clicks
something but only once the user click the button and the login is done,
therefore we need to navigate from inside code because this is where we know once this is done.
So now, let's give this a try and
let's see if it works.
Let's try logging in and we go to recipes,
great,
let's now try to create a new user.
So here with test 2, switch to sign up and click sign up
and this works too.
So navigating works, of course we still can go back to authenticate because we still have it here in
the header and on the other hand if we're not authenticated,
for example if I reload the app, then all the previous state is lost and we are not authenticated because
the user object doesn't exist anymore in memory, we'll soon add something to persist it but for now, that's
how it is.
So even if we're not logged in, we still see recipes, even though we don't really want to be able to go
there.
So the next step will be that we correctly reflect our current status here in the UI and that in this
application mostly means in the header. In the header component, if we have a look at the HTML code, in the
end the goal will be to disable this recipes link if we are not logged in, to disable the authenticate link if
we are logged in because we,
there is no sense in logging in again if we are logged in, right? To always show the shopping list, to
disable the dropdown if we are not logged in
because saving and fetching data is only available if we are logged in
and to also show a logout button that allows us to logout.
Let me start with the logout button here, for that I'll add a new list item here and in there an anchor tag
where I say logout without any reference or router or link set, just like this.
Now let's also add this style here to make sure we get a nice cursor when hovering over that but that's
of course totally optional and
now we have that logout button here and now we need to make sure we get the current authentication status
into the header component,
so we basically find out, do we have a user with a valid token or not?
And we then also need to use that information to update the template correctly. Now for that first of
all, in the auth service,
right now we manage our user here through a subject.
This will inform all places in the application about when our user changes
and right now even though we haven't implemented all the logic for that yet, let's assume that it always
changes when the authentication status changes,
so even if the token expires, the user subject will emit a new value which is then null because then
the user is invalid,
we haven't added that logic yet but we will add it.
So let's assume that the subject here is our source of truth and therefore, the header component since
it's always there in our application, can subscribe to that subject to update correctly based on the
user status.
So in the header.component.ts file, we can now inject the auth service which is of type auth service
of course and you need to import auth service from that path and we can then add ngOnInit
by adding the onInit interface here which is also imported from @angular/core and inside of ngOnInit,
I want to set up a subscription to this auth service user. So we can set up a subscription here
and as you learned in the RxJS section, such subscriptions should be managed by you
so that you unsubscribe if it's not required anymore. For that, I'll add a new private property, user sub which
is of type subscription and subscription is imported from RxJS,
so this import needs to be added to the header component and with that added, we store the subscription
in that user sub property and now also add onDestroy here, which is also imported from
@angular/core
so that we are forced to add ngOnDestroy where we can clear that subscription.
So here I call this user sub unsubscribe.
The more interesting part for us of course happens inside of subscribe here because there, we get a user
object and now as I mentioned, let's rely on the fact that this user is either null if we're not logged
in or exists,
so if the user object is not null but it's a concrete object, if we are logged in.
So if we have a user, we are logged in,
that's the core idea. Therefore let's add a new property here in this component which you could name
isAuthenticated,
of course the exact name is up to you
and let's assume by default that is not the case,
so it's false. isAuthenticated is false, here
in this subscribe function where we get a user,
we then set this isAuthenticated equal to a check, if not user,
then I want to set the value to false because then we are not authenticated
if we have no user object, otherwise it's true.
Now this is the check I want to have and we can actually shorten this,
we can write
!!user.
This might look strange but it's a little trick where we basically check if we not have a user, which
will be true
if the user is null and false if we have a user object but that is the opposite of what we need, hence
I add extra exclamation mark to then inverse this value and get true or false,
to be precise I get true when we have a user and false if we have no user.
And in case you want to see what's happening there, simply console log not user and then console log
not not user and you will see what's happening here.
So with that, we change isAuthenticated, now in the header component, we can use that property to update
it appropriately. Recipes should only be visible if we are authenticated and therefore with ngIf,
we can make sure it's only visible if is authenticated is true.
So ngIf isAuthenticated is added to this link or actually not just to the link but to the entire
list item here. On the authentication link here
on the other hand should only be added if we're not authenticated, so add an exclamation mark in front
of is authenticated. Shopping list should always be visible, so nothing needs to change here.
Logout should only be visible if we are authenticated because if we are not authenticated, we clearly
can't logout,
so this should only be visible if we are authenticated,
so without an exclamation mark here.
Now this dropdown here should also only be visible if we are authenticated because if we're not authenticated,
we can't fetch and store data anyways.
With that if you save this and this reloads, you should only see authenticate and shopping list as a
default because we start non-authenticated
but now if I do login here with valid credentials, this changes and you see the user interface also
changes, you see now we have recipes, we have shopping list, we have logout and so on and we don't see
the authenticate page anymore.
Clearly, we can reach it if we manually visit /auth and this reloads the app anyways and loses our
authentication status by the way but that's a different thing,
the important thing here is that the user interface updates correctly.
Now with the user interface updating correctly, before we work on things like storing the token and protecting
certain routes so that we can't visit them even if we directly enter the URL, before we dive into
that,
let's make sure we now actually can use our token to fetch data because that is still not working, even
though we are authenticated, why?