I mentioned a way of optimizing lazy loading, which itself of course is already an optimization and with that,
I mean how the lazy loaded code is then loaded.
Right now, we load code whenever we need it,
so as soon as we visit /recipes, for example after logging in, we bring in the recipes module.
Now the downside of that of course is that this is downloaded and parsed
just when we need it, leading to a very tiny delay in our application. We might not see that here because
the module is small and the internet connection is fast
but the bigger the module and the slower the internet connection or for example if you temporarily have
no internet connection,
the longer that delay will be and therefore, we can actually tell Angular to preload lazy loaded modules
to avoid this delay.
For this, we simply go to our root router module, so here we reconfigure our root routes and you can
pass a second argument to that.
This is an object where you can configure that root router and there, you can set up a preloading strategy
and you can set this equal to preload all modules. The default is no preloading, you don't need to set
this but you can set this to preload all modules, which is simply and in the end, a constant you need to import
from @angular/router.
Speaking of imports, you should remove the auth component import by the way to optimize lazy loading as
well.
But with preload all modules imported and set here as a preloading strategy, you're telling Angular
generally we're using lazy loading, so it will not put all that code into one bundle, it will split
it as we saw it but it will preload the bundles as soon as possible,
so when we are on the auth page, it will already preload recipes and shopping list so that these code
bundles are already available when we need them.
The advantage is that the initial download bundles still is kept small because there, that code is not
included and therefore the initial loading phase is fast
but then when the user is browsing the page and we have some idle time anyways, then we
preload these additional code bundles to make sure that subsequent navigation requests are faster,
so we're getting the best of both worlds, a fast initial load and thereafter, fast subsequent loads.
So with that preloading strategy setup, now if you reload this page here, you actually see something
interesting.
We of course see that the main.js file and so on is loaded but then we also see that here, the recipes
module is loaded and the shopping list module is loaded and therefore now if I clear this all here,
the network request output,
you see no downloads of these modules here because they already were preloaded.
Still, we had that smaller initial bundle but we benefit from these code packages being there when we
need them and therefore, setting this preloading strategy is definitely worth a thought
if you want to optimize lazy loading and you want to ensure that this goes as fast as possible. Now you
can even build your own preloading strategies here where you could have more refined logic, for example
controlling that only certain routes should be preloaded but that is beyond the scope of that course.
Being aware of that preloading strategy is super import though and that is how you could use it.