Now that we learn about lazy loading,
I can finally dive into what's special about services and modules because I mentioned that there is something
special about that but I could only explain it
after diving into lazy loading because it's strongly related to that. I want to dive into where you can
provide services and how that affects the instances of the services you're working with.
Now we can provide services in the app module, we can provide services in the app component or other
components,
if you'll remember the services section, there you also could add a providers key to the component
decorator.
We can also load services or add services to providers of any eager loaded module,
so in the recipes module before we added lazy loading for example and we're also of course able to add
services to providers of lazy loaded modules. Of course, we can also provide services by adding the provided
in root configuration in the @injectable decorator and that would be recommended for all services
that you planned on providing in app module otherwise.
Now when you provide a service in the app module or with provided in root in @injectable, the service is
available application-wide and with the service, I also mean the same instance of that service is
available application-wide,
you're always working with the same single instance. If you provide a service in a component, no matter
if that's the app component or another component, then that service is only available for dependency
injection
inside of that component tree and then all these components will again share the same instance but we're
talking only about that component tree and you provide the service in multiple sibling components of
your application,
then all these sibling component trees have access to the service but each component tree has access
to its own service instance and I mentioned this and showed this in the services module of this course
already.
Now the interesting thing is if you do add a service to providers of an eager loaded module, you might
think that that service is only available inside of that module and that every module where you add
a service to its providers has its own instance of that service but actually, that's not the case.
If a module is eager loaded, everything is bundled together initially and therefore, any services you
add to providers in an eager loaded module,
let's say the recipes module would be not lazy loaded but still eagerly loaded by importing it into
the app module,
any service added there will be available application-wide with one and the same instance.
So adding a service to providers of an eagerly loaded module has the exact same effect as adding a service
to providers of the app module or as adding provided in root in @injectable. A huge difference
can be seen if you add a service to providers of a lazy loaded module though. There the service is only
available in that loaded module and it gets its own instance. If you do provide a service both in the
app module and in the lazy loaded module, then the service is of course available application-wide
but the lazy loaded module will get a separate instance, not the same instance you use in the rest of
the app.
Sometimes this can be desirable but in other cases, it might lead to a strange behaviour where you would
have expected to work with one and the same instance when you didn't.
The reason for that is that when you do provide in the app module or in @injectable, you use the so-called
root injector, so the root dependency injection mechanism of Angular. When you do provide it in a component,
you use the component specific injector, which is not the root injector and therefore not the entire application
has access to that. In an eagerly loaded module,
again the root injector is used automatically, with a lazy loaded module,
a separate child injector is created by Angular for that module and therefore, that module has its own
instance of that service. Therefore, the default should be that you use the app module or again,
provided in root in @injectable. You of course might have scenarios where a component tree needs its
own service,
for example if that component tree somehow has a service that only matters for these components, it doesn't
matter application-wide, then there is no need to provide the service application-wide, you can instead
provide it in that component. Eagerly loaded modules should pretty much never provide services,
you should avoid this because the effect is the same as in the app module but it's kind of unexpected
and it's harder to detect services there and therefore other developers diving into your code might
look for a certain service, might look for it in the app module, not find it there and therefore be confused
whether this service is now intended to be available to the entire app or only to that module.
Now in a lazy loaded module, you can of course add a service to providers but only do this if you deliberately
want to have a separate instance of that service there,
otherwise you can have strange bugs. So as a rule, generally you want to ensure that services are always
available application-wide by using @injectable, provided in root or by adding them to providers in
the app module unless you have a strong reason for adding them only in a component tree or in a lazy loaded
module,
never add services in an eager loaded module.
Now let's see that in practice.