So now that we learned a lot about navigating passing parameters,
let's improve our app a little bit by going to the users component where we have a list of links in
the end to single users and let's add the routerLink here, pass an array as an argument
and here, we want to target /users and we already created our route, right?
We have /users, /ID and /name, so we can use that information here in users component,
the second element here in this array there should be the ID
and since we have a for loop where we loop through all our users, we can easily dynamically add the ID
here by accessing user ID and the same for the name,
the third element, the third segment in this path, the user name, we can access username.
This is how we can dynamically construct such a link
and you already saw this with the navigate method a couple of lectures earlier.
So this is our routerLink here,
let's do the same for the servers.
So here in the servers component,
let's also replace the five here with server ID.
We do have a server ID if we have a look at the ServersService, you see we have IDs and names
here.
So we want to pass the ID and we can now do this by dynamic fetching it here and I will remove edit
though because I not only want to load the edit component here, I want to load the single server component
instead. With my link added here,
we need to add the fitting route,
so in our app module here, we need to add another route where we have servers and then just ID to load
a single server with the server component here.
Right now, we're always loading the edit-server.component so make sure to add this extra route and of
course, this will be loaded because we remove the edit at the end,
so we're not editing this anymore,
this just loads the single component.
And of course now, in this single server component, this one here where we want to output our server data, we
need to get that data we pass in the route path
in the URL. We pass the ID there,
we do have the ServersService where we are able to get a server by ID and we already do this in our server
component here in ngOnInit, right now always for the server with the ID one.
So now, use your chance to update this code to do this with the ID being passed with our route.
You learn everything you need for this, time for you to do it on your own,
I will give you a chance to pause this video before we do this together.
So were you successful? Let's try it together. Of course to get access to the router parameter, we need
to inject our activated route.
So we learned how to do this, add this route property and make it of type ActivatedRoute which you need to import
from @angular/router and now in ngOnInit, you can get your ID from this ActivatedRoute from
the snapshot,
the params object here
and then the ID which is encoded in the URL and now you can use this ID here to get that server.
Now if you also want to react to any changes thereafter, you need to subscribe to your params observable
here and basically do the same.
You get the params here which is of type params,
make sure to import that from @angular/router
and once you get this, you can get a new server whenever your params should change. So here, you could
then access params ID like this to update the server whenever change is triggered on this page.
So with this in place, if we reload our app and go to servers, you'll see we get an error here which makes sense
because keep in mind on our servers component here, we still are always loading our single server component
and therefore, we are also loading it
if we don't have this ID available.
So for now I will comment this out, we will soon learn how we can nest
another router in there to have some kind of child routing, to load this route dynamically next to our
menu here.
So for now, I simply comment it out.
If I now click on a server here,
we still get an error
and now this can be a tricky one to spot, what's going wrong here?
The issue is if we parse a parameter from our URL, it will always be a string because our whole URL
is simply just text, so ID here will actually not be one in the case of /1,
it will be a string of one.
So if we try to get a server by this ID, it will actually search a server which has an ID of one but a
string one,
however we use numbers here.
So we simply have to make sure to convert our ID to a number and we can do this by adding a plus in
front of it and this is perfectly fine to do. With that, you're making sure that the ID you're retrieving is
treated as a number,
of course you also need to make sure to do this here in your observable, so convert the params here
to a number too.
So with that if we now click on servers and choose a server, you see production server here,
test server in this case
and with that, this is now working as expected.
We now improved our app because now we got working links here,
we get working links here and we're loading the correct server.
So with that, we added a lot but we see that our app has some limitations,
it would be nice if we don't load a new page with the user or the server here but load it next to our
menu in both cases. So we somehow need some nested routing, some child routes kind of, to have a router
inside a router.
Let's have a closer look at this in the next lectures.