We're nearing the end of the first part of this section, the template driven approach,
there are still some things I want to show you, for example how to work with radio buttons.
We don't have any radio buttons in our form as of now, so let's add some. Let's add a property in the app
component first with some genders.
So this is simply an array where I have male and female and I don't want to insult anyone, I know there
are more genders nowadays, I'm going to go with the classic approach here just to keep it simple.
We have this genders array and now with that array, I want to output genders here,
so let's say below our
your reply paragraph here, I'll add a new div with a class of radio
and this div should be replicated for all the genders.
So I'm going to loop through my genders, maybe bind it to a gender variable and this is just a setup
of Bootstrap uses to give this some nice styling, of course
use any other setup to style your radio buttons here. I'm looping through all the genders
and now again in the bootstrap world, to create a nice looking radio button,
I'm going to wrap it in a label, this input here which is of type radio
and I'm going to wrap this over multiple lines too, just to make it all super simple to read and to understand
and here I will give it a name of gender because in a radio button, I can only select one of them in a group,
so
the name should be gender for whichever button is selected and I will place ngModel on it to make
it a control
and I will prepopulate or I set the value of this button equal to gender,
so this variable of my ngFor loop.
Now with that if we save this, we should see that we have some gender buttons, to output a text,
I need to add it here after my input.
So again, gender here
like that
and now we have male and female here
and if I just enter something so that I can submit the form and I pick male here, you will see that on
the value object here,
we got gender which is male and of course if I pick female, this will, you guessed it. be set to female.
So this is how you can easily incorporate radio buttons by binding or by placing ngModel on the
input as always, setting the value, of course you could also hardcode the value and that well makes
it usable just like any other input.
And if you want to set it to a default gender of course, you can use one-way binding again to make sure
that one of the two buttons is selected by default at the start
when you load the form. You can also of course add the required directive or attribute to that input
here to make sure that now the form will not be valid until one of the two has been selected,
so that works just like on any other input.
So I just want to highlight this because radio buttons can look like a very special case,
they aren't, they are used like any other input when using the template driven approach in your Angular
app.