So we learned about all these hooks,
now let's see what they actually do. In the server element component,
this is the component
I will choose for demo purposes,
we already get the constructor in ngOnInit.
So in the constructor, I will simply log constructor called so that we can see when this happens in
the console and I'll do the same for ngOnInit but of course here I'll say ngOnInit called. Of
course I will add the other hooks then too
but let's start with these two
and if we reload the application here, we see right at the top, constructor called ngOnInit called
and for every new server we add, we see this again of course because a new instance of this component
was created and therefore all these hooks are executed again because it's a brand new instance, doesn't
have anything in common besides the class it was created of with the first instance of that component
here.
So that is constructor in ngOnInit,
now I told you that ngOnChanges would run first.
So let's implement ngOnChanges
and this would be enough, though it is a good practice to implement the onChanges interface too and that
is true for all hooks. Implementing the method alone will do the trick but it is a good practice to be
very explicit about which interfaces your component users or which methods your components will have.
So therefore implementing these interfaces is a really good practice,
it's very clear then which methods may be called in your component and which methods you won't have.
Now here, we're getting a lot of imports which is why I will split this up
and as you can already see, you have to import all these interfaces, onInit and onChanges.
So ngOnChanges runs first as I told you,
so let's say ngOnChanges here and this hook here actually receives an argument.
It's the only hook that does,
here we receive a changes argument which is of type SimpleChanges which also needs to be imported
from @Angular/core.
So I will simply log changes here, so that we can have a look at it and see what's inside.
So let's save this
and here are the top again, we see constructor called ngOnChanges called
as mentioned before, ngOnInit and then we see the SimpleChanges.
That's an object which has an element which is of type SimpleChange and element of course is our bound
property, here
it's this property name, that's the name we see reflected here
and then Angular simply gives us some information.
What's the current value?
Well that's the object with just a test,
test server and of type server. Is this the first change?
Yes it is, we just initialized it.
And what's the previous value?
There is no value because we didn't
didn't change this before.
Now to see that ngOnChanges actually gets fired more than once,
I'll add something to this app just for demo purposes,
I'll add a button, change first element to my app component template above
this list of server elements, give it some bootstrap styling here but that's not really important.
More important, give it a click listener, onChangeFirst would be a name you could choose
and then in the app.component.ts file, I went to change the name of the first element.
Now for this, I also need to change the way we pass this element to the server component.
Right now, we receive the full element, the full object and I will leave this here for demo purposes,
so that we can reference this code
but now I only expect to get the name because the name is the only thing I'm outputting here anyways.
So I'm duplicating this and I will comment out the old code
and now we only output the name because all the other element information was projected via ng-content
into this element anyways, into this component.
So we only get the name now,
this name will simply be a string, we added input so that it can be bound from outside
and we're outputting name here.
So in app component,
when we loop through this, I will now actually bind the name too and I will bind to server element name and
you wouldn't need to bind server element here anymore because that is not used
but I will leave it here for reference.
So this is now how we pass the data, how
we passed the name. In the app.component.ts file here in onChangeFirst,
I will now access my server elements, the first element and therefore this will fail if we were to empty
this array and set the name to changed.
So again, I did these changes so that we can really see when ngOnChanges gets fired and we couldn't
use the element as an object because objects are the reference types, so we passed the object via input,
therefore both properties in the server element component,
this one here and the object in the array of server elements here in the app component, they both point to
the same place in memory
and therefore if we change the name there, it will update in the child component, in the server element
component but it will not trigger ngOnChanges because technically, the property we're binding to, we use
here with @input, that didn't change the value of that didn't change it,
it's still the same object in memory.
So it simply this difference between reference and primitive types and you should look this up if
that's all brand new to you,
it's a Javascript concept, has nothing to do with TypeScript or Angular.
So that is why now I'm binding to a primitive with name which is just a string and therefore,
ngOnChanges should get fired again if I click the change first element button,
let's do that
and indeed, it does.
Note that the constructor and ngOnInit weren't called but ngOnChanges was
and here now we also see the previous value and the new value and therefore, this hook could be interesting
to you if you want to react to any changes and then do something with the old values, store it
before it gets dumped or something like that,
that's ngOnChanges.
We get a couple of our other hooks, so let's move on.
Besides ngOnChanges and ngOnInit, we get
do check
and as I said, this also needs to be imported from @angular/core.
This will give us a method which is executed on every change detection run.
So ngDoCheck is the method we need for this
and here we can simply console log
ngDoCheck called,
so let's see when this gets called. If this reloads, you see it gets called right at the beginning,
then one more time here
but that is only because we're running in development mode,
there Angular has one extra change detection cycle but it also gets called if I click this button as you
can see and if I click this button a couple of times here.
So ngDoCheck as I told you gets called whenever Angular checks for any changes and there are a couple
of triggers which trigger this method and event was called by clicking or a promise gave us back
some data,
so a lot of triggers for ngDoCheck.
So that is not something where you want to run amazingly powerful code in because that would cost you a
lot of performance
but the fact that change detection runs as often as it does on its own is not a problem
and this can be a great hook if you want to check, if you do need to change something manually because
Angular didn't pick it up or something like that.
So the next hook is afterContentInit, this needs to be imported from @angular/core too, this
interface
and with that we need to implement ngAfterContentInit.
Now let's call this console log ngAfterContentInit called.
If we do this here, you will see that here it is, there it is called after do check and it is called only
once because it doesn't get initialized again. Remember, content is the thing we projected into this through
ng-content,
so this here will be our content in the end.
Let's move on.
The next hook then is and this is getting long here so I will split this up over multiple lines too, all
these interfaces I'm implementing,
so the next hook will be AfterContentChecked, like this. This also needs to be imported from @angular/core
and it requires us to implement a method, ngAfterContentChecked
and well now I'm just going to copy the code from ngAfterContentInit and replace init with checked.
If we save this and have a look at it,
you see here it is called and here it is called again after do check, which makes sense because it is
called after each change detection cycle.
Well now I'm going to copy these two here
and also I will add two new interfaces,
the first one being AfterViewInit and then AfterViewChecked, both need to be imported from
@angular/core too. Now this require me to have ngAfterViewInit as a method and ngAfterViewChecked
and I will replace the text here in the console log
so that we can see when these get called.
So if we log this, you see it happens after the content has been checked. Well and with that, we're almost
at the end,
the remaining piece is ngOnDestroy and onDestroy is called, well right before this gets destroyed,
this component gets destroyed.
So let's add it here on the implements list, on the interface list I should say and make sure to add the
import from @angular/core and then you need to implement ngOnDestroy
and here I will say ngOnDestroy called.
Now to be able to actually see this being destroyed, I will add a new button,
button destroy first component and give it a class of button and then btn-danger to make it red and here I'll
add a click listener, onDestroyFirst.
I will copy that, add my method here
in
just onDestroyFirst of course,
just the name. We'll add it here to my TypeScript code and there I will something call server elements, the splice
method splicing at the first element and then just one element therefore removing it.
So with this, we should now see all the hooks called, view checked and so on
and if I destroy the component, you see ngOnDestroy was called because we removed it from the
array,
therefore ngFor reran and didn't render this first element because it was removed,
therefore it was removed from the DOM,
hence this component hook was called.
So these are all the lifecycle hooks in action,
you rarely need to use all of them but some of them can be very helpful for your application to hook
into a specific piece, a specific face and run your code.