We learned a lot about the template driven approach. Before concluding the first part of the module, let's
have a look at the suggest a username button here,
it doesn't work but I added this suggest username method here where I create a default username.
Now it would be nice that upon clicking this button,
we populate this username input here with this username.
Now you could think about some solutions using two-way data binding and they would probably work,
you could two-way data bind this to username property which you then change with this method,
I just want to show you a different approach.
Remember that we do have access to this form here
through @ViewChild, of course it would be nice if we could set the value of one of our inputs and turns
out we can.
For this, we get two different methods we can use.
The first one would be on our signupForm,
the setValue method here.
This allows you to set the value of the whole form
and here we need to pass a Javascript object exactly representing our form.
So we need to use or set up user data which is an object too where we have, let's check, a username
field, username set to the suggested name here
and then also e-mail set to maybe an empty string and secret set to pet maybe and
questionAnswer,
keep in mind this is this text area here,
so questionAnswer set to an empty string
and last but not least, the gender set to male and with this all added,
let's go to our template and hook up this button, this button here which is of type button so that it
doesn't submit the form and here I'll add a click listener
and target the suggestUserName method.
So if this now recompiles and we hit this button, you'll see super user was entered here,
however this approach does have one downside.
If we already had some value we enter there and then want to click suggest username, it overwrites
all our other content.
So this is not necessarily the best approach,
however it does show you how you can set the values of all controls with one convenient command, with
the setValue command where you pass an exact copy of that form, of the form value
I should say as a Javascript object and can overwrite the value of each control.
Now as mentioned, this is not the best approach so let's comment it out,
the better approach here would be to access the signupForm and now actually, the form object on it
because signupForm, this overall ngForm object is kind of the container of your form you could say
and there you also have the patch value method.
So this is not available on the signupForm itself but on the FormGroup wrapped inside of it
and here you can pass Javascript object too, where you only overwrite specific certain controls.
So here you could also pass user data,
let me restructure this so that it's easier to read, userData
and then inside of userData, here you might want to overwrite the username, set it to the suggested name
but don't overwrite any other value.
So with this in place, if I now save this and I already have an e-mail address entered and something here
and here and I click this button,
now it only added super user and left all my other controls untouched.
So set value and patch value,
important, patch value only available on the form wrapped by ngForm itself.
As a side note, setValue would be available here too.
So these two commands are very helpful,
setValue to set your whole form, patch value to overwrite parts of the form.
Very useful helper methods
I wanted to bring to your attention.