Now we're almost done,
let's finish up our form here.
We get a submit button and right now, we only log it,
now let's add something to our little form here, let's add a horizontal line below it and let's summarize
our data
maybe in a new Bootstrap row here,
so let's add a row class and then a column class
here, a very simple one.
Let's summarize our data there, I'll
place the horizontal line between the Bootstrap rows and I want to say or output my username here, I
want to output my mail address,
maybe my secret question and my answer to that question as well as my gender, so just a nice summary.
I only want to output this once the form has been submitted and then populate it with the data of my
submitted form.
So in the app component here, I could add a new property named user maybe, which is a Javascript object,
which holds a username property,
let's set it to an empty string by default, an e-mail property and these names here of course don't have
to match the control names in your form, that's a brand new Javascript object not related to your form
directly at least.
Then here, we might also have a secret question which is a string and then we have the answer which is
a string and finally, the gender which is a string.
So that's my user object as created by default
and when submitting the form, I want to update it.
So here I then want to say this user and there I want to access the username let's say and set this equal
to my sign-up form, access the value of this form and there we know we have a username input field,
like this and replicate this.
Now also for the e-mail and of course value of course was available on the user data grouping though,
so username and e-mail was in the user data module group, keep this in mind, so we have to access this model
group property first before we can access the final username and e-mail.
However, the secret question here was available like this,
we did name the control
secret though, so make sure to use secret here when accessing it in the form value
and the answer,
well let's see which name we gave this, we gave it the name questionAnswer,
so let's use this when accessing the form
and finally we want to set the user gender equal to what we stored in the sign up form, here
we did name this control gender too,
you can check it down there, gender.
So with that, we now update all that information in our user,
maybe we also want to track whether we did submit the form, so
we do have submitted property set to false initially and we set this to true here because well guess
what, we submitted the form
and with that, we could place ngIf on our row here to check whether the form was submitted and only if
it was submitted
I want to display this block and here,
I then want to output user, username
and of course all the other information we gathered like user.email here,
so let's quickly add all of this. Here the question would be your first
and then we store user secret question, here we have the answer and so on.
Of course structure this in whatever way you want to structure it,
I just want to show you how you can access your values and use them.
And with this all in place,
now you don't see that section by default
but if I enter something here like Anna or let's adjust the username actually, my e-mail address, my
first pet which is Nelly and then the gender, I think that surprises you,
that's not correct though.
So let's hit submit
and now we see the data here at the bottom.
This is how you can extract the data, how you can use it, how you can add a property like submitted to
make sure you only display certain sections of the form was submitted and how you in the end use that
data.
One more thing before we move on to reactive forms though.