In the last lecture, we saw how we can finally submit the form, extract the data we want to extract, just
so that you saw this too, that you can access the value property on your form.
Now let's say we did extract all the data and now we want to reset the form,
well turns out this is super simple. On our form, signupForm in this case which again is just fetched
directly from our template with @ViewChild, on this form,
we can call reset like this and this will reset the form and what this means is it will not only empty
all the inputs,
you could do this with setValue too as you learned,
it will also reset the state like the valid, the touched and so on, these properties.
So now if I enter something here again like this and I hit submit, you'll see everything is empty and
if we inspect it, you'll see that also the classes have been reset to pristine and valid and so on,
so it's really like the page was loaded again, very helpful to know this, how to reset the forms. With that,
you got a great overview over how you can quickly create powerful forms with Angular, with the template
driven approach,
this approach might be well-suited for the majority of your use cases, during the rest of the module
though, we're going to have a look at the other approach, the reactive approach which gives us even
more control over our forms and which allows you to create more powerful forms, your own validators
and much more.
So let's dive into this in the next lectures.