So in the last lecture, we try to improve our application a bit more
but the issue is our query parameters are gone whenever we navigate away from our single
server component, to the edit server component for example. So we want to preserve them because we already set
this information at the point of time we visit a single server,
now we want to preserve this information once we navigate one step further to the edit server component.
To preserve that information,
we get a simple way of doing so. In the server component where we navigate, we can pass another property
or add another property to this Javascript object we use to configure our navigation
and here, we get the query params handling property.
Now query params handling takes a string as a value and this could be merge, to merge our old query params
with any new we might add here. Now we don't add any new ones,
so we can simply choose preserve instead and preserve which will overwrite the default behavior which
is to simply drop them and make sure that the old ones are kept.
Now if we were to add new ones here, the old ones would actually overwrite the new ones,
so we should use merge in this case
but since we don't add new ones, preserve should make sure that we don't lose them.
So now if we click on this again and click edit server, now you'll see allowEdit equal to zero is
still set and therefore on the dev server where it is set to 1 if we click edit server, we do see the edit
menu again.
So query params handling here, super important, super useful to know to make sure you don't lose the
information you had before.