For this, we of course need a back-end
and just as in the HTTP section, I will use Firebase here because I don't want to write any server-side
code because that's simply not the course for that, Angular doesn't run on the server after all,
you could of course have your own back-end written in PHP or Node or whatever you want but this again
is not the focus of the course,
so we will use Firebase here since it's easy to set up, free to use and has everything we need here.
So on firebase.com, visit the Firebase console just as we did it in the last course section and there,
create a new project which you can give any name you want.
Now I will name it ng-course-recipe-book but again, you are free to pick any name you want here.
So ng-course-recipe-book accepts both checkmarks or both terms here and then create that project
and definitely check out that last course section where we used the HTTP service
Angular offers for the first time so that this is not brand new to you. With this created, let's open our
project and just as before, we'll use a database and we'll use that realtime database. So not Firestore
because that's a bit more clunky to use but instead, we'll use the realtime database down here,
create a database
and for now, start in test mode so that we have unlimited read and write access without being authenticated,
though we will add authentication soon in a separate module.
So for now, start in test mode, enable this and create your database in that Firebase project
and now as you learned in the last section, this will be the URL you use to save data or at least
a part of that URL we'll use.
But before we'll use that,
let's go back to our code and let's make sure that here, we have some way of interacting with the back-end
and of using the Angular HTTP service.