Why can't the first with you in this fit you will have a look at typing which is really the core of
typescript.
Hence the name.
So prepared a little example here and in this typing got us in this type of file which is also attached
to this lecture.
All these files are attached to this section of course you will well find some examples about typing
will start by creating a string my string and by using Tobel them and then the name of the type we're
setting this stream to the type string.
Variable excuse me to the type stream.
So now we may only assign string values to this type.
Otherwise we will get an error.
So for example here the first step where we say my string does is a string.
This is fine.
Let me comment out this line and comment in this line here where we have my string equals four.
You might already be able to see that it might.
I get this red underline indicating here is an error.
Let's try to compile this file.
Running TC This is typescript we installed Clovelly in our setup process and then the name of the file
.
And I think the number for them.
So that we get into this.
So now you see.
And the file is called type and or TS They don't need to type TS TSA can't just write C type and compile
it and then you can see here to the error type number is not assignable to type string.
That's exactly the problem we're setting my string to be of type string but now we try to compile it
.
No that's not good.
So let me.
Well commented out again and comment that an interesting thing this typing touchiest was created because
what we compiled and here you can see it did compile this even though it an error because technically
it is possible and Javascript of course you can see we're not setting any type here because we don't
have types and javascript or we can set variables to certain types.
So this is a valid Charles group but not valid types.
And this is good because as already mentioned for you this prevents us from making errors.
We want this to be a story and that we would be of an error made by mistake or whatever.
If we assign a number type of what are we.
So this is the basic typing we got here and how we make sure that we always assign the correct types
.
Now we don't have to do it like this if we initialize a variable that also already well at the point
of declaration.
Assign a value like here and line 16 typescript is able to infer the type it knows.
OK this is a string because.
Well setting it equal to a string.
So we could write code string.
This would not for ever.
That's fine but we don't have to type disable 2 in for the type of variable.
Now let's see if I try to set equal to 4.
I can already see I got this red underline if my compilers file again to get an error type number.
It's not assignable to type string in line 19 this year.
This is because I've inferred that this is the string.
So really clever and well we don't have to use this explicit typing.
If we're already signing a value at Declaration time it's important to understand inferring that type
does not work.
If we declare a variable without setting a value.
So here we're not setting a value upon a declaration and we're not declaring a type.
Now you can see the decimal fraud arrow by itself because we have to set types but it's best practice
or a good practice to do so when you see Tuscola.
Now the next step I'm setting this variable equal to a string and assigning the swelling and then assigning
a value of 5.
I could think typescript is able to infer the type as I'm not setting a pipe here but in the first assignment
or when initializing it.
I'm setting a string value.
So tapster might be able to infer it this way will ship history.
No it doesn't.
No.
This might be an accident.
Types.
No.
So it's not done for in any type off this line.
And therefore using an assigning number in the next step that's not an error as you can see if I compile
this.
It compiles fine because here we're not setting any type and therefore by evil it will have a type.
And in this type here which allows us to do this set any time like in normal javascript this is possible
.
But if you got a chance avoid it strong type your variables are class members use it.
It's very helpful.
It prevents errors.
It's really very helpful.
So which types can be used where there are a couple of basic types of typescript like streams number
Boyens and every year this is a generic type with these smaller than and greater than signs here.
We'll get to Teneriffe types in wealth section for a lecturer for hearing or lecture five actually so
this is.
And we all at this.
Type all it showed a second ago where we are able to assign any value.
Additionally what for white which means empty for function functions for example if you want to say
if it's nothing then the function return type would be void or eems which you might know from other
languages which are basically a set of values.
Of course if required create road types or classes we can use them you well ask types to make a certain
variable should only be of type.
Our custom class to that is typing.
And I hope I make this clear.
It's a huge advantage.
Use it.
It really helps you.
See you next will you.