Inside of an interceptor, you can not only log data,
you can also modify the request object.
However, the request object itself is immutable, so you can't set request URL to a new URL, that
will not work and you also get an error here.
Instead if you want to modify the request, you have to create a new one, like modified request sounds
like a fitting name for the constant, where you call request clone and inside of clone, you pass in
a Javascript object where you now can overwrite all the core things. You could set a new URL here
or you could add new headers, if you want to keep the old headers by the way, then you simply do that
by using the request headers and calling append or you add new params or whatever you want.
Now, I wanted to add a header here, so indeed I will access my headers and I will access the old headers
on the original request object and then simply call append and as you learned, this will return a new headers
object where I then have all the old headers but also the new headers and these will then be set here as
headers for this modified request. And here, I'll have my auth key
let's say, with xyz as a value, of course this just some made up header which doesn't really do anything.
And now the important thing here is, I do not forward the original request but my modified request and
that of course is a typical use case for an interceptor,
you change the request and then you forward that modified request and if you only wanted to append the
auth header for certain URLs, then you could use an if check with the request URL key for
example. Here I will indeed log request URL, so that we really see for which request the interceptor
ran
and now let's go back and let's fetch some posts for example,
you see the URL is being logged. If we have a look at the network, we fetch again and we inspect that request,
you'll see that there on the request headers, auth
xyz was indeed added and we should see the same if I now add a post. There
if we have a look at the request headers, we also see this.
So our interceptor is adding that for all outgoing requests and therefore, interceptors are a super important
and useful feature.