In the last lecture, we added the canActivate guard and it was working fine
but it was working for our whole servers path here.
Now we could grab it from here and add it to our child to make sure that only the child are protected,
the children and not our root path
but that is not the easiest way because if we add more child items, we have to add canActivate to each
of them.
There is another guard we can use,
it's pretty similar
to canActivate,
it's called CanActivateChild.
So let's implement this interface too,
you need to import it from @angular/router and this interface requires you to provide a CanActivateChild
method in this class which basically takes the same form as the canActivate method, so it has
the route and state and it returns an observable, promise or boolean.
So this is the form of CanActivateChild.
Well and since this is exactly the same form and we want to run the same logic, we can simply call
or excuse me, return
this canActivate,
so the other method we already included and here we simply pass our route and state as arguments since
canActivate expect these two arguments.
What is the advantage of adding this then?
Well since we added the CanActivateChild interface, we can now use a different hook here in our routes, instead
of only using canActivate, we can use a different one and I will split this over multiple lines to
make it really clear on what's happening,
I will comment out canActivate and instead add CanActivateChild. This now also takes
an array of services which act as guards which implement the right interfaces
and here we can still add the auth guard because the auth guard now is able to do both, protect a single route
since we have canActivate implemented or all child routes since we have CanActivateChild implemented
too.
So with this in place, we should now be able to go to servers, this works but if we try to load a single
server,
now we get redirected back because now only the child routes are protected,
something I can also prove by trying to go to /1/edit,
this also navigates us back.
So now this is the finegrained control you can implement to protect a whole route and all its child routes
or just the child routes, depending on which behavior you need in your app.