No worries, we're coming closer to having a working set up with @ngrx/effects for authentication. As
always with NgRx,
it's a bit more initial setup but once it is set up, other pieces can easily be added.
So now I want to redirect once we're done authenticating, once were successfully done authenticating
from inside auth effects because as I just explained, you could see such navigation as a side effect. For
this in the auth effects,
let's add a new property of success which has a value of this actions pipe, there
add ofType and I want to react only to my login action here
when I successfully did login. Now this needs the @effects decorator and as an additional step, after
filtering for the type, I will add the tap operator which therefore needs to be imported from
rxjs/operators and in there, I simply want to execute a function where I use the Angular router to redirect.
For that, we should inject the Angular router here, so inject router from @angular/router and with that
injected, let's use it in here
by calling this router navigate and then here, I'll go to the route route.
Now of course you could argue that the route you want to go to differs and you don't always want to
go back to just slash,
then you could of course accept that information as a payload on the action you're reacting to for example.
What's really important here though is that this is an effect which does not dispatch a new action
at the end.
I mentioned that typically, your effects do that, they typically return an observable which holds a new
effect which should be dispatched,
this effect doesn't and to let NgRx effect know about that and avoid errors, you have to pass an object
to your @effect decorator where you set dispatch to false
and this lets @ngrx/effects
know that this is an effect which will actually not yield a dispatchable action at the end and then
you can do that just like this.
Also note that I used the login action which only fires on a successful login, not as soon as we
start the login process. With all of that,
let's try logging in again,
we see the spinner and we get an error, auth effect auth login dispatched invalid
action and that's indeed an error from my side.
Whilst we need to create an observable with auth and catch error inside of map, map automatically wraps
what you return into an observable,
so here it actually returns an all new observable with our auth created observable and that's wrong.
So here, we just need to return our new action, not wrapped into auth because otherwise we're creating
a double observable
so to say. Tiny mistake on my side,
don't use auth here, with that out of the way though,
now if we try logging in again, we
see the spinner and we're there. Now let's logout and let's try logging in with an incorrect password
and we're getting the error but we're not really getting an error message here,
so this is still not working correctly, we still have to implement that.
The error case here can't work because if we're catching an error for logging in which we're doing, we're
returning an empty observable and hence, this does never dispatch anything that would store our
error.
Now actually we prepared everything we need,
we got our login fail action and in the reducer, we're reacting to it and we're storing the payload of
that action
in the auth error which we then in turn try to use in the auth component to hopefully show the error
message.
Now there are two missing pieces,
one is in the auth component, actually for showing an error,
we have to call show error alert to use our dynamic component and not just set this error
but that's a tiny thing, in here,
I simply check if this error is true-ish
and then if it is, I call this show error alert and forward this error.
So that's one thing,
the more important thing is that in the auth effects, we of course need to return our action here.
Now here inside of auth because catch error, unlike map, does not automatically wrap what you return into
an observable,
so here you need to create your own one. Still here,
the goal is to create a new auth action, the login fail action
and this requires a payload which is the error message as a string
and that's not just error like this but instead if we have a look at auth service, here you see in the
past, we called this handle error when catching an error and in handle error, we got the full error response
and from the error response, we then extracted some data and generated our own error message.
So essentially, I want to copy that logic here from the auth service into auth effect, like this, error here
is nothing else but our error response, so we can access error and so on there. Now what we must not
do however is call throw error here because as I explained earlier, your effects here should never return
errors that breaks the observable, instead here I also call auth and I create a new auth action login
fail with the dummy error message we have up there,
otherwise we get a more specific error message and we pass that to login fail down here.
Now we have better error handling code in place
and now let's try logging in with incorrect credentials and I'm getting my modal here and we can try again,
so our main observable is not that and therefore now if I try the different combinations, this all fails
but once I try the right credentials, I can login. And now this was a lot of work but now we're using
NgRx for logging in and again as before, as I mentioned it before, it is a lot of initial setup
work and it's definitely something to wrap your head around but thereafter, you have a clean flow
here where you will be able to soon get a lot of the logic out of our auth service and then again, we're
entirely in the NgRx world and as you will see, adding new effects will be now much faster than this
first initial setup.