In the last lecture, we saw ngIf, super useful directive and ngIf was a structural directive, the other
type of directives are attribute directives which are called like this because they really just look
like normal HTML attributes without a star basically.
Let's add one, on the server component here,
we output the serverStatus right and the serverStatus always is offline,
let's mix this up.
Let's say we want to dynamically create this, so I'll add the constructor which is just a built-in method
each TypeScript class has which is called once this component is created
and here I will set the serverStatus to a random value,
I will use the math.random function and this gives us a random number between 0 and 1, a floating point
number
and if this is greater than 0.5, I want to set the status to online otherwise I will set it to
offline.
So with that, we shouldn't get the same status all the time
and now let's check this,
we see indeed online and offline, that's lucky, could have of course also been both offline since we have
a 50% chance.
Now we have two different statuses here
and now let's say we want to change the color, the background color of this component depending on
the serverStatus. For this, we can use another directive, on this wrapping paragraph here,
I can add it and it's called ngStyle.
Now that's a built-in directive, you can recognize this on the ng
at the beginning and ngStyle, that's the directive, is pretty useless like this,
we need to give it some configuration to do something, that is why we will use property binding on this
directive and it's super important to understand that the square brackets here are not part of the directive
name, the directive name is just ngStyle,
the square brackets indicate that we want to bind to some property on this directive and this property
name happens to also be ngStyle.
We will see this in practice on our own directives in the directives section later
but super important to understand that property binding is not the same as a directive,
it's totally different,
we are binding to a property of the directive.
This ngStyle property expects to get a Javascript object
and here, we define key-value pairs of the style name as the key and the value of the style as the
value. So for example, we could bind background-color and if you want to use this notation with the
dash, you have to wrap it in single quotation marks to make it a valid Javascript property name or you
use the camel case notation,
backgroundColor like this
and then you could set this to red but I don't want to set it to red,
I want to set it to something depending on the serverStatus.
So here we could simply call a method, getColor, so that is really mixing now all the things and make
it clear that between the quotation marks, we are executing TypeScript code here, so therefore we can of
course call a method.
Now getColor is a method we can add here and getColor should
now let's say return green if the status is online and red otherwise.
So I will return something,
first I check the serverStatus,
so this serverStatus
and if this is equal to online, using a ternary expressing here, I will return
green, otherwise I will return red.
So getColor will return green or red
and this is then assigned as the background color with ngStyle.
If we now save this, let's have a look at the result.
We see indeed the running server has a green background and the offline server has a red one,
so that is working, ngStyle allows us to dynamically update that. If I reload,
you see now both are offline
so both are red now.
And that is the big advantage of ngStyle, it allows you to dynamically update the styles
and of course if the serverStatus here did change over time,
it would update the styling respectively.
So this binding we set up here still is working,
if the serverStatus here which is responsible for choosing the right color changes, it updates the
style.
So that's ngStyle, an attribute directive added like an attribute
and in this case, also using property binding to configure it.