We saw examples for ngStyle and ngIf, now something related to ngStyle is ngClass.
Now we learn that ngStyle allows us to dynamically assign a style,
now I will also add ngClass here and where ngStyle allowed us to change the CSS style itself,
ngClass allows us to dynamically add or remove CSS classes.
So let's create such a class and for this, I will
first of all add my styles here
and I will use back ticks to write this over multiple lines and I will give this a class name of online, in
which case I want to color the text white. So that's all I want to do because I think it's kind of hard
to read the black text on the green background.
So back here, ngClass also,
this is the directive, also only works as intended when using property binding.
So let's wrap it in square brackets too
and here we also need to pass a Javascript object and that's just the case for this property of this
directive here,
of course each property you bind to may take a different value, like disabled which took true or false.
So here it's a Javascript object and for ngClass object works like this.
We also have key-value pairs,
the keys are the CSS class names and the values are the conditions determining whether this class should
be attached or not.
So here, we have the online class,
you could also wrap this in single quotation marks
if you had a class name with a dash inside of it or something like this
and here,
well I want to attach this
only if the server is online, so only if serverStatus equals online, online
here is a string between single quotation marks.
Now of course you could also outsource this in a method, you call this serverStatus equal online check
but here I will write it inline.
So if this is online, we should attach the CSS class online to this paragraph
otherwise this should not get attached.
Let's view this in the running application,
both are offline so none of the two should have the online CSS class added to it
and indeed, I can't find the class on any of the two.
Now let's reload and hope that some of them is offline or online, excuse me, both are
so let's check it,
now we see the online class has been added,
actually to both of them because this is how ngClass works.
It only adds like CSS class if a certain condition is true
and that's an example for another built-in directive, another built-in attribute directive.