In the last lecture, we added routing, we set up our routes for this application and we can load them
but the links are not working as expected, so we should fix this. With our main routes set up,
we can go to the header component and here I want to change the way we navigate.
I no longer need the click listeners here
and also I don't need ref elements, so we should remove that so that our app doesn't reload because right
now if you click the links, it will simply send a request to the server and reload the page.
So I'll remove that and I can also remove the onSelect method here and remove the eventEmitter, the header
component,
so basically all that code, also the imports and now we can simply use routerLink
and here I want to create an absolute link to /recipes and for the shopping list, here I will
create an absolute link to /shopping-list.
And of course you could also use that alternative syntax taught in the last lectures, in the last course
section actually, where you would enclose routerLink into square brackets and then you would pass an array
between the double quotation marks here to configure the individual segments of your path.
But since here all I want is to go to these root routes, there is no need to do so
and that is the quickest way of setting up our paths here.
So with that, if we save this we should already see that navigation is working again and it is, that's
great
but I also want to mark the active route here.
So that's what I'll work on in the next lecture.