Back comeback last year we had a look at typing in this with you.
We'll have a look at classes which is another important thing typescript introduces the class.
You know I am aware that with the most recent charges from specifications we will be able to use the
Klasky word pure javascript but we're also able to do it in time.
And the benefit here is it automatically compiles down into well old shuttlers script which is well
readable or usable by all browsers.
So here in my class all types that file which are prepared I'm creating such a class that this might
look a bit complex but that's really only because I added a lot of stuff into the class.
Let's start at the basics.
We're creating a class by using the class keyword followed by the name.
And then this is the body of our class describing class.
Now I'm not going into object oriented programming here in all that.
Sure.
Look it up if you're interested in this but the class basically will be like a plu print of an object
you can create later based on this class and we'll see this in this file.
So here we what you're creating such a class.
Now I'm creating a such object excuse me Basin's class for creating such a car object.
I do this by using the new keyword and the new car creates will and you car object based on this car
blueprint.
So each object will have these methods here these properties and so on.
I'm also passing an argument into this constructor here because I set up my constructor to get in one
argument the speed of the car here.
Will this speech be a number and inside the constructor.
Well assigning the speed I pass in or zero if it somehow is invalid to just private speech property
.
So as you can see MRV this property this field here as private it's only accessible from within this
class.
Javascript does not know this.
It does no private class members but your typescript.
The compiler would not allow us or would yell at us if we tried x a private member from outside of this
class.
So here are passing the initial speed in the constructor and setting it to my private property of this
Then I got two methods accelerator throttle or free methods get speed will accelerate just cruising
speed or decrease it.
So always refer to my private property by the way.
These first two properties here.
Well they don't do anything.
I just added them to show up at public properties which are accessible from outside and private properties
which are well only accessible from inside the class.
They get speed.
Well it prints out our current speeds or protect a property and as a way we can kind of access this
private property from outside through a method which again then has access to this property estimate
lives inside this class.
But we also get the static method which means this method is callable without instantiating a new object
.
We're doing this year cons. long car number of wheels recognize that a capital C here.
So you're not calling we're not using the card or cheque.
I created I used car plus all it's all I can do this here for a number of wheels because it is marked
as static which means you don't have to have an instance of this object you don't need to have created
it.
You can access this method whenever you want because it provides a certain functionality that does not
depend on a specific instance but well that provides some general utility for example does how we use
classes in typescript course is classes in a nutshell if you want to put it like that but it's basically
all functional if you were going to use this course.
And if you want to learn more.
Again documentation is attached which will allow you to dive deeper into it.
CNN next with you on