There are of course many attribute directives and throughout this course, we will see different ones,
two we already learned about are ngClass and ngStyle.
Now just to quickly refresh how they work,
let's add a class to our CSS file here,
let's maybe name it odd
and here I simply want to set the color to red.
Now in my template, I want to assign this class if it is odd.
So here of course, I could always assign the class since we already made sure that this list item list
is only displayed if onlyOdd is checked.
Still, we could also use ngClass here, like this and make sure that we assign the odd CSS class,
therefore we define it here as a property name, only if the number we currently look at divided by two
with the modulo sign equals something else than zero,
so not equal to zero.
That means we have a remainder for this division which means it's odd.
Now we can copy this to the even list
and again, I know that this will never be odd here because we already make sure that this is only rendered
if we are not displaying odd items,
we don't have any odd items in the even numbers array.
So just to show how this works,
of course we have to check even here,
now you see even numbers are black, odd numbers are red.
Again, not super surprising but just a brief refresher on how ngClass worked and important, I mentioned it
before, the square brackets here indicate that we are binding to some property on our ngClass directive.
Now ngStyle was the other famous directive
we had a look at thus far,
ngStyle allows us to also pass an object to some property which is also named ngStyle on the same
directive
and here, we could simply set the backgroundColor and we could set it to red like this.
Now it would always be red but of course, we can also set a dynamic value here, so we could simply
repeat our check from up here
if it's an odd number, in which case I want to give this let's say a backgroundColor of yellow,
otherwise it's transparent.
Now I'll quickly copy this over to our other list, here of course
I check if even is basically even and guess what, I think it will be.
And now the even number is, still no styling at all
and the odd numbers are really ugly now to be honest
but that means our directives here are working.
Now let's build our own ones because that is something we can do too,
let's start with our own attributes directives.