So in this section, we learn about how to read error messages and how to use the debugger with source
maps.
There is a third tool you can use when working with Angular apps,
it's called augury,
so you can simply google for this, Angular Augury.
If you click on this, you should get taken to the official webpage where you can click install which
should take you to the Chrome store
since this is a Chrome extension. Now I already added it,
you can add it by clicking up here on add to Chrome and once you added it, you can open it in your developer
tools,
maybe you need to open and close your developer tools to see it and then pick augury here. Now
Augury is a nice little tool which allows you to analyze your Angular application.
So if we reload our app here, we see for example all our components and here we only have one and on this
component, you can jump into the state and see the properties of this component and also see the elements
of that
and for more complex applications, you can have a look at the injector graph and injection is something
we will cover in one of the later modules but basically which will allow you to see dependencies between
your components and your services in your app,
again this will be taught in a later module. When we come to routing, you can also have a look at your
routes here and how they work together.
You can check your NgModules like the app module, what it imports, what it declares, what it offers
you.
So that is a nice little tool to understand your app at runtime, to see the app dependencies and jump
right into them and to be able to analyze them.
So with these tools, reading the error messages, using source maps to easily debug and using augury
to understand the application and your dependencies, you've got a lot of great tools which should really
help you debug your applications and create great Angular applications therefore.