We covered a lot about the reactive approach,
there is one other nice feature I want to show you though. Let's add a new area to our form, maybe below
the radio buttons here,
here I want to add a new div and in this div, I want to allow the user to dynamically add form controls.
Let's say I want to allow the user to add his hobbies, so your hobbies, something like that, then I'll add a
button with some Bootstrap classes button and then maybe btn-default.
Make it of type button, that's important so that this button doesn't accidentally submit the whole form
and here I'll say add hobby.
Now when the user clicks the button, I want to dynamically add a control to my form here and that's actually
super simple to do,
specifically I want to add this control to an array of controls because I might have multiple hobbies.
So I'll add a click listener here, onAddHobby seems like an appropriate name for this
method here
and in there again, I want to add controls. So I'll add the method
in my TypeScript code,
onAddHobby like this
and now I need to add a new control, type of control to my overall form.
I'll name it hobbies because that is what I'll store in there in the end
and as I said, this should be an array because it could be no hobbies or 10 or 100.
So the type here is not FormControl and it is not FormGroup,
instead it's a FormArray,
make sure to import this from @angular/forms as well.
Now a FormArray of course holds an array of controls, so you pass an array here to initialize it. In this array,
you could already initialize some form controls with new FormControl or like I am doing it here,
you leave it empty to not have any hobbies at the beginning.
Now when we click onAddHobby, I want to add a new hobby to that array.
So here, I need to access my form,
now I want to get access to my hobbies array and I can do this by getting hobbies,
it is a control in my overall form in the end
and now I need to tell TypeScript that this is of type FormArray to not get an error,
you rarely have to do this but here we have to explicitly cast this. So by placing a lower than sign,
then FormArray, so the type and then a greater than sign and then placing this in parentheses, we're
telling TypeScript
this part here actually is a FormArray, so everything enclosed in these outer parentheses now is treated
as FormArray,
so now I can push a new control on this array, if we would have not casted this, we would get an error. So
now we can push a new FormControl there but I will outsource this to keep this line short,
so here the control is created and stored in a constant, formControl and the hobby,
well that should be something the user can now enter, so we'll actually create it with no default value.
Of course you could also change this behaviour to pass an argument to onAddHobby and then pre-populate it
with this value.
I want to add a validator though, so this still works because I'm creating a normal FormControl here,
so the required validator seems appropriate because the hobby input should not be empty
and now I can push this control on my array of controls.
With this, we are creating this, we are able to add controls but we won't see it,
we need to synchronize it with our HTML code.
Therefore on this outer div here, I'll add a directive, formArrayName.
So again you see the pattern, we had formControlName to tell Angular that we want to connect the input
to a FormControl,
we had formGroupName to do the same for FormGroup and now we have formArrayName to do the
same for an array.
So formArrayName and the name was hobbies, the name we chose in our TypeScript object, this tells
Angular that somewhere in this div, our array will live. Now we can use this array here,
so I will create a new div with the ID FormGroup for some Bootstrap styling
and here I simply want to have an input which allows the user to enter the actual hobby.
So this type text is all right,
I now somehow need to loop through all the controls which are in this array.
So on my FormGroup here, I will actually add an ngFor loop to loop through all my hobby controls,
so in my sign-up form, that would be my hobbies which I can get like this and there, the controls. With
that, I can loop through all of them and I also want to extract the index of the current iteration,
I will need this to assign this input to one of these dynamically created controls because on this input,
I of course want to add the form-controls CSS class
but besides this, very important, I need to add formControlName because we still need to synchronize
this input with the dynamically created input.
Now this dynamically created input will not have a name chosen by us but it is an array,
so the name will simply be the index in this array, which is why I'm retrieving it here. So I can simply
bind formControlName and now I will need property binding because I'm now not passing a string,
I'm instead passing this local variable I'm creating here, i, to pass this index.
Let's save this and see if this works as expected.
If we have a look at our console, no errors, let's click Add Hobby and we indeed see a new input,
no errors
still. Let's check it,
it's invalid,
this looks good,
so if I enter a hobby here, now it becomes valid.
And now if I enter the rest here and go to the console and hit submit,
you will see that in the value of this form,
we actually now have hobbies which is an array where we have cooking
and of course, we could also add sports and this newly submitted form, you would now find that this
array of course holds cooking and sports.
So this is how you can use a FormArray with the reactive approach very easily.
It's all about synchronizing it in the end and about knowing that you have to explicitly cast it to make
this work.