In the last assignment, we created this solution with our log here where we could add items which get an
incrementing number and this number then determines whether we have a background color which is blue
or this white text CSS class attached to it.
Now in the assignment, I said that it is one option to use an incrementing number in our log,
another option might be to use any other content,
for example a timestamp but it could be any other text.
So I'll first of all change this here in my app.component.ts file and I will no longer push this number,
instead I will use timestamp here which we can get with new date,
date is a built-in object
Javascript ships with,
so there is no need to add any import.
Now with that, we're pushing new timestamps on this array, we can demonstrate this with ng serve running
by simply clicking this button here
but now everything is blue of course because our check here now always returns true, because the string
and this is just a string as always, deemed as being greater than 5.
So our check doesn't work anymore,
we can add something to ngFor here too. Separate with a semicolon,
you can extract some extra information,
the current index or the index of the current iteration. With let, you can bind it to any variable
name of your choice like i or index, whatever you like, I will set it to i
and then you set equal to index.
Now equal to index kind of is also like a reserved expression you could say, it gives you access to the
index of the current iteration.
So in the first loop, this will be zero, in the second loop, so in the second element in this array, i will
be one and so on.
Now with this information, you can of course update your solution here to no longer check if logItem
is greater or equal than 5
but if i is greater or equal than 4 because remember, the index starts at zero.
So let's update both
checks like this and now with that, this should work with any content and not just with incrementing
numbers,
this looks pretty good.
So that's a tiny addition,
extracting the index of ngFor just like that. With that,
enough about the basics,
we got a lot of solid knowledge right now,
let's use it to set up our course project in the next section before we then dive deeper into components
and data binding.
Can't wait to see you there.