Obviously, this entire NgRx part was pretty extensive, was pretty much for authentication
but keep in mind that authentication also is pretty complex in this application because we manage the
token lifetime and so on.
Now it's basically all managed with NgRx. We were using effects for all the side effects like
HTTP requests and local storage and redirection,
we're using the reducer for our general state, like the authenticated user, if we have an error and if
we're loading and the auth component dispatches our different login or sign-up actions and takes advantage
of the error and the loading state. The auth service is used for managing our token timer then, we could
move that into @ngrx/effects somehow but we would need a lot of observable magic for this and
I think this is just a simpler and easy to understand approach. The auth interceptor and auth guard take
advantage of our @ngrx/store and therefore now whilst it was a lot of work, now the entire authentication
logic lives in NgRx. Again it was a lot of work but now whatever you add is added with relatively
little effort,
still of course, using this entire setup is optional.
Now what I want to do at this point is, I want to do some cleanup work here,
I want to look through my components and remove parts which I don't need anymore or not through my components
but at the auth component, remove the injected auth service in the router for example, remove that observable
import, the router import which I don't need anymore,
the auth service imports here, that should all be good.
Now in the auth service, I don't need the auth response data interface anymore. I can remove the user model
data therefore, the import, not the model itself
and overall, this is looking quite good.
Looks like the application is working correctly and now we are taking advantage of NgRx.
Let me login here, fetch recipes, that all is working, now all powered through NgRx. Of course, the recipes
area is missing but before we tackle that, let's look into two other packages the NgRx team gives
us.