Our application is taking shape or to be precise, it already has shape but we're moving more and more
of the logic into NgRx with the auth and the shopping list area finished, only the recipes remain and of
course we still have that data storage service
but let's focus on that and a second step,
first of all let's take a step back and let's work on our development experience a little bit.
Thus far, we had a look at NgRx where
we were using it but wouldn't it be nice if you could sometimes look into it and have a nice log of
the different actions that are being dispatched and which data they carry and how they change your global
application store?
Well you can have a look at this with a special development tool which you can install. For this, search
for Redux dev tools extension and you should find this Github repository here which is about the Redux
dev tools extension and NgRx is compatible with that and you can follow that link to find a page with
instructions on how to install it in Chrome or Firefox. So I'm using Chrome, so I will go to the Chrome
Web Store on the page of that package and I already have added it,
if you haven't, simply click the installation link which you should find here. Now that is basically all
you need to do then, you have installed that, you don't need to follow any other steps here, you just need
to go to the Chrome store and install it from there.
Once you have that installed, you can install a special package in your project with npm install and
now --save-dev because that will be a development only dependency and there,
this is
@ngrx/store-devtools.
Now let's restart ng serve and to use that part and use it together with the install extension,
you now have to go to the app module and there, after creating your store module, you now can register
a new module which is unsurprisingly imported from that newly added package.
So we just added @ngrx/store devtools, from that package,
you can install or you can import the store devtools module.
Now with that import added, add it in the imports of your app module, store devtools module like this
and call instrument on it.
Now instrument takes an object where you can configure this and there is one configuration which I want
to add and that is log only which I want to set to environment and environment is now getting imported
from our environments folder,
so there actually let me navigate there manually, one level up, then into the environments folder and
then the environment file, not from the environment.prod file but just from the environment file.
In there, in that environment file,
we have a production property in that constant, in that environment constant and that is false during
development but in the prod file, it is true
and as you learned, these two files are swapped automatically by the CLI
once you build for production. So this environment constant has this production property which is false
during development but true during production and therefore with log only,
we're basically restricting the output to only some log messages when we're in production.
With that added, you can save your application and now go back to it and maybe restart your browser after
the installation of that Chrome extension or of that Firefox extension and you should then find a Redux
element here in your browser developer tools and in there, that's pretty nice,
you now have a detailed log of what's happening in your application.
If I reload for example, we see which actions are getting dispatched here, we
see the auth auto login, dummy
and if you scroll up by the way, you see there are some initialization actions being dispatched as well
and you might recall that I mentioned these initialization actions earlier in this module,
this is important for your state getting initialized. So there, we see what was getting dispatched,
we see what the state looked like after that
dispatch, you see which action that was and you see more information about that action,
for example you can see more information once I do login,
now you see login start was dispatched,
this had a payload, that payload was the e-mail and password and we see that the state here was at this
point of time when it was dispatched, that the user was basically null
but then for login once this is done, the user, so excuse me, that's the state after this action has been
performed but for login start, the user obviously still was null but loading was true and after login,
the state was such that we had a user and loading was set back to false.
So here you can now really dive into the different steps that are being executed in your application
and you can learn more about what's going on,
you can simply play around with that and get an overview of which actions were dispatched and how they
affected the state, which state updates were made and so on and you can even go back in time and replay
your application at different points of time and simply play around with that a bit, to simulate different
states and most importantly, to get a feeling for what NgRx is doing behind the scenes.