So at the moment, in our application, we can fetch recipes but as soon as we try to visit one, we'll get
an error because we were failing to load the ingredients here
but the bigger problem is that we're failing to load the overall recipe details.
The reason for that is that if we have a look at our recipe detail component here, we are of
course still fetching our recipe here with get recipe from our recipe service but we now no longer load
our recipes into the recipe service,
we instead load them into NgRx because not here but because in a data storage service, we dispatched
the loaded recipes with set recipes and that of course uses NgRx. Hence the goal has to be that
we also fetch our recipes on the detail and then also on the edit component from our store
and for that we'll have to rewrite our logic there a little bit because at the moment, our logic is such
that we basically load our recipes or we loaded our recipes in the service, in the recipe service and
then we store them here in the recipes array in the service
so that we thereafter could simply access the recipes from that array with get recipes or get recipe.
That's not how NgRx works, there we always access the store and the data in it by using select
and we always get back an observable, so we have no synchronous call as we have it here to get back
a recipe,
we always get back an observable that might then give us a recipe depending on what we select. Even
if that happens almost instantly,
it's still technically an observable, so therefore we first of all will have to inject our store here
into the recipe-detail component and then we can see how we proceed regarding that.
So I'll inject my store imported from @ngrx/store,
we'll also need to get information about our App Store, our App Store structure by importing that information
from the root store file at the App Store folder and the app reducer file and then here we can assign
this generic fromApp.AppState type as we did it before.
OK, so now we know more about our store,
now here we have a problem. Getting route params already is done through an observable,
so now we want to add yet another observable to then take these route params and get our recipe.
Now the first way of how we could do this would be that we create a new observable chain inside of that
function we passed to subscribe of that outer chain where we select our recipes part of the store and
then we can use pipe here in this inner observable now, on this selection
observable to transform the data we're getting with map and for that, we need map from rxjs
operators and we need map because here we get our recipes state and what we really want in the end of
course is a single recipe for that given ID.
So here, we can then simply return recipes state recipes and here
as I said, I want a single recipe, we can use find for that and find takes a function where we get each
recipe but also the index of each recipe and we here want to find the recipe where the
index of the element we're currently looking at with that find method, where that index is equal to this
ID.
So this could be our logic for retrieving one recipe,
now here I'm just mapping this,
so now we can subscribe on that inner observable, so on that store selection
observable, at this point, we will get a single recipe and then we could say this recipe equals recipe.
So now we're taking advantage of this store observable, let's save this and let's see if it works, if
this reloads, first of all we now need to fetch data and then here, that looks good.
So this works, a more elegant way of handling this would be to convert this all into one big observable
chain even though you can also leave it like this and could use it like that
but if you wanted to convert it to one larger observable chain, then you would have to call pipe on that
params observable here and add a map operator as your first operator, here
you then get this params object which we previously got in subscribe,
we will change our subscribe logic soon and there,
I want to return plus params ID to get that ID and in the next step, we would add a switchMap
to switch our observable from the route params observable to the store observable. Here we would get the
ID and we would return this store select recipes in the end to kick off that store
observable for the recipes slice and thereafter, in yet another next step,
we would use map here.
So let's cut that and remove that pipe method therefore, we would add map as yet another step in this
main pipe here.
However he would get the recipe state but this ID is now not set at this point
here. To set it, we can set it here in the switchMap,
we can set this ID equal to ID because we're getting the ID here as an argument,
thanks to map.
Now this ID is available here and we can filter on our recipes state for that single recipe
and last but not least, now we have a subscribe function here
with one too many closing parentheses,
now we have a subscribe function here where we get our single recipe.
So now if we save that, we should have the same setup where we can now fetch recipes and still view the
details with this observable chain. The same approach or a relatively equal approach can be used on
the recipe edit page. There, we also load a recipe when we initialize the form
and this now also has to be done with the help of our store observable.
So just as on the detail page, let's start by injecting the store here,
import it from @ngrx/store of course
and let's also import everything as from app, from our store app reducer file to assign that generic
type here fromApp.AppState
and now down there where we previously selected our recipe like this, that won't work anymore,
instead here we now select the recipes on our store and
then again we can use pipe here and add the map operator which you still need to import from rxjs
operators of course and with the map operator added here,
we again get our recipe state at this point,
we're only interested in a single recipe though, hence in here we can return recipe state.recipes
and then find a single recipe
and then again here, we get a recipe in the index passed in automatically into this function we pass
to find and we want to return true if the index matches this.ID,
so the ID we extracted from the route params in ngOnInit since we do call init form inside of our
subscription here, this is finding
and we can rely on the ID being set at this point of time.
So now here, we basically return a single recipe, in the next step,
we can now use that recipe and therefore the next step is to subscribe,
we get our recipe here and now all that code that relies on the recipe, so all this code here, has to
be moved into the subscription because only in there our recipe is available.
Well let's give this a try,
let's fetch our data and let's try editing a recipe and
this looks quite good. Now changing this or saving changes won't work yet because we're not handing this
through
NgRx at this point but we can load the details which is looking pretty good.
Again of course, changing anything here will not have any effect because we're not using NgRx for service
right now.
Of course we have a problem
if I reload whilst I'm on such a detail page though, there we don't really load that data, so that
will be the next step that we can also reload these pages and that is simply related to our resolver
not working correctly.