When we fetch our recipes and I then load the details and we reload, you'll see that this doesn't work
and that is related to our recipes
resolver. This is responsible for actually triggering the fetch recipes call when we try to visit one
of these recipe detail pages.
We can check our routing file for that,
there you see that on the ID and the id/edit files, we normally use the resolver to resolve our data
but that simply fails here and hence we can't successfully load these pages because we're still using
the data storage service for fetching here. That is currently correct, we're also doing that from the header
component, there
if you take a look, we also use the data storage service and now the next goal will simply be that
we manage this through effects.
Now for that, let's go to our recipes effects file and let's export a class, RecipeEffects
and in that class, we need to inject something from @ngrx/effects
if you remember and that something is the actions observable.
So from @ngrx/effects, let's inject it here, again I will use actions with that dollar sign
but that is optional,
the type is actions.
Now with that added, we can add effects as properties in the recipes effects class here.
Let's start with the fetch recipes effect,
we need to add the @effect decorator which is also imported from @ngrx/effects and the value
we store here is this actions and then pipe
and now first of all we need to filter for a specific action that should trigger this effect.
For that, let's add such an action, that would be for example FETCH_RECIPES, you can name this however you
want and the identifier could be recipes, fetch recipes.
Let's export a class, FetchRecipes which implements action and on that class here, we only need the readonly
type because we need no extra payload for fetching recipes. So go back in the effects file,
now here I want to pipe ofType
which also needs to be imported from @ngrx/effects
and I'm looking for my actions,
so I import everything as recipes actions from recipes actions file and
I'm looking for my recipes actions fetch recipes action of course, when this action occurs, I want
to kick off this effect here.
So ofType is the first step in our pipe here,
the second step now is that we send our HTTP request to fetch the recipes. For that,
let's use a switchMap here imported from rxjs/operators.
We did the same in the auth section if you remember,
here for example and let's go to the data storage service where we have the logic for sending this request
and we can simply copy this code here for sending a GET request.
So let's first of all expect our fetch action data here, though we don't really need that so you could
also use an empty argument list here because we are not interested in any arguments, we're not getting
a payload from that action anyways
and now since I want to use the HttpClient here,
we need to inject this as well.
So HttpClient is injected from @angular/common/http and we also need the recipe
model here,
so import recipe from the recipe model file.
The URL here still should be correct and with that, we have logic to send that request but
let's see what else we're doing in the data storage service.
There, we're also mapping the response and that is of course something I want to do in the effect too. So
I'll just copy that map operator and of course therefore also import it here from rxjs/operators
and then in here, we still get our recipes, we map that, transform this as before and once we're done
with all of that, as before, the goal is to return a new action which will then be dispatched automatically.
We can use another map operator for this where we get our recipes and now what action should be returned
here?
Well that would of course be our set recipes action. So a new recipes action, set recipes object is required
and there we pass our recipes as a payload
and this again will then automatically be dispatched by @ngrx/effects.
Now for these effects to be considered, we need to register them in the app module, so there in the
effects module, we have to add the recipes effects and for that of course, an import has to be added here,
so import recipes effects from and now let's go to ./recipes/store/recipe.effects.
Am I not exporting it there? recipe effect, without an s,
so it's recipe effect which needs to be added here in the app module and with that, @ngrx/effects
will automatically load this effect
class here and set up all these observable listeners.
So with that, we have these listeners,
now we just have to dispatch fetch recipes to use them
and one additional note, I also need to add @injectable here to the recipe effects class which is imported
from @angular/core to make sure that things can be injected into this class.
So with that, let's dispatch fetch recipes and there are two places where this needs to be done,
the first place is the data storage service or to be precise, the place where we called the data storage
service in the past and that would be the header component. In there,
I already inject the store which is great,
so in onFetchData, we can go right ahead and use the store to dispatch our action.
All we need to do is import our recipe actions,
so import everything as recipe actions from recipes store recipes actions
and with that imported here, we dispatch new recipes, recipe action.fetch recipes, like this.
So let's give this a try
first before we work on the resolver. The app reloaded and if I click fetch data, that looks pretty good
to me.
Now this is handled through NgRx and not through our service anymore,
let's now work on the resolver and this is a bit more tricky. In the resolver, we also called fetch
recipes in the past.
The thing just is the resolver actually expects an observable as a return value here on the resolve
method and it waits for this observable to complete before it loads the route for which you added this resolver.
The problem is, when we dispatch an action, we don't get back an observable and therefore resolve would
instantly resolve and we would instantly load a route where the data is actually not there yet.
Now there are workarounds and I want to explore one workaround with you here.
First, we need to inject our store and we won't need the data storage service anymore, so let's inject
the store here instead,
import it from @ngrx/store of course
and let's also import everything as from app from our root app.reducer here so that we can inject this
and assign this generic type
and of course we also need actions, so let's import everything as recipes actions or recipe actions I think
I named them in a different file,
you can of course name them whatever you want from the recipes area, the store there and there, the recipe
actions file.
Now here instead of returning this fetch recipes call, I will call this store dispatch and now create
a new action based on my recipes actions for fetch recipes.
Now again, the thing is I can't return this because this does not yield an observable,
instead we want to wait for the effect that is triggered by that action to complete and there is a neat
little way of doing that.
Keep in mind that in recipe effects, in the end we filter for specific actions and then we run logic.
Now it turns out that you can use this filtering logic and this actions observable provided by NgRx
effects in any class, not just in such an effect class and also without the effect decorator. That just is
also required for @ngrx/effects to do other useful things for you, like automatic unsubscribing
and so on but we can also use these features in a different class
and here indeed in my resolver, I want to import actions and ofType from @ngrx/effects.
Now what does this allow me to do?
We can inject our actions here, just as we do it in the effects class and now here, we can return this
actions pipe ofType and now listen to a specific action to occur
to complete this observable basically or to trigger this observable and that specific action
I'm interested in is simply my set recipes action. When that is called, I know that recipes are there and
therefore this is the action
I want to listen for.
So here, I will use my recipes actions, set recipe action as a trigger.
Now we also need to add the take operator from rxjs/operators here to take only one value so
that we can complete and unsubscribe from the subscription, we have no ongoing subscription,
we're only interested in this event once and we're good
and now the resolver dispatches this but then also waits for recipes to be set. Now let's give this
a try,
if we now fetch our data, we go here to the ingredient page, that works and if I reload this page, I
still end up on /recipes.
Well let's fix this in a second,
first of all let me show you that our logic works though. If we use the Redux dev tools here, if I fetch
my data,
we see fetch recipes set recipes here. If I now click on the ingredients,
we see that trigger again.
So here's the first set when I manually loaded that and here is when I visit a detail page. So our
resolver kicks in and does its job, which is great,
we fetch the latest information,
however when I reload, we are redirected and that's actually not directly related to the resolver.