With the environment variables added, it's now time to build the project and you already saw the command
for that, it's ng build --prod and this builds the entire Angular application for production,
optimizes everything and gives you an output which you can deploy onto a static server.
Now again, let me highlight here that what this does is, it compiles your TypeScript code to Javascript,
that's one important step,
it also compiles all your templates to Javascript instructions so that in the end, only Javascript code
is generated, Javascript code that runs in the browser and contains all the logic for updating the DOM
in the way you defined it in your multiple components and all the logic you added in your application.
This is all done by the bundled up application which takes advantage of the Angular framework that of
course powers all of that.
Now after running ng build --prod, you get this dist folder and in there, you have a folder of your
project name and in that project name folder,
now you have bunch of assets that you might have included and you also got your main polyfill runtime
file and a couple of other files, the exact names will differ for you but you've got a couple of Javascript
files which essentially contain your Javascript code, your Angular app,
this is how it looks like in the optimized form, quite unreadable right
but that is in the end all the logic of the Angular framework and of your code and you will find some
elements here which you have stored in your template files. So you can definitely also search these files
for some snippets of your templates
but this is now the code, so everything in the project name folder, in the dist folder, all of that is
the code which you need to deploy.
It's the HTML file with a bunch of script imports as you can see and these script imports in the end
make up all your app that starts, it's all these Javascript files that make up your app and the styles.css
file which with some general styling, in this case with all the bootstrap styles.
So now, we just have to deploy this,
how does this work?
As I mentioned, you now need a static website hosts and of course there are many options for that.
You can google for a static website host to find many articles and examples, to learn where you can host
such a static website.
I particularly want to highlight AWS S3 which uses a special service of the AWS, so of the
Amazon Web Services, that allows you to host static websites, that is definitely worth a look.
You need an AWS account for that but thereafter, it's pretty straightforward to use, pretty powerful
and pretty popular
and I also want to point you at Firebase Hosting.
Now you don't need to have the rest of your back-end on Firebase to use that. It's a coincidence that
here in this course we used Firebase for the authentication and for the database because it was easy
to use and it is intended to be an all-in-one package
but even if you use your own back-end or if you use a totally different API, you can always use Firebase
hosting to host static websites
and indeed, it is what I want to use here because it's particularly easy to use. Now
here you can learn more about that in the official docs and you see how you can get started with Firebase
hosting.
You need the Firebase CLI for that which simply is a tool you have to install to automatically deploy
your Firebase application. For that,
you need to install the Firebase CLI first, for which you need NodeJS and NPM which we already got
because the Angular CLI needed that as well and therefore you can dive right in and run this command
to install the Firebase tools, which is you Firebase CLI in the end.
So here in a terminal, doesn't have to be your project terminal here, it could be any terminal or a command
prompt on your machine,
you simply run npm install -g firebase-tools, on Mac and Linux you probably need to add a sudo
in front of this to avoid permission errors and now what this will do is it will install the Firebase
CLI on your machine so that you can use it in every project, not just in this project, to deploy the
application. So with that all run, you next have to run Firebase login, to log into your Firebase account.
Now I already am logged in here,
if you are and you will be prompted for an e-mail and password combination for your Firebase account,
so you need a Firebase account for that.
If you followed through that course, you probably already have one or a Google account to be precise,
if you followed through the course you already have one because we used Firebase already,
otherwise you have to create one or simply look into one of the other static hosts you can use,
you'll find deployment instructions in the official docs of every host of course.
So here, we'll continue with Firebase,
we logged in and the next step then is to run Firebase init to connect this project here with one of
your Firebase projects
and for that, you now should be in your Angular project folder,
so cd into it
if you're not using the terminal built into your IDE. Firebase init now asks you what you want
to use,
so which Firebase feature you want to use
because you could use the Firebase CLI for other things too, not just for hosting but I'm only interested
in hosting,
so let's take that. Side note, we are of course using the database here as well but we're not using it
through Firebase SDK, so we don't need to add that, as you see it works without the CLI. For hosting however,
we need the CLI, so tick hosting here by hitting space next to it and then hit enter.
Now you need to choose a project to which you want to connect and for me, that's this project,
simply choose the project you created for the recipe book.
So here we need a Firebase project for the hosting,
if you haven't created one yet, you need to create one now, though of course the question then is where
did you store your recipes?
But let's now choose this project.
Now you are asked what your public directory is and here you should not use the default which would
be public but the public directory simply is the directory that contains all your files that you want
to deploy and in our case, that's in a dist folder,
this ng-complete-guide-update folder in my case or whatever this folder name is in your case.
So here, we want to use dist/ng-complete-guide-update or whatever folder name you have in the
dist folder, so your project name essentially.
Now you're asked whether you want to configure this as a single page app and you should definitely choose
y
for yes here to ensure that all requests that you sent to that back-end are always redirected
to index.html because that is a common gotcha indeed,
you need to have a server configured such that it always serves the index.html, no matter which
URL
you entered into the browser and the reason for that is that by default, the server always handles an incoming
request first and if it's a URL that's unknown to the server, you would normally get an error.
Of course we have the Angular router handling our different routes but that, always keep in mind, runs
on the client,
so in the browser and that only gets a chance to run if the server serves your app.
So any requests have to reach the server first,
there they are all redirected to index.html, which in the end is our starting point for the single
page application and since any request, no matter which URL you entered reaches that page, that
HTML page,
now the Angular app can take over for any incoming request with any URL on your server and can then
use the Angular router to load the correct content in your Angular app,
that's why this redirection is important,
so choose y for yes here.
Now the existing HTML file should not be overwritten, so choose no here
and with that, you're done
and the next and last step then is that you run Firebase deploy and this will now deploy the content
of this folder onto Firebase.
Now this can take a couple of seconds, so let's wait for this to finish
and once it is done, it should give you a URL where you can find your application.
So let's grab that URL and enter it in the browser and there, you should be on your application
that should work just the way it worked locally but now on a real server. And we're still interacting
with our back-end API and everything but now, this is our deployed application.