In the last lecture, we created our service and I told you to not instantiate it on your own.
I told you that Angular offers some great tool which will give us access to our services,
it's Angular's dependency injector.
What is a dependency injector?
Well a dependency is something a class of ours will depend on,
for example the new account component depends on the loggingService because we want to call a method
in that service and the dependency injector simply injects this dependency, injects an instance of this
class into our component automatically.
All we need to do is we need to inform Angular that we require such an instance.
So how do we inform Angular that we require such an instance? We add a constructor to the class, to the component
in this case where we want to use our service.
So there, I can bind it to a property by using this TypeScript shortcut of adding an accessor in front
of the name, of the argument to instantly create a property with the same name and bind the value to
it.
So here, I will name this loggingService,
this name is totally up to you.
Now this is the important part here though, add a type assignment here,
this is not optional.
You need to set the type and the type has to be the class you want to get injected,
loggingService in this case, make sure to also add the import at the top.
Now let me close the body of this constructor and this simple task here informs Angular that we will
need an instance of this loggingService. Correctly
you might ask, well how do we inform Angular, why does this matter if we write this in the constructor?
Think about who gives us the instance of this account component, this new account component here.
This is a TypeScript class
in the end so somewhere, this needs to get instantiated so that something happens in our app.
Well who is responsible for creating our components?
Angular is of course because we are placing selectors in our templates and when Angular comes across
these selectors, it gives us instances of our components. Now since Angular is responsible for instantiating
our components, Angular will need to construct them correctly.
So if we define in the constructor that we require some argument, Angular will recognize this and now
it tries to give us that argument, it tries to give us this type in this case. So it knows
we want an instance of the loggingService class because we defined a type,
this is why this is important.
Now that is almost enough but not quite,
now Angular knows what we want but it doesn't know how to give us such an instance.
We need to do one additional step,
we need to provide a service. Provide simply means we tell Angular how to create it
and that sounds very complicated and it is very simple,
all we have to do is add one extra property to the @component decorator,
the providers property here. This also takes an array like other properties we added before
and here we again just have to specify the type of what we want to be able to get provided you could
say, so loggingService again.
Now with that, Angular when analyzing the component, recognizes that it should be able to give us such
a loggingService and it will set itself up to be able to do so
and when it then actually builds the component, constructs it, it sees that we want to have such an instance
and it will know how to give us such an instance
and now we can simply in our component, anywhere in this component, access our loggingService property which
is created automatically since I use this TypeScript shortcut here and call log status change.
So now I'm not creating that instance manually, Angular does it for us
and why is this better than creating it manually?
You will see some other advantages later
but this basically let's you stay in the Angular ecosystem and Angular knows how your app works.
Again, some other advantages will come up later.
So with this, we now have the same code as before,
so if we have a look at our application again and create a new account, we still see the log here depending
on which status we chose here,
so this still works but now, we're injecting the service.
Now let's also do the same by copying that in the account component here.
So here, I'll also add the constructor
and of course here we also need to add the import because TypeScript needs to know where
this loggingService comes from, not Angular, TypeScript
and I will also add a provider of course because for this component too, I need to inform Angular how to create
this loggingService.
So if we do this and then go back to the application here, reload, create a new service again,
this works,
now let's change the status
and this also still works.
Now of course because I didn't replace this here, so let's call the loggingService now,
and call log status change and pass the status.
Now if we save this and try to change this, it still works.
So now we get this same logging functionality outsourced, centralized in a service and therefore, our
code here is a bit leaner and I guess you can imagine how in bigger applications, where you have duplicate
code, a service can really help you to get more dry,
to don't repeat yourself all the time but instead to really cleverly outsource your code into a service
and have it there.