I went to bed.
So when I look at typing classes and just with you I will introduce two more concepts interfaces and
generics.
Now you might know them from other programming languages and they were basically in the same way.
So here let's start with interfaces.
My interface folder here.
And as you can see here at the beginning I'm defining such interface now an interface is like a contract
.
I'm saying what ever implements this user interface whatever option for example needs to have a username
and password and optionally it may have a code for a password property but by adding questionmark here
I'm saying this is not required.
You may implement this interface successfully without providing this code from past property but the
first two properties here have to be provided.
Now why would you search your faces in phrases allow us to create a secure form of communication between
several options.
So to say because we know that a certain object implements a certain method or property we can safely
access this magical property in the schools.
We will see this for example when using the all in and interface which was introduced by anguage you
by doing this we can again safely tell our objects that they can safely access certain properties or
methods can also use it too well to get our own type without creating a class for it.
Maybe we don't need it.
Class We don't want to instantiate it but we want to make sure that we will create our own type blueprint
.
For example here and creating this user with a username and password as required fields and a confirmed
password as an optional field then I'm creating a variable here and I'm assigning this user tied to
it or a custom type we create here with this interface.
So know that whatever I'm assigning as a value to this user variable it has to be an object which contains
at least username and password and might contain password.
So here my sign is that you object and this does not prove the error because I have a user name I have
a password and I will not confirm password which is OK because it is optional.
Let me come in and that out and try to add this value.
A number of checked with anything and any number.
So our fields then username and password.
I don't have a username password here but I require them for my interface.
So this is not a valid user type here and therefore we can always get this error.
And if I try to compile these apps I'm in the wrong order.
Let me jump into this.
So if I try to compile interfaces you can see I get an error because well basically it says this is
not implementing the interface you specified here.
So I'm going to comment that out again.
Now this is valid again.
And then down here I get a numbered interface which is called can drive and which says what ever implements
can drive should have a method called accelerate which will take speed or number as an argument and
does not return anything.
So you're just grabbing a function method and how it should look like when implementing this can drive
interface.
So here my car which uses as a can drive interface which type can drive as well and you charge the object
created with this little notation and it is valid because well I have this accelerate method here with
which is a function which takes a number and does not return anything in its body.
OK so this is how we create interfaces and how we use them.
And I hope it's clear why we used to do this from time to time throughout this course and with this
you should be able to understand what we're doing.
Now here's an interesting question what do you think happens if I compiled this file which is valid
in this state.
How would our child script file look like.
Well a lot cleaner than you might expect.
Indeed it's just a user variable and well it is a scientists value.
But all this interface stuff is gone because Javascript has no equivalent for interfaces and this is
kind of related typewritten right.
If we don't have typing and Javascript does not have that it tell me to assign mechanical side types
there are Windows interfaces because we've got no way of telling that this variable Shippey of type
this interface anyway.
Therefore this is purely for typescript.
But you will be able to check if all code is followed up with compilation but it does not compile because
there is no equivalent.
That's interface.
Next that you will have a look at generics there by