In the last lecture, we added navigation and we are now able to switch between our pages here,
that's great.
Now I want to mark the active route and actually Bootstrap, the CSS framework we're using gives us a
class to mark the active route. If we add this class to the list item which holds the link,
it's the active class there,
if we save this, now this is marked as active.
Of course it doesn't change because I hardcoded it into there but this is the class we dynamically
need to add.
Well and you learned how to do this,
we got a helpful directive for this,
the routerLinkActive directive.
Here we simply define the class we want to conditionally attach to this element
whenever the link on this element or nested inside of it, like it's the case here, gets active.
So here, that would be the active class as we just saw
and the same of course for shopping list,
so routerLinkActive should also be placed on this one
and with this you see it's still active but now it switches because now this CSS class gets applied
to the correct route.
So that's now working,
with that let's make sure that when I click a recipe here, we don't actually reload the app as we do
now if you watch this reload icon next to the browser URL bar, that happens because we have this ref
element on it.
So we will fix this and then think about the next steps of our app.