I'm in a brand new project created with the CLI and the only thing I did thus far is I cleaned up
the app component, remove this property we had there and cleaned up the app.component.html file. All
the rest is still the same,
I didn't change anything else,
so the first thing I want to do and you can of course recreate this project by simply running ng new,
any project name you like and then cleaning it up like I did. The first thing I want to do is I want
to add the Bootstrap CSS framework so that we have some CSS classes we can work with to give this
some nice styling because in this app, I really want to focus on Angular and not on the styling.
So of course, we can add Bootstrap with npm inside this project folder, in the terminal, I type npm install
then --save as it will be a production dependency Bootstrap and this will automatically install
the latest version of Bootstrap in this project.
Now once it is finished, we get Bootstrap installed,
now we also need to inform the CLI that Bootstrap should be included in our final bundle it creates
for us because of course, the CLI bundles all our script files and style files and by default, it would
not include Bootstrap. So to inform the CLI, we should go to the .angular-cli.json file and here
in styles, in this styles array, we can add any global stylesheets we want to add to our whole project.
Now it already has the styles.css file which is a file where you can find styles for the whole
project,
here I will simply add the path to our Bootstrap styles.
Now we can have a look where that is stored. In a node modules folder which manages all our dependencies,
if we have a look at the Bootstrap folder there, the dist folder sounds about right for distribution,
there we have a CSS folder
and here the bootstrap.css file is probably what we need. So we can quickly import this here by
adding a path to that
and now the important thing is we need to go up one level first because you don't have to see this path
relative from the cli.json file here,
so this config file we're in but you have to see it relative from your index.html file
and that is in the source folder,
so it's nested one folder deep into your app you could say.
So here we target node modules and then we can target the Bootstrap folder
and now again just to make this really clear where this is coming from, in the Bootstrap folder, we can
target dist/css so let's do this, dist/css and here, bootstrap.css, just like that.
To be precise, it would even be better to target the minified version which is a file also lying in that
folder,
so let's add .min between bootstrap and .css, so this will already give us the minified code
which is of course smaller.
Now with that, this should be added and now we can run ng serve to get our CLI to build this project
for the first time and serve it at localhost:4200 as we did before in this course
and that is our running application.
Now we don't see very much here, of course because our app.component.html file is completely empty,
we can quickly check if Bootstrap styles were added successfully by adding a div for the class container
and the shortcut I'm using here is a plugin called emmet which allows me to just type dot claas name
and hit tab to autocomplete it.
It's available for many IDEs, so I'll simply Google for plus your IDE or editor and chances are you will
find it
and then in there I want to nest a row
and now let's say simply to get started, a column for medium-sized devices which spans the full width
for now
and I simply want to output in a h2 tab
I'm working.
So with this, if we save thatm it should recompile and now we're seeing I'm working,
this looks like Bootstrap is working too,  we can see those on the font size
and also if we inspect this here in the styles, all these styles here and down there
are coming from Bootstrap.
So this is working
and with that, we get our application set up.
Now let's get started creating all the components we require.