Now I guess it makes sense to start with saving recipes because it's hard to fetch them if we never
save them
and for that, I will add a new method here to the data storage service which I'll name store recipes.
Now of course, you can name this method however you want
and now here, we get two possible routes we could take. We could accept the recipes we want to store here
as an argument, by importing our recipe module up here and then defining that
this should be of type recipe array and then here, we could just write the HTTP request where we
want to store these recipes on the back-end by sending some meaningful request to some URL.
Now we could do that, we could also inject the recipes service into our data storage service, that
would be the other way and then we could directly get our currently loaded recipes from that recipe
service and we avoid this extra argument and that is what I will do indeed.
So I will inject another service here, the recipes service which is of type recipe service, let's
name it recipe service here too. You need to add that import to the recipe service of course and now
with that injected, I get my recipes by reaching out to this recipe service and by simply getting the
recipes with get recipes.
So this retrieves our list of recipes which are now temporarily stored in that constant, therefore we
can remove that model import up there, we don't need it because we're not using the type
and now with the recipes loaded here in store recipes, we can make our HTTP request.
So here we can now use the Angular HttpClient
and now we could definitely make a post request if we would want to add one recipe but I want to store
all my recipes and I essentially want to overwrite any previous recipes I stored and for that, Firebase
gives us an endpoint which we read by using a put request and again, that strongly depends on the API
you were using on the back-end, here Firebase works such that we can send a put request to a specific
URL to overwrite all the data that is stored under that node, your back-end might work differently
if you're creating your own back-end, it might be working differently, it's always depending on the API
you're working with but Firebase works such that if we send the put request to a URL, any data that's
in there will be overwritten.
So let me copy that here, that URL and
let's add it here,
that's the URL I want to send this to, though that's not the entire URL,
instead it should be sent to /recipes.json. The .json is a Firebase characteristic,
you need to add this at the end of the URL, it has nothing to do with the data you are sending or with
Angular and /recipes, that's just how the Firebase real-time database works, it gives us a
REST API where we in the end define our own nodes, which will then be translated to folders you could say
where the data will be stored in. So now we're sending a put request there but a put request, just like
a post request, needs data to work, we need to tell Angular what to put on this URL so to say or
what to attach to this request and that will be our recipes here of course, I guess that makes sense.
Now as you learned, this alone will not send the HTTP request, instead that request will only be sent as
soon as we subscribe. Now we got two routes we could take here, we can return our observable here by
adding the return keyword and then we can subscribe in the component where we're calling store recipes.
Now in our case here, that will be the header component because that is where our buttons are and in the end,
I'm not interested in subscribing in that component because I don't want to show a loading spinner, though
of course you could do that but here I just don't want to and therefore, there is no need for me to subscribe
in the component because the component in this scenario will not be interested in whether that request
is done or not. If that's different in your application, obviously you can use the pattern I also showed
you in the last section where you do subscribe in the component that triggered that request or that
method.
So here instead, I will subscribe directly in the service because I have no interest in the response
in my component and I will get back a response here and we can console log that to have a look at
it, I will not do much else with it though here. Now with that, we just need to make sure that the store
recipes method is getting called and as I mentioned, that will happen from inside the header component.
There we have that save data button, let's add a click listener here and maybe call onSaveData or whatever
you want to call that method here and then let's add that method to the header component and in here,
we now have to call our newly added save recipes method in this data storage service. And for that of
course, we need to inject our data storage service here by using its type, make sure you import that type
from your file, from your data storage service file in the shared folder
and now with it
injected, in onSaveData,
we can use the data storage service and call store recipes and that should already be all.
Now let's go back to our application which should have reloaded and let's click manage, save data.
Here I'm getting back a response, that looks promising,
so basically Firebase in this case returns the data we did store. More interesting,
let's have a look at Firebase and there indeed, we see a new recipes node and in there, we have these
recipes.
Now if you watched the previous module which you absolutely should,
you saw that there Firebase created some cryptic keys for these recipes.
It always does that when you post data, when you attach one data piece at a time.
If you put data, it assumes that you know what you're putting there and therefore if you wanted IDs
here for these recipes, you would have to generate and add them on your own
but here, I'm fine with the normal array indexes here which I have, which will be all we need. That is
looking good,
our data is getting stored, including the ingredients as you can tell
and with that, we finished the part where we store data.
Now let's make sure we can also fetch data.