In the last lecture, we used our recipe service and we create it in the first place, we filled it with some life
to manage our recipes in a central place. That is working great,
now let's use that service to improve our app.
Remember, we have this long chain of inputs and outputs getting a selected item from the recipe item
component
over the recipe list component to the recipes component, here
where we listen to that event and then all the way down using the selected recipe property to the recipe
detail component, so this cross-component communication. That is a super long way for just informing
another component that we selected an item but we can do better and we should.
So what my goal is that in the recipe item component where we have is onSelected click, that here
we can directly inform the recipe detail component.
So in onClick
what I actually want to do here is, I want to not emit an event here,
I will get rid of it here and therefore I can remove the imports from, of output an event emitter,
instead here I want to call some method in my service which will then transfer this data for
me.
So in the recipe service, I'll add a new property, the public property which will name recipe selected, of course
you could choose a different name, it will be an object instantiated by using event emitter from @angular/core,
so you need to add this import,
let's put it at the top of that file,
that's kind of a good practice to do with your Angular imports.
It will hold some recipe data and that's all I want to do in the recipe service.
With this set up and of course you could also encapsulate this by providing a method to get access to
it and want to emit the event
but I will use the property itself. So by adding this, I can now go back to my recipe item component and
in onSelected, I want to do something with that property in the recipe service.
So first of all, let's inject it, let's inject the recipe service as you learned to do it,
make sure to import it, point it to the recipe service file on the right folder and then on the recipe
service,
we can use this recipe selected event emitter and call emit and emit the recipe of this recipe item
component because that is the one we selected and that's the data we want to pass.
Now with this trick or with this approach, we can go to the recipe list component and remove this listener
where we listened to whether we did select it or not,
we can get rid of the onRecipeSelected code and get rid of our own emitted event here, so we're already
saving a lot of code,
get rid of all these imports which we don't need anymore and in the recipes.component.html file,
we can also get rid of this event here
on the recipe list because we no longer use this chain of data to pass it around
and now all I want to do is in this component here, I want to listen to this event in the recipe service
so that I can now correctly decide whether we do have a selected recipe and should therefore render
the detail component
or if we should still show this template with this please select a recipe text.
Therefore, I will inject the service here to recipe service and since I provide the recipe service on
this component, this component and all the other components in this recipe folder use the same instance
of the service
which of course is super important,
otherwise the service where I emit the event would be a different one to the one I listened to it,
so I would never get informed about the event but here it will work because we're using the same instance.
So here in ngOnInit for example, I can set up my listener, so on the recipe selected, I can subscribe
to it and get informed about any changes.
And now here, I know I will receive some data which is of type recipe because that's how we configure
the event emitter,
it would give us a recipe and in this ES6 arrow function here,
that is the argument list and here is the function body,
here I simply want to set this selected recipe equal to the recipe we got with the event. And with that,
we should get the same behavior as before if we reload the app
but now, having a much leaner approach of using a service for cross-component communication which of course
makes it much easier to pass this data
as you saw and we don't have to build this complex chain of events and property binding.