In the last lecture, we parameterised our first pipe here, the date pipe.
Now let's learn more about all the built-in pipes and how we can configure them. The place to learn more
is the official documentation,
so you can just head to angular.io and there under docs,
click on API reference.
Now you may ignore the version number up here, it should be 4.something at the point of time you
view the video,
I'm just recording this in advance
but the pipes won't change or haven't changed.
So here, you can enter pipe as a filter and then you view all the pipes which are built into Angular
and there you see we get a couple of them,
we already use the date pipe and the uppercase pipe but
there also is a slice pipe which allows you to take a slice of the input and there you would see that
the slice pipe actually takes multiple arguments, the start and the end, so where it should start slicing
out a piece of the word and where it should end.
There you can also give you a detailed explanation and an example,
so this is really a great place to dive into pipes and play around with them since there is not much
sense in covering them all in detail here
video by video as they are very specific in the use case and the documentation here is really great
for diving deeper into it.
So with that out of the way, I want to have a look at the date pipe. Here
you can see how you can configure it,
you can see a couple of different shortcuts for getting a specific date format
or you can format it from scratch with the typical symbols like a lowercase D for a day and so on.
So this is where you can dive into how to make the date look exactly how you want it to look.
Now with that, let's move on to creating our own pipe or almost move to that point
one other thing and then we'll move on.