With all these changes made, we can now also get rid of the recipe service here and that means that in
the core
module, we no longer need and can't provide it, so we can clean that up
as well and I'm getting an error about my recipe detail component. The recipe detail components still
imports it and still injects it and still uses it here in on
add to shopping list and that is now the remaining thing where I don't want to use the recipe service
anymore because I deleted it anyways. Instead here the idea is now to import my shopping list actions
as shopping list actions from and now I go to the shopping list area of this application, to the store
there and then to the shopping list actions file because there, we do have an action for adding all ingredients,
right.
So in here, we can now use the store dispatch and dispatch a new shopping list action and that would be
the add ingredients action which takes the ingredients as a payload and that would be the this recipe
ingredients data which I want to add
and with that, we fixed that. Now in the recipe-edit component, there I'm also still importing the recipe
service because I am still injecting it but we don't need it there anymore,
so here we can just remove it.
With that, everything compiled successfully and if we reload, that looks good, let's try adding these items
to the shopping list, this also works
and now we did some cleanup work and we're entirely in the NgRx world.