This was a super large module and we had a thorough look at NgRx.
Now as you can tell, NgRx can be complex, setting it up can be quite a lot of work
but as you hopefully also saw, as soon as it's set up, adding more actions, handling them with effects and
so on is really streamlined and you have a clear plan on how you handle things. Asynchronous code and
any side effects in the effects file, state changes in the reducer file and you hopefully also see how
all these pieces come together and give you one global store in your application that you can use anywhere
to access any data and dispatch any event.
Now again, if you prefer services and subjects, that is absolutely fine, you don't have to use NgRx if
you don't want to but it can be a decent alternative to services and subjects in bigger applications,
the bigger your app grows and the more people are working on it, a streamlined approach like this can
be really helpful.
Now I also want to point you at ngrx.io which is the official webpage of the NgRx project
and there in the documentation, you can learn way more about NgRx and also about advanced features
of NgRx because we actually only scratched the surface here.
Also search for Github NgRx and check out that ngrx/platform repository and in there, you'll
find a projects folder with example apps and this example app here combines a lot of the advanced and
best practice features and patterns you can for NgRx, so checking out this application also
is a right next step if you want to learn more about NgRx. And with that, you've got all the tools
to build powerful Angular applications, either with services and subjects or with NgRx for a streamlined,
highly structured state management solution.