Well now did we understood how these tests are generally written.
Let's see them in action in the terminal run energy task.
Inside this project folder to run our tests fruity Seelye which again already has this test runner and
so on built in.
Now what this will do is it will start up the testing environment and we can ignore these warnings.
It starts up Carmer.
And here we see that it executed three of three tests successfully because we have three tests here
.
Now let's change something to see a test fail.
If we go to the app component and change app works to app works without the second piece.
So just with one p then D test where we check that it contains app works as well as this test here should
fail.
So if we save this is here which automatically rerun and now we see two failed tests and now we can
simply inspect our log here and it might be a bit hard to read.
But basically here is see expected Apteryx to equal appliques.
So this is a problem when it failed and the same A-star true down there because both times we're missing
the test that we don't have.
App works here in the template where we expected to contain Eberts with two.
But now it only has one.
So this is how we can then interpret these test results and find out what's going on.
And I'm going to fix this again to save it and rerun the tests automatically just takes a couple of
seconds and now we see they're all successful again.
So that's how we run the tests keep us running and how we then see failing as well as successful tests
.
Now with that running I can add some new things to this application too.
Well and Hans a little bit and dive deeper into testing.