In the last video, we had a look at the basic set up of our form,
now let's understand how Angular creates such a Javascript object representing our form in the template
driven approach.
The great thing is you don't have to do anything, well almost anything,
make sure that in your app module, you actually import the forms module, add it here to your imports array
and have the import at the top of this file. As the name implies,
this built-in module shipping with Angular includes a lot of forms related functionalities and it's
actually needed to get this template driven approach to work, to get this form creation by Angular to
work. Now by default in a CLI project, this should already be imported so it should work fine
but again, I'm just highlighting it because it's super important that you have this import, otherwise the following
steps will not work. With this imported, Angular will actually automatically create a form for you,
so a Javascript representations of the form when it detects a form element in HTML code, like it does
here.
So you can think of that form element serving as a selector for some Angular directive, which then creates
such a Javascript representation of the form for you.
Of course, you can't see that form representation as of now and it would be very empty because one thing
does not happen automatically, Angular will not automatically detect your inputs in this form
and the simple reason for this is that whilst you could argue that it should be able to scan your HTML
code and detect that you have an input here and here and that you have a select dropdown here, you
still might not want to add all these elements as controls to your form, so with control I'm referring
to what is in the Javascript object
and again not every input in your HTML code might be a control you want to have in your Javascript form.
Maybe you have a dropdown which values only changes something you view on the UI but the input
should not actually be part of what gets submitted,
maybe you use some third-party package which adds some custom form controls which are not labeled input,
which don't use input as a selector and then Angular would have no chance of detecting that this is a
control of your form.
So you still need to register controls manually,
you need to tell Angular hey within that form element, what should be an actual control of my form?
And this is what we're going to do
now, tell Angular how does our form look like,
which controls do we want to have? In the template driven approach,
this is super simple.
You simply pick the input which you want to add as a control, like this input here
and I'm just going to structure it a bit different to split it up over multiple lines to make it easier
to read and then you add ngModel, like this.
Now you might already know ngModel from the two-way binding, two-way data binding and it actually is
the same directive. In two-way data binding though,
you saw that we use that with square brackets and parentheses wrapped in ngModel.
Now we will have a look at this later again
but for now, let's add it without any parentheses, without any square brackets just like this.
This will be enough to tell Angular, hey this input is actually a control of my form, so ngModel in
the end is a directive made available in the forms module, something I mentioned earlier in the course
when we had a look at two-way data binding.
This is key to understand,
you can use it to get two-way data binding but it actually is part of a bigger module with more features
giving you full control over forms.
Now for this to work, for this to be recognized as a control in your form, we need to give Angular one other
piece of information, the name of this control.
Right now, it would see OK this input should be part of the Javascript object representation of this
form,
so whatever the user enters here as a value should be the value of this control, of what's
the name of that control.
We need to give that information to Angular and we do this by adding the normal HTML attribute, name. So
name is nothing Angular 2 specific, name is the default attribute
you can add to any HTML control.
Now here, the name might be username because that is what we can enter in this input
and with this, this control will be registered in this Javascript representation of the form.
Now I'll do the same for the email, restructure it so that it's easier to read, add ngModel and add
a name, like for example email here.
Well and the same is true for the select here which is just another type of HTML input.
Here we can also add ngModel and we can add a name, like secret because I'm asking for a secret question
here and with that, we registered all the controls,
of course we can't see that much though.
Well that is something we're going to have a look at in the next lecture when we see how we can submit
such a form and therefore, how we can see these key-value pairs representing what the user entered into
which input.