In the last lecture, we created our third basic directive and it's doing its job,
we learned how to create a selector, how to use that selector, like an attribute
in this case since we set up an attribute selector and how to register it in app module, we also learned how
to get access to the element the directive sits on.
This however is not the best way of changing that style because as you might recall from some earlier
lecture in this course, accessing elements directly like this is not a good practice,
you should use a different tool which I'll show you in a second because Angular actually is also able
to render your templates without a DOM and then these properties might not be available.
It could do this when using service workers, so basically some advanced use cases but nonetheless, it's
not a good practice to directly access your elements.
How should you access them then?
Well there is some other helper you can inject, it's the renderer. So let's do this
but actually let's not do it
in our BasicHighlightDirective,
let's create a new one and for this, I will create a new one with the generate command or just g as you
learned with the CLI and then directive or just d and then any name of your choice and I'll name this
better
highlight.
So this will give us a new file or two new files.
I can delete the testing file and we can also put this into its own folder of course,
it's not the default but let's do it here,
better-highlight,
you could also create a central shared or directives folder where you store all your directives. For
now just for demo purposes and to have a clear separation and make this easy to see, I'll put them into individual
folders. So better-highlight directive here, in the app module, I will need to adjust my path since I just
moved it to the
better-highlight folder, so make sure to point to the right path in the right file then. In there we get a selector,
appBetterHighlight,
now let's inject this better tool
I was referring to. It's the renderer which is of type Renderer2
and this needs to be imported from @angular/core.
Now with this injected, we can use it and I will use ngOnInit again
to still stick to this best practice of doing initialization work there.
Make sure to import ngOnInit or just onInit here from @angular/core
and now let's implement ngOnInit here
and there, I can now use the renderer.
I do this by calling the property which I created here, the private renderer and there we get a couple
of helper methods we can use to work with the DOM basically.
Now one important method I'm interested in here is the setStyle method,
this method allows us to, guess what? Set the style of some element.
Now the problem here is for that, we need to have the element for which we want to set the style
and of course in Angular,
there are different ways of getting such an element, here in the directive,
it's exceptionally simple.
We already saw how to get one in the basic directive, the BasicHighlightDirective,
we can simply inject the element reference. So I'll add another private property here or argument which
will automatically be bound to a private property I should say which I'll name elRef
and this will be of type element ref which we then also, as before, need to import here, element ref from
@angular/core.
Now with this import added here,
now I can use this element ref here by calling this elRef
and here I then want to access the native element and that's important,
we can't pass the reference itself,
we need to get access to the underlying element and pass this as a first argument here to setStyle.
Now setStyle takes a couple of other arguments, we defined which element we want to style,
now we have to define which style we want to set
and that would be the background color in our case. With the style property defined,
the third argument we pass to the setStyle method is the value we want assign for this property,
now we could set the background color here to blue. The fourth and final argument is a flags object,
here we can set a couple of flags for this style and this is optional,
I will leave it out here.
What you could set here are things like if you want to add an important tag, so this exclamation mark,
important notation for a style to override other styles or something like that.
Now this however does it for my cases here
and now if we save this with our better-highlight directive already added to app module, we can go
to the app component and add it here too.
I will simply duplicate this paragraph here and use appBetterHighlight here,
our new directive, again which is available through the selector since we also added it to the app module
and then here, I want to style this with a better directive.
Now if we save this and let it recompile and reload the browser, we already see the blue background here
behind this paragraph.
So our new directive here, the better directive is working and now we're using the renderer which is a
better approach of accessing the DOM.
Now why is it a better approach?
Angular is not limited to running in the browser here,
it for example also works with service workers
and these are environments where you might not have access to the DOM.
So if you try to change the DOM as you did here in basic highlight by directly accessing the native
element and the style of this element, you might get an error in some circumstances.
Now to be honest, in most circumstances you probably don't and you probably also know if your app is
going to run in the browser or not, still it is a better practice to use the renderer for DOM access
and to use the methods the renderer provides to access the DOM.
You can learn more about the renderer in an article after this lecture here if you are interested.
Just another note, I had to rerecord this part here because the renderer type here changed from RendererV2
to just Renderer2
as did some arguments you could pass to setStyle. Therefore in the other videos in this section,
you will see that this code looks slightly different, not by much though.
Don't get confused by this,
the code you see here is the code you should use and the code which will work, all the other code shown
in the section of course is not changed,
it's still the same,
it's only this renderer setStyle method and the renderer type which is now Renderer2 and not RendererV2
as you will see in the other videos.
With that, let's move on.