As mentioned at the end of the last lecture, the next goal is to implement child routing for our recipe
routes here, so that when we click a recipe here, we actually load it by adding let's say slash and then the
ID of that recipe in our recipes array here in the URL, so recipes 1 would load the first element
or recipes 0 actually, since we started 0 in the array and so on.
So that would be great if we could load our recipes like that and render them here then,
so with a child router again. And the same for new recipe and edit
but for that, we will need a new component,
let's implement this in a second step,
the first step should be to make these items clickable and load the detail component as a child route
here in a new router outlet probably. We will also need another new component then for the case that we
first visit our page,
in this case we should have a starting component which kind of says please select a recipe, something
we right now do by displaying this template here in our recipes component, here the ng-template
but that will then also be removed because all I want to have inside of this div with the col-md-7
class
here is our router outlet.
So again, this is a challenge for you,
try implementing this child routing or at least try to do this first steps of that.
Setting up the router, creating that component which basically says please select a recipe and then loading
either that component or the detail route, the detail component depending on whether we click the recipe
in the list or not.
Certainly a challenge but also something where you can practice a lot of the things we learned in the
last lectures. Starting in the next lecture,
we will do this together,
so then you can see my approach on implementing this.