Now attached, you find this project here. It's an Angular project which I opened here,
a very simple project where we have a form, a template driven form where we can enter a title, content
and then send that post here, like a very simple post in a simple block, to store it on Firebase
and later we also want to add logic to fetch all posts that we stored on Firebase and to clear all posts
there.
But for now, let's say go with creating a new post and for that, if we have a look at our code,
you only have the app component and there in the app.component.ts file, you have onCreatePost which
will actually get some post data in this format.
Now let's first of all log that to validate that this is correct and that this works.
For that, I opened the developer tools here and now let's write a new post with some content and click
send post and we see that here.
So this seems to work,
that's perfect,
now of course we could reset that form here too if we wanted to but I'm fine
like this. The goal now of course is to not just log that here but to instead send an HTTP request and
for that,
we need Angular's help, to be precise
we need to unlock a new feature so to say. In the app module, we have to add a new core Angular module
or a new module baked into the Angular framework
I should say, which is the HttpClient module.
For that, you simply import HttpClient module here from @angular/common/http.
So that package name is @angular/common/http and you import the HttpClient module.
Now you add that HttpClient module here in your imports array, just like that.
This now unlocks the client Angular offers in your whole project and with that, we can now start sending
requests in our app component here.
In there, we now just need to inject our HttpClient and I'll store it in a property which I just
name HTTP and it's the HttpClient which you need to import from
@angular/common/http,
so make sure to add this import at the top of your path.
Now with it imported, we can use it to send HTTP requests
and how does this work now?
Now let's say here in onCreatePost once we got that post data, we want to send it to Firebase. For this,
we can use that injected HTTP service and there, you have a couple of methods.
These methods are mostly named like the HTTP verbs,
so you have get, you have delete, you have post and that will allow you to send different kinds of requests.
Now here since I want to store data, I'll start with a post request.
Now you call this method and it takes a couple of arguments,
the first argument is the URL you want to send this request to and that is the URL you can
find in your Firebase real-time database,
this URL or at least this URL is a part of the URL we'll send the request to. So paste that in here
but this is not the entire URL.
Now on a custom or on different REST APIs you were communicating with, you would have clearly defined
endpoints, like /posts/add or something like this, to which you have to send your request and the official
docs of the API you're working with would tell you which API endpoint to send the request to. For
Firebase, it's a bit differently, you have this starting point URL here and then you can add your own
segments after that and this will get replicated as folders in this database
so to say and this looks like you're directly talking to the database
but keep in mind that Firebase only abstracts this away from you,
you are still communicating with a REST API provided by Firebase,
they just translate your path you're sending it to to a folder structure in your database,
you're not communicating directly with the database here and I'm stressing this because it is important
to keep in mind that you never communicate directly with a database from inside your Angular app.
So let's say here, we want to have a node, a folder so to say named posts,
well then we would simply add posts as a segment here
and important, for Firebase you need to add .json,
this simply is a Firebase requirement,
it's not a Angular requirement, not a REST API requirement,
only a requirement by that Firebase REST API.
This now allows us to send a post request to that URL. Now
since it's a post request, it doesn't work just like this however, a post request also needs a request
body.
Now this post method here works such that it takes more than one argument, it has at least two required
arguments,
the second argument being the request body. So we pass one additional argument here and that could be
our post data, so the data we want to store, this data. Now, very important,
you normally send JSON data when interacting with a RESTful API and actually, that will happen here
as well
but the Angular HttpClient will take our Javascript object here and automatically convert it to JSON
data for us. So it will still send JSON data and we'll see this in a second when we inspect that request
in the browser developer tools but Angular will transform this automatically for us.
Now with this, we have a request that should work, it has all the core data it needs - the URL and the request
body
and for now, we don't need to set any other data.
Now let's save this and let's give it a try, shall we?
So let's go back to our application,
enter some content here and click send post.
Did something happen?
Let's check Firebase.
Well I don't see any data here and we would see it here.
Let's check the Network tab,
so in the browser developer tools, in the Chrome developer tools, go to Network tab
here, you see a bunch of network requests actually,
these are all the files that are downloaded as part of your Angular application and also Javascript
files and so on.
Let's clear that,
let's simply send another post and we don't see any request here,
so somehow this request is not being sent and that happens on purpose.
Angular heavily uses observable as you already learned and HTTP requests are also managed via observable
because they are a perfect scenario or a use case for observables.
We can wrap them and we can
then subscribe to them to get informed about the response and to handle errors and so on.
The thing just is, Angular is smart
so to say. If you're not subscribing to that prepared HTTP request you could say, so to that observable
that wraps your HTTP request, if you're not subscribing to it, then Angular and RxJS know that no
one's interested in the response and therefore, the request doesn't even get sent because if no one's
interested in the response, then it won't send the request. So post indeed will return an observable,
as you can also see here. It does not give us the response or anything like that as a return value,
it gives us an observable
that wraps your request and to get access to the response, you have to call
subscribe here and this will then be your response date actually because Angular, the HttpClient
I should say, will do even more than just giving you the response, it will automatically extract the
data attached to the response,
so the response body and give you that, though you also have ways of accessing the full response as you
will learn later.
So for now, let's simply console log that response data to get a feeling for whether that works and what
we get here.
So let's save this
and now with the subscription set up and with us subscribing here, by the way you don't need to manage
the subscription in unsubscribe because it will complete after being done anyways
and it's an observable provided by Angular for which you never need to manage subscriptions
but that's just a side note,
so now let's simply test this. Here,
let me clear all network requests again,
well actually let's first of all open the console again and let's now try this again,
send a post and now we get a log here which looks good.
Let's ignore what's in there for now, it's a Javascript object, we can see that but it has a name and
then some cryptic key here.
Let's have a look at the network tab
and there we also see that request now,
we actually see two requests even, two requests to the post endpoint.
Now that's just a characteristic of browsers when sending post requests, so not to /posts but of
type posts,
then they always send two requests.
The first one if you click on that is of type options,
that's a different HTTP verb that will first of all check whether the post request is allowed to be sent
and if that gets a success response, it will send the actual request which is this one
and there you see that was of type post,
this was the URL it sent it to,
it succeeded.
These are the response headers we got back by Firebase and these are the request headers we sent and
for example, this one and the content type headers were added automatically to the request sent for
you by Angular. You didn't add these headers, they were added by Angular and here in the request payload,
you also see that JSON data that was attached for you.
You can also of course see the response here which is the response we logged to the console.
So this is how we send HTTP requests
and besides the general syntax, the core takeaway is that requests are only sent when you subscribe.