So we're able to hard switch between states.
Now let's animate it in our animations trigger on the same level as the state method.
Implement the transmission method.
This also needs to be imported from an angle or core.
Now transition is a very intuitive method.
It allows us to describe how the transition from one state to another state should look like or should
work how it should be animated therefore transition as a first argument expects the starting state then
an arrow pointing or indicating the direction and then highlighted here.
So this means from normal to highlighted.
Well now what.
Well now in the second argument to specify what to do we specify animate.
Which all needs to be imported from an angle or coord.
So now for this direction from normal to highlighted we now set up how to animate this.
And the easiest way is to simply pass that number here the number of milliseconds it should simply take
all.
Also come to more advanced use cases where we can also have some in-between styles during the animation
.
Well before coming to so advanced topics let me also copy it and let's change the timing so that we
can see a difference for the other way around.
So highlighted to normal like this and if we now safeties
we see that now it moves and it moves slower back.
And this is now our first animation using the Anglish view animation framework or or this here with
that trigger the different states.
And then the transitions between these states.
Now let's dive a little bit deeper into this and see how we can find to do this to our needs in the
next videos.