In the last lecture, we basically finished our shopping list service
but here's one thing which is not working.
I can click this add button as often as I want,
I don't get an error but I also don't see it getting added to this list.
The reason for this is that when we call getIngredients which we of course do to populate this list,
we only get a slice of the ingredients array, so we get a copy.
Therefore once we add a new ingredient which we of course don't add to the copy but to the original
array, that is not reflected in our components
where we only have that copy to work with.
Now there are a couple of ways of solving this, for the easiest solution, you could remove slice and
that's not necessarily bad,
you would then simply return the original array
and if you're sure you don't accidentally edit it somewhere, this might not be wrong.
I choose this approach though because I want to show you a different solution,
we basically have to inform our component that new data is available.
So I will simply add a new event emitter here and I'll name it
ingredients changed
and I'll set this to or I'll of course set this to a new event emitter to be imported from
@angular/core.
This event emitter now can emit our ingredient array, so the type it will pass on is an array of ingredients
and now here whenever we change this array, we simply call this ingredients changed and emit a new event
and we of course pass a value here,
our original ingredients array, though to be precise
again, only a copy of it.
So now we always have the right ingredients array in the service and we inform other interested components
about that change in the event we're emitting here.
So now in the shopping list component, besides getting the ingredients at the point of time we load
the app,
I also want to reach out to my shopping list service and simply subscribe to that ingredients changed
event.
So now whenever ingredients change, I know that I will get them,
this will be of type ingredient array here as we learned
and now I can use them here in the body of this anonymous function I'm passing to subscribe
and here, I can now simply set this
ingredients equal to the ingredients I got here. And with this change in place,
now if we let the application reload here and go to shopping list and now I add bread and now you see
it gets added here again without any issues because now, we're getting informed that something changed.