With our component registered, let's use it.
So we have our selector here, app-server.
Now I told you we are not going to add it to the index.html file, there it wouldn't work,
instead let's go to the app.component.html file, the only other HTML we have right now
where we could add it
and here I'll add a horizontal line and below this,
I'll add my app-server element here and the shortcut I used here is just a little plugin called emmet,
available for many IDEs and editors which gives you a quicker way of writing
HTML.
So here, app-server is our own selector, our own element kind of we created.
If we now save this, it should successfully recompile
and if we have a look at our running application, you see the server component here, our own component
being added here.
So that is how you can use your components then with their selector after adding them to app module
and then displaying them on the page.