So were you successful?
Here is my solution.
As I said, I want to implement child routes, so I will do this by going to the AppRoutingModule here
and on my recipes, I'll add the children property.
Now children also takes an array of routes and each route still is just a Javascript object, here
the first route I want to have is the empty path so that we just visit /recipes/,
the default case. Here I want to load that new component I was referring to which will simply hold the
text we have in this ng-template for now.
Now for this, I will quickly create this component and I'll use the CLI
for that, with ng g c I can generate a new component and this component should now go into the
recipes folder, so recipes and then slash
and here, you may simply choose that folder,
so recipes and I will name it recipe-start, so the recipe-start component, with spec false I prevent
this spec file from being generated.
So with that, we got our recipe-start component here
and as I mentioned before, all I will do is I will output here, maybe in a h3 tag now,
please select a recipe,
so really simple. With that set up, with our start component set up here,
I now want to use that,
it has been added to app module automatically by the CLI
so make sure that this is the case
and now in the AppRoutingModule here, I will load this component,
so the recipe-start component,
this one here.
Make sure to add the import at the top from
./recipes/recipe-start/recipe-start.component
and with that added, we got our first component which can be displayed inside of our recipes component.
Let's try this out because that should be all we need to get started with it. In the recipes component because
again this is and that's important,
this is the component, the recipe component here is the component where our child routes are registered.
So it is in this components template that we need to provide a router outlet for the child routes to
be rendered.
So I will do this here.
I will add a router outlet here and when I save this with ng serve running, this looks pretty good,
we see please select a recipe and clearly that is not a paragraph anymore, so it seems to be our new component.
Of course if we click somewhere, that doesn't work anymore because we only have the router outlet there,
our old logic of loading a recipe is completely broken
but we will restore it soon.
Actually we can already take the first step for restoring that functionality,
I'll add another path here to the child routes of recipe component.
That path should be :id, so a dynamic segment added after /recipes,
that's of course something you have to keep in mind.
All child routes always come after the path of the parent route,
so all these routes here will have /recipes in front of it. So at /recipes/id with
ID being a dynamic parameter, here I want to load my recipe-detail component.
We also need to add the import to that component
up here of course,
so from the recipes folder, then recipe detail and then the recipe-detail component file. With that,
we now at least have a route which would allow us to load this component and we can kind of see this
in action if we manually enter one here
let's say. It tries to load the recipe-detail component,
of course it will break because there we try to output data which we no longer get because our old logic
of transferring data from the list item to the detail component doesn't work anymore
but we will fix it and we'll actually start fixing it in the next lecture.