In the last lecture, we created our first Angular app but we haven't changed anything there.
So it's time to do that. For that you need an IDE or editor where you can write and edit your code.
Now I'm using WebStorm here. Webstorm is a great IDE,
great for Angular development; but it's not free. A great free alternative would be Visual Studio Code which
you can find on https://code.visualstudio.com/
This is a great IDE and it is free.
You can simply download and install it both for Mac and Windows
and then you can start developing Angular with that. Whichever IDE or editor you install,
you'll always have to open a new folder (in WebStorm's case it's just called Open) and then simply navigate
to the folder you created.
So in my case here it's my-first-app.
Select that folder and open it and now it will load that folder and all the files into the ID on your
system.
So in my case, it now looks like that.
Now this is the project loaded into the ID.
It's still indexing it here but it'll be done in a second.
These are all the folders and files
The Angular CLI created for you. This is your entire Angular project.
Now as I said, this might look intimidating because you've got so many files in there.
Most of these files are just doing some configuration work and you don't really need to touch them.
One interesting file is the package.json file.
Here you can see all the dependencies of your project like Angular 6 and these are third-party
packages
your project needs to run correctly.
All devDependencies are only required for development;
for this build workflow I was talking about. But we're here to edit our code right?
So let's jump into the src folder because that is where our code is.
e2e is for end-to-end testing (we'll ignore this) and node_modules is where all these dependencies you
see in the package.json file actually were installed.
But we're interested in the source code so let's go to src.
Then we got a bunch of other configuration files and
then here, we've got this app folder and in this app folder we see some other files.
Of course I'll dive into what they all do in detail in this course.
For now let's open the app.component.html file.
Here we indeed see something which looks deceivingly like what we saw in the browser.
Do you remember? It's Welcome to app! and so on.
We see that here too. By the way,
make sure you keep the localhost:4200 process running
(the ng serve process you started here in the terminal).
Make sure to keep that running, but if you're done with development for the day
You can quit it with Ctrl-C and you'll get out of there, but as long as you are developing you should
keep it running because it will automatically watch your files and rebuild your project whenever you
change and save something.
Now since I quit it
I'll need to restart it and I will actually restart it here in my IDE.
In here there is a built in terminal but it's the normal system terminal.
So here I can also run ng serve to bring that back up.
But back to the app.component.html file, we're
outputting something here
and if we change anything here, like,
'Hi, this' (instead of 'Welcome to') and we save it with ng serve running, then if we go back,
you'll see it automatically updated;
Hi, this app!
Now, one strange thing we see is this 'app' here, but
we actually only see these curly braces and title in the app.component.html file and therefore,
we can already see some of the work Angular does here.
Angular is, of course, not a tool to allow us to write static HTML files.
We wouldn't need a framework for that.
It allows us to mix static HTML code and dynamic things we want to output in that code and actually,
what we have here is one of these components
Angular works with; the app component. A component always has a template,  the HTML code, possibly has some
styling in the CSS file (though it's empty here as you can see)
and importantly, it has a Typescript (.ts) file.
If we enter this, this is Typescript and this is now the definition of the component. This is what will
be converted to normal JavaScript by the build workflow.
And in this file, we see a couple of interesting things like @Component. I'll come back to that and what
in detail is happening here in the next module.
We also see title = 'app'.
Now, what's that?
If you go back to the app.component.html file, we also saw title here right; between the curly braces.
So an assumption would be that the title in the Typescript file is related to that.
So let's maybe change this to 'my app' and now if we save this it recompiles and if we go back, we see
'Hi, this my app!'. Now this might not be perfect English, but we can definitely see that something changed.
This is so-called data binding in action;
a concept we'll also dive into deeply in this course. This is how we can output dynamic
content.
This could of course be content that is calculated dynamically or retrieved from a server in our
HTML code.
Now interestingly, if we right-click on the loaded page and inspect the page source we don't actually see
that code there.
We just see a bunch of script imports at the bottom. That is our build code and the Angular framework
code, the head tag here
and then this strange app-root part. Now, app-root is also something we see in the app.component.ts
file here in the selector.
So it looks like this is basically like our own HTML tag we're creating
and that's indeed what's happening here.
The page we're viewing here, to which this source belongs,
actually is this index.html file in the src folder. Here we also see app-root. The script imports
are missing because they are injected dynamically.
Now, what Angular does in the the end is
always load this page.
Then we have these dynamically-injected script imports and these script imports will dynamically replace
app-root with our own component.
And of course we can have more than one component in Angular apps.
Again, these are all things we'll dive into in this course.
Now that's nice, but
let's do something more fancy.
Let's change title dynamically.
So back in the app component, I'll actually get rid of the entire code in here and I'll add an input instead;
a normal HTML input (type="text"). Below that I'll add a paragraph where I want to output, let's say,
a name.
Now, name is not something we've defined yet, we'll do so in a second.
Let's go to app.component.ts and
change title to name and I'll say Max here (because that is my name) and if I save that and go back,
we see the input and we see the name.
Now I want to be able to enter something in the input and automatically change the name. We can do
this with a tool provided by Angular; a so-called directive which is called ngModel.
Now, you'll learn the exact syntax throughout the course.
For now, let's simply add [(ngModel)],
written like that.
Make sure to get the casing correct.
There is no dash in between or anything like that.
So ngModel in square brackets and parentheses on the input and set it equal to name.
So, to the same name you're outputting here.
Now this is a so-called directive and what it does is it basically tells Angular to listen to anything
you enter here and store it in this name property, in this name model, but also on the other hand, output
the value of the name model in this input.
This is what we're doing here. Now,
if we save this we don't see anything on the page and if we open the developer tools, which you can simply
do from the menu or with the shortcut. You reach it under View ->
Developer -> Developer Tools (in Chrome) and I strongly recommend using Chrome for this course since it has
the best developer tools.
So, then we see here in the console-part there is an error.
Can't bind to 'ngModel' since it isn't a known property of 'input'.
So somehow Angular doesn't understand ngModel.
Now that's strange, because as I said it's built-in right? Angular is actually split up into multiple modules;
sub-packages you could say.
We need to add them if you want to use a certain feature from them.
And in this course you will learn about the different packages and which features they contain. To add
such a feature, we go to another file that we haven't had a look at yet;
the app.module.ts file. This is basically where we tell Angular which pieces belong to our app and there we have
to add something to imports to import another package from Angular.
So we need to import it at the top of the file first because Typescript always needs to know where things
are.
So, import  from '@angular/forms';
This is one package from the Angular framework and from that package we can import the Forms Module; written
like this: import  from '@angular/forms';
So make sure to add this import.
This is not an Angular feature; it's a Typescript feature.
As I said Typescript needs to know where things are.
But now with that imported we can add it to this imports array down here (which is not related to the
imports up there).
This is simply a feature understood by Angular since it's part of an Angular module.
And now it tells Angular that we want to import some form features.
And this directive we're using (ngModel) is such a form feature.
So now if we save that, our app will rebuild and once it's done, we can go back and see our input
with Max inside of it.
And if I start typing there, you'll see that the text below it automatically updates.
This is some magic done by ngModel.
We'll dive much deeper into everything we learned here.
But this is now our first app; with some changes.