So requests are sent
with the post method and we do only send them when we subscribe. Let's ignore the data we get back here
for now
and let's now add another request that actually gets us all the posts and for this,
I'll add a new private property here which I'll name fetch posts and in here, I want to again use
the HttpClient
and now the get method and send a get request to that same URL we used for storing the data because
is the URL from which we'll be able to get that data.
Now before we actually go further, let's have a quick look at Firebase
and there, you should now also see that posts node here and in there, you have that cryptic key
again which is an automatically generated ID by Firebase by the way,
that's a convenience feature by Firebase,
it generates such ID for you
but if you expand this too, you see your data.
So now the goal is to fetch that data,
we want to fetch all the posts that were created.
Therefore, we're preparing this get request
and now since this is a get request, this also needs
no second argument because get requests have no request body because you're not sending any data,
you're instead just requesting data. One thing you need to do here too however is you need to subscribe,
no subscription, no request.
So you need to subscribe here and we should get back our posts here,
that's the hope.
So we get back our posts here and we can then console log posts, to get an idea of what we're actually
getting back.
Now I put this into that fetch posts method because we can now call this from two different places,
from in onFetchPosts here, where I now just call this fetch posts but I also want to call this from
inside ngOnInit,
so whenever this page loads, whenever this app loads, I want to fetch post and this should therefore call this
method and send this request.
Let's save this and this will reload the page and should now already send such a request and indeed,
here is some data we get back
and it looks like we're getting back a Javascript object which has one key-value pair in our case, where
the key is this cryptic key, this cryptic string and the value of that is the original object we stored,
so it's a nested object here,
that is the data we originally sent to the back-end
and this is the data we are getting back. Now
that of course means that if I want to store all my posts in an array here through which we then can loop
to output that, we would need to transform this object here because it's a Javascript object to an array
and we need to transform that data,
that screams for observable operators.