So let's reset the form once we click update or add.
Definitely go ahead and try it on your own, time to pause the video now before I will show you how I
will do that.
So were you successful?
There is something tricky about that but let's start with the straightforward part.
After we saved our updated value or either saved the updated value or the new value I should say, we can of course
call form reset here.
Now if I do this, let's see if it works as expected. If I type bread here, 10 and I clicks add, it resets
so this works,
if I select tomatoes and change this to bread, it updates it to bread
but now we're stuck in the update mode.
If I add bread again, maybe 12, it still updates the old one right,
it doesn't add a new one because we never leave the editMode.
The reason for this of course is that initially, we are in editMode set to false,
then we switch it to true whenever we get the startedEditing observable to fire
but we never switch it back.
Well we should switch it back and actually we only need to switch it back here in onAddItem, here I
can simply called this editMode and set it to false
no matter what it was before,
this ensures that we definitely leave it because we are done.
Also we could rename this onAddItem to simply say onSubmit because onAddItem is not correct all the
time but that is not important, that is
just a little cosmetic change, also
rename it in the template then though.
So with this in place, if we now try this again, let's add a new item, that works, let's edit an existing
one, bananas 2 and now let's try adding Schnitzel 1.
Now you see, that seems to work again,
now we can correctly update tomatoes, our items here
and it switches between editMode and updateMode.
Of course I also need to make sure that the delete and clear button works,
so let's work on the clear button next.