So we saw two examples for directive now and the better approach definitely is a good approach but
it's not very interactive, right?
It always gives us a blue background
and I want to change this.
I only want to style this blue or give this a blue background if I hover over it and if I move my mouse
away, it should go back to transparent.
So let's improve the better-highlight here a bit.
We need to react to some events occurring on the element the directive sits on
and a quick and easy way to do this inside of this directive is to simply add a new decorator and this
is the @HostListener decorator which needs to be imported from @angular/core and add it to some
method we want to execute,
so the method here could be mouseover.
Now I'll move this from the top of the file below ngOnInit here,
so now this can be triggered whenever some event occurs and that event is specified here as an argument,
as a string. @HostListener here takes the argument name as an input and that would be mouseenter
let's say. That is one of the events supported by the DOM elements
this directive sits on,
so you have basically all events available you could also use event binding before.
So that's my @HostListener targeting this event
and we could also receive the event data here,
so event data of type event would be passed to us here,
so that works.
You can also listen to custom events here and retrieve that data,
so that's just like the method you execute when you add a click listener or whatever your event is and
then pass the method between quotation marks,
so that's happening here,
@HostListener is just a convenient way of listening to events on that element.
So with that, we listen to the mouseenter event, we get the event data which I don't need here
but what I want to do in this case is I want to change the backgroundColor of the element.
So what I can do is, I can copy this code from ngOnInit and comment it out and now set the style here
on mouse enter
and now I can quickly copy this and add another method which I'll name mouseleave maybe where I will
listen to the mouseleave event, another officially event I can listen to
and then I want to set the backgroundColor to transparent maybe.
Now with this in place, we should have a reactive directive.
So now, no background color and if I hover over it,
it gets blue.
So that is working as intended, now with @HostListener reacting to user event or to any events.