In the last lecture, we started adding our child routes and now loading the recipe detail component doesn't
work anymore.
The reason for this is that here, we use recipe all over the place and that's a property of this
component
but it's a property set through property binding with @input in front of it,
so it awaits to be set from outside the component.
Since this component is set through routing though, this won't work anymore,
so we have to change how we receive the recipe here, how we set the recipe and we can change it
because keep in mind, in our route which we define here, we pass this ID which is a dynamic parameter.
So we should be able to load a recipe by the ID, which will simply refer to the position in the array
of recipes.
So here is your challenge,
try fixing the recipe-detail component to somehow use that ID to update the recipe which is displayed,
to fetch it from the recipe service.
Of course you will need to implement some method in the recipe service which allows you to get that.
Here's your chance to pause the video, thereafter I will solve it together with you.
So were you successful?
Let's fix it together. In the recipe detail component,
we clearly can remove @input because that's not how we receive the value anymore,
so we can also remove the import of @input.
That of course also means before we forget it that in the recipe-item component, we can remove the
onSelected click listener here because that will not be how we passed the value anymore
and of course we could also remove the onSelected method here,
that is something we don't need anymore. Of course that also allows us to remove the recipes service
from this component and remove the import,
so we're cleaning up quite a lot here. In the recipe-list component,
we don't have to change anything
and in the recipe component itself here, we already did make a change and add the router outlet.
So now in the recipe-detail component, we somehow need to get our single recipe and we know that we will
get the ID from the router.
So let's first fetch this ID and you learned that for this, we need to get access to the ActivatedRoute.
So let's inject it here, of type ActivatedRoute,
make sure to add this import here from @angular/router. This import is important to enable TypeScript
to identify the type you are trying to inject here
and with that, Angular is able to use it.
So now we get this route and now we have two ways of retrieving the ID.
The first one would be to simply bind it to route snap,
excuse me, this route snapshot params ID but this will only work for the first time if we loaded detail
component.
Now keep in mind, the menu where we can click on one is on the left, so we will be able to choose a new
recipe
whilst we still see the details of another one. So we probably want to react to changes in our recipe
ID because that's absolutely possible in our app.
So that is not the approach I want to use,
instead what I want to do is I want to use my route, the params observable and subscribe to that observable.
Now with that, we can react to any changes in our route params and we will get them here, of type params
as we learned, to be imported from @angular/router and now, now we can really react to a new ID.
So we should probably store that ID here in a property of our class,
it will be of type number, so we should set this ID equals to params ID, though we know that what we
get back here will be a string,
so we should cast it to a number by adding a plus in front of it.
So now we will have an ID in the form of a number which we can use to identify our recipe.
Well with this information,
we want to load our recipe from the recipe service and for that, we need to change our recipe service
because right now, we got no way of loading a single recipe by ID. That's something we can easily implement
though, we can simply implement a getRecipe method which takes an ID of type number and then we can
simply return this recipes and select the item at this index,
we could also rename ID to index to make really clear what that number will be in the end.
You could also call slice before doing that because slice would now give you a copy of your array, though
it won't be a deep copy,
so the objects still are the same anyways, so you can also directly return the object like this.
You could of course also create a hard copy of the object with object assigned for example.
That's not what I want to do here though,
so we return a single recipe.
Now back in the recipe-detail.component.ts file, after fetching an ID and storing it, I want
to fetch the new recipe
and I will later also show why I needed to store the ID here. So let's fetch the recipe using our recipe
service whenever the ID changes, then I will call getRecipe and pass my ID as an argument. And with
that, we should be able to indeed make our application to work again by going manually to recipes zero,
we indeed see the detail view
for the schnitzel
and with one for the burger.
So that is working,
now we also need to enable these links here to work again because right now, they're not doing anything.