Thus far we only had starting an ending state.
Now let's play around with the animate function.
We actually cannot only pastie the timing we can control the whole animation and define styles.
The animation should take during the animation.
For that I will pass a second argument here which is the style never again we're already importing that
.
And as I can define a style in a state I can also define a style during the animation.
So year I also pass a challenge crypt object and that in-between style will now be taken during the
installation.
So here let's say I want to give as a border radius of 50 pixels.
Now let's see how that looks if I save this with this extra style during the animation.
If I hit shrink you see it now looks kind of ugly because now we let these border radios or we let it
well get around.
But once it finishes it instantly jumps to the end state.
So this is not really what you want we want to smooth fully half this in between our animation and not
any made the changing of the border radius and that instead of the chumped the end state to cater for
such needs we would replace this any made function here like this with an array.
Now we can pass an array as the second argument to transition.
And here we can also define starting and in between states during this transition.
So we could pass a style here and say background background color Shelby orange it would be one thing
.
Thereafter the second element in disarray would be an animated function which takes let's say one second
where I want to animate my border radius ask before border radius 50 pixels and now to avoid this ugly
jump at the end I add a number.
Any made function of half a second which will be executed after the border radius has been changed.
Now with that we should instantly see a change to the background color to orange.
Thereafter we should see the border radius developing over one second and thereafter we should see the
animation of well half a second where we removed the border edges again.
Shrink the object and turn it from orange back to our end state which is green for example if we do
shrink it.
Well let's see if I can shrink it What we do indeed see it turn orange see the border radius and thereafter
see a shrink and the border radius being removed and the same is true for any made back.
So with that I get a more complex animation where a chain multiple styles.
And while all this nesting here might look difficult it actually isn't it only is an array passed to
the transmission which allows us to define different phases in that transition starting phase.
If no Any made method is used then it is instantly applied that if we do get any mate we do apply a
style but over some time and if we have any made without a style this means basically now transition
to the end state.
And this is how we can set up our animation of course we could have multiple in-between styles.
The important thing is that you do end with any made 500 or whatever timing you have to get smoothly
to the end state otherwise you will see what we had before that it instantly snaps back to your end
state.
Probably not what you want.
This is a more complex transition with the in between steps.
But I think still manageable if you really think about what's happening here with these different phases