So we learned about @HostListener and this set up here is absolutely fine for what we're doing
but we got another decorator we can use which then allows us to not use the renderer.
There is nothing wrong with using the renderer but we get an even easier way of simply changing the
background color if that is all we want to do in the directive,
again using the renderer is not wrong though. The decorator I'm referring to is called @HostBinding
which also needs to be imported from @angular/core
and since we got a lot of imports, I'll quickly restructure this to cover multiple lines.
So @HostBinding,
that's the new decorator
and I will come back to what we pass here in a second.
First of all, we need to bind this to some property which value will become important,
so that could be a backgroundColor property, a new property I create here which is of type string.
Now in @HostBinding, we can pass a string defining to which property of the hosting element we want to
bind. Now properties of the hosting element,
that is simply what we also access here in the BasicHighlightDirective, style would be such a property
and there then the backgroundColor property to be precise.
Therefore we can simply say style. and now camel case backgroundColor and that's all. Camel case
is important here because we're accessing the DOM property which doesn't know dashes.
So with this, what we're telling Angular is on the element this directive sits, please access the style
property which pretty much any input has on other directives which access something like the value, you
of course have to make sure that they are only added to inputs which have this property
but here again, the style property should be available on any element.
So here we access the style property
and then there a sub-property, the backgroundColor and we set this equal to whatever background color
is set to here.
Well and we can simply change background color here when we mouseover it, we can set backgroundColor
to blue in this case and set it to transparent
in this case here, transparent and I will comment out the renderer code here, again not wrong to use it
but no longer needed it in this example.
Of course we also have to set some initial color so that we don't get an error before we
mouse over it the first time,
so here I will set this to transparent initially, give this an initial value.
With this it's transparent,
no error,
looks good
and if we hover over it, it works the same way as before but now solely driven through @HostListener
and @HostBinding, a great way for working with the element inside of a directive.
And of course here on @HostBinding,
you can bind to any property of the element you are sitting on.