Thus far, we always used an external template file and we haven't done anything regarding the styling
of components,
time to change both.
Now instead of using an external template file, you can also use an inline template which means you define
the HTML
code in the TypeScript code, sounds strange?
Well it's possible. We can do this by simply going to our servers components here for example and right
now, we point to this HTML file here,
now we can change templateUrl to template,
one of the two has to be present, either linked to an external template or just the template to define it in
this file
but each component needs to have a template,
this is the one property you have to have at all times.
So with that, now I change it to template,
now we can write our template code here.
So here we could now replicate app-server, like this,
maybe twice, we have to make sure that we don't wrap this line because this is not supported in a default
TypeScript string
and if I now save this, we see the same result as before.
So it looks like nothing changed
and that is good
in this case because we try to make it look like this
but actually, we did change the way we set up our template here,
now we're defining the HTML code in this same file.
And actually if you want to write multi-line strings here, which you probably want if you add more HTML
code to it, you can switch from a normal string with single quotation marks to using back ticks to use
Javascript template expressions, to be able to write multi-line strings in between there now.
So now between the opening and closing back tick, you may actually wrap the line and now write your HTML
code, like this. What should you use, should you use this approach here of using template or an external
file?
It depends, if you have not that much code, not that much HTML code, using an inline template like
this might be fine,
then you have all the logic in the TypeScript code and that is absolutely OK
but as soon as you have let's say more than three lines of code in the HTML part here in the template,
using an external file is a good idea to make it easier to follow and easier to understand.
It is important though to keep in mind that you can use this approach, that you can inline your templates
and very important, that you need to have at least a template in a component.
You can omit the selector, you will later in the routing section learn a different way of loading components
without using their selector and you don't have to add styles but templates have to be present. So that
was templates,
now let's have a look at the styles in the next lecture.