So we added the resetting and the clear mechanism, let's make sure we can delete the items. For this of
course and even our click listener here and definitely try solving this on your own if you want,
so that's your chance to pause the video,
if you don't want to solve it on your own or if you are already finished with it now,
well we can definitely go ahead and do it together.
So I'm calling onDelete here
when I click the delete button and I'll add this method to my shopping edit component.
Well in onDelete, what do we need to do here?
We need to inform the service that it should remove one of the items in the array and that is basically almost
all, we also need to make sure that we call this onClear because we definitely also want to clear a form
if we delete the item which was loaded.
Now in the shopping list service, I need to add a method, deleteIngredient and I expect to get an index
where I should delete it. With that information, I can simply use my ingredients array and splice one
of the elements. Splice allows us to start at a specific point, for example at index here and then splice
one element, thus removing it
and then of course as always, we should call ingredientsChanged and of course you could refactor this
in its own method
but I think that's OK, I like this too.
So here, I will slice or simply pass a copy of my ingredients and with that, the final step is before
we clear everything, I will reach out to my shopping list service, call deleteIngredient and simply pass
the editedItemIndex as a value.
Now this will throw an error if we click delete without loading an item,
so therefore I will simply add ngIf to the button and I'll just restructure to make it easier to read,
ngIf to only display the button
if we are in editMode. So now by default we don't see delete, if I switch to an item,
I can see and I click it, it resets the form and deleted an item.
Now no more items are left, of course.
I can still add new ones and delete them again. So that is our shopping list form
working with the template driven approach and a lot of other nice features like the service really showing
you how you could set up something like this,
how you can use set value, how you can reset the form and therefore hopefully both the form you need.
Now in the next lectures,
I will move on to the recipe edit form which you will create using the reactive approach.