With our child routes added in the last lecture, let's now make these links work again so that we can
really choose an item from that list. The place to make these links work of course is in our recipe list,
the recipe item here,
that is where we have an anchor tag and that is where we should set the link.
We can set a link with routerLink
but now we get a dynamic segment in the path.
So now I will bind routerLink with square brackets because now I want to pass this array which allows
me to really configure segment for segment of my path.
Now the first segment is also the only segment, that will be the ID I want to load.
So I will use a relative path because this element here, the list already is loaded at /recipes,
so whenever I just add the ID here, that is already all I want because then we're going to end up at
recipes/id.
Now to get the ID, I need to pass this extra information to the recipe-item component.
We're not doing this right now, so let's do that.
I will add a new property binding here, so I will add the index here
and the index will simply be a number and I will add @input at the beginning.
With this, I can now pass in the index of this item from outside and I'll do this from the recipe-list
component, here besides sending the recipe itself,
I can now also pass the index and of course, I have to retrieve that from my ngFor loop.
So here I'll simply bind i to index to get the index of each iteration basically and then
I'll pass this index i to the app-recipe-item and bind it to the index property there,
this property we just created. As a side note, with the ID being passed to this component
now, you theoretically could update this component to now use our recipe service and the getRecipe method
we just created to fetch the recipe by ID but I will leave it as it is here but that would be one way
of refactoring or restructuring this component.
The important thing for us now is that we have the index property in this component now and that is
all we need for this link.
So I want to pass the index here and keep in mind, this is for a single component,
so that index will be different for each instance of this component.
So if we save this, we can see it already at the bottom of the page,
this looks all right and I can switch between 0 and 1.
So that looks pretty good,
now it would also be nice to style the active item here though and that is something I'll do in the
next lecture.