So that's all nice.
We're able to animate these deaths year.
But what if we actually do want to animate the addition of an item to the list.
Or if I click on it remove movement of such an item how can we animate this.
We'll have a look at this now thus far we only animated the deaf.
Well now it's time to add a new trigger to our application so I'll copy the first trigger in this overall
animations array here.
This one here and added Make sure you pick the right level where you add it should be in the same level
as the ava triggers of course now I'm going to name this list one and there.
I only want to have one state actually d in state so that the element is on the dorm is added to the
state it's in the dorm.
The our state would be that we don't have the element because we just remove it or we just edit it.
So it kind of should appear and that is stayed handled by Anglo to us you will learn.
So the instate is how should it look like once it finally is there.
Well I want to have translate X of zero to be at the position to actually place it here in my what my
age team on the code and I wanted to have let's say an opacity of one so that it is fully visible not
transparent.
That is the one state I have here now I need transitions.
The first transition which is interesting for me is when it comes in.
So when I added to the dorm here the end state is in but what is the beginning state.
Well we could use the wildcard character but there is a specific state for this case that the element
hasn't been added yet.
That's why it so why does a reserved state name you can't use it.
You shouldn't override it when it does provide the buying won't you.
For cases where you do have an element in an end state which wasn't added to the dorm at the beginning
or of course you could also add Woit as the transition to state.
So if you remove an element for example with this it should slowly appear and we can see the action
by going to our app component to our HMO file and there on the list on the list item specifically we
want to add a trigger as before in square brackets and then at and then place to one and we don't need
to bind it to anything because it will actually set up word to anything because I don't care what the
specific state is in.
It's just a dummy or you could use any name.
I only have in here we could have some logic in the code which changes the state of our list items.
But here for the entering animation when we add a new item I don't care what the initial state is and
actually I never said it in this application.
I never apply a state of.
In two days I don't have a property managing my list element States.
I do have it forward the above examples but here I don't care.
I went to any made from not existent to any state.
This is the animation I want to execute and if I saved this and we see this in action let's add tasks
here and well that is certainly not working as intended.
So what's going wrong here.
Well the issues clearly we have no starting state.
Now it doesn't work as such that we now set up Lloyd like this before we defined are states like this
.
But since what is kind of a bulge in state it now works differently.
Instead here in our transition we now want to change this.
We will use an array here where any mate is placed in.
But before executing animate I will have a nap restyle method where I set the initial style and this
style will now be applied by English to you right at the beginning.
So when we add on your list item it is appended to the dawn and it will instantly get this style by
Angola 2 and then transition over Dyster region to its final style here.
So to a style a one a set up here therefore is a pop opacity of 0 and a 1 to transform such that it
flies in.
So translate X should be minus 100 pixels.
And now if I save this now we should see a nice animation.
When they actually add new items to the list year you saw it up on the initial loading already.
And now each new item is smooth fully animated in like that automatically by Englad to.
It doesn't work for deleting though.
So let's handle this next.
Well let's say for deleting we want to have it slide to the right so to do this I'll add a new transmission
here to my trigger and here I want to navigate or animate from any state to any state would be possible
to you but too wide specifically.
And here I want to start with the state it already has so no need to define a starting state.
Instead my animate function should now have a final state.
Because here I don't have the problem of it snapping to some state at the end.
This should be the state that takes a deep end.
So here was a second argument as you learned above here.
I set up the state I want to have it where I want to have it.
And the end.
And there are two trends for him to translate x.
The last one hundred pixels to move it to the right and to all faded out by setting the opacity to zero
again.
Well and with that in place the timing.
Well let's let's have it at 300 to Wantage reloads and I click on the element you see it smoothly transition
out and being removed and this is how you can animate lists and the same would of course also work for
energy IV where you also have the behavior of something new being added to the DOM