We do have an alternative to using this set up here censored kind of hapless synchronously anyways and
only theoretically is asynchronous.
You noticed we didn't wait one and a half seconds here.
We can also copy this test copy it down here and call fake async or use fake async as a wrapper.
This needs to be imported from the inlet to testing packet.
Yes.
Well what this allows me to do is it allows me to get rid of the when stable function here like this
.
So instead I execute expected and so on instantly.
But I call tick in between now tick all needs to be imported from the English huge testing package and
tech basically means in a fake asynchronous environment finish all asynchronous tasks.
Now when Tich is executed asynchronous tasks are finished we can finish them immediately since we resolve
it immediately.
We don't wait one and a half seconds.
That is why we wrote it this way we don't want to wait.
That's time when testing.
So we finished it immediately and we should have access to the data.
So let's see if this works if I saved this indeed we get a successful test here too.
And this is how we now also use fake async.
So you could use either async with this set up when stable and then on the callback your expectation
or fake async it takes the same time.
It's just a different philosophy here you more like fake or behave like it was really asynchronous and
here you just use tick to say yeah let's go on.
This is how you can use services and components.
I picked this task or these two building pieces as they are very important they're probably amongst
the most complex especially with the injection and asynchronous tasks.
I hope this was helpful.
Again I do have a document where you can dive a lot deeper into that.
I wanna finish this module by having a look at isolated and non isolated testing cases.
Let's have a look at this and learn what this is.