We understood that templates are important and that we can either use them inline here or point to
an external file,
what about styles?
We also have this styleUrls property here and we have these CSS files.
What can we do with those?
Let's go back to our app component for this.
Here we got a h3 tag and a horizontal line
and if we have a look at our application, it's not that pretty, right?
The I'm in the app component text here or all the text actually is sitting right on the edge here, not
super pretty.
Now since we use bootstrap, of course we can use some bootstrap classes to enhance this. So we could add
a div with a container class around it, then add a row
and this is just using the CSS framework, bootstrap,
so these are some CSS classes provided by this framework, nothing Angular specific
and then we could add a column here, xs-12 to have one column on all device widths.
Now if we add this, we added some styling, some normal CSS styling, nothing Angular specific
and our app looks a little bit nicer now.
This is great but we can also use some tools given to us by Angular.
Let's say this, I'm in the app component heading here,
we want to change that style,
maybe we want to give this some blue color.
We can do it just by going to the app.component.css file which defines the styling for this component
and now we can use or write normal CSS code,
so overwrite the style of the h3 tag and set its color to some blue,
so maybe to this dark blue here.
If we now save this and we have a look at our application, you see it's dark blue
now. This is how you can use this style file, this CSS file referenced in the app component here to
define the styles for a component.
Now just like we were able to choose between external file and inline code for template, we can do
the same for the styling.
You notice that styleUrls is an array here whereas templateUrl wasn't. It is this
because we could reference multiple external stylesheets here, so you could add pointers to other stylesheets
but besides that, I'm going to comment this out,
you can also set up another property which is just styles.
This also takes an array but now it takes an array of strings where you define the style in this string,
so now in this file. Here I'm going to use back ticks again to be able to write a multi-line expression
here and then we could set up h3 here
and to really show you that this is different, I will set the color to
now let's not say dark blue but to dodger blue.
And if I now save this and we go back to the application, you see the blue updated because now the inline
style is taking over,
I commented out the other one. Just like with the template, you have to decide which one to use,
you can't combine styleUrls and styles but both important here has to be an array, that's the difference
to template,
you must only have one template, you may have multiple style files or style definitions and you can choose
between inline and external file.
The rules are basically the same as for the template.
If you have more code in there, using an external file is a good idea, if it's a short style definition
like this,
why don't you just put it into the TypeScript file?
This is how you can work with templates and styles.