That's it for observables. You saw how you can build your own observable, to basically get an idea of
what's happening behind the scenes, how you can subscribe to it and provide different functions to do
different things for data, errors or the observable being completed.
You learned about operators which you add by using the pipe method on the observable and then by
adding the operators you import from rxjs/operators, which are tools that might not look
super useful right now but which will actually become quite handy throughout the course since they make
it easy for us to build nice code structures where we have a clear chain of steps we want to execute
on the data we're getting let's say from a server and therefore, they're really powerful. And you learned
about subjects, which are in the end a better event emitter you could say. And with that, you have a
thorough foundation about observables. Now also check out the advanced resources you find in the last
lecture of this module and which l already show throughout this module if you want to dive way
deeper but with that, we now have all the preparation to continue with the course.