Hi, I'm Edward, and I will be your trainer
for this course.
Getting started with Kubernetes is no easy task,
so reach out to me using the Q and A if you're stuck
somewhere in this course.
Setting up your Kubernetes cluster for the first time
can be hard, but once you're passed the initial lectures
it'll get easier, and you'll deepen your knowledge
by learning all of the details of Kubernetes.
When you're finished with this course you can continue
with my two other Advanced Kubernetes courses,
you'll get a coupon code in the last lecture,
the bonus lecture.
This is the course overview of this course.
You see there's a lot to cover.
I'll first talk about introduction,
what is containers, what is Kubernetes.
I will guide you through the setup on your desktop
or on the cloud.
And then once you have a cluster setup,
then we will start building containers.
We'll run the first app on Kubernetes.
Then I will explain to you the Kubernetes Basics,
what do you need to know.
The node architecture, how to scale, how to use deployments,
services, healthchecks, the lifecycle of the pod,
and how to use secrets in your application.
I'll also show you how to use a WebUI.
Then we'll start with more advanced topics.
I will talk about service discovery,
how to use config files and ingress,
which is also a load balancer.
External DNS, I'll talk about volumes, pod presets,
StatefulSets, Daemon Sets, monitoring, autoscaling,
node affinity, anti-affinity.
I will also cover operators,
which can give you extra functionality in Kubernetes.
And then I will cover administration.
I will talk about the master services,
how to set quotas and limits, namespaces, user management,
and how to limit your users using RBAC.
I'll talk about networking, node maintenance,
high availability and TLS on your load balancer.
Then a very interesting topic, packaging.
So how do you run your applications on Kubernetes.
First I will introduce you to Helm,
and then how to create Helm charts
to package your applications,
and then we're going to set up a Helm repository,
to store our Helm charts.
Then we will be building and deploying applications
using Helm and Jenkins.
I have a few extras that you can take,
kubeadm if you want to set up an on-prem cluster,
and TLS certificates with cert-manager,
which is part of one of my other courses.
This allows you to use letsencrypt to add certificates
to your applications.
Course objectives, after this course you should be able
to understand, deploy and use Kubernetes.
You should be able to get started with Containerization
and run those containers on Kubernetes.
To deploy Kubernetes on your desktop, on-prem, and on AWS.
To be able to run stateless and stateful applications
on Kubernetes.
And to be able to adminster Kubernetes.
You should also be able to package and deploy
applications using Helm,
and this last one is quite an important one.