In this next section I'll be talking
about Serverless, Functions in Kubernetes.
First of all, what is Serverless?
Public Cloud providers often provide Serverless
capabilities in which you can deploy functions,
rather than instances or containers.
Microsoft has Azure Functions,
Amazon has AWS Lambda,
and Google has Cloud Functions.
Those are the main public cloud providers
and they provide all ways to deploy functions.
With these products, you don't need to manage
the underlying infrastructure, you just only deploy
the code, the function that you want to execute.
The functions are also not always
on unlike containers and instances,
which can greatly reduce the cost of serverless
if the function doesn't need to be executed a lot.
So you also pay by invocation rather
than by minute or by hour, so it makes a big
difference in the pricing.
Serverless in public cloud can reduce
the complexity, the operational costs,
and engineering time to get code running.
You don't need to manage a Windows or Linux distribution.
You don't need to build containers,
you only pay for time your function is running.
So if your function only runs for five seconds,
you will only pay for those five seconds.
A developer can just push the code and does not
have to worry about many operational aspects.
Although cold starts, the time for a function
to start after it has not been invoked
for some time, can be an operational issue
that needs to be taken care of.
While it reduces the operational work load
for the engineering team, it also brings
some new problems that you have to take care of,
and those cold starts are one of the main
issues that you have to keep an eye on.
So serverless reduces the complexity
because it can just deploy code
instead of containers or instances
with linearis/binaries as one,
it can give you lower operational costs
because you build differently
and the engineering time to get the code running
can be lower because you only needed to code
and the run time is provided by the cloud provider.
This is an example of a AWS Lambda Function.
So this just contains three lines of code
you'd use to find a function that takes the event
and the context which can contain information
about how the function is invoked,
and then you pause, Hello, World,
this is the result of this function.
You'd still need to setup when the code is being executed.
So now you have a function, but you still need
to setup when it is going to be executed.
For example, in AWS you would use an API Gateway,
to setup a URL that will invoke this function when visited.
So what I showed you here, those three lines,
it's just a function, it doesn't tell you
when it should run.
You need to connect it to another AWS service,
for example, the API Gateway, it will give you
a host name, a URL that you can then invoke just by browsing
the URL and then you can link this function to it,
so this function executes and then it will return
Hello, World and that's what even
you would see in your browser.
So there's still some operational
work to get this running.
Now Serverless in Kubernetes rather
than using containers to start applications
on Kubernetes you can also use
functions like the AWS Lambda.
Currently, the most popular projects
enabling functions are OpenFaas,
Kubeless, Fission, and OpenWhisk.
So all those projects are providing
ways to run the functions on Kubernetes.
You can install and use any other projects
to let developers launch functions
on your Kubernetes cluster.
As an administrator of Kubernetes cluster,
you'll still need to manage the underlying
infrastructure, but from a developer standpoint,
he or she will be able to quickly and easily
deploy functions on Kubernetes.
This is the major difference with public cloud.
Within public cloud you don't have to manage
infrastructure, it is done for you,
but because you are running Kubernetes
because you are installing one of these projects
you still need to manage this serverless infrastructure,
but the new developers can use it just in the same
way as they would use on the clouds.
All these projects are pretty new as of September, 2018.
When I created this lecture, so there are features
that will still drastically change.
Most of the projects are also still in office stages,
so some of the existing functionality
can still change as well.
If you are looking in adopting a serverless technology
for your Kubernetes cluster, it's best to compare
the features and the maturity of multiple
software products, and make your own decision.
So all of these projects have a get up page,
and go to the get up page, read about them,
and compare their features with what you need
in a serverless technology.
In this course, I will demo Kubeless,
which is easy to setup and use.
It's also one of the technologies specifically
written for Kubernetes and it leverages
a lot of the Kubernetes components to integrate
this functions capability within Kubernetes.
I will talk about Kubeless in the next lecture.