And now, I'm going to talk
about a tool called Skaffold.
Skaffold is an open source project from Google.
It's a command line tool for continuous development
of applications that can run on Kubernetes.
Skaffold will handle,
building, for example with docker build.
Pushing, to docker hub or other repositories,
and deploying to your kubernetes cluster.
Having this workflow, Skaffold can monitor your application
for changes while you are developing it.
When a change happens, it can execute this build, push,
deploy workflow to get your application deployed
immediately to the Kubernetes cluster.
That way you can very quickly iterate on your application.
Skaffold can also be used as a tool
that can be incorporated into your CI/CD pipeline,
as it has the build, push, and deploy workflow built-in.
That way you can have the workflow locally
to test your app, and have it handled
by your CI/CD in the same way.
Skaffold is also very pluggable.
You can do the build with a local docker installation,
or with alternatives like in cluster build with Kaniko
or even a remote build on the Google Cloud Builds.
Other builds next to docker are also possible,
like Bazel, build packs or custom builds,
and deploying can be done with kubectl, which I find
as the simplest way to, but you also use helm,
because it's also a possibility.
Here are the Skaffold pipeline stages,
so you are the developer,
so the developer is going to open his IDE
or his editor is going to develop his code,
and at some point he's going to save his file,
and Skaffold will detect the source code changes.
There is a way to do file sync directly
with the running pulse,
but in most cases, you will have to rebuild the artifact.
The artifact is a docker container,
so it will run a docker build,
most likely on your local system.
You can also optionally test artifacts,
you can run tests if you want to,
so you can define test that need to run,
or else the build has been completed.
Then Skaffold can tag the artifacts,
it can tag the docker container,
then it'll render the manifests,
so it can make changes to the YAML file that you need
to deploy to Kubernetes,
so Skaffold will render that,
it can make changes to it,
and then it will deploy this manifest file,
digitally with cubectl,
it will deploy it to your Kubernetes cluster,
and then it will tell the logs immediately,
so you can see what the output is of your application,
whether it starts correctly or not.
It can optionally also forward ports,
so that you don't immediately can go
to your application locally.
You can also put a log in some place for example
to reach your app,
and then it can also cleanup the images and the resources.
So technically when you exit Skaffold,
then it will tear down the infrastructure that it created.
So this is the Skaffold pipeline,
once you run Skaffold, and you make a change
to your source code, then it will go
through this pipeline, you make another change,
it'll again go through this pipeline.
Then on your Kubernetes cluster, you will almost
instantaneously see the new version of your application
depending on how long it takes to
do the build of your application,
and that I'll show you in the next demo.