In the next section,
I'm going to be talking about microservices.
Kubernetes makes it easy to deploy
a lot of diverse applications.
Those applications can be monoliths
that don't have anything to do with each other,
or microservices, small services
that make up one application.
The microservices architecture is increasingly popular.
This approach allows developers to split up
the application in multiple independent parts.
Having to manage microservices can put
an operational strain on the engineering team.
Here's an example of two monolith applications.
On the left, we have a client.
That client connects to a load balancer,
the load balancer goes to an Ingress controller,
and the Ingress controller, depending on
the host name, for example, will redirect the client
to application one or application two.
Application one has its own database,
application two has its own database,
so these applications don't have
anything to do with each other.
They are independent from each other.
They could be two completely different applications.
Now, sometimes, you have one application
that is divided into two parts,
and those applications will communicate with each other,
like in this diagram.
App one and App two communicate with each other.
Maybe App one needs some data from Database two.
So we have one application, and that
application is divided into two parts,
and they need information from each other.
This is probably the start of
using microservice architecture.
When using the microservice approach,
we'll start with maybe one, two services,
and then, when the project grows,
when more people come on board,
you can split applications in multiple parts,
or you can add smaller services to your application.
At some point, it will look like this,
where you then have multiple services
multiple parts of your application
that are on, and that communicate with each other
to then deliver something to the client.
You see here that there's lots of traffic
between the applications, between the microservices,
so they need each other to be able
to serve the client.
At this point, we can talk about a service mesh.
We have all these microservices talking
to each other in the form of a mesh,
so this is the term that is used for that.
It's called Service Mesh.
This can bring some new issues that we need to resolve.
Between the microservices, you often have no encryption,
unless you implement this in every single application.
There's no retries, no failover.
The communication is often true http,
and when the request fails, it will often just
show an error, it will not try again,
or try a replica of that application.
Again, unless you all write this manually
in your application.
There's no intelligent load balancing.
The Ingress controller will deplete load balance
based on route dropping.
If a bond communicates up to in Kubernetes,
then it will go to a service.
The service will again use routing to send traffic
to the different pods.
So there's no intelligent load balancing.
It doesn't recheck the latency that it has
over different pods.
It just routes it using a simple algorithm.
There's no routing decisions that you can make
so the routing is still very simple.
You can make some routing decisions
in the ingress controller, but then once
you are between the applications,
there is no decisions that are being made.
There's also no metrics.
There's no logs, there's no traces
of the communications between the applications,
between the microservices.
There's no access control.
Every applicant communicates with another app.
If you want access control, you have to implement that
yourself in your microservices.
So to implement all these features, it will take
a lot of effort to implement those in all your
different microservices.
So one solution is to add a proxy to every single
application, to every single microservice.
This is called a sidecar deployment.
Now, instead of communicating directly
to the apps, you will communicate through the sidecar,
through the proxy and this proxy can have
some features to solve some of our problems.
For example, it can have now
encryption between applications.
That sidecar will run next to every container
that we have.
So the communication between the sidecars
can have encryption, enabling encryption
for our communications between our microservices.
You can also have retries when a connection fails.
So let's say that you do a Git request.
You might want to be able to retry that Git request
rather than just having it to fail.
It can also now have intelligent load balancing
rather than just do range routing,
you might take into account the latency
for example that you have with one replica
that is lower than your replica.
You can also add a management interface
so the management interface can push changes
to these sidecar processes.
At that point, you can make routing decisions
for example, you can deploy multiple versions
of let's say, app three and then have some of the traffic
routed to a newer version for AB testing.
You could route a certain percentage to a new version
of app three, so you can make complex routing decisions.
You can also have metrics, logs, and traces.
Because the sidecars can keep logs and they
can keep metrics and traces from all the communications
and you could get all this.
And the sidecars can also have access control.
So route, for example, can access app three
who has access to it.
You maybe need a valid certificate to be able
to access this application so that
external applications can just access our application
within our service mesh.
This brings us to Istio and this is
the architecture diagram of Istio.
It's very similar to what I just showed you.
Istio uses the envoy proxy for a sidecar deployment.
It's a very efficient proxy, very lightweight
that you can then include in your pods.
If you have app one which is a microservice,
you can have this as a container in your pod
and next to this container, you will have
an envoy proxy within that pod that will deal
with all the communication.
So the envoys will communicate with each other.
You can do this encrypted with authentication
so that only those apps within the service mesh
can communicate with each other and not outside apps.
And you can have policy checks, telemetry.
So you can get all your metrics and you can get
some insights of your traffic.
You will have your configuration data pushed
from a central application, pushed from your
Istio so all the configuration decisions
are made centrally and then pushed throughout
your envoy proxies.
And citadel, on the right here,
can also provide TLS certs for every envoy proxy.
You can then also have authentication using certificates.
This is all managed by the control plane API
which allows for central management
of this service mesh.
So once you start using microservices,
when you have a service mesh, Istio is a great solution
to get a whole new feature set ready
then implementing this on the app level.
In the next demo, I will show you how to
deploy Istio to your Kubernetes Cluster.