In this lecture, I'm going to be explaining Health Checks. When you put your app in production you will
definitely want to configure your health checks. If your application malfunctions the pod in the container
can still be running, but the application might not work anymore.
The app gives an error because of something internally that went wrong.
To detect and resolve problems with your application you can run health checks.
You can run two different types of health checks.
The first one is running a command in the container periodically.
It just going to execute a command within the container to check whether your containers still working.
The other one and the one that is used most of the time is periodic checks on a URL using HTTP.
Your app probably is going to expose an interface using periodic checks on that interface.
You can check whether your app is still healthy.
The typical production application behind a Load Balancer should always have health checks implemented
in some way to ensure availability and resiliency of the application.
Even if you're using AWS and the Load Balancer the health checks are not checking whether your pod is healthy,
it is only checking, but the node port is accessible.
So, even when you are using the AWS Load Balancer, you're going to want these types of health checks as well.
This is how a health check looks like on our example container.
Here again I have the pod, the example pod, and here is then in bold.
The health check.
It's a "livenessProbe" using an "httpget" on just path which means just the main website.
On the production application you're probably going to have something like, "/health".
But here I don't have a separate health page, so I'm just using "/".
The port is going to be Port 3000, which is the container port, or if you give your container port a name,
then you can use that name.
There's an initial delay in seconds, so the "livenessProbe" is going to wait 15 seconds
and there's a timeout of 30 seconds.
How does exactly it works?
I will show you in the next demo.