In this lecture, I'll be talking about Volume Provisioning. The Kubernetes plugins have the capability
to provision storage for you. The AWS plugin can for instance provision storage for you by creating
the volumes in AWS before attaching them to a node, instead of you entering the command to create a
new volume, Kubernetes will make the API calls to do that for you.
This is done using the StorageClass object.
This was still beta, when writing this course, but it will be stable soon.
It's best to double check the correct definitions in the documentation.
Every time you see beta you might want to check that.
So, here's a link that goes to the definitions of the persistent volumes.
I'll also keep my GitHub repository up to date with the latest definitions.
To use the auto provisioned volumes,
you can create the following YAML file.
It's very simple,
The kind is storage class.
The API version refers to a beta, the name that I gave to my storage class "standard",
but you can use any name.
The provision is going to be "aws-ebs", so we're going to provision ebs volumes for us.
Then we have EBS specific parameters like type and zone.
Type is "gp2".
The zone is "us-east-1".
This will allow you to create a volume claims using the "aws-ebs" provisioner.
Kubernetes will provide volumes of the "gp2" type for you,
which means general purpose, it is SSD.
You also have provisioned SSD and magnetic. Next you can create a volume claim and specify the size of the
volume that you want.
So, here's my volume claim ".yml", it is of "kind: PersistentVolumeClaim".
API version here is "v1", because volume claims are part of the stable API.
I give the name.
The annotation, this is refers to the standard storage class that I created earlier.
And, in the specifications it is "ReadWriteOnce"
I can only have one EBS volume that I can read and write to at the same time.
The request is going to be for 8 gigabytes.
Finally, you can then launch a pod using this volume.
So, here we have again the "volumeMounts", "mountPath", a "name".
This example is a nginx example, if you wanted to run nginx  with some static data,
then you use the nginx image, then you are going to use a "mountPath",
that is going to provide the volume for "/var/www/html"
The name of the volume is "mypd". Volumes, here is the name also "mypd" and then this persistent volume claim refers to my claim,
which is the name of the persistent volume claim from the previous slide.
You can then put some static data in this volume and
then when you browse this URL, you will see your data.
It's very simple.
The next lecture will be a demo where I will demonstrate this auto provisioning.