In this demo, I'm going to show how you can use Wordpress with Volumes.
Let's have a look at the files in Wordpress Volumes.
Lots of files.
Let's first start with a "storage.yml".
Here, I'm going to define a StorageClass,
standard storage, gp2, type storage, using aws-ebs volumes in the eu-west-1a zone.
because this is the zone that my Kubernetes cluster is running in. And, have a storage cloud
so I also "pv-claim.yml",
and this is going to be the persistent volume claim for my database, so it's going to be called "db-storage"
and I'm going to use 8 gigabytes, and this is going to be the storage
that is going to be used in the database pod.
So, let's have a look at this database pod, "wordpress-db.yml".
Now, I'm just using a very simple replication controller, with only one replica, because I never want more
than one instance of this pod running.
It's going to be a "mysql:5.7".
And I am going to add the arguments, "--ignore-db-directory=lost+found",
because this directory "lost+found"
will exist in our directory
where are we going to put our files.
It will become clear in a few seconds.
This is still the same, this is also the same, I'm just defining the root password that comes from the secrets.
And then we have a volumeMount.
Are we going to mount, "/var/lib/mysql",
this is going to come from "mysql-storage". "Mysql-storage" refers to a persistent falling claim
Called DB storage.
This one with 8Gi, this volume will be created by Amazon automatically,
we don't have to create it ourselves.
It will then, be mounted here,
and because this is a new podition a new volume with a podition on it,
there is a directory "lost+found" that is created in Linux.
So, that's why we're going to say ignore database directory "lost+found".
Otherwise, our database won't start.
Then we need a service for that.
So, we going to create a service "wordpress-db",
which we then can use in our other pod,
the one that is going to run the Wordpress itself.
Let me just show you the credentials, plus here we have Wordpress secrets.
So, here we have a database password, which is the used passwords,
and these are all going to be used in the Wordpress pod.
We need to supplying them, because WordPress needs them, and they need to be seen for every pod.
Let's have a look at how these variables are used in the "wordpress-web-yml".
It's a deployment.
We can run two replicas, because this pod can horizontally scale. I am still going to use still the wordpress 4-php7.
We define a wordpress database password, which is the same as the mysql,
and then, we define these "AUTH_KEY", "LOGGED_IN_KEY", because those keys need to be the same for all the pods.
We have two pods, so those keys need to be the same because your session
might otherwise differ between the pods.
So, these we just need to do because of wordpress itself. And then, we are going to add a volume mount.
We are going to use a volume for this "/wp-content/uploads".
In wordpress you can upload pictures, we want these pictures to be available on all the pods.
So, we need to have some shared storage.
On Amazon, we can use you for that EFS for that, elastic file system.
This is an EFS file system and this EFS file system is write and read on every node, every pod that
is going to mount, can read and write to that.
EFS is not fit for mysql, that's why we're are using block storage for that.
But, we can use it for images, for just storing small files.
This is going to be the server, we just need to change a string, because we have to create a new EFS volume first,
because this is not auto provisioned.
And then, it will mount this EFS right here.
So, let's see did I cover everything.
Well we still have a service, a Wordp ress web service, and this is just going to put a load balancer in
front of these two pods, so that we can connect to the Wordpress using our browser.
Let's create this EFS volume, we can use the AWS wordpress command for that.
So, first it "aws efs create-file-system",
you need to specify "creation-token" which needs to be unique.
I've already used one, so I am going to use "2", and this is going to create an EFS file system.
Then, we need to create an EFS mount target.
We going to create a mount target using this file system ID.
So, we're going to say, "--file-system-id". And then, this string that comes from here.
And we need to create this in the same subnet ID as our cluster.
So, we need to figure out first the subnet ID of our cluster in another window.
You can do, "aws ec2 describe-instances". And here, somewhere here, you are going to find
one of your instances and it's going to be a subnet ID.
This is one of our instances, where you're going to use this something that ID.
Then, we need a security group.
And, if two instances are in the same security group then they can access each other.
So, we are just going to use the security group, also from this node on the Kubernetes,
this is a security group "nodes.kubernetes.newtech.academy", so I am going to use this security group.
So, it should work.
And now it is creating.
So, we just need to take this string, the file system ID and replace this in our "wordpress-web.yml".
So, this needs to be the zone.
"eu-west-1" for me and then ID.
And then the region right here.
And "amazonaws.com".
So, this should work.
So, let's now create all the resources.
Let's start with the database.
So I am going to do, "kubectl create", storage first.
"-f storage.yml". Then, the "pv-claim.yml", the secrets,
and the database.
And, let's have a look whether a service is needed as well.
And then let's have a look whether
our volume is created.
Yes.
So, this is the "pvc".
This is for storage.
The "db-storage" is bound.
Okay, secrets will be created.
It's all very difficult.
And, then we have the wordpress-db,
and this can take some time for us.
Describe pod.
And it's just pulling the image. So, I mounted the "PersistentVolumeClaim" and it is pulling this image.
So, this actually created a new EBS volume for us and this "av" by the ebs volume is going to be used to store
my secret data on. These containers started, there we go. It's now running.
So, which one do we still need to create? "Kubectl create", and then let's create the web services.
It can take some time for EFS to be created.
So, we have to be patient a little bit, but then we should be able to create the web and the service,
and the service is going to launch a load balancer.
And if you want to use a proper DNS name you can go to route 53.
So, if you go to route 53, then you can go to DNS management, your DNS name, and you could create a new
recordset.
You could say Wordpress.
I actually already have one, but you could create a new one.
Let me first leave the old one.
So Wordpress is an AWS and then it's going to load the ELB classical load balancer, it takes a few seconds
and then we have our load balancers.
So, these are the load balancers created by Kubernetes.
Click create, and then you'll be able to access the "wordress.kubernetes.newtech.academy" and here then
we have our Wordpress installation.
So, we just do the install.
Here is my blog.
My username there is an autogenerated password for me.
Login with the same passwords.
And then I have my wordpress running.
The main difference now is that, two things,
I have two pods running that are going to handle the web requests, and the one pod running that is
going to handle the database, and the database data is saved in a volume.
So I'm not going to lose it.
I also have this EFS volume to create media or to upload to be able to upload media, but there is a
small but here, that it will not allow me immediately to run media, because look if I select a file,
it is going to say, "Unable to create directory in this volume", because this directory is not writable and
it is just because the image, the Wordpress image, was not built to be working on Kubernetes with
these EFS volumes.
So, a couple of ways to fix this issue,
you could just build your own image of Wordpress, and maintain your own image, or what I'm going to do
is going to change a CMD when it starts, with the risk that if the CMD ever changes for Wordpress
then it might not work anymore.
So, I'll probably not commit this to my repository,
but you can always make the changes yourself to make this work.
So, let's say that you want that we want to edit
our deployments, the "wordpress-deployments".
And then if you scroll down, here are the container's spec you, just add these commands.
"bash", execute a command, and then change the permissions, or change ownership to correct user and group of this directory
then run this "docker-entrypoint.sh Apache2-foreground"
So, if this "docker-entrypoint.sh" will change in the future,
then this command doesn't work, but you just would have to change
into the real command, which you can find on Docker Hub. So, you save this and then now we can test it.
So, now let me refresh this page, and I will add a new file,
and now it uploads. This is the file that uploaded, and I can make a change to a post, "My image" and media, this image,
"Insert Picture", Update, and then there's my blog.
So, let me show you that the volume actually works.
"Kubectl get pod", and let me just delete this pod here.
"delete pod" and let me deletes those other pods as well.
And I'm just to delete this last pod as well.
All my pods are moved.
And what is going to happen.
Kubernetes is going to spin up some new pods.
This one is creating again and these ones are already running.
So, you just have to give it some time and noe everything is running again
Let's have a look at the logs for those things.
Wordpress successfully installed.
Let's execute this pod.
Let's executes within the bash this pod.
Let's have a look in our contents, our uploads, and here we still have, here we still have our image.
So, even after I killed the pod, even after I deleted the pods, we still have our image.
Let me have a look at the database.
Database started again and even already refreshed.
I still have all my data, still available.
"Hello World" with the image.
Even after our pod was crashed, even after my node would be crashed, Kubernetes would just shuffle
The pods when there is capacity, detach and attach volume necessary if necessary,
so that my blog keeps on running.
So that's it for this lecture, for this demo.
I think this was a very useful demo to show the capabilities of Kubernetes.
Some things I showed you are still in beta.
Be very careful with those features.
But it is all very promising.
Also, when you clean up, make sure that you go to elastic file systems in AWS,
and you delete this file system.
This is EFS in AWS.
And click on delete file system, because otherwise you will be paying for it.