At this point,
you should've set up your Vagrant box,
you should've set up AWS,
so now we can set up our Kubernetes cluster
using kops.
Here, I'm logged in to
my Ubuntu xenia logs.
Before submitting the cluster
you need to make sure that you have
kubectl installed as well.
This URL you can find in the procedure document.
You can just download it.
You move it
to /usr/local/bin/
exactly where kops is, as well
and you give it
execution permissions.
Then you start kubectl.
You have kubectl
available.
Before creating the cluster you will also have to
create new SSH keys.
Those SSH keys will be used
to login to the cluster.
SSH keygen can create new keys.
So, what I'm going to do is
I'm going to create a new key
in .ssh/id_rsa.
This public key,
id_rsa.pub
will be uploaded to our instances.
That way, we will be able to login to our instances
using our private key.
So, id_rsa is our private key
and this is our public key.
The public key goes in the instance
and we login with the private key.
Just one thing I want to do
before I'm going to enter the kops command is,
I'm just going to rename the kops binary.
I'm going to rename it to just kops,
rather than having kops-linux-amd64.
This is the kops command I'm going to execute
and this kops command is not going to do anything yet,
because it needs another step before
it's really going to execute
the commands on the AWS.
But this one is going to create one master,
a t2.micro and two nodes.
Also, t2.micro.
So we have kops create cluster,
give the name,
this needs to be the full DNS name of the cluster.
I have kubernetes.newtech.academy,
the one that I setup in the root of the tree.
I'm going to save the state in s3,
it's my s3 bucket
and I'm going to launch it in the eu-west-1a zone.
You're probably going to use another zone
us-east-1a, us-west-1a and so on.
Node-count is two
and the node size t2.micro.
The master size is also t2.micro
and the DNS zone is is kubernetes.newtech.academy.
I'm going to execute this
and then you'll be able to preview the changes
that will be made to AWS.
So, it's going to make
Auto Scaling Groups for our nodes.
It's going to launch a master,
it's going to provision also SSD drives.
Then, if you want to really launch this cluster
then we can just do this with kops update cluster
and then the name with --yes
and then it's going to launch.
If you want to make changes first,
you can edit the cluster, using kops edit cluster
and then the name.
But because the state is on s3,
you also have to specify the state.
Then the command will work
and then you can still make some changes.
I'm not going to make any changes at this point,
I'm just going to launch the cluster.
I'm going to use kops update cluster
and then specify yes
and again I will specify the state.
This will then launch the cluster,
it will take a couple of minutes
and then I can try to run one of the examples.
So, now the cluster has been created.
Let's have a look what this means.
Wrote config for kubernetes.newtech.academy
in this file.
I'm just going to get to this file.
This is actually the certificates that we need
and the password to login to our new cluster.
That's what kops configured already for us.
So, for instance,
we have here the server:
https://api.kubernetes.newtech.academy
and that's what you'll be able to use.
Let's see if the nodes are up.
So, kubectl get node.
Three nodes here on Ready status.
One master.
This is going to be the master,
it's in a different IP range
and then two nodes.
Let's try to run the same deployment
as we did on the minikube cluster.
To test whether our Kubernetes cluster using kops
is working.
So, I'm going to do kubectl run hello-minikube,
which is the name of the deployment
and it's going to use this image.
The echoserver version 1.4.
An echoserver in this docker container
listens on port=8080.
So, specify port 8080 as argument.
This is going to create the deployment "hello-minikube"
and now we can also expose the service
so that we can access it externally.
You can do it using kubectl expose deployment,
the name of the deployment which is hello-minikube
and we give it a type.
This is the type of the service.
For example,
if you want a loadbalancer in front of this service,
then we can say type=loadbalancer,
which I'll cover in the next lecture.
I'll do now
a more simple version,
just NodePort,
which will expose a port
on every node of this Kubernetes cluster,
that we can contact the service on.
It is on every node except the master.
You can connect to every node
on a specific port,
but not on the master.
So, service hello-minikube exposed.
So, for now I'll do a kubectl get services.
We see now our hello-minikube service,
type NodePort
and this is the port that we can contact
our service on.
This port is now open
on every single node in our Kubernetes cluster,
except the master.
Let's have a look at the AWS console.
Let's first go to EC2.
Make sure that you are in the correct region.
I launched in Ireland,
so I am in the Ireland region.
Then you should see three running instances.
So, I have here
two nodes and one master node.
This one is terminated,
so you can ignore this one.
If you don't see your nodes,
you can also have a look
at the Auto Scaling Group,
which is here on the left.
Auto Scaling Groups.
You should have two Auto Scaling groups.
One for the master
and one for the nodes.
This Auto Scaling group that will launch instances.
So, if something is wrong,
for example, if you're reaching AWS limits,
then it should be displayed here,
than for some reason it couldn't launch an instance.
But, for us, everything runs fine.
We have two instances running.
We exposed the node port,
which means that
those two nodes will reply
on this port
and redirect my traffic to this service.
Before we can access it, you need to make sure
that a firewall is not blocking us.
Well, these nodes have also firewall.
They have a security group.
To see the security group,
you can just click on the instance
and then you can see the inbound and outbound rules.
So, here, port 22 is open,
but not the node port that we just
created using this service.
So, we will need to make changes to this.
You will click on the security group
and go to inbound,
click edit
and you can add a new rule.
You can say
Custom TCP.
I can copy and paste the port
that's exposed.
This was 30032.
I can paste this here
and you can either open it for everyone
0.0.0.0/0
or only for my IP address.
I'll go choose only my IP address.
So, only me will be able to access this service.
I click save.
I can go back to my node
and I can take either--
I can take the external IP address of this node
or of this node.
The IPv4 Public IP address
this is here.
I can copy this
and if I got to this IP address port 30032
I get the response from my service
that I launched on my Kubernetes cluster.
So, this works.
I have a running Kubernetes cluster.
I have two normal nodes and one master node.
I created our first deployment,
our fist service
and I exposed a node port that I now
can connect to
using the IP address of
any of those two nodes.
In the next lecture I will explain to you
a better approach using a loadbalancer,
that also gives you a host name.
Then you can also use a DNS to
give your service a real DNS name.
A real domain name.
Once you did this demo
and you're not using the cluster anymore.
I would recommend you to remove the cluster.
I will show you how to do that.
To delete our cluster
we can do kops delete cluster.
Then the name of the cluster
kuberenetes.newtech.academy in my case.
We can also add the state.
The state is an s3.
Then it's going to show us
what will be removed.
You must specify
yes to delete cluster.
You're going to execute the same command
using --yes
and it will then bring the cluster down again.
Then, the next time you want to use it again
you can just execute
kops create again,
like you did in the beginning of this lecture.
If you have any issues
with bringing up this cluster,
there's a trouble shooting lecture
if you have DNS issues
or you can use the Q &amp; A to ask me questions
if you run into any problems.
If everything went fine,
just continue with the next lectures.
This deleting of the cluster will take
a couple of minutes.
Then your cluster is removed.