In this lecture, I'll be talking about High Availability, if you're going to run your cluster in production,
You're going to want to have all your master services in a high availability set up. This set up looks like
this, you're going to cluster "etcd", at least you're going to run three "etcd" the nodes.
If you just run one and "etcd" fails then Kubernetes is not working anymore.
So, you need at least three nodes for high availability. You're going to replicate your API service with a load balancer and
you're going to run multiple instances of the scheduler and the controllers.
Only one of them will be the leader,
the other ones are going to be on standby.
Here is an overview of the "etcd" clusters that are typically run.
You can run one, you don't have high availability.
You can run three.
This is typical set up.
Or if you start getting a really big cluster then you're going to run five "etcd" nodes.
So, this is then how an architecture looks like with high visibility.
If you take a look at the top left, "kubectl" is now going to connect to a load balancer. So, are the Kubernetes nodes,
they will also going to connect to this load balancer.
This load balancer will then go to the rest of the interfaces on either "Master 1" or "Master 2".
Typically, if you don't go for high availability, you're going to want three nodes. Every node is unique,
so you just have to spin up multiple master nodes with the same image or the same software.
The rest the API will communicate with "etcd" not shown on this graph.
But then, you also have the components that make changes to the API like the scheduler
and the controller manager.
You can only have one active scheduler and one active control manager.
That's why on "Master 2" and on any other masters you will see that they are great out, they are on standby.
You also have a "kubelet" installed on your masters and you can also have "monit", which will then monitor "kupelets".
A cluster like minikube doesn't really need HA.
It's only a one note cluster.
If you are going to use a production cluster on AWS, kops can do the heavy lifting for you.
If you are running on another cloud platform,
have a look at the kube deployment tools for that platform.
Kubeadmin is a tool that is in alpha, but it's very promising that it can set up a cluster for you.
If you are on a platform without a tooling.
Have a look at this URL to implement it yourself.
In the next demo, I'll show you how to modify the kops set up to run multiple master nodes.