I'm going to show you how kops can run multiple masters.
I'm logged in here in my ubuntu-xenial and
you can answer arguments to kops to run multiple masters.
Have a look at this command for instance. "kops create cluster".
Then we have the name, the state which is S3, and then the zones,
you can actually specify multiple zones.
This is going to make it a little bit more complex when launching volumes, because pods that use EBS volumes
they need to be launched in the same zone.
But Kubernetes labels nodes, so you can easily use nodes like they are running pods.
You will have therefore a cluster that spans multiple zones.
Still the same region but multiple zones.
You can increase the "node-count" or you can leave it at two.
If you leave it at two, you will launch only two zones, if you increase it to three
or more, you will cover out regions. The "node-size" is still the same, the "master-size" is the same,
"dns-zone" is "kubernetes.newtech.academy",
and then here, "master-zones".
So, here you specify three "master-zones", which will mean that you have threes masters running in each zone.
So, we're going to go ahead and create this cluster and then we go to preview the change that we will make.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to show you the configuration of what is going to happen.
So, here we have the node configuration the instance groups.
So, you see here "miniSize: 2", "maxSize: 2", "t2.micro", and we have three zones.
If you still only want to launch your slave nodes you could just remove "b" and "c" here.
Then the master nodes that's a master, "master-eu-west-1a".
It's going to be our first master of size 1.
Then we can have
a second master, "master-eu-west-1b", and then you are going to have a third master.
So, even if a full zone fails, our master will still be working.
And if your cluster spans multiple zones, then you cluster will also be able to still keep on working, even if one of them
completely fails.
So that's it for this demo.
As you can see kops has ways to edit the configuration files, to make some changes, and to make your own
custom cluster.