In this lecture,
I want to show you the pod lifecycle.
This is a diagram that I created
to give you a better idea of what really happens
when you launch a pod.
This diagram also shows you the init container
that you can use,
the post start hook and the pre stop hook.
Those you can define in your yaml file,
in your pod specification, to execute commands
on certain points in the lifecycle of the pod.
Let's start with the init container.
When you define an init container in your pod specification
you can launch a new container that is separate
from the main container that will execute some commands.
This can be interesting if you have volumes,
for example, to do some work on those volumes,
set some permissions create on directories
before the main container starts.
So this is a completely separate container
and the main container will only start
after the init container is completed.
Then we have the post start hook,
and the post start hook starts at the same time
as the main container if you define it
in your container definition,
and it starts within the main container,
so you can just execute
some commands within the main container.
Again, if you need to do some work
just when the container starts.
Then we have the pre stop hook,
and that one is going to be executed
when the container stops.
So here, again, if you have to do some work
when the container stops then you can use a pre stop hook.
We have the main container,
and within the main container we can also define
the readiness probe and the liveness probe.
These readiness probes and liveness probes
will only start after the initialDelaySeconds
that you define as well in your probes.
So the moment that your main container starts,
this initialDelaySeconds will delay the readiness probe
and the liveness probe,
because often you're app needs some time to start
to connect with database and it doesn't make sense
to immediately start a probe,
but often it only makes sense after a couple of seconds,
to then start checking whether the app is working.
So this is the pod lifecycle.
Now let's go over the different states.
When the container is running the init container
then you will see in the describe,
if you go and take a look at the conditions
that initialized is still false,
ready is still false, but the pod is scheduled.
So the pod is scheduled, the init container is running,
it means that initialize is false.
Then after the post start hook is executed,
initialized will be true,
it will still not be ready,
and the PodScheduled is still true.
The reason why it's not ready is because the readiness probe
hasn't executed.
So if you have a readiness probe,
only after the readiness probe returns success,
then we have initialized true, ready true,
and then the pod is scheduled.
And then the pod is live.
It will be added to the service
and traffic will be routed to this pod.
In the next demo I will launch a container
that has all these elements in it
so that you can see them being executed.