In this lecture I will show you
the metrics using Grafana.
In Istio you can also have Metrics with Grafana.
In this lecture I will show you how to reach
the Grafana Dashboard and interpret the metrics.
Just like I did with the distributed tracing,
you can have a look at the services of istio-system,
and you can expose one of the services using port forwarding
or using a load balancer.
Also if you're using a load balancer,
everyone can contact it,
so you might also want to contour some security groups
to make sure that only you can contact it,
or put the load balancer private, for example.
So here we have Grafana, so let's edit this service,
edit svc grafana, and we'll also turn this cluster IP
into a load balancer.
This will speed up a load balancer for Grafana,
so let's get our services from istio-system using -o wide.
And then we have here our external host name on port 3000
that we can use to access Grafana.
So this is the load balancer euro port 3000,
and then you will see the Grafana Dashboard.
You can click on Home, and there you will see
all the predefined dashboards.
So we have the Istio Galley Dashboard, Mesh Dashboard,
Service Dashboard, and the Workload Dashboard,
and then we have the Mixer and the Pilot Dashboard.
Let's have a look at the Istio Service Dashboard.
So, here we see all our services are helloservice
is liked by default here.
This is the first one, and there's currently no volume.
So let's go back to our terminal,
and let's contact this app again.
This is the Istio ingress gateway on hello.
Get Hello, World! because our hello application is deployed.
If it's not deployed, then you can
just redeploy helloworld.yaml and helloworld gateway.yaml.
So we generated some traffic.
Let's go back to our Grafana Dashboard.
And now we see there's Client Request Volume 0.8 operations.
The Server Request Volume, 100% was successful.
There's no hp-500 responses, and we also see here
that all the requests were under 30 milliseconds.
We also see here the incoming requests.
I did here 2.2 operations per second.
And then right here five seconds later,
I did only 0.8 operations per second.
So this is the hello.default.
So if you have then a look at our world.default,
then we'll also see that our world
has Client Requests and Server Requests.
And if you then go to world-2.default service,
then we also see Incoming Requests,
and everything was successful.
So this is a nice dashboard that you can use
to see your traffic that is incoming,
whether there are errors on your services,
whether everything is healthy.
This is a Service Dashboard,
but you also have for example the Mixer, the Pilot Dashboard
that can give you some general information
about the health of your Istio Service, itself.
So for example, the Mixer can tell you
how much memory is in use, CPU, Disk, Goroutines,
the incoming requests that go into the Mixer.
So, this can give you some general idea
of the health of Istio itself.
And then you also have the Pilot Dashboard.
This is the Istio Pilot here are also some server metrics,
Memory, CPU, Disk, Goroutines, that you can see
whether this is healthy or not.
So mainly I think that
the Istio Service Dashboard is really interesting
because you can drill down on the services that are deployed
on your cluster and have a look at how they are performing.
In general the request rate, for example,
is a very interesting metric.
If this goes too high
then it can have impact to your clients
that are trying to reach your service, for example.
I would say have a look at it yourself.
Expose this service as a load balancer
or just use port forwarding
to have a look at this dashboard.