In this demo, I'm going to show you how to push a docker image to Docker Hub
I am again logged into my ubuntu-xenial box and I'm going to use Docker login first.
If you don't have a Docker ID yet, you have to go first to "http://hub.docker.com"
This is the Website. If you're new to Docker, you can create your free Docker ID, you just have to enter your
email address and a password and you can sign up.
And then you can use those credentials to log in here.
So, I'm going to enter my username, and my password, and then I am logged in. Once logged in, you can create
a new Repository. Your repository is always going to be prefixed by your user name.
And then you can enter a name.
For instance you can say docker-demo, then you give it a short description maybe a full description
and you can make it public or private. At the moment, you can only have a limited private repositories
but you can have unlimited public repositories.
I already have a repository, my repository is "k8s-demo", and that is the repository that I'm going
to use.
Feel free to take any name that you want.
So the next step, is to tag our image, a previously create image, with the repository name that we specified
in Docker Hub.
So, I'm going to use "k8s-demo". So, I am going to tag this image with this.
If you don't remember your tag anymore, you can use docker images, which is just going to list all the images
of your system.
Here is my node image for instance.
And then you will see the image that you have created.
I have this one now tagged
So, this is my image and my image is now tagged with the name. So, I can now docker push this image to my repository
So, I'm going to push this to "docker.io/wardviaene/k8s-demo"
This will take some time to upload and then if you take another look at Docker Hub, you will see
"Last pushed: a few seconds ago"
And then here within tree specify a tag name, it has a tag name "latest", and it is 256 megabytes.
You can specify a tag name, if you don't
It just takes "latest".
So, docker tag with column "latest" is exactly the same as not doing it.
So, we can either tag it with "latest" or we can give the version ID.
I'm not going to give it a version ID, I am just going to use "latest".
So, now everything is ready to use this image that we just pushed to Docker Hub, to use this in kubernetes.
So, that will be the next step in the next lecture
I will show you how to run this image on kubernetes.