Now let's upload our image to Docker Hub, I will now explain to you how to run this app on Kubernetes
Let's run our newly built application on a new Kubernetes cluster. Before we can launch a container
based on this image
we need to create "pod definition". A pod describes an application running on Kubernetes.
A pod can contain one or more tightly coupled containers that make up the app. Those apps can easily
communicate with each other using their local port numbers.
So, if you would have another app, you can just connect to that app on that port. Our app only has one container
to make this app running on your Kubernetes cluster you create a pod file, for instance
"pod-helloworld.yml" with the pod definition.
This is ".yml" file in the YAML format, if you want to know more about the YAML format then you can just look it up
on Google.
It starts with the API version as v1.
This is a pause definition.
So, you say, "Kind: pod". You can provide metadata,
you can give your pod a name. This pod is named
nodehelloworld.example.com
We can also give it a label
Later on we can easily filter on labels.
This pod has the label "app" as a key, "helloworld" as a value
"spec" you are going to put the container definitions.
We only have one container.
We're going to give it a name, the name of this container is "k8s-demo" and image refers to the image
that you uploaded to Docker Hub.
First you login, "wardviaene" is my login
Then "/", and then, the repository name. The ports that you want to expose on this pod.
Here I'm going to expose container port 3000.
You can use "kubectl" if you have to create the pods one the Kubernetes cluster. You just use "kuvectl create -f" and then the path to this YAML file.
All these YAML files are bundled in under git repository. The role of that git repository
you can find in the procedure document again.
Here are some useful commands that they can use on pods.
I'll just briefly go over the list now and then I will then show them in action during the demos.
"kubectl get pod", gets information about all the running pods.
So, once you create a new pod it's probably the first command that you are going to execute.
"kubectl describe pod", and then you can insert your pod name, describes just one pod.
So this gives you more information.
"kubectl expose pod", and the pod name, and a port, and a name, this exposes a port of a pod.
So, it creates a new service and then you can connect to your Kubernetes cluster
on that port and it will redirect to your pod. ""kubectl port-forward", and then a pod name, and then a port number
You can port-forward the exposed pod port to your local machine and then on your local machine you can go
to that port and to port-forward to the pod.
You can also attach a pod to see what is really happening in your pod.
You can execute commands on the pod, so this is done just execute a command in the container.
If you have multiple containers you can specify specific containers using "-c".
Otherwise, it will just take the first container. You can still label pods after they have been created.
So, if you want to add another label then we can do it like this.
And then this is very useful for debugging.
You can run a shell in a pod and then you're going to run "kubectl", you are going to specify an image
and the image can be "busybox", "busybox" is a very small image that can start you a shell and when you have
a shell you can debug anything that goes wrong much easier.
Because then, you are in a new pod and it can connect to your pod that maybe is malfunctioning.
In the next demo.
I will then show you how to launch this pod.