Now I'm going to talk about Resource Usage Monitoring.
Heapster enables Container Cluster Monitoring and Performance Analysis.
It's providing a monitor platform for Kubernetes.
It is a prerequisite if you want to do pod auto-scaling in Kubernetes.
Pod auto-scaling is going to be the next topic after monitoring. Heapster exports the cluster metrics via REST endpoints.
So, other technologies can then query Heapster to get the metrics.
You can use different backends with Heapster.
So, our backend is where the metric data is stored.
I will use the InfluxDB.
But others like Google Cloud Monitoring or Google Logging and Kafka are also possible.
InfluxDB is a database that is fit for time series.
That's why it's a good fit for our Heapster metric data.
Visualisations, graphs, can be shown using Grafana. So, with InfluxDB we can deploy Grafana
The Kubernetes dashboard that I showed you earlier,
the web UI, also shows graphs, once monitoring is enabled.
You don't even have to use Grafana and you can just see the graphs in the dashboard as well.
All these technologies Heapster, InfluxDB, and Grafana can be started in pods.
The yaml files can be found on the GitHub repository of Heapster.
This is the url that I am going to use, it is still Kubernetes GitHub account, but then there's not a report called Heapster.
You are typically going to use the master branch, because
that is the most up to date branch.
After downloading the repository, the whole platform can be deployed using addon system
Or just by using, "kubectl create -f",
and then the directory with all the yaml files.
If you don't use the addon system, if you are just going to deploy it using "kubecontrol", then you need to make some changes in the files,
which I will be explaining in the next time I am on. This is roughly how it looks like, this can change a little bit,
because there are still a few outstanding issues to make this a little more performant
and the Kubernetes team might make some changes, but this is on a high level how it's going to look like.
On the right, what we are going to deploy is the Heapster Pod,
the InfluxDB Pod, and the Grafana Pod.
The node has a process "cAdvisor", which is now in the Kubernetes, but it's going to be separate in the future.
That's why I put it a little bit out of the "kubelet" this is going to get all the metrics from the pods,
and send all those metrics to Heapster, it is then going to save this in InfluxDB
and then get an overview of those metrics in graphs using Grafana.
So, basically all the data goes from the kubelets to Heaps and Heaps then saves it into InfluxDB.
In the next demo,
I'll show you how to set this up.