I am going to show you two demos using "Secrets".
One demo will  just be my very simple example app,
and on another demo I am going to show you, how to set up a WordPress using the secrets as environment variables.
Let's first start with the first one, secrets as volumes.
I first need to set up the secrets in my deployment I have "helloworld-secrets.yml"
"helloworld-secrets" has the user name and the password "kubecontrol create"
of this file deployment "helloworld-secrets.yml"
And then I have another deployment.
I have a "helloworld" with secrets as volumes, 3 replicas of this one.
One container of "volumeMount"
And this is the volume with the secret name "db-secrets", the one I just created in Kubernetes
and this will be monitored under
"/etc/creds/", "kubectl create" again
and then, let me just get the pods.
All of them are running.
Let me describe one of them.
Describe vault and what I want to show you first is what I mentioned in the beginning that
Kubernetes itself also uses the Secrets in the volumes to share the Kubernetes credentials,
and if you can see here volumeMounts, we already have a volume, "/var/run/secrets/kubernetes.io/serviceaccount from default-token-hctrk"
This is a volume that is already mounted and is done by Kubernetes itself to share
the secrets within the pod.
So, the pod can access the API and then we have "/etc/creds", the one that we created from the "cred-volume".
So, let's start a shell, "kubecontrol execute", the pod name, we are going to execute something on the pod, as our flags
to the standard input that we can actually type in some commands,
and then we are going to execute "/bin/bash", which is a shell.
And this just gives us a shell on one of the pods.
If we didn't take a look at what's in "/etc/secrets/username", then you see root, which is in username and password--
It's in "password".
So, our credentials are available in this "/etc/creds", your application just has to read those files.
And then, those values-- the data in those files can be used, for instance, to connect to a database.
And that's exactly what I'm going to show you in the next demo.
I'm going to show you how to use credentials to spin up a database and WordPress
if you enter "mount".
Then you also see all the main points,
and here are two volumes that are mounted.
So, this one is the default one,
you can have a look at it.
It has a token and a certificate that can be used to access the API.
"exit" exits from the shell.
And then you're ready for the next demo.