Before you start
with the Heapster Grafana demo,
I want to make you aware
that now Heapster is actually deprecated.
So for new clusters, is actually not necessary
anymore to install Heapster to get your metrics.
There's now a metrics-server that came out that you can use.
The metrics-server is a stripped down version of Heapster,
is very similar but you cannot extract
any metrics from it anymore.
So, you cannot use sink to InfluxDB
and show your metrics in Grafana.
So now if you want to show external metrics,
it's a little bit unclear how you have to do that.
You will have to use a third-party tool like Prometheus.
But, that's out of the plantation art yet,
and still metrics-server is incubating,
so it's a little bit early to do a full demo
that shows you the statistics in Grafana.
But I can already show you how to install metrics-server
rather than using Heapster for newer clusters
because Heapster will be deprecated from version 1.11.
So, this is the Heapster GitHub proposed tree,
and from Kubernetes 1.11, there's an initial deprecation.
So, no new features or sinks will be added.
Bug fixes might be made,
and then, starting from 1.13, Heapster will be retired.
At that point you should be using
the metrics-server instead.
The metrics-server is still in Kubernetes incubator,
but it's now the way to go
to get you node and bottom metrics.
So, if you choose from metrics-server
instead of Heapster with Influx in Grafana,
you don't really have a front end.
Even the dashboard hasn't changed it's code yet,
but I'm pretty sure that it's gonna happen very soon.
Then, rather than using Grafana, you're just gonna get
the metrics in the Kubernetes dashboard,
and then you don't even need Grafana anymore
unless for other statistics,
but not for these specific statistics
that you then just need maybe for both out of scaling.
So Metrics-Server is definitely the way to go in the future.
So let me show you how it is set up.
In my Kubernetes course get repository,
I have directory.
Metrics-Server and here I have all the yellow fast copies.
So I just do Kubctl create over this directory.
Then I should be able to do Kubectl top,
so let me just show you without further arguments.
So you can do kubctl top node and kubctl top pod.
So let's try kubctl top node first.
No metrics available yet and actually it takes some time
to create those.
We also need to be running a pod,
so we just run a simple service.
So I created the deployment hello-Kubernetes.
This will start a pod.
Just get pod because it ties this random string here.
Let's try again.
Top node.
Now I have statistics, so now we see CP course,
CP percentage, memory and memory percentage.
So I have three nodes.
One master node and two normal nodes.
This is the master node and these are the normal nodes.
Now let's try Kubctl top pod
and this give me then the usage of the hello-Kubernetes pod.
So it only uses two megabytes.
Currently it doesn't use any CPU
because we are not even contacting it,
we're not even using it.
So two megabytes.
If you have more ProtoNym you will learn C.
This increasing and changing.
So to do the outer scaling lecture,
which will come next, you only need the Metrics-Server.
You don't need any other component anymore
that I will still explain in the next lecture.
Because those are deprecates.
If you learn all the clusters,
then you can still use Heapster and Influx in Grafana.
But for newer clusters, starting from 1.8
you don't need this anymore,
you can use this Metrics-Server.