In this demo,
I will show you how to install Istio.
There is a directory Istio in the Kubernetes Course,
where you'll find demo files in the read me.
To install Istio using kops,
we have to make some modifications to our kops cluster.
So what I'm going to do is
I'm going to launch a new kops cluster.
We'll use kops create for that,
is the same command as we used previously
to spin up a cluster, except this time,
I'm going to use node size T2 medium
instead of T2 micro.
This will give us a lot more memory in our cluster
to launch applications.
This is because Istio needs memory
for its processes to start.
So, the pilot process now needs two gigabytes of memory,
so to make sure we have enough,
we're going to use T2 medium,
which provides four gigabytes of memory.
Add an execute command to create this cluster.
So let's have a look at the read me.
Kops edit cluster Kubernetes Newtech Academy,
plust the state, and we have to add this.
The kubeAPIServer admissionControl,
and we need to make sure that we include all
these elements to admission control,
because Istio needs those features.
Let's do kops edit cluster Kubernetes Newtech Academy
with the state.
This will open the editor, and here we have
the specification for our cluster.
And here we can add the lines.
We can add them under spec or just at the bottom,
the only thing that you have to make sure
is that the indentation is correct.
So this kubeAPIServer and then the admissionController.
I'll check whether kubeAPI server hasn't been defined yet,
in our case, it hasn't, this is the only kubeAPI server
that is in this specification.
Then we should save this.
If there is an error at this point,
check the indentation again,
because kops will give you an error
if there's something wrong.
Now we are ready, so we can do
kops update cluster, minus minus yes,
with our state from S3.
This will then spin up the cluster
we'll have to wait again, a couple of minutes.
So I'll pause the demo for a couple of minutes
and start again when the cluster is reachable.
Cluster is starting, it should be ready in a few minutes.
Let's have a look at the read me.
We can download Istio, these are the instructions
for the 1.0.1 version,
or you can download the latest version.
I'm going to download the latest version
that's currently available, which is the 1.0.1.
So we're just going to copy paste these lines,
going to execute them, so this will download Istio 1.0.1
for Linux, it will extract it in my home directory,
so I have Istio 1.0.1 in my home directory,
and also going to add this export path to my dot profile.
So every time I log in, this path,
this bin directory will be added to my path.
So that everything that is in this bin directory
the IstioCTL will be in the path,
so I will be able to execute this command.
To make this work, either you have to log out and log in,
or you can just execute this,
and then you should be able to execute IstioCTL.
So that seems to work.
So Istio configuration command line utility
is now available for use.
Let's go back to vagrant, my Kubernetes course,
Istio directory, let's have a look at the read me.
So now I can install Istio from the Istio directory,
using this command to apply the CRDs,
the Kubernetes extensions,
and I can choose to install Istio
without mutual TLS authentication,
or with mutual TLS authentication.
If enabled with, then there will be authentication
on your microservices, but it also means
that you cannot reach your services
if you don't have a certificate.
So it might make it a bit more difficult
if you already have services running on the Kubernates.
So then, to get started it's probably best
to use it without authentication,
and then when you want to bring it to production,
you can enable authentication.
So let's execute this one first,
kubectl apply, the CRDs.yaml,
so now it's applying all the custom resource definitions
that are going to be used by Istio.
Should now wait a couple of seconds, minutes,
just to make sure that those CRDs are created properly,
and then we should be able to install Istio,
we're going to install Istio with
no mutual TLS authentication for now.
Now it's creating all the Istio resources.
And now we have Istio successfully installed.
We'll have to wait a little bit
until Istio is completely started up,
so we have a name space Istio system
where all the containers need to be created first.
Give it a couple of minutes,
and in the next lecture I will show you a demo app.