I'm now going to talk about Kubeless.
Kubeless is a Kubernetes-native framework.
You can find it on github.com/kubeless/kubeless.
It leverages the Kubernetes resources
to provide auto-scaling, API routing, monitoring, and so on.
So it uses whatever is available in Kubernetes
to provide this service framework.
It uses custom resource definitions
to be able to create functions.
So, remember from earlier in the course,
there's custom resource definitions to extense
the Kubernetes API with own functionality.
So, that's what Kubeless does.
It's open source and not affiliated
with any commercial organization.
It also has a UI available for developers
to deploy functions.
With Kubeless, you deploy a function
in your preferred language.
Currently, with Kubeless,
the following runtimes are supported.
You can use Python, NodeJS, Ruby, PHP,
.NET, Golang, and some other ones,
but these are the most popular ones used.
Once you deploy your function,
you will need to determine how it will be triggered.
So, with AWS Lambda, for example,
you use the API Gateway to have it triggered using a URL.
Now, you can do the same but then
with Kubernetes and Kubeless.
Currently, the following functions are supported.
You can use HTTP functions.
HTTP functions get executed
when an HTTP endpoint is triggered.
You'll write a function and return the text or HTML
that needs to be displayed in the browser.
Kubeless uses English controller for this.
You can also have a scheduled function
where you just schedule a function on a certain time.
Or you can also use a publish and subscribe mechanism,
currently Kafka or NATS is supported.
It triggers a function when data is available
in Kafka or NATS.
And you can also use AWS Kinesis.
This one triggers based on data in AWS Kinesis,
which is similar to Kafka so it's also a purpose
of mechanism you can subscribe to this AWS Kinesis
when there is data available in it
then this will trigger the function.
Next are a few demos to show you how Kubeless works.