In this lecture I am going to show you all about scaling pods. If your application is stateless you can horizontally scale it.
Stateless means that your application doesn't have a state it doesn't write any local files
and cannot keep any local session data. If you would have two pods and the one pod is going to write
something locally, then those pods would be out of sync.
And that means that each pod would have its own state and that's why you cannot kill it. If both pods
would have always the same files.
So, they wouldn't really have their own state and if a request to one pod would always lead to the same
result as doing requests from the other pods then the pod is probably stalest.
That means that all traditional databases like mySQL, Postgres, other ones are stateful.
They have database files that cannot be split over multiple instances.
Most web applications can be made stateless. Session management needs to be done as the container.
So, if you want to get hits on your web application and you want to keep information of your visitors then you
need to use an outside service, you cannot store that kind of data within your container.
You can for instance use Memcache, or Redis, or even a database to store your sessions.
Any file that need to be saved cannot be saved locally on the container, because if you stop your
container, and you started again, the file files lost.
So, you need to also save any files you want to save outside the container, either on some shared storage
or on external service, or AWS, this can be for instance S3, which is an object storage.
Our example app is stateless,
if you would run the same at multiple times it doesn't change state,
because in our app you're actually not running anything.
If you have multiple instances of the app you will just still get
"Hello World!"
For more information about the best practices have a look at the 12factor.net. This "12factor" explains
the best practices for stateless applications or you can check out my other course "Learn DevOps:
Continuously delivering better software" or another course on
"Scaling apps on-premises in the cloud".
Both explain those principles.
Later in this course I'll explain how to use volumes to still run the stateful apps.
Those stateful apps cannot horizontally scale, but you can run them in a single container and vertically scale. To better scale
apps horizontally.
So, adding more pots, you're just going to allocate more resources like CPU, memory, and disk to that pod.
That is vertically scaling.
Scaling in Kubernetes can be done using the "Replication Controller". The Replication Controller will
ensure a specified number of pod replicas will run at all time.
So, you just specify, let's say, 5 pod replicas, and then it's going to run the same pod, but that 5 times.
A pod created with a replica controller will automatically be replaced if they fail, get deleted, or are terminated.
If you tell Kubernetes to run 5 pods and there are only 4 running, because 1 node crashed for instance
then Kubernetes will launch another instance of that pod on another node. Using the replication controller
is also recommended
If you just want to make sure your 1 pod is always running, even after reboots.
You can then run a replication controller with just 1 replica.
This makes sure that the pod is always running, even when a node crashes.
To replicate our example app of 2 times we can use this YAML file.
So, what has been changed, instead of "kind: Pod", we say "kind: Replication Controller".
We still have "metadata".
We have a "name: helloworld-controller".
The replication controller also has a spec, in this spec I am telling that
we are going have 2 replicas and this is replication controller
for the "app: helloworld"
That's why we have the selector that says, app needs to be "helloworld", which is going
to select the label with "app: helloworld".
Then we have a template,
here goes our pod definition.
The pod definition also has a "metadata".
We have the "labels", the same as you saw under the selector and then we have the pod specification.
We still have one "container" with a "name: k8s-demo", and an image, and we expose "Port 3000"
What the Replication Controller is going to do in this case is
just going to run two times the pod that is defined in a template.
How does it work on the Kubernetes cluster.
I'm going to show you in the next demo.