Let's talk about Autoscaling. Horizontal Pod Autoscaling. Kubernetes has the possibility to automatically
autoscale pods based on metrics Kubernetes can automatically scale a deployment, a replication controller,
or a replica set, in the Kubernetes 1.3, scaling based on the CPU usage is possible out of the box.
With alpha support application based metrics are also available, like queries per second or average latency.
You need to make some modifications to enable this.
The cluster has to be started with the environment variable and "ENABLE_CUSTOM_METRICS" to true.
This is probably going to change in the future, because this is still the alpha stage and they are going to make some improvements.
And scaling will periodically query the utilization for targeted pods,
by default this is every 30 seconds, but that can be changed using the "--horizontal-pod-autoscaler-sync-period" when launching the controller-manager.
If you would want to change the default value you can, but it needs to be done in the initialization script,
when the control manager starts on the master node.
Autoscaling will use heapster, the monitoring tool, to gather its metrics and make scaling decisions.
Heapster must be installed and running before autoscaling will work.
So, make sure that you followed demo that it will enable heapster.
So, here is an example.
You run a deployment with a pod, with a CPU resource request of 200 m. 200m means, 200 millicpu.
Also, sometimes called, 200 millicourse. 200m is actually 0.2 which is 20% of a CPU core of the running node.
If the node has 2 cores, it is still 20% of a single core.
So, it is absolute numbers.
You can introduce, for instance, auto-scaling at 50% of the CPU usage,
which is 100 millicpu. Horizontal Pod Autoscaling will increase or decrease force to maintain a target CPU
utilization of this 50% percent, or 100 millicpu, or 10% of a core within these pods.
So, a core on this node.
This is a pod that you can use to test autoscaling.
Here, we have deployment and in the specification we are going to use a Google image.
It is an image that has a web server that is going to do some calculations if you visit the Web site.
To make this work we are going to specify resources and we are going to request, the request CPU, 200 millicpu.
This means that we are requesting that our pod can use 200 millicpu.
We can use more but Kubernetes can use this 200 millicpu for its killing purposes.
It will not pod this pod on a node that don't have 200% of a core available anymore.
For us, in this example, these 200m are also needed for autoscaling.
So, this is an example of autoscaling specifications. This object is of "kind: HorizontalPodAutoscaler".
It has a name, also a specification, and here we are going to say that we are going to use a deployment
that needs to scale. The minimum on the replicas is going to be one and the maxReplicas is ten.
The "targetCPUUtilizationPercentage" is 50%, 50% off--
If you go back to the previous slide, then this 50% off this CPU that we requested.
So, the target is going to be 100 millicpu whether it goes higher than 100 millicpu more instances
will be launched until we reach 10 replicas.
If it is less than 50 percent then pods will be removed until we hit the minimum, which in this case is one.
In the next demo, I will show you how that works.