In this demo, I'm going to walk you through the Web UI. If using minikube, "minikube dashboard --url"
This is the correct URL that you need to access the dashboard. If you are on AWS you can use the comments
from the theory to launch you dashboards. In the end,
you should both see something like this.
This is the Kubernetes Web UI. Here we can do exactly the same as with our command utility,
"Kubectl", kube control.
We can get information from the "Namespaces"
This divides a cluster into multiple "Namespaces" the cluster in multiple "Namespaces".
We have a "default" namespace, that's where we have been deploying our apps in.
We have one note here "minikube," labels it is ready, and so it was ready for four days.
The allocated resources.
So here you find some useful metrics,
we have two gigabytes of memory, approximately 4 of 110 pods running.
It's a "Boot2Docker" image.
So, we can say we can go to deployments, for instance, we have deployments, replica sets, replicated controllers,
most of these things we've already seen, pods as well.
And then, you're the other ones I'm going to cover in the advanced section
and we have services, "Ingress" in various volumes.
I'm also going to-- "Ingress" I'm going to cover later,
"Persistent Volumes" I'm also going to cover later, "Secrets" we've already covered, and "Config Maps" is going to be very soon.
Deployments, we can just click on this create button,
and you could create a deployment right here.
You can specify these app details here or we can upload a YAML or JSON file. Rather than using YAML files
and you can also use JSON files.
It is a syntax difference.
So, let's say that I just start our "helloworld-deployment", then you click on deployments,
you see our deployment is now running.
It has a label what is actually spinning up right now.
So, it's not running yet, but now it is running three or three out of three pods and we could just
delete it from here again.
We can have we can do the actions here.
We also have the details here.
It's just a dashboard.
You can do exactly the same things as with "kubectl".
So, if you don't really like the kubecontrol tool and you have a UI, you are free to use this one rather
than kubecontrol.
Will continue with kubecontrol in next lectures.