In this demo, I'm going to show you autoscaling in action.
So, I'm in my "kubernetes-course", I have a folder autoscaling and I have just one file here "hpa-example.yml".
This is the example that I showed you during the theory.
I'm just going to add this to the cluster, so we have deployments that is created.
We have a service that is created, and we have a "horizontalpodautoscaler" that has been created.
This is a service, so my app will be accessible at Port 31001.
So, we do, "kubectl get hpa", I will see that I have a "horizontalpodautoscaler" with a "minpods" of 1, and "maxpods" of 10
and it's currently waiting until it gets some metrics, which in the beginning is going to be 0%,
because nobody is going to our app yet but that's going to change, because I'm going to launch a shell and I'm going to connect to this endpoint.
I'm going to run this image "busybox" called "load-generator", which is just a pod name, but it's just a "busybox".
And because I exposed this service right, "hpa-example" I should be able to use "wget" in this pod
to connect to the web server and fetch the index. So, "wget http://hpa-example.default.svc.cluster.local:31001", [default] which is the namespace,
[svc]for service, [cluster.local].
And this works. And what is in that "index.html"?
It just says, "Ok".
It says, "Ok", but actually it executed some code that will generate some CPU usage, so if we run this in a loop,
we will get to a higher percentage and then our autoscaling will kick in.
So, let's run this in a loop.
And now we just have to wait some time.
It takes some time like a minute or so for the autoscaler to see that there is more CPU usage and then it's going to start scaling it.
So, I am just going to open a second window and here I will check how many pods I running.
Still currently I have three pods running and what the "hpa" says about my usage.
Now I have 40%.
It needs to go a little bit higher and then it will start adding more pods.
So, I'll just pause the video for a second and when it starts scaling I will start again.
And thenm you can see currently it is now 155%.
So, it is starting to scale all these pods.
So, in a few moments I will have all these pods running, which I am going then to take all these load.
Now, what I'm going to do is, I'm just going to I'm just going to stop this one, "ctrl+c" and you can stop it.
You can even close the container or end your session, and then you can remove the whole container if you want.
What you will see now is that after a couple of minutes this load, this current load, this current usage is going
to drop again, and when it drops, it's going to get lower than the target, and then Kubernetes or the autoscaler is going to remove pods.
We're going to end up with just one pod, because if the current utilization is 0%, because I'm not hitting this website anymore,
then it will keep on downscaling until the minimum, and the minimum is one. If you want to always keep a couple of pods running,
you have to specify a minimum 3 or something like that.
In my case it will just go down to zero.
So, I'm going to give it a couple of minutes again.
And here we are a couple of minutes later, current is 0% and there's only one pod running.
All the other ones were terminated, so this basically is how out of scaling works.