In this lecture, I'll be talking about affinity
and anti-affinity in Kubernetes.
In a previous demo I showed you how to use
the node selector to make sure pods get scheduled
on specific nodes.
This was the example that I was using.
It's a deployment, and in the specifications
I used a nodeSelector to only scheduled the three
pods that the deployment is going to start,
only on nodes that have the label hardware equals high-spec.
So, if the node doesn't have this label, the pod will not
be scheduled on that node.
So you need a node with exactly this label
to have this pod scheduled.
Affinity and anti-affinity that I'm going to show you
in this lecture are similar to what the nodeSelector does.
The affinity/anti-affinity feature allows you
to do more complex scheduling than the nodeSelector
and also works on pods.
It's not only for nodes, also for pods.
The language that you can use is more expressive.
You can create rules that are not hard requirements,
but rather a preferred rule, meaning that the scheduler
will still be able to schedule your pod,
even if the rules can't be met.
So if a nodeSelector, if a node doesn't have your label,
it'll never get scheduled.
Whereas, with affinity and anti-affinity,
you can create a different type of rule,
or you set a preference.
So, you will prefer nodes with a specific label,
but if there is no node with that label schedule-able,
it will still get scheduled on another node.
You can create rules that take other pod labels
into account.
So, affinity also exists, not only for node affinity
but also for pod affinity.
For example, you can create a rule that makes sure
two different pods will never be on the same nodes.
Kubernetes can do node affinity
and pod affinity/anti-affinity.
Node affinity is similar to the nodeSelector
and pod affinity/anti-affinity allows you to create rules,
how pods should be scheduled, taking into account
other running pods.
Affinity/anti-affinity is a mechanism only relevant
during scheduling.
Once the pod is running, it will need to be re-created
to apply the rules again.
Don't expect that if there is a new node with a label,
and it's a better match, that Kubernetes will automatically
reschedule your pods.
You will have to terminate your pod first,
and it needs to be re-created, to make sure if you want
to have your pod scheduled on another node.
I will first cover node affinity,
and will then cover pod affinity/anti-affinity.
There are currently two types you can use for node affinity.
The requiredDuringSchedulingIgnoredDuringExecution,
and the preferredDuringSchedulingIgnoredDuringExecution.
The the first one sets a hard requirement
like the nodeSelector.
The rules must be met before the pod can be scheduled.
The second type will try to enforce the rule,
but it will not guarantee it.
Even if the rule is not met, the pod can still be scheduled.
It's a soft requirement.
It's a preference, in this case.
So here's an example, that I will use in the next demo.
So, in your deployment specification,
you can define affinity, the note affinity and here you can
define the requiredDuringSchedulingIgnoreddDuringExecution
and also the,
preferredDuringSchedulingIgnoredDuringExecution.
So, it can combine both.
In this example, we're going to look for nodes
that match the expression env and dev.
So the environment, env, needs to be dev before this pod
can be scheduled on that node, because we have
the requiredDuringSchedulingIgnoredDuringExecution
and not the preferred.
If the label env, is dev on whatever nodes
then we can be sure it will be scheduled,
because we have a preferred rule, a second rule
and the preferred rule is a preference.
So, it'll look for nodes that match.
But, if it doesn't match it will still get scheduled.
We're gonna give it a weight,
and I will explain the weight in the next slide.
And then we have the preference.
And the preference is matchExpressions, team, In,
engineering-project1.
So, we're looking for the label
team equals engineering-project1.
But, if there are no nodes with engineering-project1
as a label, then we'll still schedule it on a node
that has env equals dev, but is missing this label.
So, I'll show you how it works in the next demo.
Now, in the previous slide I also supplied
a weighting to the,
preferredDuringSchedulingIgnoredDuringExecution statement.
So, here it is again.
Weight is one.
The higher this weighting, the more weight is given
to that rule.
When scheduling, Kubernetes will score every node
by summarizing the weightings per node.
For example, if you have two different rules,
preferred rules is, with weights, one and five.
If both rules match, the node will have a score of six.
So, in this case we have one node, where both rules match.
But, you're probably going to have other notes.
So that's it.
We have another node, and on this other node
if only the rule with weight one matches,
then the score will only be one.
So then, we have one node with score six
and one node with score one.
The node that has the highest total score,
that's where the pod will be scheduled on.
So in this example, our pod would be scheduled
on the node that has a score of six.
In addition to the labels that you can add yourself,
to the nodes, there are repopulated labels
that you can use as well.
For example, if you want to know the hostname,
you can use the label with the key
Kubernetes.io/hostname.
So this will reply the hostname,
and you can use that in your affinity rules.
You also have the zone, and this can actually change
once this becomes a stable.
So, you will have to double check your node labels
to see what labels that you have.
I will also show you that in the demo.
The zone is cloud dependent.
If you're an alias, then the zone can be EU West
1A for example.
The region, also cloud dependent;
can be US1, can be US East, US West and so on.
The instance type, for example t2.micro.
The operating system and the architecture.
So, depending where you deploy,
these can all have different values.
But nevertheless, these are labels that you might
want to use for your decision making.