I will now show you
a demo of Interpod affinity.
So I am here now in the affinity folder,
of my current discourse Interpod Tree.
and here I have found pod Affinity dot E M O.
Let's have a look at this,
it's going to deploy two deployments:
First deployment is pod affinity one,
second one is pod affinity two.
This first deployment is just a container.
No pod affinity defined.
it's the second one that has a pod affinity defined,
and here we're going to say affinity pod affinity,
required during scheduling, ignored during exclusion.
We have the label sector F, in pod affinity one.
If this is true,
then the pod will be scaled on the note
that has the same host name.
So this is Redis,
so this means that the Redis pod,
is always going to be scheduled next to the first pod,
the pod affinity one pod.
Let's kube CTL create this pod affinity.
Two pods created,
container creating,
let's use O wide,
and then we can see on what nodes they are created.
Both of them are running,
both of them are on the same node.
Maybe that's a coincidence.
So let's scale this deployment,
replicas four maybe,
of our deployment,
pod affinity two.
Now it's scaled.
All the new pods are on the same node, so you see,
pod affinity, make sure that the new pod, the second one,
pod affinity two is always scaled next to the first one.
We can use different labels as well,
So let's say we that we kube CTL delete,
this pod affinity to delete those two deployments.
Let's have a look at our labels.
Get nodes, scribe nodes.
We'll use our labels.
So here these are all the labels that we can use.
For example,
if I want to use a failure domain the zone,
then we can also use this.
And pod affinity,
here we can just change it to plodgy key,
in the failure domain.
This will also work.
I only launched in one zone,
so you will not see that it doesn't get scaled
in one of the nodes because it's all in the same zone.
But you will see now they will be scaled,
all the nodes that are in the same region,
in the same availability zone.
Let's create it again,
let's scale this to five
kube CTL get nodes,
O wide,
get pods is what I'm looking for.
And you see now they're getting scaled
on different nodes.
Because now you're using the failure domain
and not the host name,
so that's it for this demo.
In the next demo I'll show you how pod anti-affinity works.