In this demo I will show you
an example of taints and tolerations.
Before I start with a demo let me show you
how you can see the master taint,
because as you noticed when you schedule pods
they are not scheduled on a master,
and that is because the master has a taint.
So if you do kubectl get nodes,
and we get the master node, that's the second one here,
and I do o yaml to output all the yaml
I will pipe it to less.
Type in search for taint.
Then this node has one taint, effect NoSchedule,
and the key is node-role.kubernetes.io/master.
So as long as you don't have toleration on this key,
you will never schedule a pod on the master.
I have fuller here tolerations
and here in the README I have the commands to taint a node.
I'm going to taint my first node here,
this one here.
So I'm going to do kubectl taint node
node name and I'm gonna give
the taint type equals specialnode,
and I'm going to use NoSchedule.
Then I have a tolerations.yaml file.
Here we have two deployments.
The first deployment doesn't have any toleration.
Just a normal deployment, three replicas,
and a second one is also three replicas,
but it has toleration on type equal specialnode,
effect NoSchedule.
This kubectl create this toleration,
and what is going to happen,
I'm going to do kubectl get pod o wide
so we get the nodes as well.
I tainted this node.
So only if the pod has its toleration
it will be scheduled on this node.
My first deployment that launches three pods
doesn't have any toleration.
So you see is scheduled on the node where it appeared
(mumbles) 160.
So it never scheduled on the other node.
And the other deployment, the one with a toleration,
has two pods running on this node that has been tainted.
Let me now taint the same node but with a different key.
Taint node and then I will just say type2 specialnode2.
What is now going to happen, kubectl get pods o wide.
Nothing is going to happen because I'm still using
NoSchedule so it will not affect any pods.
Let's say that I delete a pod.
I will delete this pod here.
What's going to happen now,
well it doesn't match this second taint,
so it will not be scheduled on this node anymore.
This one is terminated and now there's a new one,
and it has been scheduled on the 160 node
and not on this node anymore.
I still have one pod running on this third node
that ends with six.
So let me do another taint.
And I will use testkey testavalue NoExecute.
And NoExecute is no different than NoSchedule,
because this will evict the pod.
So if I
use this node name
and I press enter
and I do kubectl get pod o wide,
and I now see that the last pod
that was running on this node is now terminating,
and a new pod is now running
but on 160 and not on six anymore.
So this is how taints work and how you can use tolerations
to still schedule pods on nodes that are tainted.
And then I also showed you the difference
between NoExecute and NoSchedule.
You can delete the pods again using kubectl delete.
To then also remove the taints
you can use the same taint commands,
but with the minus sign after the key.
For example, I did a taint nodes of this six node
with testkey testvalue NoExecute.
If I just do testkey with a minus sign
then I removed the taint and now this node
has been untainted so this key is gone.
So you need to do that for every key.
So type, minus, and type 2 minus.
And then the taints are gone.