In this demo, I will show you
how to deploy my Hello World app,
the first Istio-enabled app
that we will deploy to our cluster.
Let me first show you an architecture diagram
so that you have a high-level overview
of what you are going to do.
I'm going to use curl, which is going to be the client,
to contact an app.
This app will be a micro-service
that is not going to be one app,
but multiple micro-services.
Now that I have deployed istio,
it will be an istio-ingress and AWS load balancer
pointing to this istio-ingress controller.
So if I contact this AWS URL,
this AWS load balancer URL
I'll be redirected to the istio service
and to the istio-ingress controller.
I will have to do some configuration
to make sure that istio-ingress knows
how to contact my app using some YAML definitions
that I will show you in a moment.
This istio-ingress will then contact my app,
rather than contacting the container directly
it will contact the envoy proxy,
which is deployed as a sidecar in the same pod.
So we have one pod, two containers,
one is the real app, which is called hello,
and one is the envoy proxy deployed by istio.
It will contact this proxy and this
will contact my app, hello.
This hello app is configured that it will go
to another app called the world app
to get some of its information.
When hello is contacting world,
it will use the envoy proxy again.
So this goes over to envoy proxy to the world app.
The world app is also configured to contact the third app,
world-v2, so it will also go over the envoy proxy
to contact world-v2.
At this point everything is sent back
to the hello app again, which now has enough information
to send back the data to the client.
So the client will then see using curl,
it will then see the string that has been returned
by the hello app, the world app, and the world-v2 app.
I only show three pods here,
but actually my deployment will have
three pods per deployment,
so in total I will have nine pods.
Three replicas for every deployment.
So let's have look of the YAML definitions
of these files.
So the first file I want to show you
is the helloworld.yaml file.
I don't define any istio proxy in this file.
This will be injected by the istio-ctl commands.
So this just looks like any deployment
that you would write in the YAML file
for Kubernetes.
So I have a deployment called 'hello,'
three replicas ... I have two labels,
app 'hello,' and version v1.
This was put in a container,
with name 'hello,' and the container is called
'http-echo,' and you can have a look at my
GitHub repository, as repository http-echo
to look at the code, but it's a very simple app.
It will just output whatever you pose
as an environment-variable text,
so in this case, it will return 'hello.'
It will also have a look at
the environment variable next,
which identifies the next service
it needs to contact.
The next service in this case is 'world'
on port 8080, so it will upend the text
that it gets from 'world.'
So this one output's 'hello,'
and then for the rest of the text,
it will go to the next application.
We have one port defined, http port on port 8080.
We also have to use the word 'http,'
so that istio recognizes it, because then
istio will use the http protocol.
We also have defined a service
with the name 'hello,' also name of the port
'http,' and the port that we need
to contact is 8080.
Then we have a second deployment.
This one is called 'world,'
and 'world' is also using the same image
and the text that will be returned,
in this case, it's going to be 'world.'
So we have one app that is going to return 'hello,'
one app that is going to return 'world.'
And then the next app that it needs to contact
is world v2 on port 8080.
The rest is all similar.
Let's have a look at this third deployment,
world v2, text in this case will be
three exclamation marks.
And there's no next defined, so this service
will just return this.
So now you should already have an idea
of what the app is going to do.
If it's gonna contact 'hello,'
then it will output 'hello,' it will contact
the next app, which is 'world,'
if we have a look at 'world,' it will output
the text, 'world.'
We'll go to the next app, the next
micro-service, world v2.
Our world v2 will output three exclamation marks.
And this one also has a service.
So let's deploy this one. How do we deploy this?
Not just by kube ctl create or apply, but let's
use istio ctl and copy paste from the Read Me,
we need to use istio ctl, kube-inject
of this helloworld.yaml to inject the proxy.
I will execute this first without the kube ctl
appliance so you see what happens,
and then I will do a kube ctl apply.
First, make sure that you path this correctly.
So we're going to just set the path, so that
I have istio in my path.
Let's have a look what the istio
ctl kube inject outputs.
It will output everything in YAML format.
What it's going to do is, it's going to
add another container.
It's going to add another container
starting from here, args.
And it's going to launch the envoy proxy
as a separate container, within
the same port.
Let's apply this kube ctl.
Apply minus f, and then we're going to execute this
so that we inject the envoy proxy.
So this will launch the three deployments,
each three pods.
Let's have a look at the get pods.
You see three pods each and two containers
in every pod, one for the app, one for envoy.
Now if you want to contact our application,
if you wanted to recontact hello,
then we'd also need to define the gateway,
the istio gateway. Let's have a look at this file.
We have kind gateway ... this will select
the ingress gateway, so this is
the default gateway, default controller.
This is the default controller
that is already available.
You're going to save if you want to.
Use port 80, on this ingress controller.
Everything that matches, we want to capture
using our gateway. You can specify
a host here, a host name, or you can just
capture everything.
You're gonna have a virtual service,
again, you can specify the host.
If you don't specify a host, you can
also specify star. This will match everything.
So our virtual service is basically
our service that we want to define.
The gateway that we use is helloworld-gateway.
That's gonna be this gateway.
We're going to say http, match, uri,
prefix / hello. So whenever we
go to our ingress controller, then
if the prefix matches on slash hello,
then we're going to route it somewhere.
We're going to route it here.
Our destination is going to be
the host, hello.default.svc.cluster.local.
So this is gonna be the host name
of our first app. The hello app.
Default stands for 'default name space.'
We're going to do that on port 8080.
So typically, you always need a virtual service
if you want to define your service
in the ingress controller.
You always also need one gateway,
this is our gateway that we're going to use.
So we have one gateway and one virtual service.
If you want to directly access other services,
then we just have to define multiple
virtual services. We don't need to define
a virtual service for world and world v2
because those will be accessed by the hello app,
not by the client itself.
'Kube ctl apply helloworld gateway' is created.
Now let's have a look at the service
of the name space. Istio system.
So here we have the istio ingress gateway,
let's do o wide,
so here we have the full URL of the
Load Balancer, and then if you do curl
of this URL, we don't get anything
because we haven't configured anything.
Let's have a look again at helloworld gateway.
We only configured something for slash hello.
So let's use this URL slash hello,
and how do we get? We get hello, world,
and three exclamation marks.
This comes from ...
the hello comes from
one of these pods, the world comes from
one of these pods, and the three
exclamation marks come from one of these pods.
So these communicated with each other
over the envoy proxy to get this string
of information and send it back to the client.
The client only accessed the ingress controller,
the ingress controller contacted the envoy
on this application. This application then
contacted this one, and then this application
contacted that one.
So this is an example of a micro-service
with the envoy proxy deployed
as a sidecar using istio.
In the next demos, I will then show you
some more features of istio, to show you really
what the benefit is of having istio
running in your cluster for your micro-services.