Now that my Droplets are up,
I'm going to install Kubernetes using kubeadm.
I need those two IP addresses to ssh.
One ends with 170, I'll copy this one and one ends with 75.
I just opened a Micros terminal.
If you are using Linux, you can just open terminal.
If you're using Windows, you can use PuTTY.
You can download PuTTY and then ssh to this IP address.
ssh to the Droplets
using the login root
and using the private key that I specified.
If you didn't specify a private key,
you just don't specify this file
and it will ask for a password.
Press Yes
and then we are logged in.
So we are going to do exactly the same for the other node.
I open a new tab,
(mumbles) .75
And here we are, logging into the Kubernetes node.
First, I'm going to start with the master.
I'm going to
git clone my repository.
This repository contains all the scripts,
so that you don't have to type everything over
and I will do exactly the same on the node.
On-prem-or-cloud-agnostic-kubernetes
and then I will show you the Kubernetes scripts
to install the master.
So this is the script to install Docker,
install Kubernetes and then deploy Kubernetes.
These instructions, I got them from
the documentation from kubeadm,
so if you want to know more details about it,
you can always take documentation.
First, we're going to install Docker,
we're going to do an apt-get update
and then install some dependencies.
We're going to get the gpg key for the repository,
so that we know that when we add this repository
in this line here, that this is, for sure, the correct one.
It'll be verified using this gpg key that we download first.
Then we're going to do an apt-git update again
and then install Docker.
Then we're going to install Kubernetes, it'll be the same.
We have a dependency here that we need to install first.
We're going to download the gpg key
and add to the sources for Kubernetes,
the apt.kubernetes.io repository.
We do an update again
and then we install the kubelet, kubeadm, and kubectl
and then we can deploy Kubernetes using kubeadm.
So, we use kubeadm init,
we're going to specify pod-network-cidr,
so that IP range for pod networks
is going to be 192.168.0.0/16, so this range.
So this is a range of IP addresses
and IP space that the pods can use.
You can add multiple flags to this kubeadm init.
If you want to use a different IP address
for your API server, you can also use
apiserver-advertise-address="ip".
We only have one IP address assigned to this server,
so it's automatically going to be that one.
This is the default gateway address that will be used,
this is the IP address to get to the internet.
If we'd have another internal IP address,
then you need this flag
if you want to use internal IP addresses.
If you're doing an on-prem deployment
and you only have an internal IP address,
you also don't have to specify this,
it's only when you have multiple IP addresses.
This is going to be our config that we then can use
and then we are going to do kubectl apply
of this calico.yaml to get our CNI.
We can execute this;
scripts/install-kubernetes.sh on the master.
It's first going to install Docker
and then it will install and deploy Kubernetes.
While this is taking its time, I'm going to do the node.
So here we have a script,
I'll vim it, so we have colors for the install node.
Very similar, we also need Docker.
This for Docker, same lines.
We also need kubeadm and kubectl,
so we're going to install kubelet, kubeadm, and kubectl.
We're just not going to do the kubeadm init,
we're going to use a joint command,
So I'm going to install this on the node.
If you're going to use multiple nodes,
then you can execute this script on your multiple nodes.
I only have one node here,
so I only have to execute it once.
Back to our master, what is happening here?
It is now going to install Kubernetes.
It installed kubeadm, kubectl, and the kubelet,
so now it is going to unpack it
and then it will do the deployment of Kubernetes master.
Our Kubernetes master has initialized successfully.
To start using your cluster,
we need to run the following as a regular user,
but we don't have a user yet, so we'll have to add a user.
I have a separate script for that,
but first, lets join our auto-machine.
So, this is the token I talked about
in the previous lecture, that we then use
to make sure that not every single server can join,
only servers with a token can join.
So we copy paste this
on our node one and then here we have joined the cluster.
Let's create a user now.
So I have another script that I prepared, create-user.sh.
It adds a Ubuntu user...
Well, it's first going to create a group ubuntu@ubuntu-user,
it's going to be in the group; admin.
We're going to create a home directory for it,
going to copy the ssh keys.
If you don't use ssh keys,
then you still need to set a password for user ubuntu,
which you can do with using p-a-s-s-w-d ubuntu.
If use ssh keys, then this is not necessary.
You're going to do a chown to set the ownership rights
and then we going to add the unbuntu user to sudoers,
so that we can still do sudo to become root.
We're going to create this ubuntu kube directory
and you're gonna copy this kubernetes/admin.conf
from /etc/kubernetes.conf to .kube/config
and then we're going to chown this,
we're going to change ownership of this file as well.
So we're going to execute this, create-user,
and then we can actually go to the ubuntu user.
So I'm going to logout
and then I'm going to set our login as the ubuntu user
and now I am logged in as the ubuntu user.
I will do the same on the node,
so I'm just going to copy/paste this on the other node
'cause I wanna create the user,
but I don't want to copy this,
because I don't have his admin.conf on my node,
but I will still just create a user here,
so that I can also work with this user.
So I'm going to logout and login again
and here, I am also logged in as the ubuntu user,
rather than the root user.
If you want to disable the root user,
you still have to delete the ssh key
or reset the password or remove the password.
If you wanna use on the node the kubectl commands,
you also need to copy this admin.conf using a cp
or just copy/paste to this node.
For now I will not do that,
maybe I will do it later when I need it.
What I now want to do is kubectl get nodes,
to see where my cluster is up
and I have a master node and a Kubernetes node,
both are ready.
I just want to test what I can skip of both,
so I'm just going to run kubectl run helloworld
and I'm going to run the echoserver,
which just returns some information
so that we know that the pod is working.
You will use port 8080.
Pod has been created, container is still being creating.
It takes some time to fetch this image
and then I'm going to
kubectl expose deployment helloworld --type=NodePort.
It will create a service for us
and this is the service that has been created for us.
This is the port.
Let's have a look at the pod, whether it's available
and then to test, I just open a new terminal
to be on my local PC.
I use the IP address of the node, not of the master,
because even though I scaled the pod
using kubectl on the master,
all the pods are scaled on the nodes and not on the master,
so I need to contact one of the nodes, not the master,
on this port that is the node port
and then you see, I get back the result from the echoserver,
so it just says these are headers received.
It was a GET command,
this is the IP address of the node
and this is the URL that I asked,
so if I say, I ask for directory,
then you will see the request_url is actually directory.
So, this works.
So we successfully deployed our Kubernetes cluster,
launched the pod, the pod is now running on the node
and then I can curl to this node on this node port
and then the pod will respond.