In this demo, I will show you
how to use a Kubeless function with PubSub.
The first thing that we need
to do is we need to install kafka.
You can use an existing kafka installation
or, if you don't have one yet,
you can also use kubeless
to install a kafka on your Kubernetes cluster.
I have the commands ready in my read me.
Kafka Installtion.
You're going to export the release to get the latest release
and then you're going to use kubectl create
to install the kubeless kafka trigger: kafka-zookeeper.yaml.
So, kafka needs, also, zookeeper.
That's why you also install zookeeper.
Let's have a look.
Kubectl get pods --all-namespaces.
It's installed in kubeless namespace.
We have kafka-0 still pending.
And a kafka-trigger-control and a zookeeper.
Back to read me.
We can deploy a function.
You can use use kubless function deploy
to deploy uppercase function,
which is also based on nodejs6.
We're just gonna Copy + Paste these lines
and then show you the node-example/uppercase.js.
Which is just a simple function
that will convert the input to uppercase.
So, we have uppercase function,
event and context are arguments.
We're going to define string, str.
Str equals to the event 'data'.
So, the data that is passed in this event
and then going to uppercase it.
You're going to log it and then you're going to return it.
So, let's deploy this function.
Kubeless function ls uppercase is not ready yet.
So, we have to do it just ls, without uppercase.
We see all our deployed functions.
You have to wait a bit until this function is ready.
This will spin up a pod again.
Right here is the uppercase pod.
It's now initializing.
Now, we just launched an uppercase function,
but it's not linked to anything.
In a previous demo, I showed you how to link a function
to an ingress controller, making it a HTB function.
Now, I will do the same, but for kafka.
I have the commands, again, in my read me.
It's two commands that we need.
Kubeless trigger kafka is going to create test.
The function-selector is going to be created by kubeless.
So, we created this function, but with kubeless
and function is called uppercase.
And then the topic that needs to be triggered is uppercase.
So, in kafka, you have topics,
which is kind of a queue, where you can send data to
and when data is sent to this topic,
then our function will be triggered.
So, let's first enter this command.
Kafka trigger test created in namespace default successfully
So, now we have a trigger on our kafka topic.
Now, we need to trigger this function
by publishing some data to this topic.
To publish some data, you can also use kubeless.
Because it is kafka, you don't need kubeless.
You can just have any mechanism,
any tool, any software, any application
that rides data to kafka
and then this function will be triggered.
But, we don't really have any application
riding to this topic,
so we're just going to use
kubeless topic publish --topic uppercase
to publish some data to the topic.
So, this will publish some data to the kafka topic.
The data we are going to use is:
"this message will be converted to uppercase."
So, let's enter this.
We sent this message to our kafka topic.
Let's try something more.
This is a second message.
Now, also I'm using T2 micro instances.
So, it's possible that we don't really have enough memory
to run all these services.
If, you experience any issues,
you can either increase the size of your instances
or move some previous functions
to make sure that you don't run out of resources.
You don't run out of memory.
Let's have a look at our pods.
We have the uppercase pod.
Let's have a look at the logs.
We sent first "this message will be converted to uppercase"
and it outputted THIS MESSAGE WILL BE CONVERTED TO UPPERCASE
and THIS IS A SECOND MESSAGE.
Let's have a look again at this function.
We have the node-example/uppercase function.
So, this event is an argument that is passed to the function
In event data we have
"this message will be converted to uppercase,"
or, the second one, "this is a second message."
So, the function will be basically executed twice.
One for this message and one time for this message.
So we have one line of data in the event data.
Convert it to uppercase
and then log it to the console of this container
and then you will see here,
this message will be converted to uppercase
in uppercase letters.
And this will also basically post invite the trigger.
The trigger that we created for whenever
there is data in our kafka topic,
then, it will trigger our function
and then this function gets executed
with this data attached to it.
So, that we can covert its data.
We don't really do anything with this data.
We just log the data to the console here
and we return a string.
In reality, you store your result somewhere.
Often, you store your data, again,
in another kafka topic, for example,
and then other applications can read results from this topic
and store it or displace it to a user, for example,
or send it to another app.
The limitation here with kubeless right now
is that you can publish data to kafka
and kafka will then trigger your function
so you can capture data within your function,
but your function can not yet send data back to kafka.
You could ride your own producer,
again, in your function right here, to then send data back.
But, that defeats the purpose of Serverless
because Serverless would really provide
you with this framework where its easy
to send data to any of your services.
So, this is something that's bending.
It's a feature that's bending
where you can then return some data back to kafka,
to another topic, for example.
Right now, what you could do is you can,
for example, send this string back to another function,
now that you have uppercase,
you could send it back to a function
that stores it into a database
and then you could have another function
that reads from the database whenever
a user visits a web page.
That's all possible.
It's all up to you how
evolved and difficult you make these functions.
These are very simple functions.
They don't do much.
You can use my SQL.
You can use an undefined database
to store your results, to read your results, to use it.
With these mechanisms that are already available
and with these run bags that are available,
you can already create some really useful applications.
So, that's it for this lecture.
I hope you learned some useful information
about Serverless in this section
and this is really a nice way
of getting this Serverless architecture within Kubernetes.
It is used already a lot in public cloud
and I'm sure it will only get
more popular within Kubernetes.