In this demo I am going to show you
how to use IAM Roles for Service Accounts.
In my kubernetes course I have deltree eks
and in eks I have readme
with the commands that I need for these IAM roles.
I already executed this create cluster earlier
because it takes some time,
so I create now a cluster two with two nodes.
And now I am going to enable
the IAM oidc provider on my cluster,
which I need to use those IAM roles for service accounts.
So if you execute the commands
it will just show you what it's going to do,
and then if you add a proof to it
then it will actually apply those changes.
So now it has applied those changes
for my cluster two in eu west one.
So eu west one is my default region.
If you're not using your default region
you will have to add that (murmurs) region
to your arguments.
And then I want to create a new IAM role
using a service account,
so I have my service account as a service account
(mumbles) default,
and I want to attach the amazon s three read only access
to test.
If I execute it, it will show you
what it's going to add.
So, it's going to add one IAM service account
which has two subtasks.
It's going to create and IAM role
and then it's going to create this service account
in my default name space.
Going to approve this,
so this deploys a new stack in cloud formation
to add this new role
and then it will create in my default name space
that my service account.
This can take a few minutes.
Now it's done.
I have my service account.
So if I have look kubectl,
get service account,
in my default name space,
I have my service account,
let's see what's in there.
Using the yaml.
So here I have this annotation,
eks amazon aws dot come role arm and this is the arm
that has been created for me, that I can now use.
In my eks folder I have a file here
called amazon linux dot yaml.
This contains the deployment of amazon linux
using the service account, my service account.
So this deployment will then have access
to assume this role.
It's not going to do anything.
It's just gonna keep running,
so I have to sleep infinity here.
I'm going to apply this using kubectl apply
and then I'm going to exec it into this pod.
I'm going to open a bash cell basically.
So now I am in my pod.
Let me clean my screen
and then I'm going to install python three.
The reason why I'm installing python three,
is that if I would just install
AWS command line utility
it's not going to be the latest
AWS command line utility.
It's going to be too old to use this implementation,
so I need to use pip to get the latest
AWS command line utility.
So I'm going to use pip three install
AWS command line utility
and this is gonna download and install the latest version.
So let's now first check the environment variables.
So if you do set grep AWS it is going to show us
the environment variables that have AWS in it's name.
So here we have the AWS role, ARN
so this is the ARN role and the AWS identity token file.
So these two environment variables were injected
by the webhook so that we can now use them in this pod.
If you wouldn't use the service account
then we wouldn't have these two variables.
It wouldn't be able to read this token.
So what is this token?
Let me show you what's in there.
This is a jwt,
and this jwt we can then use to assume this role.
After the course is finished I'll remove this role
and this jwt and access token will not be usable anymore.
So I'm not going to blur any of this.
It will become unusable after I do this demo.
We need to have all the content.
I'm going to copy this and then I can go to a website
like jwt.io to paste this token.
Be careful where you paste jwts.
This website doesn't record any tokens
but others might.
So this is jwt algorithm rs256.
And here we can see that we have sts amazon.com
which is the audience.
We going to basically use ordc capabilities
to get a real access key from sts amazon aws dot com.
So what sdk's gonna go to sts
and give this jwt to sts to obtain our access credential.
This basically says that we have a service account
and that we should be able to retrieve the role linked
to this service account.
This jwt is signed using a private key that we don't have
so we cannot recreate this jwt.
This jwt will expire so it was issued the ninth of 12:58
and it will expire the tenth at 12:58
so it's now valid for one day,
but this could change.
And using this jwt we can then assume our role.
So, let's try it out.
This is of course all handled transparently
but let me show you how this works with sdk.
So right now I'm going to use AWS s three ls
and let me just grep for mybucket.
I have multiple buckets in my ls tree.
And if I ls the contents of this first bucket,
I can list this object test dot txt.
So I have access to list the buckets
and I have access to list and read data
from my bucket.
The role, the IAM role works.
What happened under the hood?
If you have a look,
in dot aws you'll see we have a cache
and here we have a json file,
where the aws sdk will have saved our access key
that is retrieved from sts.
So here is our access key
that we got from sts after sending this jwt.
And only using this access key, secret access key
and extension token we are able to contact s three.
You actually can see that the first request takes longer
to execute and other requests go faster.
So if I do time aws s three ls
this only took half a second.
Let me now remove this cache.
And then do time aws s three ls bucket.
You'll see it will take a second and a half
because it needs to go first to sts,
use this jwt, retrieve the access key, secret key
session token, cache this and then go to s three
with the s credentials.
Once it's cached it can just use the cache credential
and then it will be much quicker to go to s three.
This is how the implementation is done today.
There might be improvements in the future of course.
One last thing to say about this
is that currently the token is all only readable by root.
So if you have a look at var run secrets,
here we have eks amazon dot com,
the service account,
the data slash token and currently this is only
readable and writable by root.
So that's it for this demo.
It's pretty straight forward.
There are a few caveats that you have
to take into account when using this
but the major benefit is
that you can use service accounts.
Use those service accounts with your pods
and then have IAM policies on the pod level
instead of on the worker level.
This is a major feature of eks
that a lot of people use to make sure
that their pods have only the access that they need
to aws services.
You can exit from this show entering exit or using control d
and then you can delete the pod
and delete the cluster after wards
if you don't need it anymore.