In this demo,
I will show you what Helm Create does.
I'm in my Helm directory, but you can be
in any directory that you want,
and I'm just going to enter helm create mychart.
Creating my chart is create directory mychart
and it created the files and directories
that I showed you in the slides.
It also directory charts, which is empty,
where you can place all the charts in
that are dependencies of this chart.
I will show you that in the next demo,
when I show you a real chart.
So chart.yaml is exactly the same
as I showed you in the slides.
But values.yamls is already a little bit more filled out.
Here, these are default values for my chart.
This is a YAML format file, and you can just declare
the variables to be passed into your templates.
So for example, the replica counts,
how many pods do you want to run?
This is then passed to the deployments YAML file,
the image, which has tag stable, the pull policy,
the service, the type of a service and port of a service.
You can also use ingress, and then you have just some
resources, node selector,
and tolerations, and affinity defined,
that you could use, but are still empty.
Let's have a look at how those templates are built.
I'm going to CD in templates,
and here I have deployment.yaml, for example.
And this is a deployment YAML for nginx, in this example.
API version apps, if you want beta too,
it's a deployment, and then the metadata
is going to use a template, my chart full name.
So the full name of the chart.
Whenever it refers to a template,
then it comes from _helpers.tpl.
Here is the my chart full name defined,
and we referred to my chart full name
using the keyword template here.
Here it is defined.
We can override this full name using our values,
our values.yaml, if we'd like
to override the name of this deployment.
Otherwise it's going to have a unique name
that Helm is going to pick.
So there's a little bit of code here
to make sure that we have a fully-qualified app name.
It also says that we truncate at 63 characters,
because Kubernetes name fields are limited to this
because of the DNS naming.
Otherwise service discovery might not work.
If the release name contains a chart name,
it will be used as a full name.
That's what this piece of code does.
You will just see that it will have a unique name.
This very default, don't worry too much about this.
We are just using some variables from the templates.
You will see those filled out once they are deployed.
We have done the labels, and the app, and the chart,
the release, and we also have heritage,
which is just the service.
Here it's done something interesting.
If the values replica count, so if you split again
our screen, and we open values,
and here we have the replica count.
So this is dot values replica count that we use.
These are the values that come from this file.
Release name and release service
are just names that you can use.
Whenever you use dot values,
it refers to the values YAML file.
A little bit further, here we have the container
values image repository values image tag
to make sure that you use
the image repository and the image tag.
The image pull policy, here we can change the port
if necessary, just like a normal deployment.
And then here we have the node selector,
affinity, and tolerations that, again, refers to the values.
But they are empty,
so they will also be empty when we deploy them.
What else, ingress.yaml.
If values ingress is enabled,
by default it is disabled, or ingress enabled false.
So this will not be executed, then.
So you can use and if to make sure
that parts of it will not be executed.
We are not going to use ingress, so just leave like that.
Service.yaml, we need a service.
Here again we also the my chart full name.
Port is again coming from the service, and the type as well.
So you can specify your type in the service,
whether you want just a cluster IP,
or lobe answer, or node port.
When we deploy it, then it will also show the nodes.txt.
So the nodes.txt is also a template.
And this can help us to show to the end user
how to contact the deployed app.
We are going to use a cluster IP,
so else if contains cluster IP,
values service type, so you will see this.
How to contact the ports, it's a export pod name.
So you have the pod name,
and you're going to port forward the pod name.
How to deploy something like this?
Helm install and then the name of the directory,
or just dot if you are in the name of the current directory.
So let me install this example.
Helm install my chart.
It's deployed.
The unique name assigned by Helm is ringed-wolverine,
so this is just unique name that it assigns.
If we do kubectl get pods,
we see ringed-wolverine, my chart.
So this is the full name, is this unique part,
ringed-wolverine, and then the name of the chart,
which is my chart.
It has status deployed, it has the resource service,
deployment and pods.
The service is a cluster IP, so the node here
is saying that if you want to contact it,
we can export pod name, which is then going to
give us a pod name and a variable,
and then we can use port forwarding
to port forward from 8080 locally to our pod.
I'll just do control Z, run it in the background,
do a curl, and then you see welcome to nginx.
I'll close this port forwarding FG and a control C.
Now it's closed, so now the curl is not gonna work anymore
because the port forwarding has stopped.
If I do helm list, it'll show me what is deployed.
If I want to remove it again, helm delete,
and then the name of the release, ringed-wolverine.
And now the release is deleted.
If I would deploy again, or I would deploy a second time,
it would just give it another unique name.
This is a perfect template to get started,
to create your own Helm charts.
In the next demo I will show you a more complex
example of a Helm chart that I created myself.