In this demo, I'm going to show you how ConfigMaps works.
In my "kubernetes-course", I have a configuration file for our nginx. And I have "configmap" and then I have "reverseproxy.conf"
And this configuration is going to make sure that our nginx is
listening on port 80, the server name is "localhost", and whenever it gets a hit is going to forward its
request to this URL, where the "Hello World" nodejs will be running on port 3000.
So, I am going to edit this "reverseproxy.conf" to create ConfigMap nginx-config, from file "/configmap/reverseproxy.conf"
ConfigMap is created.
You want to see my configmaps.
Then I see that "nginx-config" has been created.
And I can also ask to give me the outputs in the YAML format.
So, this config is now with the key "reverseproxy.conf" in the ConfigMap named as nginx-config.
Let's have a look at my pod configuration that I'm going to launch at "nginx.yml".
"helloworld-nginx" is going to be my pod name.
I have two containers.
One is going to be the nginx container.
The other one the "k8s-demo" container.
One is running on "containerPort: 80".
The other one on 3000. My nginx has a volume mount with the name "config-volume"
and the mount path is "/etc/nginx/conf.d" this is a predefined configuration path
where nginx this image will be looking for its configuration.
This config-volume is defined here.
It's a config-volume.
It has the same names with this name here, so this names here are matching.
It's going to be looking for a ConfigMap with the name "nginx-config" that I've just created for key "reverseproxy.conf".
So name, the next config key, and "reverseproxy.conf".
And it's going to put that file with the same name "reverse proxy.conf".
I can execute this, "kubectl create -f configmap/nginx.yml"
I am also going to create the service.
This service is just going to expose a nodePort
"minikube service helloworld-nginx-service --url"
Let's have a look whether my pod is running.
It's all running.
So, I can do "curl", I am going to add minus and some "vvvv", which is going to increase the verbosity,
It is going to show me who is answering to these requests and it is nginx that is answering to my request
and it is forwarding to my other container in this pod, because I'm getting a "Hello World" back.
So, this is how I can put an nginx reverse proxy in front of my nodejs.
So, let's have a look at this container itself, "kubectl"
I want to execute something on my "helloworld-nginx" pod. And, I actually want to login into the container,
because we have two containers I need to specify it now off "nginx" and I am going to execute the "bash".
This is my container that nginx is running,
and now let's have a look, "/etc/nginx/conf.d/"
and here I have my "reverseproxy.conf".
So, I wrote this config, this process, right?
And then it is forwarding this request to my nodejs, that means that at this point you could, for instance,
enable SSL on your nginx it can handle the request for you on your nginx app.
You could use the same system, for let's say PHP. You could have an nginx that then connects to another container that is
then go to process the PHP for you.
So then you have a container nginx, PHP, and then you also need separate configuration files.
So you need to then configure some PHP directives, rather than directives for a proxy, for nodejs.
ConfigMap allows you to inject configuration files to inject configuration data within your application.