In this demo, I will show you how deployment works on Kubernetes. In my Kubernetes-course from my git repository
I have "deployment/helloworld.yml"
And this is the file that I showed you during the theory.
Now I'm going to create this deployment on my local Kubernetes cluster.
"deploymente 'helloworld-deployment' created"
Let's try
"kubectl get deployments" ... "deployments"
I asked for 3 replicas so my desired state was 3 replicas, and the current state is 3 replicas,
which means that it's already launched these 3 replicas. All the replicas are up to date.
They are running version-- "k8s-demo" latest version that I asked to run and they are also available.
So, they are running for a minimum amount of seconds, which means I should be able to connect to them.
I can also get the replica sets.
This is the replica set that has been created for these deployments.
So, you don't need to create those replicas yourself.
Kubernetes does it for you.
I also do get pods, to see the pods.
These are 3 pods and I can also say "--show-labels", and then you see the label, so I said that my label
should "app: helloworld".
So, you will see here, "app=helloworld" is the label for this pod, but it also has a "pod-template-hash",
which is ultimately generated.
I also asked the "roll out status" of this deployment, "helloworld-deployment".
And this successfully rolled out.
We didn't really need to enter this command, we could have seen this information using the
"get deployments", but these is just another way to see if our app is deployed.
If I log into "http://hub.docker.com", then I also pushed earlier a newer version with tag number 2.
So, not with the tag "latest", which is automatically added
if you don't specify your tag,
but with tag number 2. This is a different version and it is going to say, "helloworld v2".
when I would launch this app. What I am going to show you is how to change the version of this first version
to version 2 and I'm back to the old version.
Let's first check what the app would give back if you would connect to it right now.
To do this we have to run, "kubectl expose" again, "kubectl expose deployment", and deployment is going to be the
"helloworld-deployment", and that type is going to be a "NodePort" like you want a static port
automatically assigned that we can connect to. This exposed command created a service for us.
So, let's do "kubectl get service" and now we can see that that has been a service created.
So, let's describe this service, "helloworld-deployment".
So, we see that "Port 31969" has been opened as a node port for this service,
so we can go next to our app.
"minikube service helloworld-deployment --url",
is going to give us the URL of our minikube cluster.
It's going to be the IP that we can use and the port that has been exposed here. The internal IP addresses
of Kubernetes are different than the external IP address that we can connect to.
So, we going to go to this URL
I am going to use curl.
It keeps our "Hello World!".
So, let's now change this version.
So, what I'm going to do now, I'm going to set a new image.
"kubectl set image" of deployment, "/helloworld-deployment", and my image.
I am going to change my Kubernetes demo image into my new "k8s-demo" version 2.
So, we're going to change the "k8s-demos" that was tagged with letters,
because we didn't a tag,
so it's going to be letters with the tag number 2. And this now says, "image updated". We can now follow
this rollout status using this command.
And it is already successfully rolled out.
So, if you've done curl again to this URL, you will see "Hello World v2!"
So, our image is now updated and it actually update all our running pods
because we have multiple pods running.
So, we see three of them have been terminated.
Three of them have been started again with this "v2" version.
Let's say you want to see the history, "kubectl rollout history", I see revision 1 and revision 2,
you don't see any "Change-Cause". Because, when we did the "kubectl create -f" over this,
we could have added, "--record", which would also show changes right here.
I haven't used this, this is the reason why it showed "none" there's a reason why it shows "none".
So, we're not really happy with this version 2.
I rather want to see, "Hello World" without "v2".
So, let's undo this deployment.
We're going to do, "kubectl rollout undo"
And then the name of our deployment.
So, now it's rolling back successfully rolled out again, it was very quick
because those images are still on file.
Again, three new containers.
And then, if I "curl", it's back to "Hello World".
So, this way you can easily change your versions from one application to another application version
and very quickly do rollbacks if necessary.
Let's say that I want to go back to another revision and the revision is from a long time ago.
That's also possible but by default it only keeps two revisions.
So, we would have to edit, "kubectl edit" can do that, our deployment object,
and we would have to change its limit parameter.
So, these are objects, we can just make some changes here, and the change that we are going to make is
I'm going to set a revision history limit of 100.
I edit this.
And now let's do another rollout.
Let's go back to number 2.
Let's check our history again.
And now that we've made a few changes.
You can see that our history is getting longer.
So, here I have my three revisions.
And then if I want to go to another revision I can say, "--to-revision=3" for instance, and that
it is actually rolling back to revision 3, which becomes a new revision because now I'm at six.
Using the "undo --to-revision" can just let you jump to any revision that you want.
And I have no idea anymore on what version we are.
But we are back on the original version.
Deployment objects are the objects that you want to create when you are deploying your applications.
You can also use a replica set or replication controller, but those are just too abstract.
Deployment is going to be the way that you want to put your app on Kubernetes.
And then, you can manage the lifecycle of your app much better using "rollbacks", and
the "rollouts", and so on.
In the next couple of lectures we will see some more details about the labels and about health checks
and also how health checks can improve the resiliency of your app.