Let's talk about Ingress and Ingress Controller. Ingress is a solution available
since Kubernetes 1.1, that allows in inbound connections to the cluster. It's an alternative to the external
Load Balancer and the nodePorts.
So it's a very interesting alternative for cloud providers that don't have a Load Balancer.
Ingress allows you to easily expose services that need to be accessible from the outside to the cluster.
With Ingress you can run your own Ingress Controller or basically a Load Balancer within the Kubernetes cluster.
There are default Ingress Controllers available from Kubernetes or you can write your own Ingress Controller.
Basically, you can even write your own Load Balancer.
This is how it works.
If you connect from the internet on port 80 or 443, which is HTTP and HTTPs,
You're going to be hitting this Ingress Controller, you configure what ports need to be handling the connections from the Ingress Controller.
You can use a nginx Ingress Controller that comes with Kubernetes.
That nginx Ingress Controller is going to distribute the traffic to your services. So, we can have "application1"
that can receive traffic from Ingress Controller and "application2", which one is going to receive traffic is
going to be based on rules that you define in this Ingress object.
So, the Ingress rules can be that if you connect to "host-x.example.com" go to "pod 1",
if you connect to "host-y.example.com" go to "pod 2",
"application2" in our case.
It comes from rules based on the path.
So, the first two rules were based on the host.
You can also make a rule, for instance, "/API/v2" needs to go to "pod n".
Another pod, a third application for instance.
You can create those Ingress rules using the Ingress object.
You can see the API version here is still in beta at some point it's going to come out of beta
and you will have to change this.
But for now it is an extension that is in beta. The object is of "kind: Ingress", that gives the name "helloworld-rules".
And then you are going to specify those rules.
You can see, if it matches the host "helloworld-v1.example.com",
then do HTTP forward to this backend that is described here.
Then, you can specify a path, "/".
The backend in our case is going to be "helloworld-v1"
Which is a service we are going to launch,
And this service runs on port 80.
Then we're going to have a second host
"Helloworld-v2.example.com"
Also HTTP forward, path is also a "/", and we have a not a backend.
So, depending on which host you're going to hit, you are going to get to a different application basically.
These examples come back as "host is non-existent", but you can configure your own domain name,
your own hostname, or you can just work with balance, and say "/v1" goes to my v1 application,
and "/v2" goes to v2 application, that's also possible.
In the next demo, I will show you how this works.