In this demo, I will show you how to build
and deploy a chart using Jenkins.
First, we have to deploy Jenkins,
if you want to use Jenkins.
Luckily, there's a chart for Jenkins
so we can deploy it easily.
I have here Jenkins folder,
and in this Jenkins folder I have a ReadMe.
Let's first create a service account
that we are going to use later on
to deploy our application.
Service account is called jenkins-helm,
and I will use it to deploy our application.
I'm going to do helm install,
I'm going to give the name Jenkins,
I'm going to say rbac.install=true
and I'm going to run it as user 1000.
Instead of user root, I'm just going to run it immediately
as a normal user.
And the chart is called stable/jenkins.
So I'm going to install Jenkins
and it is going to bring up a LoadBalancer.
To know the password for the user admin,
I can execute this command.
This gives me this password,
so this is the password I can log in with.
And then this is to get the service.
I have to wait a couple of minutes,
and then I should be able to execute it
and then I can log in to Jenkins right here.
So this will spin up a Jenkins on our Kubernetes.
This Jenkins comes pre-installed
with the Kubernetes plugin,
and using that plugin we can launch jobs as pods in Jenkins.
So let's go to this URL.
This brings us to the login page,
user admin, the password.
I'm going to use a password
that was operated by one of the commands.
Login, and the the first thing I'm going to do
is I'm going to update the plugins
because they can actually be a bit old.
So I'm gonna go to Manage Plugins,
select all, download now,
and then we're going to install the update.
Restart Jenkins when installation is complete
and no jobs are running.
So the first job that we are going to create
is the build job,
and I'm going to build our package, our helm package.
We're going to push it to our S3 repository.
So while this install is running,
I'm going to create the necessary permissions
for our S3 bucket so that Jenkins can access,
so that Jenkins can access our S3 bucket
where our charts are stored.
So I have another script in helm
that's called put-bucket-policy.sh.
I'm going to open this.
This is a script that is going to add
the necessary permissions to S3
so that our node, our Kubernetes node,
can retrieve and put new objects in our S3 bucket.
Make sure that you change the region
if you're in a different region.
This is the bucket you will have to change as well,
helm dash and then your random string.
And then NODE_ROLE_ARN, you will have to look
for the NODE_ROLE_ARN of your Kubernetes cluster
and of the nodes of your Kubernetes cluster.
So let's have a look.
I'm going to use aws iam list-roles,
and I'm going to filter on my cluster name,
kubernetes.newtech.academy.
And this is gonna give me the master roles
and the role of the normal nodes,
and it's this one that I need.
I need ARN of this nodes.kubernetes.newtech.academy.
I'm going to edit this NODE_ROLE_ARN here,
and also make sure that you use the correct bucket name.
This is then going to do aws s3api put-bucket-policy
on our bucket and it's going to allow
GetObject and PutObject on our bucket
for our NODE_ROLE_ARN.
It's also going to allow ListBucket.
We'll need to execute this,
and if you don't get any output then everything went fine.
So at this point in time, our nodes will be able to
read and write from and to our S3 bucket.
Let's have another look at Jenkins.
Admin and our password.
And now we can start creating new jobs.
I already created the jobs that you need,
so you can just do Create New Job,
and you can use a pipeline.
First one will be demo chart deploy, type is pipeline.
I'm gonna press Ok,
and then you can copy-paste a pipeline script.
You can either do a pipeline script from SCM, from git,
and then you can put my repository there,
but you'll have to fork my repository first
because you will have to make some changes.
So I will just copy-paste it,
just in case that you didn't fork it.
So let me copy-paste it from my git up repository.
So I'm going to go to Helm, Jenkins,
Jenkinsfile.build.
So let me go over this file.
What's going to happen,
I'm going to use the Kubernetes plugin.
I'm going to use the label helm-pod,
and I'm going to use the container helm.
And this is a container that I created
that only contains the helm client with the S3 plugin.
ttyEnabled true and command cat.
So this container will run in the background,
and then here I can start using this container.
What will I do in this container?
I will get my Kubernetes course and I will start executing
a shell script.
So here's a shell script.
I need to define my helm bucket,
so that's why we need to make changes.
This line you will have to change.
Same with AWS_REGION, you will have to change.
The package is demo-chart.
First I have to copy my settings from home/helm.helm.
These are packaged with the container
and I just have to copy them to my home directory.
I'm then going to add the repository
helm repo add my-charts,
so then I can start using this repository.
I will cd into the package I create.
I will run the same what we did earlier,
helm package update, helm package, and helm s3 push.
I use force just in case that the package already exists,
then it doesn't go and throw an error,
and then the package dot tar gzip
and I'm going to push this to my-charts
which is the helm repository here.
So this looks all pretty good.
Let's copy this.
Make sure that you change the region and the helm bucket.
And if you forked it,
you can use the pipeline script from SCM,
and you will have to put this path,
helm/jenkins/Jenkinsfile.build
if you want to do it like that.
Because this is a Jenkins file.
I'm going to save this.
Build now.
It's going to build.
So this will launch a pod on one of my nodes,
and then it will connect to S3 to then push the helm chart.
It takes some time to wait for an available executor,
spinning of the pod, pulling the correct images.
So it's running helm-pod and then this name.
It's checking out git, the git repository.
HELM_BUCKET, PACKAGE, REGION.
It's updating the helm charts,
it's packaging it and does a helm s3 push.
And that worked, so now we have demo-chart-0.0.1
on our repository, on our helm repository,
and now we should be able to deploy it.
So we're gonna create a new item,
demo-chart deploy.
Pipeline, and then again we're going to copy-paste a script.
This script comes again from my git repository.
It is a Jenkinsfile.deploy.
What's happening here, it's almost the same.
This part is almost the same
except that we use the service account jenkins-helm,
the one that we created,
because here we're going to deploy the app
which means that helm needs permissions
to be able to deploy apps on our cluster.
It will also connect to our cluster,
but we don't really have to configure anything for this
because it's already running in a pod.
So here again, container template, helm-pod,
my helm S3 package and this runs the command cat,
so I have this running in the background.
And then here we will start executing commands on it.
We are again going to clone our git repository.
Here you have to change these lines again
if you want to run this demo yourself.
We're going to copy the .helm again to our home directory.
We're going to add to the repository,
and now we're going to run a command, helm list.
Going to filter on our PACKAGE, going to filter on DEPLOYED
and we're going to count the lines.
This is to check whether the package
is already installed or not.
Because if it's not installed,
we're going to do helm install.
If it is already installed, we're going to do helm upgrade.
Let's say the first run is not going to be installed,
we do helm install --name $ my-charts/$.
If this is already installed, we do
helm upgrade $ my-charts/$.
This will either install it or upgrade it,
and then it will echo deployed.
So none of those commands are really new.
I just put them in a script
so that they can be executed in Jenkins.
Going to the crowd.
Going to copy-paste these again
in these pipeline scripts.
Going to save.
Going to do Build Now.
It's going to run.
It was never deployed yet,
so we did a helm install.
So now our chart is installed.
It will take some time before this chart is running,
and then once it's running, we can actually
make some changes to the chart.
You might change a version, you might change a YML file.
And then the typical workflow is that
whenever you increment your version,
you're going to re-run the demo-chart build
which you can link to our git repository
so every time you update your chart,
then the demo-chart build will re-run again.
It is something that you can do in Jenkins.
And then you can choose to re-deploy your app.
You can upgrade your app to a new version.
So let's have a look whether our app is already running.
Let's have a look at the service that has been created now.
O wide.
So here we the demo-chart,
here we have the LoadBalancer.
Let's curl this one.
This one is working.
So let's do an upgrade.
Back to Jenkins.
If you forked the repository, you could make a change
in the demo-chart build.
And then if you configure Jenkins here,
you can also poll SCM, for example,
to rebuild when you make changes.
Let's assume that you make some changes
and then you can re-deploy your application
by doing Build Now,
and the script will now see that you already have
an installation running,
so it will do an upgrade instead of an install.
So, again, this Kubernetes plugin will make sure
that this runs in a pod.
In the pod it can communicate with Kubernetes.
We are using a service account to get us admin privileges
to deploy or upgrade on our cluster.
And then here, let's have a look.
DEPLOYED=1, helm upgrade demo-chart.
So now we are upgrading our release
based on my-charts demo-chart.
So now there will be an upgrade that will run
to upgrade our charts.
So these two scripts you can use with Jenkins
to build and deploy your application using helm
on the Kubernetes.
So now we have a full workflow,
how you can write your own app,
package it using dependencies,
build it in Jenkins
and then deploy to install or upgrade it
on your Kubernetes cluster.