The next coming lectures will all be about Volumes.
I will show you how to run apps with state stateful apps.
And one of the demos is also going to show you how to run WordPress to get over the database because those are statefull application.
Volumes in Kubernetes allow you to store data outside the container.
When the container stops
all data on the container itself is lost.
That's why up until now I've been using most of the time stateless applications: apps don't keep a local state,
but can store their state in external service in a external  service.
With external service, I mean like, a database, a caching server, like mysql, object storage like S3 can be useful for that, and FS Azure can be useful for that.
You can only use those external services even without using volumes,
because S3 we could code that in your app a database, you could run as a service.
Now I'm going to show you a way to run those services inside your Kubernetes cluster and then we can use volumes for that
and then we can run stateful applications.
Persistent volumes Kubernetes allow you to attach a volume to a container that will exist even when the container stops.
So, the container stops, the pod stops,
but your volume can be reattached to a new container and you can keep the state of your application.
It can keep files that are necessary for your application to run. Volumes can be attached using different volume plugins.
Here you have an overview of different plugins.
On the left, we have our node with a couple of pods on and the containers in the pods can now be used to attach them to.
Let's say for instance, "Pod 1" has a local volume attached to it, so that that data can be saved on "Node 1"
and it can be attached to another pod on the same node.
The more interesting ones are the ones that don't exist on the node itself.
Like if you're running on an AWS for instance, you can use EBS storage.
You can attach this EBS to any node in the same EBS if the availability is on.
Your node could completely die, you can spin up an on a node, or you can reuse another node,
reattach an EBS following to that, your pod can still be working.
That's a big advantage of using these Volume plugins that have storage outside your Kubernetes cluster.
If you're running on Google Cloud, you can use Google disk, if you're running a Microsoft cloud,
you can use Azure disk, and then there are some other network storage providers that you can use,
that you might even implement yourself like and FS or Ceph.
Those are a little bit more complicated because you might have to set up a Ceph cluster or NFS cluster,
before you can then use those Volume plugins.
The one that I'm going to discuss is obviously the EBS volume plugin, because we can use it on our AWS cluster.
Using volumes, you could deploy applications with state on your cluster.
Those applications need to read and write to files on the local filesystem that needs to be persistent in time.
You could run mysql database using persistent volumes for instance.
Although this might not be ready for production yet.
Volumes are new since June 2016 release in Kubernetes, so depending when you're going to take this course
you might still want to be very careful about this.
It will become stable at some point in time.
Let me show you an AWS EBS example.
If your node stops working the pod can be rescheduled on the node, or the volume can be attached to the new node.
So, here we have "Node 1" and "Node 2". "Node 2" doesn't have any pods, no one has myapp, and myapp is using EBS storage.
Let's say that "Node 1" completely disappears.
Then what's going to happen is myapp will be rescaled on "Node 2".
And then the container will link the EBS storage again so that myapp can access the data that was written
on that storage that is in this EBS storage, that is safe and out the cluster.
So, this works, but only when those nodes are in the same availabilities on.
So, let's have a look at the definitions that indeed used to create volumes. To use volumes you need to
create a volume first. In the next lecture and I'll show you how we can do this automatically,
but now we are going to do this manually.
So, here I am using the AWS tool to create a volume in "eu-west-1a", that is 10 gigabyte of size.
And also, specifying the "AvailabilityZone", "eu-east-1a". And you need to write down this volume ID,
because this is what we are going to need later on.
Next we need to create a pod or we can create a pod with a container.
These are the containers you always use, we can specify "volumeMount", the "mountPath" can be "myvolume",
and the name is "myvolume". This name "myvolume" comes back under volumes,
and then we go into the "awsElasticBlockStorage" and we going to specify the volume ID.
And that's what I'm going to show you in the next demo.