Hello, and welcome to this course, AWS Systems Manager: Getting Standard,
and to this module, Onboarding AWS EC2 Virtual Machines.
My name is David O'Brien.
I'm a cloud architect and Microsoft MVP working on all things
around modern cloud infrastructure and security.
I'm going to be your guide through this course and hope you
enjoy learning about AWS Systems Manager.
Without further ado, let's start with an overview of this module.
First, we're going to have a look at who this course is for,
what should you bring as a prerequisite to be successful in this course.
We will then look at the course scenario and what we're going to work
through over the course of the next couple of hours.
Next, we will introduce the AWS Systems Manager suite,
what it is, and the components that it is made up of.
After that,
we will start deploying AWS EC2 virtual machines and their supporting
resources that we will need throughout this course.
We'll also look at then subsequently onboarding those
virtual machines into AWS Systems Manager.
So, who is this course for?
Well, you're most likely infrastructure focused.
You're just about to start off with the cloud,
and you do probably also have some scripting or programming experience,
whether that's PowerShell, Bash or Python,
or other programming languages like C#,
it really doesn't matter as long as you do believe that automation
is key to being successful in a cloud world.
Additionally,
you're also more interested in Infrastructure as a Service
right now because most of your infrastructure,
currently and for a while, will likely still be virtual machines.
So if that's you, or close to who you are,
then welcome to this course and let's see what we are
going to deal with in this course.
So, we're part of Globomantics, a highly specialized
company for global flight planning.
They have infrastructure all over the world that is critical for airlines to
do their flight planning, and they're currently just starting off on their
cloud journey. The business decided that AWS, Amazon Web Services, would be
their strategic cloud platform of choice,
and they want to go all in wherever they can.
From an infrastructure point of view, they are really a mixed bag.
They have some Windows virtual machines and some Linux virtual machines.
Really, it's more of a 50/50 mix.
And going forward, the business understands that Infrastructure as a Service
is going to be there for at least the first 12 months,
or even longer, as their main focus initially is not to transform to any
Platform as a Service, or even Software as a Service offerings.
However,
overall, the goal for Globomantics is to reduce the footprint
of traditional management software without losing visibility
into what is actually happening.
As an example,
one of the management software platforms that they want to remove is their whole software deployment and server management suite.