After having executed a built‑in command, we now want to
understand how we can create our own custom command.
For that,
we need to understand that commands are just documents and
that those are plain JSON or YAML files.
I prefer the YAML version of them, by the way,
as it's much easier for humans,
or at least for me, to read. They can be created via the
console, CLI, or other tools like CloudFormation,
and they are deployed into a single account.
But from there, it can be shared to other accounts so
that they can then in turn use them.
This is handy in environments where a central team might create and manage
these documents and then shares them to other accounts so that other teams
can then integrate them into their own workflows.
This process applies to Run Command and Automation workflows.
Both rely on the same type of documents. So let's look at creating a new
document for Run Command. In the Systems Manager console, we scroll all the
way down to Documents in the Shared Resources section.
We'll find all the documents here that are owned by Amazon and
the ones we created or that are shared with us.
We want to create our own, so we click on Create command or
session to get to the Create document console.
We give our new document a name. A naming convention helps to
find the document later on. In this case,
we call it chocolatey‑install‑app to show users that this
document can install applications using chocolatey. The hyphens
are important as spaces are not allowed.
We can then optionally configure what AWS resource types we
want to allow this document to run on. Let's search for
instance and select the EC2::Instance type.
This makes sure that it will only run on EC2
instances. I mentioned I prefer YAML,
so that's what I'm going to select here. And the code editor
changes the example code from JSON to YAML.
I will paste the command in here and then walk through it step
by step. The schemaVersion needs to be 2.2.
That's a fixed version number, at least for now.
The description can be any string that describes what this document will do.
The parameters property is a list of parameters we want users
to provide when executing this document.
The only parameter we need is the name of the app we want to install.
Moving on to the mainSteps part, we have a list of actions we can execute.
Essentially, here we reference built‑in actions of the Systems Manager service,
for example, the aws:RunPowerShellScript action.
The AWS documentation is very helpful in finding other available actions.
Each action will have different input requirements.
This specific action here only needs the Run Command input,
which is the command we want to run. To install an app via Chocolatey,
we need to run choco install on the application name.
We can reference document parameters using this double curly bracket
syntax here and reference our app parameter. The yes parameter tells
chocolatey to approve all prompts.
That's all we need to do.
Click Create the document, and then under Owned by
me, we can now see our document.
We can also go to the Run Command service tab, execute a
command, and in here filter the commands by those we own, and we
can see our command with the app parameter we configured. Voila, our very own custom document.