Enough talk.
Let's look at the Session Manager Service and use it to connect to
our AWS instances. In the Systems Manager console, we scroll down
to the Session Manager tab. And the first thing we will do is check
out Configure Preferences.
In here, we can see a few options we can configure.
For example,
for Linux, we can configure a different user to use
when logging into an instance.
We can configure encryption between the instances and the user's local machines.
And we can configure where information about every single command a user
executes while connected to an EC2 is sent to, either to an S3 bucket,
CloudWatch, or even both. For this demo, we just want to focus on the
functionality itself and leave all these options disabled,
but understand that they're here when we want to use them. In the
Sessions tab, this is where we can find all active sessions.
Right now there aren't any, so let's change that and start a session.
First, we will select our EC2 instance,
the Windows Server 2019. Once we started the session, a new browser tab
automatically opens, and we are presented with a PowerShell prompt in just a
few seconds, almost no time. From here, we now have full access to the
PowerShell command‑line. Query a service.
Easy. Maybe check what Windows features are installed.
Yep, sure.
Maybe we expect an issue with the Amazon SSM agent,
and we want to tell the log file.
Just browse to the correct directory, Get‑Content on the errors file,
and, yep, it can be easily done just like this.
Remember, there's no public IP required on those instances.
All communication happens via internal AWS APIs, and we,
as the user, really only see images presented to us in the browser. As an
administrator, we can now go back to the Session Manager tab and refresh the
session's overview to see our currently active session.
From here, we can select the session and then click Terminate.
We might have a valid reason for that,
or we just want to terminate the session. Over on our
active Sessions tab, as the user,
we only get a notification that our session was terminated.
In the session history, we can now see our previous session
and some information about it.
Right.
So this was us connecting to an AWS EC2 instance,
but I mentioned that we can also connect to non‑AWS machines on‑premises, on
other clouds, as long as we on‑boarded them to Systems Manager.
For this, we need to enable the advanced tier,
which will incur costs per machine, if you remember.
Let's see what this looks like.
We'll start another session, but this time we select
the managed Ubuntu instance here.
Once we click on Start session, we get this popup saying that advanced
tier needs to be enabled, and it asks us to accept that this will change
our billing model for Systems Manager to the advanced tier. We read and
accept this, and click Change setting. We can then see the confirmation
of this action up here in the green ribbon, and we can now click Start
session again.
As before, this opens a new tab and connects us straight into our Linux
terminal on our on‑premises VM. Just like on Windows, we can do many
things here on the command‑line to assist us with troubleshooting any
issues we might have. Again, note that we did not need to connect any networks for this to work.