We're going to talk about virtual machines or EC2 a lot during this course.
So we will need to take a look at how to onboard EC2
virtual machines through Systems Manager.
And for that, we need to talk about the SSM Agent.
It's preinstalled pretty much on most Windows and Linux Amazon machine images,
which are also referred to as AMIs.
But make sure that whatever AMI you're using does have this SSM Agent installed.
If not, don't worry.
It is available as a standalone installer as well.
The important thing, however,
is for it to be able to communicate with the Systems Manager APIs.
This IAM policy here needs to be attached as a bare minimum.
You might be wondering, by the way,
why I called the agent and the policy as the same.
Well that's because back in the day,
the service was called as the same service, standing for simply Systems Manager.
But AWS chose to rename it to just Systems Manager.
It's now just a relic of the past really.
So once the SSM Agent is installed and the policy applied to the EC2 instance,
that's it, we're done.
That's all we need to do to onboard an EC2 to Systems Manager in theory.
So why don't we take a look at actually doing this in practice now
in this demo here and look at deploying an EC2 virtual machine and
registering it to Systems Manager.
Here we are now in the AWS Management Console.
Before we do anything else,
we want to make sure that we are in the correct region,
whatever region we want to be in.
We can do this up here in the upper‑right corner.
And in Globomantics's case, the region will be Sydney.
First,
we want to deploy a virtual machine. And as they are part of the EC2 service,
we need to browse to that one first.
We're going to type ec2 in here into the search box and
hit Enter to get to the EC2 dashboard.
As this is a brand new account to us,
we're not going to see any instances here yet.
So you probably don't have any either.
But if you do expect some to see here, they should show up.
If you expected to see some here, but can't see any,
again,
make sure you're in the correct region or you have the correct permissions.
First, we want to launch a new instance now.
So the next thing we have to do is after clicking this button
here to search for an AMI to deploy from.
We want to deploy a Windows Server 2019,
so that's what I'm going to search for here.
I'm going to pick the first image,
which is the default Windows Server 2019 AMI and click Next.
Next thing,
make sure you select an instance type that's applicable to your situation.
I'm going to pick the free one here as that's sufficient for our use case.
Click Next and configure more instance details.
In this demo, I'm going to go with the default values for almost everything,
especially network‑related choices.
Make sure that that works in your environment though.
I'm going to pick the default VPC and a random subnet in that default VPC. And
I'm going to assign a public IP to this virtual machine.
The public IP is not actually being used by us to access the virtual machine,
but more for the virtual machine to be able to communicate to the internet.
The next step is where we need to select an IAM role.
Remember,
I mentioned a specific IAM policy and role needs to be attached to
the EC2 instance. This role will allow the EC2 to communicate with
the Systems Manager APIs. Looking at the dropdown list here though,
we don't have an IAM role yet.
So we click on Create new IAM role here, and a new tab opens up in our browser.
We can create the new role straight from here.
So just click on the Create role button.
We need to select the EC2 servers because we want to
attach this IAM role to an EC2.
Next, we need to add the permissions.
Remember, the policy was called something with SSM.
So let's type that in here,
and yep, there we go, that's the AmazonSSMManagedInstanceCore policy. We
select this and click Next. In a production environment, I recommend you add
tags to your resources obviously. But in here, we're just going to skip that
for now and move on to the next page.
Give the role a name, any name really that's easy to identify.
But if you have naming conventions,
please follow them obviously. We'll change the description just to make it
a bit clearer that it allows EC2 instances to access AWS Systems Manager
on our behalf, and we click on Create role.
A new role has been created now, and we can now go back to the previous
tab. Hit the Refresh button here, and we can now select our new role. We'll
leave the rest as it is and move on to the storage page and also leave this
on default. Again, as before, I recommend adding tags. And as always,
depending on your situation,
the tags might be different. But for now we skip this and
move on to the security group page.
We're going to select an existing security group instead of
creating a new one, and we're going to select the existing
default security group here.
The important thing about this existing default security group
is that it accepts all traffic on all ports and protocols that
originate from within itself.
So even though the virtual machine has a public IP attached, we can't
actually talk to that VM via its public IP and connect to,
let's say,
an RDP port on that virtual machine unless the origin has
the same security group attached to it.
So let's go to view this and launch, and this will give
us an overview of what we have done.
Clicking Launch will pop up this dialog here.
Normally, this is where we create or select an EC2 key pair.
This key pair is used to later on connect to the EC2 via SSH or RDP.
Because we don't actually have to connect to this virtual machine with a
username and password in these traditional ways,
we would proceed without a key pair.
We need to acknowledge that we understand that we won't be able to
connect to the switch machine via RDP if we don't already know the
password for that machine baked into the AMI.
However, later on in the course,
we will see that we don't actually need to know the
password to connect to that VM.
But for now,
we'll just accept this warning, click Launch, and view the
instances and wait for a few minutes.
Let's jump ahead, and we can see our new instance has begun to being spun up.
The instance state shows pending, and the status
checks are currently initializing.
Let's jump ahead again, and the instance state just turned to
running. We just have to wait into the status checks are also
showing the two positive checks.
One more jump, and we can now see that it's done and changed over to these
Systems Manager service. Pull this list down here and start typing until we
see Systems Manager. In the Systems Manager console, we're now going to
scroll down all the way to Managed Instances.
Let me just clean this frame up here. And here, as expected,
we can see our instance with the instance ID.
It says it's online and shows us all the other information that we would expect to see from a managed virtual machine.