In this demo, we will execute the second type of Systems Manager document,
an automation document in order to build a new AMI from an EC2 instance.
We're in our, by now, very familiar Systems Manager console.
And in order to execute an automation document,
we browse to the automation entry here.
Inside of automation,
we can find historical information about previous automation executions.
And from here,
we can also execute a new automation document There are plenty of
categories of automation documents available here.
I definitely encourage you to have a browse through them.
But for now,
we're interested in the AMI management category where we
can find the AWS‑CreateImage document.
This document is used to create a new Amazon machine
image from existing EC2 instances.
This can be very useful, for example, as a backup solution for certain workloads.
In a previous module,
we talked about maintenance windows and how they
can execute automation documents.
Imagine a maintenance window that executes this document on a
schedule and creates a new AMI once a week.
These are very powerful scenarios that Globomantics
will definitely want to make use of.
Click on Next,
and all we really need to configure is which instance to execute this against.
But hold on, what's this?
AutomationAssumeRole.
We need to create an IAM role that has permissions to execute these
actions against our EC2 instances because the automation service will
have to assume this role to get the permissions.
Okay, over to the IAM console to create a new role.
We create the role and select the EC2 service as the use case.
This will give us a good scaffolding to work with.
Permissions is next, and we search for automation.
There's only this one AutomationAssumeRole,
and it's named here, and that's also the one we now need.
Skip the tags and give our role a name.
And that's pretty much it.
We create the role.
However, there's one more step we need to perform.
As you can see,
selecting the EC2 service configured EC2 as the trusted entity on this role.
That means only EC2 services can assume this role.
Let's change this.
Go back into the role we created and click on Trust relationships.
Edit and,
here under service principal, we need to change this here to an array and
add the ssm.amazonaws.com service. Update and done.
We can now see both SSM and the EC2 service as trusted entities.
We can now go back to the automation service and select our
create AMI document again just like before, only that now we
have all the information we need.
We select the simple instance picker and select our EC2 instance. Here
in the dropdown, we can now simply select the IAM role we just created.
Notice also the NoReboot option here. By default, this is set to false.
Setting this to true means the instance will not be shut down while the
AMI is created.
This doesn't guarantee application‑consistent backups.
We need to make sure we understand this.
If possible, I recommend this should stay on false.
We also get this nice execution link here that we can give
to other people in order to execute this automation document
without going to the console.
Very handy for further automation workflows.
Let's execute this process. Depending on the size of the EC2 instance,
this process can take anywhere from 2 minutes to a couple of minutes more.
Eventually, the status would change from pending to success, and we can go and
check the output. It will tell us the new AMI ID here,
which we can then use to create new AWS instances,
for example.
But where do we find this AMI? That's over in the EC2
service console. Let's go over there.
And in here, we can browse to AMIs. We need to make sure it's configured to
show the AMIs that are owned by us. And yep, here we'll be able to find the AMI ID we just saw in the Systems Manager output.