In this demo,
we will see how we can use parameter store parameters
inside of run command executions.
For this,
we first browse to the parameter store to refresh our
memories of which parameters we created.
We have these two parameters, super‑admin‑name and super‑admin‑password here.
Let's use them both in a run command. Over in Run Command,
as we have done in previous modules, we execute a RunPowerShell
document and plan on having it just output our value.
We put this super simple PowerShell Write‑Output into the Commands text box
here. We rerefer to an existing parameter store parameter.
If it's not encrypted, it's by using this syntax here with the squiggly
brackets and inside the ssm column, followed by the parameter key.
It's important to understand what will happen next.
The instance that we will run this command on will need to have
permission to get parameters from the SSM service.
This will be the case if you followed the earlier demos and used the default
systems manager IAM profile on the EC2 instance. At runtime, the Systems Manager
service or SSM agent, rather, on the EC2 instance,
will look for this parameter and replace this reference with its value.
We select one of our instances to run this on,
disable the S3 logging, and execute the command.
Just a few seconds later,
we can check the output, and as expected and hoped, the
parameter was replaced with the correct value.
Okay, that was easy.
Next step, what do we need to do and look out for
when we need to get a secure string?
We saw that for plain text parameters, there's no code
required, but for encrypted values,
we need to do a little bit more. As a template for other use cases at
Globomantics, this short PowerShell script was developed.
Let's go through it step by step.
You will also find it in the exercise files.
The first two lines depend on the environment we're in, specifically the
region we will execute this run command in and secondly,
the managed instance we want the run command to execute on. And the
next step just sets the shell up to use the default AWS profile in
our PowerShell AWS setup as referred to in the previous demo. In
order to get the actual value from an encrypted parameter, we can use
Get‑SSMParameterValue,
but also have to pass the WithDecryption Boolean true parameter here to the
cmdlet. The return object will have the plain text value then under Parameters
and Value, and we will just store this value in the secretValue variable.
Executing a run command is simply done using the Send‑SSMCommand cmdlet. Similar
to when done in the console, we specify where to run the command on, which
document to execute, in this case,
the RunPowerShellScript document, and we pass in the
required document parameters in the form of this hash
table here. Just like in the console,
we pass in the reference to the unencrypted parameter
with the squiggly bracket syntax.
But for the encrypted value, we have to use the value from the variabile.
We store the output of the SendSSMCommand in the runPSCommand variable here,
which will be the reference to this execution.
We know this only takes a few seconds,
so we can now go and use the Get‑SSMCommandInvocationDetail cmdlet with
that reference under that instance we executed on to get the actual output
just like what we did before in the console.
Here in the output, we can see the standard output content
with the output of our PowerShell document.
So I guess we can already all see a small issue here.
Our secret seems to have been locked in clear text.
We can verify the same has happened in the console
when inspecting that execution.
That is obviously not great and definitely something we should be mindful of.
Alternatively, for PowerShell scripts,
we could look at passing secret parameters in as
PowerShell secure string variables, making sure we never output any secrets or follow other similar patterns.