Hello everyone and welcome to this exciting biking tutorial.
In the previous video we trained our transfer learning model and achieve almost 97 percent of our validation
data set which means that our model is nearly every time correct in recognizing cats and dogs but before
we did into the second part of this section fine tuning let's perform the final evaluation step of our
transfer learning model as you can see I prepared two very simple lines of code for this lesson.
The evaluation function always returns loss and accuracy as it did in the previous sections as well.
The only difference here is that we are using the function that can be fitted with data generator so
instead of evaluate we are using evaluate generator provide valid generator to it executes excel and
we get ninety six point five percent.
That is fantastic results.
Guys we achieved almost state of the art results on these data stand in the next part of the section.
We are going to try to improve these results with a technique called fine tuning for now.
If you have any questions or comments please buzz them in the comments section.
Otherwise I'll assume the next tutorial.