Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial in the previous with you.
We try to improve our results after France for learning by applying the fine tuning technique but we
ended up getting even worse results than before our network overheated and we didn't have the opportunity
to improve previous results which is still fine.
We have achieved amazing results with the transfer learning step alone in some cases the transfer learning
step will produce better results and in other cases the fine tuning will achieve better results.
That really depends on the task itself and the model.
And basically our data set the goal of this video is to perform the evaluation step of our refined you
and model and to confirm results that we achieved in the previous video if you look at the code here
it is the same code that we used in evaluation step of our transfer learning model.
The message here is changed but everything else stays the same.
Let's execute a cell then execute a second cell to print our results.
And as you can see we are getting ninety three point four percent.
The validation and accuracy we achieved during the fine tuning step is correct 1 and that's it for this
section.
If you have any questions or comments please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I assume the next tutorial.