Hello everyone and welcome to despite an editorial in this video we are going to start with our data
validation project.
In the first step of our data validation project is to import all dependencies that we are going to
use.
So let me walk you through them.
The first dependency is pandas we'll be using this library to read and see as few files of our data
set then we have tens of flow in case we use any functions from it.
Next up is our transit flow data validation package.
Next up is our tens offload data validation package which we installed in the previous video because
I'm using Python 2 instead of Python free.
I'm importing these brain function from the future so we can use the same brain function that we use
so far in Python free.
Now we can start with inputting our data set and performing a simple data analysis before we start using
tens offload data validation package.
The first step is to import the data set.
Let's call it data set equal to be the shorter for pandas daughter read CSP.
And now here we have to specify the name of our data set file in our case it is pollution small dots
he is fee execute the cell we imported the data set we can check in the shape of the data set to see
how many samples we have in it and because we have the data set of two thousand and almost two hundred
samples we are going to split in the training set and the test set it is not necessary for this section
but we are going to do this anyways since we want to demonstrate a few additional things that turns
the flow data validation can do right.
Training data is equal to data set and now we will see the first sixteen hundred samples are going to
be our training data then we will use the same technique for the test set but before we do that let
us describe our training data to see what statistics we have in our training data portion so to do that
right.
Training data that describe you can see that we have a few columns in our data set we will explain each
column in a second on the left side we have all statistics that our described function calculated for
us for example the standard deviation for each column demean the value minimum maximum and so on each
column in the data set is a type of particle in air that we are going to measure based on the volume
of each particle on a particular day we can determine if the air is good or bad let's do something more
interesting we will say that the suit the variable of our data set is our target variable we are going
to use m 10 and 0 2 and S.O. 2 to see how well we can perform prediction of the suit variable but just
keep this in mind since we are not going to dig into modelling or creating models for prediction we
are going to use this information to create environments for our data set later on in the last task
for our video is to create our test set so let's write test set is equal to data set and use this sixteen
hundred and arrest of the samples to be in the test set let us describe the test set as well to compare
statistics now we can see the statistics of the test set as you can see there as you can see there is
around 600 points in the test set also the standard deviation the mean and the minimum values are similar
to the ones in our training set and that's it for now in the next video we'll start with our analysis
and validation by using our Denzel flow data validation package if you have any questions or comments
so far please post them in the comments section otherwise I'll assume the next tutorial.