All right let's do this.
Let's build the artificial neural network with tens of low 2.0.
All right.
So first of all the first thing we have to do whenever building an artificial new network which in this
section will be a fully connected neural network is to create the model object itself.
And this object will actually be an instance of a class called a sequential class.
And that's because we are building a fully connected new network which is a series of dance layers and
as opposed to being a computational graph.
Well it is a sequence of layers and that's why we use the sequential class and that sequential class
is taken from the morals module from the caris library that we take from the tensor flow library.
All right.
So we have our moral basically it is initialized as a sequence of layers.
And now we're going to add one by one the different layers that are going to be in this new network.
So once again if you're new to new one that works you absolutely have to close distance only right now
and jump down to the annex parts at the end of the course where we provide the whole theory of artificial
neural networks.
However if you do know about neural networks well you will understand what I'm going to explain in this
tutorial meaning how we're going to add the different layers inside this artificial neural network.
All right.
So let's start with the first one which is a first fully connected hidden layer.
So I specified here in the text the different hyper parameters there are going to be in this first fully
connected hidden layer and we're gonna have one hundred and twenty eight neurons which are called units
by tensor flow.
You know that's the units here.
We'll get to that very quickly then the activation function you know which breaks the linearity inside
your new networks that indeed your new network can learn the nonlinear relationships that are between
the pixels of the images and the output saying which kind of clothes it is.
You know there is no linear relationship between the pixels and the output.
So we have to break the linearity that happens in the way that some of the inputs and then of the neurons
inside the neural network.
In order for the new network to be able to learn the nonlinear relationships and the activation function
that we're using for this first fully connected hidden layer is the realm.
Right.
Classic one this is most of the time the one we use when building a dense layer a dense low by the way
means nothing other than a fully connected layer.
And for this we used to relook also called direct fire activation function which is of course part of
the annexes in the artificial neural network annex.
Okay.
And then the input shape.
Well you know what input shape is.
We understood that the input of the new network are the single vectors which contain all the pixels
of the images flattened into one dimension.
And that's why the input shape here is indeed a vector of 784 elements corresponding to 784 pixels of
each image.
And the fact that we have a colon here and nothing after just means that indeed this is a vector of
seven hundred and eighty four elements.
And so when we add this first layer Well what we have to do is first take our model object which I remind
is an instance of the sequential class.
And as in every class where we have some method and a method we use to add a new fully connected layer
or any layer for that matter is the add method and in the add method well we enter indeed which kind
of layer we want to add to our model.
So right now we're adding a first fully connected here and there and therefore the class with this is
the dance class.
So actually what is being added exactly is an object of the dance class which represents a first fully
connected hidden layer.
And inside this dance class well we have to specify three important arguments.
The first one is the number of units meaning how many hidden neurons we want to have in this first fully
connected hidden layer.
Then the second one is the activation function to break the narrative.
And as we saw this is the relook or rectify activation function which has the string released with no
capital letters.
And the third argument is the input shape which contains basically the input layer or your input vector
that is fed into the new network.
And right.
Remember this input vector contains the 784 pixels that were all flattened from the to the array of
the image.
OK.
So very simple.
But again you don't have to remember this.
The purpose of this course is just to give you some notebooks that you can keep with close to you on
your machine and that you can use any time you want to build a new network with tons of load 2.0.
For one of your projects so you don't have to remember for example that the dance class has taken from
the layers module from the Cairns library and from the Townsville library.
No you can just copy this and then make sure to change the parameters especially this one for the right
input shape and then you can keep this architecture if you want.
You know there is always big work on finding the optimal architecture.
All right so there you go.
Great stuff with added Our first fully connected hidden layer.
Now moving onto the next one.
What we're going to add now is going to be a second layer with drop out.
So what is dropout dropout.
I specified it here.
I explained everything dropout is a regularization technique where we randomly set neurons in a layer
to zero.
In other words you know you're gonna have a layer inside which some neurons are gonna be deactivated
therefore not learning during back propagation you know their weights won't be updated.
That's why I say here while training those neurons won't be updated.
And so how many neurons are gonna be deactivated and therefore not dated.
Well that's a certain percentage of them which we choose when adding this layer will drop out and usually
which is 20 to 50 percent.
All right so let's do this to add this new layer was true about Well of course we use again the add
method inside which we're going to input what we want to add and a new layer with drop out is simply
given by the drop out class which takes as input.
Exactly this percentage of neurons that we want to deactivate basically that want to drop out.
And so that's why here I specified 0.01 meaning 20 percent of neurons are gonna be deactivated from
time to time of course they're not going to be the same deactivated neurons.
Every iteration you know just 20 percent of them will be activated from time to time to block the learning
process.
And the reason why we do this the reason why we added about is to indeed avoid overfishing because by
preventing some neurons from learning well intuitively we understand that this will prevent from learning
too much.
No learning to close the training set and you know when you learn to learn on the training set you'll
have poor results on the test.
And that's what we want to avoid.
Thanks to this drop out technique.
All right so that's for the second layer was drop out.
Now you know the syntax to add a new layer withdrew drop out with sense of flow.
You understand that it's very easy.
I recommend to include this in your new networks drop out as always very efficient and can improve the
results on the evaluation set.
So just make sure to keep that close to you.
And now we're going to add the output layer which is of course the final layer of your new network that
contains the output meaning that contains the final class that the new network predicts on the image
you know the new network predicts which clothes basically is the input image that was fed to it.
And so well here I specify the info the units argument which is how many neurons you want to have in
your output layer.
It's gonna be ten because we have ten classes and we're actually using the soft Max activation function
in order to get probabilities for each of the class.
And you know the final output the final prediction will be the class that has the highest probability.
So that's why instead of having one neuron in the output layer as the final predicted class well we
have 10 classes with their predicted probabilities.
And so there you go.
That's how you add this final output layer using again the add method and then the dance class.
And that's because you want some full connections between your second layer with about and the output
layer and this dance class takes again as argument unit which is how many neurons you're gonna have
in the output layer meaning ten because we have ten classes and the activation function that will get
you the final output which is set Max meaning that before getting the final output we will return some
probabilities for each of the classes and return the final class that has the highest probability.
All right.
And that's it.
That's how you build the full architecture of the new network intensive flow.
And by having this you know I included enough so that then you can build any other architecture of any
neural network you want because now you know how to add any type of layers.
I'm not talking about the ones we're having a convolution on the one network I'm talking about the layers
and fully connected neural network.
We know how to add a simple first fully connected here and there with the dance class you also know
how to add another layer with drop out and you know how to add the output layer.
So for if you want to add a second fully connected here and there and actually this will be one of the
exercises.
Well you know you just need to use the add method again and input the dance class inside with a certain
number of hidden neurons.
You want to have in this new hidden layer and then I'm giving you an extra and you have to remove this
because you need this is only entered when adding the first fully connected hidden layer therefore connected
to the input layer.
Right.
Otherwise you can just simply include this.