Hello and welcome back to of course on deep learning.
Today we're talking about stochastic gradient descent.
Previously we learned about gradient descent and we found out that it is a very efficient method to
solve our optimization problem where we are trying to minimize the cost function.
It basically takes us from 10 to the power of 57 years to solving a problem within minutes or hours
or within a day or so.
And it really helps speed things up because we can see which way is downhill and we can just go in that
direction and take steps and get to the minimum faster.
But the thing with the stick of gradient descent is that this method requires for the class function
to be convex.
And as you can see here we've specifically chosen a convex cost function basically convex means that
the function looks similar to what we are seeing now that it's just convex into one direction and that
it in essence has one global minimum.
And that's the one that we're going to find.
But what if our function is not convex.
What if our cost function is not corrects what if it looks something this.
Well first of all how could that happen.
Well that could happen because if we first of all choose a cost function which is not the squared difference
between white hat and why or if we do choose the cost function which is like that.
But then in a multidimensional space it can actually turn into something that is not convex.
And so what would happen in this case if we just tried to apply our normal gradient descent method something
like this could happen we could find a local minimum of the cost function rather than the global one.
So this one was the best one.
And we found the wrong one.
And therefore we don't have the correct weights.
We don't have an optimized neural network.
We have a subpar neural network.
And so what do we do in this case.
Well the answer here is stochastic gradient descent.
And it turns out the sarcastic gradient descent doesn't require for the cost function to be convex.
So let's have a look at the two differences between the normal gradient descent that we talked about
and the stochastic readings.
So normal gradient descent is when we take all of our rows we plug them into our neural network and
once again here we've got the neural network copied over several times but the rows are being plugged
into that same neural network every time.
So there's only one neural network this is just four viz. purposes.
And then once we've plugged them in we've calculated our cost function based on the forming on the right
and looking at the chart on the at the bottom and then we adjust the weights then this is called the
gradient descent method or it's also the proper term is the batch gradient descent method.
So we take the whole batch of from our sample we apply it and then we run that the stochastic gradient
descent method is a bit different here we take the rows one by one.
So we take this row we run our neural network and then we adjust the weights then we move onto the second
row we take the second row we run our neural network we look at the cost function and then we adjust
the weights again and then we take another 0 take or 3 we run our neural network we look at the cost
function we're just away.
So basically we're looking at we're adjusting the weights after every single row rather than doing everything
together and then adjusting weights to different approaches and now we're going to just compare the
two side by side.
So here they are.
This is how to visually remember them.
So you've got the batch gradient descent where you are adjusting the weights after you've run them after
you've run all of the rows in your neural network and then basically you just the weights and you run
the whole thing again iteration iteration iteration in the grip stochastic gradient descent method you
run one row at a time and you are just the weights you are just a way to adjust the weights and then
you do everything again and again and that is called discussing gradient descent method.
The main two differences are that the stochastic gradient descent method helps you avoid the problem
where you find those local extremes or local minimums rather than the overall overall global minimum.
And the reason for that in simple terms is that the as GDR or the stochastic gradient descent method
has much higher fluctuations because it can afford them.
It's doing one iteration or one row at a time and therefore the fluctuations are much higher and it
is much more likely to find the global minimum rather than just the local minimum.
And the other thing about the stochastic gradient descent nothing compared to the batch gradient is
that is faster like the first impression that you might have is because it's doing every single roll
one at a time it is slower but actually in fact it is faster because it is.
It doesn't have to load up all the data into memory and run and wait until all those rows are un altogether.
You can just roll around them one by one so it's a much later algorithm is much faster in that sense
so though it has way more in that's in those senses it has more advantages over the batch gradient descent
method.
The main advantage of all of the main kind of like pro for the batch gradient descent method is that
it is a deterministic algorithm or other than stochastic gradient descent.
Being a sarcastic algorithm meaning it's random and the batch gradient descent method as long as you
have the same starting weights for your neural network every time you run the batch gradient descent
method you will get the same iterations the same results for yo for the way your weights are being updated.
For us to have for the stochastic gradient descent method you won't get that because it is a stochastic
method you are picking your rows possibly at random and you are updating your neural network in a sarcastic
manner and therefore you're just going to every single time you run the sarcastic gradient descent method
even if you have the same weights at the start you're going to have a different process and different
iterations to get there.
So that's in a nutshell what's to cast a gradient descent is also there's a method in between the tool
called the Mini batch gradient descent method where you combine the two new basically run rather than
running a whole batch or running one at a time you run batches of rows maybe five 10 100 of them in
euros you decide to set you run those that number of rows at a time then you update your weights and
you obliterates and so on and that's called the Mini batch gradient descent method.
If you'd like to learn more about gradient descent there's a great article which you can have a look
at.
It's called a neural network in 13 lines of Python part 2.
Gradient descent by Andrew trust.
And the links below it's on GitHub 2015 article.
Very well-written very in very simple terms.
It's got some interesting philosophical or just interesting thoughts on how to apply green descent.
What are the advantages and disadvantages and how to be how to do things in certain situations so he's
got some very cool tips tricks and hacks.
Very easy read so definitely check that out.
And another one a bit more heavier read.
For those of you who are into mathematics who want to get to the bottom of the mathematics why gradient
descent is that specific.
What are the formulas that are driving greenness and how is it calculate and so on.
Check out the article or actually the book.
It's a free online book called neural networks and deep learning by Michael Nielsen 2015 book it's just
basically it's all online you can go ahead and check it out there and there.
Again very soft introduction to the mathematics.
But then for a mother.
But the mathematics are pretty heavy as you go along as you read through the article.
But at the same time it gets you into into that movie.
I think you mean it has like a warm up chapter where you first warm up with the math and then you jump
into them.
So interested in math then this is the article to go to and there we go.
So that's in a nutshell.
The difference between green descent and stochastic gradient descent and how to work and on that note
we're going to wrap up today Central.
I look forward to seeing you on the next one.
And until then enjoy deep learning.