Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial.
In the previous video we define our custom model by combining a Bayes network which is a pre train model
called Mobile that to be two in our custom head for the specific task of classifying cats and dogs.
The next step for us is to compile the model if you remember how we compile all models in previous sections.
It is going to be the same even though we are using the pre train as well which are more complicated
and loading in different ways.
The combining step is totally the same so in the first free cell right model does compile and now we
have to provide free arguments as always an optimizer a lost function and metrics.
So in this case we want specified the optimizer with the string as before we are going to use a specific
tensor flow function for it.
I'll explain why in just a second.
So just write they don't care us but optimizes and now we have to choose what optimizer to use since
we are using that mobile Net.
Architecture is our base network.
It is proven to be the best optimized for it.
Air mass prop so we are going to choose it.
And because we are using a pre train network we have to specify smaller learning rate than default 1
if we want to specify an optimizer with a string.
It will take all default arguments but we have to change the learning rate parameter.
In this case and that's why we have used that tends to flow function to set our optimizer instead of
simple string so inside Aramis prop provide L are shorter for learning rate and said that to be zero
point three zeros and one at this point.
You may wonder how do they knew what learning rate to choose when I prepared this section for you.
I use mumble net architecture for the first time as well so I had to google a lot of stuff and they
found on Stack Overflow what learning array to choose for this architecture now said the loss to binary
cross entropy since we are only have two classes in our set.
And lastly let us provide metrics that we are going to monitor throughout the training process in this
case.
We are going to simply use an accuracy execute the cell and we have successfully compiled the model
in the next video.
We are going to create our data generators for the data set for now.
If you have any questions or comments please bother them in the comments section.
Otherwise I see in the next tutorial.