Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial in the previous with you.
We have compiled our model and basically our model is ready to be trained but before we start with our
training process there are some steps that we have to do about data in the previous sections.
We performed all data sets pre processing steps manually from scaling to reshaping the data set in this
section and we haven't done any of these things except extracting the data set and now for the first
time we are going to use tensor flow data generators to accomplish all of those data celebrate processing
steps since we are working with Image Data.
We are going to use imagery data generator and not only that but we are going to create two generators
one for each data subset one for our training data and another one for validation.
This is good practice in general because sometimes we are going to perform different year processing
steps on a different data set subset.
Here we have some essential nodes that we are going to use to create our data cell prior processing
steps.
If you remember from a few years ago we have set a very specific AMG shape for our data set.
You may hear wondered why that shape each retrain the model supports only specific inputs sizes.
And if you want to use those models we have to reshape our data set to match some of those.
In the case of mobile led here you can see all of supportive input sizes.
Okay.
Now that we have that cleared let's write the code for our data set the generators to define our First
Data generator.
Define a variable called Data Jan and then specify for what subset it is to train for this one then
the right image data generator.
And if we check into doctoring we will see that it accepts a lot of arguments in all of those arguments
are used for pre processing of image in some way I encourage you to study them in more detail for our
example we are going to use only reskill which is what we did so far.
Divide each pixel by two hundred and fifty five to make them between 0 and 1 since these re scale works
by multiplying each pixel and not dividing it.
We will said that to tourist scale by 1 divided by two hundred and fifty five let's copy this line to
create a data generator for our validation data set pasted below and rename these data and train to
data.
Jan Barrett.
The next step is to specify for each generator where to find the data set and how to process it defined
the train generator and set it to data.
Jan train as you can see there are a lot of things.
What we can do but since our data set is in the folder we have to use these function flow from directory
function this function will load our data set from the specific folder in the background so it won't
occupy any room for us or slow down the train process for arguments of this function.
There is the directory where all images are located and that is the first argument.
Then we have target shape which should be the same as I am the shape that we defined before then we
are going to specify the batch size or how many images we feed through the model.
At the same time.
Lastly we are going to specify class name.
It can be a binary categorical or input since we only have two classes in our data set.
We are going to specify these two binary okay for the first argument.
Use the train Dir.
Let's be defined at the very beginning of a dissection target size is 128 by 128 which is the same as
our AMG shape then said batch size to 128 as well.
You can set this to higher if you want since we have a lot of resources in Google column.
And lastly said the class mode 2 binary execute a cell and as you can see it automatically detected
two classes in our dataset and how many images we have as well.
Let's copy the whole declaration for the train generator and pasted in the free cell instead of train
right.
Valid and instead of data Gen train set data Gen valid and the first argument is train their specify
validation the rest of arguments to stay the same.
And now we have data.
Generally there is for our train data set and validation data set.
That's all what we have to do for this video.
If you have any questions or comments please post them in the comments section otherwise I'll see in
the next tutorial.