Hello and welcome in this video we are going to be adding a new model behavior called the base stats
script which is going to have two important properties the starting level for this particular player
or character and then the character class which could be any one of player grunt at major Archer in
my game.
In your game it might be different.
Let's dive in and see why this class is important and how we're gonna use it in the grand scheme of
things one of the key mechanics that differentiates an RPG from any other sort of game is progression.
And the idea with progression is that you level up as you go through the level you encounter more and
more difficult enemies and their stats and the whole system increases you can easily beat a lower level
enemy but you find it tricky with higher level enemies.
One of the core mechanics.
So one of the ways that we want to do this is give the designers the tools to implement the progression
of our game.
Now the way typically designers like to think about this is in spreadsheets.
So we often want to have tools for importing spreadsheets full of numerical values into our game.
Now we're not going to do that in this part of the course we're going to do it in part 2 but we are
going to have a central script for objects where you can define the progression within unity.
So that's the idea we've got our grunts and our player prefabs which have got health and fighter components
on them which might want to know about certain stats like what is my health.
What is the damage that I do as a fighter.
And that should be defined by the progression which is going to be basically this big spreadsheet this
big all object assets in unity that is divided up like so we start off with having all the stats for
the grunt and we have the stats such as health and damage and those stats are then broken down by level
so you've got the health at level one healthy level to help at level three etc. and then we have the
same thing going on for the player and that's all broken down by level as well.
I just haven't gone into the detail showing here because I don't have enough space on the slide and
then what we need to do to tie these two things together is to introduce this base stats game scripts
will object.
Sorry not script logic mono behavior that's the one I mean mono behavior on our grunts and on our player
which basically says hey I can provide you these stats from progression if you tell me what my classes.
So for example the grunt is a grunt class and the player is a player class.
And what level you're at then what I can do is if you ask me for health so example for the health component
says hey base stats what is my health then base stats goes off and consults the script will object to
the progression and says Hey well you are a grunt and you're asking for health and you're asking for
help at level 2.
So here is your health.
That's the system that we want to put in place in the next few lectures.
And as the starting point at least and then we've got lots to go from there is such as doing more and
more attributes and sterilizing this and making sure it's all saved in the save system and gaining your
experience points and leveling up and so on.
But first of all we've got to implement this basic structure and architecture.
So I'm going to start off with implementing the base stats class.
So let's go ahead and do that.
I'm going to create a new folder first of all in scripts and I'm going to call this folder progression
now.
Actually scratch that I'm going to call it stats because at more general it's gonna be all about the
stats of the player the health the damage and the fact that we've got a progression within stats is
more of a detail.
So we're going to go ahead and create a new C sharp script here.
I'm going to cool this base stats.
Now why do I call it base stats and not just stats because later on in the game we are going to have
things like modifiers.
So when you equip a certain weapon it is going to give you a bonus to your base stats and your health
stat might go up based on having a particular healthy sword or something like that.
So we're gonna go ahead and open up the base stats script and just sort it out a little bit.
I'm going to put it all in a namespace for example.
So when start a new namespace RPG stats and then we are going to go ahead and I think just strip out
start and update.
We don't need these as of yet but what we do need is some serialize fields.
So the first serialized field is going to be easy the easy one is going to be the end.
It's gonna be a level.
So we're going to have the level of character that is straightforward I'm going to start off with a
base level of 1 as the default.
Now the second thing is slightly harder because what we want to have is the class.
So you could start off with having a string for your class or I'm going to call this the character class
to avoid conflicts with keywords like class up here.
Now you could have a string but I wouldn't recommend that.
The reason being it's going to cause all sorts of copy and paste issues and it's much nicer if we could
just have a dropdown in the editor and to do drop downs in the editor.
It's fairly straightforward.
All you need is an enum.
So we're going to go ahead and create a new file for our enum because enemies can just go in the root.
I'm gonna call this the character class don't see S and E can just go in the root like this.
So if I go ahead and use one of the auto completes for enum it's fairly straightforward that's all it
is.
So it's going to be an item called character class like so and I'm going to wrap that actually in a
namespace.
So it's going to be namespace RPG dot stance again and we don't need any includes here.
So we've already talked about some of the classes we might have here if you want to add more classes
you'll have to come into this file and add it that's the downside of not using a string.
But I think that's relatively straightforward down sides to avoid you can just come in here and add
anything that you want to the end of the enum.
So we're going to have player is going to be the first character class the second one is going to be
the grunt and we're going to have for the sake of it a mage in here as well just to show you that there
could be more and more values in here you might have spiders you might have all sorts of different character
classes that have their own slightly different progressions.
So we're going to go with this player is going to be probably the one we're going to use but we're going
to use a character class that's what I mean say and to use this character class as the class for character
class serialized field.
Oh wow.
We get all stuck up in all those things.
So we've got the character class that's going to be some that we set.
And also I'm going to just rename levels just before we get any further into starting level because
we know the characters can especially the player can level up.
So this is going to be just the level that you start at.
Really.
And one more thing we might want to do is stick a range in here so that we can't go and make it negative.
We can't give it values that we don't want it to have such a zero and we don't want to.
If we're starting level is one we don't want a level zero as well.
So we can do this easily with the little range annotation just before our serialized field and the range
annotation takes some arguments like this a minimum and a maximum I'm gonna to say that our minimum
is going to be one level one all the way to ninety nine.
And what this is going to do is it's going to put a slider on our mono behavior.
So when we go and edit it in unity talking of editing and unity I think it's time for you to have a
bit of a challenge here.
So I'd like you to set up the prefabs that character prefabs the enemy the player set them up so that
they have this base stats script on them and make sure you change the default class the default character
class depending on whether it's the player or the grunt so that in the world they have the right default
class and you can even mess around and have a look at how the level is showing up in the editor that
plays video and how to go.
Welcome back.
Let's give this a shot shall we.
So we're going to go ahead and find ourselves out of the game folder and characters folder.
We want the character first of all and the character.
We aren't going to go ahead and add on a component called the base stats components.
And as you can see it's defaulting to the Player class I'm actually against default it in the character
prefab to the grunt character class.
So that's basically if we're creating things off of this by default then a grunt then not a player because
that's gonna be a bit weird if there were always players.
So they're starting level is going to be a one.
I think that's fair enough.
Now let's go and check it out.
If the enemies and the archer we've got an archer here maybe we should add a character class for Archer
to do that in fact.
So we've got the Archer as a new character class would go over into our arch prefab then with the archer
selected we can go down find his base stats and just switch him over to being an archer at level one
archer then we'd go over to the enemy and we can find the enemy's base stats he should be a grunt by
default and that's fine.
And then if I go over to the play Alice the final piece of the puzzle the players base stats should
be player.
So his character class is plan that's going to know how to look it up in this progression prefab progression
scripts will fit rather so we've created our first part of the puzzle this base stats thingamabob and
in the next lecture we're going to set up an actual progression scriptural object so that we have something
to point our base stats at C that.