Hello and welcome to the next section of the course in this section we're going to be creating a moment.
Our first gameplay moment for the player.
And we're going to make it even more interesting by exploring sinner machine and creating ourselves
a little bit of a cinematic where we take control away from the player.
We switch around the cameras we present the scenario that they're about to engage with and then we take
the control back to the player again so that the person playing the game can work their way through
the moment or the challenge that we've created for them.
So we're going to be talking a little bit about game design theory we're gonna be doing a bunch of snow
machine.
We're going to be doing timelines in a machine and tunneling go hand in hand.
And the end of it hopefully we'll have something that feels pretty cool as it's just a 15 to 30 second
moment that we can say this is what our game is starting to feel like and it will give us a great feel
for what we need to work on next to make our game even more interesting.
Okay.
We've got this moment.
What is next.
So let's jump in and create ourselves our first moment.