This video is a quick overview to show you what we'll have done by the end of this section.
We will have our character running around in our world navigating seamlessly around objects looking
cool with a full blend tree animation that we'll set up from scratch.
Here we are in our scene.
You'll see that we'll set up a simple terrain just drop a couple of place holder houses in there a little
bit of structure.
No need to go to town just yet set up our navigation using a nav mesh and putting a nav mesh agent on
our player.
So the player does some really cool things like just understands that it needs to go around objects that
are marked as static in the world you can see they're just kind of figures it out like a clever little
sausage that is great work and you can see our blend tree down here which will be part of our animation
system sorry animator system.
There we go.
Just one state of locomotion in a blend.
tree dropping in a couple of assets and implementing a follow camera to follow the player around.
So let's jump in and start getting a little bit of a sandbox together so we can make movement for our
game.