So the beginning of a new section it's time for me to tell you about all the wonderful features we're
going to be implementing here I am in the prototype you might see some differences because I based it
off some lectures before Rick finished off the last section.
So what have we got going on here.
What are we going to be implementing it's the enemy I.S. obviously we're gonna be talking about enemy
II but let's be more specific about the features that we actually want.
So the first thing we're going to have is a chase radius.
That means that when we are within distance of a player of a player of an enemy.
Let me get my scale right.
If we're in the distance they're going to come and chase after me.
Okay.
So what's next after the chase radius.
We're gonna have aggression behavior.
So if I let him actually get to me he's going to give me punches.
And that's going to reduce my health.
I look at the player then you can see my health points going down as he punches me.
So you've got some symmetry there we can punch them they can punch us now.
Whoops.
Now there's gizmos so gizmos are what we're seeing here.
And both the scene view and the game view you can enable them and disable them from these menus and
I can disable them in game view so we don't have to see them.
But what they're telling us is this blue sphere for example is the chase radius.
That's when I get with and that he comes and tries to attack me.
These little gray orbs are actually that patrol routes which we'll talk about in a sec.
So we've got to have suspicious behavior as well.
So let me demonstrate this if I move out of his chase radius.
He's going to try and chase me to the last known location and then he's going to go back to whatever
he was doing before.
Which brings me on to the guarding behavior and the patrol routes which are also going to implement
you can see he's on a patrol route.
He's going backwards and forwards and there's other guard too who's going backwards and forwards between
his patrol routes which is all hunky dory.
But we've also got guarding behavior.
So these guys are just standing at the door.
And if I go and attract their attention but run away then they will return to their posts as guards
where they left off just like this guy returns to his patrol route.
So that's the general gist of the section lots of fun stuff to be implementing and obviously there's
other things I haven't mentioned that we will be going over to on the course of implementing all of
these features.
I look forward to it and I'll see you in there.