Hey and welcome to this.
Saving asset pack S..
So in this section we're gonna be looking at importing a saving asset pack that I have created for you
that you can use not only in this game but in any games that you create in order to add in a savings
system that is entirely flexible and we'll be able to save any of the data in any of the components
that you create.
I'll be taking you over how to use it how to implement it in the RPG which will give you the transferable
skill of being able to use it elsewhere.
Now the actual creation of this asset pack is going to be quite in-depth and quite advanced.
I have included it in the next section of this course which is an optional section you do not have to
take that and if you don't consider yourself an intermediate to advanced but just on the lower end of
intermediate then I don't recommend you take that section at least not yet.
Maybe it's something you want to loop back around to once you have finished this course.
So the only day of the saving system is that when we hit play it reloads the last level that we were
in.
And also all the state that is relevant.
So my location and the level my health and also the health and status whether they're dead or not of
the guard.
So you can see this.
God I had killed in a previous round.
But go ahead and kill this guard as well or even lure him away is all the locations of the guards are
also being saved.
And then I go through to the world again so you can see the fading transitions are still in place.
What happened as I went between worlds is that it saved and reloaded the state from that other world.
And if I come back here you can see that God is a stayed dead.
So we're keeping that state between at different levels.
But also if I go ahead and hit play again it's going to reload me from a last check point which is when
I came through the portal and that God is still dead.
And also that same thing is true for my position my health and so on so forth and all this is going
to be saved to your file system for you to reload at a later time it's a very flexible system and allows
us to save not just the health and position but anything that you might be storing in any components
the state of a quest for example is all going to be possible and extensible using this system so that's
what the saving system looks like.
Let's dive in and see how to use it.