Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we are gonna be creating a fading carotene so that when I hit play on START we're going
to fade out.
It's gonna wait for the fade out to finish before printing something and fading back in very quickly
and all of that is going to be configurable the amount of time.
These are the building blocks with which we're going to create our fading out between scenes let's dive
in and see how to create them so we've got this Fader object which allows us to change the alpha of
the canvas group manually.
But what we want to do is turn this into a scripted approach that effectively over time will fade the
Alpha out and then back in again.
This is fairly straightforward to do with Ko routines.
But first of all let's go ahead and create a class.
So I'm gonna go over to do this in Visual Studio code and in the scene management fall down and add
a new file called Fader dot c s and then I am going to create a mono behavior and it is going to be
put into a namespace of type RPG dot scene management like so and then in this we are going to create
code routine.
So we're going to need to return AI in numerator.
And this isn't included yet.
And then we aren't going to have a functional fade out.
And the argument is going to take is a float time.
That's the time it's going to take to fade out.
Now we're going to need to include the right namespace for iron numerator so controlled dots will do
a using System dot collection and it's giving us an error on fade out because we're not yielding anything
returning anything.
So what are we going to put in fade out.
Well the general structure of this is that we're going to go over for a few frames.
We are going to every frame update the alpha by a certain amount so that at the after the time given
in here the value of the Alpha will have arrived at 1.
So we're going from zero to 1 in a fade out.
So how is that going to look.
How much Alpha do we need to be applying each frame.
Let's have a look.
So imagine these are your frames that you have in which you are going to update the alpha to get from
zero at the beginning of this all the way to one at the end.
So at the time this takes is the time variable and that's how much time we've got to do fade.
And each individual chunk each in the visual frame takes up delta time amount.
So how many frames do we have in total.
Well you can have a little mini challenge here if you want to figure out how many frames we have in
total from the delta time in the time.
That's right.
It is n divide is going to be the time divided by the delta time.
That's how many chunks we've got right.
Simple maths and the Delta Alpha.
How much we have to change Alpha in each one of these frames to go from zero to one is going to be one
divided by n.
Because we want to go from zero to one that's a change of one amount when he unit and if we divide that
through equally between all the frames that we'll make give us the Delta Alpha.
So in total what we end up with is Delta Alpha is equal to 1 times delta time divided by time.
And if you know your mass one times is just negligible we don't need to have that in there it's the
same as saying delta time divided by time.
So that's what we're going to want to update every frame.
How do we do something every frame in a car routine when why not use starts.
Well we want to do every frame but only for a limited amount of time.
So we're gonna put in a while loop that says Do this only for a limited amount of time for now I'm just
going to leave.
The condition is false which basically means it's not going to ever execute but I am going to leave
it up to you to actually flesh this out maybe mini challenge for you to think about when is it that
we should stop this car routine.
When is it that we aren't executing anymore Well we're not going to be executing anymore.
Once Alpha has reached 1 so the condition for a while loop is going to be the opposite of that that
Alpha is not one because we want to update Alpha until it is 1.
Similarly inside the body of the while loop.
What are we going to be doing moving Alpha towards 1 right.
And the amount we're moving it is given by this equation here for you to figure out how to do so that
is the basics of it but we're going to need a few more things we're going to need for a start access
to our canvas group.
So many challenge if you like to get access to the canvas group we're going to create a canvas group
variable and I'm just in a cool less canvas group and in start let's create a start method.
We're just going to set that canvas group variable to a get component of type canvas group.
Like so now with that canvas group you're able to do things like do the canvas group dots Alpha and
you can set that and you can get the Alpha value from that.
But what I'm also gonna do for testing purposes.
Because we're not calling this car routine from anywhere is we going to start the keratin here in start
and just use it to debug our fading in and fading out.
So I'm going to do a fade out of three seconds like so just to test things out.
Obviously nothing is going to happen just yet.
And by the way to make something wait for one single frame in a car routine if you don't already know
this.
You need to yield return something because that's what we do when we want to wait for anything to happen
inside a car routine and the way to wait.
Exactly one frame is a yield return.
No it's very simple.
We'll return null basically says to you and say hey this coating should be run again on the next possible
opportunity on the next frame.
And that's what we'll do.
So your challenge is to finish this car routine off.
What should the end condition be and what and how.
Will you update the alpha pose video and have a go OK.
Welcome back.
So we're going to have a go.
The Alpha is not one.
So let's try that.
I'm going to do a canvass group dot Alpha is not equal to one.
Simple as that.
That should work for now.
And there is a caveat here that generally we should never do equality comparisons between floats but
it will work.
It's just a general safety thing that we shouldn't do it and I'll show you how we can get around that
in a sec.
But don't worry about it for now.
OK now we're going to move the alpha towards one how we're going to do that.
Well canvass group dot Alpha plus equals I'm going to increment Alpha and I'm going to incremented by
that Delta amount that we looked at on the previous slide which is just the delta time divided by time.
So it's going to be time dot Delta time divided by time which is the total time it's going to take us
and that should allow us to increase Alpha all the way up to 1.
Well let's see if that does the trick.
Let's go ahead and hit play and it's not working because I haven't put the fader script on the fader
game object let's add that and see if it works.
Now Yep sure enough it is fading out over the course of about three seconds up to 1 and then Alpha stops
at 1.
Is what we'd expect.
Now generally speaking is this could be a bit dodgy because for example we could overshoot alpha in
this case the alpha in canvas group doesn't allow us to overshoot it clamps it but it is possible that
we could have overshot alpha so that we shouldn't really have done an equality here.
Could've done inequality for example so we should say that while Alpha is maybe less than one would
have been a better option here and we can give that a try it should be the same.
Go ahead and hit play.
It should increase until it reaches 1.
Perfect.
Done done the job.
And that's about it.
That's what we want to do with a fade out now.
I'd like to create a fade in as well.
So let's go ahead and just copy this method and we won't try and extract it out and make it more abstract
than this.
We're just going to change it to a phased in over certain amount of time fade in basically is going
from one to zero.
So you might want to have a little mini challenge here to update the code here to allow it to go from
1 to 0 1 2 0 instead of 0 to 1.
So have a go Okay so what we're going to do is we gonna have to change this inequality around so it's
gonna be that Alpha has to be greater than zero while it's greater than zero.
We're going to be decreasing the alpha.
So it's going to be a minus equals and still the same amount of time applies because according to our
slide we're still making a change of one.
Right.
We're going from zero to one it's still a change of one over the whole time span.
So that should be allowing us to do fade in.
Now what I'm gonna do is actually show you how we can nest Ko routines here.
What I'm going to do is create a new car routine I enumerate or called fade out in.
Which is going to fade out and then fade back in again.
And what I want to show you is that we can yield return a KO routine function really a function that
returns an iron numerator and by doing that we are telling this co routine the fade out in that it should
wait until this carotene has finished so I can do a three second fade out then I can do a print statement
saying faded out and then I can yield return the fade in Chi routine and maybe I don't know.
Take two seconds to do that so it should be a bit quicker or maybe one seconds make it really obvious
that it's quicker.
And then after that fade has finished we are going to print faded in like so.
So we can tell hopefully that this is waiting because of these print statements.
So I'm going to instead of starting our fade currently I'm going to start our fade out in routine and
start and see what happens let's get my console open and clear the logs and hit play so starting fading
out and we get our log message saying fade out and then very quickly afterwards one second afterwards
it fades back in and we've got our faded in log message.
So that's how nesting coatings works.
It can be very very handy and we're going to use that here in our transition because we want to fade
out before we do our scene load because we don't want any jarring changes to the scene to be visible
so we want to make sure we're fully Alford out the scene.
So to summarize this lecture we've created this fatal component and we have created two main code routines
which I'm actually going to make public so public fade out and public fade in.
Which are going to be the interface to this Fader that just allows us to fade it out over time and fade
it back in over time.
Great stuff in the next lecture we're going to learn how we can make this Fader persist between scenes
so there's only ever one fader.
I look forward to seeing you that.