Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we're gonna be learning how to save experience points so you can see you've got ten
serious points here.
I go into the next level and find my player again.
Then you can see that the experience points are still 10.
So we've saved our experience points into the save file.
Let's dive in and see how to do it.
So this video should be really brief because what we're going to be doing is just saving the XP of your
player.
And basically this should be very easy and it's going to be entirely a challenge for you.
So you're going to implement IceSave bill on the experience class.
And what will you store.
And then obviously go ahead and test it out and make sure it's working when you go between scenes you
keep the same experience points when you save and quit and come back.
You should have the same experience points.
Those videos have a go OK.
Welcome back.
So let's give this a shot.
So first of all we want to go into scripts and it is the resources we're looking for and the experience
script.
And as we can see in the experienced script what we're looking at is something that just stores experience
points.
So that's quite easy.
We're going to include.
So using RPG dot saving and then we're going to implement the Icesave ABL interface which with the control
dots implement interface we are going to have a capture state and restore state.
I'm just gonna order it.
So that capture state comes after the experience gain experience public method.
And what we're going to return for capture state.
Well quite straightforwardly we just want to store our experience points.
So let's just return that the experience points on the other hand restoring the state.
We know that what comes back must be a float.
And that's what we're going to use to set our experience points so that experience points can be equal
to these states except that we want to cast that state to a float to make sure that we are getting the
right type back.
And that should pretty much be it can be a really short lecture if that works.
So let's go ahead and hit play over in the editor and let's see.
So currently what's our experience for go to player and find his experience he's got zero experience
going to whack this enemy a bit and then he's going to die and I gained 10 experience points go to the
next level and find my player again in the hierarchy scroll down and his experience points is still
10 and I just want to verify that if I go back through here thus saving the game and that enemy is dead
if I exit the game play the game again then you can see the enemy died but also if I look at my player
sure enough it still got 10 experience points shy and successful and time to move on to the next lecture
where we will see how to display the experience points.