Hello and welcome in this lecture we're gonna get it back to working so that we can come back.
We can cancel our combat and all of that good stuff and we're gonna be doing this using a new language
feature you may not come across before.
Call the interface we're going to be implementing an interface and figuring out how that helps us to
call from the action scheduler to the mover and fighter depending on which one it is without having
to introduce more dependency cycle.
So this is quite cool quite interesting.
Let's dive in and see how it's done so we're in a bit of a conundrum here where we've got printing cancellation
working correctly but it can't possibly call the functions of cancel on mover and fighter because they're
of different types.
If I were to change this mono behavior to fighter then it wouldn't work for mover if I changed it to
move then it wouldn't work for fighter.
So one way I could try and solve this is by casting I could say in here for example if you know something
along the lines of if it's a fighter type then we can do something if it's move then we're going to
call a different function but there is a problem with this at the moment we've got a dependency set
up this way but if I were to try and call it a movement in combat I would be also creating dependencies
from the scheduler down to the movement in combat modules which means that we've got dependency cycles
again which is absolutely no good whatsoever.
So what we can do to solve this problem is introduce something called an interface to invert the dependencies
where we had dependencies that would go down from scheduler to movement so we could call from schedule
to movement.
We can invert these dependencies so then instead there's a dependency going from movement to these scheduler
to the AI action in fact what is an AI action it is an interface it is a contract between the implementer
of the contract this would be movement and combat are the implementers and the caller of the contract
which is gonna be the scheduler which is gonna depend on AI action.
So how does an interface work.
Let's have a look.
I'm going to create a new file for our interface and call it AI action and we'll see why in a sec.
I'm also going to put it in a namespace of RPG or core.
And then we can use the interface syntax which I've got a snippet for the unity snippet will automatically
add the name for me and it's very much like a class except instead of using the keyword class we use
the key word interface.
Now what does that mean.
Well it is a contract so we can say that anything that implements this interface that's movement and
combat has to have a certain method.
So I can say that it needs to have void cancel.
For example notice I don't have to say that it's public.
Everything in an interface is public because there is no implementation in the interface.
You can't have any bodies to these cancel for example notice I put a semicolon on the end.
I can't actually put any kind of implementation in here.
I can't put any variables I can't do anything like that.
I can only be methods or properties things that can be implemented in other classes.
So it is just a contract.
There's nothing more to it.
It doesn't actually implements anything itself.
So the point of this is that now when I have this I action and I've told it that it must implement cancel.
Well I can go to the action scheduler and say instead of a mono behavior let's take in this cool I action
thing and I can because I know that end of anything that implements I action has to implement cancel
I can call action or cancel the eagle eyed among you might notice.
This actually introduces a bug what I wanted to do was call current action dot cancel and I will correct
that later on in the video but just say this doesn't trip you up when you come to do the challenge that's
what you need to change.
Now let me demonstrate this.
This is how you would implement my action.
You go over to something that you want to implement I action.
For example we go to the mover and we know that we want it to implement I action because it's giving
us this error here that if I try and pass in this to start action it's saying hey I can't convert mover
into an AI action it should make sense because it doesn't implement that interface so I can get to implement
the interface to obey the contract and you can sit by basically putting comma and then the interface
after the things that are inherited at the top here.
So notice you can't inherit from more than one class but you can inherit from as many interfaces as
you like now.
Now it's saying to me the error is move or does not implement interface member cancel.
So what I am saying is I need to have a function here a public function called cancel right.
So that should be public void.
Cancel.
It has to be the same in all respects the same number of arguments the same type of the arguments the
same return value.
And once I've done that.
Notice that era has gone away because now move implements I action.
And that means I can safely pass it into the start action because when I.
Because then in start action I can treat it like a start action I can call cancel I know it must have
a cancel implementation.
This is basically why it allows us to invert the dependencies when the scheduler wants to call cancel
on EI action.
It actually gets redirected to the movement to the movers implementation of cancel.
If instead it was an instance of combat if it was an instance of fighter instead of movement then what
we would get is it would call cancel on the fighter instead.
So that's what I'm going to want you to do is to implement the interface on both the fighter and the
mover.
The moving should stop attacking very much as we've had it doing before.
But I'd also like you to have a go to see if you are actually able to cancel movement by attacking.
Now this presents a bit of a problem because by default attacking does some movement.
So if you clicked on an enemy while you were moving somewhere else it would start moving towards the
enemy whether or not it has cancelled the move.
So one way you can check that the movement is actually being cancelled.
When you start an attack action would be it's a comment out this block of code here.
So the combat action does no movement.
We'd only do this temporarily.
So then what you'd be able to see is that if you're moving along the ground towards a certain location
and you click on an enemy the movement is disabled for the fighter so it won't do any movement but it
should cancel the move.
That's the behavior we want to see.
And then you can comment the code again and everything should work.
Again you should then cancel stop in its tracks but then move towards a target.
I'm just saying too common out this code so that you can test this independently to see that the cancel
is coming through and working as you'd expect.
If you find your struggling with the second part of the challenge do attempt the first part first and
see how far you get with the second part.
So pause the video and have a go if you can wrap your head around how these interfaces are working and
try and implement that knowledge through this challenge okay.
Welcome back.
Hopefully you didn't find that too tricky.
Hopefully you've got the right building blocks in place.
If not it's my fault and I'm sorry.
Hopefully you will get it from their solution.
So first of all we want to implement let's say the AI action move.
We've got that and we got cancer.
What should cancel do.
Well I think it should probably be synonymous with stop.
So I'm going to I should remove this cancel function and I'm going to just rename.
Stop using F2 to rename across multiple files to be called cancel instead which should rename across
the project including where it's called in fighter now in fighter.
I want to implement AI action as well.
There we go.
Like so.
And you notice that we already have a cancel.
So I don't have to implement it and I think it does the right thing.
And if I go to the mover there's one thing that we can now remove is this fighter dot cancel we don't
want it doing that anymore.
We want it to be entirely via the action scheduler so I can remove this dependency on combat which removes
our circular dependency so we're happy.
Let's go over and hit play and UTC.
If I missed any to build errors.
No.
So I can move around if I click on here to combat.
Then we are seeing that bug I mentioned earlier in the video where we are actually calling action instead
of current actions so let's go ahead and change that so let's try that again.
Hopefully you noticed that managed to pick up on that so I moved towards this guy and then I move away.
Yeah that seems to have canceled it all right.
And if I'm moving I should be able to cancel half way.
Let's see if that's actually working whether we're actually canceling movement by as I said going to
fight this Yes and just commenting out that movement behavior that we're doing so if I'd done that correctly.
Now what I expect to see is we're moving and as soon as I click here it stops.
So just to convince you that this is actually the case let's click as far away as we can go.
I clicked on the capsule I'm clicking over here near the shed.
I didn't get to the shed because I clicked on the cat's capsule and that canceled the movement.
So I'm going to uncommon that again.
And we've got the right behavior that we're expecting with no dependency cycles whatsoever where we
can attack an enemy then cancel the action move on to something else.
So I'm chuffed that that is working as we wanted to we've covered interfaces we've covered dependency
inversion.
And I'll see you in the next video will actually be adding some animation in fact it probably won't
be me.
It'll probably be Rick doing that.
So hand you over to him.