Hello again.
In this video we're going to set it up so our player runs through a trigger volume that triggers our
cinematic moment.
We play through our cinematic moment and then after it's done it returns control back to the player
and we can set it up so that when we run through the trigger volume again it doesn't trigger the cinematic
sequence.
So let's jump in and get started.
Let's start by finding our game object where our playable directories for me it's my intro sequence
going to add to that a component first of all I'll add a box collider that will be somewhere in the
scene over in the middle in there.
So what I will do you know it's something very interesting see how it might transform on my intro sequence
is bloomed out.
That means that if I try to move it like there you can see it's been moved.
If I click away and then click back it's back where it was before.
That's because whenever you see the blue here that means that this game object thinks that there's some
animation taking place and the animation is pushing it back to wherever it thinks it should be in the
first frame.
If I click away and click back to it and that is because when we set up our timeline sequence it automatically
added this intro sequence animation track on here that is causing that particular I think I'm being
animated issue so I'm gonna go ahead and delete that we're not using it for our synth machine or our
Dolly animation.
So now that it's deleted when I click on intro sequence you can see that the fields here aren't blue.
Now I can move my intro sequence down to their has to click away and click back again.
You can see that it has retained its memory of where I put it.
OK.
So we're particularly looking at the box cloud Ask.com make it a bit bigger ten on the x axis of six
on the Y and two on the Z or Z.
And I've got to place it on the bridge on big fan of placing the trigger volume so you can't accidentally
not walk through it click on my intro sequence I'm going to rotate that so it fits nicely across my
bridge and you know I'll start it up a little bit just so it's not too wide and doesn't need to be actually
that high at all because the play is nowhere near that high.
Okay.
Drop it down now Trig volumes what else do we need to do here for trigger volumes.
Well first of all we need to click is trigger for our box collider.
We need to add a rigid body rigid body and my rigid body I'm just going to put that kinetic and turn
off gravity.
What else do we need to do when we have this trigger moment.
Well we need when we run through the trigger volume we need to have a collider on our players.
Let's find our player as of yet we haven't got a collider on it.
So add component this one I will do as a capsule collider capsule collider.
Okey dokey will alter that a little bit.
Just make the radius a little bit thinner for me.
Probably what's at Point Three ish will increase the height up in the air a bit and I will.
Sorry that was increase on the y axis and now I'm going to increase the height to about one point seven
six doesn't need to be perfect just needs to be.
So it looks pretty good.
Okay.
There we go.
And you know it just to be super thorough.
I'm going to delete the C or delete.
I'm going to paint over the texture that I've got from my little note saying here's where the cinematic
takes place.
What next.
Well we need a script.
So let's go and create ourselves a script folder right click Create folder that I will call cinematics
a Matt Dick's over there now.
Right click Create C sharp script this C sharp script.
I will call cinematic trigger cinematic trigger.
Okay.
Step one I'm gonna get rid of start and update.
We won't need those.
We'll wrap this in a namespace what should we call this namespace name space.
We'll call it RPG cinematics seems like a pretty good thing to call it and then curly braces at the
top curly braces down the bottom and then highlight an indent.
Now we need to use a particular namespace.
We need to use so using Unity engine dot playable as playable as is where we'll find all the good things
related to our playable Director.
Where is it playable director just in here.
Okay.
So in our class here we're going to on trigger into and then we need to get our playable directed component
and play it.
So get component Yep angle braces playable director parentheses dot and it's as simple as just saying
play that will play whatever playable director is associated with this game object.
Let's save that and see if it works.
Just quickly before I look at that I'm just going to get rid of my trees over here they keep getting
in the way of my camera and frustrating me no end.
Okay cool.
Got rid of those.
Now I know that there's a couple of issues of why this isn't going to happen first of all.
I remember if you click on intro sequence play on a wake is currently on so as as soon as we hit play
that would get that triggering our sequence which we don't want to do so turn off play on awake.
The next thing when we click on play you notice is an issue with our ray casting where we've got our
trigger volume.
If I click to try to run through it if I click there the player runs up and stops which doesn't quite
make sense does it.
So I'll try clicking again and he's saying I'm not sort of going through there at all.
The problem is that our ray cast is not making it through this trigger volume there's an easy solution
to that which in our intro sequence up in the top right under layer.
Currently it's on default to change that to ignore Ray cast which pretty self-explanatory means that
this game object will be ignoring the ray cast of the ray cast will be ignoring it.
We might want something a little bit more sophisticated later on but for now this will serve our purpose
of making sure we can trigger our cinematics properly so click on play.
Now I try to run through it but I run through it.
Okay but it didn't trigger.
Why is that.
Well that's because as I sometimes do I've forgotten attach this script to my game object so cinematic
trigger needs to be over.
It's gonna roll up rigid body and animators and then I'll tell you us one surefire roll up box collider
then I can't see my box collider so I'm going to leave it expanded so I can see it.
Click on play.
We should be at a run through the trigger volume.
Yep that starts out sequence.
Excellent.
Go through the cameras and then it should return back to the player.
Okay awesome.
We have a problem though.
If I run back again this way it triggers it all over again.
So that is something that I want asked to solve in a challenge.
Also it's probably not going to happen in this instance but if one of the gods came wandering through
there that would also trigger our cinematic moments so we don't want that to happen so I've got two
points of our challenge here for you is to improve our trigger.
First one is to make sure it's only triggered once and the second is to make sure that only the player
can trigger it.
And if you want some hints I'm going to give you some hints.
You don't need hints jumping to take that on now.
You want some hints.
Here they are hit number one.
Use a ball for the first part and hit number two.
Use a tag for the next part.
So they hint saving and figure out the logic to improve our trigger when you're done.
I'll see you back here.
Okay let's do this together.
Back over into our cinematic trigger.
I'm going to add a ball right at the top of our class ball and of course all ready triggered and we'll
initialize that at false now instead of just straight up playing We're gonna get ourselves an if statement
if what are we gonna do here.
Well if we haven't already played so if exclamation already triggered already triggered I should say
not already played and this is the part where we'll say make sure it's only the play and the way we
do that is by accessing the players tag.
Now just double check that when you click on your player the player is tagged as player.
If it's not this won't work.
So make sure is play tagged as player and then we can type in here are the DOT game object dot tag.
Equals equals what well equals player in our quotations.
So we haven't already triggered and it's the player then that's where we want to play our playable director.
And at the same time we are triggering this to play.
We also want to flick our ball so it goes from false to true.
So already triggered equals true save that up.
Jump back over.
Now I'm not going to check that.
It's only the player that can trigger this.
I'm pretty sure we've got our code.
Good for them but I will check that we can only trigger at once.
We'll go through we do our cinematic sequence which for me is about eight seconds
and then we run through it a second time and nothing happens.
Awesome.
Great stuff.
And just a reminder.
Don't be like me where I keep forgetting to apply my changes back to my prefab on the player I've got
a few things that I have changed.
Apply all of those.
Or better still be working directly in your prefab so that you know those changes are applied immediately.
Now there's one other thing that I want to highlight.
We're not going to fix in this video but we're going to fix in.
Most likely the next video is that when we run through our trigger volume and we're in our cinematic
moment the player can still click in the world.
If you look over my scene view the character goes running off to go wherever you've just clicked.
In this scene.
So what we need to do is take away control during that cinematic moment and that's gonna be the topic
of the next video.