Hello and welcome in this lecture we're gonna be learning about an awesome concept called a unity event
which allows us in the unity inspector to hook up functions to certain gameplay events for example to
help script exposes an event called take damage and we're able to hook this up to the spawner to spawn
damaged text and you can see that the result is that if we go ahead and hit someone then they spawn
damage text when they are hit and when they take damage.
Same goes for the player if he gets hit also spawns text let's dive in and see how to use these awesome
events okay.
So at the moment the what we've got is that the damage takes is spawning up dynamically but it is currently
only happening.
We have a look at our damage tech spawn it's only happening on start.
Now that's not the way we wanted to do this so I'm going to go ahead and remove our start function entirely.
We've got a public method called spawn and we want this spawn method to get called with some damage
amount when we actually take damage.
So where does that happen.
What triggers damage what can tell us that we've taken damage.
Little question for you.
Well that is the health component.
So if we go over to our health component and have a look.
Where could this be happening in take damage for example we can see that there is some damage being
taken now.
I want to show you yet another way that we can subscribe to events we've seen how to use delegates to
subscribe to events in code.
Now I want to show you how we can subscribe to events in the Unity Editor.
You may have seen it if you are have used buttons before in the UI that you can click a plus button
and you can say what function I want that button to call when it is clicked and we can do that for ourselves.
The thing that we need to use is called a unity event.
Now unity events will need to include a UI namespace when not gonna use that just yet.
We'll just allow Visual Studio code to do that for us and it is a C ball field and the type is going
to be a unity event and we'll see what it looks like in just a second and then I'm going to do a take.
Damage is going to be the name of the event.
Like so now is complaining at me because I don't have the right namespace.
So unity event we need to be using the unity engine.
Dot events namespace and that will allow us if we go over to the editor and let's open up our character
it's gonna have a look at our character where as a character is the character and you'll notice that
the character has got a health script and under the health script we now have this new section this
take damage section which looks very much like the UI for a button or binding the button callbacks.
So how does this work.
It basically means that with the plus button we can go ahead and drag in any object.
For example I might drag in the character and I can select any function I like so for example I could
on any of these components so I can go and say hey I want to go and set.
I don't know the mover to cancel something like that.
I can go and cancel the mover whenever we take damage and it obviously doesn't make sense.
You can obviously hook this up in a better way but that's just an example.
Now we want and also one more thing is that you can add multiple things so you can have it call a list
of functions each doing something.
So for example we could have it trigger a particle effect.
We could have it then trigger this damaged text.
We could then have it trigger some sound as well.
Basically this is allows you your imagination to run wild.
So where are we going to do the call to take damage.
Remember that with delegates for example the level up in our base stats remember that level up in base
stats is very much like a unity event and we call it just like this.
Just like we would call any function.
Now when it comes to unity events things are a little bit different.
So we want to call our take damage and I'm just now going to call it in start and what we do is we do
take damage dots invoke instead.
And then we call the invoke function and that's going to trigger off all of those functions in the list
on that serialized ball field.
So that brings me to your challenge to trigger the take damage event so call it in the right place or
invoke it in the right place hook up the correct function and your goal is that at the end of this once
you hooked up the right function and hooked up in the right place the damage text should spawn when
you take damage when the particular character that is being hit for example takes damage that puts video
and have a go at the challenge.
Welcome back.
So hopefully that helps you solidify your understanding of the unity event and see that they're very
much the same as the delegates that we have seen in the past.
So going to remove this take damage and vote from start.
That's not where we want it where we want it to happen as I've hinted is intake damage itself.
I'm gonna do after we have updated the health point value I'm going to invoke the take damage notification
at that point but before we do any dying or anything else then we can go over to in fact.
Actually I only want to invoke take damage if we aren't going to die.
So I'm just gonna put an in an else statement in an if else here and that's where I'm going to do the
invoke of take damage so you can go ahead and do the same thing and then we're gonna go over in it to
damage text spawn and no actually we're gonna go over into the inspect.
This is the magic of it is that we can hook up these events in the inspector rather than in code which
allows us immense flexibility and allows the designer an awful lot of flexibility to say I'm gonna add
a new take damage event with the plus icon remove any of the previous ones and I'm gonna drag in as
the object the damage text spawner because we wanted to spawn some new damage text and if you go down
in the list of functions under the damage tech spawner components we can call the spawn function.
Now notice that it takes a number because our spawn function takes a number so we can enter something
we could say something like 13 so that we can distinguish that is actually being called by this particular
piece of hooking up logic and if we go ahead and hit play now well I would expect to see if I go and
bash this guy with a fireball boom he'd get some text above his head.
Let's try that again.
Boom.
Get some text above his head every single time.
And if he hits us we get text above our heads too.
Now one little bug that I want to fix before we move on is if I go and have a look at our player in
the inspector you can see that all the damage texts that were spawned are still there.
If he keeps attacking me they keep spawning and they aren't being destroyed.
Now an easy way to fix this is just to change and add an event into the animation.
So I'm gonna do this by going back to damage takes prefab and opening up the animation tab at the same
time.
And here right at the end of our animation where we want it to destroy we can add an animation event
which is just this little icon here just at the top right of this left pane.
We add that in and we need to select the thing that we want to call a function on such as damage text
we would want to have a destroy function where there are no components here that have a destroy function
that will destroy the whole prefab though.
But fortunately we do have this damage text script that we've already created.
If he is the work around where you in bed your canvas within a game object then you'll need to do things
slightly differently.
At this point just hang on till after this explanation and I'll show you how to do it.
So if we go into a damaged text script what we gonna do is create a function that allows us to destroy
the whole prefab and it's going to have to be public so a public void destroy text and it doesn't have
to take any arguments and all it has to do is call destroy on the game object.
Now just this is just because you can't call things directly on the game object from an animation event.
So this just does the pass through for us.
And now if I have my animation event selected and I select the damaged text object which is the one
that has the correct component make sure you have that one selected first because it need unity needs
to know where it can look for the functions that it can call so you then select the animation event
and go to the function dropdown here.
Then what we can do is scroll down or just start typing the destroy and Vega found meat destroy text
as the only option.
Now if you're using the work around where you have the canvas embedded within a game object to be able
to see your animation text then you need to do things slightly differently because the animation event
cannot call a function that is on a different game object.
So we need to have ADD destroy a script on here and not be able to use our damage script which needs
to stay on the root.
So the way we're gonna do this is to add a new destroyer script and it's going to be generic and what
it's going to do is it's going to have a target linked in the inspector which is going to be the parent
the damaged text.
That's what it's gonna destroy and it will have a destroy target function.
So let's flip over to that script and create it.
So first of all we need serialized field and it's going to be a type game object and it is going to
be the targets to destroy and we'll set it to no.
And then it's going to be public void.
Destroy target takes no arguments.
And just like we've seen it's going to destroy.
But instead of destroying the current game object it's going to destroy the target to destroy.
And then what you can do is you can simply go and hook up that serialized field because we want to destroy
the parent here.
We don't just want to destroy the anything or we're gonna leave the parent prefab around it's not going
to fully clean up.
And then we can hook up at event animation events to the correct destroy target function.
So now let's just check that that's working so I'm going to go ahead and attack the enemy and actually
get him to attack makers easier to find the player in the inspector.
And then what I want to do is pause this before I die.
Go and find under core player damage to export.
You can see the damage take spawner is currently empty because there are no damage texts hovering over
my head.
And if I go ahead and hit play you can see it's creating them and destroying them repeatedly as can
be seen by this arrow which is showing them and hiding them repeatedly.
So that was quite an action packed lecture.
What we have done is we have introduced the concept of a unity event which allows us very much like
a delegate to bind functions to particular events.
But the difference is it allows us to do it in the inspector rather than in code which allows the design
lots of flexibility and we've also made sure that we're clearing up all the damage texts that we spawn.
The next thing we're going to be moving onto in the next couple of lectures is working out how we can
display the correct damage amounts above the head.
See there.