Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be leveling up so down here.
I've currently got some debug showing me that I'm a Level 1 noob.
I go and attack this enemy I'm going to gain some experience points 10 experience points and you can
see here my progression that 10 experience points is the amount required to level up at level 1.
Sure enough down on my debug I have got myself to level two.
We're gonna figure out how to calculate this in a reliable way and then how to use it to look up our
stats such as health.
Let's dive in and see how so.
At the moment the level at which we look up a stat is fixed but down the line what we actually want
is for that to vary depending on the experience.
That means we're going to need to calculate our level.
So I'm going to create a new function inside of base stats.
It's going to be a public function that returns an int which is gonna be the level and it's going to
be called get level and it's just going to calculate the level from the experience points.
And just to be super clear it's doing this by replacing the starting level.
So starting level isn't going to be used anymore.
We're going to be calculating the level entirely from the number of experience points you've got.
So one thing we're going to need to do is get hold of our experience points.
So it's going to be a gets components.
It's going to be experience and we are going to need to include a module for that.
It's in resources at the moment but you might notice that creates a circuit dependency and I kind of
realized that experience isn't a resource it's really part of stats.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna go over to our project and I'm gonna go in to the code to the resources
and move everything to do with experience from there into the stats folder instead.
Now I'm going to have to open up experience afresh from its new location and what we've got here.
So now hopefully get experience should be working correctly.
We should be able to do a get points on it.
Oh yeah.
One thing we're gonna do obviously is move its namespace.
So it's now going to be in two states rather than in resources.
And now what we should have is experience.
Yep and we can do get points and that is going to be the current XP.
So now save that isn't it.
So it's a float current XP and we've got to ask ourselves what are we going to do with this current
XP.
Basically what I would like to do is find a way of saying look at the stance of our player and figure
out from the stats what his XP should be.
So this is how I propose we do it.
We introduce a new start kind of thing the experience that is required to level up.
So at level one you might require 20 experienced total to level up to the next level at level 2 you
might require 30 experienced total to level up to Level 3 and so on.
So let's just have a look at how we would calculate from this information what level we're currently
at.
Let's say we have 10 experience points this one's an easy one.
We are on level 1 initially and we don't have enough experience to level up so we don't go anywhere.
Second one.
Basically we got experience 40 Well let's think about this algorithmically how would we do this in the
algorithm we'd say Okay first of all we're going to check the first level and it's got 20 experience
points we've got more experience points than that.
So we can level up we've got to level 2 30 experience points we've got more than that we can level up
3 we've got more than that or equal to that so we can level up again.
So this is going to be level 4.
We don't have 50 experience points so it must be level 4.
Basically what we're doing is we're waiting until we find something that has more experience points
than we have got.
So we're just going through to find something that's got more so in the first case we found that we
will level one.
Second case we've found that we are Level Four.
What happens if we have got 60 experience points well then we don't find any level that has more than
us.
Therefore we must be one level above.
So we want level above the maximum which is five.
So we're Level Five.
If we've got 60.
Okay.
So that's how we're going to be calculating experience points.
So a few things we have to do first of all we have to introduce a new start going to create a stack
which is going to be the experience not the reward but to level up.
Okay.
And we're going to add that in to our progression particularly for the character because the character
is going to be the only one that can level up in my game.
So the character is going to duplicate the Health Stat going to right click on Element Zero duplicate
array change over to experience reward and then let's give some sense sensible rewards and just gonna
have a 10 20 30 40 and then I'm going to stop there and delete the last element of that array so that
we can test out basically all of these levels we should be able to go from level 1 to 2 to 3 to 4 and
then finally we should get to Level 5.
So that's what we're hoping for.
Now there is an issue in here.
Oh yes experience display is in the wrong namespace.
Got to move that one to I think that should be the only issue we're having there.
Yep.
Now obviously get level is not yet finished.
So let's crack on with this one.
So if you think you can do this you can create get level in the algorithm that I described on the slide
then do go ahead and give that a shot.
If on the other hand you would like to see me do it then watch on and we're going to do it.
So the first thing we're going to need actually is to have in stats we're going to need nice stats in
progression.
We need to find a way of knowing how many levels there are for us to look through.
So I'm going to create a new public int called get levels and it's going to have to take the stat and
the character class and it is going to just return basically and I look up the length of this levels
array so against return levels dot length and just to be safe.
We're going to make sure that the look up has been built before we start.
So we've built the look up and then we get the look up character class stat and the length of the levels
array.
That's what we need.
And then what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna do a for loop.
Basically we've seen this before it's going to flip over all the levels that we have available in our
experience stat.
So we're going to start at Level 1 again to go up to let's see.
So we're going to do a progression.
Dot gets that and it is going to what status against need is gonna need a stat dot experience to level
up and it is going to need the character class which is our current character class.
I'm going to pull this out seeing as it's a little bit large.
I'm gonna bring this into its own variable control dots introduce local variable the variable I'm going
to rename to something useful such as Max level and actually you'll notice I did get stats.
What I want to do is get levels.
So that should return an int is the max level.
And actually that's not the max level that is the penultimate level because the max level is one more
than that once you've achieved those experience points.
So we're gonna call that penultimate level.
And if we're less than or equal to the penultimate level in this for loop why am I starting with a capital
letter.
Let's go with a lowercase letter there.
Penultimate level so we're less than that in the levels or equal to that then we are golden we can actually
look up that stat because remember we've only got like one less.
As I saying here.
So if I got a Level Five here we're only gonna have four in the array.
That's why it's penultimate level.
So basically what we're saying here is that we need to get the experience required to level up within
here.
And if we've got that experience or rather if we don't have that experience that's the level we're at.
So what we're going to do is get our current XP and we want to compare that to what is it to the progression
don't get a stance and we don't get levels get stat complete the right thing and it's the experience
level up character class and the level that we're currently looking at.
So this is going to give us the experience XP to level up and that is going to be a float.
So you've got an XP to level up then what.
So how are you going to compare that to our current XP was saying that if this XP to level up isn't
greater than the current XP then what we want to do is just return the current level like so otherwise
what we're going to do is if we've passed through all of the levels up to and including the penultimate
level what we want to do is return the penultimate level plus one which is the ultimate level that's
what we essentially did here when we said 60 gone through all of these.
None of them are greater.
So we must be one greater than the penultimate level plus one.
So that is how we are going to calculate get level.
Now what I want to do is just put in some debug.
So we're going to have an update method in here.
Put my curly braces on the second line and what I'm going to do is basically put a print statement that
prints out get level but big portions because this will work for all the enemies as well.
Once at the moment so I'm just going to put in an if statement or do a game object or tag equals player.
So if this is the player we are going to print out our level just a little bit of debug stuff we're
going to delete this by the end of the lecture.
Now let's go in and hit play and see.
We've got some errors.
Let's have a look.
What is the problem.
Looks like I've named my four variable a little bit wrong I wanted it to be level not levels so that's
probably why it is complaining let's go ahead and play now.
Silly me looks like I have forgotten that I've actually put the stat here as experience reward I wanted
experience to level up.
That's why it's not finding the key.
Go ahead and hit play now instead of experienced to level up.
I've done the right thing.
I've got zero experience starting out and I'm at level 1 that's what the log is telling me.
If I go and kill this enemy let's see first of all I should go up to level 2.
Yes I do I get 10 experience points I go to Level 2 Let's go and kill another enemy.
So this Archer over here he is going to be dust.
He's gonna be toast.
I whack him a little bit and I'm level 30 which actually puts me up to level four as you can see here
because four thirty is the level up for Level 3 so we go straight up to Level 4 straight away they're
bashed this guy and just want to check my last thing is correct I go up to Level 5 which is one more
than the levels I've got and experience to level up which had a penultimate level.
So my calculations are now working just to recap what has happened.
We are getting the penultimate level by querying how many things are in this level array then we are
going over all the levels from one up to the penultimate that's done by doing this for loop and then
we are getting the experience to level up for a particular level and we're checking whether we have
got less experience than that.
Basically because if we've got less experience we stop and that's the level that we're currently at.
If we are not held back by any of these restrictions then we are going to be one greater than the penultimate
level.
So it's time for your challenge to use the new level that we have calculated.
Well I'd like you to do is look up the stats by that calculated level and what if they have got no experience.
What if for the example of enemies there is no experience component.
How can you calculate the level.
Then have a little head scratch and saving come up with something okay.
Welcome back.
So the trick is that when they are enemies we don't calculate the level at all we can just keep using
the starting level.
So what I'm going to do is going to adapt get level to do that.
Basically we're going to say that this get experience I'm going to pull that out as a local variable
and I'm gonna say that if the if this is null.
So if experience equals no then we're just gonna go ahead and return the starting level instead.
And that just exits early from asked get level we don't do any other calculation that is required requires
the experience.
Otherwise we get the current XP and we move on.
So that sorts out that question and finally we just need to replace our starting level in get start
with the current level and hopefully that should help us out.
So if I go ahead and hit play now zero XP let's go ahead and bash this guy and you can see my health
is going down quite phenomenally and actually just jumped down a little bit further so our level is
correct it jumped down.
Why did it jump down.
Let's think about this the way we're currently doing health is that we've got these health points right.
So I've got a certain amount of health points based on what I started with.
Maybe it was 50 health points right.
And those were going down as I was being hit.
Then what happened is as I leveled up the maximum possible health I could have jumped up to 100.
So suddenly the percentage has gone down because my health point stayed where they were.
The percentage went down.
That's something we're going to have to change.
We're going to have to track instead.
Maybe the points that we have lost the health points that we've lost as opposed to the health points
that we have still got that way when we go up in health.
We are going to essentially gain health points and kind of heal ourselves a little bit which is how
I want my game to work.
That's something we're going to do in later lectures but in the next lecture we're going to solve the
immediate problem which is that we have no display for what level we are actually at.
And that's what we're going to fix next.
See that.