Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We are gonna get civilising again so that the character's position gets remembered but not just that
all of the enemy's positions are also going to be remembered that's the benefit of this saleable entity
system.
So now if I hit load I go back to my previous safe game which is here where my enemies were already
starting to beat me up and that is a location that was saved in my previous save.
So that's what we're going to achieve in this lecture.
Let's dive in and see how so.
You've been patient and been waiting a long time to get back to having our civilization working again.
Now this is actually pretty easy now we've done this before.
We've been able to capture the state the location of our character so I'm just gonna very quickly go
through that same process I'm going gonna remove my log message from capture state.
And here I'm in saleable entity dots.
Yes by the way.
And remember that saved blends tears on all the characters players and enemy included.
So it is able to save all of those in one go.
Now before we dive any further I want to address why we're returning object type in capture state.
This means that we don't have to be as dark down to what type is actually returned here as long as it's
serialized Bill.
Let's revise what this means.
You remember back in the combat section we introduced the AI action interface which was a super type
for the mover and The Fighter.
So whenever we used an AI action we could substitute either the mover or the fighter into it and use
it in its place.
Well object is exactly the same as that object is the root object for pretty much everything.
So you can return anything that you like including a serialized ball vector 3 or a dictionary which
are both serialized ball and so we can turn those into binary in our files.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna grab the stake that we want which is the transformed position so
transform dot position but you will remember that at this stage we are not able to serialize transform
that position.
So if I were just to return that from capture state it would go into the dictionary at the top level
but then it would be not serialized born we'd get an error.
So what we have to do is we have to wrap this in our new serialize and what's it called serialized bool
vector 3.
So if we wrap it in these serialized vector three create a new one from the transformed opposition vector
then that will be able to serialize.
So this is where I'm going to ask you straight away to do a challenge because we've got this restored
state method that is empty and we have done this before in a previous lecture.
So you should be able to be fully equipped to try and restore this state so as we said I've done it
before and we first thing I do is going to have to cast state to serialize vector three Why is that.
Because it comes in as this generic state object because the saving system that has called us doesn't
know what type this is because we've told it that in here.
But as you can see the return type of capture state was object.
So we know that it's a serialized Bill back three because that's what we've returned to capture state.
So in restore state we are going to restore and see reliable back to three so we need to cast.
Now obviously this could go wrong if a previous version of your application were capturing something
different if you had been capturing I don't know a float at this level.
And then you open a safe file from the old version of your game then the restore state will not will
be a float not as a reliable vector 3 so your new code will actually fail.
But as I said at the moment we're just gonna get around that by deleting safe files.
So for now it is safe to do a cast and then you are going to move your player to the location of the
serial visible vector three remember how we've done that before.
And then a couple of bonuses for you.
Is there any gotchas to do with movement that we've encountered before that if we move our characters
sometimes it glitches out and doesn't move properly.
Have a think about that when we were moving our player to the starting location of the transition points
of those portals.
Was there any gotchas and another bonus for you to stop our character from running to the location that
was previously set.
How can we cancel that current action post a video and have a go okay.
Welcome back.
So the first thing we can do is we gonna do this cast and I'm gonna remove the print statement so we
are going to want to save a serialized vector 3 and we'll just call this the position and we're going
to wants to cast two serialized vector three from our state object.
We know the state object should be of type C realizable vector 3.
So that's the caster.
Now this position we know we can do a two vector to get it to whatever we want and we want to update
and transform dot position.
So transform the opposition is going to be equal to position dot to vector because we need to convert
it into a real unity vector not this serialized vector that we've got now.
That's okay.
But as I said there is that problem with the nav mesh.
So if we do a get component nav mesh agent and then we want to enabled it to be false on that so that
we disable it first and I'm gonna have to include a namespace here the unity engine A.I. for the nav
mesh agent and then we're just setting enable to false because we know that moving it sometimes causes
glitches.
If we've got enough mesh agents enabled there's also trying to move things.
So that's what we're going to do to position and a player.
And then finally we also want to cancel the current action.
So that's going to be a component action scheduler and we're gonna need the right namespace for it.
It's going to need RPG cool.
And so the action schedule we're going to do a dot and then we are going to do a cancel current action.
So if we were moving to a certain point where we restore the point restore the state we're no longer
doing that current action.
Now you're seeing the there start to be a problem here right.
This saleable entity which is part of the saving system which is a low level dependency for a lot of
different classes is suddenly having all these dependencies on our RPG core.
It's having dependencies on the unity engine to a I.
These are dependencies which I'd argue it doesn't need.
We could invert these dependencies that's going to be the subject of subsequent lectures but for now
let's see whether this is enough.
Let's dive devote to the Unity Editor and hit play and see if we can save and load our character.
Okay so I'm going up to a location.
I'm gonna hit save.
I'm going to go to another location I'm going to hit load and we go back to our location and we have
ended up pause and stopping our movement.
So our movement has changed and what's also different now is that all our enemies have a saleable entity
too.
So if I get them to chase me and I go and save at this point and then I carry on then we should be able
to load back and we both go back to that location that we had before previously it was just our character
that was going back.
Now it's the enemy as well.
Now I'm seeing some some issues here with some errors around and nav mesh set stopped and I think this
is happening just because of the order of our operations we're calling cancel just after we've disabled
an mesh agent and it hasn't been enabled again so we could re enabled enough mesh agent just after we've
done a transform update so I can set and able to true again so that we can do our cancel operation happily.
Let's go ahead and hit play and see if we can do that.
If I go and load we're back here with a cactus beating us up but there are no errors this time.
Fantastic okay.
So in this lecture we have got back to serialized but with an added bonus that now we are also serialized
in the position of our enemies.
There is a drawback here however because I have got the position of the enemies if I go ahead and load
here's my enemy positions.
But if I were to go ahead and go into a different scene here it's going to go into my transition scene
and if I were to save this state and then come across in it to my enemies where the main action is if
I go ahead and hit load here you will notice that it's saying there's not a key present in the dictionary
and we didn't load back the enemies.
Why was that.
That's because when I was in the other scene the dictionary from that scene completely overrode all
the state that we had about this scene that I'm currently in.
So that's not good.
We want to be able to have both of those ones have the information from the first scene and the second
scene both in our safe file so that's going to be the subject of the next lecture and I'll see that.