Hello and welcome in this lecture we're gonna be throttling the attack.
By this I mean we're going to be able to slow it down so he's not constantly punching all the time there's
a bit of idle breath time between and we've got this low configurable parameter the time between attacks
where if I increase this you can see he waits a lot longer on his locomotion state waiting around until
he attacks the second time around that's what we're gonna be implementing let's dive in and see how
it's done.
As we observed at the end of last lecture if you go up to this capsule our guy just punches as quickly
as he wants.
Now obviously this is something that we would like to control because for example you might have a lower
level character that has to has weaker and needs to take his breath between punches.
Things like that and also for different sized weapons big hammers can't really be swung as quickly as
you would like you need to take a bit of a breather between swings that kind of thing.
We want to fix so if we go over to our fighter c s script what we're going to do for now is add a serialized
field.
Eventually this will be a property of the weapon equipped but we are not going to do that just yet.
And that field should tell us basically the time between attacks the time between attacks like so because
Currently what we've got is it's going back to back because we are constantly setting the trigger every
time we want to attack.
Now how the trigger works we didn't quite talk about this fully and maybe you know already but a trigger
is quite clever.
It's like a boolean value but when you set it it waits until it has been acted upon that means that
the transition has actually happened.
They see notes we've got this condition transition.
Now if this had been a boolean it would keep making that transition as off basically all the time.
It is possible but the trigger is very smart.
It basically makes that transition once and sets the trigger back to FALSE sets the boolean back to
FALSE which means that the next time we go back into locomotion unless we've hit trigger again it won't
go in attack.
So that's a good thing and that's what we want to do we basically want to do the trigger wait a certain
amount of time and then do the trigger again.
So that's how this time between attacks is going to work time between tax is going to be a float value
and we can default it to I don't know once every second is actually quite a long time for time between
attacks if you if you actually work it out it turns out well what if you actually use it and play with
it one second or two seconds is actually quite a long time to wait between attacks.
So how are we going to figure out how long has passed since the last attack and whether we are ready
to attack again to do this.
You might want to introduce a variable so I'm going to introduce a float time since last attack.
And I'm going to leave up to you to do some of this implementation.
But what we want to do here is update this time since last attack every single update no matter what
even if our target is no we want to be updating this time since last attack because imagine that you've
stopped targeting the particular enemy and you want to run away to catch your breath.
You want the time since last attack to keep incrementing.
So every single update we are going to increment plus equals the time since last attack.
And that's going to be time dot delta time which gives us the time that the last frame took to render
basically the time since the last time update was called.
So you can see how adding this repeatedly is going to give us the total since we last reset the time
since last attack.
Now what I'm going to leave to you is the actual making sure we only trigger once the time enough time
has elapsed and resetting this time since last attack.
So that's going to be a challenge to implement the throttle I'm calling a throttle because it kind of
slows down the throttles the ability to attack.
Now how to only trigger after time has elapsed that's your first question to answer and implement.
And the second is how will you reset after you have actually triggered so suppose a video and have a
go okay.
Welcome back.
So the first thing how to throttle so in our attack behavior we are setting the trigger.
So this is the logical place to put the throttle.
The first thing we want to do is basically say if the time since last attack is actually greater than
the what is it we're looking for time between attacks then what we can do is we can actually trigger
this attack.
So what I'm going to do it this way for now you could do an early return and flip around the boolean
here say whether it's less than but I'm gonna make it I think slightly easier to read here by saying
if it's time for us to attack we're going to attack and we're going to reset the time since last attack
to zero because we've literally just done want.
So the time since that last attack is in fact zero.
So that should be sufficient for throttling our attacks.
Let's have a go and see if this now works.
If I go and hit play I'd expect to have a second before starting every punch.
So let's go over to our capsule I guess it seems to be a bit slower.
Let's just make sure by changing our time between attacks three seconds between attacks.
There you go.
That's much longer and you can see it stays on locomotion for a while before hit.
Before getting a new attack trigger and going into the attack state and obviously you can tweak this
to your heart's desire.
The minimum of course is if you make the time between attacks very small then you're going to notice
that he the minimum he can do is as fast as the animation will allow.
But that's kind of okay for now.
We can just slow it down a little bit if we want to.
Using the time between attacks.
So that's how we got throttling implemented.
Hope you enjoyed that video.
And the next one's is gonna be very exciting because we're actually gonna be implementing damage so
I'll see you there.