Hello and welcome.
In this two part lecture we are going to be making it so that our state between scenes is saved independently
and doesn't overwrite each other.
So if I have my gods saved here on the grid on the bridge in this scene I go over into a different scene
and I can go ahead and save in this scene as well so that if I load in this scene I go back to the state
for this scene.
And if I go back to my first scene and load there then I'm back on the bridge with those gods punching
me.
So that's the idea of the next two lectures let's dive in and see what the restrictions are and how
it's done so let's have a look at why we have this multiple scene saving problem.
This is our list of your ideas from scene one and from scene to an imaginary list as it were.
What happens when we decide to save and scene one is that we serialize these new ideas into the save
fall so the save file ends up containing this list of ideas.
In the second scene if we go in we loaded up and we save in there.
Then what's gonna happen is this list comes in and completely overrides our Save File which means that
if we go back to Scene 1 and try to decentralize to it we no longer have any new ideas that match up.
So we try to load for example this first item and we find no state in the save file that matches this
idea which is a problem because now we have lost state save file has no longer remembering things about
Scene 1.
So what do we do.
Well the way that we would solve this is instead to merge scenes.
So I've got two slightly shorter lists of EU ideas hair and color coded for Scene 1 and Scene 2.
Now what happens is we serialized first the first scene and then in the second scene once we serialized
that once we're saving in the second scene.
We get a second list of new ideas in here.
Now the good thing about this is that we emerge these two together we didn't take the save file and
overwrite it.
We took the old contents of the safe file and we added to it and then saved it back in.
So what happens is if we go back to Scene 1 we now have as well as the extra new ideas from Scene 2.
We do have the ideas and the state from scene one so we can DC realize that this is what we're going
to aim for.
But before we head towards this we have got to try and make this a little bit of a nicer class to work
with.
Now there's two ways in which I'm gonna do this.
It's going to be to update these two methods.
First of all so that's one thing and then the other thing is in here we have our restore state takes
an object we do casting in here.
I'm gonna take that.
So we don't have to do any casting in our restore state.
So the first thing is to refactor these methods because at the moment they're quite hard to read.
They're doing a few things and I would like to make this easier.
One of the things they're doing here is they're doing all this file writing stuff.
So here's what I think the end should look like it should be.
Save File and that should it take in the file that we want to save to this one here at the top.
The save file and it should take in the state that we capture.
So it's going to take this capture state here.
That should be the end.
Basically that's what we should aim to have at the end of this I'm going to comment out our current
code and you can use that for reference.
So I'm just gonna go ahead and generate this method.
The Save File method and unrest and cut it and I'm going to pay state just above and capture state here.
So fantastic.
Now how do we want this load to work.
I'm going to comment.
Our current load and basically it should work in a very similar way that but invert it because we've
got our restore state that needs to take the state from the file so we're going to restore state from
a load file method that is going to take our save file has the argument so you can see how they are
similar these two methods but they're kind of flipped around and it really tells us at the top level
how load and save is working how it's a two step process you get the stuff from the file you restore
the state so we're going to implement this load state as well by generating this method and that means
it's ready for you to do your challenge.
So I would like you to implement the save file and load file methods take that attack commented code
and use it and then you're going to look at the return values and save file Load File and the arguments
you've got coming in to make sure that you provide the right stuff and then make it work like it was
doing before.
So pause the video and have a go at completing this refactor.
Okay.
Welcome back.
So let's have a look.
First of all this Load File business.
I'm gonna take all this comments in code and put it in to our Load File method and I'm going to um comments
what we've got in here and see what's working.
So we've got our save file coming in that works fine.
The only thing we've not got working fine is it's not returning anything out of Load File we want it
to return the state.
So instead of doing restore state here which is now happening out at this load function level we want
to just return the stuff that was D serialized from the stream.
So if we go ahead and just return what's de serialize from the stream that should do the trick.
Fantastic.
Now the save file very similar.
I'm just going to take this commented out code and I am going to stick it in the line.
They file for me in the save file method and I'm going to uncommon the code and see what the matter
is.
So what's going on at the moment is we've got this object called V.
Let's give this a better name.
I'm going to call this the state instead.
And what do we want to do with the state we're currently not using it.
We don't have to return anything out save file so that's fine.
But we're calling capture state in here which we don't need to do because the state has already been
captured into this object that is being passed into safe farm method.
So I can just replace this capture state with the state that we've already captured and that makes it
nice and readable nice and reusable too.
Now one thing I would like to do to make this just a little bit better even is when we've got this state
we're currently passing the state around as an object and basically the most generic type that we could
have and then we're having to cast that in the restore state.
Now what I want to do is actually be more honest about what our state is at a higher level so that when
we are trying to load from a file that's the type we want to return.
So I'm going to change the return type of load file to this dictionary String object type instead.
And I'm also going to change the type that we take into restore state to the dictionary String object.
So that now I don't have to cast in restore state and I can just use this state dictionary directly
like so.
And that should be good.
Now the other thing the other problem we've got now is that load file is trying to return this thing
that is decentralised and it's not sure whether that's a dictionary or not.
So that's what we've got to do here.
We've got a cast to a dictionary and this is a quite long time so I'm always going to copy and paste
it and we're just going to cast to that dictionary object of going from string to object and let's see
if we can now understand what this is doing.
So if I have a look at the load system what's going on is a load file we are loading out a dictionary
from string to object type and then that state is being used to restore the state which also as it happens
takes a dictionary from string to object and that works great.
Now we could also do that for consistency sake.
Now with our capture state and save file so let's just be really consistent here that the save file
is going to take in.
It could still take in an object but we're just going to make it more specific that it's going to take
in a dictionary from string to object in fact actually let's just leave it as object.
It could save whatever it likes it doesn't matter at the save file level.
But for our capture state we're going to turn that round so that the object it returns has to be a dictionary
from string to object type which is actually already what it returns.
So that was quite easy to do so let's just hop back over to the Unity Editor and check that this is
working as it was before if I go ahead move hit save move away and hit load bam we go back to where
we were before so we haven't changed any of the functionality now.
I'll see you in part two where we'll actually do the changing so we're merging these two save files.