Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we are going to be introducing these health balls at the moment they are inert.
But in the next lecture as well we are going to be looking at making them active.
So let's dive in and see how great these health balls okay.
So I'd like to create a health bar in very much same way as we've done with our damage text.
So for me I'm only going to put health bars on the enemy.
So let's go to the enemy prefab and create an empty object which is going to be the root of our canvas.
Now I want the root of our canvas to not be a canvas itself.
And we'll see why in a few minutes.
But basically the idea is I'm going to have a health bar prefab and I'm going to prefab this into the
game UI in game folder.
So we have this health bar prenup.
Okay let's open up the health bar prefab and under that I'm going to put the canvas.
Now the reason I'm not putting the canvas at the root level is that I don't I'm going to want to change
things like this scale in here and the width and stuff like that.
And I don't want that to get messed up by where I'm including it.
Remember that where you include a prefab often overrides the transform of the proof of the root elements
of the prefab.
So if you want that not to be messed with then you need to put it underneath a little parenting game
object.
So this canvas we are going to want to scale appropriately now with the text.
I did a bit of a hack of changing the scale factor.
Now it's not going to work very well for all UI elements.
So what we're going to do instead is the UNITY OFFICIAL way which is in the render mode.
You go and select 12 space and then you have to decide what kind of resolution you're going to be dealing
with.
And because this is just a health bar we don't need a lot of pixels to define this health bar.
I'm going to go for 100 width and 10 in height and I'm going to reset the position while I'm at it 2
0 0 0 and then we can focus in on our health bar and the aspect ratio looks about right to me might
struggle to see that on your screens.
Now this is going to be absolutely humongous in our world because how it's currently set up it's going
to take up 100 meters 100 unity units.
So we want to bring this down so that maybe it just takes up one meter and the way to do that is to
change the scale.
So if we wanted it to take up two meters what we would do is do two divided by whatever the width is
100 in this case.
And that would be the scale that we want in our case.
I want it to be one metre wide so it's going to be one divided by 100.
So it's going to be one hundredth knot.
It's gonna be nought point not one.
And I'm going to use that same value in the x y and z scale.
They don't really need it in the z and then you can zoom in on the canvas and it's going to be much
more small and appropriately sized.
You might be thinking it's quite odd to change the scale and why not just make the width and height
smaller.
Well that's because the width and the height of your canvas has a special meaning that actually tells
the rest of the UI rendered within the canvas how many pixels of resolution it has to render.
So we don't want to change those we want to have that resolution.
We just want to make that resolution smaller in the world.
Now in this canvas I am going to set up a background image and a foreground image and the foreground
image is the one we're going to scale to give us the inside of the health bar.
So I'm going to go to right click UI and image and then I am going to make this image a slightly D saturated
red and then I'm going to.
Okay.
So I want it to take its height and width from the size of the canvas.
So I am going to change the way that we are doing our anchors to select the anchor preset.
And just this one at the bottom right where it does kind of the width full stretch and both directions.
That's what I want to do.
And then you can see the rack transform has been modified to now instead of saying the width is saying
the distance from the left top and bottom so I'm going to set the top and bottom width to be zero so
that this red image just takes up the whole of our canvas and I'm going to rename the image to background
and what I'm gonna do is add a duplicate and put a foreground and I'm actually going to child the foreground
to the background and change its color to green.
Now White I child it to the background because now if I were to change the size of the background for
example I might bring in 20 from the canvas.
It actually also changes the foreground because the foreground is being sized relative to the background
so it's just undo that modification.
And now the foreground the way I want to be manipulating this in script to show our health is by changing
our X scale.
So if I change my X scale you will see that it is essentially bringing in from both sides.
I want to avoid that.
So how do we avoid that.
Well let's just make sure I've got my right transform tool on and you'll be able to see that there is
an anchor here and I can change the anchor manually or I can do it in the rect transform components.
I'm going to set my pivot to zero and I'm going to position my bar to the far left of the background.
And now what we're going to see is that if I change my scale it is behaving as we'd expect at 1 which
would be full health is fully green at zero.
It's going to be fully empty and at point five it's somewhere in between.
And then we can change this scale this along so that for now that's what I'm going to use as my preview
will get round to updating it in code in a later lecture.
Now many challenge for you is going to be getting this hovering above the enemy's heads and facing towards
the camera as we have done before pause the video and have a go.
So first thing is going to be to get it facing towards cameras very easy.
Go to the root health bar components or even the canvas doesn't really matter which one I think they'll
put it on the canvas.
And I'm going to do a face or camera face scripts going to add the camera facing script and then I'm
gonna go to an enemy so open up the enemy and you can see we've got ourselves a health bar at their
feet.
And it's one metre wide if you change the scale than that it's going to be a different sized health
bar.
And then we can take this health bar and bring it up just above their heads you can choose where you
want it above the head you might choose that with a big boss that has a lot of health you might want
to change the scale of the health bar so that it is bigger and looks more intimidating but in my case
I'm going to leave out the default.
Now we are going to just go and check whether the facing is working correctly.
Yep sure enough there are all these health balls every enemy has a health bar and is facing towards
us.
And if I go and attack them nothing happens because there's health bars I'm not actually being updated
correctly yet.
Now one more mini challenge for you we've seen how to do scaling the unity way in the health bar and
we haven't been doing that in our damaged text.
So if we can damage text prefab you can see the damage text is currently doing it using a dynamic pixels
per unit thing which is a bit weird and I'm just gonna go ahead and reset the scalar and the challenge
to you is going to be to reset your scalar and get things back to working but this time using a scale
and a width that is appropriate just like we did in the health bar.
Try that okay.
Welcome back.
So I'm going to go with.
Let's see.
I think about 100.
Width is going to be correct here again and I'm going to go for 50 height and then we can have a look
at our text which is absolutely minuscule down here.
We want that to be taking up again the whole of the canvas so we can stretch in both dimensions and
set the top and left in all of these to zero so that it takes up all the space.
Double click so that we have the space available to us and you can see the text is a little bit small.
That's because we need to increase the font size so increase the font size a little bit.
I'm still feeling that this is very low resolution text so I might decide that 100 pixels isn't enough.
Let's go for 200 pixels by 100 something like that.
And now scale up attacks even further say increase the font size.
Now that's looking like about the right sort of resolution.
I'm also going to center a line in the vertical axis as well and let's see.
So now we just need to pick our scale.
So if I'm going to say that this text should be about a meter across.
That seems a bit large I'm gonna say it's half a meter across so point five.
The scale is going to be point five divided by 200 because that's the width of the rect transform.
And that gives us a scale value.
And I'm going to use that across the board and we can just go ahead and have a look and see that that's
still looking fine it's just much much smaller.
And we've got to go ahead and update the animation because if you go ahead and play at the moment and
do some damage to somebody then you'll see that in fact that's actually pretty small.
I think I'm going to double the scale there.
So let's we can just do that by doing a star to will increase the scale by 2 on this on that scale there
and bring it across to the X Y and Z and just have a look in games check that it's not so small anymore.
Go ahead and hit this guy with five balls and that's a little bit better.
But you can see the animation is not quite working as it used to.
So we can see that that's because we've basically been monkeying around with how things are scaled and
so on.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm going to go ahead and change the location that we fade out to so take our
text and shift it up like so like we were like with him before and make sure that we keep frame it so
that we have the new values totally key framed you might have to deselect this canvas group in order
to do the key framing.
Let's try that see whether it's now going up.
Yes it is.
But you can see it's only doing it after having faded out so I'm going to just remove the key frame
for the anchor position that is halfway along our timeline.
So now it is going up and fading out after a little while.
Okay.
So that should hopefully fix up the in-game animation.
Let's give it a go.
And do some damage and see if the animation is working as intended.
Yes we've got 13 little no evaporating over the top of this guy's head so everything is working as it
was doing before except now we're using proper canvas scaling and just one more little tweak to that
damaged text at the moment.
If I do damage to my enemy here you can see overlaps with the health bar.
I don't like that.
I think we need to put that a little bit higher.
So let's go to character and find where that positioning is.
Oh actually it looks like if I select my damaged text born and that is not what does the positioning
of the text.
So what is doing the positioning is in the prefab it's the default value of in-game and we go to text
prefab you can see that this is currently positioned not at 0 0.
So its position is 0 0 and the damage text.
And then we can go in it to add character and in fact I'm going to go to the enemy directly so I've
got something to position it above and we can take our damage text spawner and just position it just
a little bit above the health bar so that they don't overlap one another.
That's the idea.
So that should hopefully do the trick.
I'm just going to apply that position back to the root character so applies override to the prefab character
that's what I want to do I go ahead and hit play now then hopefully if I do some damage then that text
is spawning above the health bar which is just a little bit more sane cool.
So in this lecture we've seen how to set up proper canvas scaling and we've applied it to our damaged
text and also to create some health bars next lecture we're going to be looking at setting that scale
of our health bar in code so that it really reflects the health of the particular enemy.
See you then.