Hello and welcome.
In this light show we're going to be looking at making our health balls actually represent the amount
of health that the enemy has.
So if I have this enemy here with a full green health bar he's got full health.
Start attacking him and the health decreases decreases decreases until he is dead.
Let's dive in and see how to achieve this OK.
So we've got lovely health bars.
But at the moment those health bars are not being updated so that they reflect the actual correct amount
of health.
So how are we going to do this.
Well we're going to create a script and first of all actually before we create a script it's been brought
to my attention that naming our resources namespace resources does clash with the fact that unity likes
to use that folder name to dynamically bring in objects.
So it's not a good idea to call it that.
I'm going to rename it to attributes and I'm going to rename the namespace to attributes too so we're
going to do this in Visual Studio code.
I'm going to bring up where is that attributes folder now.
Right the top of course and I'm going to rename the namespace by selecting RPG dot resources doing control
shift F and then this little arrow next to the search box.
I can drop down and I have already done this in prototype so it is already pre populated this with RPG
or attributes for me.
And first of all when you do a find replace in multiple files in Visual Studio code you have to first
do the search which will search through and give you a list of results and the the results you can just
check for sanity.
And then once you've got that list of results check for sanity you can hit the replace all button which
is right next to the replacement field you do replace all.
It should replace about 10 in my project.
And then if we go back into unity and just double check that everything is still playing.
I think it will be because that replacement is very straightforward.
Yep everything still playing still able to find all the classes et cetera.
Okay.
So that was just a little bit of tidying up because I'm about to use that attributes folder to create
a health bar script that's right click Create a new C sharp scripts and it is going to be a health bar.
Let's go ahead and open up that C sharp script and put it in the namespace first of all.
So it namespace RPG dot attributes and then we've got ourselves a health bar and it's going to need
an update because update is where it's going to update that health bar.
And I'd like to see if you can figure this out.
Actually I'd like to see if you can set the scale of that.
Let's have a look.
Open up the health bar and just clarify what it is we're trying to do.
So this foreground image what I'm asking is that we are able to set this scale programmatically based
on the current health of our health components.
And you can give it a go.
I'm also going to show you how I'm going to what I'm going to bind.
So if you feel like giving a go now or you want some more hints just wait.
OK so some hints are going to be I'm going to add a serialized field with square brackets serialized
field and it's going to take the health components and it's going to be our health components equal
no.
And then I'm just gonna take another sterilized field which is going to be our ball ground.
So it's going to be an image.
In fact it's going to be a rect transform because all we care about is that scale called the foreground.
That's what I'm gonna call it again equal to no.
So see if using those two components you could set them up hook them up and then in updates update the
correct thing.
Okay.
So as for setting them up that's fairly straightforward.
But one thing that might catch you up is that we'll add the component first of all to the roots of health
ball.
So it's going to be health bar C S that's what we're adding.
And before grand I can hook up here in this prefab because we've got access to it but I can't hook up
the health in this prefab so that I'm gonna have to hook up in the enemy prefab.
So just dragging the enemy in to the health components field of a health bar script and that should
be an override that applies only in the enemy prefab.
Let's go back into the health bar prefab and in here in the C++ natural fact a C sharp rather I'm gonna
go and update the grounds scale so foreground dot and then you can have a look at what is available
there.
It's going to be using the local scale against set the local scale.
And we are going to be it's a vector so new vector 3 and the scale I want to set I'm only really interested
in setting the x values scale.
So I'd note for example I'm going to set point five for that at the moment and then do one and then
one for the other scales we want to just keep those at their current scaling factor and this should
be a point five F to make sure it's a float and not double because that's what it wants to take.
And if we do that the moment all it's going to do is set that health bar to a constant half.
But we do want to take that health from the health component.
So what do we have available in our health component for this kind of task.
Well we've got a get percentage but get percentage is going to be between 0 and 100.
What I want is a value between 0 and 1 which is what actually we have calculated here and then multiplied
by 100 seems a bit wasteful to multiply by 100 and then divide by a hundred.
So what I'm gonna do is just pull out a new public float get a fraction function and get fraction is
just going to do this calculation in the brackets.
So just makes things a little bit clearer as well.
So get fractions going to be the health points divided by the total health make sense and then forget
percentage we're just going to use get a fraction multiplied by 100.
So that means that now we can use get a fraction when trying to calculate our local scale.
So we're going to use the health component dot get fraction and that's going to give us the value between
0 and 1.
So let's go ahead and try that out.
So what I'm expect to see is that all the enemies are going to have full health bars which indeed they
seem to.
And if I go ahead and hit the enemy you can see is health bar starts to decrease all the way down to
zero at which point he dies and we are happy because that is a health bar that is working now in this
lecture we have looked at how we can update the scale of our foreground to reflect the actual health
of our enemies.
The next lecture we're going to look at how we can enable and disable this health bar when we have full
health and when we have no health.
So the health bars don't just float they're above dead enemies.
I'll see you that.