Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be getting notifications when we level up so we'll get a log message down here saying
that I leveled up when I killed that guard.
We're also going to make this much more efficient so that levels aren't being calculated every frame
or more than once a frame but only calculated every time the experience changes which is the only variable
that matters to us.
And in the process we're going to learn about delegates and events and actions in C sharp to help us
make that happen.
Let's dive in to this action packed lecture so suppose that when I kill this guard over here and take
my experience points with me then I get a level up.
But there's no real signal to the player that that has happened other than looking at the level score
in the top left.
So we want to have some sort of gameplay event triggered when that happens.
And the best way to do that is to store some state because we need to know what the previous level was
in order to know whether we've leveled up or not.
And at the moment all we're doing is there's no state that tells us what the level is we just know whether
the experience points have gone up or not.
In fact we don't even know that we just know that what the experience points currently are and we can
calculate the level from that.
So if we want to keep track of the current level we need a new variable.
It's going to be an int called current level and I'm going to start it off with zero which is actually
invalid level just to make sure that we actually initialize it properly and initialize it from either
the starting level or via the experience points.
So talking about initialization let's create a start to do it in and the first instance what we should
do is get our current level from get level get level will do the grunt work of actually figuring out
where it should go from starting level or from the experience.
Next up we can replace this update which is currently printing stuff out that we don't need the log
messages for anymore.
And what we're going to do is essentially every update we want to update the current level via get level
but we actually want to check whether we have changed the current level so I'm going to store in a variable
first called new level the level that we calculate and then we gonna say if the new level is greater
than the current level.
Now obviously if your game can have levels go down as well you might need to tweak this logic then here
we want to signal or do something.
I'm going to just use a print statement here saying leveled up and then before this we want to just
set the current level.
Want to update it to the new level.
So we've calculated the new level now we want to set the current level to it.
Now we've done the comparison and this is this will probably work and this is okay but there's a couple
of problems here.
The first one is that we're recalculating get level every single time.
And in fact when do we call get level externally we're also recalculating it.
So let us consider instead basically turning get level here in to a different method and just using
get level as a successor.
Let me show you what I mean.
So we do a public int get level another get level which basically just returns current level and then
we change the name get level to calculate level instead.
Then calculate level is what we're gonna be calling in start an update.
And that means that now we're not having to recalculate the level more than once every frame which is
a good thing.
But we're still having to calculate it once every frame which is a bit more than necessary because the
experience doesn't change every single frame at least not often.
And what's even worse than that as potentially a race condition because you gain experience in a particular
frame in a particular update from somewhere.
This exp gain experience gets called when you take damage and we've got update being called to assess
the.
And calculate the current level.
Now what could happen is that depending on the order of these updates you might calculate the level
using the old experience points and for a frame at least you will show the old level on the display.
Now you might say that doesn't really matter is just a short problem will soon go away.
Well yes that's true but I don't like the messiness of it and with the performance consideration I think
we can do better.
And it's a good excuse to teach you about delegates and about events in more depth.
Now remember we have done events and delegates before when we created our cinematic control remover.
And here we had this playbill director and we learnt how to subscribe to these events but we really
glazed over how to create our own events and that's what I'd like to go into more detail with here.
We're not going to have a challenge on this you're just going to watch me code along and do it.
But in an upcoming video we are going to challenge you to actually create your own events as well so
don't worry that is coming very very soon.
Just to test your understanding but because it's a lot of concepts to cover in one go.
I'm just gonna do one video that covers the concepts first.
So what is the level what is a delegate.
We've heard these words may be bandied about maybe you haven't heard these words bandied about.
Well let's take a step back a second and see why we need this in the first place.
So we've got this base stats and we know base stats depends on experience because it gets the experience
in order to calculate the level.
But what we want now is a callback from experience saying hey base stats I've updated it's time for
you to recalculate your level.
And this is a classic example of the observer pattern very much like we did with the cinematic control
remover.
It allows us to have the dependency go in one direction but execution go in the other.
Also very similar to interfaces but in this case delegates are a better fit.
So what are delegates I keep using these words and delegates and events interchangeably what's the difference.
Well a delegate is just a list of pointers to methods.
Remember how we talked about that in the cinematic control remover.
Basically we've got a delegate which is a list of pointers to methods how do we declare a delegate.
Well it looks like this if I go to my base stats and actually get experience because it's from experience
that I want to allow sloughed to be subscribed so from now until the end of this video I'm going to
be working through an example that we're subsequently going to delete.
So for now put down your editors and just watch along.
So I'm going to create a new public delegate so that it's accessible outside a delegate just looks a
lot like a function or a method.
So you give it a return type.
So we could have a bool return type and then the name of the delegates.
So example delegate and then potentially some arguments.
So we could have a float value and this is a delegate or at least it's the type.
It's a delegate type and we can create instances of this delicate just by using it as a type.
So I can have a public again making accessible externally example delegates and then on done stuff for
example.
And that's the name of the delegate.
So now what can happen is we can set this delegate in other classes.
So for example in base stats we could get hold of the experience in start.
It's a good place to subscribe to events is usually start because from then on we'll get notifications
about it.
We're going to check whether experience is no and if experience is not No actually we want to go ahead
and subscribe.
So is can we experience dots on Dunn's stuff.
And now remember that I've said that delegates are essentially just a list of pointers to methods.
Well so what I can do is I could add to that list so I can do.
Plus equals and I can.
I don't know.
I need to have a function that it can called.
And crucially it can't be a function that doesn't match the signature of the delegates so that they
delegate signature returns boolean.
And it takes a float value.
And so if I had update as the function that I'm adding to this list of delegates is going to say Nope
that doesn't match the signature.
So I need to create something it does.
I can.
It can be private.
Doesn't have to be public even though it's being called outside of this class.
Doesn't have to be public because it is not part of our public interface.
No one else can call it unless it's done through this delegate.
So it's gonna be a bool return value and it's going to have on stuff done as the name.
And then it needs to take this float to value as well.
And then we can just alternate prints the value in here and then return true or something like that.
This is just some example code really obviously it's not doing the right thing.
So now we can add on stuff done to the list of events or methods in add delegates and this means that
now inexperience we can call this delegate list just like we would call a method with the parentheses.
So on stuff done parentheses means hey call this but notice I need to pass in a float because again
that is the signature it needs a float to go in and it will actually return a boolean out of here if
I wanted to bool result like so.
And now you might be thinking Hang on its returning one result but this is a list of delegates how that
happening.
Well that's happening because it only returns the last result in the list of things that it called.
Now notice there is a bit of a confusion here because what I can do is instead of doing plus equals
I can do equals as well.
So I can say on done stuff equals on stuff done like this.
And that's basically the same as saying overwrite everything in the list with just a list containing
this one method here.
Now you might think hang on a second.
That seems a little bit dangerous doesn't it.
Because I could have one function and then I could have an on stuff done to like so let's go and do
this in fact we can try and run this.
So I haven't stopped on to and I'm going to have a print on stuff done to plus the value add to distinguish
it from the first print statement which is just on stuff done plus the value.
So if we had done this by accident and we're calling this on gain experience let's just see what happens
if I go ahead and gain experience.
So I'll go and pick up the sword kill the enemy and have a look at the log message.
You notice that it's only calling on stuff done too which makes sense because in this second line we
have overwritten the whole list of methods to call.
So what we really want to be doing is plus equals and we don't want to be doing equals and that doing
that would be dangerous.
So there is a way of preventing us from overwriting delegate lists like this in C sharp and that is
to use the event keyword.
So what's an event and event is basically a protection on top of a delegate instance that prevents it
from being overwritten.
So now if I tried to do the same trick over and base that so if I had this equal sign it's going to
give me an error right there and then saying it can't appear I can't be used.
Basically an event can't be used with an equal sign has to be used with a plus equals or a minus equals
if you're wanting to remove the event notification.
So that should now work as we would like.
So let's summarize what we've learned in this lecture we've learned that delegates are essentially a
list of pointers to methods.
We can have a delegate type to be the type of that list and then we have events which are protections
on those delegates to stop us from being able to overwrite those lists from outside of the class.
And we've seen how this can be used to implement the observer pattern where we want other classes to
subscribe to our events without us having to know who they are.
Now in the next lecture we're going to go ahead and apply this to our own code and we'll also need to
learn about something called an action which C sharp gives us for convenience.