So in this lecture we're going to be carrying on from where we left off in the last one to use events
and delegates in order to notify base that's when experience changes so it can change the level and
in turn show some cool particle effects and other things to the player.
Let's dive in so what I want to do is actually create a delegate that we're going to use it's going
to have a void return type and a no arguments.
And it's going to be experience gained delegates like so and it's gonna be an event because we want
to prevent overwriting by other classes and then we have the.
We're going to call it on experience gained like so.
And this we can call when gain experience is called so on experience gained parentheses and that's going
to cool everything in that delegate list.
Now notice that we often very often use delegates they have a void return type and no arguments.
So actually in C sharp they make this super easy by having the action and action is a predefined delegate
with no return type and it is included in system so you need to have the system namespace.
So instead of declaring this delegate let me just comment it out we can just go ahead and use action
instead.
And action is exactly the same as this delegate is just got a different name.
It's called action instead of experience gained delegate and that tends to be a lot easier to read as
well because you often have to name these delegates for the specific use case they're being used for
and there's a lot of repetition going on.
So I like to use action because it's just really clear what's going on there.
And we did in fact use action in our example for the fake playable director you might recall.
So now we haven't got this on stuff done.
Instead we have got dot and noticed we've even gotten out using an event it is has got the thunderbolt
symbol in our autocomplete.
So we're going to do on experience gained and then we have to register for the thing that we want to
do which is actually everything in this update method.
So we want to do is rename this update method to update level and that won't get called every update
now but we will call it on experience gained so little mini challenge for you.
I'd just like you to see if you can remember how to subscribe to this delegate.
There's something you've done before OK so we do a plus equals and then the update level and notice
we don't put any parentheses here.
Don't make that mistake because we don't want to be calling update level.
We wants to be adding update level the method to this list of methods on experience gained.
So that's what we're gonna do.
We're gonna remove all this on stuff.
Done test malarkey.
And if you haven't been following along up to this point this is a good point to go and catch up and
make your code reflect this.
So again what we're doing is we're having over an experience we have got this event which has got action
type which we know is basically saying it's functions that return void and take no arguments.
It's called unexperienced game that is being called over in gain experience and then we're subscribing
to it in base.
That's where we are subscribing the update level to the unexperienced game notification and then that
is when we are count recalculating our level.
Now there will be a bit of a bug at this stage which happens when you have a save file that is restoring
the experience points and you've got some experience points to restore then you will notice that sometimes
and they're in some weird conditions the level will not be correctly updated when you load the game.
Now don't worry about this.
We will be dealing with it in the next lecture.
But for now I go and kill this guard.
Then what we should get is that when he's dead the experience points go up in the very same moment the
level is recalculated as well it's not being recalculated every update is just being recalculated every
time the experience points get changed.
Okay.
So in summary what we've come up with in this lecture is a system by which we can recalculate the level
every time the experience points change.
And also if we have a look at the console we get a notification every time that happens and in the process
we have learnt about delegates which again are a list of pointers to methods.
Multiple things and they can be called by something.
And it's a good way of doing an inversion of dependency we've had events which are protection on delegate
instances.
And then we have action which is a predefined delegate which is very useful and we'll be using all the
time.
So quickly before I go there is this weird bug where if I add to the script execution order the health
script and the base stats script then if I make it such that the health script runs before the base
starts script and hit apply what you're gonna notice if I go ahead and hit play and first of all I think
I have to make sure I delete any save files and I might have around but if I've got no save file it
will give me this index out of bounds error.
What's going on there.
Well the problem is that our current level is set to zero unless it has been initialized in start.
And if we try and use the current level before we get to start in base stats for example if we're trying
to set the health points here in start of health then we are essentially going to be using that default
value which is not a good default value that current level of 0 is not a good default value.
So what we're going to do is make sure that if we are getting the level the current level has been initialized
and we can do this fairly easily.
And you could challenge yourself to figure out how but the way we can do it is to say if our current
level isn't initialized which one way of saying that is that it is less than 1 basically is an invalid
level.
If our current level is less than 1 then what we want to do is we want to just go ahead and calculate
what the current level should be.
So we can just call calculate level like so and then we'll update the current level and make sure that
it is cached and ready for the next time we call get level.
So this just makes sure we prime our pump and we have the current level set now to finish off.
I'm just going to go back into the into projects and fix up the script execution order.
I want to first of all check that it's working so before I do the script execution order we can see
that I can actually start playing this time but also I want to go ahead and remove any changes that
I made to the script execution order we don't need them.
And generally speaking I don't like fixing bugs by imposing a script execution order.
It's better to fix things in the code.
So as I said in the next lecture we are going to be looking at fixing this weird bug that arises with
experience being restored from safe so you that.