In this video we're gonna have ad hit impacts for our projectiles so that when things land Kaboom we
spray a little particle effect to give a bit of visual feedback that you've landed your target.
So let's company get started to make this process a little bit simpler.
I've given you a fireball impact that you can go ahead and download against this lecture and then drag
on into your project import that should all go in the right places.
It's probably created an effects folder so game effects and there's the fireball impact just drag it
in so you can see it's just a little impact like that seeing effects called fireball impact.
Okay.
So we need to open up our projectile script at the start at the top.
I mean we need to add a serialized field that will be of type game object and we'll call that hit effect
and we'll initialize that at no.
I'm going to scroll on down and show you the location where I'm going to put our instantiation.
So the moment where the impact takes place kaboom.
We want to instantiate that fireball impact at the position where the impact took place.
I'm going to give you that too as a challenge instantiate the impact effect instantiate a final impact
vector.
The point of impact.
Okay.
Summarize that three times now those who challenged take that on.
See you back here when you've given it a shot so on trigger enter.
I'm going to go all the way down just before our destroy.
I'm going to add a new line which is if hit effect is not now so will protect against now in this instance.
If not now then what are we going to do.
Well we want to instantiate instantiate so if we've got a hit effect we want to instantiate it will
be the hit effect that we just created a variable of where is it going to be.
Let's have a look and see what we've got access to.
We've got to get a location that is basically where we are trying to shoot at.
So we'll use that as our as our position.
So you get aim location parentheses and then the rotation will just say transform dot rotation semicolon.
Okay we'll save that jump back into unity and then find my fireball projectile so fireball projectile.
There we go.
Open up the prefab you can see now we have a place for our heat effect.
I'm going to find my new effect.
I just brought in fireball impact drag that on over.
That should be pretty good.
Click on play.
If I don't have the fibro equipped I can run out of my little fireball symbology thing there and shoot
and see what happens.
And kaboom we have this effect that plays really cool.
I like it nice and simple straightforward.
Having a fireball effect.
So what we could be doing is adding a an impact effect for all of our projectiles which just go ahead
and quickly make a variant of the fireball impacts.
I'm going to right click Create let's see beep prefab variant.
I'll call this generic impact effect.
Okay.
I'm not sure where I'm going to use it I'll probably just use it for my arrows for now might color it.
I might not but I was gonna make one here see if we can go through this process to make it work.
Open that up and we've got our kaboom.
I'm going to scroll out a little bit play that.
Okay.
Make it a lot smaller.
So start size from point let's say point 0 1 to point 1.
See how that looks.
Yep.
And then we'll make the start speed between 2 and 4.
So it shouldn't go as far.
Push.
Okay.
Then I'm gonna narrow the hole shape down a whole bunch so it's more of a.
If it's an arrow strike it's gonna be in a tighter tighter area.
I think play blink and then we'll change the color to make it a little bit more neutral because color
over lifetime.
Click on that selector.
Now I've got a whole bunch of presets I've created already but you can go in and add new selector things
you can delete them you can change the color.
I think you've probably done that enough before so you know how it works.
Transparency at the top color down the bottom double click to add a new one.
I'm going to just choose one of my other ones I've created previously.
This one that looks a little bit wacky.
It's got greens and yellows.
Okay just to differentiate it from what we had previously and you know what I'm going to do one last
little tweak.
I'm going to have this last for a shorter amount of time but go faster.
I think from say 10 to 15 sorry start lifetime point one two point two and push and start to be 10 to
15.
Bam bam.
Okay that looks okay.
Now we've got our generic hit impact jump back into our other projectiles will find the arrow projectile
blue.
We will give that the hit impact of heat effect of generic hit effects.
Awesome.
And now I'm going to find my projectile red.
Do the same thing effects generic impact effect cause I could be adding this to my root arrow projectile.
That would be a place to put this so my heat effect is the generic heat effect that would be a smart
thing to do wouldn't it.
So generic hit impact is on our projectile at the root level so particularly for our arrows it means
they'll all get that.
I've also gone and added it to the blue and the red I didn't need to do that but we've got all our bases
covered now haven't we.
So I'm gonna click on play run over to my bow and arrow so that I actually am shooting the blue arrows.
We'll see how this looks and pull.
Okay.
They're hitting me I'm hitting them so I recommend you go and create a red one and maybe make this blue
one a little bit more blue.
I've got it a little bit green in my approach here but you know you can see that I'm actually landing
it and having that moment of impact I think makes our arrows and our missiles and all that kind of stuff
a lot more interesting.
So there we go.
That's a quick one for this lecture.
Great work and I'll see you again shortly.