Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We're gonna be creating a scriptural object asset called a progression.
And as you can see from this progression it's laid out hierarchically.
So we have multiple character classes which I can expand in and out.
And these current classes have a property called the character class and that is a dropdown list here.
And then we have a health element which is actually itself an array and contains all the different health
at different levels so we can look at this spreadsheet basically and say hey I've got a player and he's
a level two so he should have 100 health.
That's what we're gonna be solving in this lecture.
Let's dive in and see how we can use the scriptural object system to achieve that.
So in our progression design that we've got here we've currently got our base stats but it needs to
point to a progression asset which is going to be a scripts will object and that's gonna be the subject
of this lecture.
So let's dive in and create one.
I'm going to go to the scripts folder to the stats folder within it.
Create a new script in here and you see sharp scripts and I'm going to call this a progression and then
this progression I'm going to go ahead and open up and actually replace the contents of this file entirely.
What I want to do is I want to have a script object so I'm going to use the autocomplete here in Visual
Studio to do that.
And it's giving me that obviously it's called progression and I can create a new progression by going
into the RPG project menu.
So let's just go ahead and see how that looks.
Is that what I want.
If I go over I'm going to create my progression actually in the roots of the game folder and I'll put
it in core.
So in core I'm going to go ahead and create a RPG project progression.
So is that what we want no weapons is at the top level here.
I'm going to have stats and then new progression in here.
Like so let's have a look if that looks better it's going to right click menu here create stats new
progression.
Okay so we've got ourselves our progression asset we're only gonna be needing one.
In actual fact because everything is going to go ahead and point at that progression access.
So that's how I can look.
Well if we go to our base stats it's going to point to it just by having a serialized field that's as
easy as what we need.
So we're going to do a progression type for this field and we'll just call this the progression that
we want it to point to.
Now I'm going to start off with this as no just to avoid any compilation complaints and warnings.
So if I now want to hook this up I need to go to the characters and the root character which has this
base stats on it.
And where is that based at.
Here it is.
And I can hook it up to the progression.
We've only got one and every single character in our game is automatically going to use that whether
it's an enemy in Archer a player that's already been hooked up with just this one variable in this one
prefab that's the power of prefab variants for you.
So we're going to go over and just have a look.
Obviously our progression is looking pretty plain at the moment it doesn't have anything like what we
are intending it to look like over here in the design.
So to do that we're gonna need to go down on kind of multiple levels because we don't want to do arrays
of stuff that contains health contains damage also contains the class that we want and to do that there
is a feature that's really handy in unity which is that you can use any old class in a serialized field
with a few conditions.
So for example I want a list of the character classes in here the character classes being this whole
thing the health the health at each level and also which character class I currently am.
So I'm going to create a class within a class which you can do by the way called the progression character
class.
Like so just as differentiate it from the e num that is the character class and in here we can do whatever
we like.
We could have some ints called value and I'm going to get that default three.
We could have a string called name and I'm going to default of Hello.
And just this is for sake of argument.
Now why want to do is I want to create a serialized field in progression of type progression character
class and then I can just call this the character class like so.
And what's gonna happen here is if we go over to have a look in our progression scripts will object
should change as soon as the compilation is done.
Except it isn't.
And why is that.
If I go and have a look at my console there's not much of use in there either.
But the key is that this class here is not marked as something that unity knows how to serialize.
Now the way we can do this is simply to put a system dot serialize a ball as an annotation on this class.
Now if we head back to that progression asset wait for it to update.
You can see that it's got this character class in here but there's nothing in there.
Now the other thing you have to do is make these variables public and in this case we aren't going to
worry with annotations you'd think that you could do serialized field.
But let me show you that because we're using a different set of annotations here we're using the C sharp
annotations.
I don't think that works.
We go back over to have a look at the refreshed set things on it.
It works.
Sara ice field on value works as well.
So let's just go with serialized field but we do have to put this annotation here.
If you comment that out nothing's going to show up in here at all.
There you go.
So we gotta have system dot serialized bool just to tell unity that this is a class that it can use
in a serialized field and then it can have serialized fields within it that it can then display in the
editor.
So we've got this character class which inside it has this value and has this name.
So it's time for a challenge for you to create this progression.
Scripts will object.
It's a bit of a tricky challenge but hopefully you feel up to it and want to give it a try.
So the progression as I said is going to be in these levels we're going to have many levels for our
character classes.
So we've already said that we've got this class progression Character Stats.
How can we do a serialized field that has potentially multiple entries in here it could have three it
could have 10.
We could keep adding them next.
You want to have a way for that character class to identify that it is a grunt or it's for a player
or for a mage and then you're going to want to have the different fields which at the moment we're just
going to deal with health and each level within health itself.
So which class is this Which class is this cat's class you're going to want to think about this character
class and how we can have multiple of those in the progression and then only health and ours.
Interesting.
Don't worry about damage just yet you can do damage for extra credit if you want to now.
But we're not going to use it for a little while we're going to change how it's done later on so maybe
don't invest too much there.
And how will you do multiple levels.
So just thinking about this multiple stuff in serialized fields just does that ring any bells.
If it doesn't ring any bells I'll give you the hint that you should use arrays basically.
So you should do an array of the progression character classes and you should do an array of whatever
type it is.
For example for health it's going to be a float should do an array for health supposed video and have
a go OK so with those two hints hopefully they have elucidated that we should do the character classes
in here and just to avoid any compilation errors.
I'm going to set this to no.
And then what do we want in here.
Obviously not value a name for the character class.
That was a bit of a decoy.
What we do want however is a serialized field called the character class whereas this character class
I'm not in a namespace.
That's why it's not showing up.
Fantastic.
So I can just pull this out and do a namespace of RPG stats and paste the whole class back in.
So now we should have access to the character class which I'm just going to call the character class
like so and then we're going to have a serialized field for the health and we know the health is a float
but then we also know that we want a different value of health for each level of health.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to add in making just that float an array of floats.
So the health has multiple levels now.
I work with Rick basically to get this hierarchy set up this way.
But if you prefer a different hierarchy you might want to do it slightly differently and I'll explain
in a bit.
So let's start off with three character classes the first one I'm going to set to the player second
one to the grunt and the third one is going to be the mage.
So then what we're going to see is that we've got health under here with size zero.
So currently there are no levels for the player to have but I could set this up to be five different
levels and we can say hey at level.
Okay so element zero will say is Level 1 Let's just go for that convention.
There's no real easy way of changing this you can do custom that isn't the done thing it's worth it.
So all say let level Element Zero is Level 1.
So we can start off with know 50 health then we're gonna go up to 100 health then maybe 200 health maybe
then 400 health and then I'd know 700 health or something like that.
That is the idea of a progression.
Now I talked to Rick and he said it was most convenient for him to be thinking about one character class
and then thinking about one particular element and how that element progressed.
You might disagree you might say well it's easier for me to go into a particular level and think about
all of the different classes and what all their different characteristics would be in that case what
you'd want to do is just switch things around and hopefully this gives you the flexibility to do that
you might do that by creating an array of different progression character levels for example that could
be a new class that you set up and that class itself can contain an array of the character classes and
then this float wouldn't have to be an array because you've already got an array at the top level so
you can think about how you can change around this to suit your own needs.
It doesn't have to be done exactly this way but the important thing is that we end up with one skeptical
object that can contain all the details.
We want great stuff.
So we've overview how we can use C realizable classes in fact classes within classes and we've seen
how we can use the serialized file system serialized or annotation to allow us to put a class nest classes
within classes inside the inspector in unity in the next lecture.
We're gonna be looking at how we can get the health component to ready being ready for getting in the
progression data from progression and from base stats.
See you there.