Hello hello.
We're nearly finished this section we've got a little bit of cleaning up that we need to do and I'm
going to give us another one of our problem solutions style video so let's have a look at the problems
we've got at the moment mostly to do with destroying things so one when we're shooting and we're instantiating
our cool particle effect you can see we've got all of our impact effects just junking up our hierarchy
we need to tidy that up another thing when we kill our target you can see that this fireball Where is
it it's going and going and going for ever and that's something that we want to address and make sure
it doesn't do that.
And finally the last thing is we've got a few different components to our fireball and that's cool for
us to be out to have.
We're gonna create a little bit of functionality so that we just pause this and get into my scene here
so that we can have different aspects of our fireball be destroyed at different times so you can see
as we're going along here the head of the fireball and the trial the moment we impact the whole thing
blinks out of existence.
We're kind of covering it out with the impact.
So you don't see it so much but you might not have such a big impact.
You might want to have that a little bit more subtle so that we can for example destroy the head of
the fireball and then let the particle finish off doing what the particle wants to do.
So then the three things we're going to do I've broken this out as challenges so that you can have a
look at it.
I will be cleaning out the following destroying out impact effect after it's finished stopping the orphaned
of projectiles flying on forever and destroying different parts of the projectile at different times.
If you wanna take on all of those challenges now here's the time if you want to take them on one at
a time and see how you go only the first one first and you can give that a shot and then I'll show you
my solution and then if you feel like it you can give the second one a go and so on.
So first up let's work on destroying our heat impact.
After it's finished doing it he hit impacts do first of all I'm going to find where is my hit impact
it's on my effects here we've got the fireball impact and we've got the generic impact effect.
I'm going to create a script which will just be a pretty generic destroy after the effect is done scripts
so we'll go into our scripts folder I think this is more in core than it is in combat right click Create
C sharp script and I will call this destroy after effect effector effects will say effect singular I
think and then open that up in Visual Studio code to get rid of the start method we don't need that.
And as always I really need to be reminded what an update does.
I think we know that by now what I do want to do is to say if we don't have a particle system if the
particle system is not alive and this is a method that we can call upon I know as a challenge I didn't
really give you a clue for this.
It might have been tricky but you want to know the answer already.
OK enough waffle let's start.
If we do not have or there is not a get component what sort of component we're looking for we're looking
for the particle system dot.
And in here we have a mechanism to see the very first option here is is alive that's returning a ball.
So if basically when we look for the particle system it's not alive meaning that the particle system
itself is no longer alive no longer producing particles then pretty simply we just destroy this game
object save that and we'll go find the game object we're going to attach that to the look effects let's
see just here jump into my fireball impact click on Add component destroy after effect and that should
be added nicely and then over to my generic impact effect open prefab same thing add component destroy
after effect well it's already been added because this one I believe was the prefab variant of the fireball
impact okay probably could deserve a little bit of a rename to make that clearer the generic impact
effect is actually a prefab variant all viable impacts so I'll let you play around with that I'm probably
not going to do too much more with this myself in my particular game so I'll leave that to you however
you want to structure it make sure it makes sense to you which one is the prefab variant of which other
one.
Let's see if that's worked we'll jump on over into the game or fire off some fireballs come on over
shoot was not so close but he shoots and you see we have an impact that is quickly produced then quickly
destroyed so yep success we have successfully tidy that up.
Okay onto our next thing what's next on our challenge stopping often projectiles flying on forever.
This one is a more simple challenge so if you want to give this your best shot how do we make it that
we just don't have them go on and on and on we want to have a maximum limit on them so let's go over
to our projectile script I'm gonna make myself a new variable up the top here serialized here I'm going
to put it in the right spot first all serialized field this will be of type float and we'll just call
this Max life time and what is a good maximum lifetime we want to have as our default probably something's
not going to need to stay on the screen for more than 10 seconds so starting off at 10.
So where shall we destroy how projectile.
I think on a set target that's right at the start of our projectile coming into existence we will simply
decide destroy.
What are we destroying.
Again it's game object.
And after how long Max lifetime.
Okay.
We'll save that jump on overseas that's worked again.
Run run run run run and shoot you shoot 1 2 How many is this take about six or seven after we do that
we'll get this one fly off into the nowhere and okay and it's going to take 10 seconds I might speed
up the video here and it is destroyed itself excellent so so far two.
Two down one to go.
Let's have a look at the third one destroying the different parts of the projectile at different times.
Okay cool.
So once again let's get over into projectile.
We need to give ourselves a concept or we need to give ourselves the opportunity to say which things
do we want to destroy on immediate impact.
So I'm going to again serialize fuel create a new variable up here and this will be a game object type
once again but it will be an array so that we can take in more than one we might want to have five things
that get destroyed and others that do not so well cause destroy on collision destroy on hit we'll call
it we'll start that off.
Now initialize that it now and then within our code all the way down the bottom to do so after we've
bumped into something we are destroying the game object we don't want to destroy everything at that
point so just before this final destroy let us say destroy the things that are within our.
What do we call it destroy on hit array.
So for each game object and we'll call it to destroy game objects we want to destroy in destroy on hit.
What are we gonna do.
Well just pretty straight forward we destroy all of the.
To destroy semicolon.
Okay that's cool so we've got all these things that we destroy immediately.
But now this is also happening immediately it's destroying everything immediately so we want to have
something in here comma a certain amount of time which we'll call live after destroy life after life
after impact.
I think life after impact.
So how long do we want it to live.
After impact.
Making my variable a bit backwards here.
Copy this all the way up to the top and ourselves and other serialized field.
This will be of type float and called Life after impact and I'll initialize that and more to.
OK so make sure it's all cleaned up and tidy up.
If you have any projectile stuff going on that you want to linger around like some smoke or something
linger around for a while you might want to make it.
You may want to make it more than two.
So now we need to go over to our fireball projectile.
That's the main one I won't worry about doing it with the arrow at the moment because the fireball is
the one I'm interested in and you see our destroyer on hit a ray.
I'm gonna make it a size one and that will give us one thing the fireball ahead that I'll drag in is
the game object that will be destroyed immediately everything else will be destroyed after two seconds
that we've got the two seconds resting here.
Okay.
Let's see how this one goes.
Click on play.
Very excited.
Boo boo boo and click.
I'll need a pause and getting all nice and close it's all set up for us step ahead step ahead.
Okay so you can see on impact.
The trail is still living the head has been destroyed and then the trail gets time to resolve the remainder
of its kind of flying into the dude and then sticking around for probably a little bit too long.
So let's adjust that a little bit.
Open up our file fireball prefab point too.
I can also go into the projectile itself into the flamethrower and change this duration so it's lower.
I think that would make sense as well so that we're not having all this time after the fireball has
hit that it's still sitting there generating generating its particles but for now I'll solve it the
other way just by changing up that value we have on here life after impact point too but those are the
two levers that you can pull.
Again these things aren't exact science sometimes you have to fiddle and tune and tweak until you get
the look you're going for.
So we'll throw this fireball okay and that looks pretty good.
We get leery of that trail of the fireball.
Bum bum bum bum.
Yep and it sticks around for a little bit of time.
I think that looks pretty good.
Okay.
Couple more things to tidy up and before we wrap up I think I've gone and broken our arrows.
Let's have a look at those couple of reasons why.
First of all let's see what's going on.
It hits me and it goes flying straight through.
So first of all what we can do is say well we want to have the arrow head destroyed upon impact.
I'm going to go to my root arrow projectile open prefab find the destroy on hit.
Change that to one and drag in the simple arrow that should destroy the arrow.
And for our prefab variance that should work as well.
What we need to do in our Projectile class is to scroll down and say that upon impact we want our Arrow
or want our projectile to have a speed of zero so that it doesn't try to keep going.
Let's say it doesn't try to keep going bird bird bird bird straight through our target.
So that will also help us in this instance underneath.
Take damage before we play our hit effect.
Adding here speed equals zero speed I'm referring to here is our instance variable speed run up every
top there so the speed of the projectile.
Save that and see what sort of impact that has with those two changes.
Run run run run run stand in the middle of the bridge.
Don't miss me.
Got me got me.
Okay.
We'll slow it down and see what's happening with the trail here just to make sure the trails behaving
as we'd expect it to behave.
The red ones coming in and hits me bam.
And then the trail slowly disappears.
I think that's awesome.
Pretty good and success.
Okay.
Another thing I'll do with a fix.
I've been thinking about this and getting lots of great feedback from people.
This is really dumbly name so I created my first impact here which was the fireball put a lot of effort
into that and then said Well let's do use a prefab variant but then I encoded generic impact effect
which doesn't make any sense.
I'm using this as an arrow impact effect.
So now it's okay for the Arrow impact I think from a naming point of view to be ab prefab variant of
the fireball and if we were to create another layer of effects underneath this we probably would want
to rename the fireball impact.
So it's very clear that this is the the prefab parent if you will of the other variants that come underneath
it.
But for now I'm comfortable that this is differentiated enough.
I think we need to do is go to projectile and put this in a namespace.
I've totally forgotten to do that so I'm going to highlight everything in here.
Cut the top name space and it will be namespace RPG dot.
What are we in here in combat and then paste all that inside.
Excellent day.
Save that up.
We also need to do the same thing for what do we create.
Recently that I didn't namespace under the core.
We have destroy after effect story after effects.
Let's highlight everything in here.
Boink cut all that name space and the name space is going to be RPG dot core core core.
It's what you say when you're really impressed with something in Australia.
Cool.
Check that out.
Okay so that's all looking pretty good.
So let's just do one last quick run through.
Make sure everything's working as it should before I declare all my bugs and all my tidy ups done.
Grab this thing shoot that guy firewall works kaboom.
Well I've got one last thing that I keep forgetting to do.
Thank you for Sam pointing this out to me.
Rick what were you thinking.
Can you guys.
But here's a little sleuthing moment for you.
See if you have the powerful brain that Sam patootie has.
What is wrong with this moment.
Just here OK.
What is wrong is we've got this guy thrown left handed left handed throw is a tricky enough as it is
but the fireballs coming out of his right hand.
Well done Rick.
You're using your brain there so fireball click on the fireball scriptural object and turn off is right
handed.
This is why we do our quality assurance testing this is why QE test is in the industry super valuable
look.
Now it's actually coming out of the right spot.
Well done.
Who.
That looks okay.
We'll pick up the bow.
We'll let them shoot at me.
Pam's crunch crunch.
I'll shoot at them and due to success OK.
I can't see any issues here now.
I'm sure there are some.
If you've found anything else please let me know in the comments and Sam or I will come in and do some
extra bug fixes these things often don't come up until later on but hopefully we've found everything.
Hopefully your game is looking awesome please do share the latest screenshot latest video in our comments.
We'd love to see where you're at with your game and I'll see you in an upcoming lecture.