Welcome this lecture we're gonna be fixing another race condition that could happen if you move between
your portals very quickly and you have a particularly large large fade wait time.
So let's dive in and see what that bug is and how we can fix it.
So there is still a potential race condition in the portal script.
Now if we go and have a look at it the issue that we had here was essentially that at the same time
we could have two co routines being called and that wasn't a very good idea.
Now if I open up the portal C.S. script then what we're going to see in that script is there are lots
of opportunities for two transitions to be going on at the same time.
Let's have a look.
Now basically whenever you're evaluating current scenes for potential race conditions you only have
to look at the yield return statements because these are the only places where something else could
be happening because the execution control from this transition function is being handed over back to
unity.
So in this first yield return the fader fades out.
Could anything else happen in this time.
Well yes potentially what could be happening here is that while we're fading out and before we saved
or loaded the level our player could move away and go into a different portal instead.
And then that could trigger another transition that's going to be racing with this transition to load
a different scene.
Obviously we don't want that sort of thing to happen.
Let's see.
Let's evaluate some more of these yield returns.
So the loading async there's not really much that could be happening while the scene is loadings.
That's probably quite safe.
This yield return new wait for seconds.
Well while we're waiting for that time we loaded up the new level we've saved it.
We're now waiting and we could potentially go back into the portal at this stage and that would trigger
another transition while that portal is still around.
Remember this portal has not yet been destroyed so that could potentially lead us to having some issues
as well.
That's not something that we want.
So how do we prevent that source stuff and let's see what does this actually happen.
Is this something that I'm just inventing.
Well one way that we can exacerbate the issue is if you open up the portal prefab and change it our
fade out we're going to put back down to about Point five.
But our wait time we can put up to ten seconds.
And because that's going to wait with a completely white screen I'm also going to make a little tweak
to our Fader script where instead of fading out to one alpha we're going to make it slightly transparent
of point five.
So we can still see what we're doing in here and can make that point five F because it wants a float.
So let's try this out.
If I hit play what I'm expecting to see is the following I try and go through a portal.
And while it's waiting with this alpha I go back through the portal.
Okay.
Nothing's happened there but what if I go back again then I am transported into some weird location.
Now I'm hypothesizing that this is because of a portal still being alive that should not have been there
any more so when it is going to try and find its corresponding destination portal it's actually finding
a portal that should have been destroyed.
And so it is putting us in a weird location so we can delete my safe folks that save files now Borked.
As a result of that.
But what should the fix for this kind of thing be.
Well really what should be happening is that while we're going through that portal transition the player
should not have control and shouldn't be able to get themselves in this mess in the first place.
So my challenge to you is to remove control from the player.
Now let's talk about where that should happen.
We should remove the control straight after we trigger this portal.
So before any of the yield returns.
So this is the first you'll return this fade out.
Remember we said while it's fading out we could go into a different portal so we want to remove control
here and then remember that once we load a new scene there is going to be a new player in that scene.
We want to remove control from that player straight away as soon as that scene is located.
We want to remove control from that new player.
And finally when do we want to restore that control.
Well we only want to restore that control just before we destroy this portal again.
It's fine if we restore it here because that last yield return is already done so we couldn't be running
any other code in between this restoring control so restore control can happen here.
Now that is because again there is no code can run between these two lines because we haven't got a
yield return.
So Paul's video and have a go at seeing if you can remove and restore control.
And remember that we have done this before in the cinematic control remove supposed video and have a
go okay.
Welcome back.
So the way we're going to do this is actually I'm gonna go and have a look at how we do it in the cinematic
control remover.
So I've got it here.
And first of all we're getting the plant by tag.
Yes that sounds like a sensible thing to do.
And we are then getting hold of the player controller component.
So let's do that.
Let's first of all get hold of the player then do a get components where we're getting the player control
oh we don't have access to the play controller yet.
So we're gonna have to add a namespace.
Is that a sensible thing to do.
Always remember to ask yourself is it sensible to have this scene management depend on the control namespace
which is what we're gonna have to include.
I think it is.
I think it's quite reasonable I don't think the control namespace depends on scene management so there's
no circular dependencies there.
We're going to store this player controller and I'm going to store it as a variable called a player
controller locally
like so.
And then this player controller we can remove control from it by doing play controller enabled equals
false.
So there is no control possible at this stage.
Now what we're going to do is we're going to have to remove control again after loading the scene.
Remember that you have to find the player again because it's a new player in a new scene so I'm going
to actually name this new player controller in here just to make things super clear with disabling control
and then and without a last comment.
This restore control.
We are just going to go to play a controller enabled equals true so that the control is returned to
the player once we have gone through our different fades.
So what I would expect to see now is if we go ahead and hit play and then we go through our portal I
expect to see that I can't move until this fade out has completely happened.
Takes 10 seconds and then if I go back through it's not giving me any issues whatsoever.
Okay so now the only thing left to do is restore things to how they were before.
So let's go to our portal and let's just restore this component reset the components to its originals
or maybe not everything to its original so let's set some sensible times.
The wait time I think we were saying well let's see what we had as our defaults in the portal C.S. our
fade in time is going to be about 2 seconds the wait time is going to be about point five and that should
be okay for the portal.
Next we want to make sure that our Fader code is fading out completely so fade to 1 and let's just check
that everything is working as we'd expect.
So come into the world and then we go between portals it fades out and it fades as back in over the
course of two seconds and until that fade is complete.
We are not able to do anything which I think is better means we can't get ourselves into any problems.
In fact there is one thing that I find slightly annoying about moving between scenes now is that that
fade out time is quite long and does prevent us from moving for a bit too long.
So what I'm gonna want to do instead is instead of yield return and waiting for the fade in.
I want to re enable control immediately and or rather just fade in and relinquish control and let the
CO routine run in the background.
Now in order to do that we need to change the way these co routine functions work.
Instead of returning an AI numerator we want them to return a CO routine directly.
And basically we can still yield return that car routine and other coatings.
Which basically means that we wait for that car routine to finish but it will now just run independently
without having to be yield returned.
It doesn't have to be yield return but if it is it will wait.
That means we need to change the return types of all of these fades so they return a car routine and
then crucially we are changing this yield return to a simple return of the currently active fade car
routine and that is what makes the difference is because now we're not yield returning here.
We don't actually have to yield return the whole function in order to get to this statement.
Now this statement just runs it returns a car routine that has been started in here.
And then if we yield return it great.
If we don't yield return it will go on running.
So that means that we can now remove the yield return from our Fader dot fade in and then it will go
subsequently on straight away.
As soon as it is started that currency and it's going to go on and enable control which means it will
be able to get control back immediately.
So let's go ahead and try that.
If we move between worlds now it's still fading but we can move around and because of the protection
we put in place on the fade it doesn't matter if we start another fade a while that fade out still happening
it just cancels the fader and does a fade up and fade down just as we would expect.
So I think that's just a little bit neater.
Great stuff.
So in this lecture we have figured out how we can stop these portals racing against each other and how
we need to be careful sometimes when we have yield returns because these are opportunities for other
code to be running so we need to think about what could happen in those yield return pauses and whether
that could conflict with what we are trying to do.
Awesome stuff.
I'll see you in the next lecture.