Hello again in this video.
We're going to fix an issue that I mentioned previously that I think is a bit broken when we kill an
enemy.
You can see that is capsule colliders sticking around if I get in a position where that capsule collider
is in front of another enemy if I'm clicking there I can actually click through to get to the other
enemy.
So that's something that's going to cause a bunch of issues and frustration for the player when they're
getting there saying why can't I click on a guy.
So let's fix that.
And what I'm going to do is give this to as a big advanced challenge right from the get go.
So our goal is to ensure recast is not blocked by the dead enemy.
And here are some hints in terms of what you can do so within the fight I don't see a script create
a can attack method that returns true if the target is valid and the target is not dead.
So that's the can attack that we want to do before we attack we want to say can we attack and then remember
that the health component is the place that knows if something is dead when we're looking here and saying
is the target dead or not.
Then there is a way for us to return whether the target is dead or not.
And that's in the health component and in the player controller script.
We need to check if can attack returns falls.
Then we continue in our cast.
Hit for each loop.
OK.
So there's some explanation if that doesn't quite make sense or it seems to advance.
No worries we'll go through it together.
But give it your best shot.
Again it's another one of those logic ones get in there.
Have a look at your code.
This is the end of the section.
So this is a good chance for you to really show that you understand your code and how it's working at
the moment.
So take that on I'll see you back here in a moment OK.
So I'm going to open up Visual Studio code I'm looking in the fighter dot CSI and play a controller.
They'll be my two scripts for this video.
Physical in fighter.
I'm going to create.
Down down just above.
Attack on a.
Create a new method which will be public.
And I want to return a ball and we'll call it can attack and in here we are passing in combat.
Target.
Combat target and we'll call this combat target.
Combat.
Target combat target.
And as I mentioned this is something we'll be calling in play a controller which we'll get to in a moment.
So now curly braces here.
First of all I want to get the health component.
I'm going to store this as a variable so health target to to test.
So I've type health and we'll call this target to test.
It's going to equal combat.
Target.
Get component what component we're getting here while we're getting the health component parentheses
semicolon.
Okay.
Now that we've got the health component what can we do.
Well this is where we're going to return.
We need to return true or false what are we on return here.
Well we will return target to test is not equal to now.
Sorry if targeted test is not now and the target is not dead.
So we'll say not in here first of all not exclamation mark.
Target to test don't.
Now what's the method that lets us return whether something's dead or not he's dead.
Parentheses and semicolon.
So save that and head over into our player control of scripts and we're looking at the behavior within
our for each loop.
Yes this is our ray cost hit and we're saying cycle through.
So with an hour for each go through all of the things that we're hitting with our ray cost and when
I think I'll do is instead of checking if the target is null here I'm going to take if the target is
noticed back over to our fighter script when check it.
The target is null.
Within 10 attack I think that's a better place for it.
Second delete if Target is no continue and create.
If we want to say if we can't attack.
So if not sorry.
Exclamation mark get component fighter.
Because this is within our fighter script that we've just fought a class we've just created this parentheses
dot can attack and we're interested in target which is our combat target just in the line above.
So if not so in other words if we can't attack then what do we do.
Well Kelly braces we say continue continues one of those confusing things takes me a while sometimes.
Continue doesn't mean continue on down the page continue means continue within our for each loop so
go to the next hit.
So now though as if the can attack is returning false then go on to the next thing and I mentioned I
was taking out my null check.
I'm going to go back over my fighter script within here within can attack the very first thing I'm doing
here is just add an if statement if combat target that's its combat target that's being passed in equals
equals no.
So if it's now then return false.
And is pretty in couple of spaces in here because that's my preference for my curly braces.
So now play a controller we're saying.
If not so in other words if it's returning false for can attack then we continue.
In other words don't try to do anything with it.
What are we doing in our.
We're saying if the combat target is no then return false.
If it's the terrain or something else we've clicked on and then we're looking at the health component
and within that we're saying let us know.
Is this character if we've clicked on a character.
Is it dead.
If it's dead return false returning false in play a controller is going to continue through our for
each loop and not go into the other actions that we could take in terms of attacking that particular
enemy.
Okay so before we celebrate too much let's save all these up and jump back over into unity.
Make sure that we're not getting the issue that we had before might just reposition that guy a little
bit because he wasn't perfect in his demonstration before put you just there get rid of the game give
him a couple of smacks in the midriff and then can I still click.
You can see that I clicked just in the bit that the collider was in front of and he's hitting cool great.
No problems at all.
OK.
That's fixed one more thing that I thought was either broken or distracting when nearly done with this
section.
I will see you in the next video.