Hello and welcome in this video.
We're going to be making our pickups response so if I pick up the five flower pick up the sword and
regret my decision.
Then in five seconds the Firefly will come back and I can re-equip that one instead let's dive in and
see how to do this responding so as we said at the end of last lecture The problem with our pickups
is that they get destroyed after you pick them up.
And because we don't have any inventory management system.
If you pick up a different pick up you can't go back and re-equip the sword.
So what I'd like to do is to have a pickup responding process so instead of destroying what we're going
to do is create a car routine and it's going to be a private eye innumerate car routine and it is going
to return.
What's it going to be.
It's going to be basically something like hide for seconds and it's going to take the float of how many
seconds it should hide for now.
This is just we're going to call this basically in on trigger enter.
So when do we equip the weapon we're going to start co routine for the hide for seconds of how many
seconds.
Well that is going to be so we can make it configurable so it's going to be a serialized ball field
float respawn time and I'm going to start off with 10 seconds as the default in fact make it five for
now just make it easy to test and that's what we're gonna pass into our hide for second.
So at the top level hands it read on trigger enter if it's a player equip the weapon to the player and
then start the car routine hide for seconds of the respawn time.
So this is where we now want to go ahead basically and do the following.
So we're going to hide pick up then we are going to do a yield return new wait for seconds
and we're gonna wait for the seconds given and then we're going to show the pickup now.
How are we going to show and hide the pickup.
Now you might be tempted to disable the pickup so we've got our pick up under this folder.
You might be tempted to say hey let's just disable the game object.
Well that would be great if it didn't stop the car routine from running which is not ideal.
So instead what I would like to do is disable the sphere collider so that we can't trigger it again
and also disable its children.
So you go through each of the children of the sword while driving your pickup is in our case.
That is what the prefab that shows us the sword and just disable that instead.
So the pickup body is still there that route.
Game object will still be there but all of its children will be disabled and its sphere collide it will
be disabled and that's going to be the trick to disabling our pickup so this is going to be your challenge
to disable the pickup.
So first of all you're going to disable the collider then disable the child's game objects remember
that you can do a for each loop over transforms so that you can get all the children of the current
transform.
That's one way of doing this.
You can Google it a little bit if you're not sure how to get all your child game objects and you're
going to rename them all.
Now before I tell you to pause I would like to say that.
Remember there's a slight difference between disabling a game object so you can do a game object dot
set active and you can set that to false.
For example that's how you disable game objects whereas a component such as this weapon pickup for example
you need to do enabled equals false and that's slightly different.
So there's there's two different ways for a component and disabling a game object itself so pose video
and how to go at this challenge okay.
Welcome back.
So let's go ahead and implement our Hyde pick up and our show pick up as well and in Hyde pick up.
The first thing we can do is do a get components our type collider and we're going to do enabled equals
false.
Simple as that.
And I'm actually going to do show pickup and high pickup has one thing because I think this can make
it nice and easy.
So we're going to have this renamed to show pickup taking a boolean should show and this can be set
to false.
So if it shouldn't show then we should it should if it should show it's enabled if it shouldn't and
it's disabled.
And similarly so now we can call this show pickup is going to be true at the end but we're going to
do show pickup false at the beginning like that.
So now it kind of makes sense and then we want to go through all of the children.
Now one way you could have done this is to do a transform dot get child and then you can get the child
indexed you get the zero child for example to start off with and you could get the game object associated
with this transform and then you could set it active too well depending on whether you should show or
shouldn't show we are going to use this should show boolean.
So that's one way of doing it but that if he had more transforms then this wouldn't necessarily work
he wouldn't disable all of them.
So I'm gonna do a for each loop over transforms so that type is gonna be transform we're going to have
this child in the transform our own transform.
So if you do it like this transform child and transform Guess Who will the child transforms of the current
transform and then we can do is child dot and then the game object set active as we've done here and
that should pretty much do the trick.
So let's go ahead and see whether this is working now I'm going gonna go ahead and play and go over
to our pickups in the other world avoid this enemy.
So I'm going to step on the fire flower and you notice that has now gone and we wait around for five
seconds and it comes back.
So all of these should now be doing the same thing.
So if I accidentally picked up the bow but actually should wanted the fire flower then I can go and
get it in five seconds time.
So that just hides that issue that we currently have of not having an inventory system we can kind of
how our inventory system in the world for now until we've implemented it.
So to review what we have done is we have started a code routine when we pick up a weapon that hides
the weapon pickup for a few seconds.
It calls this show pickup method which does two things disables the collider and disables all the child
game objects doesn't disable this game object because otherwise the code routine would fail to run.
Cool stuff I'll see you in the next video.