Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We're gonna be bringing in a game dev utilize namespace package that I have produced with a library
class called lazy value we're going to see how to use this lazy value and how it can save us lots of
code and lots of heartache when dealing with things that need to be initialized a little bit later than
awake and needs to talk to other classes.
Let's dive in and see how it's used so in this video we're mostly going to be making use of an asset
that I've produced called The Lazy value.
Now this is an asset pack for you is a script but we're just going to be using it like any library as
we would a using a unity class or using a C sharp class.
So don't worry about the implementation details unless you really want to.
I'm just gonna go ahead and import the asset pack you should have it to download and import against
your lecture and the idea of the lazy value class is that it works as a container for those values that
we don't want to initialize in awake but we want to be safe to access.
Basically they'll be initialized when we first use them.
So let me show you an example of how the lazy value script gets used.
So we'll go into our health components and we want to protect say our health points.
We want to say okay.
So this is being initialized in start.
And it might be possible that it gets queried outside.
What if we ask for Get Health points in Start for example in the display script.
Who knows maybe we want to choose to do that in the future and we should basically based on our guidelines
make sure that everything is available in start all our state should be fully initialized or at least
safe to use.
So the lazy value script allows us to do this by wrapping the type so that instead of using a float
here we're going to use a lazy value.
And here we need to include.
So if I just put in a space so it's using the right thing for whatever reason it wasn't giving me the
option to complete that until I put these two chevrons around the float which is how we're going to
need to use it.
There's going to be lazy value Chevron float Chevron and we need to include the namespace game.
Def TV don't utilize.
So this now is a lazy value wrapper or container if you like if you hover over the class you can see
some documentation about it that is a container class that wraps a value and ensures initialization
is called just before first use.
What do we mean by initialization what we mean this bit here to the right of health points where we
get its initial health.
Okay.
So that makes sense we are going to be using it like that.
That means that now at default initialization here isn't going to work because it's a wrapper class.
We actually want to get to the value of this wrap class we have to do health points dot value and as
you can see from the documentation of that it will get or set the contents of the container so we can
use this to get the value out or we can use it to set the value.
But that's not how we're going to use it at least not initially.
So we're not going to do our initialization here in start because that would be a bad idea right.
If we had to wait until start it's initialized it's not safe.
So what we're gonna do is we're going to initialize our lazy value in a week like so and you're saying
Hang on Sam but we don't have the ability to call to base stats in a week and you would be right.
So what we do is we use the very cool feature of the lazy value class where we can say hang on lazy
value we're going to create a new lazy value so new lazy value of type float like this.
And then in the constructor for the lazy value we need to pass it and initialize a and initialize a
delegate.
And we've used delegates before and the context in which we've used them is events but you don't have
to use them as events you can just pass them use them as a way of passing function pointers around as
arguments.
So that's what we're going to do we're going to create a private function that returns float and it's
going to be called get initial health like so as can take no arguments and that is the signature of
this delegate needs to take no arguments and it needs to return float because this is a lazy value of
float type.
If it was of type it would have to return it.
So then all we need to do is take this initial value for our health and base do a return of this.
If I had typed my return correctly that would work better now and get my spaces.
Okay.
So I need a semicolon on the end of that line in a week and what I can now do is pass this delegate
in now note I'm not using parentheses on the end of it because we're not calling the function yet and
that is a crucial thing because in awake we are initializing the lazy value.
So the health points is set to something and is safe to use because of the lazy value will initialize
it before it first gets used but we are not calling get initial health we are just passing it to the
lazy value which will use it when we need to initialize when we need to use it basically.
So now we can go throughout our class in the places that we're using health points and just replace
health points with help points dot value.
So we just add a dollar value on the end here and that goes in and reaches in and gets the value out
and what that's doing is it's basically saying that when we want to get this value we need to make sure
that it is fully initialized and it will call the initialize a if necessary.
Right at this point so that it has its default value.
So now we could call take damage in Start and Even if start hadn't been called in health yet it would
make sure that we had got the correct default value for health points and everything would work as we
expected.
Same thing down in get health points we're going to add a dollar value on the end and that's going to
make sure that if we get health points it will have been initialized and the same thing in percentage
and the same thing in regenerate health and let's see any other places that capture states we need to
make sure it is returning the value rather than the lazy object and the same thing in restore state.
Let's just check that all the locations of using health points is now using the value instead Yep looks
like it is.
Okay.
So that's great.
So if something calls two health points and tries to query health points and start it will get initialized
but there is a opposite case which is the possibility that nothing calls to the health points before
start or during start.
And it's not until some updates way down the line that we actually use health.
And so it gets initialized to its initial value and that might be okay in the case of health but I just
want to show you that one of the features of the lazy value is that you can do health points not force
in it.
So in Start we can do health point stop force in it and this will mean basically if at this point we
haven't already accessed health and caused it to initialize we will do it now we'll do it now and start
and make sure we take a snapshot of the health points right now at this point.
Now this isn't so important for health but for some of the other classes that you're going to use it
in.
It might well be very important.
So let's just have a look at other things that are still using start and might still be initializing
some state in start.
So we've got our fighter class.
Yes that's initializing a weapon that could be dangerous.
So we're going to leave that one tab open for something that we want to work on the projectile.
I'm not worried about setting the transform the A.I. controller yet the guard position that could be
potentially a problem again.
The mover has nothing and starts I'm going to actually remove it start altogether.
We have got health which we have already updated and base stats which has got current level which is
currently guarded against.
But couldn't we do that neater if we were using than you lazy value.
So these are the scripts that I want you to update we've done health but I want you to update the current
level in base stats.
The fighters current weapon the air controllers guard position and the move up we said we don't care
about.
So these three classes is your challenge to go ahead and implement a lazy value for the state that they
are initializing in start posting a video and have a go okay.
Welcome back.
So let's just repeat rinse and repeat the process from before current level is an int.
So we're gonna be doing a lazy value of the int type this time and we're gonna have to include the right
game to utilize.
And then what we're gonna do is in a week we're going to be setting up our current level equal to the
lazy value.
So new lazy value.
And then we need to go ahead and put in a delegates in here.
Now actually you can just put in the calculate level because calculate level already is something that
returns int and takes no values.
It basically calculates the level exactly as we'd want it to do.
But now we're just gonna do it the first time it's called.
And then in start we want to make sure that that level has been calculated so we're gonna get a force
in it.
And everywhere else where we've got the current level we can do just a top value on the end.
So in here and update level we'll do it value current level values.
Not too many dots that go.
And then where else have we got current level.
Got it down here and get level now notice we can simplify this away because we no longer need to check
whether current level is set up.
We can just go ahead and access the value.
We can do current level DOT value and we know that that will initialize it if it wasn't already initialized.
So that's simplified our code.
Lovely.
I love it when we get simplify code and that's it.
I think we have basically got everything else the current level is not used.
So we've updated everything to the value and the only thing is we don't set an initial value for the
current level because it didn't have one.
It just gets that lazy initialization.
Now I'm gonna go ahead and quickly repeat the process for both fighter and a on a controller.
Now you notice what I'm gonna be doing here is just stripping out the bit that sets the current weapon
and making that a separate method.
So this is going to be the one that I'm going to call attach weapon like so and so then attach weapon
I'm going to call up in the set default weapon and the weapon I'm going to attach is the default weapon.
And I'm just going to return that default weapon.
So now it's vitally important that I call the current weapon dot force in it because otherwise we're
not gonna have a weapon in our hand.
So this is the case that I was talking about very important that we do a force in an instant because
otherwise we won't have a weapon visible when we start the game.
Let's go ahead and look for all the values
so that's the fighter converted over.
Let's now have a look at the A.I. controller and do the same thing for the guard position
and then we go.
Everything has been updated to the lazy value and we can be safe in the knowledge that nothing is being
done in our stop methods so that everything basically is ready to go after we have had a wake.
Once we get to start everything is ready to be called all our methods on our safe array.