Hello again my friend it's been a while.
You've been hanging out with Sam what a great job he's been doing.
Let's give it up for Sam round of applause Thank you Sam for all of your hard work and all of your awesomeness.
What we're gonna do now we're nearly finished we're nearly finished polishing where we are with our
particular part of the game with our core combat and what I want to make sure is that you've got something
that really sparkles so that if you're showing it to people if this is a demo to say hey do you want
to work on this game you want to give me some money for this game I want to do a kickstarter for this
game whatever it is you've got it to the point where it's not looking like a tech demo so listen to
me loud and clear on this if you're a programmer and you want people to pay attention to your game it
can't look like you slept together haphazardly it needs to have a little bit of polish so I'm recommending
spending an hour or two doesn't have to take a long time to do it and polished your game and what I'm
gonna do for my game is a little bit of an audit where I'm going to grab a screenshot that allow me
just have a look at it and say What do I need to do here.
So it doesn't look so place hollering OKAY.
SO WHAT I'M GONNA DO IN HERE I'VE lining out as I've been told I've been lining this up so I get most
of my moment in here you don't have to get your entire level if it's huge but you get something that
is indicative of yet.
That is my game that's my level.
And what I'm going to do I'm on windows I'm doing Windows key W and I've got this snip and sketch you
can do a screenshot.
There's a million ways to get a screenshot.
You want to get to the point where you can sketch over the top of your image here so you can make some
notes.
And it's entirely up to you how much effort you do wrong button how much you do or don't put in at this
stage.
Totally up to you.
You might say Rick I don't care for that stuff.
That is totally fine.
So first thing to note for me is all my trees.
Trees are very same me.
So what I mean by Samy is they all look the same don't they.
So say me I need to get some variation in there some variety I can't just have the one tree asset over
and over and that's a similar thing with my houses in here.
I think my houses look very bland so I need to find some assets switch them out.
I can't have the same house house house exactly the same.
That was just place holder.
Also there's a lack of consistency.
These two look different which you know we're just using a an asset pack as a free asset pack.
That was awesome but they look like they belong in different worlds and this is one of the things that
you'll find people on forums will be very upset with you or if you launch your game if you have things
that don't look like they belong in the same world.
Often that happens with a character doesn't look like it's in the same world as a as a building or a
tree and environment.
Okay.
I think my water needs a little bit of love.
It's looking not very good at all and that and is are supposed to be bridges so I'm going to need a
bridge asset.
I think that's very important.
I also need to create some sort of story some sort of moment with my environment and I'm not gonna go
in massive detail at this point we're not at that stage of this entire journey that's going to be for
other parts of this entire series where we're talking more about level design or talking a lot more
about set dressing.
But I do need a little bit of what I'm going to call set dressing what I mean by that is imagine you're
in a theater in the theater and you are wanting to show this is a particular medieval theme or it's
where it where on a spaceship or whatever it is you need some props you need some things so I've got
a blockade at the front here so I need some things that say I'm a blockade at the moment I've got what
two crates.
That doesn't really say on a blockade.
So I need props need props to bootstrap my world.
The other thing a couple of things is my my path is very flat and this is something I see a lot when
people are putting together their prototype level is they have a very flat journey for the player.
Maybe some hills on the side.
We do have some undulations on our journey some ups and downs maybe not quite so Loch Ness Monster as
I've drawn it here.
Hello.
Not quite yet but we do need to have the playoffs have some elevation and run down something run above
something so it's not just flat the whole way.
It feels very very basic feels like input that much effort in when the whole thing is just flat.
So I want to put in a little bit of elevation.
Also we need to have some foliage foliage.
Personally I think this makes a huge difference to some grass like let's put some grass around our trees
so that our game isn't just a big flat round playing with these textures.
These look good.
These textures here you can see the green and the brand that looks good underneath something.
But if it's just that doesn't look so good in my opinion.
Okay so I've done my audit let me just make a note here.
Props is one thing.
Bland houses.
I needed a little bit with my houses.
I think this is also number two.
This is also part of the houses the town 3 so trees Samy.
That's a 3.
What else I need here for I needed a little bit of elevation in there.
5 I need some foliage.
This is not actually the order I'll do it in it's just me making a note at bridges.
There's one down there as well so make this a six four bridges and set dressing that seven.
Put some stuff throughout town.
You know if you feel this is a final level you'll have a new game then you can really put a lot of love.
A lot of effort a lot of work into it.
Little lanterns hanging off the buildings a little fire pit in the middle of town.
But for me I'm going to put in a medium amount of effort to make it look better than it does now but
not necessarily final.
And what I'll do is I'll show you a little bit of how I'm going about doing that but a lot of the things
you know already in terms of how to do this.
So I'm going to skip through it pretty quickly.
Just so you can see what I'm up to maybe get a little bit of inspiration for your own game and your
own level and your own process.
So great work and I'll see in the next video.