Hello again my friend in this video we're gonna use Unity's nav mesh system.
You can see the blue stuff there to have our player move to a target in our scene.
So let's jump in and get started soon we'll set out the functionality where we click to move our player.
But for now we're going to make it a little bit automated and to do that we'll have a target that we
just make our player walk towards.
So in my scene I'm going to create a new object 3D object.
Make this a sphere and we'll call it Target.
Here we go.
Target.
I'm going to move just away from the player some way doesn't really matter have it down at ground level
so there's no issues that make you a little bit bigger so we can see it nice and easily.
There we go.
Looks fine.
OK.
Next up we want to just make sure that our camera is going to see the action at the moment if we look
through our camera or is it main camera you can see our view put down here it's looking at now and I
what the ground or something.
If while I'm selected on my camera I move it around you can see that update.
There's my play I just there the camera is pointing at the player.
So what I'll do is get my scene view in a spot where I like it so I'm in the scene tab.
Just move around a little bit.
That's where I can see most the action go on.
And then while the main camera is selected got the game object and align with view means that the camera
will be moved so that we see exactly what I see in my scene view here.
So when I rotate around a little bit you can see that my camera's now being moved to that spot where
I was looking at just a second ago.
This is what we see in our camera when we click play on the game.
OK.
Now for the most important part of this video we need a nav mesh so go to window find a I and open up
navigation in here we've got four tabs mostly we're going to focus on the bike tab for the moment and
if we have a look in our scene look at your terrain and your buildings and stuff.
When you click the bike tab take a moment and then a lot of the place turns blue this blue stuff is
our navigation mesh.
This is where our navigation agent is going to walk and say I can walk here and walk here I'm not walk
there and you can see I'll explain this in the next video we'll go into a little bit more depth on how
to fine tune and control and what's going on but you can see here there's this line around my building
that says well the player can't walk through there there's no navigation mesh so we're not going about
a walk into that particular area.
Similarly we can't walk on the side of the mountains because there is no navigation mesh there.
So this is a way for the player to say Okay where can I go I can walk anywhere on the blue I have to
avoid spots where there is no blue.
And for this particular lecture we're going to say let's just walk from here to the target point on
the map at any point in time you can just click rebate again so if I clear it all goes away.
And then there is no navigation mesh at the moment if I click bike then it just rebates it again.
And as we tweak and tune stuff in the next video you'll see that slight changes take place in our navigation
mesh.
The other thing we need to do is click on our player.
Back to inspect.
Make sure you not so accidentally clicked on the navigation tab.
And we're going to add a new component so click on Add component and type in nav mesh.
Agent C.C. nav mesh agent click to add that nav mesh agent has a bunch of different cool stuff speed
angular speed acceleration etc..
This is what's driving the game object that the nav mesh agent has been placed on.
So we now have our player with a nav mesh agent that's going to move it and it's going to move it where
you guessed it it's going to move it along the nav mesh and we're going to do that as a challenge.
And this is a challenge where I think if you know this stuff then it should be a good meaty challenge.
If you don't know this stuff I'm going to give you a couple of hints.
So they should be out of figured out.
So what I'd like you to do is create a mover dot see script and attach that to the player and then to
serialize within this script serialize a transform target variable that we can assign our target game
object to and then within the Update method you can have one line where we want to get the nav mesh
agent component so get component and set its dot destination value as the target's current position.
Okay.
So if you're feeling a little bit advanced that's the challenge.
That's a good intermediate challenge for an intermediate course.
Starting off with something meaty hopefully.
But if you look at that and say I've got no idea.
Not a problem.
Here are the hints.
So if that's enough jump in take on that challenge if you want the hints here they are the hints are
the target is currently at Target dot position and we use get component nav mesh agent dot destination.
So basically you're assigning the value of target position to the nav mesh agent's destination.
And just as one last clue you may need to add the unity dot a I namespace.
Okay.
Sorry.
There's enough clues in there that you should be out to piece it together pretty straightforwardly.
If not no worries we'll go through it together.
But give it your best shot.
As if you've not been through courses before.
The most important part of our courses is taking on the challenge.
So I implore you whether you think this is really easy or really difficult.
Jump in nonetheless.
Give it your best shot.
And once you have given it your best shot really thought about it.
I'll see you back here and I'll show you my solution okay.
So I think this is a pretty straightforward script to create.
I will start off by giving myself a script photo to keep ourselves nice and neat so create folder scripts
and within my scripts folder I will right click Create C sharp script and call this mover okay mover
while I'm here.
I often forget this step and I feel dumb afterwards I'm going to attach it to grab it and drag it over
onto player so that now is a move a component on the player.
Great double click.
Open up move it this will be our first real time in visual studio code.
Okay.
And you can see how warnings come up again about dot net core debugging.
This is not something we need to worry about so I'm going to x out of this dialogue go over to the settings
which is in the bottom left corner you see the code there click on that scroll up to the settings and
from here while clicked on the settings Tab I'm going to search for C L I that will show me under extensions.
So here on the left hander extensions C sharp configuration click on that and then suppress dot net
install warnings so click the checkbox there and our warning should be never more again seen.
Okay.
Closed the settings tab and then back over to move to get rid of the start method just leaving update
and at the start of our class I'm going to serialize field serialize field and this will be of type
transform.
This will be called target and then within our update pretty straight forward we're going to say get
component and then in our angle braces it's the nav mesh agent we're getting parentheses dot destination
and that equals what it equals target dot position so it's basically saying change the destination for
the nav mesh agent to the target position.
Now we're getting a red squiggly line.
What's that mean.
Well usually it means we're missing a namespace that's mouse over it could not be found yet.
So up the top here we're using Unity engine and I know this song is going to be dot a I semicolon.
And then our squiggly line is gone.
Save this up.
Back over into unity.
Now we have on our player just checked that we did a sign that I think I even made mention that I often
forgot.
Yep.
So a mover is a component on their call.
Now we find the target we assign our target bop bop bop bop down into our Target Field.
That means the player should walk to our target.
We've set up our camera.
Yes there it is.
Oh some nice shadows and everything click on play and there we go walking from a to b point.
Excellent.
That's the foundations that's the fundamentals of using the nav mesh and applying an F mesh agent to
move from a certain point to another point in the next video.
We're going to get a little bit more complicated and just play around with obstacles with static and
to look at the different variations we can have without nav mesh training so great work in this video.
And I'll see you on the next video.