Hello again another visual Polish video.
This is where my level is right now.
And this is what my level is going to look like by the end of this video.
Now I'm going to be importing some assets all be using as we've done in the past.
I'll be using assets from Sony Studios for example this lovely Knights pack.
I encourage you to check them out.
It's are amazing so many packs now as dozens of them.
Just one thing I want to point out is that I'm bringing these assets into my level so that it can look
good at the end of the course he has it all looks nice and shiny.
But these are assets that you do not have access to use yourself.
You need to buy them if you want to use them.
So I'm not going to be providing these for you these Sinti assets these ones that I'm buying myself
and using because I have the license for.
So you might want to go and grab yourself some more assets you might want to make your own assets whatever
it is how you're going to approach it.
This is a good time to fill up your world with a lot of excitement as I did before.
I'm going to be starting playing around importing things moving things around.
And if there's anything that I think would be useful for you from a learning point of view I'll stop
my process and record and just take you through what I'm doing at that point in time.
For now it's going to focus on buildings and props and probably some trees as well.
Not sure about that yet but I'm gonna jump in and get started and I recommend and I have a challenge
for you that you do the same as well with your level.
Okay.
See you again shortly.
Hello again.
As you can see I've been making progress putting down some windmills and water mills and this is an
in just trying to stylized things a little bit a little bit of a stone path trying to create a little
bit of story for the player so he's a stone path leads up to this abandoned I guess ancient castle up
the back here and just generally trying to give it more flavor and more substance to my level.
One thing I wanted to show you in terms of a problem I've got here I wanted to make a little bit of
farm kind of action is the player was running into the level and I'll show you what the problem is at
the moment here.
Ignore the fact that there's some smoke coming out of my chimney we'll talk about that later on.
Oh the player might want to come up here and find something.
Maybe this is later on where we can put a quest giver that says hey there's some soldiers in town but
the problem I've got can you see it as this great big gaping hole that we've got on the side of our
train now I've deliberately tried to keep my terrain as small as possible because there's no point having
massive terrain if our level doesn't require it.
But what can we do in this instance.
Well several unity in more recent versions have has given us a tool if we click on terrain then go to
the the pike terrain brush.
The very first one create neighbor terrains is how we can solve this.
Once we've clicked on that it says our click the edge to create neighbor terrain which is pretty easy
just find the edge that I want over here click and that will give me a whole new terrain over on the
side.
Now I just ignore all this stuff down here this is me just grabbing assets and chucking them around
my scene because I tend to be like oh I want to grab that thing and put it in.
So this is kind of my palette to the side is how I work but the terrain here I don't need it to be that
massive.
All I want to do is just make sure that the player can't see underneath here.
So what I'll do from this point is click on the cog make sure I'm clicked on the correct terrain.
It's renamed it terrain underscore.
Whole bunch of stuff.
I'm going to call this terrain underscore south so I know this is the one just down the south.
Now if I scroll down in my settings I'm going to find the width.
I think the width is one I want change that to 200.
Yep that's it.
And it's just made it a lot less a lot less wide.
I guess just move to it on after there.
Now what do we do still got this gap.
The cool thing is when I click on this terrain if I go all the way back up to the top get on the paint
tools I'm going to find the set height.
I'm going to grab the height from the terrain.
That's just next to it.
And then when I come and paint here it will paint my new terrain up to that height so I can make it
all nice and smooth.
It's gonna make my brush size gigantic.
Increase the opacity and then just be like well that's not what I'm sorry.
And then just increase this here just so I can close off the gap.
So plenty of ways to paint that but this is the process where we can make sure that we don't have that
little seam down the middle.
That is just painting the same height cool and it's pretty seem less pardon the pun.
So that's how you can make sure that you don't have those weird gaps or if you say yeah I made my terrain
too small.
That's really easy nowadays to make your terrain much bigger.
So just double check make sure we read back out nav mesh.
But yeah that's cool.
Now we can't see under the world.
And you know what I think I'm pretty happy with the placement of my buildings.
Next up I'm going to concentrate on trees and I'm going to show you a way that I get more variety out
of my assets using trees as an example.
So I've brought in an asset pack into a new project and I've paid it down so I've gone through so I
like which ones don't I like just dragging all of the assets into the scene playing around with them
moving them around and seeing which ones I want.
So here's a subset of assets that I actually do want and I want to add a little bit variation the more
variation we get we can turn like 10 assets to make them feel like they're 100 assets.
I've taken this tree and I've just slightly changed the texture so it's a different color.
Okay.
Let me show you the process that I do for that so grab one of your one of your assets if it's a prefab
then I'm going to duplicate that.
You can see down here we've got the duplicated going to right click and unpack prefab just so it's not
linked to the the original prefab that we had before.
I can read prefab this back in a moment.
But for now I'm just keeping it as a game object that's not prefab.
There's no connection there.
And then in here you can see it's using this particular material to give the colors and you can go into
the material itself and you can you can edit that in Photoshop but an easy way to do it a quick easy
win.
It's not amazing in terms of quality but a quick easy win to get there and say Okay let me fine.
This is the material 0 1 I'm going to duplicate that that's gonna make a material for I'm going to apply
the 0 4 to this game object is going to look exactly the same.
I haven't changed it yet.
And now on this 0 4 material I'm going to find the color.
So just up on albedo color here and let me just change it around.
And this allows me to quickly make a variation.
So just a caveat to this it'll look a little bit weird on some objects it doesn't work for everything
because it's putting a tint over the entire game object.
So if you wanted to keep say the White on these these tree trunks exactly the same and just tint the
leaf area then it's not going to look so good it's not gonna be as easy to do that.
But if you say you know let's just make this all more of a brownie colored object.
Now I have and you sitting right on top of the other one that's what's confused me here I'm like Where
did the original one go to.
But there it is.
So now I've got these two.
They look a little bit different and if I get there and say scale it a little bit rotated a little bit
put it on a little bit of a lean and maybe stretch it round just doing it a direct overall scaling.
So now they're similar trees they look like they belong in the same family but they're different enough
that if the players is kind of running through a level run run run run You can see that there's some
variation in there.
So as you can see in just a few minutes I've made a whole bunch of different trees is grab a tree duplicate
moved to the side grab one of my textures I haven't used already on that particular type of tree dragged
on there we go boom but it is so quick to collect duplicate Blunk kind of and say it duplicate over
there drag on top.
There we go.
Got a new thing and now I'm up to a whole bunch of variety and you can see that looks much better from
a distance than just having them all exactly the same color.
Okay.
When you're ready to export what you need to do is to group all of your objects underneath one game
object grab that game object drag it down into projects that will create a new prefab and from that
prefab right click and go to export package that'll have all of the things you're interested in you
can export that save it somewhere and then re imported into your main project you've been working on
and you'll have all these assets ready to go to drop into you say nicely organized nicely color coded
already you don't have to try to fiddle around and do that within your main scene you can just do that
here in a nice clean easy way without having a full project folder to wrestle with.
So there we go there's a little bit of just creating variation for your game so that you've got a whole
bunch of assets with only having a few starter assets I can back in my main build I'm adding my trees
to my terrain tool here just wanted to show you my process just quickly so you can see what I do.
Edit trees add tree and then I've got my assets down here in my my prefabs then my project folder rather
than clicking and searching and cycling through I find it easier to grab it drag it over into the game
object click on add great edit free add tree grab the next one which is 14 dragon and boom there we
go.
I've just found that's a quick way to do it as opposed to doing it the other way I thought I'd show
you that.
Okay I'll put them all in I'll be back here again in a moment.
Now once you've got all your trees set up you can do this one of two ways you can do the adding or removing
method.
Let me show you the removing method if I click on mass place trees that will place it everywhere on
my terrain probably 10000 to many let's dial this down and say I 300 just to see how it goes click on
place.
Here we go.
That is one busy interesting full kind of town.
I like it.
The great thing about this is it immediately puts all of your your portfolio of trees into the scene.
Now all we need to do with the brush selected so click on one of the trees.
If you hold down shift you can go and remove these trees where whether in the spots where you don't
want them to be.
I really like this method it can speed things up for you particularly if you've got a lot of little
levels going there just whatever.
And then you can go on hand place what that's a bit too many make sure the tree density is where you
want it to be.
Three that you want and put a couple of trees in there.
Cool.
So you can you can do this really quickly I think it speeds things up a lot the other way.
Obviously if I undo all of this if it gives me enough undo this is literally to get them and place them.
I want a couple of trees there maybe reduce the density reduce the brush size and like that particular
tree right there.
That's a good spot for it.
Okay.
So once again I'll pose the video and I'll be back here briefly when I've finished adding trees into
my scene right here as you can see I've placed the trees in my world here I have gone through a major
that the trees aren't blocking the camera anyway that's super important to do and a quick note if you
find that you trees are blackening out off in the background there as you move around then that's because
of the fade length.
If you click on the train then click on the settings button scroll down until you find a fade length
if you move that around you can get it to the position that you like.
I found that a value of about 70 works for mine in terms of the size of my terrain where my camera's
going to be in the game.
In particular when I have my cinematics I want to make sure that my trees aren't being cut off in the
background.
My cinematics because often the camera is down here at ground level so that we go I've got my old macro
things in my scene now my buildings my trees placement of things the path going through town I'm putting
my new costly kind of thing I'm really happy with the layout the vibe the feel of it in the next lecture
I'll get a little bit more micro looking right down at the ground level got to get some grass in there
maybe play around with some little positioning of things just to get the fine tuning done on it now
that I've got the broad tuning done so great work hopefully your level is coming all along well as always
please do share a screenshot of it with us so we can see what you're up to I'd love to see it and I'll
see you in the next lecture.