Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we are going to be implementing agro.
So if I attack an enemy from a distance then they will come and chase me down if I cause them to hemorrhage.
They get angry about it and want to come and hurt me.
So let's dive in and see how we can implement that in the enemy Ali.
So we really want to have a situation where if I try to attack an enemy from a distance with a range
weapon the enemy doesn't just sit there and take the damage we want to have some sort of aggro behavior
as it's commonly called which basically is just code for saying that the enemy enemy gets aggravated
when you attack them and tries to attack you back.
Now the logical place to start looking at this behavior is in the A.I. controllers.
Let's head over to the our controller and usually I always start from the top with classes to try and
review how things go.
I'm going to skip forward a little bit to review from the update method because I think in the update
method it really makes it clear what the A.I. controller is doing now.
This A.I. controller basically either is in an attack behavior a suspicion behavior or a patrol behavior.
And that is based on the current state.
So if it is in range of the player and it can attack said player it will attack by preference.
Otherwise it's going to be suspicious if the time since it last saw the player is less than this configured
suspicion time otherwise it's going to go back to its patrolling behavior.
Now where can we insert some sort of aggro in here now.
I think aggro is basically just an attack behavior.
And that means that we want to configure when we are in and attack behavior we essentially want to say
either I'm in range of the player or I am have been aggravated and I can attack that plan.
Now basically I think that we can do that by changing this method that currently does is in range of
player to saying am I aggravated basically your aggravated in two conditions one you're very close to
the player in which case area like that you're an enemy you want to go and attack them or you have recently
been aggravated by them that could be by the fact that they've attacked you or it could be by the fact
that one of your mates got attacked and are going to deal with that in the next lecture.
But for now we're just going to deal with the case where you yourself have got attacked.
So we are going to create a method a public method that allows us to aggravate an A.I. and we're gonna
call that when we attack the A.I..
So let's try that.
I'm going to put this under updates and I'm going to have a public void aggravate and the context for
this is that I'm going to leave empty for now.
But the context for this is that if I go over to an enemy prefab what I want to be able to do is hook
up the event that we've got from our health component.
So the health components got a take damage event.
I could go and add a new event here drag in an enemy game object and go to the A.I. controller as a
function and slightly aggravate function.
So if we take damage we have been aggravated.
And that means we will start basically replying to this is attacking range as true.
So actually let's rename that as well instead of is attack in range of player.
We can change this too is aggravated like so now of course that's not what it currently does.
So what we need is a timeout because you could have aggravation as a boolean but I'm going to have it
as something that cools down.
So if you are aggravated you aggravates for so many seconds and then eventually it wears off.
So we've done lots of times before.
So actually I want you to go ahead and implement that the behavior that we want.
Is that the aggravate sets the timer and inhere down in our is aggravated we basically check whether
that time has expired yet and if it hasn't expired yet then we are aggravated.
So check aggravated in here.
So post video and have a go at setting up such a timeout in a controller.
And for reference you can have a look at times such as time since the last so plan was video on how
to go okay So time's this last supplier where are we using this.
We are updating it in the times.
We are checking that it's less than the suspicious time an update and we are resetting it in the attack
behavior.
So let's go and add it first of all which is up here on line 29 and line 30 we've got some timers let's
add another float time since aggravated and we are starting off at math f infinity to basically say
the time since we last aggravated is basically never.
So then we want to in app update timers.
We want to make sure that we're adding to this.
So the timer is constantly growing remember that we do growing timers because of floating point numbers.
And then we got and time since aggravated at some point we had to reset it and that is in aggravate.
So at times it's aggravated is zero.
Once you have been aggravated logically then we want to is aggravated we need to do a check here and
basically what we're saying is we either return true because the distance is less than the chase distance
or so boolean or double bar symbol.
Then what we're going to do is that the time since aggravated is less than and this is where we need
to introduce a new configuration variable.
So we've got a suspicion time I'm going to duplicate that to create an aggro cooldown time
and I'm going to have that start off just a bit more than suspicion time at five seconds.
So the aggro cooldown time is what we want to use when we're checking whether we are aggravated or not.
So if the time since aggravated is less than the agro cooldown time then we are aggravated or we're
aggravated if the distance to the player is less than the chase distance.
So let's see if that has our desired behavior and remembering that I have hooked up here already in
the enemy prefab that our take damage calls aggravate.
So that if we damage our enemy he is getting aggravated.
Let's go ahead and hit play and I'm going to pick up the fireball weapon over here to go and attack
one of these enemies so I attack this enemy.
And when he takes damage he starts running towards me to attack me.
But obviously he doesn't make it in time because my fireballs are too powerful for him.
But at least it doesn't look like he's standing there defense and defenseless while I'm trying to attack
him.
Now in the next lecture I would like to achieve is if I attack somebody.
Well this guy over here his mates over here on the right.
Well he should be coming over and attacking me to within a certain radius.
He should be able to notify the Band of Brothers around him that I am in range and that I should be
attacked.
So I'll see you in that lecture to see how it's done.