Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we are going to be designing a mob behavior so that if I have a ranged weapon and I
go and attack one of these guys he's going to bring his mate with him so he'll get aggravated but he
will also bring his mate it won't be in it won't just be him on his own.
Similarly if any of these enemies get alerted such as that Archer can see me from over there he's going
to bring these sword guys with him to making them a much more formidable threat.
Let's dive in and see how we can achieve this kind of mob behaviour so that's kind of behaviour that
I want but how can I alert the guards in my vicinity that I want them to attack as well.
Basically what we'd like to do is say hey all the guards within five metres of me I need to give you
aggro.
They need to get aggravated and try and attack the player as well.
Now that's in order to do that we need to use something called a sphere cast.
So you've come across Ray casts before but sphere casts are a little different.
So a ray cast is quite simply just a laser beam type line that hits the first collider that it goes
through.
And that's quite straightforward and simple.
A sphere cast is probably just as it sounds just a little bit different where instead of taking a a
line a single no volume line we're taking a sphere with a potential radius and we're tracing it through
still a kind of path from the start point to the end point and seeing whether we hit anything on the
way.
So if I was trying to trace from here over to this guy over here I would hit this little guy in the
way in between which I couldn't do with my laser beam because it passed right over his head.
Now there's a few situations WFAA casts can be very useful for example if you wanted to create a grabbing
type component a sphere.
Can be useful in giving you a margin of error.
So instead of having to be pointing directly.
So if I had a grabbing component and I was zoomed in on let's say I'd try and grab maybe this barrel
over here I'd have to be pointing the center of my screen right to point directly through the barrel
in order to grab it.
And if I was slightly off over here then because my laser beam misses the barrel it would not actually
try and grab it but if I did a sphere cast then you'd have a much larger area and a basically a margin
of error.
Anyway that's a little aside because we don't actually need it for that we want to do a sphere cast
in the same way as we're doing Ray casts for movement and so on and so forth to get a bunch of objects
in and when we did it for Ray cast we're doing it down the line of our cursor.
But we might want to do it in a radius around our enemy to find all the enemies within radius.
So that's what we can do.
So let's go over to our attack behaviour and call a method that we have not yet created.
So we're going to call this aggravate nearby enemies and I'm going to go ahead and create that generate
the methods and basic.
This is where we want to do as fair CAS now fear casts work exactly the same as the physics recasts.
So you've got the option to do a physics dot right cast and recast all and all those options that we've
used before or you could do a sphere cast or a sphere cast all in our case.
I want to do a sphere cast all because I want to find all the enemies within a certain radius.
Then let's have a look at what arguments we've got we've got the origin where we want this fear to be
centred on the enemy.
So that's going to transform dot position then we've got the radius.
Well we don't yet know but I'm gonna call this the shout distance and that is going to be a property
that we can do as a serialized field.
So it's going to be a serialized field of type float called shout distance.
We're going to start off at five meters being the default short distance some enemies might be able
to shout louder OK so we've got an aggregate nearby enemies that transform centred on ourselves a radius
of the shout distance.
Now it's asking for the direction now because we're not actually casting this sphere.
It doesn't really make sense to give it a direction what we want to do is just create a sphere that
centers around our play we don't want to then move that sphere in a direction so any direction would
do.
I'm just going to use vector three dot up then the max distance again this can just be zero because
we don't actually want to move this sphere anyway I would just want to do a cast around.
So we're using it in a slightly different way to that which I've showed here on the slide where we're
having the sphere and then we're sending our direction and we're giving it a max direction which might
be all the way over here.
That's not how we're using this sphere cast but we're using in a slightly hacky way then we don't need
to provide the layer mask or anything else them.
And the result as you used to is actually just an array of recast hits.
So we've got recast hit array which I'm going to call the hits so charged to you is going to be to fill
out the rest of this method.
You're going to start off by looping over all of the hits then you are going to try and find any of
those hits that have enemy components.
So basically the enemies surrounding us.
And finally you want to call aggravate on those enemies so that they come and attack the player as well.
Pause the video and have a go at this.
Welcome back.
So first of all the for loop we're going to do a for each.
We're going to.
OK let's use the right expansion shall we.
And it's going to be a for each each element in the for each is going to be a recast hit which I'm gonna
call hit and the collection we are collecting over is hits now in this for each loop we want to find
any enemy components.
So that's going to be a hit dot.
Now it could use either the Collider or the.
Game that was their game object in here.
I think there might be a transform but I'm just going to use the collider.
Any of the components within hit will do.
And then we can do a get component.
That's the goal is to what component do we want to get.
We want to get the enemy A.I..
So it's the A.I. controllers ourselves basically and some but not ourselves but a class the same as
ourselves.
But on a different enemy.
And so what we want to do is take this A.I. controller story in a variable and now obviously there's
the potential that the thing that we hit did not have an AI controller so we need to check that we actually
have one safe AI controller is not no or maybe if it is now then we're just going to continue with the
for loop basically skip this iteration of the for loop.
Otherwise we are going to do a dot aggravates you go so we can call to I don't aggravate and that's
going to aggravate any enemy that is within ASCII cast radius so hopefully that should do the trick.
Let's go over and test it out in game I think I'm not missing any semicolon.
That was an old error.
If I go and hit play and go past this enemy see they both came towards me.
Let's check that that works when I have a ranged weapon as well so I'm going to go and pick up the five
flower in the distance.
Attack this enemy near me and he gets aggravated and brings his mate with me which now makes it much
much harder for me because I was able to kill the first enemy.
But the second enemy has still got some punch.
By the time the high time he arrives and that gets me my health down a little bit.
It also means that if any of the enemies have sights to me like that Archer had cite to me he's gonna
alert his friends with the swords and they're going to come at me as well which I think is basically
about the right sort of thing that we would expect.
We don't want an archer shooting at us and his mates with swords just standing around doing nothing.
They would be running at me as well he'd be saying hey look there's a guy over they should run an attack.
So that is what we've achieved here in this lecture we've now got enemies that when they attack you
also bring their mates with you a kind of mob behaviour.
In fact while we're here dealing with spear castes we can improve our current recasting system.
So at the moment the recasting can be quite finicky sometimes to get it exactly on these tiny little
players when they're off in the distance.
So one way that we could improve that actually is to change the interacts with components recasting
to recast with a sphere instead.
So let's see if there's anything else that would need that.
Well the movement is pretty straightforward.
It's hard to miss the terrain.
We don't generally miss that terrain so that doesn't need it but the components are a little bit more
finicky.
So where we've got recast all sorted.
If we go into recast all sorted you can see we're currently using a recast.
All we can easily just change that to a sphere cast all and Sphere cast all requires one more argument
and just requires the radius.
So let's add a another parameter up here in our player controller which is going to be serialize field
and it is going to be the float Ray cast radius and I'm going to set that to a default of one meter
to start off with.
And that's what we can go ahead and use down here in our recast sorted all.
So it's going to be recast radius and that should do the trick.
So very simply using a sphere cast instead of array cast we are now able if I go ahead and hit play
to have a larger area for attacking the enemy so it's just much easier to target an enemy than it used
to be.
You know you can just click in quite a large radius around them without having any sort of issue.
So that about wraps it up for this lecture.
We'll see you in the next one.