So I just want to show you a quick issue that has been pointed out to me regarding how we deal with
can attack and not being able to move to targets.
Now this doesn't quite work with ranged weapons.
Let me show you how for example let's take this god here.
The one with arranged bow and put him on the bridge.
Let's delete a segment of bridge here and rebuild at nav mesh.
Now what I'm expecting to see is that I could walk up to this bit just before the bridge and shoot at
this guy with a fireball.
Let's try that out.
So if I go ahead hit play I get my fireball from over there and go to the bridge.
And I want to click on this guy and I can not because there is no route to him even though my fireball
could indeed reach him and he is also not attacking me.
So let's fix that quickly the way I'm gonna do that is by saying in this statement that if we cannot
move to and we are not in range of the combat target then we want to drop out and we can't attack but
if we are in range then we can attack.
Just to give us that option so we can attack things that are on an island or separated by a body of
water.
So the way I'm going to do this is I'm going to modify and get it in range.
So that actually takes the target transform in so let's do that.
I'll take a transform call it Target transform like so and we're going to replace the argument in here
where we're using the target that is set on the fighter which means we'll have to change where that
is called up in updates.
So we're going to pass in the target transform in here.
So get is in range target or transform produce and then we are going to call that in that can attack
if statement.
So I'm going to put an ampersand Ampersand to the end here can fix up my inventing a little bit.
Make things a little bit pretty and put my return statement on a separate line now that things are getting
a bit longer here and what we can say is that if the mover can not move to basically and we are not
get is in range of.
And what are we trying to get in range of the combat target that we are querying here.
Combat target transform like so.
So we're not in range of a combat target transform and we can't move to it then we're going to return
false.
Let's see how that affects things.
So let's go and try that out in unity.
I pick up the fireball what I'm expecting is that if I am out of range but can move to somebody like
this God over here then it will move me within range and then launch the fireball if I cannot reach
the rain the person by foot then it will still launch fireball at them.
And as you can see the enemies are also able to attack me in the same way.
So that fixes that little issue of not being able to attack things that we cannot reach with ranged
weapons.
Hopefully that helps.