Hello my friend a huge congratulations you have finished the course vote for all of your hard work.
If you have a look at your game now I think it's looking pretty good.
We've got our core combat feeling really tight we've got the player running around we can shoot we can
bonk people on their head we've got different weapons that we can switch in and out.
Those weapons have different stats.
We've got progression for the player so as you level up your players stats can change.
We have enemies with some clever A.I. in there.
They've got their patrol paths.
If you hit the enemy they aggro towards you their friends see that aggro.
Lots and lots and lots of stuff that we've covered in this course.
You might be wondering what's next.
Well Sam and I are hard at work on prototyping the next part of this RPG series which will be a course
focused at the other things to do with the RPG things such as questing inventory and dialogue and so
on and we'll keep you updated on the progress.
It's gonna take us a number of months to get that to the point where we're happy with it.
We don't wanna just rush it out similar to this cause you've just finished.
We want to do it properly and to give you the best learning experience.
So thank you very much for joining us on this cause.
I would love to see what you've come up with with your RPG.
So please do share a video screenshot and description of what you've created.
I'd love to see it and if you continue to push it further and make it into a bigger game then please
definitely do show us and share that with us.
So again thank you for joining us and we'll see you again real soon.