Hello and welcome in this lecture we're gonna get some programmer UI in here with our health percentage
by go up to this garden he starts beating me you can see that my percentage starts to go down we're
also going to learn how we can make sure this is rounded so there's no decimal points in our display
as well.
So let's dive in and see how it's done.
Okay so the first thing I want to do is create some basic program UI to show our health in the top left
corner.
So I'm gonna go because I want this in all scenes I'm going to do this in the core prefab.
Going to add a new piece of UI so I'm gonna go to right click UI text she's gonna be our text for the
help we're just gonna use how basic text here rather than using health bars or anything like that.
I'm gonna rename the canvas to HUD.
Heads up display for those who don't know and in the game folder I'm gonna go ahead and create a new
folder and call it UI and in here we're going to drag this heads up display to create new prefab so
we can edit this prefab.
I'm just going to switch over to the scene and editor in to demoed and then what we're going to do is
take this topped out.
This text element and position it in the top left I'm going to move the anchor to the top left as well
and change the anchoring sorry so I move the pivot to the top left and change the anchoring.
Then I'm going to change the color of the text to white because we mostly got a dark background and
changed the text itself to be hair health colon like so let's see what that looks like in the game view.
Yep top left Nance a bit too close to the top left it's moving out now.
If it ever gets stuck to the left like this which keeps doing for me I find that restart and the editor
is the only solution so I've gone ahead and done that I'm going to open up the HUD prefab again and
go into the game view and you can see it's unstuck itself from the left corner.
For some reason it does that I don't know why now it's looking a little bit blurry.
So what I'm going to do is switch from free aspect to low resolution aspect ratio and then there's a
few other things I want to tweak because that's using my full resolution now having switch that over
it's now using the full resolution my screen if you are using 100 percent scaling then you won't have
this problem if you're using a higher scaling ratio high DP high screen then it will give you the option
to have a low aspect ratio so then we can go to our text and there's a few more tweaks I want to make
in fact for the scope to the canvas object the first tweak I want to make is to the UI scaling mode
is say it's in constant pixel size which means it won't make use of the extra pixels in the screen if
you have high DP light displays because it will basically make smaller text instead of making sharper
text.
So if I go for physical site constant physical size instead I'll try and make sharper text when you're
on high DPA screens which I think is probably the better way to go in this day and age and then what
we want to do is also check off pixel perfect mode for really lovely font rendering in the canvas components
and in the go into game now you've got really nice clean font rendering up here.
So now I'm going to duplicate this text component and create a second piece of text for the actual health
value that's what we're going to update with a script in just a moment we're going to put the health
to 100 percent as a placeholder now we're gonna rename these two elements so we're going to have a health
label and we're going to have a
text value to you in fact OK so that is our heart pretty much done you can see that's what it's looking
like the text is a little bit big let me scale the text and change the font size something like 12 go
in game now then still a little bit large let's bring it down to 10 get back in game OK that's small
enough it's debug so we don't need it to be massive so we've got our health value just bringing a little
bit closer make things a little bit neater.
Okay so what we want to do is update this by a script so we're gonna create a script in the resources
folder because we want to have access to the health component and I think that's going to be the easiest
for now it may choose to move it at some point we'll call this the health display C.S. s to create a
mono behavior in here and we're going to move the mono behavior into a namespace RPG resources the existing
resources namespace.
So we have access to the health component and then what well I want to display the health as a percentage
on this health display.
So we need to get that to come out of our health component in the first place.
We also need to get hold of the players health component.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to have a reference to the health component for this class.
And I'm going to basically cash it on awake.
So we're gonna create an a wait method and sort out these curly braces and then I'm going to set the
health to basically the.
Game Object Dot.
Fine whereas it fine with tag we're looking for the player and we're looking for his health component
so get components health components and that should do the trick.
So now we've got the health components we can now do something in update I'm going to leave update as
a to do for you guys to just update to do updates your text basically but there is one more thing we
need to be able to do out of health is we need to be able to get a percentage.
So I'm going to create another public method we've got is dead take damage after take damage.
I'm going to create another public method which just returns a float which is going to be the percentage
essentially of of what we've got.
So.
How how much health we've got.
So I'm going to have this as get percentage does need to take anything just to get.
And that's where we're going to do our calculation of the percentage.
Now there's a little mini challenge if you think you know how you can calculate the percentage of health
points to return here then go ahead and do that.
If not I will go ahead and write this.
So we're going to do a return value here and we've got our health points.
So that's the current health points.
But what we actually want is the health points divided by the initial health points which was this The
get component base that get health so we can do that division divide by the original health that we
set and then what.
So that's giving us a fraction of the health.
But we said percentage which is in basically this times 100.
So let's do that to go a hundred times remember the order of multiplication doesn't matter 100 times
the health points divided by health so we can see right up front that it's gonna be in percentage units
so time for your challenge to display the health.
So you're going to write your update method that we left as a to do you going to set the text on the
text component that we're attached to.
You're going to have to obviously put our mono behavior act components onto that tax component as well.
And don't forget to add your percentages at the end.
So doing a little bit of string composition puts video and have a go.
Okay.
Welcome back.
So we've gotta get percentage notes we got.
That's what we're gonna use.
We're also going to get the text component so get component text.
And this that we don't have yet.
So we're going to have to use the unity engine UI namespace and then using this text component can set
its text to the text content too.
Well health dot get whereas it get percentage that we go and at the end of this I'm going to have to
add the percentage sign because that we're going to overwrite and that will go.
So that should pretty much do the trick.
If I drop that onto our health value added components the health display component where is it that
would go and if we go ahead and hit play now hopefully that's going to show us our health.
So got health hundreds and I woke up to this god and pummel me a bit and my health goes down.
Now it's giving me lots and lots of decimal points which is not what I want.
I think I want to stick with probably no decimal points actually would be better for this display.
Now beware this won't happen if your damage perfectly divides into percentages.
So try tweaking it if you're not seeing this behavior.
So the way I'm going to get round this is using the string format method from C sharp.
So what we're going to do is wrap this all in a string of capital s String dot format and what this
does is it takes a what's known as a format string which basically tells you how to insert variables
into the string and then the values you want to insert.
So a format would start off with saying Hey take the first thing zeros thing that you want to insert
and then put it in here and then I can write stuff after it so I could put my percentage sign afterwards
and what this is going to do if I remove the percentage sign that I was adding here is exactly the same
thing as before.
Now I've got to include what do I need to include the system namespace in order to use string dot format.
So what we've got here is it's saying take the first thing on the right here the percentage and plop
it in place of this thing with the curly braces the zero with the curly braces and you can add extra
arguments with one for example like this with curly braces.
And just to show you.
And I can add something before like health maybe even.
This is obviously not what we're going to want to do but let's just have a look what happens if I go
ahead and hit play now.
Why expectancy is health.
Health and they go as formatting that string and including the health percentage in that but this hasn't
actually helped us.
If I remove this because I'm gonna go ahead and hit play and go and get pummeled a little bit.
That's going to get pummeled and you can see it we've still got loads and loads decimal places.
Now the good thing here is that we can do some formatting options on the things that we try to include.
So what I can do is I can put a colon here and then I can put some formatting options.
In this case I want to say how many decimal places I want.
So I could put zero for example and that's going to say OK don't include any decimal places.
The precision is going to be zero decimal places.
So let's go ahead and play.
Go get pummeled and you can see that our health is decreasing in single units.
So you can see it's going down every other time he hits us because he's taking off something like a
half health half percentage every time he hits.
So you can see the health is going down and it is using no percentage points to display that.
So what if we did want to add more decimal places then instead of having zero here instead of putting
we don't put one we put zero dot Zero we're saying that we want to have always one decimal place visible.
So if I go ahead and play that then you can see we've got a hundred percent point nought and if we go
up to the guy he's going to batter us and we can see that percentage is going down and we've got that
always one decimal place so that's how you use the string format operator in order for us to get the
0 decimal places which is what really we want to see in this display.
So to summarize what we've got is a health display that gets our players health components and updates.
This tax component in our HUD so that we can see how much percentage of health we have got left as the
player in the next video we're going to look at how we can get the health for the enemy that we're attacking
as well which is also gonna be very useful.
So you that.