Let's wrap up this quick design section by finishing off our one point five page DDD to the best of
our ability.
So I want you to open it up again and we've already completed the top part.
The Game Summary now this is the point where you say what's my game.
Just go with your gut here and write out to the best of your knowledge at this stage.
And I was really early you haven't prototype your game you're not really sure what's going on.
The point of this whole process is write something down and have it change how it evolve have it iterate
over time you want to get something at the start where it's going to paste in what I've created for
mine to give you an example of what I'm writing in here so project Dragon.
So at this point I don't even know the name of my game that's totally final I'm going to tell you an
idea that I've got at the moment is a Diablo style RPG with the absurd humor of Monty Python once make
this a tiny bit bigger on the screen and the Holy Grail.
So straightaway I'm getting my player experience in there which is all about absurd humor making the
play laugh.
The game is set.
So next up I'm talking about where it set the location the the time theme if you will the setting.
The game is set during the grubby phase of the medieval era when brave sir knights were bold and foolish
and the unbelievers peasants reeked of cabbage.
I'm just trying to be funny that may or may not be funny but trying as our unlikely elderly hero so
I'm starting to think about who is my hero.
Now we haven't flesh this out in our GDP.
I've got a point down here which is our central story theme we're gonna talk more about the protagonist
and the antagonist are the hero and the baddies and the story theme later on in the course.
But for now I just want you to know give you a gut feel for who your hero is.
For me I want my hero to be old.
That's the funny part of my life.
He's his old geriatric guy.
Maybe he's a he's a past hero someone who's a has been.
Maybe he's just a dirty stinky old peasant guy who's like what am I doing here.
But I think that's going to be funny.
I must battle the Queen's soldiers so I'm having a stab at who is my enemy.
Maybe it's the Queen.
I think it's the peasants versus the the Empire kind of thing.
What we that Star Wars kind of thing the unlikely hero that I'm going from there so maybe the queen
is the enemy and the queen soldiers and the grotesque monsters by finding sorry I said you must battle
the Queen's soldiers and grotesque monsters by finding ancient weapons levelling up your character venturing
to far off lands using special wizard magic.
This is me trying to be funny and clever again known as metal map fast travel and seeking answers the
ultimate riddle.
Who am I and why a dragon such jerk.
So this is the game summary.
Give this your best shot.
Do a little bit of your player experience a little bit of the setting a little bit of who your hero
is a little bit of who the enemies are and a little bit of kind of what are you doing in the game.
What are you up to what's your purpose.
So they're the they're the bits that the construction of your summary so give it your best shot now.
Even if you've got no idea just put something in.
And as time goes on will improve it and we'll update so pose a video now and write a game summary okay.
Welcome back and great work.
We've already put in our core player experience and next up the central story theme.
I mentioned a moment ago.
We're going to talk a little bit more about story later on why.
Later on and why not now.
Well when you're making a game like this you've just got to stop making it get into unity.
Start prototyping things playing around with things get your character moving because that's what all
these ideas will come to you when you're seeing your game come to life.
If you spend your time thinking about story at this point there's a very good chance you're going to
get stuck and never make your game.
I've seen that a lot.
So for now I'm just going to say unlikely hero.
That's the story.
It's an unlikely hero going on his journey to be the hero.
And you might know it.
You might want to think more about it.
That's cool but just a sentence here on what your story is and we'll talk about it more later on design.
What is going to be the cool thing about your game when you're playing it.
Is it going to be you know really great combat system.
Is it going to be really it's a game about crafting.
Is it going to be a game where there's tons of of dialogue and stories and choose your own adventure
style branching storylines.
If you're already like oh this is what I would like to have my game be all about from a design point
of view.
Then you can put that in now.
I'm gonna say putting the player in absurd absurd absurd slash funny slash ridiculous situations.
Okay so it's not about the greatest combat ever it's not about an amazing crafting system.
It's just about I'm going to have the player flight fight a flying pig or attack a talking radish.
I'm not sure what it is yet but that's what the game's going to be about and when I'm designing the
game that will be the coolness of it.
And so pause the video now and write down what you think your design pillar might be for your game and
next up we have a remarkable city.
What this means is.
What about your game is going to have it stand out and have one person turned to their friend and say
well you have to play this game we have to look at this game.
This is more than just why is my game fun interesting great game to play.
It's more than just what's the experience.
It is.
If someone watches a 10 second video of your game why are they going to say Wow and again for me it's
the same theme I'm hitting over and over.
Absurd humor.
So when I show that 10 second video it's gonna be something ridiculous.
When people talk about it it's going to be something ridiculous.
An example of this is I've been thinking about this for a while.
I think a cool name for my game could be the dirty old ho.
Now you might look at that and say What are you talking about Rick.
So h o e the word HIV is a farming implement and it can be dirty and it can be old but in English the
word ho is also kind of a rude naughty word to say someone who has relationships with other people for
money.
So it's got that double meaning it's a little bit edgy it's a little bit mature but it's absurd.
It's setting the tone for my game so I'm not gonna put that into this document at the moment it's not
needed but that's the kind of thing that if someone sees the name of my game and it's the dirty old
hurry they're gonna go What are these idiots on about.
This is very juvenile.
I like it.
So it's not going to appeal to everyone but I'm looking for people who are immature like myself and
Sam and Ben.
So that's what I'm going for.
So remark ability for you could be.
The graphics are going to be amazing it could be massive worlds it could be a never seen before combat
system.
It could be your game is played completely in the dark.
It could be that there is no hero.
You like the showing in the previous video flower where you're playing is the wind.
That's very remarkable.
And again this is gonna be something that won't come to you straight away you're going to discover it
as you prototype your game but just have a guess.
Now what could your game have about it that is so special that makes it remarkable so pose a video and
writing a remarkably okay.
The other thing I like to have personally in a game design document is a little piece of production.
Production is making of the game.
I know this isn't design but what's the anticipated Steam early access launch dates in other words.
Give yourself a little bit of a deadline.
When are you going to get the game done for you.
It might not be early access launch date.
It might be when am I going to put it on the App Store.
It could be when am I going to have my prototype finished or if my demo to go and show people for investment.
So for me I'm going to put in here end of 2019 just I I don't know how long it's going to take to make
it but I'm giving myself tons of time to say.
That's when we would launch it.
End of 2019.
So again putting something for you that's meaningful that's a date of when I'm actually going to get
this thing done and then the feature development prior is this is a tough one if you don't know what
you're building yet but for me I'm going to paste in what I've got already mapped out here because I've
already put it quite a bit of thought into this because I have to teach it to you guys.
So for us it's real time combat is number one all the required arpeggios abilities and stats strength
and constitution and experience points.
That's coming in next level building and game progression that needs to be in there branching dialog
system and then inventory loot usable items.
The main point of us doing this again in our one point five page GTD is to say you've got to start somewhere
and you've got to know what is more important than what else.
So if you've got inventory and loot and usable items is your number one thing you like.
That's what my game is all about.
That is what's gonna be amazing for my game and you know what if I don't get to dialogue that's okay
not a problem.
So if you've got enough of the feeling of what you'd like to have in your game what the priorities are
then you can put something in here.
If not if you like why I'm just following along with you Rick.
So that's cool.
Just putting exactly what I've got in here or leave it blank.
If you want.
This is not a super important thing for you to do at this point but I want to show you the process I'm
going through so that in the future you can be making your own games using the process that we would
use in a professional studio and then reference games.
I showed you a video a little while ago where I talked about Amber as go out and talked about Amber
but Ember is a good one that I like battle hot legacy Diablo Torchlight 2.
These are games that I've been using as reference games in terms of the the flow the style the artwork
the gameplay and it's good to have reference games in here so if an outsider is looking in this document
and saying you know what I've read all this stuff but I kind of don't get what your game is you can
say well it's kind of a bit like battle hot legacy meets Diablo and Torchlight 2 an ember.
But as I've got at the top here Diablo meets Monty Python so it's all funny.
It's like oh okay I know these games all it's that kind of game.
Sometimes it's really important to allow people to pigeonhole your game a little bit.
So this is what I've got in all of my one page one point five page DDD at the moment.
You can see what's one point five pages because I can never seem to squeeze it into one page.
That's why it's one point five or not one.
So I'd like you to do as your challenges to finish your first draft of the GDP.
If there's gaps in it no problem.
Do your best finish of as much of it as you can.
And then once you've done that please share it with our community share a link or share a screenshot
of your one point five pages pasted in let us know what you've come up with so that we can have a look
at it.
There's a link against this lecture where you can go and share your one point five page GDP.
So please do share it with us and I'll see you again real soon.