In this course Sam and I will be using Visual Studio code as our editor.
So if you'd like everything that look the same as us then we're gonna go ahead and download that now
and install it. In the past.
If you've been on our other courses you may have seen us using Visual Studio 2017 community or a different
version of Visual Studio.
They'll both work.
You can use any code editor you'd like for this course.
But if you want things to look the same as us then go ahead and grab Visual Studio code now by clicking
on the link that I've given you against this lecture you can find the link or you can just copy what
we've got the top or you can search for Visual Studio code download.
So click on the free download.
That'll take you to a page with a bit more information and also start your download.
Visual Studio code is open source which is great it's very clean it's very easy to use one of the main
reasons we're using it in this course is it looks the same for Mac and P.C. users.
So we wanted to give everyone a consistent experience so once it's downloaded click to install open
that up click Next yes I'll give Microsoft my first born child, whatever its asking.
Now take note of where the installation process wants to put it for me it's putting in my users Rick
app data local programs Microsoft Visual Studio code, Ok i'm just going to copy that so I've got it
for reference in a bit in case I need it.
Jump over.
Next Visual Studio code.
This all looks pretty good and click on install.
Now it's gonna take a moment or two to install.
I'm going to pause the video now and I'll be back here when mine is installed.
Okay i was actually pretty quick.
Just a 15 second process launch Visual Studio code yes we want to do that because there's a couple of
things I want to show you in terms of our set up that's quite important.
Maximize the window here.
Okay.
Just a quick intro you can see we've got our tabs over on the left hand side here and then a panel which
is going to give us some information.
This is where our code will be once we've got some code a little welcome thingamajig in there.
Get rid of that.
So few pop ups I'm just gonna exit out of those for now and what we need to do is add a couple of extensions
or at least make sure they are added.
Now I've added this already because it's from a previous installation and what you need to do is make
sure sure you've got C sharp for Visual Studio code that should come default if you don't have that
then you can search for it up here.
C sharp and that should take you to Microsoft.
Microsoft's official C sharp extension and then the other thing we need to have is unity code snippets.
So again you can search for unity code snippets up at the top so click on the make sure you clicked
on the extensions tab and then search for that.
I'm using the one by Kleber silver and it is unity code.
So click on that and then click on install and that will go through the installation process
to install that.
Now you might go and look if you click back on your extensions here.
I'm just gonna remove my search from the search bar.
Show me what is installed.
If you don't see it in there after installation you might need a close down and then reopen Visual Studio
code and then the unity code snippets should be there.
Why do we need that.
While So when we type in things like start it auto completes or it knows what on trigger enter means
so it understands the unity code and it can help us and give us hints and clues to do with Unity code.
Also while I'm here I'm going out to edit  to file Preferences Settings.
I've got a search bar at the top here.
We're gonna look for code lens shows code lands controls whether the editor shows code lines I'm gonna
turn that off.
I won't go into a lot of detail about what that is but that gives a little extra clutter within our code
that I'm going to turn off in the future if you want to play around with it you can.
But now I'm going to turn that off and the other thing I want to search for his format on paste and
make sure format on paste is turned on so it controls whether the editor automatically format the pasted
content.
So just pretty set up a little bit gives it indentation and always good things want.
So there the two changes to the settings that I've made as well as the two extensions that I've added
into you Visual Studio code.
The last thing we need to do is to tell unity that this is our editor of choice so I'm going to go and
find my Unity hub and open that up.
That's what we installed in the previous video.
Open up your unity hub.
You can open up just any of the projects that you've got.
Or if you don't have a project already just click on new and from new you can give yourself a name the
location and the version I'm using twenty eighteen point three point three.
It's going to leave it all pretty default here.
Create the project I'm going to get rid of this later on this is just so we can go into unity and give
ourselves a setting within our preferences there to make sure that we have visual studio code setup.
Okay so this is going to take its 20 or 30 seconds to load up I'm going to pause the video and I'll
see you back here in a moment.
Once my project is loaded okay.
Now if this is the first time first time it's open up might have a couple of things in here tmp imported
has to do with text mesh pro, I'm going to close that window just because I don't need it and jump up to edit
preferences within preferences we need to click on external tools and then external script editor.
I'm going to look for visual studio codes not in there so I need to browse for it.
I remember I copied my installation point before which was users, Rick, Application Data,  local, programs Microsoft
Visual Studio code that's open that up yours might be in a different spot if you chose to install it
in a different spot.
That's where it is for me on P.C. and then just double click on code and now it's changed to visual
studio code as my preferred editor.
Excellent close that down.
Make myself a C sharp script in here.
So just click on assets right click Create C sharp script call it test and then double click on Test
if it's all gone according to plan it should open up visual studio code maximise the screen, you can see we've
got a pop up down here I'm gonna ignore these for now this might be something we need to pay attention
to later on but for now it's going to dismiss this message you can see we have tabs up the top all should
be looking pretty familiar and if you want to minimize this window on the left here you can drag it
around like that and the final point I'll make is that we asked our community would you prefer for us
to work in a dark theme or a light theme and it was pretty much 96 percent of people said please use
a dark theme so here it is we're using a dark theme might be a little bit different a little bit unusual
if you've been following our other courses we've been using a white theme but I think it should be I
think you'll get it.
This is an intermediate course I think you'll be out to accommodate the fact that it's a dark background.
Okay so that's it.
We've set up visual studio code we've got unity pointing towards it correctly we're all ready to go
so in the next video Sam's going to give you a rundown on the architecture that we're going through
in this course and in our project.