Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we are going to be restoring the health status or saving and restoring the health component.
It's gonna be a challenge that you're gonna do but watch.
If I hit load here currently we have full health.
I hit load and this enemy over here just died because I had saved that I had already killed him.
And also in the process I had lost him healthy you can see that my player has actually got less health
than he started off with.
That is going to be what we're going to do in this lecture.
Let's dive in so this lecture is all going to be a challenge for you to implement the health saving
in the same way as we've done with movement.
So here is your instructions.
The you're gonna implement the interface first of all so you don't have to be asking yourself what is
it.
What's the state that I want to save about this health system.
So what is it that I should be returning from capture state.
Then you're going to be looking at how will you restore the state once it comes back to you.
Remember that you need to cast that object to whatever it was before you can use it.
And finally a hint is that all basic types are marked as Sarah liable without you having to do anything
clever like we did with our vector 3 vector 3 is not a basic type but things like int bool float and
string are all basic types which are by default serialize bool meaning that they can be converted into
binary and put into a safe file.
So with armed with this knowledge armed with these steps have a go at implementing the health saving
in the same way as we did with the movement component Hey welcome back.
So let's go over and open up our health C.S. which should be in a core and what we want to do here is
first of all include a namespace so we can do a using RPG dot saving and then we are going to inherit
from or not really inherit but implement the interface it's going to be an ice saver ball and control
dots to implement the interface.
Now let's put it in a bit of a weird location for me so I'm going to go ahead and move it on down and
put it at the bottom of the file just so it doesn't interfere with any of the other kind of public interfaces
and stuff for me it's quite separate the ability to save a component is quite separate now the real
state pretty much the only state of the health system.
Here's what our current health actually is.
Now where are we storing our current health we're storing it in the health points.
So that's what we need to go ahead and return.
We can just go ahead and hit return on the health points basically.
Now that's fine because health points is a float a basic type so it can be serialized and it won't give
us any errors.
Now coming back from that float we need to get our health points.
So that's basically what we want to do.
We just want to set our health points to whatever was captured from before.
So we're gonna do health points equals state basically but it won't let us do that because state is
not the right type.
So we need to cast to float basically putting in brackets like this means that we are casting the state
to a float and putting it into health points and that should basically restore our health points.
Let's go and try this out.
So if I go ahead and hit play then what I want to do is get myself beaten up a little bit.
I know counterintuitive and I'm going to get beaten a little bit like so and I'm going to save my health
and I am going to go and get beaten up a little bit more by this guy should reduce my health points
even further and I'll try and run away.
It's not really working.
Let me go and have a look at my player.
In fact I'll pause Have a look at my player in the inspector and we can have a look at my health points
I'm currently health points one hundred and twenty.
Now what happens if I hit load we all go back to different locations again and you'll notice my health
points went up so they have been successfully restored to what they were before I went and attacked
this guard.
Now you'll notice this guard is currently dead because that's where I saved it.
But here's a problem if I hit play and hit play again and now I want to hit load.
You'll notice this guard is still alive and kicking.
Why is that.
Why did he not die.
Well I'd die method which is the one that runs the animator makes him look dead essentially and cancels
any of his current actions is only run if our health points equals zero.
But if we take damage now in this case we are not taking damage.
So what we need to do is we need to do this check of the health points equaling zero and we need to
do this in restore state so we restore the health points.
Then we check all the health points equal to zero.
If so we must kill off that character again because he is dead and he should look dead.
So now hopefully what we'll see is if I go ahead and hit play and hit load.
Then you see my enemy drops dead because he has his health restored to zero and then we hit the DI method
because we've noticed that special condition of health being zero has been met.
So hopefully after this lecture you've got a better understanding of how the saving component I save
bull actually works and how you can implement it for yourself.
Now if you want to you could go ahead and extend this knowledge to apply it to other elements of your
game such as for example the cinematics maybe you want to save the fact that the cinematics has already
been played and you don't want to play it again.
That is a little challenge for you.
If you're interested in not going to be doing it here at this stage in the course but it is something
that you might want to have a go and flex your muscles with in the next lecture.
We're gonna be looking at saving loading as we go between portals so that it gives us the illusion that
the world we just came from all that state is exactly the same.
When we come back to it I'll see you in that lecture.