Hello and welcome to this lecture where we're going to have a health display for the enemy as well so
it's currently the targeted enemy.
So if I let this enemy you can see his health percentage and it goes down as I attack him until he dies.
And the same is true for all my other enemies.
I can attach tacky Archer who has a little bit less health and he dies a bit quicker.
You can see the percentage of health goes down quicker.
Let's dive in and see how to achieve this so we want to include health for the enemy as well.
So I'm going to do is I'm just going to start off by duplicating our health labels and you can follow
along with this.
I'm going to call the first one the enemy health label.
Let's rename that enemy health label.
There we go.
And then the second one is going to be the enemy health and family.
So OK.
And I'm going to move these two down a notch.
So we won't be seeing this in the rec too.
And ideally I wouldn't be moving it to the left and right.
OK.
So there we go.
Enemy health label needs to be changed and is going to change this over to enemy like so.
So we're going to have that we can see the health and the enemy's health at the top left.
Let's see how that looks in the game that looks about right.
So what we want to do now is to be able to update this.
So instead of having the health display on here we're going to remove this component and instead we
are going to have to create a new health components but one for the enemy.
So I'm going to copy the health display because that is a good place to start.
And I'm going to pay states into combat.
Now you're going to ask me why am I pasting it into combat.
Can I paste here.
Yes I can't.
We'll control V.
And I'm going to instead of calling his health is playing and call this enemy health display and I'm
going to do the same thing for the class name.
So it's going to change over to any health display like so.
And here.
Basically instead of getting hold of the player's health component we want to get the hold of the fighters
while the players fighters targets health components for what a mouthful.
So we currently have no way of finding out what the fighters target is.
There's no public method for that.
So I'm going to scroll down to our public methods we've got this equipped weapon public method after
that.
Then add another public method which is going to return a game object which is going to be the target.
Or is that right.
Let's have a look at Target actually a health component so we can just return the health component directly
that's what we actually need.
I'm going to call let's get targets like so.
And as you can imagine it's just going to return at target variable.
Very simple get that.
So I would like you for your challenge to fill out basically replace what's going on in this enemy health
display with a display that actually will show the enemy's health that we're currently attacking.
So you're challenged to create an enemy health display so store the players fighter value in a wake
get the target from the fighter every update because Target is going to change and include a default
value.
So if you don't have a target what are you going to display.
Think about that.
Pause the video and have a go at the challenge.
Hopefully this wasn't too tricky.
So instead of storing the health component we're going to be storing the fighter.
We're also going to change the name space should be RPG.
Combat in here.
So restoring our fighter in the awake so fighter is fine.
Play with Tag component is going to be fighter like so.
So we've got our fighter component.
Now what we want to do is see whether we have actually got target.
So if the fighter top the top get target is equal to no.
And then what we want to do is set our text and the text component to model.
Maybe just not applicable or not available.
That's what I'm going to put in there for the text and then.
Otherwise we want to get this health percentage.
So how do we get our health components.
Well we can get that from the fighter.
So going to do a fighter dot get target like so and we don't have health because we don't have access
to it.
But if we go ahead and include using resources then which is okay because combat already depends on
resources then we can go ahead and basically get access to our health component.
So let's see if that's working.
If I go and add the components I want the enemy health display this time like so and if I go ahead and
play then hopefully we should see not applicable.
There's no enemy selected.
But as soon as I select the enemy he's got a percentage and it decreases every time I bash him until
he's dead.
Now there's no point to issue that I'm forgetting to address you can try and investigate for yourself.
Many challenge to try and fix it but it will be fixed in the next lecture.
Don't worry.
Okay.
So that seems to be working.
If I can I can go and attack different enemies.
You might notice this guy has got an A and which stands for Not a number.
Now why was that.
If we're going to have a look at that particular guy I think it is because he's an archer and we haven't
assigned any health to the Archers yet.
So he just gets the default zero health and dividing by zero is something we aren't allowed to do so
let's just go ahead and give some health to the archers to check that hypothesis.
We go to our core progression and we go to our class I'm going to add in the archer class give level
1 archers health.
So let's give them a little bit less health than the default grunt.
Go ahead and hit play now.
Then hopefully if I go and attack that Archer he now has got 100 percent health because he's got some
health to divide by in calculating a percentage.
You see he dies much much quicker than the other guys.
Cool so now we have got health for the enemy and health for ourselves.
Well basically the current target.
So we've been able to look up the current target from fighter and display that and also give a default
value when we don't have any target currently set in the next lecture.
We're going to be doing something very exciting we gonna be learning about how we can have experience
points and gain experience points when we kill enemies.
So let's dive on and find out how that's done.