Hello and welcome in this lecture we're going to be adding an experience component like this one down
here as you can see I start off with zero experience points.
But if I go and clobber this god and knock out his lights then what you see is my experience increases
and if I go on to kill more guards it goes up and up and up and up.
So we're gonna dive in and see how that's possible and how we can make it so those gods depending on
what level they're at.
Give us a different amount of experience points so here's the plan for this lecture what we want to
achieve is that when the enemy is attacked the enemy health knows who the instigator of the attack was.
So by instigator we mean the person who initiated the attack.
Then if the enemy is killed in this particular attack what we're gonna do is get the experience points
for the.
That should be awarded based on the particular enemy that we've killed we'll get out from base stats
so the progression tells us how the experience points of the enemy progress as we get to higher and
harder levels maybe an archer is worth more experience points than a grunt.
Things like that those are the kinds of decisions you can make.
So we're gonna get that from base stance then we're going to get the instigators experience which is
gonna be a new component that we're going to create a new resource essentially we're gonna get hold
of the experience see if it has one and if it does we can award experience points to its experience
component.
So that is the outline of the lecture this is what the flow that we want to do.
So how does this line up with our code.
Well if we go and have a look at visual studio we're talking a lot about the health component particularly
the enemy's health component.
So we've got this take damage and intake damage what we're going to do is if we are dying we want to
award experience points but we have mentioned in here that we need to know who the instigator is when
we take damage.
And at present we don't know that.
So I'm going to change take damage so that it takes in an instigator as well.
So the type will be game object instigator and obviously this is going to cause us issues in other parts
of the code base where this no longer works.
So for example the fighter no longer has it doesn't doesn't work because we don't have the instigator
Well that's easy we can just say pass in the game object that will be the instigator because we're the
person doing the damage on the target but there's also another place which is the projectile and the
projectile does not have an instigator set.
So we don't have anywhere in here a way to refer to who shot the projectile.
So the projectile itself when it has set targets we're going to have to set up who the instigator was
as well.
So I'm going to create a new state variable for the projectile type game object.
We're going to call it the instigator.
Start off as normal by default.
And this instigator we want to set through our set target.
So I'm going to add in a variable we've got the target we've got the instigator we've got the damage
so then this dot instigator is going to equal the instigator argument that comes into set targets and
that means that hopefully now and take damage in on trigger enter as well as passing in the damage we
can pass in the instigator and that at least fixes up projectile.
But now our weapon script is the one that does the launching and you can see that we're kind of having
to hop back here.
So set target.
No it doesn't have an instigator.
So we need to pass in an instigator but we need to pass that into launch projectile as well so left
hand right hand target.
And then the game object instigator as well.
And finally that should take us back up to fighter actually launches the projectile and we can pass
in the instigate game object with our projectile.
So that's done a few hops.
Let's just review that shall we.
We've gone into launch projectile which is in the weapon script which then goes in to the projectile.
So set an instigator as a variable here that gets later used on trigger enter where we take damage finally
to the health component.
So that basically the health component can know who its instigator was who actually gave us this damage
and this killing blow so that we can award the appropriate experience points.
So hopefully that all makes sense.
So the next thing is that we want to get the experience points from base stats and we don't currently
have a stat for that but we are going to look at more general stats in the next lecture.
So for right now I'm just going to have a get xp method and in fact I'm going to rename it to experience
reward.
So we've got the experience reward coming back from there and I'm just going to return 10.
So everything gives us 10 experience when we kill it.
That's a straightforward assumption at the moment.
Obviously we're going to want to look up in the progression later on but I think what we're going to
actually have to do is make all these different types of stats into E names and that's gonna be the
subject of a future lecture.
So we've got the experience reward.
Okay.
What next.
The instigator gets the X sorry we get the instigators experience.
We don't have an experienced class.
So what does that look like.
Well we're going to go ahead and create a new class so and the resources in fact create a new file called
experience
and we're going to make a mono behaviour in here that's going to reflect very much the same as the health
component so it's going to be a namespace RPG.
Dot resources and then they experience what does experience need to have.
Well we need to keep track of our experience points.
So we're going to have some state called the make it serialized field so we can see it serialized field
float experience points and we're gonna start off at zero and we're going to need a method to call in
order to award experience points.
So I'm going to have it void and just call it gain experience and in here we're going to take the flight
value of the experience that is gained now very straightforwardly these experience points just get increased
by plus equals.
The argument that we've passed in the experience so that pretty much sums up what experience does.
It just grows over time as we call this experience method.
So I think that just leaves us with enough for a challenge that in the health components I would like
you to do the final bits of awarding the experience.
So you need to get the experience from the base stats get the instigators experience components and
then gain points on it by the appropriate amount and go and check in the inspector that when you're
killing the enemies you are gaining experience obviously it's not going to be safe just yet.
That's going to be a subject of a future lecture as well post video and have a go okay.
Welcome back.
So first of all I'm going to just create a method called ward experience and it's going to have to take
in the instigator like so and I'm going to go ahead and also create that method in health.
Got this award experience it's a private song and put it under and get percent and under die because
it's a bit more specific than that.
And what we're going to do.
Well first of all we want to get hold see if the instigator actually has so get components does it actually
have an experience component festival.
Does it have an experience component.
And if it does have an experienced component then we want to do some stuff.
So festival was just store that
so storing the experience and then we can say if experience is null then we can just return.
So if it's no to a quick return out of here.
Otherwise with our experience we aren't going to gain experience points by how much.
Well that's going to depend on get components and then we're going to get.
Remember the base stats and from base stats we are going to get our experience reward which at the moment
is fixed but later on down the line will not be will flesh that out.
So that's it.
Basically this is going to return how much experience we should reward.
This tells us who we should award it to and so on and so forth.
So let's dive in and see if that works.
So I'm gonna go ahead and hit play.
Some no references why there's no reference is happening.
Well it looks like I forgot to do an early return here.
Sorry about that.
Folks must been screaming at me about that.
That basically wants to set it to N.A. and then return early so hopefully this didn't put you off too
much in the last lecture.
Now go ahead and hit play.
And now we've gotten those errors.
I can attack the enemy and try and kill it kill the enemy and go and have a look at our player and see
how much experience he's got.
He has got no experience because I didn't have an experience component so let's add the experience component
to the player.
Notice I want to add that to the player but it's my choice that I'm not going to add it to the enemy's
as well so we're not gonna have enemies that are beefing up as they kill players or kill kill NPC because
that's just a bit weird.
So we're just gonna add the experience script to our player then we're gonna go to kill the enemy.
You can see his experience points are currently at zero and once I kill the enemy I gain 10 experience
points.
Let's go and check that if I go and kill another enemy.
Say this Archer dude over here shouldn't take very much to kill him he's quite weak I would go and I've
got now 20 experience points so you can see I got the basics of levelling up so let's review what we
have done we have passed through the instigator all the way from the fighter through projectile through
weapon to the health component so that the health component knows who instigated an attack so that we
can award experience.
We also updated our base stance to include experience so we can pull those two things together to award
experience when we die now at the moment.
Our experience is static so in the next set you're going to fix that and improve our stat system so
that we can add more stats really easily.
See you there.