Welcome to the architectural overview.
In this video I'm gonna get you really excited about the different features we're going to be implementing
in this RPG by showing you the prototype we've already got and showing you how it breaks down into bite
sized modules that we are going to be implementing one by one and which courses you should go to to
learn which bits of this RPG
so let's take a look at the modules that we're gonna break this down into the first core module is going
to be movement is gonna be a namespace in C C sharp parlance.
So basically this is going to be a point and click movement system a bit like torchlight.
You can see how it's based off a nav mesh here that blue stuff and all these widgets are showing us
how the nav mesh stuff works.
So next dependent upon that movement system we are going to have the control system which is responsible
for the player movement but also it's going to be responsible for the A.I. of the enemies which will
be able to move as well.
Then after that we are going to build a combat system.
This works very much like you would expect a combat system to work.
You point click you click on an enemy and if you have a weapon equipped that is you walk up to the enemy
and you start attacking them and obviously they can attack you too they've got A.I. that allows them
to do this after the combat.
We are going to notice that the combat has to rely upon movement because when as you saw when we click
on an enemy we have to move up to the enemy.
So there's a dependency there and you can see it start to get complicated but also we're gonna have
a core component which all these things depend upon.
Now it's gonna get more complicated than this.
Bear with me.
After that we are going to be implementing saving.
This is going to be as a separate course hence it's in gray and combat and movement and going to rely
on saving because they will need to know how to save their content.
That's going to be implemented on per module basis combat will save things like the health state movement
will save things like your current position and so on and so forth.
Then we're going to implement stats which combat is going to rely on and that's going to allow us to
tweak certain parameters we might have stats such as how much damage we do per hit how quickly we hit
what's our base health rate.
So combat is going to rely on that and stats will be modifiable later on by our inventory items by the
attributes of the player such as their strength and so on then we're going to be implementing a progression
system.
This is basically experience points levelling up.
That's something else that can affect the stats.
So if as you level up your base health is going to level up as well.
Then in blue because this is gonna be in the part to course not in this course we are going to be doing
inventories.
So you can see that going on here.
I've got inventory I can equip items I could also pick up these items from around the world and depending
on what I equip that's going to affect the combat system.
So if I have the sword which is much more powerful than this hammer I am killing these minions in no
time.
And that's going to depend upon the saving system to save what you currently have in your inventory
and on the stat system because it is going to implement things in stats.
It's going to modify the stats just like progression and also it's going to be depended upon by combat
and control systems as well combat because combat needs to know what weapon you've got equipped control
because it needs to know how to pick things up and so on and so forth.
The next system going to be implementing is the special actions system.
This is special abilities also known as.
So if we take a look at this epic box battle scene I'm clearly losing healthcare so I've equipped a
special ability the health potion which is consumable so if I use it up as I do in the course of battling
this boss I have no more and he's eventually going to go ahead and get me killed.
And you can see this is dependent upon combat it's dependent upon inventories it's dependent on saving
and core.
So saving because we need to be able to remember which special actions we currently have enabled which
ones we have in our hot action ball.
It needs to depend upon inventories because we are going to be equipping actual actions from inventories
you might just do it through a spell book but it's pretty much like an inventory and it depends upon
combat because we can essentially have special actions that act like combat and control because we need
to be able to activate these special actions.
The next thing is going to be questing and to enable us to do questing we're going to have a dialog
system.
So the dialog system can look a little bit like this particularly it's gonna come in two parts.
This is the editor where you can add nodes you can write in your text you can then go ahead and make
the connections to create a tree which is going to be your conversation tree then that conversation
tree when you go up to somebody who wants to talk to you.
Looks kind of like this you get the options under the tree and the dialogue to choose from and you can
follow the tree down that way.
And as you can see the dialogue system is also control because we need to be able to click on and on
certain characters and for them to be able to activate the dialogue now we're gonna be creating the
attribute system which I hinted at it's going to be things like strength and so on in many games it's
called a stat system.
But basically these are things like strength dexterity very common to most arpeggios and you can see
I'm not doing well in this fight but if I increase my strength I'm doing far more damage to this ogre
and I will eventually be able to kill it.
That depend on stats because it's going to modify as we've seen the different stats such as your health
and your damage per second.
Going to have a progression import system which is going to bring in things from an Excel spreadsheet
into our progression so we can say things like at level 2 you should have this base health and so on.
And then polish it all off we're going to bring this together with some UI which is just depending on
a lot of stuff because it relies on a lot of things dialogue needs UI special actions inventories and
attributes all need UI.
Now that being said you don't have to take this course as part 1 then part 2.
This is you at the start.
You can choose to go down part one's route and do movement combat control stance and progression or
you could if you decide you prefer the features from Part 2.
Go ahead and start part 2 first.
You're not going to need the knowledge we're going to just import the code from part 1 but anything
we touch we're going to go over and most things we're not even going to touch.
They have been specifically decouple this way and split into the courses so that you can start Part
2 and just treat Part 1 as a library as if you were using Unity you know you don't know how Unity works
do you but you are able to use it the same with the part 1 code.
So if you're more interested in learning about inventories first please go where your motivation takes
you as you will have a much better learning journey and start Part 2 instead.
So there are these two completely decoupled paths and if you want to you can also go down the route
of doing saving or dialogue mini courses which are gonna be separate courses because they're quite applicable
to other games and they're quite bulky in themselves so you can go ahead and choose your learning journey
and I'd like you to share your choice with other students as well as your reasoning and what you're
most excited about.
So tell us what the plan is.
Use the sharing link against this lecture I'll take you to the forum with a pre populated post and which
modules are most exciting to you fill out that post.
Share with people and go and see what other people are excited to do and maybe you'll find something
in common to chat about and I'll hand you over to Rick for that lecture.