Hello and welcome in this lecture we're going to be hooking up and portals to each other.
So this I can go through to the next scene.
Okay.
That's nothing new.
But if I go through the other portal it actually takes me to a different place in the original sandbox
scene so we can use this to navigate across our world and we can link these portals together.
Let's dive in and see how.
So we've worked out that if we were to go into our transition level then we get teleported to this particular
portal this portal one.
What.
But I've got two portals in this level and I want to be able to decide which one we actually get teleported
to.
So how are we going to distinguish and connect portals.
Well the easiest way I find overdoing doing this and I took inspiration from the Unity 2D game kit which
is a great example project to have a look at for all sorts of things in fact we are heavily modelling
our transition and seen loading stuff off of the stuff that's going on on the 2D game kit and basically
just in general having a look at example projects is a great way to learn anyway.
That said the way we're going to do this is with an enum.
So we're going to create an enum and we're going to do it within the class.
Hopefully you've used an enum before.
I'm going to call my enum destination identifier and it is going to be the identifier of the destination
that we want to go to basically linking up the two destinations.
And the way I'm gonna do this is I'm just going to have a list of a b c d e and you can go on as long
as you want basically to give a number of identifiers you could do this with string references if you
wanted to but then you've got the whole issue of copy and paste when you do it with an enum.
I'll show you why it's really cool because if I create a serialized field that tells me the destination
so it's gonna have type of destination identifier and it's going to be called a destination.
If we go over into unity and wait for it to reload the code you can see that by default and enum is
a dropdown.
So this is a great way of making sure there are no spelling mistakes because I can say hey this portal
over here that's Portal A this portal over here that's portal B and that's a great start basically.
So let's have you do as a challenge the move to the correct portal now you've got an identifier it should
be fairly easy to make sure you're selecting the right portal to move to.
So update the get other portal method that's where you're going to be making the change and create a
counterpart to both portals.
So in transition look we've got two portals at the moment make sure there's two portals with corresponding
counterparts in the main sandbox scene as well.
And test it out and see that you can correctly get to the other portal pause video and have a go OK.
Welcome back.
So let's give this a shot shall we.
Basically we want to find a portal that isn't this portal and if the portal dots destination is not
equal to this destination so just the destination really then we also continue basically we're only
going to be retain the portal if it has the right destination and it's not us.
That should basically do the trick.
Let's go over to our sandbox scene and in here we are going to go ahead and try to to do fine.
So we've got portal one over here and the other portal I want to have over the bridge.
So this is just for testing purposes obviously this isn't a game design decision that is very sensible
but let's try and position this so drop the portal into the world and and resizing the collider to fit.
Then I'm gonna go ahead and start adding in the visual language of these gates and resizing them reshaping
them rotating them as Rick has been doing previously and just making a copy of this and scaling it and
changing it so it looks a bit higgledy piggledy and then I'm going to change the size of the collider
to match with these gates.
And we want to connect up this portals.
So the first portal in our level is going to destination a the second portal is going to be corresponding
with destination B and that's just check that out if we go over to the main scene.
I think I already changed this over sandbox to look at Portal 1.
Yes it's got destination of peace.
Let's try that out.
If we go from sandbox to I'm going to go over into portal B and there I am in this part of the level.
Looks like we need to rebuild that nav mesh so open up sandbox and then we can bring up the navigation
pane hop over there and hit back they go.
That seems to fix that issue so maybe if we go back to sandbox to now it should be better.
So I'm going to run through this portal and.
Mm hmm.
There we go.
Yep.
We were just in front of these gates.
If I go through the gates.
What happened there.
No reference to something.
What's going on.
You know I think what's happened is that we have forgotten to set the scene to load.
So this error message is a bit rubbish.
Let's improve it.
I'm going to on our transition.
Just gonna check and say if the scene to load is less than zero then we're going to want to return and
not do our transition.
But we also want to print out a log message so going to be a debug dot error log error.
And we are going to be logging out at the scene to load is not set.
And notice I need to return something from this.
I can just return no.
And hopefully that will do the trick.
It doesn't seem like it actually if I hover over the return statement it kind of gives me the hint it
says if you in an iron numerator you can either do a yield return statements return a value or a yield
break to end the iteration.
So here we actually need to do a yield break.
I actually learned something new there just by the hovering over things in Visual Studio.
So let's give this a go now.
Hopefully we should be able to go through the transition portal and back the other way or it should
give us an error which I'm expecting it'll give us an error go through try and go back the other way.
And sure enough at saying scene to load not set.
So let's try.
It should be able to just click on that log message it takes me a cake to the code.
Not very helpful but if I open up the sandbox and select Portal 1 then I should be able to in the inspector
say hey I want this to load.
Scene one please.
In the build index.
So let's try that.
So playing through is not going to work because I'll get attacked too much so I'm just going to pause
come out and move the player towards the bridge
and resume some getting chased again.
Let's go through the portal trying to escape.
And there we go.
We load into our transition area.
My portal placement could be much better.
Fact let's try and correct that a little bit.
So I'm basically going to go to the sandbox scene and find that little hillock that hides an exit point
and just trying to road it down a little bit with its rain to say that we'll be able to see when we're
going in to that trigger volume we can click on it.
Most crucially and I'm gonna move the player towards the end of the level so that I can play through
and test so that about wraps it up for this lecture now we are able to go through portals as we intended
and go back to the other side a set portal and I can use this transition level to basically go from
the beginning to the end of our map nicely.
Like so now just one thing I want to finish off is I moved my player.
I'm just gonna move it back because I don't want Rick telling me off for spoiling his moments.
Great stuff.
The next lecture we're gonna learn how to cover up this kind of jarring moment of transition with the
camera bouncing around in just a sudden transition by doing a fade out and fade in.
See you in that lecture.