Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we're gonna be learning how to edit the asset files in unity the asset files the scripts
of object files directly and figure out how well this formatting means what all this information actually
is and how we can change the structure of our progression to give us more flexibility and introduce
a stat enough so that we can add things to the enum easily and say we want to add experience rewards
to all of our characters.
Now we might want to add I don't know some sort of armor value you can go in and those really easily
now with a stack in them.
Let's dive in and see how it's done so our base stands at the moment isn't hooked up with experienced
reward.
And the reason for this is that to do that I would have to add another method to progression and this
method would be pretty much a duplicate of the get health.
So I'd like to do is create a system for us to add stats more easily and are going to do this very much
like we've done the character class where we can easily add a character class by editing this enum we're
gonna create a new enum.
So it's great file new and it's going to be called stats so yes.
And the idea of stat C S is to be an enum of things like health and experience reward.
So we're going to create a namespace first of all RPG stats and then inside we gonna create the enum
which is going to be just stat and the stats that we have here are health and we have experience reward
these are the first two stats that we're going with.
Obviously there will be more to come.
And what I'd like to show you is how our progression is currently laid out.
So we've got this visual conceptualization of the fact we've got a list of progression character classes
which in turn have a character class and a list of floats.
Now that we have seen in the ED If we go to our progression asset you can see how that is set up we've
got this list of character classes inside each character class.
We have got the character class variable and then we've got the health with which is an array of floats.
So that's one way of visualizing it but also we could actually read the contents of this file if I'd
just drag the file over into visual studio onto my onto my ball at the top then you can see that actually
that structure is pretty much reflected down at the bottom here from line 15 onwards for me.
You can see that it's very legible because unity is using a very legible system called Yammer or yet
another markup language.
But basically let's break this down line by line what is it doing how does it relate to structure.
So the progression structure we've currently got is character classes which is this variable at the
top level this list up here.
And underneath that we have got items so items you can see are denoted with this dash this hyphen and
then we have got a character class which is not actually the name of our class here.
That is the name of the variable it is saying there is a variable and its value is zero.
Why is its value zero.
Because character classes an enum and the value 0 corresponds to the player.
So that's a little bit harder to read but that is still the same information and then still within this
particular character class because we haven't had another hyphen yet we've got the health variable and
the health variable if we go back to progression is a list.
So we don't have the value straight away.
Instead we've got more hyphens which each have the health item.
So that's how you read e-mail and we go onwards.
So we then got another hyphen down at this level of indentation which means that it's part of this character
classes list and it is a character it has a value has a field of character class with one which if we
look at our character class is the grunts and so on we've got the health list of health which has just
got one item 40 and then the character class 3 which if we look it up is the archer and so on.
So that's got health as well.
Now the new structure I'm proposing so we keep the couch class the same.
We still have this character class identified by the character class a variable the character class
field but now instead of having health directly we're going to have a list a new item a new field called
stats and that is going to be a list of a new type of object and this type of object is going to have
a field called stat which is going to correspond to for example zero is gonna be the Health Stat and
as well another field that's going to have a part from identifying what stat it represents.
So it's going to have the levels of the stat.
So 50 and so on 50 100 200 400 same as the levels of floats that we had down here then we could have
other stats in this list as well.
So we can have the experience reward stat and the various progression levels of the experience reward
and then so on and so forth we can do the same thing with character one who can have substance as well.
A list of stats and a list of levels under each stat.
So that's the progression structure we're going to work towards.
Now if you feel confident in reproducing this in the progression scriptural object then do go ahead
and give it a shot.
If not then just follow me so we've got a progression character class we're going to want to do very
much the same thing in order to have a list of something in here.
So instead of having this list of health we are going to just comment that out for now because instead
what we want to have is a public variable we know it's called stats because that's what I've got in
here it's called stats.
In fact stats plural and it's gonna have a go to have a type.
It's doesn't show the type in Yama but we know it has to have a type in C sharp to call it the progression
stat like soap because following the convention that we had above.
So we've got the progression stat and we can create this.
It's gonna be a system serialized Ball class.
So let's use the system serialized ball system dots serialize a ball class progression stat and then
in the progression stat we know that we want to have this list it's not going to be called health anymore.
It's going to be a list of floats but it's going to be called levels because it's the different levels
of this particular stat.
And how do we identify the stat remember that there's one more variable in here which is the stat field
itself.
So we're gonna call it public.
What's the type going to be that types is going to be stat and I'm just gonna to call it stats.
So that tells us whether it's health whether it's experience points et cetera.
So that should work nicely.
I'm just going to basically comment out the return statement that's giving us issues in get health at
the moment so that it compiles and I'll go over just to have a look at what's going on with the progression
over in the inspector.
Now it's a bit broken because when you change the structure of scripts will object unity doesn't know
how to migrate your data into that new structure.
We've still got the player setup still got the grunt set up but now they've items in this list of stats
is no longer working.
In fact what we have got is as you can see is I made a slight error because what we wanted here was
a list of stats not just one progression stat.
So if I put the array notation there that should make it a list of stats.
Let's see if that's working navigates progression.
Then here we go.
We've got stats and list as currently of size zero.
Now I don't want to go and reproduce all the data.
You might not necessarily want to go and reproduce all the data so you can actually just edit up this
gamble file if you're careful you can edit it up like I was showing you in the slide.
Now to take care here because the Yemen file unlike C shop is space sensitive.
So if you get the indentation wrong then it does actually make a difference.
So I'm gonna just fast forward through doing that.
So as you can see what I've had to do is replace health with this kind of just little let level of nesting
and then moving these levels in a bit.
So if I go ahead and save that go over into unity it's not very happy with me.
Oh and the reason is because I'm missing this colon at the end of stats so stats should have a colon
on the end to initiate the list and then sure enough you can go and have a look and we've got ourselves
all the levels of health just as we had them previously but now they're nested one level deeper inside
our progression Stat object.
So that's just the way that you by the way you don't have to lose your data.
That's cool.
So time for a quick summary of this lecture.
We haven't got anything working yet it's a broken project but we'll fix it in the next lecture don't
worry.
What we have done is figured a little bit better how Unity is storing stuff and civilising stuff into
Yammer.
We've seen the Yammer with edited the Yamato and we have created another level of indentation and flexibility
in our progression stats.
Now we can have multiple character classes and we can have multiple stats as well both of which are
working through in.
And it's just one more level deep of less nesting for you to have lots and lots of flexibility.
The next lecture we're gonna look at hooking it all up so that we make our get health work.
Again.