In this video we're going to tune now enemy so that they have a different speed when they're walking.
As to when we have a combat moment you can see oh he's really chasing me down fast now.
We're also going to tweak our placement of our patrol pass just get everything tidied up and ready to
declare our combat aspect of our moment done.
So let's jump in and get started.
Let's start by updating our enemy patrol parts where they need to be patrolling.
I'm going to grab the existing patrol parts and then I'll need to make a couple more so we've got this
patrol path zero at the back there.
Who's going to use that over here for the gentleman who's patrolling around in the shrubbery is up the
back here and I grab the waypoints just move it around a little bit so he's not doing such a massive
patrol.
Yeah.
Come forward a little bit and then to speed up the video for this bit and then within our eye controller
we drag in patrol path.
So he's using patrol path these two guys at the front.
I think I'll just have them standing stationary.
They gods.
After all we could have a little bit of milling around but I'll leave them stationary so this one in
the middle here I'll grab the patrol path that I've got.
Patrol path one in the back.
Just change the waypoints around a little bit.
I'll speed up this part of the video.
I just kind of wandering around in a circle which I think is all cool.
Now he is enemy number two enemy number two needs patrol path.
Number one Okay then the guy at the back here I want him to be wandering around a little bit as well
up the back.
So we will duplicate the patrol path.
I'll duplicate patrol path.
One controlled D grab this patrol path.
Where are you there.
Leave it up to the back.
This is only got just the four points I think four points is enough for this guy.
And once again I'll speed up the video as I just move around these waypoints and if this tough enemy
currently has a patrol path a sign will just click up here and assign none.
So no patrol path enemy four correct three has none at the moment.
But we need to assign that patrol path.
We just made which was the patrol path to the enemy out the back so you do this however works for you
and your game you don't have to follow along exactly with me.
Just make sure that all enemies have a patrol path as the patrol path.
Game Object up the top there.
So first guy doesn't need one but he has one.
So let's click on that and set it to none.
Just make sure you don't want them patrolling then they don't have a patrol one that's cool too.
He's got 1 3 he's go on for he's got one and tough enemy does not have one.
Perfect.
Okay.
And offscreen I've been tidying up my red marks that I had on the ground.
I've nearly got them all just paint over those last couple of little bits.
Not trying to make it look too amazing just to get the read out the way so it's not confusing.
Okay now I want to show you a little bit of a problem that I've got at the moment and see if we can
figure out a solution together to speed the video up as I run around the back to my patrol.
You can see as my enemies walking around his work he's chasing me now.
Well you can see when he chases me he chases me at a pretty old slow pace.
I can easily just run away thanks for a bit.
And when are you patrolling.
He's patrolling at exactly the same pace as well which I think is a little bit faster than normally
patrolling to be kind of meandering a little bit.
So the fact that both the speeds are the same patrolling and chasing is something that bugs me a little
bit.
So I wanna resolve that and give this to you as a slightly different challenge.
It's a problem with a solution challenge but I want you to think about the solution not necessarily
implement it although you're welcome to implement it if you're ready to do that.
Sam and I have talked about it.
We came out with different solutions so there are plenty of ways to skin a cat.
I'm going to show you Sam solution after we've had to think about it because Sam is far wiser than I
am about these matters and I think his solution is pretty amazing.
So currently we've got a problem where we have one speed for patrolling and for chasing.
I want you to write out a plan or pseudo code for how you would solve this.
So where would you put particular lines how would you change your logic.
What classes or what scripts would you.
I've got here somewhere.
Which classes would you modify how you manage the two different speeds so how do you expose the tuning
variables.
What's the input to it.
So one of these ones where once you just have a look at your code have a look through your scripts and
think about it conceptually how would you go about having a patrol speed and a chase speed and having
them different.
So there's you challenge take that on have a think about it if you would like to share your answer in
the forum.
That would be awesome so we can see what you came up with.
And you can brag if you think you came up something cool and I will see you shortly.
OK.
I'll also play my play I got killed.
Okay.
Thanks for that God at least you're doing a job wonderful.
Now I'm gonna go ahead and open up visual studio and jump into our movie script.
So my natural inclination with this was to go into the A.I. controller and say OK here is where we have
the attack behavior behavior.
Here's where we have the patrol behavior.
Let's just make the speed during patrol behavior slower than the speed during attack behavior.
That's one way you could do it.
Sam had a great point which was well our movie is the thing that is controlling our nav mesh agent.
That is the place where we're making changes and it's our nav mesh agent that we're going to need to
change on our enemies too.
Let me just open up one of our enemies here to show you that the speed is where we're changing how fast
or how slow they go.
So that's the thing we wanted to be changing nav mesh agent dot speed and the best place to do that
is within the movie.
So let's start the process first of all I want to create a concept of a maximum speed.
So at any point I can say that maybe the players maximum speed is 10 whereas the enemies maximum speed
is 2.
So I want to have that control cells within my movie script.
I'm going to serialize field.
This will be a float and I will call it max speed so the maximum speed that you can go and I'll initialize
this at 6:00 just because that's what we've had our speed at to date.
And now likewise I want a place where I can change the speed of the enemies while they're doing their
patrols.
I'm going to go into the A.I. controller ad myself a new variable in here.
So again serialize fields so it's exposing the inspector float.
And this we will call patrol patrol speed for action.
OK.
And I'm going to initialize that at zero point two F so point two of whatever our maximum speed is.
So if our maximum speed is six then point two is going to be a speed of 20 percent of six.
Now why a fraction.
Well we're creating this notion of.
Here is your maximum speed.
And then when you're patrolling you're going at a smaller fraction or a smaller percentage of that speed.
And if we want to change the speed in other places for example if you want to have an enemy that gets
injured then you could have injured Speed fraction in the future.
Still equating back to a calculation on our overall maximum speed.
So back over into move it let's go and find where we need to change the speed stop move action and move
to the areas we're looking at here start move action is cold in a couple of places where we're starting
to move the the enemy the enemy II also to move the player.
So we need to take into consideration here that the player also needs to be not broken by our approach
when we're changing the enemy.
So when we call start move action what I want to do is require whatever is called it to pass in a type
float speed for action and that's what we're just creating over now.
II controller a moment ago this fraction of point two so when we're calling this we want to be passing
in what's the fraction and then we will be using that in our move to destinations so destination comma
Speed fraction and then of course moved to is complaining because right below which is where we have
our move to method we need to give it the extra parameter of float and again we'll call it Speed fraction
so right after where we've said where the destination is we're going to add a new line and this is where
we'll be changing the speed.
So we'll be accessing our nav mesh agent dot speed and that will equal our max speed multiplied by a
fraction.
Now I'm going to put in a little bit of a protection here where we're going to use math f dot clamp
0 1 which is a really cool way of saying that whatever value is in our parentheses needs to be between
0 and 1 we're clamping it so we're forcing it to be between 0 and 1 and then what are we passing in
we're passing in Speed fraction and then semicolon.
And you know to protect ourselves even further I'm going to go back to the II controller and right above
where we have our patrol Speed fraction just to make sure that it's impossible for us crazy designers
to break I'm going to add in square braces range parentheses zero comma one and that means that whatever
patrol Speed fraction is can only be from zero to one.
Saving that bike every day.
Mover now that's going to have broken a couple of things because we now have an extra parameter that
we're asking to be passed in so going to highlight smart move action and right click find all references
and open these up.
The first one is in here.
Now this is broken because it's not passing in the Speed fraction that we're looking for and can see
within eye control a What is that fraction gonna be what we've just gotten created that variable right
up at the top patrol's Speed fraction.
So in here it's going to be start move.
Action.
Next position comma patrol speed friction and let's see if there's any other instances in here.
Stop move.
Action.
Okay.
So interact with movement get mouse button down.
This is in the player controller.
So see when I did the final references it's opened up our various scripts that we're looking at here
we're currently in the play a controller stop move action.
It is passing in hip point and then what do we want to have for the player.
Well at this point we always want the player to be going at full speed so we're gonna say one f in here.
It's okay to put one one is not a magic number in this instance it's just saying do the maximum the
maximum value that we have.
And then what else do we have the last one.
That was the one that we've already been changing.
Okay.
So then we are back into move to the other place that we changed was moved to.
So again highlight that right click final references.
This will change over on our left here in our fighter script.
We have let's see move to target transform position while we're in this fighter mode.
We want fighting to be at full speed don't we.
So again micro challenge for you what do we put in here.
Putting one if and then what do we have moved to they were the ones that we've changed already back
from our movie script and I think that's pretty good.
We've updated the areas that are calling start move action and move to save up all of our scripts make
sure it's all saved.
Looks all pretty safe to me jump back over into unity find one of our enemies and find this guy at the
back here he's enemy number four.
Let's see in our move are whereas move at the moment nav mesh agent close that up just one little note
just make sure you don't get confused there's a speed variable here that is not going to work if you
change that because we've gone and overwritten that with mover and with our A.I. controller let's race
around Assad to speed up the video a little bit as I'm running around to the side OK.
Watch from a distance OK he's dawdling along nice and slow fast to speed that up.
Pop pop pop pop he's gonna get even faster up to the point where he runs which is really cool we now
have our slider that allows us to change how fast our enemy is patrolling and then let me just check
when I run up I'll put it back to point two when I run up the trees kind of in the way isn't it.
Now he chases me and he's count for it he's chasing me down there's a little bit of foot sliding there
which looks a little bit wacky but I'm gonna leave it in because it's just the fact that our animation
when we're punching he he's locked his feet in the position but I want him to be able to do that to
be at a punch and kind of chase me down we kind of need a different animation where he's swinging and
running at the same time which I don't have at the moment so I'll leave it as he is but I'm pretty happy
with that I'm happy that we've updated our patrol behavior now look at me dying now it's not going to
be possible for us just to sprint the whole way through town past all these guards run straight to the
end and say Well that doesn't matter they can't keep up with me if I try to do that which is a kind
of fun thing to do they're right on my tail maybe I'll have them a little bit slower so I can get away
from them a little bit only to have them all keeping chase for quite some time till I get to the end
trying to fight the big boss and I've got these gaggle of guys trying to beat me up and which they successfully
do.
Okay so I'm happy with that now happy that this is a combat moment we've got some choice we've got our
enemies behaving in a clever way we've add a little bit more depth to our patrol I think now we're ready
to switch over to our cinematic moments so great work and I'll see you in the next video.