Hello and welcome in this lecture we're going to be setting it up so that we can set our experience
reward progressions.
And then we can go through the world and beat people up so beat up this guard and we just want to see
that his progression does indeed get the experience points.
If I run over to the Archer and beat him to a pulp then we should see that he gets a different level
of experience rewards and gets 30 points which was indeed what he had in the progression setup.
So let's dive into the lecture and see how it's done so in the last lecture we saw that we had broken
our get health method and this lecture were going to be fixing that.
So first of all I want to change it from being get health to something more general basically a get
start method instead.
And how can we do this well we can now make use of our stat class that we've got as one of the arguments.
So we're gonna give it a character class but we're also gonna give it a stat and catching a lead with
the stat because that's the most important thing is the methods name.
So stat is the first argument then we can say it's the stat for the character class and this particular
level.
Okay so this is how get stats being modified Now you notice it's giving an error again inconsistent
accessibility we've done it again the E enum needs to be a public enum in order for us to not have that
error.
So the stat needs to be a public enum.
And then what.
Okay.
So at this point what we're going to do is change out the body of get stats.
So that actually works with a new progression structure.
Now if you feel confident in doing that for yourself then do go ahead and pulls a video and have it
go.
Otherwise just follow along with me.
So caution crucially we've got two lists now we've got the list of the top level which is the character
classes.
We've also got the progression stats list.
So we're gonna need to for loops one for each of those lists.
And in fact we've got another list the floats.
But that when we just index directly rather than having to do a for loop looking for the character class.
So what we're going to do well we're going to okay we're going to have a look and do a full loop but
if I do a full loop inside this if statement we're going to have lots of levels of indentation.
So I'm gonna break that level of indentation by just doing a instead of if progression cash class and
not equal ends do and then continue.
So we're going to break out this loop iteration a little bit early and go and continue to look for other
character classes because this is not the droid that we were looking for.
Okay so I'm going to then remove this body or I'll keep it around because we want that later and I'm
going to include a for each loop like so that's gonna go over what it's going to go over these stat
in the progression class.
So the progression class dots stat stats in fact and then we're going to get a progression stat is the
variable type and also going to use it for the name but with a look lowercase P so then we're gonna
do exactly the same thing.
Basically you can do for if the progression stat so the progression class the progression stat dot stat
is not equal to the stat that was passed in then we want to continue because we are looking for a different
stat and then finally if we have got the right thing this is where we want a return statement.
So just paste that in here instead of doing the progression class they were looking in the progression
stat for the health.
Okay.
So that should hopefully make sense.
Except it's not the health it is the levels.
So that pretty much fixes it up.
Now one more thing I want to do here is I would like to guard against a situation where we are looking
for a level that is not in this array.
So the way I'm gonna do this is just to say Hang on.
If the progression stat dot levels is not the right length we're going to continue in our for loop.
So how we're going to do that.
So the progression starts levels dot length and a relationship.
Not quite sure what the relationship is with the level that is being passed in.
So have a think about that what do you think the relationship should be between these two.
Well if we reason about it.
If we had an array of length zero and we are looking for a stat at level two for example that's clearly
wrong.
But let's think about the edge case right.
We've got an array of length one and we're looking for this stat at level 1.
That should work whereas the stat at level 2 should no longer work.
So we've got this relationship where this would be one and 2 this would be wrong.
And but at 1 it would be correct and at zero it doesn't really exist.
But say we had array of length 2 instead at 1 it would be fine at 2 it would be fine and at 3 it would
no longer be fine.
So what we're saying is that the length of the array has to be greater than or equal to the level.
So another way of flipping that round is to say that the length of the array is in fact less than the
level.
And if it is less than the level then we should continue with our search basically.
So that should pretty much do us for the get stat.
So now I'd like you to refactor forget stat in the rest of the code base and propagate the changes through
there as best you can.
And in fact I want to clarify that in base stat I think we can make this method here instead of having
a get health and get experience award.
I think we can just replace all of that with a get stat method there as well.
So find the errors and fix the errors if you can pause a video and give it a shot.
OK.
Welcome back.
So as I said we're starting with base stat we're going to change this over to get health so and I'll
get healthcare stat and we want to pass in these stat class but we don't have one.
We have to get that from this method.
And change the method to get stats in base stats and this stat that we want to get.
So depending on who is asking they might want different things we might want health we might want experience
to level up we might want other things that we add into this in a.
It's a later date.
So get stat is going to pass on these stats to the progressions get stat method and that means we no
longer need to get experienced reward because that is now redundant.
We can just do get stats with the enum onset to experience reward now that's created some issues particularly
in the health component which I think is the only component at the moment that gets things from base
stat but it won't be in the future and it's in three places.
So we've got one place that is getting health so we can do a get stat and then stats dot health instead
and we can do that in the other location that is getting the health as well which is down here where
we're doing the percentage points calculation and then there's one more place which is a ward experience
where actually we're not getting the health but we are getting the experience reward.
Okay so that should do the trick.
Now we need to go and update our progression to make sure that the progression is going to return experience
reward for the grunt and the Archer.
So I'm gonna go ahead and duplicate at this level here.
The stats list we're going to duplicate element zero and change the stat to be the experience reward.
And I'm going to give experience reward of 10 for the base level level 1 grunt and I'm going to duplicate
again the array element for hell of a health and change over to experience reward and experience reward
for the archer is going to be 20 and level 1 because an archer is slightly more advanced or something
like that.
So I'm going to go ahead and hit play and see if we can get this.
So attack the first enemy I'm gonna look at the players experience see what it's doing starts off at
zero goes up to 10 when I kill that enemy and if I go and kill the second enemy over here then sure
enough that gives me 20 points instead so we can tell that it is using the data from the progression
and we also saw that health was still working as expected.
So it's all in all what we've now got is a more generic way of getting stats into the system we can
add more stats in here and then all we've got to do is update our progression to have the relevant stats
that we want and we can use it somewhere else in the code base without having to pass it through base
stats and rewrite lots of code.
So there is a mission here because I had to go into player to look up the experience points.
We would like an experienced display as well and we would like those experience points to persist just
like the health points when we go between worlds or we just save a game.
So that's going to be the subject of the next lecture.
See you then.