Let's now discuss the scatter plot. A scatter plot is a type of plot or
a mathematical diagram that uses Cartesian coordinates to display
values for two variables of a dataset. It is usually used to show the
correlation between two variables.
We will create a scatter plot to show the relationship between the
actual sale price and the overall material quality.
So I am going to rename the sheet to Scatter Plot.
And then I will choose the scatter plot visualization type, and the
field wells section is enabled too. In the X‑axis, I will choose the
overall material qualification, while in the Y‑axis, I am going to
choose the actual sale price.
And, as you can see,
the overall trend is that an increase in the actual sale price when there is an increase in the overall material quality.