Let's now discuss the bubble chart.
A bubble chart is a variation of a scatter plot in which the
data points are replaced with bubbles.
Bubble charts use the size of the bubble to indicate a
third dimension of the comparison.
I will create a bubble chart to find the relationship between the actual
sale price and the overall material quality and taking into account the
size of the garage as a third dimension.
So I am going to rename the sheet to Bubble Chart,
and I will choose the scatter plot visualization type.
In the X‑axis, I will choose the overall material quality,
while in the Y‑axis, I will choose the actual sale price.
Up to now, our bubble chart looks like a scatter plot.
Let's add the third dimension. And for the third dimension, I am going
to choose the average garage area. And I will change the aggregate
type to average. As you can note, the bubbles have different sizes to
indicate different garage sizes.
However,
I would like to limit the results for one year to have better visibility,
and I will do that using a filter. A quick size filter makes it possible to
limit visual view to a specific filtered value.
Let's filter this bubble chart by the year sold column. I
will click in the filters in the left.
It tells me that there is no filter applied in the selected visual.
I will click on Create one.
Then, I will choose the Year Sold column, and I will click on the filter.
As you can see,
it automatically recognized all unique values in the column, and it
makes it possible for me to choose a specific value.
Let's choose 2010 and apply the filter. And as you can
see in the visual, for houses sold in 2010, as the overall material quality increases, the sale price and garage area increase.