Let's now discuss the pie and donut charts.
I will rename my visual to Pie and Donut Charts.
Let's just start with a pie chart.
A pie chart is a circular statistical graphic,
which is divided into slices to illustrate numerical
proportion. So, I will create a pie chart to show the
percentage of sale price by the fireplace quality.
I will choose the Pie Chart visualization. In the Group/Color I will
choose the Fireplace Quality and in the Value I will choose the
Actual SalePrice. And, more specifically,
I would like to look into the average sale price.
As we can see,
houses with excellent fireplace quality take around
28% of the average sale price.
But let's say that I am interested in seeing those
values for a specific year sold, so I will add a filter for that.
I will click on Filter on the left and I will create a new
one. And I will choose the Year Sold.
I will click on the Year Sold filter, and let me choose 2010 once again.
And I click Apply. And as we can see that houses with excellent fireplace
quality took 30% of the average sale price.
And now we can proceed with discussing donut charts.
A donut chart is a variation of a pie chart except that it has a hole
in the center, which makes it look like a donut.
I can follow the same exact steps I did to create the diagrams.
However, I want to show you a quick shortcut.
If I click on the three dots in the right of the visual and I
click on Duplicate visual, and I would choose to duplicate the
visual in this sheet. Simply,
I can change the visualization type to a donut chart. And here is our donut chart.