Let's now discuss the TreeMaps.
A TreeMap is a data visualization technique that is used to
display hierarchical data using nested rectangles.
So, I will create a TreeMap to show the average actual sale price
and the average of garage area by year sold.
That sounds like a lot, but you will see it.
I will rename my sheet to TreeMap,
and I will choose the TreeMap visualization type. In the Group
by, which is used to group different items in rectangular form,
I will choose the year sold. And I will also format the year
sold for more readability.
The size of the rectangle will be the average garage area. And
let's color it with the actual sale price.
The darker color indicates the higher sale price while the lighter
colors indicate the lower actual sale price.
And, as you can see, year 2009 has the largest rectangle, which is the highest average garage area.