Let's now discuss the KPI and gauge visualizations, which are
used to measure the progress towards a goal.
I will rename my sheet to KPI and Gauge. And what I will do here, I
will just create a simple visualization that aims to provide an
executive summary of our progress towards a certain goal. And this
goal will be the percentage of the total actual sale price to the
total expected sale value.
I will change the visualization type to KPI. And in the value,
which represents the current value, I will choose the sum of
actual sale price. And in the target,
I will choose the sum of expected sale price. And as we can see,
the actual sale price is 88% from the target.
Let's now duplicate this visual and create a gauge. And I
will change the visualization type to gauge. And here it provides the same information, but a nicer look.