Let's now discuss the area charts.
Area charts have a pattern similar to a line chart.
However, the space between each line and the X‑axis is filled with a certain
color. Area charts are ideal for indicating a change among different
datasets. So we will create an area chart to compare the housing prices over
time for different zoning classifications.
I will rename the chart to Area Charts, and I will change
the visualization type to area line chart.
The area line chart is similar to the line chart,
but it's filled to help visualizing the differences between the lines.
So I will start by choosing the year sold in the X‑axis. And I will sort
it in an ascending fashion and improve the formatting.
Then, I will put the average actual sale price in the value field, and I will
differentiate the colors using zoning classification. And now,
as you can note, it's very easy to visualize the actual difference
between the average sale prices in a specific year between different houses in different zoning classifications.