And now it's the time for the table,
which I believe is a straightforward visualization,
and we use it a lot in our daily life.
I will create a new sheet and call it Table.
Then, I will change the visualization type to table.
Let's assume that I want to see the count of sales period.
So in the group by field, I will put the year sold. And in
the value, I will put actual sale price,
and I will change the aggregate type to count, and let's
rename the column to Number of Cells.
I will click on the gear in the right of the table, and then I will go to
value column names, and I will rename it to Number of Cells. And as you can see, that column has been renamed.