Let's quickly recap what we have learned in this module.
We started by positioning AWS QuickSight in AWS Big Data Specialty exam,
and we identified that it lies in the fifth domain,
which is the data visualization domain, and it's worth 12% of the exam score.
Then we discussed the importance of data visualization.
We stated the reasons why we would like to do data visualization,
such as seeing data on aggregate levels.
Then we introduced AWS QuickSight and its benefits.
Then, we dived deeper and discussed the core components of AWS QuickSight,
which are different data sources we can load data from,
such as databases and APIs, datasets that we load our data to,
which can be backed by SPICE engine, and analysis,
which is a collection of visuals, different visuals which can be bar charts,
pie charts, and so on.
In the next module,
we will see AWS QuickSight in action, and we will make our
hands dirty with a demo as we will discuss. Are you already?