There are also different types of garbage collection. So one type is do nothing.
The garbage collector might just decide never to run,
never to do anything, no memory gets freed, but we do still
have the guarantee of not collecting live objects, and
that's obviously a good thing.
There's also reference counting garbage collection, and a good
example of this is the COM programming environment.
In COM, applications make calls to two functions, AddRef
and Release. AddRef increments a count on an object, and
Release decrements a count.
When that count goes to 0,
the object is no longer being referenced, and the object can now
clean itself up and remove itself from memory.
We have mark and sweep garbage collectors. With a mark and sweep
garbage collector, when the garbage collector runs,
it runs in two phases.
The mark phase walks through all live memory,
marking that memory as still being alive.
And the sweep phase removes all unused memory.
And this leaves us with memory that could be fragmented.
We have a copying garbage collector, and typically
with a copying garbage collector,
this will work hand in hand with something like a mark and sweep collector.
In this case,
after the sweep phase, all the memory that's left is copied from one buffer
to another. And at the same time, once the memory is being copied, we'll
rearrange it so that it's no longer fragmented.
We also have generational garbage collectors.
The idea behind a generational garbage collector is that if
an object survives a garbage collect,
it's likely to be an object that's going to be around for a long time.
In that case,
once an object survives one garbage collect, the garbage
collector may not look at it again for a while,
and this improves the performance of the garbage collector. And finally,
there's incremental garbage collectors.
And in fact,
the generational garbage collector is a form of incremental garbage collection.
So an incremental garbage collector is a garbage collector that doesn't look
at all the memory all the time during the garbage collect.
And as we can see from this, garbage collectors tend not to be just of one type.
So we tend to have a mixture of mark and sweep, copying, generational within a single garbage collector.