So when the garbage collector collects objects in the young generation,
this is called a minor garbage collection.
And what happens is this.
Objects are allocated initially into the Eden space.
When the garbage collector runs, objects are copied into this survivor space,
so it's copied into the empty survivor space.
Objects from the survivor space that was used during the last garbage collect
also get copied back across into this new survivor space,
and the survivor spaces are now swapped.
So the next time a garbage collection runs,
what was the old survivor space is now the new survivor space,
and that will be used to do the copying.
The next allocation will then get allocated into the Eden space.
So it looks something like this.
Here we have some root references to objects that are both
in Eden space and in the survivor space.
The initial survivor space is called the from space.
At this point, somebody has tried to allocate some memory.
We try and allocate that object into the Eden space.
Eden space is full, so we're we'll kick off a minor garbage collection.
What happens now is you walk the heap, we mark the objects,
and then we copy the objects into the new survivor space.
The figures on these objects, 0 and 1 here,
show how many garbage collects these objects have previously survived.
So the object in the survivor space has previously
survived one garbage collection; whereas,
the newly allocated objects in the Eden space survived zero garbage collections.
But we'll see that as we copy them to the to space, this number increases.
We go from 0 to 1 for each of these objects.
And then when we move the object from the survivor
space into this new survivor space, its count gets increased to 2.
And then finally, the Eden space is cleared,
and the survivor spaces are swapped.
And the next allocation happens into the Eden space within our count of 0,
i.e. this thing hasn't yet survived a garbage collection.
So minor collection happens when the young generation is full.
When the old generation is full, then a major garbage collection happens.
Now major garbage collections are going to be slower than minor
garbage collections as a major garbage collection is going to walk
through a large section of the heap.
It's also possible that memory that's been allocated has been
paged so that memory has to be paged back in.
So we'd like these major garbage collections to run less
frequently than the minor garbage collections.
So a major garbage collection is triggered when the old
generation or the tenured space is full.
It will typically, on the Oracle Java VM,
collect both the old and the young generations at the same time.
Well this is really called a full GC. A major GC collects the old
generation, a full GC collects the young and the old generations at the
same time. But the terms tend to be used interchangeably.
So with a major garbage collect,
memory gets copied from the young generation to the old generation.
So this is called promotion. So the JVM will eventually
promote memory into the old generation.
This happens after the memory has survived a certain number of garbage collects.
It also happens if survivor space is full.
If the survivor space is full,
there's nowhere for objects that have survived a garbage‑collect
from the Eden space to go into that survivor space.
So we'll start promoting from the survivor space into the old generation.
There's also a flag you can pass the JVM to say always
tenure, i.e. always create objects inside the old
generation. So it works something like this.
So here we have a similar picture to before. We have a number of objects in
the Eden space that have yet to survive a garbage collect.
We have a large object in the old generation with a collection count of 9. It
survived nine garbage collections. And we have an object in the survivor
space that has survived eight garbage collections.
When we run the GC,
we'll notice that the objects from the Eden space get copied to the to
space, and the object that was in the survivor space has now survived many
garbage collections and so is promoted to be part of the old generation. As
well as objects being moved to the old generation once they've survived a
number of garbage collects, it's also possible to allocate objects directly
into the old space.
Now there's no direct way of doing this.
There's no JVM option to say always allocate objects in the old space.
But what you can do is set this option on the VM called
PretenureSizeThreshold, and then objects larger than n bytes will be allocated into this old space directly.