Welcome to the use of MICRA services section.
This is the section that you have all been waiting for.
Here we are going to start with hands on coding, but what exactly are you going to build?
Let's again have a look at the implementation and deployment view of the architecture of everything
that we are going to build in this course, in this section, we are going to implement micro services
for our user domain.
We are going to use securest to segregate a user domain into two micro services, including a user command
API and the user query API.
The User Command API is going to handle several user commands and once handled, it is going to raise
user events and stored into an event store using a Mongo DB event storage engine.
And then it is going to publish these events to the event.
Plus the query API will then subscribe to these events.
Once handled, it will use the event payload to create and update the user database, which will also
be stored in a Mongo DB database.
Our query API will also expose in a restful endpoint that will allow client applications to query our
user data.
Now let's zoom in a little further.
The component diagram details all the projects, packages and software components that you're going
to implement in the section.
We will start by implementing the domain models, including the main user model, the account model,
which will contain the user credentials such as username and password, and the role model, which is
going to be an enum that we use for specifying the user roles for authorization purposes.
They after we are going to create the user command objects, including the registered user command,
update user command and remove user command objects.
We will then define the event objects, including the user registered event user updated event and user
removed event.
Once our command and event objects are created, we will create the user aggregate.
The user aggregate will form the core of the User Command API.
It is where the commands will be handled and once handled, events will be raised stored into the event
store via the event sourcing repository and published to the event press notice.
The event sourcing repository is placed outside of the User Command API project because it forms part
of the action framework and is abstracted for the sake of simplicity.
We will then implement the user, event handler and initial user repository.
The user event handler will subscribe to the event, pass and handle the User Register event to create
a new user record via the user repository into the user database.
In the same way it will handle the user updated event and use it to update the user record in the user
database via the user repository and likewise use the user.
Remove the event to delete a user record from the user read database.
We will then create three controllers, including a registered user controller, update user controller
and remove user controller to expose restful endpoints that client applications can use to create,
update and delete users.
We will also create a base response DTA object that will contain a message field that most of the command
type controllers will return.
However, for the registered user controller, we will create a registered user response DTA object
that will extend the base response update to include the idea of the newly created user.
The after we will define our query objects, including a find all users query, find user by idee,
query and search users query.
Then we will implement and user query handler that will handle these queries and query data from the
user database via the user repository.
At this point, we will be extending the user repository to add some custom query methods and finally
we are going to implement a user lookup controller that will expose a racial endpoint, that will allow
client applications to query user data and it will return a user lookup response Tyto that will contain
a field for list of users which return one or more users.
And likewise the user lookup response D2 will extend the base response.
Teto, I hope you are now excited to start building your user Marcus services.