Navigators started at Spring Dot Io so that we can generate our bank account MICRA service projects
like we've done with our user MICRA services projects for both automation tool use Mavin Language Java
Spring Boot Version two point four point one as the latest table release version at the time of the
recording.
Again, make the group name come that spring bank for artifact.
Let's use bank I.C.C. for count dot com the dot API for description, bank account command API project
leave the packaging type jar and select Java 15.
Then we add the spring whip dependancy.
And spring security for the command API, click on Generate.
Now for a bank account query API changed that to bank account query API project, and we need to add
two more dependencies.
Spring day to JPA.
And the my sequel driver click on Generate again.
And then finally, let's generate our bank account called Project.
Change that to core and then we can take away the spring rape dependency because we will not expose
any restful endpoints.