In this lecture, I'm going to show you how to containerised your first Springburn military service,
navigate to the user dot Oath 2.0 project, go ahead and add a new file to the root of the project and
call it DOCA file.
First, we're going to add the from instruction, the from instruction initializes and Newbold's stage
and set the base image for subsequent instructions.
For us, the base image will be a JDK image.
I'm using open JDK 14, therefore my base image is going to be open JDK 14, JDK Alpine next line arge
jor underscore file.
He target forward slash Strix Daija.
Then copy the copy instruction copies the new files or directories from the source and add into the
file system of the container at the path destination.
And then the last line entry point.
They need square brackets and array of arguments, including Java.
Hyphen Jor.
Forward slash Dodger.
OK, and that is all we have to do, so as you can see, the darker file is very simple, but is all
we need to run a springboard application.
It literally only needs Java and a jar file.
The build will create a spring user and a spring group to run the application.
It will then copy the project files into the container as a jar that'll be executed in the entry point.
The array form of the Docker file entry point is used so that there is no shell wrapping the Java process.
Now, let's open the application at properties file of a project at the moment we are connecting to
our Mongar DBE database.
Using localhost, however, localhost means something else to the container.
Each container will interpret localhost is local to the container and not local to the host.
Therefore, we need to change the host to the name of the container.
We can get the name of the container by running the Docker P is command in Lennix.
You need to add SEDAR at the start of the command and in windows the equivalent would be to run command
prompt topower shell as administrator.
OK, there you can see all of our containers that are running at the moment.
Now, instead of overriding localhost in our application or properties file, we will make use of spring
profiles.
This will come in very handy because our local host will similarly not be able to resolve the container
names when we try to build our projects locally from our ideas.
Spring profiles provide a way to segregate parts of our application configuration and make it any available
in certain environments.
So let's go ahead and create a copy of our application or properties file and rename it to Application
Hyphen Docker Properties.
If we set our spring profile as DOCA, it will let this application hyphen Dockett or properties file.
Thus, the profile name should be specified after application hyphen and before DOT properties.
In the real world, you will most likely have development, staging and production profile names.
I'm just using Dukkha to emphasise that profile names can be anything and to distinguish between our
local development and Dukkha configuration files.
Now, go ahead and open the application docket or properties file.
Let's change localhost to monga container.
OK, now let's go ahead and build our project.
We are now ready to build our rocket image.
This can be done by using the Duck-billed command, so let's type Dukkha bold hyphen T for tech and
then the name of our container, let's call our container user hyphen OS two and then space dot.
The DOT represents the present working directory.
We are Dukkha file is located and then hit enter.
The first time we do this it will download the base image.
OK, the Donald has been completed and ought to 2.0 out service has been packaged together as a darker
image.
Now, importantly, a darker container will only be able to communicate with other Dukkha containers
if they are in the same network.
Therefore, we need to find out what the network name is that are Mongar DB container is running in.
We can do this with the Dukkha Inspect Command, so let us type Dukkha inspect
Monga container, which is our Monga DBE container hyphen if and then in quotes two sets of curly brackets
and then in the curly brackets.
Jason space dot network settings.
Dot networks.
OK, hit enter.
So the very first field, the Spring Bank Net, is the name of the network.
So now let's run our docker image as a dock, a container dock run Typhon defo detached so that it's
not attached to this terminal window.
Specify the ports, port 884, internal and external.
Let's give it a name or two hyphen service.
This doesn't have to be the same as the container name and.
Then for network, let's specify Spring Bank Net, put it in the same network as the Monga DV container.
We can then type Desh E to set an environmental variable, we want to set the active spring profile
to DOCA so that the container will use the application DOCA that properties file that we have just created.
You can do this by setting spring and the scope profiles underscore active equal to DOCA restart, saying
that our container should always restart.
Most importantly, I use this so that the container starts up when the host starts up or when it fails.
Let's copy our image name right at the end and that gives a nice good.
And if you run DOCA pace, you'll see that our oath to service is now running on Port 884 in Dukkha.
OK, open up Posman and make a request.
And there you can see that we have a JWT.
Let's run the docker containers stop just so that you can see that we are actually connecting to the
container and not our localhost, so let's stop our oath to service.
Let's try again.
Let me show you this.
It's not running dry again and no connection.
OK, let's clear our screen for more space.
Then you can run pseudo docker containers, start all to life and service, and that'll start docker
container get hit send and again we have a JWT.
Now, you might ask me, but hang on, how do I get that image onto a server?
And the answer is the Docker hub repo.
So go ahead and open your browser and navigate to hub dot, dot, dot com and register a free docker
hub account.
I already have one, so I'm going to log into mine.
Now I'm not going to give you my password, but this is also a free one, like the one that you are
busy registering.
So when you log in, you can see the repo and if you want to push images to it is the docker push command
with my username, forward slash repo name, kolon tag name.
So after you've done your registration, you can run the Docker login command, provide your username
and your password.
OK, and the doctors should give us a message saying that we are logged in, logging succeeded like
you can see there.
And then again, let's run Dr. Pace and we can also run duck tag.
Now we are going to tag our image, our local image, to a Dark Reaper image.
So copy everything just before the tag name pasted there and then our image name will use at the end
there.
So we are saying in my case, in the Campbell take rieper for the take Zeta username.
So now let's push our image, copy everything from the user name all the way to the tag name at the
end.
Sudhakar push with that name and then it is going to push it into Rieper.
So I've done this before and that's why it's saying like this, yours might take a little longer than
mine.
And then when it's done it will give you HHI 256 unique idea there and there you can see the user to
image that we've just pushed.
You could do a Dufka polls show you just now.
Let's just go into the container image and there you will see all the contents, amongst others, the
open JDK for base image cetera.
So now let's consider Docker container.
Alice, there you can see all of our containers.
So let's clean out our local containers to sort of mimic a server where we don't yet have these images.
So let's remove oath service container.
It's going to say, hang on, you can't remove a container that is running.
So let's first say docker containers stop with the container name, because obviously you need to first
stop the container to be able to remove it and remove the container before we can remove an image again
list.
Let's just clear the screen and ran the docker image.
And again.
There you can see images.
So let's run Docker image, aim four, remove copy the local image first.
OK, and it's removed and take there and then let's also run Docker image, R.M. aim to remove our image
that's in our repository and remember Kolan with the tag.
OK, so this sort of mimics a server that doesn't have those images.
OK, you can see we don't have it anymore.
Just go back, copy the docker, pull command from your container image and pasted in your terminal
and then it's going to pull that image on the server.
Let's pretend for the first time and then the server will have that image in its local dock, a service.
OK, now it has been downloaded so we can actually start our container with that image name again,
doctorand detached port 80 84 again for external and the second one internal, the name again will use
the same name OS to service space network.
And it's the spring bank net.
Again, as an environmental variable, let's set our active spring profile as Dukkha.
Will specify the restart policy, we say always.
And then right at the end, we need to put the image name, and that's going to be our full image name,
including the user name Ford Slash Reaper, name tag, name or image name is Dr..
Again, they can see our oath to service running.
And there is the image full image name.
So let's open Posman again.
And they you can see again we get a JWT.