In this lecture, we are going to create the domain models for user micro services.
We will start by creating the user model and the models package that we have created in the user core
project.
Let's create a new class and call it user.
Now, the first thing that we are going to do is to add an ad data annotation.
You will remember that we added Lombok as a dependency when we generated our springboard projects.
When adding the ad data annotation, Lombok will automatically generate the Gators and Setas, the two
string method and the equals and hash code method for the user model class.
Next, we will add the ad Borlaug's construct constructor annotation to tell Lombok to generate a constructive
for a user model class that takes in an argument or parameter for each of the fields that we are going
to define.
Let's also add an ADD No ARC's construct to generate an empty constructor that takes in no arguments
or parameters.
OK, now let's add the Etch Boulder annotation, which tells Lombok to generate a complex boulder for
the user model class that complies to the Boulder creation of design pattern.
Finally, let's add the document annotation, which is a Mongo DB annotation that is used to mark a
class as a domain model that will be posted to the database Monga DB store such records as Jason like
documents that is referred to as besoin documents or binary.
Jason Monga DB is also referred to as a document oriented no siecle database.
The document annotation also allows us to specify the name of the collection.
We want to put or store our user documents.
So let's call our collection users.
Notice a collection is always in the plural.
OK, now let's create a few private fields for our user model class.
We can start by adding an add ID field.
If you're familiar with Mongo DB, you will know that a Monga DB document contains an underscore ID
field, which is a unique identifier that uniquely identifies each document in a collection.
We can use the at Idy annotation to map idee field to the Mongo DB ID field.
OK, next, let's add a private field for the first time of the user,
another for the last name.
An email address failed.
And finally, an account field.
Now let's create another class for our current model.
We can create it under the same package models.
Now, again, we are going to add the data annotation, the ad all arcs, constructor annotation, the
ad no ARC's constructor annotation and the at Boulder annotation.
Then we are going to add a few important fields.
Let's start with a user name.
We also need a password
and then we need another important field that allows us to provide a user with one or more user roles.
So let's add a list of role where role will be an enum that we are going to define just now.
Let's create a new enum.
And call it role to ensure that our roles complies to the granted authority roles that are part of the
spring starter security package, we need to implement the granted authority interface.
Let's just implement the interface.
Get authority, miss, it will come back to just now.
Now, if we think about how we are segregating our military services into Command API and the Query
API, I think it is good to have a role that allows reads or queries and another role that allows rights
or commands.
So let's add the first role for read privilege.
And the second role for right privilege.
Now, for the Gate Authority method that we are overriding, we are just going to return the name,
let's just make that case, OK, now our roll in is completed.
Let's just add the import for the list.
And current model is fine as well as our user model.
That concludes the creation of our domain models.