In this lecture, we are going to create our command objects for our user command MICRA service, if
you recall, a command is a combination of expressed intent, which basically in our context describes
what we want to use a command military service to do.
We are going to create three command objects, a registered user command update, use a command and
a remove user command object.
We will create them under the commands package that falls under the User Command API project.
Let's create a new class and call it Register User Command.
Now, the first thing that we are going to do is add the data annotation and the builder annotation.
Then we will add a couple of private fields, starting with an ID.
Importantly, we will annotate the ID field with Target Aggregate Identifier in order for Exxon to know
which instance of an aggregate type should handle the command message, the field carrying the aggregate
identifier in the command object must be annotated with at Target Aggregate Identifier.
Also, remember that a command should carry the information required to undertake action based on the
expressed intent.
More specifically, we need the user information to enable us to register a new user.
Therefore, let's add the user domain model as a filter register command object.
Now, let's create another class and call it update user command.
Now, basically the update use a command object is going to look exactly the same as the register,
use a command object.
That is because we will use the put HTP verb instead of the PETCH in order to replace the entire user
object rather than doing a partial update.
So let's go ahead and copy all the fields of the register.
Use a command object.
Let's create another class for our remove user command object.
Now, what's different from the other user common objects is that we will only add the data annotation
because the remove user command object will only have a single field, which is basically an ID field,
and the builder would be an overkill.
Again, Target aggregates identifier.
And we basically only need the ID because typically when you remove an object, you would only pass
the ID.
Okay, that concludes the creation of a command object for a user command MICRA service.
Let's build.
And everything seems to build successfully.