By now, you have already created the domain models and command objects that are required for the use
of micro services in this lecture.
We are going to create the user event objects.
If you recall, an event is an object that describes something that has happened in the application.
Basically, events are raised once a command has been actioned.
Let's start by creating our first event object, the user register event and the events package that
form part of the user call project.
Let's create a new class and call it user registered event.
Importantly, we are placing the objects in our core library package because the events are raised in
the command API and handled in the query API.
The user register event object is going to look exactly the same as the register user command object.
We will also create an I.T. field and we will add a field for our user.
We will then create another class for our user updated event.
Again, it would look the same as the user register event.
So let's copy the annotations and we can copy the fields.
And then finally, let's create our last class, the user remove the event object.
Again, we will only add the data annotation and we can just go ahead and copy the ID.
That's all we need for the user removed event.
Let's build our application.
And everything built successfully.