Now that we have completed the project set up, we can begin to implement our bank account micro services.
Let's start by creating a bank account domain model, navigate the models package under the bank account
called Project, creates a new class and call it bank account.
First, let's annotate our bank account model class with the entity annotation entities and JPA are
nothing but plain old Java objects that represent data that can be persisted to a database.
More specifically, an entity represents a table in a relational database.
In our case, my sequel and an instance of an entity represents a row in a relational table.
Now let's add the data annotation to reduce the boilerplate code.
The old constructor?
No ARC's constructor.
We can also add the boulder annotation.
Let's create a idy the idea annotation specifies that the I.T. field is the primary key of the entity.
It's also create an account holder I.D. field.
This is going to be the user ID from our user MICRA services.
It's at a creation date.
Also, add a private feel for the account type.
Now let's go ahead and create an Inam count type.
You can edit in the same package, let's add a savings and a current account time, OK?
And then our final field is a field for the balance of the account.
OK, now copy the package name.
Let's go over to our application clause in our Query API.
And here we will tell the application class to scan for the entity by using the entity scan annotation,
and yes, we will set the base packages to the package where our bank account model is situated.
Let's go ahead and build our project.
And everything should build successfully.