Now that we have an oath to point out authorization service, we need to secure our user MICRA services.
Let's start by opening the XML file of our User Command API.
We need to add three spring security dependencies.
Let's start with the spring security o auth dependency.
Take the latest version.
Secondly, we are going to add the spring security oath to auto configure dependency.
Again, take the latest version, and then finally, we are going to add the spring security JWT dependancy
again, take the latest version now go ahead and copy all of the three dependencies that we've just
added and navigate to the user query API.
We are also going to need it for the query API.
The next thing that we need to do is to add the JWT signing key to the application of properties file
of each of our user MICRA services.
Now, if you recall, the JWT signing key is actually the key that we used in our OS 2.0 authorisation
service for generating a JWT.
There you can see it in the application or properties of yours to put authorization service.
As well as in the oath server config, you'll see that that's exactly the signing key that we use during
the JWT generation.
So it's also the signing key that we will use within our user MICRA services by the Resource Service
to actually verify if the JWT that is passed is correct.
So let's add config to our application of properties for security oath to that resource, JWT, that
key value, and then we can go ahead and actually post that spring bank signing key in there.
Now, again, for simplicity's sake, I'm using a very easy signing key that in production, please
use a much more complex one that will make it hard to crack pasted into the application of properties
fall of the user query API as well.
And then we can actually start by adding some needed annotations to our application files.
First of all, go ahead and add the enable resource server annotation, enable resource server annotation
is a convenient annotation for all to resource servers, enabling a spring security filter that authenticates
requests via an incoming or to token also at the enable global message security annotation and say pre
post enabled to choose.
Let's copy these annotations and go to our user query application class and paste it in their.
OK, now we've added all the needed configuration, so now we can actually go ahead and secure our wrist
controller methods by adding the reauthorise annotation, and then we are going to say that it needs
the following authority, so has authority.
And then in there we are going to say that it needs the user role.
In other words.
Basically, it needs right privileges because it's the command side or the right side.
So just go ahead and add right privilege there.
So we are saying that only uses with right privileges will be able to register users and then we will
add exactly the same requirement for our remove user control, as well as for our update user controller.
That's all on the command API side, which is our right side.
And then for user lookup controller, we are going to say that you only need to read privileges to read
from the user, read database and basically access the query controller methods or read controller methods.
OK, so let's go ahead and build our project.
And everything should build successfully.
OK, let's debug our User Command API.
Also, I use a query API.
And we also need to run our Earth 2.0 authorization service.
OK, now that they are all running, let's go ahead and add breakpoints in our control methods.
OK.
Do the same for the user query API.
It's at breakpoints in our user look controller methods.
There we go.
So now we have great points every way, open up, Postman.
So first we are going to try and register a new user.
Let's call him James Doe.
Let's say James only has right privileges, it's not common to any give ride privileges, but we actually
want to try that.
So there we get an error, an authorized HDB status code for a one full authentication is required to
access this resource that confirms that registered user control method is now secured.
So let's go ahead and get a JWT for Jane, who's only got read privileges.
So copy that and then go to authorization, so they buried Tokin and then paste the JWT in the.
Try again, so Nazis' access denied because Jane only has read privileges and not right privileges,
so let's get a token for John Doe.
Was John Scott both read and write privileges?
OK, let's copy the JWT, the.
And let's just update that JWT token.
And this time it heats up control and makes it.
And then it's dispatched by the command gateway and uses successfully registered.
So we can go and check it out, Mongo DB database, if the user was actually added first.
It's like an event store.
There's a new user register event.
If we inspect the details, you'll see that it's new user James Doe.
OK, and let's look in our database and the users, the use this collection and they you'll see we now
three records with James Doe being added.
OK, and James only has right privileges.
OK, so let's now try to update a user.
It's copy James Doe's user ID.
Pasted in there.
We can actually copy the entire body that we've just created because we're doing a put basically a full
replace of the entire object, and let's change his email address to James Doe username to James Daewon
and positive password 45.
And authorized, OK, it proves it's secure, so let's get a JWT for John Doe with right privileges.
Again, at the JWT is a spirit taken under authorization.
And it hits our breakpoint and uses successfully updated status code 200.
Now let's look in our database.
Now you'll see the email address has been changed to James Tato and the username James Daewon password
is encrypted, so we can't tell.
And there you'll see new user updated event, and that is the event where we changed James's email address,
username and password.
OK, now let's try and delete a user.
We can try and delete James Doe from our user database.
Again, it proves that it's secure because it's telling us basically that we don't have a JWT, we're
not going to delete anything.
So let's just skip over.
Just proves that secure.
Now let's get James record from the user query military service, but we first need to get a token.
Let's go ahead and get a token for James Doe with only right privileges.
Now we are going to try and query with right privileges, so it should tell us that we can't.
Just place the JWT there and it says Access denied because James can only write and not read.
OK, there you can see he only has right privileges.
So let's get a token for Jane Doe.
Remember, Jane Scott only read privileges, so we should at least be able to query data with her JWT.
Just update the very Tolkan there and it heats up Breakpoint for Searching by Folta.
And they you'll see that we have a record for James Doe that was successfully returned.
We can change that to DOE and their returns, all of the Doe's John, Jane and James.
OK, let's try another controlled method using the by ID, it's copy John Doe's ID, the.
It hits our break point because we already added the very token and it's still valid, the JWT is still
valid and the AOC John Doe being returned, we can change it to use a look up to return all of them,
get all users there, and it will return all of our users, all of our controller methods are now secured.