If you feel a bit confused at this point in time, do not despair.
This is the lecture where everything will start to make sense.
The aggregate is probably the most important domain driven design artifact in this lecture.
We are going to create a user aggregate where the user commands will be handled and where the user events
will be raised once the commands have been actioned.
If you go to the aggregates package under the User Command API project, let's create a new class and
call it user aggregate.
The first thing that we need to do is to take the user aggregate class with the aggregate annotation,
to tell the Xen framework that this is an aggregate for the user command API.
Now let's create two private fields.
Firstly, and I feel that we will annotate with the aggregate identify annotation.
This annotation marks the idee field as the reference point to the user aggregate object that X1 uses
to know which aggregate a given command is targeting.
Remember, we mock the ideas of our command objects with at Target Aggregate Identifier.
Secondly, let's add a user field to the aggregate.
Now, Exxon requires that each aggregate object contains two constructor's one, taking in no arguments
or parameters and another that takes in a command object as a parameter.
This is the command that creates the aggregate.
In our case, it will be the registered user command.
Now let's create a constructor that takes in the registered user Camonte.
Importantly, we need to mark the constructor with the command handler annotation to tell Xen that this
is a command handlock constructor.
Then we can add Camonte handling methods for other user commands, so let's add a command handler method,
call it handle, that is going to take in the update, use a command.
And then we also need to add another command handling method that will handle the remove user command.
Now, once the commands are handled, events will be raised.
So we need to add an event sourcing handler for each of these commands.
So let's start with an event sourcing handler method for the user registry of it.
Now, the event sourcing hand annotation is what tells the Exxon framework that the annotated function
should be called when the aggregate is sourced from the events, as all the events sourcing handlers
combined will form the aggregate.
This is where all the state changes are going to happen.
So let's add another event sourcing handler method that is going to take in the user updated event.
And then finally, let's add an event sourcing handler method for handling the user.
Remove the event.
OK, now let's create a new variable and call it new user, and we can get it from registered use it
command.
So now let's set the user ID and we can use the command ID to set our user ID.
And then we can go ahead and obtain the password from the command.
So this is the plain text password that will be submitted with an HTP request to our controller method,
which you will see in later lectures.
So we need to hash this password.
We can't save it into the database as plain text.
So let's go ahead and create a new package in our User Command API project and call it security and
then go ahead and create a new interface and call the interface password encoder.
And we will define any a single message that will return a string, let's call it hashed password,
and then it will take in a string parameter that we will call password.
Let's implement the interface and intelligence allows us to automatically create the implementation
class.
Now, importantly, annotate the class with the service annotation, and then we are going to implement
the hash passwd method, so create a new variable, call it encoder.
And then instantiate a new B creped password in code, for instance, and set the strength to 12 and
then create a new variable hash password
and then say encoded dot in code and then pass in the password
and then we will return the hashed password.
OK, now let's go back to user aggregate.
OK, so let's create a new private final field for our password in at.
And then in our constructor, that takes in no arguments, let's instantiate a new password in the implementation.
And then for the hashed password, let's call password encoded or hash password and pass in the password.
Now, importantly, this is also a constructor.
So since it's an overloaded constructor, we will also have to instantiate the password encoded implementation
in this constructor.
OK, so let's go ahead and replace the plaintext password with the hash password and then we need to
raise an event so we will instantiate a new event using a fluid builder.
Remember, we added the boulder annotation.
So let's set the idea first from using command dot gate ID.
And then the user and then passing the new user.
And then you can invoke dart board, which return the constructed user registered event, if you invoke
aggregate life-cycle the reply, it will store the event in the event store and publish it into the
event bus.
So now on the events sourcing Handyside, we will set the aggregate idy equal to the event ID, which
comes all the way from the command.
Then as well as the user filled to the user that we get from the event.
OK, so now we can implement the update user command handler, create a new variable and call it updated
use, it will look similar to the registered user command handler can get the user from the command
and as well as set the user ID using the command ID.
And then we will also get the password from the updated user's account.
And go ahead and copy the line of code where we are getting the hashed password, then again can replace
the normal plaintext password with the hash password, and this time we will raise a user activated
event and we will again use a fluent builder to construct our updated user event object this time.
Importantly, we will not use the command ID, but we will generate a random idea using you ID idiot
random eweida to string and then set the user with the updated user.
And they invoked God both to return the constructed event object and again aggregate life-cycle, the
reply will store the user updated event in the event store and publish it in the event bus.
And this time we will just update the user field of the aggregate since the correct aggregate instance
was already selected when the update user command was handled.
Remember, this is where the target aggregate identifier annotation on the command object comes into
play.
And then finally, for the remove user command handler, we will simply instantiate a new user, remove
the event, we can set the event ID using the command ID
and then we can invoke aggregate life-cycle to reply and pass the event.
And again, the event will be stored in the event store and published to the event bus.
And this time on the event saucing Handyside for the user removed event.
We will invoke aggregate life-cycle that mark it to delete the actual aggregate.
That concludes the implementation of our user aggregate.
So let's open the terminal and build our user MICRA services using M.V. and clean install.
And everything should build successfully.