Now that you have installed all the prerequisites, it's time for us to set up our micro services projects,
open your browser and navigate to start that springboard IO to open the spring initialise, we will
use the spring, initialize it to generate our spring with projects with all of its required dependencies.
Spring, initialize plug ins or extensions are also available for most IDs.
But let's rather use the Web based spring initialise to ensure that we are all in sync.
OK, so let's start to create our first spring project.
We have a choice between Maven or Gradle built automation tools, but we will only use MAVEN in this
course.
We also have a choice between Java, Cocklin or Groovy as our Java based programming languages, but
we will use Java throughout this whole course.
OK, next we need to select a spring boot version.
We will select version two point four point one as the latest stable version at the time of this recording.
The next thing we need to do is to set up the project metadata.
The first thing that we need to do is to choose a group name.
A group name is normally com dot org dot, followed by a company name.
We are going to create bank account MICRA services, so let's assume we have a company called Spring
Bank.
Then the next thing is to select an artifact name.
We will first create user MICRA services.
The User Micra service will consist of a user command API and a user query API like you've seen in the
course introduction.
We will also create a user core project is a common project between the command and query APIs.
So let's use user dot cmd for Camonte dot API as an artifact name.
We can also provide a description.
Let's call it User Command API project.
Now you can see that our package name is com the Spring Bank to use it or cmd or API.
We will use Java as our packaging type and like I've mentioned previously, I'll be using Java 15 in
this course.
Okay, now it's time to select Springview dependencies.
We can click on the add dependencies button in the right top corner of our screens.
The first dependency that we need is Spring Web.
We will use spring web to create arrays controllers and to ensure that we can expose our restful endpoints.
You can hold down control to select multiple dependencies.
The second dependency that we will use is Lombok.
Lombok will help us to reduce the boilerplate code that we normally have to write, especially when
we create a command event and decode type objects.
The final dependency that we will need for the User Command API is the spring security dependency that
we will need to protect our micro services.
Okay, now that we have selected all of our dependencies, our project is ready to be generated.
You can click on the generate button and the spring initialize will generate your springboard application
and download it for you.
Okay, now we can generate a springboard project for our user query API as well.
So let's change the artifact name to user dot query dot API and we can change the description to user
query API project.
Okay, we will keep the packaging and Java version the same.
However, we need to add one more dependency because I use a query.
API will use Mongo DB as its database.
As you have seen in the first video of this course, when we looked at what we will develop.
So let's click on the ad dependencies button and search for Mongo DB.
You can go ahead and select the spring day to Mongo DB dependancy, OK, that's all we need to generate
our user query API project.
So again, we can click on generate.
OK, now let's generate our final user project, the user core project.
Let's start by changing the artifact name to use it at core, and we can give it a description like
the user core project we will still use as our packaging type and Java 15.
Now, the user core project is like a class library project, so we will not expose any for endpoints.
So go ahead and remove the spring dependency.
We will still use Lombok to reduce boilerplate code and spring security for some configuration objects.
And finally, we'll use spring data Mongo DB to annotate domain entities with the document annotation.
All right, click on Generate to generate your final user project.