In this lecture, we are going to create a race controller for registering a user, let's create a new
class under the controllers package of the User Command API project.
We can call it registered user controller.
Firstly, let's add the race controller annotation to indicate that this is our full controller.
Then to set up our request mapping route, we can at the request mapping annotation.
A common standard is to always add forward slash API
the version.
And then the name of the controller or controller method.
Now, you can also add the request mapping on your method, however, I prefer to create it on class
level because I try to keep the controller classes as small as possible, often only having a single
method per class in an attempt to comply to the single responsibility principle.
The single responsibility principle states that a class should only have one reason to change the single
responsibility principle is, of course, part of the solid principles with solid is that abbreviation
for single responsibility.
Open, close principle, lisk of substitution, principle, interface, segregation and dependency inversion.
So just to come back to the version in the request mapping, it is best practice to never change the
signature of a restful endpoint once it has gone live.
Therefore, the version is critically important, you might say, but change is inevitable.
For example, a client might want you to return more fields in response DTO.
Fortunately, the open closed principle can help us here.
Now the open closed principle states that a class should be open for extension but closed for modification.
Luckily, in object oriented programming, we have several options.
A simple, practical way of extending is to extend your response DTA by creating a new response to object
that inherits from the original DTA, effectively adding the additional fields without touching the
original object.
Then we can create a version too, of a controller that will have two as the version in the request.
Mapping your path.
Now let's create a private field for our common gateway.
The common gateway is a command dispatching mechanism that will dispatch the registered user command
and once dispatched, it will invoke the command handling constructor for the register user command
and command handling methods for the other user commands.
Let's create a public constructor that takes in the command gateway as parameter.
Lets do the assignment.
Now, let's create a post method by using the post mapping annotation, remember, a post is used for
creating a resource and with the registered user command, we want to create a user.
We are going to return the response entity, which basically allows you to return a response, Teto,
as well as an HTTP status code.
But we will return registered user response that we are going to create just now.
And then for our request, buddy, we will pass in the Register User Command.
Now, let's go ahead and create a new DTL, creates a new class and call it based response.
For all of our commands, we want to return a message now, let's add a private field for our message.
And then we can create a registered user response, Teto.
Now, in this TTR, we want to extend the base response because we also want to return a message when
registering a user.
But for the registered user command, we also want to return an I.D. to say what the idea is of the
user that was just registered.
OK, now let's add the import statement.
We can start by adding a try catch.
When an exception occurs, we can basically respond with HDP status code 500.
But before we do that, create a safe error message variable where we will return our custom message.
We can say error while processing register user request for ID and then we can add the command ID.
Now it's important to return a safe error message because sometimes the exception that the application
generates could contain some sensitive information.
But we can also go ahead and print the actual error to the container log by simply using the system
to print line.
Now, let's return a new instance of registered user response, where we will post the same error message.
And then we can also return HTP status code 500, which is internal server error.
Now we can set a unique command ID.
By using you ID.
Which stands for Universal Unique Identifier dot, random eweida dot to string.
Then we can invoke the command gateway to send or send and wait.
Now, if you use the send and wait method, it will actually only respond when the command handler has
completed its work using send will immediately respond and assume that the user was registered.
And we can return a new instance of registered user response and we'll add a message user successfully
registered
and then the correct HTP status code to return when you create a resource, the status quo, to one
which is created.
Also, we need to remember to add the auto wired annotation to our constructor to ensure that the spring
IOC container injects the command gateway dependancy via dependency injection.
At the moment, we are only returning to HTTP status codes, including the created HTP status and the
internal server error.
When an exception occurs, you might ask, hang on, shouldn't you add some logic to validate the registered
user command object?
And if the user makes a bad request, return status code 400.
Instead of creating logic to validate each of the fields of our request object, we can use validation
annotations to validate each of our fields.
Let's open up our user object.
We can validate our first name to ensure that it's not empty.
And if it's empty, we can add a message that will be returned to the user.
We can say first name is mandatory.
We can do the same for the last name.
Let's change it to last name is mandatory for the email address we can add at email and we can say,
please provide a valid email address
and for the account we can say not now and return a message.
Please provide account credentials.
Now, let's open the account object for the user name, we can say that we want to use a name that is
at least two characters in size.
And if it's not, we will return username must be at least must have a minimum of two characters,
we can do the same for the password.
But let's say a person needs to have a minimum of seven characters.
And we can add the not null invitation for the rose.
And for a message, we could say that.
You should specify at least one row.
OK, now let's build our project.
You will notice that we have an exception, and that is because the validation dependency is not added
by default.
So let's add a new dependency.
For Validation API.
And we will use the latest version 2.0 point one final let's build again.
And this time, everything should build successfully.