In the previous lecture, we completed the creation of a registered user controller in this lecture.
We are going to make an HTP request to the registered user controller to register our very first user.
I will also show you how to query the right database or event store in Mongo DB as well as the database
after we have successfully registered our first users.
Now let's debug User Command API.
In intelligence, you can simply right click on the user command application file and click on Debug.
Now, you will notice that I use a command API is running on Port 1881, like we've configured it in
the application that properties file.
Now let's open postmen to make a HTP post request to use a command API.
Remember the request mapping forward slash API, forward slash version one forward slash register user.
Let's change it to a post htp zip and then select raw and body and change the content type to Jason.
Now, for now, we only going to send an empty Jason body.
Notice that we got a photo, one, which means our request is unauthorized.
The reason we got a photo one is because we added the spring boots start to security dependency to use
a command API project.
In the end, this is exactly what we want.
But first, we need to register a couple of users and we still have to create our own 2.0 authorization
server, which we are going to do in the next section.
For now, we can go ahead and create a security config clause where we will temporarily configure our
User Command API project to accept all HTTP requests.
This is a temporary class which we will remove once our OS 2.0 authorization server is ready.
Go ahead and create a new package under the User Command API project and call it config.
Let's create a new class and call it security Kornfield.
Let's go ahead and add the ED configuration annotation
and the ED enabled Web security annotation.
Then we will extend the Web security configure adapter interface.
Go ahead and override the configure method.
The one that takes in HTP security, then you can say HTP that authorized request.
Dirt and matches.
Forward slash star, star, dot permit all.
I'm just going to move these to the next slide, looks much better like that,
and then dot any request dot authenticated.
Dot and dot, see is our Earth
dot disabled and that will basically allow that any HTP request will be authenticated.
OK, now we are going to dbag again.
Let's go ahead and add a few breakpoints.
I'm going to change it to the second method instead of sending wait, I found that it's better when
trying to step through your code.
Then we can also go to the user aggregate and add a breakpoint in the command handling constructor as
well as in the event sourcing handling method for the user registered event.
We can also go to the user event, handle the implementation and add a breakpoint in the event handler,
a method for the user registered event.
OK.
Now that we have all our breakpoints in place, let's debug the user query application.
As well as the user command application.
Now that both of them are running, let us go and look at the structure of a user domain object.
As well as our can't object because we need to send a Jason request body that resembles the registered
user command open postman again, we can start by adding the Jason body for the user object will use
the infamous John Doe first name,
John.
Last name, though,
for the email address,
we can use John at Spring Bank dot com,
then for the account credentials
for the username, we can specify it as John D.
And then for the password, something as simple as password.
One way we can add a capital P and add sine and zero.
And then finally, remember, for the roles, we have two roles, a privilege and a right privilege.
Let's give John Doe both privileges, which effectively means that John will be able to make requests
to the User Command API that represents the rights as well as the user query API that represents the
reads.
Let's click on Send.
And there you can see that it hits a breakpoint in a post, makes it.
It also invokes the common handler constructor in a user aggregate there we are getting the hashed password
from password hashing algorithm.
And then we can instantiate a new event object, and then when we invoke aggregate life cycle or apply
the event, saucing handler will be raised.
And once that happens, the event handler will consume the event that was published to the event store
and save the user object into Mongo DB.
OK, open robo three T or the Mongo's Shell and connect to your local Mongo DB instance that is running
in Dukkha.
Here you will see that two new databases were created, including Xen Framework and Yuzu, where the
Xen framework is our event store or right database and the user database is Arete Database.
Exon Storrar User Registered event at the moment that are event saucing.
Handler was raised in the user aggregate and we're now event handler method was raised after the event
was consumed from the event.
But in our user event handler, we invoke the save method of our user repository to store the user record
in the user database, expand the Exon Framework database to view our events.
We can right click on the Domain Events collection and click on View documents.
I like the adjacent view.
Yeah, you can see our user register event with details in the serialized payload.
Expand the user database and right, click on the user's collection and click on view documents.
Again, I'm going to use the adjacent view.
They can see John Doe we have just registered.
And here you can see how the hash password is stored in the database.
Let's register another user, Jane Doe.
Let's change it to Jane at Spring Bank dot com Jane D..
Let's make it past two.
And now let's only give Jane Reid privileges, which means she will only be able to call the query APIs.
Again, we can step through the code, the command gate, but we'll dispatch the command.
Again, we will hash Jain's password.
Publish, stole the event, consume the event and save it to the Mongo DB user database, press F5 and
they you'll see Jane Doe was added to the database.
We can also look in the domain events to see a new entry of user registered event that was used to create
Jane's user record.
Remember, we added the validation annotations to other main updates.
Now, it will only work if we add the at valid annotation before our request body in our post method.
We also need to add the Ed Fetich annotation to use a field in outrageous to use a common object.
And let's also add a not no validation annotation to provide the user with the message that no user
that no user details were supplied.
We also need to add the at valid annotation for nested objects, we can go ahead and add it to the account
object.
OK, let's stop Dybek sessions.
And let's restart a new session.
For both the user query API and the User Command API.
OK, if we go back to Postman.
We can exclude some of our fields.
Now let's first add a McDo.
And let's add an incorrect email address there you will see that a default message states please provide
a valid email address.
OK, let's only give Mike a username, email.
This time, it will say username must have a minimum of two characters.
Let's give Mike a password of only three characters.
Again, it would say it must have a minimum of seven characters.
Now, let's take away the roles.
This time, it'll say specify at least one user role, we can also take away the last name and we'll
get a 400 bed request.
Last name is mandatory.
OK, now we've actually corrected everything and you should see Mike being created in our users collection.
It's a five.
And there you see Mike Doe in our database, also see the user register event for Mike, I realized
that the ID was always null in our HTP responses in Posman, and that was because I forgot to add the
ID field to the constructor of the registered user response.
So let's go ahead and add it to our constructor as the first parameter and then we can assign it.
This was because I used the Intellisense of intelligence.
We had asked me if I wanted to create a matching constructor for the super.
Let's create a new variable and assign a random, unique universal identifier to its variable.
Let's set it to our command, Idy Positon is the first parameter there and also in our try catch and
we can also exchange command that Kate ID with the Idy variable.