In this lecture, I'm going to show you how to structure a securest micro services project, and in
particular when you use the Xen framework, let's start by creating a package for our models.
Now let's go to the User Command API project and create a package for the commands.
You'll remember that I told you what commands are in the previous section.
Let's also create a package for the aggregates.
Once a command has been executed, an event will be raised.
We will create a package for events under the user core project because the command and query APIs will
share the events.
Now we can go over to the query API and create a package for handlers where we will create our event
handlers and our query handlers.
Once an event is raised, for example, a user created event, we will store a new user object into
the database.
Therefore, let's create a repository package.
We will also create a package for queries
similar to a command, basically saying, I want to query some data and let's create a package for our
restful controllers.
Now for serializing our Jason objects, let's create a package for DETRO, which stands for data transfer
objects.
Let's do the same on the command side.
First, adding the controllers package and then finally also package for the DTA O's.
Now let's go ahead and give our application names, proper names, let's call it use a command application.
We can also do it for our test classes.
And go ahead and do it for our query API as well, we can call it user query application.
And that should make it sound more secure, compatible.
OK, so also for our test class.
One for configuration, and that's basically where we will add a configuration class or classes that
will be shared between the command and query APIs.