It is now time for us to create the controllers for our bank account command API.
We will start by creating a controller that will expose a restful endpoint for opening a new bank account,
like in the case of the user micro services, we always want to respond with at least a message.
Therefore, let's navigate the DTA package and a bank account core project and create a new class and
call it based response.
Let's add a single field for returning a message.
Also, go ahead and add the data and all construct annotations.
OK, now let's go to the bank account command API project and create another DTA and call it open account
response.
We are going to extend the base response
and let's add just a single field to return the idea of the newly created bank account.
OK, let's also add a single constructor that takes in the ID and the message.
We will pass the message to our base class and then we will sign our Idy,
Lomborg does not work well with inheritance, so let's create the cities and get ourselves first for
setting the idea
and then our gater that gets the current state of the idy.
Okay.
Now.
It creates a new class under the controllers package and call it open account controller
annotated with the controller annotation as well as the request mapping.
We can make our path forward.
Slash API, forward slash version one forward slash open bank account.
Now, let's create a private field, you can make it final, the command gateway, and we will use it
to dispatch the open bank account command.
They do the assignment
and then add auto wired to ensure that the spring IOC container injects the command gateway dependency.
Now we are going to create a post method at the post mapping annotation and then we will also secure
our controller method to ensure that the requested user has rights privileges.
We will return the response entity and the open account response.
It's called our method open account.
And we will do validation on the request body, which is our open account command.
Now let's go to Ed validation annotations to open Camonte clause, you must ensure that account holders
never know.
And if it is, we will respond with a bad request and no account holder ID was supplied.
Go ahead and copy that for the account type.
We will simply change it to no account type was supplied.
And then for our opening balance, we will change it to men.
To ensure that the balance is always greater, the zero, and then if it's not zero, in other words,
we want at least the balance of zero and not a negative balance, then we will reply with bad request
and opening balance must be at least
now let's change that to 50.
Let's say they need to have at least fifty dollars, whatever your your currency is to open a new bank
account.
OK, now that we've done the validation, let's implement open account post control method.
Let's generate a new random ID for our new bank account and then we will say command to set it will
set that idea to the open account, common object and then let's do a try catch.
And as always, let's first implement our catch where we will respond with internal server error and
a safe error message.
So the safe error message, let's make it something like error while processing request to open a new
bank account
for ID and then we can just add the newly generated bank account.
If they say we will print out the actual error to the container log, you'll see when we deploy our
military services to Docker that we can view that in the container log.
And then if the error occurred, like we said, we will respond with a new idea as well as the safe
error message and SCDP status code 500, which is internal server error.
OK, to implement the actual method command gateway that said, we will dispatch the command object
and then if everything went well, we will again respond with the open account response stating that
we have successfully opened a new bank account.
With HTP status code to one which is created.
OK, now we have successfully completed the implementation of our open account controller method.
Now open up the API Gateway project.
Let's go and add an API gateway route for our new open account controller.
So let's give it a unique ID, something like bank account, see the API hyphen open account
for your eye.
Let's go and copy the registered user command.
And just make sure the indentation is correct.
Change the port to 1991 and then request mapping to open bank account and also copy that to the predicate.
OK, let's run our API Gateway application.
It's Dybbuk Bank Account Camonte API, as well as a bank account query API.
And we'll also have to run our Oath 2.0 authorization server to get a JWT or else we won't be able to
open a bank account.
OK.
And also run the user query API because we need to get an account holder ID from our user query API.
So we've got all our applications running.
Let's start by getting a JWT.
OK, so let's paste taken the.
And then go ahead and copy John Doe's I.D., which is going to be our account holder I.D. at a new tab,
they change it to post your eyes.
HTP localhost 2000 through the API Gateway Forward Slash API V1 Open Bank Account.
And then for our post body change to Jason, we will pass in an account holder ID and will use John
Doe's user ID, the.
OK, then, for our card type will say John's got a current account.
And then for our opening bell, it's.
Let's say John's got a balance of a hundred dollars.
OK, let's get another JWT.
Edit as a berry token.
And then let's just make sure we add a breakpoint in our control method, as well as in our bank account
aggregate.
Well, the command handled and event sourcing handler.
As well as a break point and our current event handler in our current event and implementation.
And yes, let's go back to Posman and hit send there you'll see it hits our controller method, the
command gets dispatched, the command handled, then it's published to the event, passed and stored
in the event store.
Then it's consumed and persisted to the Reed Bank account database, the U.S. status quo to one with
a message successfully open a new bank account login to buy sequel.
Then you'll see that we have a new entry into the bank, a card table, and they you'll see John Doe's
I.D. with the balance of 100 also open Mongo DB.
There you'll see a new collection that's been created with the tracking tokens of the bank account,
as well as look into our right database at the main event database.
They'll you'll see a new event, account, open event.
And if we scroll down, you'll see it's the new account that was opened for John Doe.
Now we have successfully completed the restful endpoint that will allow clients to create new bank accounts
via a bank account command API.