In this lecture, we are going to implement the update, use a controller, this will provide a user
command API with an endpoint that we can use to update users.
Navigate to the controllers package and they use a command API project, let's create a new class and
call it update user controller.
Go ahead and add the race control annotation and then let's add our request mapping for the path we
could make it forward, slash API, forward slash V1, forward slash update user.
Again, let's create a private field for the command gateway.
And a public constructor that takes in the command gateway as parameter
dates to the assignment.
And then remember the auto wide annotation to ensure that it gets injected via dependency injection.
OK, we're going to use a put htp verb.
So put is basically when you want to do a full update, you can also do a patch if you want to do a
partial update.
But for the purposes of this course, we will only do a put.
Now for our path variable, we will pass in an ID that will basically specify the user that we want
to update.
Again, we will return the response entity and this time we will only return the base response.
Let's call our method update user and then we will pass in a path variable with a value ID as per put
mapping.
Which should be a string.
And let's go ahead and add a request party, basically taking in our update user command.
At import, and we also want to add the vetted annotation to ensure that our object gets validated.
Let's go to our user command object and specifically specify that we want to validate the user object.
And if it's null, we want to tell the user the following.
Let's copy the same message that we've used for the register.
Use a command, no user details were supplied.
OK, so let's start by adding a try catch.
Let's copy the registered user controllers.
Try catch.
Posted there.
Let's change it to error while processing update user request.
And this time will only return a base response with the safe error message.
Now, let's go ahead and set our command ID with the ID that we are passing in, then we can invoke
the command gateway to send to dispatch the update, use a command, and then if all goes well, we'll
return a base response.
Where we can say user successfully updated.
As well as return HDB status quo 200, OK?
Now, let's at a break point the.
And then let's debug our user command application.
Also, go ahead and add a break point and the update user command handler.
Also at a breakpoint under the user updated event handler.
And let's debug our user query application as well.
Go ahead and copy the request mapping for updated user open Posman, open a new tab.
Change it to put HGP verb, say, copy the localhost, put 1881.
Now, let's go and copy the Jason body from the registered user command.
And change it to Jason.
OK, let's change the email to Mike Dotto, the password to password 38, username to Mike Diabolo seven.
And let's give Mike also the right privileges.
OK.
Let's first go and get the idea of Mike.
Go ahead and copy the ID.
And we can edit as a parameter to request Urai.
Now, let's step through the code, dispatch the update, use a command there, you'll see the command
handler.
We can hash the password again.
And let's add a breakpoint under the event, saucing handler for use an updated event as well.
So that gets published to the event, plus the event handler consumes the event and we can invoke the
save method of the user repository.
Now they you'll see we got a status quo, 200 and a message user successfully updated.
Let's go back to our database.
It's a five.
And they will see that the email is Michelotto and the username Mike Doubler saved, as well as the
right privilege that's been added.
Let's go to Demesne Events Collection, which represents events.
To day, you'll see an additional event.
And we can see that we first registered John Doe and then we registered Jane Doe and another user registered
event for registering Mike Doe and a user updated event for updating Mike Doe.