In this lecture, we are going to add the Exxon dependencies to the poem that XML file of each of our
user projects, we are then going to create an Exxon config class where we will configure Exxon to use
a Mongo DB event storage engine instead of the out of the box Exxon event store.
OK, let's start by opening up the period of XML file of the User Command API project.
Let's give it a proper version, version 1.0 point zero.
And then we are going to add the Xen spring, which started dependancy with the group Idy org dot framework
and version four point four as the latest version at the time of this recording.
Let's copy that and then we'll open up the user core project, that XML file.
Let's face it there and then we are going to add another dependancy.
The Exxon on dependency, this time the group I.D. is awkward Exxon framework, that extension's that
Mongar and version four point four is the latest version at the time of this recording.
OK, let's head over to the user query API project.
Open up the Pimlott XML file.
Let's give it a proper version, version 1.0 point zero.
And then we are only going to add the Exxon screen, which starts a dependency.
Okay, let's just paste there.
And that's all we have to do.
Let's build see if everything builds with the inspiration space still.
And everything should be fine, let's just say yes and everything, but successfully.
OK, open up the configuration package and the user call project and create a new class and call it
X on config.
This is where we are going to configure Exon to use a Mongar DB storage engine.
Okay, let's start by adding an add configuration annotation to tell the spring framework that this
is a configuration class.
Then we are going to add three private variables.
First, private string Mongo host for the host address of our Monga DV database, then private int Wango
Port and then finally private string Mongo database.
We are going to add the values of these fields in the applications to properties files in the User Command
API project.
And then we'll start by giving it just a normal port.
That's going to run on a server port.
Let's use Port 1881.
And now for the actual configuration.
Just put a comment there, Mongo DB and then it's going to be spring dot data dot Mongo DB dot host
equals let's use localhost, we are mongered bestriding and Dufka on our local machine.
So just copy that first.
But in the port is the default mongered report two seven zero one seven and then the database.
It's called our database user because we are storing our user info the just copy that for the User Query
API project to locate the applications that prompted this file.
And the only difference is let's make the API Port 882 now go ahead and copy the spring DOT data that
Mongar and then we are going to add the add value annotation to tell the spring frame to get the value
of that field from the application that properties file.
And 127 that that that one is obviously the same as localhost and that's basically the default value.
And then we'll add the same for the port says copy that and will default to the same two seven zero
one seven default port.
And then the Mungai database will default to the user database, just change that database and use user.
OK, now we are going to create a few methods.
Let's add to add being annotation, the API annotation tools that A method produces a B to be managed
by the screen container.
OK, we are first going to return a Mongar client.
Let's call our method Mongo and we will create a new instance of Mongo factory and we will use the Mongar
factory to set our Mongar address.
But before we can do that, we need to instantiate another factory, the Mongo's Settings Factory.
So let's create a new instance of Mongar Settings factory and the Mongo's Settings factory is actually
the one that we're going to use to set the Mongered races.
In our case, only a single address.
So let's use collections.
Dot Singleton list.
And then we pass in a new instance of severe dress that takes in the Mongar Hurst and the Mongar port.
And then we say Mongar factory that set Mongo Clines settings and then we pass in Mongo Settings factory.
Not create Mongo client settings, and then we can go ahead and return the Mongar client by invoking
Mongar factory that create Mongo.
Okay, the second method that we are going to declare, he will return a Monga template, let's call
it X on Mongar template, and he will use a default mongerer template builder.
So they should default mongered template dot builder
and will pass in the Mongar database, which takes in a Mongar client.
Let's call the Mongar method that we've declared just above.
And then also it needs the database name DOT and that will return the constructed Mongar template object.
OK, the third method that we are going to declare is will return a token stock in let's market with
it being a return token store object.
It's called a token store and it's passing in a serializer.
And then we will use a Mongar token store builder to construct our tokens, to object that builder,
and we will set a mongered template object.
We can call the X on Mongo template to create just above.
And then it also requires a serializer pass in the serializer parameter and call Duck-billed to return
the constructed tokens to object.
OK, now the two methods again will at the end annotation this time will return the event storage engine
we will call our method storage engine and this time will pass in a Mongar client as a parameter and
we will use a Monga event storage engine builder.
This is all part of the Exon framework.
Packages got bolder and will set the Mungai template actually use a default Mongar template build again.
Set them on good database.
Scott Dotts.
Mongered database.
Just fix the indentation there and then Duck-billed to ultimately return the constructed event story,
change an object which is Mongar even story angel.
OK, let's add it with add being a final method and will return.
We'll call it public and return embedded events store.
Let's call Method Event Store.
It will take in two parameters event storage engine and as well as an X on configuration object.
And this time we'll use an embedded event to build up to construct our embedded events to object.
In Builder.
It set the storage engine by passing the storage engine parameter.
Then we'll set a message monitor.
It needs a message, money to object to, we'll say configuration dot, message monitor will pass in
the type events to that plus.
And then it also requires a component name and we'll use the name events to.
OK, now let's just add the import statement and then call Godbolt to return the constructed embedded
events to object.
The final thing that we have to do is to tell the user command and query API applications to make use
of the X on conflict class.
We can do that by using the import annotation.
And as the type Xen conflict clause.
We need to add a dependency in our PMed or XML file on the user core project, basically our library
project.
So let's go ahead and add a dependency for the user core project.
Now, we should be able to add the import statement.
OK, let's go over to the user query API application.
And again, we will import the X on conflict clause, we need to add a dependency on the user coal project.
I had it right at the bottom to just use it at call.
OK, now we should be able to add the import statement.
OK, now we have successfully ended the conflict clauses for command and query.
Let's do a clean and a fresh build and see if everything built correctly.
Importantly, at this point in time, you have to have Mongo DB up and running like I've shown you at
the start of the section, how you can deploy it in DOCA.
Everything both successfully.