In this lecture, we are going to create another risk controller, this time we will create one that
exposes an HTP endpoint for depositing funds to a bank account, navigate to the controllers package
and the bank account command API project creates a new class and call it deposit funds controller.
Annotated with the race controller annotation, as well as the request mapping annotation.
For the path, we'll use forward slash API, forward slash V1, forward slash deposit funds, we again
need the command gateway.
So let's go and copy the command gateway field and construct from the open account controller.
They just change it to deposit funds controller.
Then we are going to add a put method.
So at the put mapping annotation with the path including an I.D., which should be the bank account
ID.
Again, we'll also add the reauthorise annotation to ensure that only authorized users can access this
method.
So let's copy that and paste that there,
then we will again return a response entity.
But this time only the base response called the method deposit funds.
And then we will pass in a path variable, which is going to be the ID, which is the bank account ID,
we will also pass in a request body.
Again, we will validate the request by.
We will add the validation annotations in a couple of minutes.
OK, so let's add a try catch.
Again, if a an exception occurs, we want to reply with a safe error message, so let's copy the entire
catch section there and then we'll change the safe error message to error while processing request to
deposit.
Funds into a bank account for ID, and that would be the IDB policy, and let's just change that to
their base response.
And we weren't passing ID, only the safe error message.
OK, now to implement the method further is we will set the ID, the command object to the idea that
we pass and then we'll dispatch the deposit funds command and then if everything goes well, we can
return a successful message.
With the base response, a message such as fans successfully deposited
and we can return HTP status code two hundred.
Which is OK.
Now, let's look at the validation parameters.
We only need to add a single one, we will say that the deposit amount should be at least one dollars.
And if it's not, we can provide the user with a message such as the deposit amount must be greater
than zero.
OK.
Just remove the unused import statement and then we can go ahead and add an API gateway route for our
controller method that we've just added for depositing funds.
So let's just change our idea to something like deposit funds.
And then also fix the request, Mappin, they change it to deposit funds, forward slash star star,
which if you remember correctly, means that anything that we pass in after the forward slash will be
translated into URAI later on our API Gateway application.
At breakpoints, in the control method, in the aggregate command handler.
Once again.
Deposit funds Camonte as well as the event sourcing handler.
And then we will also add breakpoints in our account event handler implementation.
Let's go ahead and edit for funds deposited event.
And then we can debug a bank account query application.
As well as our bank account Camonte API.
Also ran the Earth 2.0 authorization server so that we can get a JWT.
And then finally, the user query API.
In fact, we don't need to use a query application because we will only need the bank account ID, let's
get the bank account ID from my school bank database.
Just log in there.
Then go into the bank account table.
Then he will take the I.D., which is the bank account ID from our single record, so let's change it
to put Method Urai localhost for 2005, the API Gateway Forward Slash API V1 deposit funds.
And then we'll pass the I.D., which is the bank account ID there, it's go ahead and get a otherkin
or JWT.
And then we can add it as a token.
And then for a request, body change to Jason then will simply specify an amount and let's deposit 50
dollars into John Doe's bank account before we hit send, I just want to show you the balance is still
a hundred dollars hit send.
So it hits our break point now, the command is being dispatched, it's handled, you'll see that the
map there is 50 and the balance is 100.
It gets produced to the event bursts and stored in the event store.
The balance is updated to 150.
It hits the event handler and the change has persisted to the bank account.
MySQL database status quo two hundred and success message funds successfully deposited there.
You can see in the database that the amount has been updated to one hundred and fifty.
It's also like in our event store.
Then you'll see a new event fund deposited event and if we inspect the details, you'll see that an
amount of fifty dollars was deposited.
The updated balances, one hundred and fifty.
So we have successfully completed the implementation of the deposit funds controller.