We have already implemented two race controllers, one for opening a bank account and another for depositing
funds into a bank account.
Now we need to add one that will allow us to withdraw funds from a bank account, navigate to the controllers
package, and at the bank account command API project, let's create a new class and call it withdraw
funds controller.
Go ahead and annotated with the rest controller annotation as well as a request mapping annotation.
For the path, we'll have forward slash API, forward slash V1, forward slash withdraw funds.
Now, the withdraw funds controller will look much like the deposit funds controller, so let's copy
everything up until the reauthorise annotation.
Change the construct to name the and then we will add the signature return, a response entity based
response, and then let's make the method name withdraw funds.
It will likewise take in a pause variable, which will be the bank account ID.
And we will also validate the request body,
which is going to be the withdraw funds command object.
Now, let's add the validation and attention to the amount of.
But.
We will say the withdrawal amount must be greater than zero
now that withdraw funds controller method is going to look a lot like the deposit funds controller method.
So let's go ahead and copy the entire method now.
Very importantly, I have been using the normal same method of the command gateway because it just debunks
better.
And I wanted you to follow along in a synchronous way, however, rather use the sand and wait method
in production.
The reason I am pointing this out again is because there is an exception that will be generated that
we have added to the account aggregate where we handle the withdrawal funds command.
They will check if the balance is smaller than the withdrawal amount.
And if it is, we throw an illegal status exception to say that the withdrawal is declined due to insufficient
funds.
Now, if we invoke the normal sane method like we have done with the previous controllers, the controller
method will actually respond with a success message before it is able to report the exception that has
occurred to ensure that this does not happen at DOT Gate Command gate that send is a computable future
and the dot gate method blocks until the future is complete.
Thus, if an exception occurs, it will hit our catch and respond correctly.
Let's change our response message to withdraw successfully completed.
And error message to error while processing request to withdraw funds from bank account for I.D., and
that should do it.
Let's go ahead and build our project.
And everything should build successfully.
Now let's go ahead and add an API gateway route for withdraw funds, control the message, we can copy
the deposit funds method,
and then they change the idee to withdraw funds
and request mapping past to withdraw funds as well and leave the forward slash star and change that
to withdraw funds as well.
Let's run our API gateway.
As well as a bank account command API.
Also, our bank account query API.
And then we also need to run our OS 2.0 authorisation server to get a JWT.
Now, let's go to Ed Breakpoints.
A break point in our control method.
As well as in our account aggregate, where we handle the withdrawal defense command.
Also with the event sourcing, handler is raised and then finally also add a breakpoint in the account
event handler.
Where we consume the funds withdrawn event.
OK, so let's log into my school bank database again.
Again, we want to go and get the idea of the bank accounts in the bank database, in the bank account
table, then just go ahead and copy the bank account, the.
Add a new tab in person and change it to put your HTP localhost for 2005, the API Gateway again API
V1 withdrawal funds forward, slash the bank account idee.
Let's get a JWT.
Again, added as a parent, taken the.
For our request body, we will add an amount so we know that John Doe's got 150 dollars, but let's
try to withdraw 200 dollars from his account.
He'd send now it will hit our break point.
Also put a break point in the catch in the command handler will see that it raises an illegal status
exception.
It's a catch.
And then it replies with 500 internal server error and error, word processing request to withdraw funds
from bank account.
For Idy, the actual error description will be in the container log.
Now let's update the amount to ninety dollars and then let's try the withdrawal again.
Again, it's our break point.
Dispatch the command and ultimately the event handler considers the event and updates the balance in
the database.
And then you'll see the new balance for John Doe is sixty dollars.
Let's check our right database or event store and there you'll see a new funds withdrawn event.