To process queries as a dedicated messaging type is in line with securest best practices to segregate
your query models from your commands.
Now to create a query, API is fairly easy and you could do it without the need of Exxon.
However, using the Excel framework to build a query, API holds a few benefits.
For example, the reuse of features such as interceptors and message monitoring.
In this lecture, we are going to create three query models, including one for finding all users,
another for finding a user by idea, and yet another for searching for users.
Let's start by creating our first query model navigate to the queries package under the User Query API
project.
Let's create a new class and call it Find All Users Query.
Now this object will contain no fields'.
It will simply represent a query where we want to return all users without any way close or faulter.
Let's create another class and call it find user by idee query.
And let's add the data annotation and we can go ahead and add an ID field.
And then finally, let's create another class and call it search users query.
Again, at the data annotation to reduce the boilerplate code and go ahead and add a Stringfield for
a search full to.
OK, let's build our project.
And everything should build successfully.