In this lecture, we are going to implement the user query handler query handling components, Akton,
incoming query messages like the ones we have to find in the previous lecture.
The purpose is generally to query data from the database, navigate to the handlers package under the
user query API project.
Now, let's go ahead and add a new interface, and we can call the interface user query handler.
Now we are going to define three methods and we want to return a response DCO, so let's add a new clause
to the DTA package and call it user Look-Up Response.
Now, go ahead and add the data annotation.
And then we will add a user field that will be used to return the user data that we are going to query
from the database.
Also at the edge, all ARC's constructor annotation.
Now, let's define our first method, let's call it get user by I.D..
And it will take in the fined user by Idy query.
It's at a second method that will also return the user Look-Up response, let's call it search users
and it will take in the search user query.
And then a final message will also return the user Look-Up response, let's call it get all users and
it'll take in, find all users query.
Now, go ahead and add a new Java class and call it user query handler EMPL.
Let's implement the user query handly interface.
Importantly, we need to add the service annotation to use a query handle handler input clause to market
as a service.
We are going to need the user repository to query the user database.
So let's add a private final user repository field and then we are going to use dependency injection
to inject the user repository.
It's added as a parameter to our constructor.
Let's do the assignment.
And then to ensure that the spring IOC container injects it, let's add the auto wird annotation.
OK, now we are going to add the query handler annotations to each of our methods in X on an object
made it clear one or more query handler methods by annotating them with the query handler annotation.
The declared parameters of the methods define which query message it will receive in our case, find
use about idee, query, search user query and find all users query.
Let's start by implementing the get all users method creates a new variable and call it users and then
we will return multiple users.
By invoking the user repository dot find all method, which is, by the way, available out of the box
when you inherit from the Mongo repository and then.
We can return a new instance of the user Look-Up Response DTL.
And pass in our users now they just go and modify our user Look-Up response because I originally added
a single user as a field.
So let's just change that to a list of user.
And then let's change it to users at the airport.
OK, now it should be happy.
The next method that we are going to implement is the search uses method.
Now, remember, the search uses query object contains a search filter.
And we want to use the search filter to do a like query on a number of users and account fields.
In order to do so, we need to extend the user repository by adding a custom Mongo DB query.
We can do so by making use of the query annotation, which allows us to add our own query.
Now we want to do the like query on a number of different fields so we can use the poor operator, you
can do so by using dollar or and then we will use regular expressions to do a like on the first name.
But
if you are not familiar with Mongo DB, the syntax might be a bit confusing.
Let's copy everything.
Let's look at the main object again.
Let's include the last name, as well as the email address.
So let's change the first time there to last name, so we'll do it like on first name and last name
and then go ahead and copy everything from the curly brackets.
The second curly bracket, OK, and a comma basically included as part of the or OK, let's change that
second last name to email address.
Again, copy everything there and another comma to include it as part of the order.
Let's go to the account object.
We also want to do it on the username.
So we can change the day to account.
DOT username.
And then the ore will also be done on the user name, so we've got the user name, the email address,
the last name and the first name.
So we will return a list of users.
It's called out Method Find by Folta Radix, and we can pass in a string filter.
At the airport statement.
Now, let's go back to use a query handly implementation class.
Again, we can add a variable for users
and we will return a list of users, let's invoke user repository that find by Folta rejects and we
can get the filter from the search user query.
Can return in the instance of user Look-Up response.
And we can pass in the users now the final message that we can implement is to get user by ID miss it.
Yeah, we will only get a single user.
We can invoke user repository dot fined by Idy, which is an out of the box method that's available
when you extend the Mongered repository.
It's going to add a new constructor.
It'll take in a single user.
And then we can basically instantiate a new list.
And we can simply add the single user to the list of users, so when invoking the gate user by ID method,
you always only have a single user in the list of users.
OK, let's return a new instance.
Let's see if a user is present.
And if it is, we can instantiate a new instance of user lookup response, passing the user to our new
constructor alse return.
No.
And just call doGet because the user is optional.
OK, now let's build our project.
And everything should build successfully.