It is now time for us to implement the query side of our bank account domain.
Let's start by creating our query objects.
We are going to create four query objects, including one for returning all accounts.
Another returning a bank account by ID.
Another for returning an account by Holder.
And finally, one for returning accounts with balances that are greater or smaller than a give and balance.
Navigate to the queries package and the bank account query API project.
Creates a new class and Corlett find all accounts query.
Now we don't need to add any fields, create another class and call it find account by Idy query
again at the data annotation as well as the all ARC's constructor annotation.
And then we only need to add a single field, basically a field for the idy.
OK, add another query.
Object Aulet find account by holda id.
We can copy the annotations.
And then we will add also only a single field, basically the account holder is
OK, and then our final query object, the find a card with balance query
also at the annotations data and all constructor.
And then we'll add two fields first and enum that we are going to create just now equality type.
Let's go ahead and added and Dito.
Add a new Inam, call it a quality type, the first Inam will be greater than basically four accounts
with balances greater than and less than.
OK.
And then add another field.
For the balance, so basically this query object will allow us to return balances that are greater than
or less than a certain balance.
OK, let's go ahead and build our applications.
Everything should build successfully.