In this lecture, we are going to implement the user lookup controller to provide our user query API
with a restful endpoint for retrieving or querying user data, navigate to the controllers package and
through the user query API project.
Let's create a new class and call it user lookup controller.
Let's at the wrest control, annotation and our request mapping annotation for our path, we can use
API forward slash V1 forward slash user Look-Up.
Now, the next thing we are going to do is to add a private final query Gateway Field.
Now the query gateway is a convenient interface and query despatching mechanism that allows you to send
a query and wait for a single or multiple results, either synchronously with a timeout or asynchronously.
Okay, let's add a constructor that takes in the query gateway and then we can do the assignment.
I've also added Auto Wired to ensure that the user query gateway dependency gets injected.
OK, now let's create our first gate mapping.
A get htp verb is obviously used to retrieve data.
So we will return a response entity and we can return a user lookup response.
Let's call it get all users, and we won't have any parameters there.
We can first do our try catch.
And then, as with our previous controllers, we can create a safe error message variable where we can
say failed to complete, get all users request.
But again, we can print the actual error out and that will be printed out in the container log when
we deploy our military services to DOCA.
And then let's return a response entity and then we can instantiate a new user lookup response instance.
Now, in this case, we actually also want to send a message.
Remember, we use the base response that contains a message.
So let's cut the base response and move it to the user core package so that both the user command API
and Query API can access it.
It's created DTL package and we can paste it in there.
And intelligence allows you to refactor, which is quite nice.
And then let's go back to our comptroller and then we can go and.
Update user Look-Up Response.
Let's extend the base response object.
Now, unfortunately, Lomborg does not work so well when you inherit from another object, so will remove
that
and let's create a new constructor that takes in the message and a single user so you can use super
to pass the message to the base class there.
And let's copy that and create another constructor.
And he takes in a message.
That's the one we will use just now.
In this case, we can say no to the base response class.
And there we have Lombok annotations on our base response object.
OK, now we can pass in the safe error message and we can return HDB status code 500 internal server
error.
OK, let's create a new instance of the find all users query,
then create a new variable and call it response.
And we will use the query gateway and invoke the query method.
And we will go ahead and pass in our query instance and specify that we would want a response type.
Of User Look-Up Response.
Now, remember, in our user query handler, we implemented all those query methods, so the query Gateway
knows exactly which one to invoke and then we can return a new response entity.
And passing the response as well as HDB status code, OK, if all goes well, but obviously we can't
assume that.
So let's see if we actually have one or more uses in our response.
Now, we remove the data annotation because we inherited from base response.
So we need to go ahead and add the gates and setters ourselves.
So let's start with gate users where we can return our list of users.
And let's get ahead at the center where we will set our users policy on a list of user.
And then we will just to sign it to users.
OK, so if we go back.
We can go and check if our response actually contains uses its first check of the responses now or if
Kate uses is null, if either is true, we can return a new response entity.
When we return, null and HDB status code two for no content.
OK, now we can implement two more Gatemouth, it's.
And kidnapping again, and this time we will actually add a parameter as part of our path, Heidi,
this will be our Kate user by Idy method.
Just copy everything and change the method name to Kate, user by idee.
And then we can instantiate find usable I'd Creary, let's pause in a path variable, the value will
be idy the same as our Kate mapping and will pass in the string ID as a parameter.
And then we can pass in the I.D. for our find use of Bidi Creary.
Let's just go to our query object and add in at all ARC's constructor, that'll take in an idea the.
OK, then everything seems fine, let's just change our safe error message to fail to complete Katusa
by Idy request, the rest of the code should remain the same.
And then finally, let's implement a search uses method will take in a full to.
Let's call it search user by Folta, our path variable will change to filter and will pass in the string
filter.
Change that to search users query.
Let's just make sure that we have the name correct.
Yes, search uses filter to copy that name also at the auction constructor, because we are going to
need it.
OK, and passing the floater to the constructor.
The race remains the same.
Let's change our safe error message to fail to complete user search request.
OK.
Now, let's go ahead and debug user query API.
You only need to debug or run your user query application.
Now we have an error there.
Oh, yes, we need to go and add one more constructor because we no longer have the loan book at all.
Instructor on our user lookup response object.
So let's add a another constructor that takes in a list of user.
And we'll just pause now as the message to the base response.
And a sign that uses.
And that should do it.
OK, let's try again.
Let's pull that application first to make sure that we have no errors.
Go ahead and add a breakpoint on each of our Gatemouth, it's.
Also in the query handly implementation.
We query handly methods for.
And now let's dbag again.
OK, there you can see that application is running on Port 882.
And copy the request mapping path.
They open up postmen space that they go ahead and copy the HP localhost 881 and then just change that
to 82.
OK, now you will see that we got an unauthorized so we also need to add our temporary security conflict
clause that we will remove when we have implemented the security on our APIs.
OK.
Stop the debug dbag again.
Let's go back to Posman and send our request, you'll see it hits our kid will use this method.
And they dispatched the query and they you'll see we actually have two users, John Doe and Jane Doe
and.
If we continue there, you'll see there you have John Doe and Jane Doe in our results.
OK, now let's copy the idea of John and Postering.
Send it and we get an internal server error.
The reason is because the signature of Katusa by Idy and search users is the same.
Both have a string, so let's rather add a method name in our path.
Let's call it by faulter.
Dbag again got by Idy for the Katusa by idee.
Open up Posman again at by forward, slash the ID and now it hits our breakpoint in Katusa by Idee.
Nice to see.
There you'll see that we have one user, John Doe, and if we run, you'll see it returns John Doe back
again.
We can get both users to.
And let's go and copy Jane Doe's ID
plan, let's call the buy I.D. May 3rd party, Jane's ID, and there you can see Jane Doe being returned
now to try the buy filter.
Let's pass it, Jane.
And it hits the search by filter method runit and Jane Doe is returned.
This person Doe turns nasty.
Let's try.
John turns on John.
Let's again try Spring Bank at Spring Bank
there due to its birth, because birth email addresses are at Spring Bank, though it was needed to
add a capital D for the last name.
Seems like it's case sensitive.
The.