In this lecture, we are going to create an account query handler to extend the query messages that
we have created in the previous lecture.
This account query handler will be responsible for querying data from the bank account re database via
the account repository.
Again, a bank account database is our MySQL database where our bank account records are stored.
I want to emphasize the beauty of the database service approach that we are following in this course
for our use of micro services.
We have a Mongar DB Right database entry database and for our bank account micro services we have a
Mongo DB Right database or event store and my sequel read database.
We could really have had four different database types here.
However, the focus of this course is to emphasize that since each micro service has data sovereignty
over its data, your architecture becomes database agnostic, application driven rather than database
driven guy to hand this package under the bank account query API project, let's create a new interface
and call it account query handler.
We are going to define four methods.
Let's start by defining a method that will find an account by idee.
It will take in the fight to count by Idy query.
Now, let's copy the Kadlec up response name and create a new clause and the DTA, now the account lookup
response DCO will extend the base response.
Let's create a construct that matches the super.
Then add a new private field, full list of bank account.
Let's call it accounts.
Let's just add the import statements there.
Go ahead and copy the constructor and add a new one in the second constructor.
We will also pass in the list of bank cards.
Then we can do the assignment.
OK, let's go back to Creary handler at the impact statement there, let's add a third constructor and
this time one that takes the message as well as a single bank account.
Let's change that to new array list.
This to count start ed, and then we'll add the single account that is passed to the constructor.
Now, we still need to create Sator and Gatemouth it
the first set of cards then will pass in a list of bank account.
And then our kids, that would get the list of accounts.
OK, so that is all we have to do for the account lookup response, a second method will also return
the Caleca response, let's call it find I can't buy a Holda ID.
This will be the user ID of the user that holds the account and will pass in find account holder ID
query.
OK, and then our third method will return a countercoup response again, let's call it, find all accounts
and we'll pass in, find all accounts, query, and then for our fourth and last method, return a cowardly
response, find accounts with balance
and we'll pass in the find accounts with balanced query.
OK, now let's create a class that will implement the interface, call it accounts, query handler input.
And then start by annotating it with the service annotation
and then we can add a private field for the account repository.
Again, we will use dependency injection to inject the account repository dependency into account,
query handler EMPL.
And don't forget to add or to what?
OK, so now go ahead and add the query handler annotation for each of our query handler methods.
Let's start by implementing the find account by Idy method, we can get a bank account from our bank
account database by working account repository DOT fined by Idy and we can get our bank account ID from
our query object.
Now we need to make sure that we actually have a bank account, so for our response, we can go ahead
and use the present method to see if we actually have a bank account, because Finbarr Idee returns
an optional bank account.
So if we do, we can return a new account Lookup responds with a message such as bank account successfully
returned.
And then we can pause in bank account dot gate if we do not have a bank account.
We can return a new account lookup response with only a message such as no bank account found.
For I.D., and then we can add the bank account I.D. to our message.
And then we can return the response now let's copy the final account by dimethoate.
Because the final count by Holda ID will look similar instead of query dot gate ID, will you get a
card holder ID and will change messages to no bank account found for Holda Idee.
But we also need to do one more thing, go to the account repository and add a new method that will
return an optional bank account like the Finbarr ID.
Let's call it fine by account holder Idy and spring day to JPA would make sure that everything after
fined by the field name, in other words, will be translated into a sequel query.
Let's go back and change our method to find by account holder idee.
OK, so now let's implement the find all accounts method.
So will add a bank account iterator because you'll see a current repository dot find all returns and
iterable of bank account and then to check if we do have bank accounts or not, we can say not.
Bank account iterated dot iterator dot has next.
And if that's not true, then it means we don't have any bank accounts and then we can return a new
account lookup response with a message that says no bank accounts were found.
But if we do have next in The Iterator, we can get the bank accounts by creating a new array list of
bank account.
Just add the import statement, the.
And then bank account iterator taught for each for each item in the iterator, we can say bank account
Dot and I, we I would be a bank account, for instance.
And then let's add a variable for the count.
And we can simply say bank accounts that size to count the amount of bank accounts.
Let's return a new account lookup response with a message that is successfully returned.
And then we can add the count.
Bank accounts.
And also pass in the list of bank accounts.
A final message that we need to implement is the final accounts with balance method.
So we need to add two more methods to our current repository, one that returns a list of bank accounts
and we'll call it Find.
By balance, greater then and then we can pass in a balance now again, Spring JPA will ensure that
that is translated into a sequel query.
And then let's also add one full find by balance, less than make sure that you say less then and not
smaller then, because Spring JPI expects less and not smaller.
OK.
So let's use query that kit, a quality type, if the quality type is greater, then then we invoke
the find by a balance greater than method.
And we can pass in the balance or else we can invoke the find by balance less than.
And again, we'll pass in the ballots.
Then we can do a check to see if we actually do have bank accounts by checking if the bank accounts
or not now or if the size is greater than zero.
And then we can return a new instance of a Kadlec up response with a message such as.
Successfully returned.
And then we can get the count again, bank accounts that size
and bank accounts similarly to the find all accounts message that we are returning, they are supposed
we could have also added a variable for the count, but nonetheless, both will work perfectly.
And if we don't have any bank accounts, then we can say no bank accounts without just copy it from
the above method and then go ahead and return the response.
OK, we have implemented all of our query, had methods to go ahead and build your project.
And everything should build successfully.