In the previous lecture, we have implemented the account query handler.
Now we are going to create a risk controller that will expose an HTP endpoint for querying data from
the bank account database.
It is going to use a query gateway that will dispatch the query object to the query handler methods
that we have defined in the account query handler.
These again will utilize the account repository to query the MySQL database where we are storing our
bank account records, navigate to the controls package and the bank account query API, create a new
class and call it account lookup controller.
Start by annotating it with the rest controller annotation as well as the request mapping annotation
for our path.
We can use API forward slash V1 Forward slash bank account lookup.
Now, let's add a private final field for the query gateway, we are again going to use dependency injection
to inject the query gateway dependency into a card lookup controller constructor.
Now, let's start by implementing our first kid method for our kid mapping, we can simply go ahead
and add forward slash for our path.
We also need to secure our gate.
It therefore add the preauthorization annotation and make sure that the user that makes the request
has read privileges.
We will return the account lookup response as the response entity, let's call our method, get all
accounts, it is not going to take in any parameters.
So let's start with the try catch.
As always, it's good to add a safe error message.
We can add a message such as failed to complete get all accounts request.
And then we will also log the actual error message to the container log by using system that OUTHRED
print line, and then we are going to return a new instance of a card lookup response with a safe error
message, as well as HDB status code 500 internal server error.
Now, let's instantiate a new instance or find all accounts Creary.
And then we can get the response with all of our accounts by invoking query, gateway, dot, query,
passing in our query and specifying the response time as a card lookup response.
That class and dot join.
OK, and then let's make sure that we actually have a response.
So if the response is no or response that get counts.
Equals now.
Then we can return the Icard lookup response.
As now as well as SCDP status quo to for no content.
But if we do have a response and we do have one or more accounts, we can return our response with HDB
status code two hundred.
Okay.
Go ahead and copy the entire kit method and then we are going to change it to return the account by
I.D. to change the path to buy Ida forward, slash Ida and then we'll pass in the account I sold.
Also change the method name to get a count by Ida.
And then we are going to pass in a path variable that is going to be the bank account Ida.
And let's change the query that we instantiate to find it count by Idy query, and then we are going
to pass in the ID, OK?
The race stays the same.
Just change the safe error message to fail to complete account, but by the request and then go ahead
and copy the entire git method again.
And then we are going to change it to buy whole dite.
And also change that to account holder, the for a path variable and copy that across for the value
of the path variable as well and change the parameter name as well.
Also, change the method to get a card by Holder Idy and pass in the account holder ideas.
Well, change the safe error message to fail to complete.
Get a card by Holder ID request.
And then it's copy the entire method and change it to with balance, and then we are going to pass in
a quality time greater than or less then and another parameter, which is going to be the balance and
then add that, change it to quality type enum.
Also change the parameter name and add a second path variable for our balance.
And then it's going to be a type double and balance and change the query to find a card with balance
query plus in the equality type as well as the balance.
OK, and then change the safe error message to fail to complete credit cards with balance request.
OK, so that concludes the implementation of all our methods, so let's build our project.
Both successfully.
Now, let's go ahead and add API gateway routes for a new account lookup controller.
So copy the user lookup API Gateway route and change it to bank I.C.C., query API.
Port 1992 and change there, two bank account, look up
this, just copy it over and make sure that it's the correct name and also changed it for the predicate.
OK.
Let's go ahead and run our API Gateway application.
As well as our bank account query application.
Also, go ahead and run the Health 2.0 authorisation server, we'll need to get JWT to get.
And then go ahead and run the user query API as well, because we are going to need to get a few user
IDs because remember, we deleted one and only bank account, so also ran the bank account command API.
And then that should do it, so put a break point in all of our controller methods.
Then open postman.
So let's add a new tab, and for the year, I will use SCDP localhost 2000 through the API Gateway Forward
Slash API forward slash fee, one bank account, Look-Up Forward Slash.
So that's to return all bank accounts.
That's going to say that we are unauthorized.
So let's get a new JWT.
We are using John Doe.
That's got right.
And probably just remember.
That it is a period taken and then it hits control method and you'll see that we actually have no accounts
left and we get a state escucha for no content.
So now we need to go and create bank accounts for our users.
Let's start by making a post to the open bank account controller, Messitte.
But first, we need to get a user I.D. for account holder I.D..
So for John Doe, that's copy his user ID.
And then as the account holder item, we will pass in John Doe's.
Let's give him a savings account, this time with an open balance of 100 dollars.
OK, let's just make sure that that JWT hasn't expired yet.
OK.
Update the pyrotechnician and let's hit send.
The bank account was successfully opened to one created.
OK, now let's go ahead and add one for Jane Doe's well.
So just update the account holder.
I'd say it's given a current account with the balance of two hundred dollars.
Hit send.
And her account was opened successfully as well.
And then for James Doe.
Katie's user ID, they change the account holder ID, leave it a current account and change his balance
to 300 dollars.
No, let's give him a savings account, rather.
OK, hit send and successfully open a new bank account for James Doe, log into your MySQL database.
Into the bank database, bank account table, and then you'll see that we have three bank accounts and
they are the balances that we gave each of our users.
So for the bank account, Look-Up, get a new token.
And then we will retrieve all bank cards, just update the period in the.
And it hits a kid on the accounts query controller method, reads the query handler.
And then it queries the MySQL database, returns the Kadlec response, we have response status code
two hundred and successfully return three bank accounts.
And you can see bank accounts for John, Jane and James.
OK, so now let's look up by I.D. and then we'll pass in James's I.D., Remember, he's got three hundred
dollars and then it hits it count by dimethoate and you'll see it hits Creary handling method as well.
And then bank accounts successfully returned with status quo two hundred and they you can see the bank
detail now again, they get all the cards, get the cardholder I.D. of Jane Doe's account
ID, send it hit Skate's account by Holder idee.
Now you'll see that there is actually a mistake.
I made it find the account by Idy query that should be find a card holder idy query, see what copy
and paste does.
They just build our project again to make sure and everything should build successfully debug the bank
account query application again.
And let's go back to pressmen, try that again, it hits and try to make it dispatches, the query is
the query handler method.
And it successfully returns the bank account of Jane Doe.
This is the bank account holder, Eyedea, that we queried with and that works.
So let's try with balance, let's say with a balance greater than
50 hit.
Send it a controlling method.
Gets dispatched, his secretary handling method.
And it returns it, see what it returns, it actually returns all three accounts because all of them
are greater than 50.
Change that to a hundred and fifty.
And then it's supposed to return to great.
OK, so let's try greater than 200 and it only returns.
James does a count of 300 dollars.
It's less than 200.
I only have one John Doe's account with 100 dollars.
They said to 10.
We get two hundred and hundred, John and Jane.
And they nothing less than 50.
Less than 300.
Again, I need to 310.
All three.