Let's take a look at building a more in‑depth look at
CodeArtifact and setting it up.
First,
we need to make sure you have the right
prerequisites required to use CodeArtifact.
There's only one thing we need to have,
and we already have it set up, and that's IAM.
Okay, so we already have everything set up and in place.
Let's take a look at what CodeArtifact domains are.
A domain is the highest level component of CodeArtifact.
It combines all of CodeArtifact's repositories in one group. You
cannot create a repository without a domain.
The domain names are unique per account.
You can combine repositories from other accounts and upstream
repositories in one domain. Domains handle deduplication of software
packages in your repository so it'll save space.
We'll talk more about this later on.
It allows for fast copying of packages between repositories by using metadata
using a deduplication process we'll talk more about on later.
Using a domain, you can easily share packages across repositories and teams.
It is the first point of contact.
It also allows you to easily set an IAM policy to all of your
repositories in one go, and we'll also find out how to do this.
Okay, so we learned what a domain is in CodeArtifact.
Let's take a look at how to create one. In this demo,
we're going to cover how to create a CodeArtifact domain.
Here we are inside of the AWS CodeArtifact dashboard.
Let's go over to Domains. In here we're going to click
Create domain and then we'll give it a name.
So let's call it a globomantics‑domain.
You can also configure a different customer managed
key that will encrypt your data.
Well, for simplicity during this demo I'm going to use the AWS one.
Let's click Create domain. Boom, how easy was that?
So now we've just created our first domain and in here
are going to live our repositories.
For the next thing, you need to know about
CodeArtifact domains or domain policies.
In this section,
I'll talk you through what they are and how to apply
them to your CodeArtifact domain.
You can attach a domain policy to an AWS CodeArtifact domain.
A domain policy is a resource level IAM access policy that you
can use to restrict or give access to your AWS CodeArtifact
repository inside of your domain.
When you attach a domain,
it is then applied to all of your repositories in that domain.
This is really handy if you want to quickly apply the same policy to
each repository. You can even use domain policies to allow
cross‑account access from different AWS accounts.
This is handy if you have a multi‑account architecture and want to use the
same software packages across all of your accounts. And the benefit of
this is it will save you time and also money.
There are multiple ways to create a domain policy either
via the AWS CLI or using the dashboard.
Okay,
so now we know what a domain policy is and what it does, let's take a look at
how to create one and apply it to our CodeArtifact domain. In this demo we're
going to create a CodeArtifact domain policy.
Let's jump straight in.
Okay, so now we have a domain set up, let's go and give it a policy.
So at the top right,
I'm going to apply a domain policy. This policy that I'm pasting in
right now can be found inside the course documents,
and it's going to allow a simple set of basic access to our AWS account.
I'm going to hit Save, and that's it. We now have domain policy set up and our domain.