Hi there, and welcome this module in our Pluralsight course,
Monitoring and Event Response on AWS for DevOps Engineers.
My name is Mike Brown.
In this module,
we're going to be looking at AWS CloudWatch log retention and archiving.
In this module, we're going to learn how to store logs for long‑term retention.
By storing logs long term,
we can keep coming back to those logs and asking different
business questions against the data inside there.
There may also be different compliance reasons that we
have to retain logs longer term.
So we're going to discuss the importance of long‑term log
retention and demonstrate how to archive logs from
CloudWatch into products like S3.
So let's begin by discussing log retention and archiving logs.
So with CloudWatch log retention, we have two options.
The default is never expire.
So if you do nothing, all your log data will be stored indefinitely.
The second option is expire after.
So if you want your long information to expire,
you can configure settings from 1 day to 10 years.
And there are several factors to consider,
which will guide us towards either never expire or expire after.
So one of the first things to know is we get 5GB of logs for free per month.
This 5GB includes log storage,
but also actions like data routing. After that 5GB,
we are charged a per‑GB fee for log collection,
storage, and analysis.
That analysis covers features like Log Insights.
So the more you store and analyze above that 5GB,
the more expensive CloudWatch logs gets.
In a region like eu‑west‑2 then,
we are paying 0.0315 per gigabyte for log storage.
Now that might seem like a small amount,
but these fees still start to add up,
particularly when you consider how much data we're collecting in logs every day.
Logs from AWS services,
logs from our EC2 instances will soon mean that this 0.0315
per‑gigabyte fee starts to add up to serious money.
In comparison, if we were to store the same information in Glacier storage,
our per‑gigabyte fee would be 0.0045 per gigabyte.
So it's much cheaper to store logs longer term in
Glacier than it would in CloudWatch.
There's lots of questions to ask here.
How quickly do you need access to log information?
What actions are you performing against those logs on a regular basis?
But if we're talking purely about archival,
then Glacier is a more cost‑effective option for
storing your logs than CloudWatch is.
When working with CloudWatch Logs,
one of the things we can do is export our log data to Amazon S3.
Amazon S3 itself supports some really powerful tools for
working with and storing logging information.
We can also stream our CloudWatch log data to Elasticsearch.
This gives a more powerful search environment,
plus integration with visualization tools like Kibana.
We can also stream log data to Amazon Kinesis.
This gives you the ability to work with that data using features
like Kinesis Analytics and other Kinesis applications. By
archiving our CloudWatch log data to S3, we get the ability to
work with S3 storage classes.
This allows us to choose a storage class for our information with the
correct level of service and at the right price for us.
Once in S3, log data can be used by products like Elastic MapReduce,
EMR, Amazon Redshift, our data warehouse service, as well as search
against that log data using Amazon Athena. It might also be easier to
find third‑party applications that integrate directly with S3
compared to finding third‑party applications that integrate directly
with CloudWatch.
So by getting that CloudWatch data into S3, it could be
used by a wider range of services.
It's also true that CloudWatch is pretty regional.
Whenever we're looking at CloudWatch,
we're looking at CloudWatch for a specific region. Integration with
S3 means that we can take CloudWatch logs from multiple regions,
store them in a single bucket, and have this centralized information
from all of our different regions.
When exporting log data to Amazon S3, we need to create an
S3 bucket to store the information in.
And although the buckets can be encrypted, encryption
with a KMS key is not supported.
We need to use S3 zone encryption on the buckets that we're going to
archive our CloudWatch log data into. Logs from multiple log groups can
be exported to the same bucket, but log data can take up to 12 hours to
become available for export.
So when we export data to Amazon S3, this is not a real‑time service. Log
data will be available CloudWatch almost straightaway, and a some later time,
it's available for export to S3. If you want near real‑time access to log
information, consider using Log Insights. So almost immediately as
information is logged to CloudWatch, Log Insights can view it or consider
integration with Amazon Kinesis.
One other thing to consider is automation. So we can manual export our logs
to S3, or we can set up a scheduled CloudWatch event to trigger a Lambda
function or a Step Function for daily exports to S3.
Remember, automation is key. When we do export log data to S3,
our logs become objects.
Each object has a storage class, and we can manually set the storage
class for each object, or we can use lifecycle rules.
Lifecycle rules allow us to automatically transition objects
between one storage class and another, as well as allowing
us to expire objects as well.
S3 is very feature‑rich, but a couple of features you might want to
consider using are object lock and replication.
Object lock has been configured when your S3 bucket is created. With
object lock, we can put in rules that guarantee that objects cannot be
deleted or altered for a given time period.
This will help us satisfy various compliance standards that we might be trying
to achieve. Replication allows us to replicate objects from one region to
another. We might do this to guard against regional failure or to get our S3
data closer to the people that need it. Let's take a look at some of this integration action then.