Hi there, and welcome to the module in our Pluralsight course,
Monitoring and Event Response on AWS for DevOps Engineers.
My name's Mike Brown,
and I'm a senior cloud instructor at Firebrand Training here in the UK.
In this module, we're going to introduce you to Amazon CloudWatch.
We're going to begin this module with a brief course overview
followed by a discussion of why this course might be important to
you. We're then going to give a very quick module overview before
introducing Amazon CloudWatch.
So let's begin then with a course overview. This course is intended
to give you a detailed understanding of Amazon CloudWatch so you can
leave this course with understanding of how CloudWatch can be used
for your DevOps projects.
We're going to begin by introducing CloudWatch's main features before
setting our focus on Amazon CloudWatch Logs to give you an
understanding of what can be logged in CloudWatch and how you can use
those logs for monitoring and automation.
Throughout this course,
we're going to be working with Amazon CloudWatch Events and
EventBridge, and we'll see how event‑driven architectures can
help you in your DevOps teams.
We're also going to be looking at CloudWatch Alarms and looking at
how CloudWatch Alarms can be used to automate responses to
performance metrics and information in our logs.
We're also going to take a look at how CloudWatch integrates with other
AWS services to help fulfill your DevOps requirements.
So, why might this course be important for you?
Well, automation is key to a successful cloud project,
and CloudWatch sits at the heart of automation inside AWS.
Now, we're all keen to save time, and usually for saving
time, that means we're saving money.
So understanding how CloudWatch integrates with event response will help
you save time and money that can be spent elsewhere.
Security is important to us all, so throughout this course,
we're going to be looking at different security aspects of AWS with a focus
on securing access to CloudWatch, as well as implementing tagging and EC2
metadata to help secure our AWS infrastructure.
So if automation, saving time and money, and
security is important to your projects, then you will benefit from this course.
If I was asked who should attend this course,
I would say anyone interested in using CloudWatch for
event monitoring and response, well,
this course is perfect for you. Also, any learner that's part
of a DevOps team or who has monitoring as part of their job
rule will benefit from this course.
But there are a couple of things that I would
suggest before attending this course.
The first is an understanding of core AWS services, services like EC2, VPC,
RDS. A basic understanding of these will help you understand the concepts
we're about to cover in the next couple of hours.
Also, an understanding of AWS cloud concepts, like server‑based deployments
for EC2 and serverless deployments with products like Lambda and API Gateway
will help you get the most out of this course.
But even if you are new to AWS and new at DevOps,
I'm sure there's going to be plenty during this course
that'll make the next 2 hours worthwhile.
Now,
to help us understand some of the concepts that we're going to
be discussing over the next couple of hours,
we're going to be working of our customer, Globomantics. Now
Globomantics is a global healthcare organization.
They've been working with AWS for some time and use most of the AWS
core services, such as EC2, RDS, S3, and more.
We've been asked to identify solutions that Globomantics
can use for monitoring an event response.
We've also been asked help Globomantics understand how key monitoring
solutions integrate with other AWS services. So we're going to keep
coming back to Globomantics' requirements throughout this course, and
hopefully by helping Globomantics,
it'll make it easier for us to understand the concepts that we're
going to introduce over the next couple of hours.
So in this module, we'll be introducing CloudWatch.
We're going to start by listing some of CloudWatch's key features and
what they do. We'll then cover some of the details of logs and log
streams before going on to discuss securing CloudWatch with a focus on
permissions and encryption of logs. So, let's begin.