In this demonstration,
we're going to take a look at archiving CloudWatch logs to Amazon S3.
Throughout this demonstration, we're going to be working with the AWS Console.
And as always, to follow along this demonstration,
you will need your own AWS account.
Keep in mind that anything you deploy to AWS can incur costs.
I'm in the AWS Console,
specifically the CloudWatch dashboard in the London region.
Let's select Log groups.
and from inside here, I'm going to choose Globomantics‑CloudTrail‑Logs log group.
Then from the Actions drop‑down, we can see Export and Subscriptions.
So if you want information in this log group to appear in Elasticsearch,
we can create an Elasticsearch subscription,
or if you want information in this log group to trigger Lambda function,
we can select Create Lambda subscription.
I want to export data to Amazon S3, so I choose Export data to Amazon S3.
We can then define the data that we want to export by
putting in a From and To date and time, and then we choose an S3 bucket.
So I want to export to a bucket in this account,
so I choose the bucket name from the drop‑down list.
We can add a prefix value here,
so we can more easily identify the objects that
will be created in the S3 bucket.
And then we select Export.
It should only take a minute to export the data,
and here we can see that it was successfully exported.
If I select Actions again,
there's an option here to View all exports to Amazon S3.
Let's select that.
And here we can see a couple of exports.
If I select the export from 1 minute ago,
I can choose the option View in Amazon S3.
So let's select that.
So we're jumped to the appropriate bucket,
if we navigate down,
we can see the object that was created for me as part of that export.
Now we have to update to an S3,
we can use things like storage classes to reduce costs,
lifecycle rules to automatically transition between
storage classes and to expire objects,
as well as advanced security controls like object log.
One other thing we're going to show you here while we're in S3,
if I go to the S3 bucket itself,
this is the S3 bucket that my objects have being exported to.
If I go to Permissions, and then Bucket Policy.
In order for CloudWatch to export data to S3,
the CloudWatch service needs permissions on the S3 bucket.
This bucket policy grants those permissions.
Notice the two Principal sections.
These identify the CloudWatch service.
It's important though we get the region correct.
If you're exporting data from the US region,
the US region needs to be listed as principal.
I was exporting data from eu‑west‑2, so eu‑west‑2 is the principal.
Also in this policy,
you have to include the correct bucket name in the Resource sections.
This has to match the bucket that the bucket policy is created on.
Without this bucket policy, CloudWatch will not be able to export to S3.
In this module, we discussed the importance of log retention.
We discussed different ways to archive logs,
and we showed you how to archive logs to S3.
In our next module,
we'll be discussing event‑driven automation, we'll learn how to
use event rules to trigger Lambda functions,
and we'll go in for a quick course review.
So join me there, and we'll continue along our Monitoring and
Event Response on AWS for DevOps journey. Thank you.