In this demonstration,
we're going to be working with the CloudWatch event
rule to invoke a step function.
Throughout this demonstration, we're going to be working with the AWS console,
and, as always, to follow along with this demonstration,
you will need your own AWS account.
But be warned, anything you deploy to AWS can cost you money.
I'm back in the AWS console,
specifically the EC2 dashboard in the Ireland region.
In Ireland I've got a single EC2 instance that's currently running.
This instance is host to an application that I want to protect.
So if this instance was to fail in any way,
I would like it replaced, and I don't want to do that manually,
I would like AWS to automatically replace that instance on my behalf.
To that end then, we're going to use several services.
For example, we're going to be using CloudFormation.
This is the CloudFormation dashboard for Ireland,
and I would like a new CloudFormation stack created that launches my
replacement EC2 instance when the first one fails.
This CloudFormation stack then is going to be invoked by a lambda function.
Let's take a quick look at that lambda function.
This is my Node.js lambda function then that's going to
get triggered to create that CloudFormation stack that
will deploy my infrastructure.
This function is capable of doing several things.
The part of the code we're particularly interested in is this
section that will create a stack when invoked,
and it'll create that stack based on a CloudFormation
template stored in an S3 bucket.
It gets the location of that template from the environment variable,
and if I scroll down a little bit, we can see the environment variables,
that includes a name for the stack and location of the CloudFormation template.
So the function will deploy the stack, the stack will deploy the instance,
but what triggers the function?
Well, this lambda function is triggered from a step function,
so let's take a look at the step function.
I'm in the step function dashboard in the Ireland region,
and I can see this single state machine deploycode.
Let's select Edit.
Here then you can see the state machine code and a graphical
representation of this state machine with a startpoint,
an endpoint and two steps in between.
The first step is a deploy step that will invoke a lambda function,
and as we know a lambda function is going to create that
CloudFormation stack that deploys the infrastructure.
The second step sends a message to an SNS topic,
and this topic is used for reporting,
to report this event has taken place and to inform the relevant support
teams that their infrastructure's failed and been replaced.
Now in order for this function to interact with lambda and SNS,
it needs to be given an IAM role, and if we scroll down a little bit,
we can see the role that's been assigned and we can also see login information,
at the minute turned off,
but you can enable login so that invocations about the
state machine can be logged to CloudWatch.
So let's enable that.
So under Log level if we select the drop‑down list,
I will choose to log all events,
and you can see it's going to create a new log group for us inside
CloudWatch to store all this login information.
Let's save the changes to the state machine by scrolling up and clicking Save.
So, with our state machine in place,
our lambda function in place and our CloudFormation template in place,
let's bring all these things together by using CloudWatch.
I'm in the CloudWatch dashboard, specifically in the Ireland region.
I'm already in the event rules section, so let's select Create rule.
Here, I want to match an event pattern.
So under Service Name, let's choose EC2,
and for Event Type, I'll choose EC2 Instance State‑change Notification.
Now for the purposes of this exercise,
I'm going to have to simulate a failure by stopping my EC2 machine.
So if I choose the specific state radio button,
then from the drop‑down list, I will choose stopped.
Now you could further tune this event pattern by
including a specific instance ID, but I'm happy with my settings.
We can see the JSON representation of our pattern as well,
and now I select Add target, and we want to invoke a step function,
and we can choose the step function name from the state machine drop‑down.
As you can see, it's going to create a new IAM role to invoke this step function,
or you can select an existing role.
But if we're happy with our event rule, we can scroll
down and say Configure details.
We provide a name and optional description for our rule and then say
Create rule and here we can see our rule's been created.
So the thing to do now is to simulate the failure.
So if I go back to the EC2 dashboard and shut down this running machine. So
under Actions, we can select Instance state and then I'll just say stop
instance. Similar in our virtual machine failure.
So things should take a second or two to kick in, but if we
go back to CloudFormation stacks, we can see that our stack
creation now is in progress.
If we go back to the EC2 dashboard,
we should see that a new EC2 instance is being launched.
So back in the EC2 dashboard, we can see we've got this
second running machine that's now initializing. So this
is all our healing in action.
One virtual machine failed, that event was picked up by a CloudWatch
event rule, which then automated a remediation process. We have so much choice when it comes to event response and healing in AWS.