In this demonstration,
we're going to be implementing CloudTrail and CloudWatch integration.
We're going to be working with the AWS Console, and if you
wish to follow along with this demonstration,
you will need your own AWS account.
Now, we do encourage you to follow along,
but please keep in mind that anything that you
deploy in AWS could cost you money,
so if you do follow along with the demonstration,
make sure you delete the features that you've
deployed once you no longer need them, or you will incur charges.
I've signed into AWS Console and, specifically,
I'm in the CloudTrail dashboard in the London region.
We can see here that a couple of trails already exist,
and if I scroll down a little bit, we can see the Event history.
Remember,
Event history stores 90 days of CloudTrail activity, but
Globomantics has decided that they need to start their
CloudTrail activity over a longer period.
So if we select Trails,
and then Create trail, we're faced with a standard address form. So
we'll first of all give our trail a nice name,
and we'll call this trail GlobomanticsTrail.
Notice the tick box here that says Enable for all accounts in my organization.
If you select this,
and presuming the user you've logged in with has the appropriate permissions,
then this trail will be duplicated to all AWS accounts in your organization.
We'd be creating centralized audit logs for our entire organization.
If we scroll down a little bit, here we can see the S3 settings.
So anything that CloudTrail collects must be stored in S3,
and optionally can be sent to CloudWatch. So we can select to
use an existing bucket or create a new bucket.
I'll create a new bucket and give it a name that I'll remember later on.
Remember, S3 bucket names have to be globally unique,
so I've used my 12‑digit account ID here to hopefully guarantee a unique name.
Further down, we can see that log file encryption is enabled by default,
and we get to set the key that we use as part of this encryption.
So I'll choose the existing key. And if we scroll down a bit more,
we can see that log file validation is selected by default.
That means that for each log that's created a signed
hash value will also be created.
At a later date, I can use the same hashing algorithm,
compare hashes,
and if they're the same I know my log files have not been tampered with.
We can enable SNS notification if I want to be notified when
a log is created. Scroll down a little bit more, and we get
to our CloudWatch integration.
Now, I want to integrate this CloudTrail with CloudWatch, so let's tick
enabled. And we're asked about our log group, so which log group in
CloudWatch will this CloudTrail log be stored in. We can choose to use
an existing log group, but if I leave new log group selected and give
it a nice name. Again,
scroll down a little bit more, and we're going to choose a
role that has the correct permissions to send these
CloudTrail events to CloudWatch.
So you could leave New selected here if you don't already have a role
that can write to CloudWatch, and then just type in a nice friendly name
for that role. Or if you have a role already,
select Existing and choose a role name.
If you're happy with the role information, scroll
down, we can add tags if we need, and then select Next. Now,
as long as all the information you've put in is valid,
it would move to the Logged events section, but if,
like me, you receive errors, read those errors and adjust accordingly.
So in this example, it tells me this CloudTrail name already
exists so I have to choose a new name.
So instead of GlobomanticsTrail,
let's call this GlobomanticsCloudTrail. Scroll back
down, I'll select Next again.
Now it's about choosing the type of events we want our trail to
log. Management events are enabled by default.
Then we have Data events and Insights events. I'm going to select both of these.
We can then select the type of Management events that we wish to log.
Remember, Management events are all about our authentication and our
API activity. So here you can select if you want to log either Read or
Write API activity. I'll leave both selected, scroll down, and we're
now on Data events. With Data events, we can log S3 or Lambda function
activity.
If I leave S3 selected, we can monitor all S3 buckets, including current
buckets and future buckets. Or, if I untick Read and Write here, we can
choose a specific bucket. So let's do that.
So if I click in Browse, you can choose one of your buckets from the
drop‑down list. And, again, we can choose where we want to record Read or
Write actions on this bucket in our CloudTrail logs.
If you wish to add additional buckets, select Add data event type.
Or, indeed, if you want to log Lambda function activity, again,
choose Add data event type. Scrolling down again, I can select Next. We
get our Review screen, and everything looks good.
So now I'll select Create trail.
It should only take a couple of minutes to create the CloudTrail.
Once we create it,
we're sent back to the Trail dashboard, and we should be
able to see our CloudTrail in the list.
The thing to do now is to generate some activity and see what gets registered.
So, try logging on, logging off. If you're monitoring an S3 bucket, upload
content to the S3 bucket. Once you've generated some activity,
go to the CloudWatch dashboard and see what you can see.
So let's do that.
So I'm back in the CloudWatch dashboard.
If I select Log groups,
we can see the log group that CloudTrail created for us,
here Globomantics‑CloudTrail‑Logs.
So if I select that, we can see a log stream. If I select the log
stream, we can see all the CloudTrail log entries that have been
registered so far. We can expand them here and see the details, or under
Actions we can choose View in Logs Insights.
So here in Log Insights we can use this default
query or type in a query of our own.
If I select Run query then, we can see all the the different
entries organized by timestamp and message. Later in the course, we'll show some more detail filtering using Log Insights.