In this demonstration,
we're going to be working with CloudWatch metrics and alarms.
We're also going to be working with the CloudWatch agent on one of our
EC2 instances. Throughout this demonstration, we're going to be working
with the AWS console, and follow along with this demonstration, you
will need your own AWS account.
A little bit of caution here, anything you deploy to AWS might cost you
money, so by following along in this demonstration,
you may incur charges.
I am back in the AWS console, specifically the
CloudWatch dashboard, in the London region.
Let's start off by selecting Metrics. So here you can see there is over
2000 metrics for London region organized into namespaces. We can see
here custom namespaces, and if I scroll down a little bit, we can see
AWS Namespaces. Let's select EC2.
Inside the EC2 namespace then, we can see different dimensions that we
can use to see groups of metrics in different ways.
So you can see here Per‑Instance Metrics and metrics by autoscale
group. Let's select the Per‑Instance Metrics first.
So here we can see things like Instance Name, Instanceid, and Metric Names.
For the minute what I'm interested in is CPUUtilization,
and we could see an example of that here for
WebServer2. So let's select that metric,
and we can see that metric added to our graph, but how does WebServer2
CPU utilization compare with my other web servers?
Now we see drop‑down option next to CPUUtilization.
Let's select that and then select Add to search.
So now we can see the CPUUtilization metric for a bunch of
instances. I'm going to select a few of those instances.
So WebServer2 is already selected, let's have in there
WebServer 1, 3, 4, and 5. And now we can see the CPU
utilization in relation to each other.
Right now, we'll use our line graph,
so let's click on the drop‑down next to line and select Pie.
Here, we've got the same details then, but now it's a pie chart.
If you have time,
spend a few minutes and have a look at the different graphing options.
Let's give our graph a name. So WebserverCPU there, and then
on the Actions, let's say Add to dashboard.
So here, let's say, create a new dashboard and give it a name.
We can see widgets that allows us to display information in different ways.
I map with pie there, so now we can click Add to dashboard.
Let's add a couple more metrics to this dashboard. So here you can
see we've added packetsIn and packetsOut metrics.
I want to keep this dashboard so I can click Save dashboard, and
again, notice how you can change the timeframes.
So if I change to 3 hours,
12 hours, or 1 hour, we can see the data change in reflection
of that new timeframe. Let's go back to metrics and look at
that WebserverCPU metric again.
So we're back looking at our CPU utilization metrics
for our different web servers.
If I click on Graphed metrics, here,
we could do a bit more of our metric information.
Let's take Webserver4,
for example. Over on the right‑hand side here, we have actions.
Let's have look at a couple of these.
The first action here enables anomaly detection.
This can be useful if you want to be alerted about anomalous activity.
We could also duplicate this metric so we can view the
information in a slightly different way on the same chart and
we can create an alarm for this metric.
So if we hover over the little bell here and select that, it
takes us to the Create alarm wizard. In this wizard, we've
already got the metric selected.
So let's put in some of the values.
I want to be informed if CPU utilization is greater than 80%.
We've also got greater than our equals here,
lower than our equals here, or lower than. I'll stick to
this greater threshold and 80%. If we say next, so if this
alarm goes into alarm state,
I want to be notified. With Select an existing SNS topic selected, we
can use the search option here to choose an SNS topic.
So when this alarm is in alarm state,
it'll send a message to this topic called informMe who
will in turn inform all its subscribers.
Now this is the only action I want for my alarm. So
if I scroll to the bottom now,
I can select Next. We now provide a name for the alarm and an
optional description, and then Next again. We review our settings
and here you can see the current CPU utilization and the threshold
that will generate the alarm, and if we're happy with everything,
we say Create alarm.
So here we have our alarm created and notice its status Insufficient data.
It'll take a few minutes to gather enough information to make a determination,
that's why we have to go to the alarm state or the OK state.
And we should find with these web servers that their CPU utilization is well
below 80%, so this alarm should transition to the OK state. And here, we can
see it's gone to the OK state. If you have time,
play around with metrics and create alarms from them.
Bear in mind, though, I'm seeing lots of metrics in my
CloudWatch dashboard because I've got lots of AWS services deployed to the London region.