In this demonstration, we're going to work with Amazon CloudWatch logs.
We'll be working with the logs through the AWS Console.
To follow along with this demonstration, you will need an AWS account.
Now we do encourage you to follow along with demonstrations,
but be warned, anything that you configure inside of AWS may cost you money.
So if you do follow along with this demonstration,
remember to remove everything you've configured once you have finished with it,
or you may incur charges.
So here we are then in the CloudWatch dashboard.
And as you can see, we're in the London region.
When you first connect to the CloudWatch dashboard, you get this Overview view.
If I select the drop‑down list next to Overview,
and then choose an AWS service, for example,
Lambda,
we can now see a customize dashboard showing us metric
information for our Lambda functions.
If I click on the drop‑down again, and this time choose Kinesis Data Streams,
and now we can see a customize dashboard for Kinesis.
You'll find that most AWS results you deploy present a
customized dashboard in this way.
The dashboard you can see might be different per region depending on the
resources you have deployed to that specific region.
On the left‑hand side here, we can see Dashboards.
Here we can create our own customized dashboards with the
metrics we're particularly interest in.
We can see Alarms, Billing, Metrics, and Events,
all of which were are going to be looking at in later modules of this course.
What we're interested in right now is Logs, so let's select Logs.
So here in Logs, we can create Log groups,
View Log groups or Launch Logs Insights.
We can also select Log groups and Insights from the left‑hand side.
Let's select Log groups.
Here we have three log groups.
Two of these log groups have been generated by Lambda,
and each one of your log groups represents a unique lambda function.
We then have a log group that was generated by CloudTrail.
Now the log groups in your account might vary depending on which
services you have logging into CloudWatch.
I'll select the aws/lambda/KinesisLOG group, and let's see what's inside there.
So we can see some general information, we can see the Creation time,
any metric filters that have been created for this log group,
and over on the right‑hand side, we can see the log group ARN.
This is the Amazon Resource Name that we can use
send log streams to this log group.
If we scroll down a little bit,
we can see that this log group contains a single log stream.
So let's let that log stream and see what's inside there.
So in here we can see lots of log entries.
If I scroll down,
we can see hundreds and hundreds of log entries inside this log stream.
If I select one of these entries and expand its details,
we can see additional information.
So CloudWatch logs contains log groups, log streams, and logs events.
Now you can search through here by using the event
filler, or if I select Actions,
we can select View in Logs Insights. So let's select that. Here in Log
Insights then, we can see that log insights has been filtered to our specific
log stream, and it's going to sort the logs based on two fields, timestamp
and message. Notice the custom times above.
If we run in the query now,
it going to show us events that occurred in the last hour.
Let's try that.
If I select Run query, and we wait for the query to run,
and as you can see, there's no results.
Let's change the time frame to 12 hours, and run the query again.
So now you can see it's found 389 messages..
If I scroll down,
we can see those messages, and if i expand one of
them, we can see additional details.
Log Insights, then,
is a really useful way for searching through the logs that we've
collected in CloudWatch, where you can customize the queries and
search for any of the fields inside our logs.
We'll have my information about the format of these
queries coming up in later modules.
For now,
let's change the fields that our query is using from timestamp and message to
timestamp and requestId. So if I scroll up, and make the change, and then run
the query again. It just takes a minute to run, and when complete, if I scroll
down, now we can see the message is sorted based on the timestamp and requestId.
I expand one of these messages, we can still see the message details.
If there's a particular query that you constantly run against your logs,
you can say Save. So if I select that, so we can give our query a nice name,
we can add the query to a sub folder if we need, and if I scroll down,
we can see the query we're going to save. If I select Save, we now have a
saved query that we can use over and over again without having to type in
the details. You'll find these under queries.
So if I select Queries,
you can see the GloboQuery1 saved, and through that again, you
would select that, and it would be loaded into the dashboard.
Notice here you've got other sample queries.
So if we expand Lambda, here are a few options for Lamda functions.
Let's click Apply, and if we just expand the real estate a little bit,
we can see that appear in Log Insights.
You can search through individual logs streams or through an entire log group.
We can see a history of the queries that have been
run, and we can export the results.
Here we can see we can download the results or copy the
results to the clipboard in various formats.
Throughout this course,
we're going to keep coming back to log groups, running queries.
As we get further into the course, we'll learn more and more about logs, as well as the other features of CloudWatch.