We've been through a lot of information in the last 2 and a half hours,
so let's spend the final couple minutes here highlighting some
of the key features that we've discussed.
This course is focused on CloudWatch.
There are lots of services AWS that DevOps engineers will find useful.
But if we're talking about even response and monitoring,
then CloudWatch is our main tool. In various modules of this course,
we've looked at CloudWatch metrics, dashboards,
CloudWatch alarms, CloudWatch events, and of course,
CloudWatch logs and logging sites.
All of these will be valuable tools to DevOps engineers.
We've also spent a lot of time talking about event response. Using
CloudWatch events, we also highlighted EventBridge.
Remember, everything we did in CloudWatch events,
you can also do in EventBridge,
but EventBridge extends event in service to include custom service busses
and greater integration with third‑party applications.
We also spent a big chunk this course talking about automation for event
response. We discussed automation for infrastructure events,
security events, and briefly, for application deployment.
The key here is to identify the events that you would like to capture and
use the appropriate tool to capture those events, and ideally, trigger your
automated response. In one full module and through sections throughout this
course, we discussed CloudTrail. We said that CloudTrail is enabled by
default, but we also discussed CloudTrail integration with products like
CloudWatch and Amazon S3.
When looking at CloudTrail logs, remember that you're looking at management
events, so all that API activity that's being generated against your account,
data events, which record Lambda function events, and events generated against
the S3 buckets, and insight events. Remember,
insight events will alert you to any anomalous activity in your account.
We also spent one module talking about tagging,
which is such an important aspect for our administration inside AWS, we
discussed cost allocation tags, we discussed how we can use tags to group
resources using resource groups in system manager, we talked about using
tags for our software deployment to identify the compute resources that our
code should be deployed to, and we talked about using tags for
attribute‑based access control.
All organizations should have a good tagging strategy. And remember, we
can enforce tagging today if your accounts are part of an organization
using tagging policies We also spent the module talking about metadata,
and we said that metadata can be used to provide instance details to your
EC2 deployed applications,
we said it can be used to provide raw information to EC2 deployed applications,
and it can be used to provide user data to EC2 instances to configure
those instances at launch, or if the system properties have adjusted,
to reconfigure the machines each reboot.
And finally,
here, if we only take away one piece of information
from this 2‑hour and 40‑minute course,
that should be automation is the key to success. In this module, you learned
about the power of event‑driven automation. We discussed automated healing,
and we had a look at a brief course review.
Thank you for spending the last 2 hours and 40 minutes with us.
I hope you've learned some new tools that you can use in AWS. My name is Mike Brown, and I hope to see you on other Pluralsight courses soon.