Now that we've demonstrated CloudTrail and CloudWatch integration,
let's finish off this module by discussing centralized CloudTrail logs.
Most companies today using AWS use multiple AWS accounts.
Resources such as EC2 and lambda functions are deployed to
individual AWS accounts, and each AWS account has its own IAM,
identity and access management controls.
If we have multiple AWS accounts it's best practice to start
audit logs from those accounts in a centralized,
secured location, somewhere where we can secure access to the
logs so that we can have a dedicated audit team that can read
and work with logging information,
but they are stored away from environments where they might be
accidentally or maliciously overwritten. In this diagram,
we have an AWS organization. An AWS organization is the top‑level
administrative unit in AWS. AWS organizations contain AWS accounts, and
it's into these accounts that we deploy resources. In this example, this
organization has four accounts, a master, a development and production
account, and here you can see a separate audit account where all of the
CloudTrail logs are centralized.
It's this account that we restrict access to, making sure that
only our audit team has access to this account.
When working with centralized CloudTrail logs it's good to
understand that AWS organizations are not a requirement.
You could be working with independent AWS accounts and
still want to centralize their logs.
Having said that, AWS organizations do make the whole process that much easier.
We will need to configure the appropriate roles in each
account so that accounts are able to log information to
the centralized audit account.
And it's probably beneficial if we enable AWS Single Sign‑On as well.
This way our auditors can log into the audit account,
but also using their same credentials they can log into other accounts in the
organization if they need to view additional information.
Finally, it's important that users in the member accounts of the organization,
such as development, production, and even the master account,
do not have rights to alter the trails. In this module we have taken
a look at CloudTrail and CloudWatch integration.
We have worked with CloudTrail and shown the process of setting
up a trail and the resulting logs in CloudWatch. And we discussed
centralized CloudTrail logs. In the next module we'll be working
with CloudWatch events.
So join me there and we'll continue on our monitoring and event response journey in AWS for DevOps engineers.