Hi friends, welcome to Docker tutorials for
beginners and decisions that ended up instructor for this course.
First, let me go with introduction to Docker anyway before entering into Docker concert.
First, let me tell you what is the story before Docker.
Now to understand about this concept,
I am taking a very simple example that is,
just assume that we need to run one Java application.
See whenever if you want to run any Java application,
we need some database or were some application server and web server.
So here in my case is simply I'm taking,
we need one MySQL database server,
one Tomcat application server,
and one IIS web server. That's fine.
And here, just assume that because of
some compatibility issues with your operating system,
we need only Windows Server to those untoward to run MySQL database server,
and 2016 to run Tomcat applications or what?
Anyway, it needs some Java.
And then Windows Server 2019 to run IIS web server.
Fine.
So now we need three servers.
One is Windows Server 20122016, and then 2019.
That's fine.
So here my question is how to get required servers.
So actually we need three different operating systems or servers, right?
So how to get them?
Actually we hope to ways before Docker concept they are
first one is get three computing the wedges with the required hardware.
I mean, let say suppose I need each computer with
16 GB RAM and then to TB hard disk just to get three devices under
then install with your required Windows server operating system so that we can create
our three servers directly get your required server from any cloud,
but is one way audible simply,
we can create 3D virtual emissions from VMware.
Now here, to get more clarity on Docker concept,
simply, I'm going with second week.
We are going to create virtual missions from VMware.
And assume that your VMware is running on Windows Server.
Fine.
Now let me go with how to create VM missions or required servers from VMware.
See whenever if you want to create any server from VMware.
First of all, you need to run your VMware on any one of the server.
So just assume that I am running my VMware or
simply hypervisor on one of my Windows Server.
And for this Windows Server,
just assume that we have 128 GB RAM and hard disk.
Fine.
Now we have VMware.
Using this VMware, we can create any number of settlements,
but be clear that any number of solvers depends on this configuration information.
Suppose e Here we have 128 GB RAM and ten dB hardness.
Anyway, in our case,
suppose we need three servers.
Now, just assume that we are going to create
each server with 16 GB RAM onto TB hard disk.
So 16 into 348 GB,
a 102 into 36 PB.
Yes, we have more than that with your host operating system.
So that way we can create three servers.
Now just assume that we are going to create three servers.
Anyway from VMware.
Whenever if you want to create any server,
we need one ISO image.
That is nothing but your operating system image.
And be clear, suppose I'm going to take waste image are suppose Windows Server 2012.
So using that email,
I can create my requires hard work for my database.
And assume that second time I'm selecting my ways imaged as Windows Server 2016.
Yes. From that we can create one Windows Server.
Same way.
I'm going to take different waves image that is Windows Server 2019.
And by using that with image,
I'm going to create one more server.
Fine.
So after creating your three servers using your VMware,
now I'm deploying MySQL database server on your toes and tool server,
then Tomcat server on Java on your to-do and 16 server,
and then IAAS webserver on total.
Fine.
Now we'd done our required setup to run Java application.
This is fine.
But what is the drawback here?
Very simple.
C before telling that C actually as of no,
on my laptop, Suppose I have Windows ten.
Let me open start Minow on my Windows ten.
Now if i how by default,
different types of software with my Windows ten.
But I am not using all these default software
to run either database server or Tomcat server IIS web server.
I don't need them to run any one of these application.
So if you're not using them,
why we need to install it with our operating system.
See if more number of softwares with your ISO image,
then it will take more time to launch your server.
But if you how less softwares with your ISO image,
then it will take less time to launch your server.
So if you launch your server with the less time,
then we are saving some time for our production.
Right?
So because of that here,
what we will do is we will minimize our ISO images as much as possible.
Fine.
And one more thing, if you observe here we are using all servers,
Windows servers, including your host operating system.
Say actually, if you go with any operating system,
we how to parts.
They are carnal and softwares.
See here, colonel is simply a program using that we can interact with the hardware.
Now that can really sing,
go with Windows Server 2012 or 16 or 19 or whatever it may be.
Now, same colonel, across all your servers.
Then why we need to install same candle on all your sorrows and shove that.
I can use the canal which is there on your operating system so that,
that canon software part also I can reduce in my ISO image, right?
So if you reduce your iOS where you may size
then will take very less than to launch your server.
That is actually an advantage.
Fine.
Anyway, softwares are nothing but required libraries and packages 40 what server?
That's fine.
Now, our concept is.
If you are able to reduce image,
then it is an advantage.
So that is the concept of your Docker.
But how let me tell you that.
Oh, let me go with create servers using Docker.
See whenever if you want to create servers using VMware,
actually we are running somebody where VMware.
Same way whenever if you want to create service using Docker,
we need to run your Docker somewhere.
So let's say I'm running my Docker on Windows Server.
Fine.
Now, here, using Docker,
we can create our servers.
But here we have a small difference between Docker and
VMware with respect to operating system or host operating system.
That is, if you're host operating system is Windows server,
then using Docker, we can create only Windows servers.
So like Windows Server 2012 or 16 or 19.
Only Windows servers we can create using
docker if you're a host operating system, Windows.
Suppose these host operating system, let's say Linux.
Then using Docker, we can create Linux operating systems,
let's say open to our HDL sent ways.
So say Linux, something like that.
Fine.
But if you go with the VMware respect to of your host operating system.
Using VMware, we can create any type of operating system,
any type of server.
Fine C, to create your servers using VMware.
We are taking ISO image.
So here also to create your required servers using Docker,
we had to take ISO image.
But here that ISO image is minimized
ISO image nothing but it consists of only a required software's.
Nothing but libraries and packages to run your application, let's say.
And here that minimize the ISO image is called Docker image weekly or don't get confused.
See if you want to create a server using VMware,
we are taking an operating system IS where you made.
So here also using docker,
if you want to create a server,
we need one ISP amazed,
that is nothing but Docker image.
But we have a difference between your normal operating system IS well,
you mentioned and Docker image that is either operating system,
ISO is complete one,
but Docker image is not a complete ISO image.
It is not having kernel and also additional software.
It will only required libraries and packages to run your particular application.
That's fine.
Now, using this Docker image,
with the help of Docker, we can create any number of servers.
Of course that n number of servers
depends on the configuration of your host operating system.
Fine.
Now assume that we need to create three servers.
And one more thing you are running now your Docker on windows server.
That's why using Docker,
you can create only Windows servers.
Fine.
Now assume that I want to create Windows Server 2012.
So if you want to create your particular server with Watson,
you have to sell it to proper Docker image.
We have n number of images already available with the Docker.
So we will select the required image based on our required server.
Now assume that I selected are darker remains for Windows Server 2012.
So now by using that image with the help of Docker,
we launch in one server.
So now the server is not a complete one.
That's why it's simply I am calling it as mini Windows server. That is what, 2002.
Well, anyway we need two more.
Now assume that I selected Docker image for 2016.
So from that, with the help of dagger,
I created many windows server 2016,
same way, mini Windows Server 2019.
Fine.
Now we have our three servers.
No, let me deploy our required database server,
Tomcat server on Java,
on ASR, we're on our servers.
Fine.
So be clear.
Our servers, whatever the servers we created with the help of Docker,
by taking Docker image,
they are not complete one, they need camel.
Now these three servers will use carbonyl
from your host operating system with the help of Docker.
Fine.
Now instead of calling these three servers as Mini servers,
simply we are calling them as containers Nazi. And here one more thing.
Suppose I want to create Linux servers.
So in that case first the thing,
you how to take your host operating system as the Linux server.
It may be open to or ritual or CentOS, whatever it may be.
So using that Linux host operating system with the help of darker,
by selecting required Linux image,
it may be open to image for auditorially maize or CentOS image,
we can create your Linux servers.
Fine.
So this is just a very basic idea about your Docker.
Oh, this idea, let me go with what is a docker?
Simply, Docker is this software to create a mini server,
but don't tell that it is used to create a mini server.
Instead of that, Docker is a software to create a container.
So how we are creating a containers using Docker with the help of image, Docker image.
So finally, we can create n number of containers on a host operating system.
On all containers are virtually separated.
So while running your containers with the help of Docker,
all containers, we'll assume that they're running on separate operating system.
Fine.
And finally, simply, Docker is
a containerization tool because we are creating containers using Docker.
Fine.
Now, if you search in Google, what is a Docker?
You will get different definitions, right?
But as of now, I don't want to go with them.
So well, going forward, step-by-step,
I will add concepts to your Docker so that I
will make complete definition for what Docker,
so that it is very easy as a beginner.
Okay.
Okay guys, thank you for watching this video.