Fringe here or construct is building
custom Docker images using docker file. Let me go with that.
See, we already know that there are two ways to create custom Docker images.
They are from a container that is with
the help of Docker commit command and using docker file.
And we already gone through our first method,
that is custom Docker image with a container using the docker commit command.
But actually it has some limitations.
And one of that is it is not scalable and it
is very difficult to automate the tasks in our real time.
That's why it is not preferred in real time.
Then the preferred way to create custom Docker image is using docker file.
Now first let me tell you what is a Docker file.
So in simple terms,
Dockerfile is a script which contains some instructions or commands for our talker.
And we can create a custom Docker image by
executing Docker file with a Docker command called Docker.
So simply, first, we will write some Docker file with some instructions or commands.
Now, by using Docker,
we will run docker build command on this Docker file.
Simply, we are executing Docker file with the help of docker
build command so that it will create a Docker image.
See after that we know that, I mean,
how to create a container from Docker image simply by taking docker run command,
we can create Docker container from Docker image.
Fine.
Now here let me take our previous example itself that is
deploying Jenkins application on Tomcat application server using Docker CentOS container.
So actually, if you go with manual steps, we are having,
these are the steps to create your set up.
I mean, deploying Jenkins application
on Tomcat application server using NACA CentOS container.
But here what we will do is first we will create a Docker file. This requirement.
And that Docker file we will execute by using
docker build command so that it will create a Docker image.
Now we will use that Docker image to launch our container with the setup.
That's it.
No, let me go with that.
Creating custom Docker image using docker file
C. We had to write our own Docker file to create a custom Docker image.
So based on our requirement,
we have to write our own Docker file and we have
to know some important points to create a Docker file.
The very first one, we need one base image to create a custom Docker image.
So based on your requirement,
you have to select this image.
Now, we will select that base image from Docker official website called Docker Hub.
And this base image information is the first instruction while creating our docker file.
And we have to represent that with an instruction called from.
Not only from based on requirement,
we have different types of instructions or commands for our docker file.
Some of them are like maintainer, run,
ENV him in a neuron when exposed,
command entry point and so on.
And here, all these instructions or not case sensitive.
Mean while implementing your Docker file,
whenever if you are using these instructions,
you can write these instructions in terms of lowercase letters or uppercase letters,
but the suggested way is using uppercase letters only.
And here, first I will show you already developer Docker file for our requirement that
is deploying Jenkins obligation on Comcast application server using CentOS container.
Now if you remember, while going with the manual steps to create our setup,
we followed these steps first week later one CentOS container.
Then we installed some packages and we did
some modifications so that we got finally our requirement, I mean, our setup.
Now here, what we are doing this for our requirement.
First we are writing Dockerfile.
From that we're going to create Docker image from that we are launching our container.
Now, let me show you already developed a Docker file for our requirement.
Now see here this is the Docker file for our requirement.
Now if you observe this Docker file,
the very first instruction is from.
Now with the help of from instruction,
we will mention our required base image.
So with the help of base image only we are going to create custom images.
And generally in real-time,
they how they wound base image.
So using that base image,
they will create the custom images based on application.
That's fine.
Now here, often we were first instruction,
remaining, all instructions or simply like you are manual steps commands.
If you remember, these are the minute steps commands.
So all these steps in play mentioned here.
But along with that outtake and
some where R1 and somewhere commands somewhere entry point.
So we'll discuss about these instructions later.
Fine.
Now, this is the simple Dockerfile.
Now let me create a custom Docker images simply by running docker build command.
Docker build dot.
Now here.me in the current location without Docker file.
In case if your Docker file in the different location,
then you have to mention the poppy here about your Docker file.
Let's go to that location then you have to run
your docker build command. And one more thing.
Generally, we will take Docker file as in this way I'm only,
I'm in capital D Docker file.
You can also take any different file name.
But if you take any different file m,
then you ought to mention that file in here instead of dot.
Even though if you are in the current location where you,
how your Docker file, that's fine. Now let me run it.
And one more thing before building your Docker image,
you have to know one more thing.
That is, whenever if you build
your custom Docker image using docker build command with the help of Docker file.
So what it is going to do,
E's the base image,
each and every instruction is going to add a layer.
That's why wave bailing your custom Docker image.
It will take a more time at very fast.
But later, if you modify your Docker file and if you read on your docker build command,
it will take very less time.
I will show you that first let me run at very first-time our docker build command,
docker build dot indices,
simply docker build command.
You are also having tags options.
Those we'll see later.
Now see the Docker build dot.
Now each and every instruction is going to add
as a layer on top of your base image. You have to remember that.
Now whenever if you are going to create the very first time you
were custom image with the help of your Docker file,
it will take more time.
Suppose later based on your requirement,
suppose if you modify your Docker file and if we read on your docker build command,
it will take very less time.
We will see that.
Just wait for some time to complete this command to create your Docker custom image.
See that it is taking some time.
Ok, it is almost done.
Again, nearly, we need five more seconds.
Find done.
See once it is completed,
it is also going to do the image ID here. See that?
Or else you can simply run docker images and you can see that.
See that let us image 148 anyway,
it is not creating any tags or repository name.
So that options you have to provide while creating,
while building your custom Docker image with help of docker build command.
That's fine.
Anyway, to create your custom Docker image,
it has taken some time.
What I am doing is just simply,
I'm modifying some instruction.
Let's say I'm removing last instruction.
So removing is nothing but simply,
you can comment simply with the help of ash.
No, let me save it.
Now here, this instruction we removed,
that is a meaning of hash here.
Now if you rerun your docker build command,
it is simply going to delete this layer on your existing image.
That is why it is going to take very less time.
Now let me renin, so docker,
build dot c that it has done.
Now, let me once again a modify simply by adding that line.
Now already we have some image with these instructions.
So on that image simply it is going to add the last layer.
That's why it is going to take very less time.
See that?
So that point is very, very important.
Then. Anyway, find, we created
our required or Docker image from cent waste base image. Fine.
Now see that Docker images, sorry.
Now this is the image we have for our requirement.
No, let me create a container using that image.
Simply we know that command to create a container is docker run hyphen,
hyphen D. Then let's say I'm providing name as Tomcat with Jenkins on St. ways.
Latest. Then, you know,
tom cat is running on the port number h 0,
h 0 that I want to map with a docker host.
Let's say I'm taking on Docker host
also edge-to-edge report because as of now I stop all my running containers.
That's why a journal entry report on my Docker host is available.
Then finally, how to mention your Docker image ID.
Of course, you can also mention ribose to rename,
but here I don't have a positive name.
That's why I simply am taking Docker image ID.
Now let me run it.
That's been created or container has been created.
See that docker ps is running five seconds ago.
So if you want to verify you are a setup,
just enter into your container with the bash shell.
And it will clear is not there,
simply use Control L.
Now.
See that under user local,
we how our Tomcat, Yes.
And then inside that we how web apps inside that see that there is Jenkins dot val,
or simply go to your browser and selective or IP of your Docker host.
Undertake port as edge-to-edge hero than slash jenkins?
No, it will open your Jenkins application.
It is opening, right?
So if you have a custom Docker images,
it is very easy to create container at anytime with less time, right?
So finally, that is the advantage with the Docker, Docker container radiation.
Okay. Okay. Thank you for watching this video.
Later, we will see each and every step of
your Docker file to create your Docker file for your custom Docker images.
Required.