Friends here we are creating our
first two Dockerfile c. We already know that Dockerfile is
used to create custom Docker images simply by
executing docker build command on your Docker file.
Now here to write our foster Docker file for our custom Docker image.
Let me take a small requirement.
So here my requirement is I need to launch a container using open to 20 dots 0-4 version.
An offer that my container should have Python 33 and a flat packages.
So simply Finally, I will use this container to run some Python Flask application.
Anyway, this is my requirement then how to write a Docker file.
So anyway, after writing Docker file,
simply build your custom Docker images by running docker build command.
After that, from that custom Docker image, simply,
you can launch your container by running docker run command.
That's fine.
And here, before writing Docker file,
just for our understanding purpose,
first I we launch manually container with 01 to 2004 base image.
And then manually I will install Python three p53 and Flask packages.
After that, those stiff simply I will convert
into Docker file so that it is very easy to understand.
I mean how to write your Docker file.
Now let me go to my Docker host.
So here simply, I'm searching for existing images.
If you observe this output,
we are not having 01 to 2004 image.
So let me search for that.
So simply by using docker search, open to,
with a DAG S t dot 0 for C,
you are getting some images,
but I am not seeing exactly open to name here.
They are with the combination of some other packages.
So instead of that, what we can do is we can also go to
our official Docker registry that is called hub dot dot dot.com.
So here simply go to explore.
And simply as such here using open to key.
Now you are going to get our very first as some open to image and just open
that anybody sees official image from your Docker.
And if we go down,
we're having different types of tags.
And here, view available tax option is there just click on that.
Then scroll down. See that there are different images.
Tags.
I mean, for this open to image,
there are different tags.
Now go down somewhere,
you will get your required tag.
So here we have a tag, 2004.
And for this, there is already a command that is
docker pull command how to pull that he made NPO docker host.
So simply copy that and come back to our docker host,
paste that command and then run it.
Now see docker images.
We have 01 to 2004.
Now we have our required base image.
Now let me launch a container from this first.
So simply by using docker run iphone, IT hyphen D.
I am not giving any name,
simply I'm launching the container.
It has been created.
Now see docker ps.
Yes, your container is up and running.
So let me enter into
That container simply by using Docker EX EC hyphen IT using Bash shell.
Now we're inside of our container.
Now let me verify,
Is there any default Python with these host, I mean,
within this container C that simply we can verify it
which Python there is no Python or which Python three.
There is no Python three.
If Python three or Python is not there,
then anyway, there is no chance to how Pip and packages.
That's fine.
Now let me install Python three on this host.
So how to install your any package on your own to
operating system simply by taking APT get installed.
Python, I need Python three.
It is not installing.
So actually before installing any PAG is you need to update
your APT repo equity get update.
Now once if you update after that,
you can install any package.
So now I am updating that.
So it has been updated.
Now let me try to install Python three.
So equity get installed Python three.
Now see that it installing and it is actually asking conformation as Torno.
So here instead of giving yes, sir,
no confirmation is here in the command line itself
while running APT get install Python three,
we can provide hyphen Way option yes, conformation.
That's it.
So now it is installing Python three.
It's done.
You can verify it.
Which Python three?
Yes, Python three is there or you can also verify the West Chen.
So you are getting Python 3.1a dot-dot-dot.
Suppose if you want to get you are required to Python.
Three dot 6370 here to mention that Python.
Anyway, let us Python you are getting here. That's fine.
Now let me install PIP three.
Now if you want to install pip three,
actually you need to mention with respect to Python.
So now we have Python three, hyphen Pip.
Let me provide hyphen byte.
Now it is installing one pip package.
So once it is done, again, we'll verify it.
Just wait for sometime.
It is almost done.
Yeah.
I'll see that.
Which PIP3?
Yes, PIP3 is there.
Then actually what we need,
we need Flask package as well.
Now see that let me enter into Python terminal.
So here simply I'm importing flask.
Sorry.
There is no package called Flask Python package with your Python.
So if you want to install that,
you need to install pip, install Flask.
I'll see that it is installing your package package done.
So what we did manually to get your requirement,
the very first step is we have taken
base image that has open to quantity dot 04.
Then after that, we updated APT, APD get update.
Then after that we installed Python.
Three, then offer that we installed.
Python three hyphen.
Then after that we run this command pip
install Flask c. These
are the commands which we installed inside of your base container.
Now for this requirement,
if you want to create a custom Docker image,
you how to write Dockerfile.
So how to read Dockerfile,
very simple for all of these steps,
just to make an instruction in your Docker file,
C. In our docker file.
The very first step is always about your base image.
Now to get our requirement,
we are using this base image.
Now, that base image information you have to mention as
a very first step in your Docker file.
And that is with respect to from,
that's from the base image.
We are going to create custom Docker image, right?
And actually inside of this container,
we executed all these commands.
That means just to install these three packages in our container,
we install these three commands.
It simply take all these commands,
whatever the commands we executed manually inside of your container and paste them.
And for each and every command,
you just to start with R1 instruction.
Capital One.
Of course, you can also add small as well, but preferred,
we use capital letters or uppercase letters.
Now here what is mean by R1 means while creating your custom Docker image, in your image,
you are run will execute all these commands so
that in your image you will get APT, get updated version.
And in that image you will get Python three,
Python 3p and then flask that say,
now this is simply our docker file for our requirement.
Now let me go to my Docker host.
Let me come out from the container.
So you whenever if you want to create a Docker file,
always it is better practice to create some folder on
directly based on the work required project taught application.
Suppose here we are going to use this container later,
let's say for flask applications,
then let me create Flask app,
then navigate into it.
The NEA, just simply create a Docker file so you can take any name for your Docker file.
But preferred way is using capital D Docker file.
Then open that file and then simply paste your instructions.
Let's see.
We can also write empty lens,
no problem, but let me remove that empty line.
Save it.
Then after creating your Docker file, from this Docker file,
actually we had to create our custom dog remains so far that we have a command
called The occur dot.
And for your image,
if you want to provide some tag's name,
then you can use hyphen T.
And let say suppose I want flask gap
anywhere that I'm creating with the help of base image called Woburn,
do then assume that this is
very fast to Washington than simply I'm taking colon V1, that's it.
Now it is going to create your custom image.
The very first time we are running.
Yeah.
Cd stopping because we did some mistake.
So what is that you see on each and
every command at the end you need to provide confirmation.
Yes.
But for pip command you don't need to know.
Let me modify our docker file.
So it because of density is exiting with some ETL code.
Let me open our docker file.
The Czech.
So don't forget to provide hyphen way at the end of your APT get install command.
Okay, that's fine.
Now let me rerun.
So at very first time we are running this Dockerfile execution.
I mean, we are building customers from this Docker file.
That's why it will take some time.
But later if have any modifications on
this Docker file and if you read on your docker build command,
within less time, it will build your new custom image from this Docker file.
Anyway, just to wait for some time,
maybe less than two minutes.
It is almost didn't see that after completion of your docker build command,
it is giving you a tagged,
right, or I'll simply The occur images.
See that just now we created this image.
Now from this image,
if you launch your container,
human container will how your Python three, b,
three as well as flask module. Now let me do that.
I mean, let me launch a container using this image.
So docker ps.
So you just know we created this container,
this is previously executed container.
Now, just now we cleared this container,
let me enter into it.
Now.EXE Z hyphen IT.
Container ID badge.
I'll see that simply as such with the which Python three.
But there is a Python. So which p53,
p63 is there and go to your Python terminal and then simply import Flask.
Yes, flux model is also there.
Okay, so there is the simple way just to create
a one simple Dockerfile for your requirement.
So what is our docker file?
This one.
Okay. Okay. Okay, guys,
thank you for watching this video.