Prince here or concept is Docker architecture,
says simply this is Docker architecture.
But let me go with our known concept that is creating containers using Docker.
See whenever if you want to create a container using Docker,
first of all, you had to install your Docker on any one of the operating system.
So after installing your Docker on anyone of the operating system,
based on the type of container.
We will select a Docker image.
Then from the Docker image,
with the help of Docker,
we'll create our containers.
We RDD hybrid discussion on these, fine.
Now if you observe clearly in this diagram itself,
we have our Docker architecture.
Now let me extract that step-by-step.
Now, here, if you observe the very first
took part in this entire diagram is you were infrastructure.
Now assume that this is our infrastructure with some RAM hard days and some
CPU's fine on top of your infrastructure simply we are installing,
suppose here Windows server, not only Windows server,
we can also go with open to a Linux or our HCl or CentOS, whatever it may be.
Now assume that on top of this infrastructure,
suppose I installed some x-ray did operating system.
Now this is called simply your host audio server.
Now onwards host or on your server,
we are installing Docker.
Now assume that I installed Docker.
Anyway, that is called simply Docker Daemon or Docker Engine.
Fine.
Now, once if your Docker, using Docker,
we can create containers by selecting required Docker image.
Fine.
Now one more thing. See, this Dockery is simply a service or engine.
So with the help of this Docker Engine or service,
we are going to create containers.
That means we need to pass some instructions to this Docker daemon.
So how we can pass,
we need some interface between us and docker engine.
Now for that, we are using a simple software called Docker CLE.
That's it.
Now using this Docker CE and Lee will pass instructions to
your Docker Daemon or Docker engine so that that
will create our start or stop or destroy your containers.
That's it. Fine.
And here, this Docker CLI,
you can install on the host to where you are running
your Docker Engine or else you can take one separate host there.
We can install your Docker CLI from the remote server.
Also, you can interact with this Docker Engine.
Or we can also communicate with your Docker Engine from remote location using rest APIs.
So how to do that?
We will see now, That's fine.
Now here, if you observe we are creating containers
by taking Docker images with the help of Docker engine.
Now assume that I need to create three types of containers,
let say Windows Server 2012 container to those,
and 16 container and 2019 container.
That means here you need three types of Docker images.
So from where you will get those images,
you no need to worry for that already.
Docker is maintaining some images in Docker history.
So how to get them we will see in our course.
So be clear, Docker images are already available with the Docker registry.
So whenever if you want to create your required container simply we will
get our Docker image from Docker history and we'll create our container.
Fine.
Suppose I want to customize that Dockery, MS.
Yes, we can customize and weekend store images in your Docker history.
Alleles.
We can maintain our customer base three.
Then we can store our docker images.
Fine.
Now, this is simply Docker architecture.
Okay? Okay guys, thank you for watching this video.