Print sheared or concept is how to install Docker on Ubuntu server.
So here we are installing Docker on
Ubuntu server using Bash shell script anyway before that,
if you remember, this is our Docker architecture.
So if you observe here, we are installing Docker on top of some host.
That host may be with Windows operating system or with any Linux operating system.
So again, in Linux operating system,
We can go with either open to or CentOS or Rachel,
or Amazon Linux or IBM Linux.
It could be any operating system. Fine.
Now first let me get my open to server C here.
I'm taking open to server from AWS cloud.
Now, I already created the server.
Let me login into it. So simply,
I'm logging into our urban to server.
Now.
Just let me verify what is
the operating system to that open to anybody. This is the latest one.
That's fine.
Now, we how our required operating system.
Next thing is when it installed Docker,
not to install your Docker.
We hope to go and get Docker software.
Anyway before going to that,
actually docker comes in two editions.
One is Docker Community Edition,
and the second one is Docker Enterprise Edition.
There are some differences between these two additions.
Anyway, simply, Docker Community Edition is like open source.
You can download and install with your required operating system.
And this Docker Community Edition purposes just to get
practice with your Docker container ation concept. That's it.
And here, Docker Enterprise Edition, definitely,
it has some advanced concepts compared to your Docker Community Edition,
because this is Enterprise Edition.
Again, Docker Enterprise edition is available in
terms of basic standard and at once, additions.
Simply are given some differences between
your community edition with your Docker Enterprise Edition.
So initially we will practice with Docker Community Edition.
Anyway, Docker Enterprise Edition is also available as trial version.
So later we will use that and we'll use
some advanced concepts from our Docker Enterprise edition as well.
Fine.
Now let me go and install Docker Community Edition on our open to server.
Now here we are installing through Bash shell script.
Now you can get your required bash escape in this location.
Now let me open my repository, GitHub repository.
So just open Docker tutorials for beginners.
Clone this repository to your local host.
I mean, where you want to install your Docker.
So this is the server.
So what I am doing is simply, I'm cloning it.
So anybody is open but opposed to read vertically, you can clone it.
Git clone that URL.
Fine.
Now here we have the repo.
So enter into it.
Now here we have our first introduction concept.
So go to that.
And here we have a shell script.
Now see here we have shell script.
So nothing is there. Whatever the steps are manually we are performing to install Docker.
All those steps I added in this script.
So if you open and if you go with one by one,
you will come to know what are the steps, very simple steps.
Anyway.
First, let me try to forward the execution permission for it. Now I am running it.
Say that please run this script from root only C to install your packages,
you should have root privileges or you should run your commands from root user.
So anyway here I designed descrip such that it has to execute only from root user.
Now let me switch into root.
You can copy your required script into
your root location or directly can provide complete path.
So let say home.
Under this user, we how Docker tutorials
in that introduction part, we have a shell script.
Now let me run it.
See that oases I interpret as open to then DES installing.
So whatever the steps we are performing manually,
all those tips I added in this city.
So it is going to install your required Docker Community Edition anyway,
it will do, it will install latest Docker on your host.
So just wait.
So before executing the script,
just to open it and see step by step,
what is the logic is there inside that?
Fine.
Now it is almost hidden.
And one more thing, this script will work only on open to server.
Yeah, fine. Now Docker has been installed
successfully on this host and it is up and running.
You can verify it using system CTL status Docker. Docker is up and running.
Now, after that you just verify some commands.
Let's say docker space hyphen, hyphen version.
We'll use docker Watson, anybody who has the latest version
as of now, then Docker version,
see that how you are going to get,
you're getting some information about your plane,
turn your Docker Engine in within his community version.
Fine.
And one more thing, you can also run docker info.
So just us off no, just update this log.
You don't need to worry about this anti log information
going forward based on our known concept,
I will explain about this step-by-step.
Fine. Okay guys, this is the simple way just to install
your Docker on open to server using Bash shell script.
Okay?
Okay guys, thank you for watching this video.