Friends here, our concepts or creating our
foster Docker container and basic commands of Docker.
Saying before entering into our concepts,
First, let me log in into our docker host.
See Docker host is nothing but when we installed our docker,
if you remember, we install Docker on our open to server in our previous video?
Yes, Docker, is there? No. Let me verify once our ways open to server.
Fine.
Now let me switch into root.
Initially, I will work with the docker from root user.
Later we will see how to work with Bucher from different users find.
And one more thing, let me verify the status of Docker
simply by using systems CDL status Docker.
Docker is up and running.
Now let me verify the darker version.
Simply docker space iPhone, iPhone version.
It will do only your Docker version.
If you want to see client as well as
your Docker server information simply you can then Docker version.
And you are also having one more command called Docker
info to get more information about your Docker.
Fine.
Now we are ready with our Docker.
No, let me enter into our concept that is creating our foster Docker container.
C.
If you want to create a container using Docker, unique Docker image.
Suppose if you want to create a container with CentOS operating system,
then you need doc remains for s2 is
suppose if you want to create a container with open to operating system,
then you need Docker image with open to operating system.
Fine.
But from where we will get this Docker images.
See Docker images can be good from Docker registry or simply from Docker Hub.
Anyway, before going into that,
let me show you some basic commands, S0.
These are the, some of the basic commands.
We will explain them one by 1.
First thing, Docker images.
That is simply a command just to know that what are
the images are available with your Docker host.
Docker host is nothing but where we install our Docker C,
this is our docker host.
Let me verify with Docker images.
So as of now with my Docker host,
I don't have any Docker image.
Right?
Then how we can get it c before getting it.
First, let me open our Docker registry or hub dot docker.com.
That is the official website of Docker to find the available images with Docker?
No, let me open that. So once it is open,
simply click on here, explore.
There is explored option.
Click on that.
Now here we have some such bar.
Let me such with the CentOS simply type sin2 is and then Enter.
You will get lot of images with respect to send to AC maze.
But don't worry, we'll discuss them step-by-step as of now.
After that, yes, there is a central image with your Docker Hub.
Suppose I need open to humans,
simply type urban to under then enter.
Yes, there are number of open two images, fine.
See internal searching your required image from Docker Hub,
such option that Italy from our command line itself.
By using this command,
we can such required image from Docker Hub.
By default, our Docker is configured with the docker hub.
So whatever you are searching from command line,
that such information is from hub dot docker.com.
Fine.
Now let me set simply Docker.
Such.
Let's say sent away is just enter this many number of images.
Centos images are available with your Docker Hub or else.
Let me search for Open to.
Now see that this menu open to images or available with your Docker Hub.
Fine.
So now we can able to such our required image in your Docker Hub.
But how to download that with our local host or without Docker host.
Very simple.
We have a command for that,
that is simply docker.
Pull your required imagining.
So suppose here.
First, let me run docker images.
So as of now, we don't have any images with our local host or without Docker host.
Now what I'm doing is simply Docker sent ways.
No, it will download sent ways image to our local host or to our docker host.
Now, it has been downloaded.
Now verify by running docker images.
Yes, now we have CentOS image with our local host or without Docker host.
Fine.
Now let me pull open too as well.
See that it is downloading.
You are open to amaze.
You had to wait for some time. It will download.
Yes, it has been done. Let me verify it.
Available images on your local host or with the word docker host?
Yes.
Now we have two images with our docker host.
Fine.
Now, once if you download your images in case if you
want to remove any one of the image or all images you can remove by taking Docker RMA,
remove image with respect to image ID.
See that if you run docker images,
it is giving some repos.
That is, you are open to or CentOS image name then tax as of no,
don't worry about tags.
We will see in detail ago tags.
There is image ID and it,
when it was created size.
Suppose I want to remove CentOS image with my Docker host.
Yes, we can remove it.
See simply docker.
Remove image, then image ID, enter.
It has been removed on your Docker host.
Docker images.
See that we have only open too,
because just now we removed our CentOS image on our docker host.
No, let me pull it docker, pull sent waves.
It is downloading. So once it is downloaded,
if you rerun your Docker images,
it will list Oliver available images with your Docker host.
Anyway, we have two images.
That's fine. Then what is the next command?
Docker ps.
C docker ps simply will list the running containers anyway as AF No,
we did not created even a single container.
But let me verify.
Docker ps, there are no running containers.
And we have one more option with the ps that is hyphen yea or hyphen, hyphen all.
It will list the running and stopped the containers.
Let me run it once again.
Docker ps, iPhone, yay.
Iphone, iPhone all.
So we don't have any running containers or
stopped containers as of no width our docker host, fine.
Now, let me go with how to create a container.
C. If you want to create a container,
we how to use docker run command.
But for docker run command,
we have number of options for time being.
Just remember this command going forward will discuss in detail about this command.
Now simply, if you want to create a container,
you how to use command as docker run hyphen,
hyphen D, then you are required imagining.
See that?
Docker hyphen,
hyphen D. Suppose I want to create CentOS images simply run s2 is the trip.
So your container has been created.
So how to list containers simply using docker ps c
that we just know we created one container with respect to CentOS image.
That's what it is giving. C whenever if you run docker run hyphen
IT hyphen D sent away is then
automatically it will create a container with the operating system as CentOS.
And one more thing. Whenever container is created by default,
your Docker, We'll do one ID for that.
That is nothing but Docker container ID.
Now, see, this is the container which we created just now.
And this container is created with respect to CentOS image.
And seven seconds ago,
let me verify it once again.
About a minute ago we created this container,
right? What is the status?
It is up.
And as of now we are not giving any ports.
Don't worry about this. And observe here names.
See by default you are docker will use some name for your container,
but you can also modify that. We will see that later.
Fine.
So as of now we have only one container with our Docker.
Now, let me create one more container by taking images as open to.
So simply Docker, run hyphen,
hyphen D. Simply, you are imagining open to see that container has been created.
Now let me list all the running containers simply by
taking docker ps c that we have two containers.
Now, this container is created by taking images
as open to or simply with open to operating system.
And this container is created by taking images are
sent waves or operating system has sent away as fine.
And see that whenever if you create a container,
Dockery is giving some container ID,
along with that by default is giving some names.
So be clear, going forward,
we can change that name.
That's fine.
Now, let me go with the remaining commands.
S0, we created a container.
Now, I want to access that container.
I want to enter into the container, yes,
you can enter by using this command,
simply Docker, execute e FCC,
hyphen IT container ID.
Then with respect to some shell,
suppose I want to use SSH shell or bash shell.
So based on that shell,
you can access that container.
C, that simply Docker EX EEC,
hyphen IT, take anyone of the container ID.
Then I want to login.
I want to access this container.
I want to enter into that container using,
let's say Bash shell.
So that now you are in this container.
Fine.
If you want to verify what type of operating system is there with that container,
simply run cat slash EDC ways released CentOS Linux, let's say, fine.
Now let me come out from the container C,
if you want to come out from the container unit to press Control,
and then immediately press P and Q so that you will come out from your container.
Fine.
Now let me enter into open to image.
So simply again, Docker 0x e,
c, hyphen IT, then Container ID.
Let's say I want to enter into this container using SHE shell.
You can also use Bash.
No problem. No.
Let me verify operating system for this container cat slash EDC ways release.
Yes, open two. Now, if you want to come out from this container,
simply control immediately P and then Q.
That's a fine.
Now see that docker ps we have two containers.
No, let me stop one of the container.
It may be any container.
Suppose I am taking this container.
So if you want to stop your container,
simply Docker, stop container ID.
That's it.
Now if I run docker ps c that D showing only one container which is running.
Just know we stopped open to container.
Now, if you want to list the running as well as Stop the containers,
then you have to run command called docker ps with option called hyphen yea,
our iPhone, iPhone all see that?
Now this is exited, which is not running.
Anyway, to list running as well as top to containers,
you have to take docker, ps,
hyphen yea, or iPhone, iPhone all command.
Fine.
Now let me start this container.
Yes, we can start it simply by taking the Docker start container ID.
Now that container has been started,
if you want to verify simply docker ps.
Yes. Now both the contains a running fine.
Now, suppose I want to delete any one of the container or all containers.
Let me remove this container.
If you want to remove the container, command is docker.
Remove your container ID.
But if I run that you will get an exception C that you can't remove a running container.
So if you want to remove a container using Docker RM command,
you how to stop it and then you have to remove it.
Audience forcefully also, you can remove that container simply by taking remove hyphen F,
c. Now let me display docker ps,
or docker ps, iPhone yay or iPhone, iPhone.
All we have only one container. It has been removed.
Which one?
Yeah, this one.
It has been removed.
Not stop, but it has been removed.
There is no container now.
Fine.
Now we have only one container called CentOS container find.
Now, instead of using hyphen EF option,
if you want to remove a container,
what we have to do is first we need to stop the container.
Now let me stop this container first.
Now.
See docker ps. There are no running containers but Docker PSI,
funny, a stopped container.
Is there not to remove,
stop the container directly.
You can take command called docker.
Remove your container ID, that's it.
Now there are no more containers running or stopped.
Fine.
Now I want to create a container.
Yes, you can create it.
Docker.
Run hyphen, hyphen D,
Let's say CentOS container has been created.
See that? It is running.
Let me run only docker ps.
Let's wait.
So if you want to enter into this container,
again, what is the command?
Docker EX EC, hyphen IT,
then it may be shell or bash shell. You can take initial.
Fine.
Now if you want to come out from the container,
simply press Control and then immediately P and Q on your keyboard.
Let's say.
Okay, so guys, these are the basic required commands to work with your Docker.
Okay, guys, thank you for watching this video.