Hello everyone.
My name is Catalin Tudose,
and welcome to my Implementing a Test Pyramid Strategy in Java course.
I am a Java and web technologies expert at Luxoft Romania,
and I have more than 20 years of experience in the IT field.
More than 15 of them have been dedicated to Java and the technologies around it.
In this course,
we are going to follow one of the most frequent situations in
the development of contemporary projects.
The focus will be on clearly explaining the concepts of a
particular testing level and to apply them in practice.
You'll be able to replace most of the previous manual
testing build strong and safe applications.
The main topics that we are going to approach will
be introducing software testing, unit testing,
our basic components work in isolation,
integration testing units combined as a group,
system testing, looking at the complete software,
and acceptance testing the compliance with the business requirements.
By the end of this course,
you'll know how to develop Java applications that are tested at all
levels from the units up to the acceptance testing.
So making the software ready for delivery to the end user.
You will be prepared for the real-life challenge to know how to develop
reliable applications starting from solid building blocks,
integrating them, working with external systems,
and arriving at the target of software development
satisfying the business needs.
Before beginning the course,
you should be familiar with object-oriented programming
concepts and with the JUnit tool, be proficient in writing Java Core code,
and have some basic understanding of the Apache Maven build tool.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn
implementing a test pyramid strategy in Java, at Pluralsight.