This section will focus on demonstrating the way to cover from the
requirements analysis to the features breaking them into stories
and writing the acceptance criteria.
During the requirements analysis phase,
the discussion takes place between the business analyst and
the product owner representing the customer.
It is important that both sides have a clear understanding about
what the project will need to deliver and about the business
goals that this delivery will satisfy.
So the two sides need to express and For our flights operating company,
one business goal that we can formulate is increased sales by
providing higher quality overall flight services.
It is a very general goal and can be expressed in
more detail with a few requirements,
provide an interactive application to choose flights,
provide an interactive application to change flights,
provide an interactive application to calculate the optimal
route between source and destination.
To define the requirements, the features generated by their analysis,
need to achieve the customer business goals,
or deliver business value.
The initial ideas need to be described in more detail.
One way to describe the previous requirements would be,
as a passenger,
I want to know the flights for a given destination within a given period of
time so that I can choose the flights that suit my needs or,
as a passenger,
I want to be able to change my initial flights to different ones so
that I can follow the changes of my schedule.
A feature may be detailed and have to work as it is,
but often you will need to break it up into smaller pieces.
When a feature is broken up in stories,
each story addresses a different facet of the problem.
For example,
the I can choose the flights that suite my needs feature
might be too large to be implemented at once,
so it must be divided.
Additionally,
you might like to get some feedback of the
functionality before you build a whole feature.
The previous feature may be broken into smaller stories such as the following,
find the direct flights that suit my needs,
if any, find the alternatives of flights with stopovers that suit my needs,
find the one-way flights that suit my needs,
find the there and back flights that suit my needs.
Generally, particular examples are used as acceptance criteria.
The acceptance criteria represent what will satisfy
stakeholders in order to agree that the application is
working the way it is supposed to do.
The definition of acceptance criteria is made using the given,
when, then keywords.
More exactly, even a context when something happens,
then some result is expected.
As concrete example, given the flights operated by the company,
when I want to travel from Bucharest to London next Wednesday,
then I should be provided two possible flights,
10:35 and 16:20.
The examples that serve as acceptance criteria may be refined and grow in complexity, but the general idea remains the same.