We'll move to our next demonstration.
At the time, the provider has offered some partial implementation.
So we'll replace the previously mocked behavior with the real one and
we'll continue to mock the not yet implemented behavior.
Let's see now what we have from the side of the provider.
We have received this DistancesManager class that
provides not only the agreed interface, but also,
some partial implementation.
We see that we have three implemented methods,
getPassengersDistancesMap, getPassengersPointsMap,
and calculateGivenPoints.
And there is still one unimplemented method, addDistance.
Internally, we are maintaining these private fields,
Distance_Factor, initialize with 10,
passengersDistancesMap and passengersPointsMap both
initialized as empty HashMaps.
We see that that calculus of bonus points based on the
covered distances is already done.
You may ask,
is this a realistic situation when you get a partially implemented class.
I may say that you would rather get a partially implemented API.
You'll receive some fully implemented packages or classes while
some other part is still under construction,
but it follows the agreed contract.
For an easy understanding,
I have reduced our situation here to a simple class with four methods
from which only one does not have an implementation.
What is really important is that the API contract is
respected and that we do have an addDistance of Passenger
passenger and int distance method,
even a dummy one that works with the classes from the consumer side,
passenger in our case.
How will this change our tests on the consumer side?
As we know how to get the bonus based on the distance,
we'll no longer keep this passengerPointsMap,
but a passengersDistancesMap.
Here, we are keeping the distances that have been traveled by the passengers.
The bonus points will be calculated based on these distances.
Here into the testFlightsDistances method,
we'll no longer mock the behavior of the getPassengersPointsMap,
but mock the behavior of getPassengersDistancesMap method.
And then we call distancesManager.calculateGivenPoints.
We have seen that calculateGivenPoints is already implemented,
so we'll provide only its input, passengersDistancesMap,
based on which we are expecting to have a correct
calculus of PassengerPointsMap.
We run the test and the modified testFlightDistances is
failing with a null pointer exception.
Why?
What may be wrong?
The fact is that we are mocking the whole DistancesManager object.
We have instructed Mockito only about the behavior of
the getPassengersDistancesMap method.
How to tell that we would like to keep the functionality of the other methods?
This is simple.
Replace the mock annotation with this Spy one.
So when needed, you can create spies of real objects.
When we use the spy,
then the real methods are called unless a method was stopped.
This is all to have done for the getPassengersDistancesMap method.
Let's run the test again and now the test succeeds.
Just understand that we have arrived.
Let's run the whole suite with code coverage.
The code coverage is 100% at the level of the classes,
but only 94% at the level of the methods.
If we have a look here,
we see that this is mainly due to the DistancesManager class.
As we have mocked the implementation of some method,
only three of the four ones are really tested. We'll fix this when the full implementation of the provider will be available.