We'll go now for another practical demonstration.
We'll add test on the Flight class using JUnit5 and looking for
the verification of its correct behavior.
We'll include here the creation of a flight,
the restrictions on a flight number format,
the business logic of a flight.
Let's start a unit that's the Flight class.
We are creating this FlightTest.
We'll write our first simple test.
We create a flight object and verify that it is not null.
We run the test and see that it is green.
We have created the flight and checked its existence.
We would like to check the constraints of a flight number.
This flight number is a code for an airline service consists of
two-character align designator and of three to four-digit number.
So we may describe this condition by a regular expression.
We'll write a test that checks that the creation of a flight
with an invalid number will throw an exception.
We have chosen two flight numbers,
one with two digits after the airline designator,
the other one with five digits after the airline designator.
If we run now the test, it will be red.
This means that the flight number verification was not there.
This has only been exposed when starting with the unit tests.
Let's fix this.
This is the regular expression that the flight number must match and this
is the verification at the beginning of the constructor.
Let's re-run the tests.
The tests are green.
Let's write the test to check a valid flight number.
We have chosen two flights, one with three digits after the airline designator,
another one with four digits.
Let's run the tests.
The tests are green.
We have checked both the valid and invalid flight numbers.
We would like to check that we cannot sell more
tickets than the number of places.
So for this, we'll write a test.
We have a flight with 50 places from London to Bucharest.
First, we sell exactly the number of available places.
We check that the flight is now full.
Then we try to sell one more ticket expecting an exception.
We run the test and it fails.
The logic that verifies that one cannot sell above the capacity
of the flight hasn't been yet implemented.
Let's add this logic.
Into the sellTicket method,
we check that the number of passengers is not above the number of places,
otherwise, we throw an exception.
Let's re-run the test and it is green now.
We see that we have provided a setter for the number of places.
So as long as it is possible to change this field,
we should check it to follow the same restriction that we have presented above.
We write a test that checks that setting an invalid
number of places will throw an exception.
We have this flight from London to Bucharest.
We presume that we have already sold the 50 tickets,
and after this,
we would like to reduce the total number of places into the flight.
We should prevent this and throw an exception.
We run the test and it fails as the logic is not yet implemented.
So we go to a setPlaces method and implement this restriction that
will throw an exception in case that the number of places is
reduced under the number of passengers.
We run the test again and it succeeds.
In order to fully check the setPlaces method, let's add another test.
We have a flight from London to Bucharest,
we sell all places, and then we try to increase the number of places.
We run the test and it succeeds.
We would like to measure the code coverage again.
And we run mvn test from the command prompt.
Into the index.html file,
we'll be able to take a look at the code coverage at the level of the package,
at the level of the classes,
and at the level of individual constructors and methods.
We see that we have covered some of the Flight class with tests.
We'll take care of the remaining part by verifying
some new business logic as well.
The business logic says that once flying,
a flight cannot change its origin any longer.
Let's write a test to verify this.
We have a flight from London to Bucharest,
it is taking off so it should be flying,
and then it tries to change its origin.
This should be prevented and an exception must be thrown.
Let's run the test, the test is failing.
Let's fix this.
If the flight is already flying and we try to change its origin,
an exception must be thrown.
We run the test again and it is succeeding.
In order to verify that the flight is no longer flying after having landed,
we'll also write a test to check this.
We have a flight from London to Bucharest,
first it is taking off, then it is landing,
the flying state should be false.
Let's run the tests.
The tests are green so the condition is fulfilled.
We would like to measure the code coverage again and
run mvn test from the command prompt.
Into the index.html file, we'll be able to take a look at the code coverage,
add the level of the package, add the level of the classes,
and add the level of individual constructors and methods.
We have seen that we have fully covered the Flight class with tests.
We'll get rid of the initial main class.
It is no longer needed. And our next steps will focus on the new business logic that will be required.