[Autogenerated] in this clip,
we're gonna consider the essentials of working with File Explorer.
Now, File Explorer is a very important application that's built into Windows.
It helps you to work with your files and folders they're located on your
device or any networks that you may be connected to.
Now there's several ways open file explore.
The easiest is that if it's pinned to your taskbar,
you could open it from there.
If you select the start button,
you'll also see File Explorer listed there by default.
When you first opened File Explorer,
there's some basic features that are important to understand.
We're gonna take a moment to consider those first of all off here to the left,
you have an area that's called the navigation Pane.
Now the navigation pane is basically an important tool that
helps you to get around quickly on your device or other
places you may have access to.
In addition,
you'll see that there may be more than one way of presenting some of
the same files and folders on your device now,
anything that's selected over here to the left,
the contents are displayed here to the right,
so I select this PC I can see some key folders and different drives
that are connected to my device are enlisted.
If I select a folder, I can see files and folders that air within that folder.
No, you'll notice these arrows over here in the navigation pane,
and these allow you to expand or collapse folders to view their contents.
Now the contents could be displayed in different ways.
For example, this is a detailed view,
and this gives me columns that I can actually use to sort my information.
You can use things like list view, or you could use thumbnails,
which is helpful when you're looking for maybe images or videos.
I'll show you how to change views really quick.
Here in just a second above the Syria, we have the address bar.
Now the address bar shows me where I'm at in my navigation and again in
the address by you'll see these same little arrows,
and I can use those to expand or collapse the contents of those folders.
And again,
I can jump to those folders right from there to the left of my address bar.
I have a few other arrows that are good to know.
I have a forward and backward arrow,
and these let me step forward or backward in my steps of navigation.
The up arrow will let me to go up one level in the Iraqi.
So if I'm in a sub folder,
I could hit the operator and jump up to the main folder.
This little arrow here shows me the history of places I visited while this bile
explore has been opened here to the right of the address.
But I see a search field I could type in a file or folder name or a
keyword that may be associated with one of my files,
and the search will be running the folder I've
currently selected in my navigation pane.
Above this, we have the ribbon.
We're gonna look at the ribbon and more detail in another clip.
But I just want to show you the View tab and from the View tab,
we can control our layout that we see down here below.
So besides the navigation pane and my main pain that
shows the contents of a folder,
I can also enable the preview pain or the details pain and I can change
the layout of the contents by using different size icons on list or a
detailed view now here above the ribbon,
we have another important tool that sometimes has overlooked easily,
and that's the quick access toolbar.
Now the choice is listed here are related to common tasks within File Explorer.
I can enable additional ones here and you'll see the checkmark
appears that lets me know that they've been enabled,
and I'll see there's a button that appears on my title bar.
So these again are for common tasks that I use.
Maybe quite often.
For example, there's several ways you could create a new folder,
but the button here lets me create a new folder with one simple click.
Finally, down at the bottom.
We have our status bar.
Now the status bar will give me information about the folder
immune or any files that may have selected here.
To the right,
I have to shortcuts again that affect how things are
displayed in the contents pain.
In this clip, we briefly looked at using File Explorer. Thanks for watching, and I look forward to seeing you in the next clip