[Autogenerated] in this clip, we're gonna look at understanding Windows APS.
This clip is designed to kind of get you familiar with.
Some of the terms will be used throughout this series.
Window zaps are modern APS that are installed through the window store.
Desktop applications really meet more of the traditional criteria.
They have been downloaded from the Internet.
They're installed.
Or maybe you have a installation disk to install this on your device.
It may make a difference if it's a 64 32 bit application.
They download both Windows.
APS and desktop applications are really applications,
so sometimes you hear the term applications used in
reference to both of these categories.
Generally, when I use the term desktop application or windows app,
there's a reason I'm being very specific.
Window zaps are designed to work very efficiently with Windows 10.
In fact,
the installation and updates are managed right from the windows store window
zaps install very quickly and then install Justus quickly.
Another thing you may have noticed with windows,
APP says they're designed to keep the content as the focus,
so generally menus are kept to a minimum.
The windows will be borderless,
and you'll see a lot of consistency in the way menus
appear and behave in a Windows app.
So what else makes windows App is different.
Well,
Windows APS are designed to meet certain design criteria that
Microsoft has set out for developers that wanna write
applications that work with Windows 10.
Now these design characteristics don't just include
the overall appearance of the app, although that certainly is a factor.
But it also includes the way they interact with the operating
system and with the hardware in your device.
Window zaps are designed to run sand boxed,
which means basically that they kind of run in their own little enclosure.
And any tax that need to be handled outside of that enclosure outside of the
app such as printing or sending something to the display,
are handed off to the operating system.
This takes a lot of load off of developers,
since they don't have to know every piece of hardware variation that
computer might have to run a windows app because of the way windows app
is installed in this sand boxed environment,
windows after don't make changes to the operating system.
In other words,
there's not a lot of registry changes or special files that are
installed somewhere in the Windows operating system.
Now there's a lot of benefits to the way these modern Windows APS install.
Because of the nature,
it's very difficult for some malicious individual to try
toe damage or change your computer.
You'll also find that when a system is being overtaxed,
a Windows app will simply _____ rather than have the whole
operating system come to a screeching halt.
So Windows APS are really designed to let the operating system manage
them as far as how much resource is they're using and how much of an
impact this is having on your devices performance.
You'll also find that window zaps meet a certain design
standard that affects the overall appearance.
So things like menus and other characteristics of
APS are gonna be pretty universal.
Whether using them on a tablet, a desktop computer or a Windows phone.
Let's just take a moment.
We'll look at some of the basic characteristics
that you'll find in a windows app.
You know any app for application that's running on?
Windows will have a title bar.
These tidal bars generally will have the same controls to minimize,
maximize our close a window.
In some cases, you may see a back arrow.
You'll also see hamburger menus,
another common feature that's been introduced with Windows 10.
These hamburger menus are designed to expand and reveal additional
controls when needed when not in use the minimize so they're not
obstructing your view of the application itself.
That's also common to see pains that may open from the left
or the right side of the application.
These may include other settings or other configurations.
Some Windows APS will have a command bar,
and it's gonna have to be revealed if you're using the most by right clicking,
and you may then see additional commands pop up
either from the top or bottom or both.
Window zaps often use an ellipsis, the three little dots,
as you can see here, and this also could be expanded.
That's letting you know there's more options or more
commands available in this clip.
We've looked at understanding Windows, APS. Thanks for watching had look forward to seeing you in the next clip