[Autogenerated] and this little look at the action center,
The Action Center is without a doubt one of the most important
new features that Windows 10 brought to users.
The action centers actually located within the notifications area,
which we've looked at it in another club.
We have a small icon down here that lets us know if there
are notifications we've not looked at.
If we select the icon, we can open the action center on that screen device.
You can actually just swipe in from the right the actions
that is divided into two principal sections.
The upper area is a scroll herbal list presenting
notifications that originate from APS on your device.
While the lower area has a series of _______ that are called quick actions,
quick actions are shortcuts to important settings that
affect how you device functions.
But as you glance through this group of _______,
you'll see that some quick action _______ include sightings
like screen brightness for a laptop or tablet or controls a
switcher WiFi to airplane moment.
Most quick action _______ are simply an on off button when enabled will
see the button has the accent color that windows uses on your device like
this one for location service is on color.
_______ are currently not enable, so I select location.
It loses the color and actually states that it's off.
Location service is air used where many APS to show
information relevant to you APS for weather,
travel or shopping when that work is intended
without access to location service is.
If someone wanted to disable the service for privacy reasons,
they would otherwise have had to dig in the
settings to prevent location tracking.
So having a quick action button that pulls the setting up
in the action center is a good example of how these
_______ could be very practical.
There are some _______ they're gonna have a few options when enabled.
Generally,
each click will allow you to cycle through additional
options if there are multiple settings,
and yet other _______ may actually launch in action
or open a settings pain this area.
Quick actions can be expanded or collapsed,
and we'll stay in whichever configuration you select until you change it.
Returning to the upper area,
we have those notifications that originate with our wraps.
When does 10 uses banner notifications to briefly bring
events to our attention by means of a small text field down
here above the notification area.
These are only on the screen for a short time by
the fall for about five seconds.
And we may miss some of them,
especially if we've stepped away from our device brought convenience.
These banner notifications are collected in the action center.
So what we are actually seen here is a recent history of banner
notifications that we may not have looked at yet.
Once we have seen them, most of these notifications will have disappeared.
The next time we open the action center and I don't feel
like you need to clean this area up,
the notifications collected here will roll over.
They will not just stay here forever.
Notifications are grouped by the application that generated them,
and we might have a few notifications here so you could
actually scroll through the list.
If you're looking for a specific notifications,
notifications can come from a variety of sources and APS
reminders and alarms new emails that human updates from a
smartphone mentions in a social media app.
Little just some examples of types of notification you might see here.
Selecting a notification will open the app that triggered that
notification and will take us right to that email,
news item or picture that was the focus of that notification.
Most no vacations that you see.
The Action Center will also allow you to perform actions
without envy and open the app e mails.
A good example, right?
If all you can see options to archive an email message or a
set of flag to take care of it later,
these actions could be displayed right in the notification
by means of _______ and touchscreen.
Devices may also include the ability of swipe left or right to take action.
Notifications could be tackled individually or as a group.
The APP name includes an accident.
I want you to clear all the notifications from that particular out.
Also, don't hear the top of the quick action _______.
There is a link to clear all notifications that wants.
Generally,
APS have their own default settings when they're installed that
determine how notifications they're generated.
If you're seeing notifications from an app that you don't want to have appear
as banner notifications and accumulate in the action center,
you can actually manage how those notifications appear and where they appear.
We're gonna look at all of those options for
managing notifications in another clip.
In this clip,
we've looked at using the action center you for watching and forward is he knew in the next clip.