[Autogenerated] in this clip, we'll look at using the start menu.
The START menu has received a lot of thought and attention,
and it's far as how it functions and peers in Windows 10.
A lot of elements will be familiar to you from Windows X,
P Windows, Vista or seven.
It also includes elements from Windows eight.
When you open your Start menu,
you'll see it's basically broken down into two sections off here to the left,
you have a navigation area, and to the right you'll see tiles.
Obviously, with the tiles,
they kind of grab your attention because many of them are life tiles.
Lifestyles are designed to provide you with information from within the app.
So at a glance you can get important information such as weather or news,
and you also see things that are designed to catch your
attention and encourage interaction with the zaps.
This area of tiles could be organized and rearranged to suit your needs,
and we'll look at how to do that in other clips.
Here to the left, you have a navigation area,
and you'll see things like most used APS you'll see recently installed.
APS entered the bottom of the navigation or you see a few shortcuts.
The start menu can be resized by simply selecting
and dragging one of the borders.
And there's a few key settings with the start menu should
be aware of the open your settings, app and select personalization,
and here we're gonna look at this.
Start options so you can choose to include most use
APS or also recently added APS.
I recommend you leave those on.
You can choose to have your start menu just appear as a full screen menu,
and another clip will look a tablet mode and we'll see that.
That's how that actually works by default.
You can also choose to use jump lists or not on your start menu.
I recommend you leave that I'm well, look,
a jump lists in another clip as well Friendly.
You can choose which folders appear on start.
If you select that, you can see file Explorer and settings are on by default.
You can also add other key folders, such as documents or downloads,
or maybe some of your libraries.
So they're right there at the Start menu.
We're actually going to look at a lot of the features of the start menu
in more detail through quite a few different clips.
So I encourage you to watch those as well.
In this clip, we've looked at using the start menu, and I look forward to seeing you in the next clip.