[Autogenerated] in this little look at the ease of
access controls included in Windows 10.
Ease of access or accessibility Controls are nothing new to Windows,
and you may have used them in the past.
There is a wealth of tools here that are designed to help people
with disabilities interact with their computer.
However,
just about anyone could make use of some of the tools that are located
in ease of access to enable ease of access tools,
open your settings out and then select ease of access navigation pane.
Here,
there's a nice grouping of tools that help us to locate tools that
target vision hearing or interaction challenges.
Now we're not gonna look at every tool here in detail,
but we're gonna look over many of them as we're going through these.
Take note of ones that could help you or those you know under vision.
We start with display,
and we can see or hear that the purpose of each tool is clearly labeled.
Use the slider here, for example, to make text bigger on the screen.
If we're happy with the sample text size,
we can apply that we'd also make everything a bit bigger from this drop down,
scrolling down we can hide or prevent some of the eye candy and Windows 10.
That could be distracting for some.
Incidentally, if the graphics hardware in your devices being taxed,
this could actually help improve performance.
There's a good sitting here to know about that changes how long
banner notifications will stay in the screen.
Under cursor and pointer size,
we can manage things like the pointer size that we see when using a mouse.
The current selection is marked with a check mark,
and I have to say that I rather like the third option here to
swap the color of the pointer under magnifier,
we can enable the magnifier tool and control it using
keyboard shortcuts also scrolling down here.
There's several options related to how that magnifier starts and
whether it would be a full screen experience.
We're just an area that can follow your cursor under color filters.
There's some settings now for color blindness.
In addition to inverted in gray scale choices,
we also have a few high contrast themes.
You would select the switch to enable this,
and immediately you would see high contrast themes applied.
You can choose from themes in this dropdown list to pick
the one that best fits your needs.
The last tool under vision is the updated narrator tool now enabling
this school will read any tax that appears on the screen where your
mouse pointer happens to be located, such as men use in Web content.
You can choose from different voices.
You can tweak the speed pitch and volume major scroll down here.
You can see there's many more sightings than in the past that can allow
you to manage just how the narrator tool he used.
Our next category is hearing challenges.
And under audio,
we have a visual other tool that helps us to see
win and where audio is generated.
Closed captions is a relatively new set of tools that lets us manage the
appearance of closed captions where they could be used by Windows.
Changes to the font,
color and transparency are all settings you can manage from here.
Under interaction,
we see tools that help us to use voice commands throughout windows.
Many of these air links it's actually see everything all in one place.
Now, Windows 10 includes a new dictation tool,
and we'll look at that tool in more detail.
In a separate clip here,
we also see length related to Cortina and speech recognition under keyboard.
We have some switches here related to the onscreen keyboard.
Now this is different from the touch keyboard that pops
up when needed on touchscreen devices.
And if you find yourself accidentally hitting your caps lock button quite often.
This switch here,
let's windows generate and beat when cap lock and other of
these locked _______ are enabled or disabled.
Mouse has a switch to use the new Mary keyboard to control your mouse cursor,
and lastly, a newer area here is divided to buy control.
Of course, we need to have an eye tracking device connected to our computer,
but it's nice to see Windows 10 including new tools and expanding others to
better accommodate the need of many users as possible.
In this clip,
we've considered some of the ease of access tools
that are included in Windows 10. Thank you for watching Hack for to see New in the next clip