[Autogenerated] and this clip will be looking at using the settings out the
settings at please a very important rule of Windows 10.
If you're a longtime Windows user,
you likely have used the control panel on Windows to
manage settings and hardware in the past.
The control panel still exists in Windows 10.
However,
most of the apple it's and settings that were managed from the control panel
have been brought into the settings out with future updates.
This migration will continue.
There's actually several ways open the settings out.
The most common way is from the start menu by selecting
the settings icon over here on the left.
When you first opened the settings up, you'll see the homepage.
The categories you see may vary a little bit,
depending on your device and the hardware you have.
For example, not all devices will display mixed reality settings,
but you will at least see 13 categories,
and most of your windows 10 devices throughout this course will
examine many of the settings and categories in detail.
This clip is intended to provide us with an order of you so
that you get a general feel for what's in here and how to find
savings you need when you need him.
A lot of thought has been put into making the categories logical,
and settings have moved around a bit since when Justin was first
released between redesigns and migrating settings.
It's simply not reasonable to try to memorize where every setting is located.
So throughout the course,
I'll often point out how useful it is to use the search tool down
on your taskbar rather than opening the setting.
Zap it all.
As you can see right on the home page, there's a search tool appear labeled.
Find the setting.
And if you open up a category,
that same tool will appear on every page in the city's
aptly includes this navigation menu here.
If we type in a keyword,
we'll see a quick list that provides the most common results for the key word.
If we don't see what we're looking for, we can select show all results.
Depending on just how many results there are,
we can actually scroll through the list.
Selecting on any of these will jump a straight to that page or pain
within the settings up that contains that setting.
As I mentioned there are still some settings that could
be found in the older control panel,
and you may have come across sayings that over that
meaning they could change the same setting.
And both the sayings that and the control panel,
for example, if I type in sound and then I scroll all the way down,
notice that there's a few icons that seem out of place,
these icons actually will.
Open control panel Apple it's that are used to handle that related setting.
This comprehensive search tool that uses both the settings up and the
control panel makes it so much easier to locate those very hard to find
settings when you make changes in control panel Apple,
it's it's important to realize that changes to settings must
be applied before they will take effect.
You may see an actual apply button, but often it's enough to select.
Okay,
Cancel will actually close the apple it or dialogue box
without ever having made a change.
Now this is very different from changes you make in the
settings that won't you change the setting.
It's almost always up immediately applied,
and you'll rarely see cancel or pie _______ when working with the settings out.
Another factor you'll occasionally run into is that some
sightings may make changes to your device,
and they require administrator rights to make that change.
For that reason, you may see additional prompts to confirm a change,
or you may be asked to provide an administrator user name and password toe.
Authorize the change.
For example,
Watch what happens when I tape in remote and then I select
remote desktop settings now find able to switch here to
allow remote desktop connections.
I'm prompted to confirm this choice,
even though I'm logged in right now with admin rights with this account.
And this is actually to protect me,
because normally it would be unwise to facilitate a
remote connection in my device,
and a standard user wouldn't even be ableto flip the switch house I mentioned.
This is actually a protective or security measure because some settings,
by changing them,
could have malicious results that could damage your account security.
They can affect your device performance or even compromise access to your data.
If you're asked by Windows to confirm in action,
it's a good indication that you might want to pause to consider why
this may not be a recommended action in this clip.
We've looked at using the settings out there watching, and I look forward to seeing you in the next clip.