[Autogenerated] in this clip,
we're going to look at snapping windows to the screen.
Snap was first introduced with Windows seven,
and you may have used in Window seven or Windows eight with Windows 10.
Snap gets some new features.
Snap is designed to help you manage the windows that appear on your screen.
As you can see here, I have a mess of different windows that are open,
overlapping one another.
Now the taskbar can help me to jump between windows.
Or I could arrange these in a way that maybe it makes it easy
to jump to windows that I want to work with.
But you'll find Snap really is useful in Windows 10
Snap works by grabbing the title bar, which I simply select,
and then I can drag a window around.
If I take it to the top of my screen,
you can see a faint outline that lets me know that
this app will now be full screen.
If I take the toolbar and I drag it to one of the left
or right side of my screen noticed,
the outline shows that that will occupy half of my screen,
and this is where a new feature snap assist comes into play.
The remaining part of my screen could be used by different app,
and snap assist lets me choose from available APs that are currently open,
and I can simply select the app that I want to use for the rest of the screen.
Now, with Windows 10 and dependent on the display that you're working with,
you're also able to snap windows to the quadrants of your screen.
In this case, if I dragged the title bar up to a corner of my screen,
noticed that it now just takes 1/4 of the screen and snap a system again,
let me select which app can occupy the remaining quarter.
Well,
this way of snapping windows obviously would be a lot more
effective in the screen with a much higher resolution.
So even though you may be able to snap multiple applications to your screen,
it may not be a very practical arrangement,
given your resolution, Tablet mode also will use snap.
However, you cannot currently snap applications to the corners of your display.
So again, now I'm in tablet mode.
If I take my app and snap it to the left or the right.
You can see that there is a central border that
appears snap assist appears again,
and I can select the app to share the rest of the screen with.
And now we can grab this vertical border in dragon,
left or right to change the percentage of screen
that each application will share.
You'll also notice that a small vertical bar lets me see
which application is currently selected.
I'm gonna return the tablet mode,
and let's look at some settings that affect how snap functions in your device.
Hair minutes.
I've been snapped.
You know, there's a few settings related to snap that appear.
Any of these will take me to the system portion of the
settings up to the multitasking pain,
and here the upper section will see is labeled snap.
So let's let me turn some features on and off so you can see on by default.
Is the ability to trigger the snap by dragging the window
itself to the corner or edge of your screen.
On by the fall again is the ability to snap a window to fill in the
available space and snap Assist is enabled lets me see what else I
could snap next to a snapped window.
Oh, snap.
Also confused with your keyboard.
If you have a selected window,
simply hold your windows key and use your arrow keys to indicate
which direction you want that window to snap.
Generally holding the windows key and selecting left or right,
we'll put it the left or right side of your screen,
and then you can use the up and down.
Aargh!
Next didn't get if you wanted to go to the upper or
lower corner on that side of the screen.
Snap works with multiple displays,
and if you work a little bit with re sizing the
windows after they've been snapped,
you'll find there's quite a few configurations you
can come up with a plan created,
experiment a little bit with snap and see how it could
be useful to you in your routine.
In this clip, we've looked at snapping windows to the screen. Thanks for watching, and I look forward to seeing you in the next clip