[Autogenerated] in this clip will look at understanding tablet mode.
Another clips.
We've made reference to tablet mode and rapture, wondering what is tablet mode.
It certainly is a new term for long time Windows users.
Well,
Tablet Mode is a new feature with Windows 10 that allows your device to
dynamically change the way it interfaces with you.
Now.
Windows eight was really designed to work with
tablets in touch screen interfaces.
Obviously, many computers don't have touch interfaces,
and it could be a pretty awkward way of working with your desktop computer.
So when does Time was designed to work well with desktop hardware?
They have a keyboard and mouse while the same time
working well with tablets that use touch.
Now there are actually quite a few devices out there that I
referred to its hybrid devices or two and one.
So it may be a tablet with an attached keyboard,
and sometimes you'll see these keyboards can either
detach or they fold behind the tablet, and in doing so,
they're disabled.
That allows you to use the screen itself as a touch interface.
Now,
Windows 10 can see this difference and recognize when there's hardware
such as a keyboard that's available for interface or not.
When it detects that the keyboard is no longer present,
it will automatically switch the device to tablet mode.
Knowing that touch is now going to be the preferred method of interaction.
It's really a pretty slick transformation now.
You can also manually make this change and you confined tune
how tablet mode works for your device.
Let's look at some of the settings involved.
First of all, from the action center,
you'll see a quick action button that's labeled tablet mode.
By enabling tablet mode, you'll see quite a few changes automatically take place.
Any open APS will now be full screen by default,
and in this case you can see how my taskbar lost all of its icons for open
APS tablet mode also provides a more subtle differences.
You may see things they're more spaced out,
allowing for better and easier touch interaction.
For example,
the icons that are visible on my taskbar have more space between them,
so it would make it easier to touch the correct ones just using my fingers.
Another thing in Lotus with tablet mode is when you select a search field or a
text field touch keyboard automatically appears so again,
Windows consents when it needs to have text input
provided the keyboard will appear.
And when you select somewhere outside of your text field,
the keyboard can go away.
Now, as I mentioned earlier,
there are some settings that allow you to personalize or to fine
tune how tablet mode works and your device.
If I open the settings, APP and I select system and then tablet mode,
notice that I can choose the default behavior of my device when I sign in.
In this case is going to remember what I used last.
I could change that always go to the desktop or always
go to tablet mode and again as faras,
allowing the device to automatically make those changes.
I can control that from here.
Don't ask me, don't switch.
Always ask me before switching or just make the switch.
So if the hardware changes, that computer can actually make those changes for me.
Finally, this is one.
You may want to make a change with Hyde App icons on
the taskbar when I'm in tablet mode, so again,
by default to avoid clutter,
you'll find that Europa naps are hidden on the taskbar.
This allows you to turn those back on now.
Some other observations to be aware of with tablet mode
is that when you're in tablet mode, you'll rarely if ever see your desk top.
So if you have the habit of saving shortcuts or documents to your desktop,
you won't have easy access to those when you're in tablet mode.
Another thing is was mentioned is your ___ will default to
full screen view Now that doesn't mean that you can't have
more than one at visible at a time, and another clip will look at using snap.
And this allows you to have more than one app available
or visible on your display at a time.
In this clip, we've looked at understanding tablet mode. Thanks for watching and look forward to seeing you in the next clip.