[Autogenerated] in this clip,
we're gonna look at working with groups on the START menu.
Does your no doubt noticed by now is you start to pin APS
and applications to your START menu.
It starts to look a little bit like the Wild West windows will
just pin new APS to the bottom of the start menu,
and even if you rearrange them, it still can look a bit chaotic and disorganized.
So when does 10 really has some good tools built in the hope you
keep your start menu under control and organized?
One of the best ways to do this is actually through the use of groups.
When you first open your start manual actually noticed that there
are some groups already created by default.
Here you see one of those groups,
and I've been adding APS to that and playing Explorers,
another group that was included with Windows 10.
Now creating groups on the fly is really easy to do.
Rather than just moving an app from one group to another,
notice what happens if I take this app and drag it
jin area below one of my groups.
Notice the spacing that's given to this new app.
Location.
Harold, grab another app and notice.
I'll drag it between two existing groups.
And again,
we can see that the way things rearrange and move is
actually allowing space for a new group.
Now, here I have a few APS already grouped kind of by category,
So I would consider these to be news oriented APS.
And another nice feature about groups on the START menu is that
you can actually name these whatever you want,
and you can rename ones that are already there.
If I hover my cursor over the top of the group knows
there's actually a place holder there.
That's his name group.
If I select that, it actually turns into a text box,
and I can now type in a new group name.
I'm gonna call this news so I can continue to add other APS.
Maybe that are related to news to the same group,
and I can create similar groups for gaming for photos for social media.
No,
the other nice thing about using groups is that you
can actually move groups as a whole.
So here, in my case,
I don't want my new zaps toe all a sudden be down out of
sight where I have to scroll down to find him every time I
want them right at the top.
Somebody selecting drag my group of new zaps to the very top of my start menu,
and that's all there is to it.
It's really very simple Dragon drop method of keeping
your Start menu organized in this clip.
We've looked at working with groups on the START menu. Thanks for watching and look forward to seeing you in the next clip.