[Autogenerated] in this clip,
we're going to look at uninstalling an application from time to time.
We need to remove applications that we've installed on our devices.
It's good to remember that Windows 10 uses two types of applications.
There are modern apse, which are obtained through the Windows Store,
and desktop applications, which can be downloaded from the Internet,
installed where they can be installed from some type of installation media.
The easiest way to uninstalling application is usually to locate
the application from our start menu and right click the
application to bring up the context menu.
You'll see the option to uninstall now.
If this is a modern app, you'll see this pop up,
confirming that the APP and its data are about to be removed.
Select uninstall again to confirm it will quickly disappear,
and it will be removed from your device.
If the application is a desktop application,
the programs and features window will open,
and it will show you all of the desktop applications
that are installed in your device.
You'll need to select your application here and then
select uninstall from the top of the list.
The uninstaller for that application will be launched and it will
walk you through any steps and may be needed.
You may be asked to make decisions related to saved
information or components that were installed.
Additionally,
you may find that in some cases more than what item was
installed for a particular application.
So you may need to look through the list to make sure everything was removed.
Another way to manager on installs is through the settings out under settings,
select APS and features,
and here you can filter the results in a few different ways.
Besides size, you can also sort by name and date of installation.
You can also focus the results to specific drives if you
have more than one location on your device.
This could be especially useful when you're trying to create
some space on your device and just need to see what chaps
are taking up the most space.
Select an application and then select uninstalled to start the
same on install process we described earlier.
In some cases,
you may select an app on your start menu and find that no uninstall action
is present where you may see an option on installed,
but it may be great out depending on the version of
windows you're currently using.
But this will be the case when an app is considered a core
app and is really part of Windows 10.
You can find instructions on the Internet for manually uninstalling most
of these core APS if you really determined to do so.
But I don't recommend doing this as some of these acts are expected to be there,
and you could find Windows to be negatively impacted if they were removed.
The main reason Windows 10 uses APS to handle some system tasks
is that these could be updated easily without requiring any
major updates to Windows 10 itself.
In this clip, we've looked at uninstalling applications. Thank you for watching and look forward to seeing you in the next clip.