Hello and welcome to this module of continuous delivery and
automation on AWS for DevOps engineers.
My name is Fernando Medina Corey, and in this module,
we'll learn about deploying our applications with AWS CodeDeploy.
Let's look through everything we'll be doing in this module. To get started,
we'll look at what is AWS CodeDeploy, some deployment configuration that we
need to provide to it, CodeDeploy benefits that we get when we use the service,
and some other deployment tools that we might end up using in AWS just to
differentiate them from CodeDeploy.
From there,
we'll take a closer look at some CodeDeploy concepts that we need to
understand when we work with it. After that, we'll visualize different
deployment types that happen with CodeDeploy.
And then we'll look at AppSpec files and hooks, and both of
these concepts will be used with CodeDeploy.
From there,
we'll look at a demo, and see how we can design an ECS
deployment strategy by leveraging CodeDeploy. So let's get started.