Now that we know some basic concepts around Git,
let's look at some different workflows we might use depending on the
project that we're working on. We might have a simple Git workflow that
looks very similar to what we were doing earlier,
where we just have one single remote repository and our
local repository, and we go through all the steps I talked
about earlier on the same branch,
typically something called main, or sometimes master.
But in this case,
we'd only really do this when we're working on our own,
without a team putting in commits alongside us,
and also without having to worry about whether we're stomping
on our own toes by working on multiple features at the same
time. For more complicated projects,
we might end up using something like Git Flow,
which is an option when you have to maintain multiple
versions of the same pieces of software.
So if you have one customer expecting that you'll maintain one
version of software for them, and another customer expecting that
you'll maintain another version for them,
Git Flow can be pretty useful for this because it has the ability to
support those sorts of changes and that kind of maintenance.
One of the drawbacks is that it is pretty complicated, and while it can be
great for managing those multiple versions of software,
it was actually popularized before web development,
meaning that for a lot of web developers, you don't really have
lots and lots of people expecting you to maintain multiple
versions of the same piece of software.
Rather, you push that piece of software out with constant changes,
and everybody gets those changes, sometimes in A/B tests or staged rollouts,
but eventually everybody's working from the same thing.
Now, even the creator of Git Flow, Vincent Driessen,
says that another workflow called GitHub Flow is
actually well suited to web development,
possibly better than Git Flow.
So let's look at what GitHub Flow looks like. With GitHub Flow,
you'd have a pretty similar example to what I was showing you earlier,
where you have a remote repository, except instead of only having one
branch you'll have multiple branches coming into that remote
repository, the main branch where you're merging everything into and
other feature branches that you're putting pull requests on to merge
into that main branch. Again, the naming of this main branch might
differ by your organization, but the logic here is basically the same.
So why would we use GitHub Flow as opposed to some other workflows?
Well, right now it's one of the most popular options for web development,
and it encourages best practices with frequent smaller merges for your features.
It's also well suited to see CI/CD practices that we talked about
earlier, by allowing you to quickly merge into a main branch, by
making sure that you run your unit tests as you might merge into
your main branch, and also,
if you do your deployments to a test environment, running some integration
tests in that test or development environment. From there,
you might use continuous delivery to actually send your code out
to a production stage so that your customers can interact with
it. Because it's well suited to CI/CD, we'll primarily be using GitHub Flow in this course.