Hi, everyone.
My name is Fernando Medina Corey, and welcome to my course,
Continuous Delivery and Automation on AWS for DevOps Engineers.
I'm a Lead Cloud Architect, and I've previously used AWS as
a data engineer and software developer.
I also hold six AWS certifications and have made
courses that span dozens of AWS services.
This course is a tour of several important AWS DevOps services.
With DevOps being one of the most in‑demand engineering skills,
we need to learn how we can use it to improve our development practices.
Some of the major topics that we will cover include creating
build and test pipelines with AWS CodeBuild,
deploying applications with AWS CodeDeploy,
managing infrastructure with AWS CloudFormation,
and creating automated release pipelines with AWS CodePipeline.
By the end of this course,
you'll know how to leverage several important AWS services to
streamline your development practices and improve the
reliability and quality of your code.
Before beginning the course, you might want some experience with AWS or with Git,
but the demo code and the commands will all be provided for you.
From here,
you should feel comfortable diving into other AWS
development topics with courses on AWS Lambda,
Architecting for Cost on AWS, or Collecting and Storing Data on AWS.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn about DevOps
on AWS with the Continuous Delivery and Automation on AWS for DevOps Engineers course, here at Pluralsight.