Hello and welcome to this module of Continuous Delivery and
Automation on AWS for DevOps Engineers.
My name is Fernando Medina Corey,
and in this module we'll learn how to create deployment
pipelines with AWS CodePipeline. To get started, we'll
look at what AWS CodePipeline is,
as well as the basic concepts that we need to
understand to work with the service.
From there, we'll visualize CodePipeline in an example.
And then we'll take a closer look at CodePipeline action types and
the concepts that are inside of those action types.
At the end of this module,
we'll look at a demo and see how we can build our own
CI/CD solutions using AWS CodePipeline. So let's get started.