In this demo,
we'll look at creating a CodeCommit user and repository
and getting it set up on our machine.
We'll start by creating a CodeCommit repository by using an AWS identity and
access management admin user, then we'll create a specific developer user
for AWS CodeCommit, and we'll create credentials using that user that we can
access the CodeCommit repository with. From there, we'll clone the
repository to our local machine, and then we'll be ready to start working
with it in the next demo.
So let's go over to the AWS console now. Over here in the AWS console,
we're going to go to this Services drop‑down and start by
creating our CodeCommit repository by searching for CodeCommit in
the search bar here and clicking on it.
Now in here in the CodeCommit section of the AWS console,
we'll click Create repository and then give this repository a name.
Now I'm going to call this repository flasky because we'll
be working with the Python library, Flask, to create our
application later in this course.
So let's leave that repository name as is.
We could also give it an optional description, and we could also
add tags to attribute this repository to a particular part of
our organization or for dealing with other billing purposes or
organizational purposes.
And if we were coding in Java instead of Python,
we could also enable Amazon CodeGuru to automatically
make recommendations on our code.
But because CodeGuru, as of this recording, doesn't have support for Python,
we're not going to check that off.
So let's click Create here, and let's see how we would
actually interact with the repository.
Well,
you'll notice that we have this warning down here that's saying
that we're currently signed into the root account,
and we can't configure SSH connections from the root account because it's
not tied to a particular developer or a particular user.
So in order to create SSH connections to our repository,
we're going to need to go in and create a new IAM user.
So to do this,
let's go over to the Services drop‑down and search
for identity and access management, or IAM.
We'll click on that, and that will create a new user.
So I'm going to click Users here, click Add user,
and I'm going to give this user a name,
which is specific to the developer that's going to be interacting with this
repository, not a generic name like admin or something else because we want
to tie all the commits that are being made to our repository to a specific
developer and a specific person.
So from here, we'll click,
enable Programmatic access and AWS Management Console access,
and we'll click Next. And then in this section, this is where we
determine what permissions we want our user to have.
We could either add them to a group to give them
permissions associated with a particular group,
or we could attach policies directly to a user.
Now the best practice is generally to have a group that we put all of
our users with the same types of permissions in.
And in this case, I'm imagining I'm Fernando the developer,
not Fernando the administrator.
Administrators might have full access to everything,
including managing IAM. In this case,
we probably just want our developers to have a slightly more restrictive access.
So I clicked Create group there,
and now we're going to create a new group called developers.
Now these developers will need a lot of permissions to interact
with many different AWS services, and we're not going to lock our
environment down too much because we'll be working with so many
of them in this course.
So I'll leave the developers name there,
and then we're going to search for two different policies.
We could use a combination of many different managed policies in the
process, but for right now, I'm going to search for power user, and then
I'm going to scroll down. You'll see that we have power user access as one
of the managed policies that AWS provides.
I'm going to check this off, and then I'm going to look down at the policy
summary that this has. Then you'll notice we have permissions for a lot of
different AWS services, 238 of them actually.
Now basically, the only thing that this power user can't do is
start to manage the IAM users, groups, roles, and permissions
associated with all of those different things.
So we're one step down from being an administrator.
So, let's make sure that that box is checked and that we are
associating this PowerUserAccess policy with our new developers
group. From here, in environments that are a little more locked
down, instead of using power user,
we might want to end up using a policy specific to CodeCommit.
So, for example,
if we wanted to grant people full access to manage
everything inside of CodeCommit, we could use the AWSCodeCommitFullAccess policy,
which would allow us to do basically anything inside of here,
including managing other services that interact with CodeCommit.
Now,
if we wanted to use other policies that only grant a little bit less than that,
we could use something like the AWSCodeCommitPowerUser policy,
which is, again, one step down just like the power user policy was from an
administrator policy that we were looking at earlier.
So with both of these two policies checked off, let's click Create group.
Now in this developers group, if we click on it, it has two different policies.
The AWSCodeCommitPowerUser and the PowerUserAccess policy.
And these policies will both be plenty to allow our new
user to interact with CodeCommit.
So let's close this out.
In addition,
these policies will help us work in future demos when we're interacting
with other AWS services that we need for DevOps tooling.
So let's make sure we add our user to this developers group by checking
that box, and then we'll click the Next: Tags button.
We won't add any tags in this case,
but we could again if we wanted to work with tags for the purposes I mentioned
earlier. Then finally, we'll review the user we're about to create, and you'll
see that it's in the developers group, and it's going to give us both
programmatic access and AWS console access.
Now we'll click Create user.
Now on this next page,
we'll need to make sure that we copy down all of the
credentials that are shown here,
both the Access key ID, and also the Secret access key, and the Password.
Now if we navigate away from this page at any point before we copy those down,
we'll have to do this process all over again.
So make sure you click the Show buttons next to Secret access key and Password,
and copy all this information down so we can sign into our AWS account.
After you've copied down all the credentials below,
make sure to also copy this sign‑in link so you can sign in with a non‑root user to your AWS account.