After we create the Identity and Access Management user,
we'll then need to sign out of the AWS console and sign back in with that user
using the sign‑in link that was provided when we created it.
So we'll enter our username and password,
sign into the AWS account,
and then we'll go over to the CodeCommit section of the console again.
Now,
what we're going to be doing is creating an SSH key
in order to use with CodeCommit,
and then we'll set that SSH key up underneath Identity and Access Management.
To do this,
we'll go back to the flasky repository and click on
the SSH section to connect with SSH.
Now,
there's going to be a few different options for setup instructions for macOS,
Linux, and for Windows.
Go to the section that's most appropriate for your operating
system and then follow the steps there.
I'll be going through the steps for macOS since that's
the operating system that I'm using.
Now, we've already done most of the prerequisites here.
We have to have a Git client,
which we've already downloaded in a previous demo from the Git website,
and it might already have been on our machines.
And we have to have a policy that gives us permissions to
access the AWS CodeCommit repository.
Now,
this is given both by the CodeCommit policy and the power user policy
that we attached to this user when we created it.
Now,
the last part of this first step is to create an SSH public‑private key pair.
it'll show you the instructions of how to do this when you click on the
Learn how to generate public‑private key pair link here,
but I'm going to assume that you've either done this already or that
you can go click on that link and get started.
It'll be a little bit different depending on the machine
that you're using so make sure to refer to the steps
underneath that operating system.
Once you have a public‑private key pair,
we'll need to register it inside Identity and Access Management.
So let's do that now.
We'll go over to the services drop‑down,
and we'll type in IAM and open up a new window here so that we
can work both with IAM and with CodeCommit.
Now, in the IAM window,
we'll probably see a lot of denies in terms of different
resources we're not able to access.
Now, this is fine.
That just means that the permissions we apply to this user are working
properly to not allow it to do everything in IAM.
Then we'll click on the Users section here,
and under the User section, we'll go to our user that we just created,
and we'll click on Security credentials.
Underneath here, we should see SSH keys for AWS CodeCommit.
Now, here, we'll need to click Upload SSH public key.
Now,
make sure to paste in the public key and not the private
key for your SSH public‑private key pair.
I'm going to go ahead and do this now.
Once this is pasted in, you can click Upload SSH public key.
Now, you should have an SSH key ID next to the key we just uploaded,
so go ahead and copy this SSH key ID now because we'll need to use it when we
set up some configuration for our Git client with our SSH key.
So let's go back to CodeCommit,
and you'll see the next thing that we need to do is take that SSH key ID and
set up a config file in a directory related to our SSH keys.
Now,
the steps here might be slightly different depending on
the operating system you're using,
so be sure to follow along with the appropriate one for your operating system.
In my case,
I'm going to need to create a new file named config
in the local tilde/.ssh directory.
Now, this is the home typical SSH directory that you'll have on a macOS system,
and it'll be pretty similar to what you do in Windows and Linux systems.
So I'm going to go over to my VS Code editor here,
and we're going to touch a new config file.
So let's create this new file with touch ~/.ssh,
which already exists because I've already created my SSH key pair here,
and then I'm going to need to create a new file.
Let's call this config.
You'll notice I have config_backup here,
which is an earlier version of my config so I don't lose it.
And inside of this config file,
we're going to want to add in what's included right below here in Step 3,
the Host, the User, and the IdentityFile.
So we can actually copy this entire thing here,
and then we can go back over to our VS Code editor,
and then we'll open this file up inside of VS Code.
We'll do code ~/.ssh/config,
and you could open this in whatever text editor you might be using.
But in this case, I just want to open it up in VS Code,
which I'm already inside of, and then we can paste that in here.
Now,
we'll need to copy and paste the different parts of this to make
it appropriate with our actual IAM SSH key ID.
In fact, we have to go back to the Identity Access Management console,
and we'll need to make sure that we copy this key here into
our VS Code editor and replace it there.
Then we're going to need to replace the IdentityFile for our private key name.
Now, in this case,
my IdentityFile is what the standard SSH key is on a macOS system,
which, if we list off the contents of the ~/.ssh directory here,
you'll see is id_rsa.
So I'll replace that here inside of the ssh section with id_rsa,
and we can save that here.
Now that I've done this,
we can go back over to the instructions in CodeCommit, and
the last step should be to make sure that the permissions
on this file are appropriate,
so we'll have to run one command on this Mac system to
change the permissions on the file.
So in this case,
it's not going to be exactly what is included in the pasted command
because this is referencing the current directory.
So what we'll need to do is go ~/.ssh/config,
and then this should change the permissions on the file so that
we can use it with the CodeCommit service.
Now,
be sure to save the config file before and after you do this to make sure
that all these changes are reflected when we're using it.
Now,
the last step is to copy the Git clone command that we'll
be using to work with this repository.
So after you copy it, you could go back to the VS Code editor,
and we can clear the screen here.
And actually, I'm going to close the config file out,
and we can just paste it in and type in git clone and ssh,
and you might have one other step that requires you to accept a fingerprint.
You can just type in yes and hit Enter if you see that.
So now that we've cloned the flasky repository,
you'll notice there's actually nothing in it.
So if I go and change directories into flasky and list the contents out,
there's nothing in here.
But if I list the contents out and look a little bit
more closely with the ‑al flag,
it'll look for hidden files as well, and we'll see
that there is a git folder here.
This just means that we've set up Git with this repository,
and we're about ready to start committing to it. So we'll push our first commits in the next demo.