In this demo, we'll be implementing our first Git workflow using CodeCommit.
We'll add new code directly to a main branch that we create,
and then we'll add new code via feature branches that we merge into that
main branch. We'll do this by opening CodeCommit pull requests and then
merging those pull requests into the main branch.
So let's go over to VS Code and get started.
You'll notice that the default name of the branch that we're
working with is called master, but if we wanted to,
we could change the name of that branch where we'll be merging everything into.
If we wanted to do this, we could use git checkout ‑b for branch,
which will create a new branch and check it out,
and we'll call this branch main.
Now I'm going to clear the screen,
and we can start making commits to this main branch where we'll be merging
everything in after we've put it in feature branches.
So to do this, let's just add a new file.
Let's do touch app.py,
which we'll be working with later on. Now inside app.py,
we're going to import the boto3 library,
which we'll be using later on with AWS.
So I'll leave that in there, and we can commit this code. First,
we'll do git status to check the current status of everything in
this branch and this repository, then we'll do git add to add
app.py, and then we'll do git status to see that it's been added to
our staging environment.
And from here, we'll do git commit to commit this to our main branch. We'll
do add app.py as our commit message here, and then we'll hit Enter, and this
will be the first commit on our new repository.
So now I'm going to clear the screen.
And if we wanted to push this up into our repository, we can do
git push, and then we'd have to select the name of the remote that
we're working with. Now in this case, by default,
that remote is called origin.
Now we need to pick the branch name right after the remote name.
In this case, we want to push it to a branch called main,
which is what we'll be calling the branch we're merging everything into.
Now, we should see that eventually it'll push everything up into
CodeCommit and create this new branch called main.
So let's clear this out, and now let's go to the AWS console to confirm
that this worked. Over in the AWS Management Console, we can go to the
Services drop‑down and look for CodeCommit,
and then we'll go into our repository that we created
earlier called flasky. Now in here,
you'll notice that we now have an app.py file that
appears inside of the flasky repository.
Now we push this directly to our main branch, which shows up the top here.
If we click the drop‑down,
you'll notice that it's currently our default branch and the only branch
that we're working with just because it's the first branch we pushed any
code to when we pushed code to our repository.
Now if anybody goes and clones our repo,
they'll automatically get this app.py file that we created.
But for the rest of the time that we're adding code to our repository,
we'll want to be adding code using a feature branch,
so we'll need to create a new branch and then merge
it into main with a pull request. We'll do that in the next video.