Nice work throughout this module.
We covered a lot of complicated stuff about CodeDeploy,
ranging from the basics about the benefits CodeDeploy offers, some of the
configuration and the concepts around it, and also the details around how
CodeDeploy can be used with multiple platforms like EC2 or on‑premises
environments, and ECS, as well as AWS Lambda. And you took a closer look at
things like AppSpec files and the hooks that they have available to them when
you're working with different platforms. Both to run scripts at particular
times and installations on EC2 or on‑premises environments, we had to run
Lambda functions as tests in situations where you're deploying to ECS or AWS
Lambda. Now, at the very end,
you did a lot of great work deploying your own ECS application.
That was a pretty complicated demo and a pretty sophisticated
deployment process, so you should pat yourself on the back
for getting through all of that.
There's a lot more to learn about ECS and working with it
that I wasn't able to cover in this course, but if you're
working with it in the future, you should feel pretty good about how you could integrate CodeDeploy with it.