Nice work in this module.
We covered everything ranging from DevOps fundamentals to what
CI/CD is and the different parts of CI/CD.
We also looked at Git concepts and all the basic commands we need to
know to get up and running with different Git workflows, as well as
which ones we'll be using in this course.
After that, we looked at different repository hosting tools,
but of course, we were working most with the repository
hosting tool CodeCommit. In the demos.
we managed to create a CodeCommit user and repository,
and we pushed our first feature branch and merged our first pull
request using AWS CodeCommit. In future modules, we'll be doing a lot more with CodeCommit and other AWS services.