So now that we understand some of the basics of AWS CodeBuild,
let's take a closer look at build spec files.
Build spec files have different sections that determine
different things that we'll be doing with the file.
One of the first sections we could choose to add is
an environment variables section.
This could contain different pieces of information to help us distinguish
between different environments such as production and test, but it could
also include things like different secrets.
Maybe we want to use them differently across different environments,
for example.
But when you're working with secrets,
it's important to realize that in the environment variables
section, you can also reference other AWS services like the SSM
Parameter Store and the Secrets Manager.
Be sure to use those services when you're putting secrets into the built spec
files so that you don't actually have to hard code the values, but you can just
code references to those values and those services.
There's also other sections like the phases section. In
the phases section, you'll determine what happens in each
phase of your build process,
and you can also configure things like the reports section,
which will output tests that you can then later
review after the build is completed.
Additionally, if you're building different pieces of code in your build,
you might output artifacts.
This is relevant when you have language runtimes that require
artifacts to be built to deploy your actual application.
But it could also be relevant when you're building things like front‑end
applications or other things where you have deployment artifacts you need to
send out rather than just your existing application code.
So let's take a closer look at a build spec file.
Here's an example that only includes a phases and a reports
section. Underneath the phases section, we have an install,
pre_build, and build section,
and each of these will do different tasks that the build container
needs to do in order to run the entire build.
For example, in the install section,
we're configuring it to work with Python 3.8,
and in the pre_build section, we're installing some dependencies,
setting up a Python virtual environment, and making a directory for our
test reports to go into. Later in the build section, we're actually not
building anything because with Python you don't need to output
deployment artifacts in most cases.
Instead,
we're just running tests against our Python code to make sure that
those will pass for a successful build to have run.
And then in the reports section,
we're configuring where to expect the reports from those tests to
end up, in this case, in the test report directory with the file
format that we've included up in the python ‑n pytest command
underneath the build section.
Now we'll be using a very similar file like this later on in the demo,
but you can customize these sorts of files pretty significantly.
So let's take a look at some of the ways we can do these customizations. In
the phases section, the overall purpose of the phases section is to control
the flow of the build process and to allow us to structure and execute build
commands, depending on where in the build process we are. Some example phases
would be the install phase, the pre‑build phase,
the build phase, and the post‑build phase. And you can start to see, we might
want to run different commands in each of these phases,
depending on what we want in our build. With the reports section,
as I mentioned before, the purpose is to allow us to define
different reports that will be generated,
and we might configure different testing frameworks and output
locations. Now with the artifacts section,
which is one I didn't show in that earlier snippet of code, the
purpose is to allow us to configure and define output locations
for artifacts that we're building, and this is also completely optional.
For example, with Python builds,
we wouldn't use it because we don't typically have output from Python builds.
But with Java builds,
we might build a .jar file and similar for other runtimes that require
deployment artifacts to be created in order for your application to then
eventually run. Frequently, you'll see this with languages that are
compiled rather than languages like Python,
which are not. So now that we know what to expect inside of build spec files,
let's give this a try for ourselves in the demo when we're working with AWS CodeBuild.