In this demo, we'll be deploying CloudFormation stacks.
We'll start by creating a CloudFormation stack in the CloudFormation Designer.
Then we'll review the CloudFormation console during the
resource creation process so we can see all the steps that
CloudFormation takes to create our resource.
After that, we'll update the stack and add some tags to
the resource using CloudFormation,
and then we'll redeploy it and see those changes.
From there,
we'll deploy a separate stack using the AWS CLI
instead of the CloudFormation console.
So let's go over to the CloudFormation console now and get started. Over here in
the AWS Management Console, we can go to the Services drop‑down and look up
CloudFormation, and we should be able to click on that and then create a new
stack inside of the CloudFormation console.
Yours probably won't look like this, as I have a bunch of other
stacks created here from previous projects.
However,
you can click the Create Stack button regardless of the screen you're on,
and you'll probably get an option to click with new
resources or with existing resources.
We'll use the with new resources, which is the standard. The other
option is available if you want to incorporate additional resources
that already exist inside of your template.
Now there's a few options here.
If we already have a template file uploaded in Amazon S3
or locally that we want to upload, we could use the first option.
Otherwise, we could use a sample template,
which would allow us to create a CloudFormation template with previously
existing templates that AWS provides for us like a Ruby on Rails
application or a WordPress blog, but for right now,
we're going to use the Create template in designer option,
and we'll click Create template in designer right below that.
Then, in this section,
the first thing we'll need to do is click the Template tab here
rather than the Components tab, and we'll need to go over to our
code for this section of the course. Inside of the demos for the
first demo in this module,
we should have a file that's called sns‑stack‑json. We're going to copy the
entire thing, and then we'll paste it into that section of the template here.
We'll paste over everything that's already there so that the only thing left
is what we just pasted in from our file.
Then we can click the Refresh button in the top right and see
the resource that's included inside of it.
So let's review what this code does.
We have a Resources section in here,
which describes the different resources that we're working with. In this
case, only one exists inside of this file called My Topic,
and its type is an AWS SNS topic.
It also has two different properties,
one for its display name and one for its topic name.
From here, it should allow us to create the resource using CloudFormation.
So let's validate this template by pressing the checkmark here,
and then we'll go over and upload it after it's been
validated and confirmed as legitimate JSON that we could
use as a CloudFormation template.
From here,
we can scroll down and click Next, and skip the Parameter
section, because we don't have any parameters, but we will
need to give this a name.
So let's call this devops‑sns, and then we can click Next. From here, we could
add additional key value pairs and tags for our stack that we're deploying, or
set the permissions for how we want to deploy these resources. By default, it
will use the IAM user and the permissions associated with that IAM user that
we're signed in as, but we could also choose to use permissions related to a
particular deployment role.
So let's skip over the advanced options and click Next at the
bottom. In the Review section, we'll also scroll down to the bottom
and click Create Stack, and this should start the process of
creating our resources. Now, right now,
there are no resources whatsoever in the stack, but if I refresh it,
you'll see there's the myTopic resource that's currently
in the status of CREATE_IN_PROGRESS.
If we go back to the Events section,
you'll notice that it starts at the bottom by starting the
creation process for the stack and then the resources
within that stack, in this case, the myTopic SNS topic.
Finally,
it finishes creating the myTopic resource, and then it finishes the stack,
which means that if we go back to the Resource section,
this AWS SNS topic resource should be complete. And if we
wanted to verify that it was actually created,
we can go to the Services section and look up SNS, go over to the Simple
Notification Service, and then look at the topics we have in here.
Currently,
I have one left over from a previous project, but we
also have this myAwesomSNSTopic, which, if we look at the Tag section,
doesn't have any tags right now.
So let's say we wanted to add tags to this topic.
If we go back to the code for this section,
you'll see that I also have an sns‑stack‑v2.json file.
Let's copy this here,
and we're going to take this in a moment and put it back in
the AWS console and update this stack.
Now I want to point out before we do this that I've added some
code here on line 8 about tags for this resource.
We now have a key value pair of department and Engineering, so
that we can associate this topic with our engineering
department for any costs that it accrues.
So let's go back to the AWS console,
go back over to CloudFormation, and then let's go over to the
Stack Info section, and let's update this.
Let's click the Update button here,
and we'll do the Edit template in designer one more time, and Click View
in Designer to go to that section to update it. Now I'm going to paste
over the previous template that we have,
and then I'll refresh it, and you'll notice that nothing
really changed, because we haven't added any resources; we
just added tags to this resource.
I can validate the template again if I'd like, and then upload it
into AWS so that we can use it for CloudFormation.
So now that we've done this, we'll be able to go through the exact
same process as before. We'll click Next, Next again,
scroll to the bottom and press Next one more time, and update the stack.
Now, if I go to the Resources section,
you'll see we still have the same resource, but we should
start to see a few different events here about updating this
stack and the resources inside of it.
So currently the update is in progress for our SNS topic called myTopic,
and if I refresh this a few times,
it should eventually show that we've finished updating myTopic, and
we've finished updating the entire stack. To confirm that this worked,
we can go over to the Simple Notification Service, scroll down in the
Tags section, and while we don't see any right now, if we refresh the
page and then try this again,
we should now see this department Engineering tag associated with our SNS topic.
So these are some of the basics about how you could start to use
CloudFormation to describe the resources that you want inside of stacks, and
then deploy them into AWS, and then make changes as we want to change what
our services and our applications look like, using the descriptions of their
infrastructure. Now in the next section, we'll look at how we could do this not using the AWS console, but instead using the AWS CLI.