In this demo, we'll learn how we can do automated testing using AWS
CodeBuild. First, will review a Flask application that I've put together
using Python and some of the tests inside of it.
They'll basically just be boilerplate tests that will always
pass, but it will help us set up a framework for adding more
tests later on to our application.
From there, we'll add our application's code to a CodeCommit repository,
and then we'll configure CodeBuild for our repository.
After that, we'll trigger both a successful and a failed test build
and see the results in the CodeBuild console.
So, let's go over to our code now and take a look at our application.
I've downloaded the code for this particular demo from
the material section for this course.
If you haven't already,
make sure that you've gone into those materials and reviewed the first section
of the materials so you know what the installation setup steps are for things
like Python and the AWS CLI. Now, importantly,
if you haven't already finished the previous modules of this course,
you'll need to in order to connect with CodeCommit, as that
will be a prerequisite for doing this demo.
So assuming you've done all of that,
the first thing we'll do is get into this
demo1‑automated‑testing‑with‑aws‑codebuild folder. Inside of here, I have a
few different things going on, so let's take a look at some of these files.
The first and probably most important one related to what I'm
doing with CodeBuild is the buildspec file.
You'll notice that this is almost exactly the same thing that I
showed in an earlier section for my example buildspec file. It's
allowing me to set up a Python runtime that will help me run some
tests against my application.
Now the only different thing about this buildspec
file now is that it's not alone.
It also comes with a Flask application that I'll be
using to test inside of CodeBuild.
Now, in this flask.py file,
you'll notice I'm importing Flask as a dependency. Now, this means
I'll need to install it before I work with it,
because Flask isn't included inside of the Python standard library,
which includes things like the JSON import that I have on line 1.
Basically,
what this does is it allows me to set up a web application, in this case,
just doing something pretty simple like returning
information on a particular user.
Now I've made this application basically a bare‑bones application to
return user profile information from a data.json file.
In reality,
what we'd be doing is connecting this over to a
database, but to make things simpler,
I've just included the data we get from the database inside of this
data.json file. And then, everything that's happening in my app.py file
will allow me to go in here and grab the relevant data for a particular
user from all of the data in here. Inside of app.py, you'll see this
happening when I interact with the data.json file, and then run a little
bit of code on line 12.
If it's not entirely transparent what this does,
don't worry. It basically goes into the data.json
file and looks up the ID for a user.
If it sees the ID for a user, it returns that user's information,
and then it sends it back out as JSON to the results for the API. Now,
in order to test this,
what I've done is included another requirement for
this project, and that's pytest.
Pytest is one of the most commonly used Python testing
frameworks, and in order to use pytest,
I have made it a little simpler by including a tests
folder that has a tests_routes.py file.
Now this is, as you expect, probably going to test the routes in my application.
So if I click into here, you'll see that I have one function inside of here,
which will be called test_get_user_profile.
This will be testing the only route I've included in app.py,
which is called if we scroll up to the top here on line 7, the user route.
Now, in order to make this test work, I've also created a conftest.py file,
which will essentially just mimic the app that I've created in app.py, and we'll
be using this to make sure we avoid some other potential issues that might
happen if we didn't have the conftest.py file. I won't go into pytest in a ton
of detail in this course, because there's a lot of other great courses on
Pluralsight that cover it in more detail.
So now that we know what most of these files are doing inside of here,
let's see how we're actually going to set this up
inside of the AWS CodeBuild console.
The first thing we'll need to do is to make sure to move
this code into a CodeCommit repository.
Now, there's a few ways for us to do this,
but let's go to the AWS console now to see what they are.
The first one would be to go to the services drop‑down and look up code commit,
and then from the CodeCommit console we could use the previously existing
repository that we might have worked with in earlier modules, and then just
update the code in there and then hook that up to CodeBuild.
But because I'm not sure if you've done that yet,
I'm going to make it a little simpler and just have us create a new repository.
We'll call this flasky2, and now we'll know there's a
difference between this one and the previous one.
Then I'm just going to click Create. Now from here we should hopefully
have already gone through the steps in order to make sure we can
connect to CodeCommit using our credentials.
If you haven't done that,
I'm not going to repeat it, so go back to that module on
CodeCommit where I explain how to do this entire process.
We'll click the SSH step here.
And if we haven't done this,
they'll be instructions for all of these. But then we can actually just
scroll up to the top and click Clone URL, Clone SSH, and then we should
have copied the SSH URL for this repository.
You can see mine up here in the second notification at the top of the screen.
So now that we have this URL cloned, let's go back
over to our VS Code editor here.
Now this currently isn't a Git repository,
but in order to create a Git repository here,
we could do one of two things.
We could clone that empty repository and then move all the stuff in there,
or we could use a command like git init, for initialize, to create this as a
repository and then hook it up to the CodeCommit repository.
But the easiest way I think to do it right now will probably just be to
go git clone, and then to paste in that SSH URL. Now,
this should create a new folder inside of our existing folder.
So if I list this out here, you should see that we have this flasky2 here.
Now, this means that that's our Git repository,
not the containing demo1‑automated‑testing‑with‑aws‑codebuild
folder, but actually flasky2 is our Git repository.
So to fix the fact that we have all this code in the high‑level repository,
we're going to move everything from here into that repository.
So let me make sure that I scroll out a little bit so you can see this properly.
I'm going to use the mv, or move command,
and then I'm going to say that I want to move all these
different files into the flasky2 folder.
So I'm going to do ./*,
and that will reference everything in the current directory, and I
want to move it into flasky2. Now, this is probably going to fail, and
the reason for this is because it's going to pass everything into
flasky2, including flasky2 itself.
But technically it worked on everything else, so if you see a message like this,
don't worry.
This command should work on Mac OS's and also Linux OS's, but it's
possible if you're doing this on a Windows machine,
you might just want to open up the File Explorer and do all this
migration that way by moving the files by hand into our flasky2 folder
that's now a Git repository. Now, you could do the same thing on a Mac
machine or a Linux machine too, if that's easier.
So let's change directories into flasky2 now, and then let me
clear the screen and let's see what's going on inside of our VS
Code editor if I open it up. It looks like everything's been
moved in there correctly.
So now if I do git status,
it should say that we have a bunch of stuff to add to our repository.
So in order to do this,
we're going to use git add . to add everything inside of here.
And we'll do git status one more time, make sure that we've got everything added.
Now the next thing we'll need to do is commit these changes.
So we'll do git commit ‑m, and this will allow us to pass in a message.
In this case,
we'll just say first commit, and then we'll hit Enter there. And now we
should have everything inside of our Git repository,
so we should push it up over to the CodeCommit repository.
So let's do git push origin. Now if we wanted to,
we could choose a different branch name than master,
which is sometimes the default when we call repositories. For simplicity here,
I'm just going to keep it as is,
and we can push it and have it go over to CodeCommit.
So now that it's done,
we should be able to go back to the AWS console and just
refresh the Repositories screen, click into flasky2, and see
our new pieces of code inside of here. And this is where we'll need to be in this demo to start working with CodeBuild.