So now that we're ready to start working with CodeBuild,
I need to point out one thing to you.
We're currently signed in as the user I created in the
CodeCommit demo earlier in this course,
which means if I click on the drop‑down here,
you'll notice that my IAM username is fernando.
We're not underneath the root account for this AWS account.
And if I go to the Services drop‑down,
you can tell this pretty clearly if I go to a service like IAM.
When we created this account in that section,
we Limited the IAM permissions pretty heavily for this user.
What this means is that we won't necessarily be able to create an IAM
role that CodeBuild can use to build our project.
So to fix this,
we can either give this user more permissions or we can set up
a build pipeline using a higher‑permissioned user like an
administrator or the root account, probably an administrator,
since that's the best practice.
So in order to set up CodeBuild,
I'm going to instead sign into an administrator account
in AWS in the exact same AWS account.
We'll double‑check I'm there by going to CodeCommit, and then we'll check that
are flasky2 repo is currently listed inside of the repos.
Looks like it is,
and we have all the code that we just pushed from the command line.
So from here,
we should be able to use this higher‑privileged user
to create a CodeBuild project.
We'll collapse the Source section here,
go over to Build, and click Getting started and Create project.
From here we'll be able to give this project to name.
I'll call it flasky‑build, let me make sure I add the y there,
and then we'll need to select the source where the code
comes from in order to build our project.
We'll keep CodeCommit selected as the source provider,
and then we'll click flasky2, which is the repo that I push my code to.
But if you're sticking with flasky just without the 2,
you can also select that here.
We'll pick the branch that we're using.
For flasky2, I kept the master branch, but when I was working with flasky,
it had the name of main.
But either way,
select the branch that you'll be merging everything into and pushing
your changes into when you want builds to happen.
So with master selected,
I'll scroll down and we'll set up the environment section.
Instead of a custom image, for example,
if we wanted custom stuff inside of a Docker container that ran our build,
we'll instead use a managed image,
which means that AWS CodeBuild will deal with all the
dependencies and everything else inside of it for us,
and it'll make it a little bit easier to get off the ground with our build.
We'll then select the operating system.
By the fault you do have Amazon Linux 2,
Windows Server, and Windows Server 2019,
but Ubuntu is typically the most recommended build
process inside of AWS CodeBuild.
So we'll select that, click the runtimes,
click Standard, click the Image and click Standard:4.0.
And if we wanted to pick a very particular version of the image,
we could go into these image versions and pick the one we wanted,
but we're going to use the latest image for this runtime
version and just leave it at that.
We could also specify if we wanted Linux or Linux GPU to run our environment,
but Linux should be fine for us for here.
From there, we'll scroll down and you'll see this Service role section.
We have the option to click an existing service role or a new service role.
In this case,
I logged in as the administrator user in order to create this new service
role without having to go get additional permissions.
Now if you're managing an organization of people that sets up build pipelines,
it's possible you might already as an administrator want to
create a role that they can then reference and use inside of
AWS CodeBuild without having to go out and create their own
roles for CodeBuild themselves.
This'll get around a permissions issue we might have faced if we
tried to do this as our lower‑privileged user.
That's just fernando that we created in the IAM console in earlier demos.
So now that we've clicked the new service role,
it should automatically populate a CodeBuild role for us,
given the name of our service.
So now that it's done that, I can scroll down to the Buildspec section.
In here,
we could write our own custom build commands if we
click the insert build commands button,
and then we could also switch to the editor if we wanted to do
this manually and write out every single command.
But because we already have a buildspec file, we'll leave that option selected.
Now by default,
CodeBuild is going to look for a buildspec.yml file in the root level directory.
And inside of our code here,
that's exactly what we have, a buildspec.ymlfile at the top level
of our directory that we pushed into CodeCommit.
So because we're using the default configuration we can leave this
section blank too and scroll down to the Artifacts section.
We're not going to do anything with this one either,
because since we're working with Python,
and we're not actually outputting any deployment artifacts to go
anywhere after we've run this testing build,
we'll leave this section configured with the type of No
artifacts and just leave it it as is.
From here we can scroll down to the bottom and click the Create build project.
We don't need to configure anything with logs because
all the defaults will be good for us.
Now,
once we're done creating this build project we'll have a few
different options for how we can interact with CodeBuild.
Immediately, we have the option to start the build right off,
so let's give that a try immediately.
From here we should have the ability to just kick off the
build with some basic configuration.
We shouldn't need to change any of this,
as we've already set up a lot of it in the steps we just did,
so we'll click Start build.
Now this build will start up and follow all the steps inside of
our buildspec.yml file and work with all the code that we
included in our CodeCommit repository.
If we want to see what's going on inside of this
build we can review the build status,
or we can scroll down to the Build logs section.
If we click the Tail logs button here,
this will allow us to see everything that's happening
inside the container as it happens.
So since we just started, there's not much here yet,
but you can start to see the information appear as it goes
through the PRE_BUILD stage and entering into the INSTALL
stage and the other stages, all the way to the POST_BUILD stage.
Now this happens pretty quickly because our tests don't take very long to run.
And you can see that the build has succeeded with a message in the top left.
So let's close this out.
now.
And let's see the reports for this build,
not just the build logs, but the actual reports from our pytest tests.
And if we click into them to see them in more detail,
we'll have an actual summary of all the tests that ran
and how many of them passed or failed.
In this case, we only had one test and it passed,
so we have a pass rate of 100%.
And we can even scroll down and see the different
test cases that passed or failed.
Now as you add more complexity to your applications,
having full reports like this can help you see what's going
correctly and what's failing and point you to what you need
to fix or update immediately,
so you can resolve it without having to do too much back and forth.
You can also set up CodeBuild to prevent builds from
going forward if they fail your tests,
meaning that if you're trying to deploy immediately after a successful build,
you could do it, but if you're tests fail,
you'll prevent yourself from deploying anything that has failing tests.
Now if you want to see what a failed build looks like,
let's go back over to our flasky2 application.
Inside of the tests folder, let's go to our test_routes section,
and let's add a new test.
Instead of def test_get_user_profile,
let's just copy this here and add another line to the end.
In this case, we're going to add an assert statement here,
but instead of asserting that something is true,
we're going to assert just false, meaning this will fail every time it runs.
And let's change this from test_get_user_profile to just test_failure.
Now this is going to fail every time, so we'll leave it with that name.
We'll do git status,
make sure that our changes are saved inside of the test_routes file,
git add . to make sure that we added to our staging environment,
git status one more time to see it there,
and then we'll commit these changes from staging into our branch.
We'll call this add failing tests.
And after this commit has been made, we can do git push origin,
and in this case to our master branch,
which is the main branch that we're using and pushing all our code into.
If we go back over to CodeBuild and we make sure that we're in our
flasky‑build project we can start a new build here.
Now there are ways to make this happen automatically,
but in this case,
we have to go all the way through everything and click
Start build manually one more time.
Usually those ways when we're working with CodeCommit and CodeBuild
directly will either involve creating a lambda function to
automatically trigger builds based on a commit to a pull request, or
maybe if you're merging into a particular branch like the master
branch or the main branch.
However,
there are are other ways we'll cover later in the course of
doing this with services like CodePipeline, so stay tuned for
that and putting these pieces together.
Now once CodeBuild has started this back off, we should be able to go
down to the build logs one more time and see the entire build process.
If we scroll through everything, we can see exactly what's happening
inside of it. But in this case,
we're going to start to expect it to fail once we get to the bottom. You'll
notice that we had an error when running this pytest command, so let's see what
the actual error was inside of the pytest report.
Let's go over to the Reports section and click into this report right here.
It looks like only 50% of our tests pass,
which kind of makes sense,
since we just added one failed test to this repository.
Now, if we wanted to fix this,
we could go back to that repository and update the test so it passes.
But now you should feel pretty comfortable with getting your
project set up with CodeCommit and CodeBuild.
But don't worry.
We'll integrate these to services a little bit more in later modules.
So let's recap what we've learned. In this module we covered a
bunch of information around AWS CodeBuild,
including its purposes and some basic concepts that it requires.
We also created our own custom buildspec file for our testing
project with a Flask application and some Python code. From there
we ran some automated tests with CodeBuild,
and we reviewed the results inside of the CodeBuild console.
In later modules we'll look at how we can integrate CodeBuild into a larger CI/CD workflow.