Back in the AWS console, let's remove the resources we created in this demo.
We'll start by going to Elastic Beanstalk because this is the most
important resource to remove as you'll likely be charged the most
for this one compared to other resources.
Go in here and select the environment you created,
click the Actions, and then click Terminate environment.
You might have to type in the name of the environment in order to do this.
In this case, Flasky3‑env, and then we can hit Terminate.
Now, once this is done,
we can also go to the Applications section and delete our
application from the drop‑down here.
We might want to wait until the environment is done just to
make sure that that's all cleaned up though.
While we're waiting,
we can go over to other parts of the console to remove some other resources.
Let's go to the CodePipeline console first just to
start there. From inside of here,
we can remove our flasky3 pipeline just by clicking Delete pipeline,
and then we can type out delete here, and then hit Delete.
Next, we can remove the other resources we created, like our
build project and our build pipelines there.
So we'll go over to flasky3 and click Delete build project and then type delete.
And once we click Delete, this should start deleting too,
and you can also clean up the other resources you created
from other sections of this course.
Now, once you're done with the build step,
you can even go over to the Source and the Repositories section,
and then you can select the repository we've been using and
click Delete and then type that out too.
I went ahead and deleted all the other repositories
that I created for this course too,
and you might want to to save yourself a little bit of money.
So after we've deleted everything,
let's go back to the Elastic Beanstalk portion of the console and then
click the Actions drop‑down for our application this time.
Now, we'll click Delete application.
This one is called flasky3, and then we can click Delete.
Now, this application and environment should have been deleted, and we
can double check by going to click Recent environment here. It looks
like it's still terminating this environment,
so we might have to wait a little bit longer just to be
sure all the resources get removed.
But once it's done, which it looks like it just finished,
we should be able to remove flasky3 the application for
good now that the environment is gone.
So let's try that one more time.
Let's click Delete, and now everything in our
application here should be gone too.
And if you want,
go ahead and go through the rest of the services we created throughout
this course and just make sure you've deleted them in order to save
yourself a teeny bit of money on some of those. But the most important one definitely here is Elastic Beanstalk.