In this demo, we'll be leveraging Parameter Store in lambda functions.
Now it seems like this is a bit of a change of pace from the
infrastructure as code that we've just been doing; however,
you'll see in a moment why it's so important to know how to use Parameter Store.
It'll allow us to add secrets inside of the Simple Systems Manager
Parameter Store that we can then reference from inside of
applications that run our code like AWS Lambda.
Then we can test the lambda functions out with the values
that are stored inside of Parameter Store.
Now this all matters because it helps us avoid
storing secrets inside of our code.
Either our application code or our infrastructure as code code.
You'll see in a moment how this will help us out.
Let's go over to our code editors now. I've already downloaded the
code for this module, and its inside of the
demo2‑leveraging‑parameter‑store‑in‑lambda‑functions folder. And
inside of here, we have a few different files.
I'll have some commands that you can run to work with CloudFormation,
some commands you can run to work with Parameter Store,
and then a lambda‑template.yml file.
This is actually a CloudFormation template that will
deploy out a lambda function using the same CloudFormation
CLI that we worked with earlier.
It'll look a little bit different than the JSON that we worked with,
but overall, it contains a resources section,
which has different resources inside of it that'll
automatically be created when we deploy it into AWS.
Now,
even if we look down on line 38, you'll see that some of the
code is written inline for our lambda function.
Now,
I won't go into too much detail about what's
actually happening in this template,
but essentially, we're creating a lambda function that will
then return the value of an SSM parameter that we're storing
inside of AWS' Parameter Store.
So, let's go ahead and get started by going over to
the ssm‑commands section first.
Now I've already downloaded and installed the AWS CLI and
configured it, so if you need help with that,
remember to go back to the instruction section for this
entire course to go through with those steps.
The first thing we'll need to do is to create a parameter.
We'll do this using the aws ssm put‑parameter command.
Then, we'll put a space and a \ so we can see everything we're
typing out, and we'll use ‑‑name, in this case, giving the parameter
a name of site and then capital C, Color.
Then we'll do one more \ and hit Enter, and we'll give this value for
the siteColor, currently as the siteColor of purple.
Then we'll do one more \ here, hit Enter, do ‑‑type in order to
indicate whether or not we're going to store it as a just regular
string or an encrypted string. And to store it as an encrypted
string, we'll use the SecureString value like you see up here in
the ssm‑commands.txt file.
Then I can hit Enter, and this should create a parameter
inside of AWS' Parameter Store for me.
You'll see here that the current version of this parameter
is 1, meaning I haven't created this before and we can
iterate on it later on if we want.
Now if we wanted to get this back using the CLI,
I'm going to go ahead and clear the screen to do this and show you what
the command looks like as well. We could run aws ssm get‑parameter, and
then we could do a \ here, go onto the next line, do ‑‑name, and then get
back the parameter we just created, in this case, called siteColor, then
I'll hit Enter. And you'll notice that we get back a bunch of different
information, including this value here.
Now this value is an encrypted version of the purple color,
and you'll see that it returns in all this gibberish
rather than just giving us purple.
So if we wanted to, instead, get the value back decrypted,
we could use the same command we did earlier.
Except now,
instead of just passing in siteColor, we'll do another \,
hit Enter, and use ‑‑with‑decryption,
and then this should come back with the value decrypted, currently purple.
So now that we've done this,
let's change gears a little bit, and in the next video, let's look at how we can deploy the lambda function template using CloudFormation.