We covered a decent amount about CodePipeline during this module,
we went through all the essentials we need to know around
the concepts of working with CodePipeline,
as well as how we can integrate it with a bunch of
other different kinds of tools,
and we even went through a demo and created our own pipeline to help
us deploy code directly to an Elastic Beanstalk environment every
time we make a commit in AWS CodeCommit,
and we even included a build and a test step inside of
there and then did the deployment.
So, overall, nice work throughout this course.
You've learned a ton about different AWS services that'll help
you to streamline your development processes.
Now, right now, you might be thinking what's next,
and what should you keep learning?
Well,
I have a few suggestions about other tools that you
might find useful when working in AWS.
The first is some tools that might help you
integrate different services together.
You might have noticed that AWS Lambda comes up in
several of these development services,
and I have an introduction to AWS Lambda here on Pluralsight
that you might be interested in taking.
I also have another framework course related to
something called the Serverless Framework,
which will help you develop AWS Lambda applications and
deploy them a little bit more easily.
From there,
you might want to look at how you can do cost optimization on AWS, something
that DevOps engineers are frequently tasked with doing.
I have a course on Architecting for Cost on AWS, here as well.
And if you're interested in learning more about other fundamental AWS services,
I have some courses on Collecting Data on AWS and Storing Data
on AWS, as well as a course on DynamoDB,
which is a pretty common one when you're working inside of AWS.
So hopefully this will give you some suggestions of what to take next,
but I want to take a moment and just say thank you.
I really appreciate you taking the time to go through this course.
And if you have any questions,
please don't hesitate to reach out in the discussion section on
Pluralsight, and also, feel free to get in touch with me and make
recommendations for other things that I should be working on. Thanks again, and I hope to see you in another course soon.