Hello and welcome back to the course on statistics.
Today we're solving the challenge for the high end fashion boutique and the line of clothes that they're
creating for very tall people.
So let's have a look.
All right.
We're going to open up my folder stats for analytics Section 1 distribution's and let's have a look.
This is our I just copied basically I haven't done much.
I've just copied the text about the distributions on the means and standard deviations into Excel and
we're going to start off from here.
All right so let's create a new tab and here what we're going to do is we're going to first require
that information that we had.
So we're going to say men women just so that we don't have to jump around between the tabs.
OK so here we're going to say mean standard deviation and top this is going to be easier right.
This part topped 2.2 percent or at least this toll this whole challenge was is pretty easy until you
get to the charts.
If you're paying the charts because they weren't asking the challenge and I'm you know I wonder how
you went with it.
Now we're going to be able to compare the results or be able to see your how you how you went in terms
of the findings.
So let's have a look.
You can do either in inches or centimeters I'm going to two inches.
Sixty nine point one trying to get used to these inches like is still a mystery to me.
How do you do it in the US do not understand anyway.
63.
But it's fun.
It's it's good it's good to know both or be able to operate both.
I already know that I'm six foot tall.
So that's pretty cool.
Sixty three point seven inches.
Sixty three point seven was just seven 24 7 inches.
And for women 2.7 inches.
Standard deviation 2.7 inches.
You can already tell that the mean is lower but it's also narrower So the chart is going to be taller
for women.
And is going to be it's going to be more like wider for men just a little bit.
Toke point 2.2 percent or in this are at least this tall.
So that's a threshold that cutoff that we're looking for.
So how do we get it.
So let's have a look.
Remember this part where they were asking about a fall for each of the two populations you have been
asked to identify the minimum height of 2.2 percent of the tallest people in that population.
So that's that's what we want to do.
And the way we're going to do it is we are going to say all right 2.1 Clozaril point on as you can see
it matches up really nicely.
Further down in the course you'll you'll learn how to do it for any value.
It doesn't have to be like 2.2.
You'll learn how to or basically operate.
And you cut off here just create your own cut of and understand anything how to do anything.
But here is just very convenient that in this chart is very point two percent so you just need to do
your center.
You're a mean plus two standard deviations.
And so that will be the value after which like you know hundreds like I'm doing against engineers with
say hundred seventy centimeter plus 10 centimeters and or 20 centimeters and then everybody over that
will be 2.2 percent.
That type of thing.
So we just need to take I mean in this case it's zero but an hour because it's not zero.
So I mean plus one or two standard deviations and that means that will be this value that's already
here and that will be everything to the right anybody Tola then that will fall and the 2.2 percent.
So hopefully you're able to pick up on that.
Another approach would have been to generate the distributions first and then from then pick out the
2.2 percent.
But that is kind of like a bit of a trap because that's not the population that's the sample.
And here it's asking and the challenge is saying totalist of in that population.
So if you generate the distributions first that will be just samples rather than populations.
So let's do that let's do what we planned.
We're going to say.
I mean Plus we'll all two times stand deviation and go.
So seventy four point nine inches and sixty nine point one inches.
That's what we need.
And you know what I'm going to do the same thing but I'm going to do it for centimeters as well so if
you did it in centimeters and also because I'm just curious real curious 175 do I fall into that 2.2
percent.
Probably not.
When do you fall into the 2.2 percent when if we have very tall students taking this course.
All right seven point four.
All right.
For men it's 190 centimeters.
And for women 160 one point eight sixty one point eight.
And standing ovation six point nine.
All right so.
Aha.
Interesting.
Are we sure about this hundred sixty one point six or nine.
Very interesting so for men or in inches or in centimeters if you are seventy four point nine inches
or taller or 190 point three inches or taller.
If you are living in the U.S. or if you live in the US you fall in the top 2.2 percent of men in terms
of height for women.
You need to be sixty nine point one inches tall or a hundred and seventy five point six centimeters
tall.
OK.
So if you know any friends who are very tall ask them how told they are and tell them if they fall in
the 2.2 percent.
And we're going to now proceed.
So that was that part of the challenge where they were asking about the cutoff so obviously they need
that for us to understand.
You know the is probably for the Close to understand how to cut the clothes or how to what to what to
create for the cause.
Maybe maybe somebody needed that there and that probably is not for the financial model.
That's probably for the clothes part.
Now we're going to be solving the parts.
Let's go back to the challenge here.
When we saw the part where we need should not two three means you create two distributions.
So basically samples we need samples I should have written samples to make it more like clear what we're
doing.
But a normal distribution of a thousand or or 1000 oversoul a sample from a normal distribution which
contains a thousand observations for heights.
And then in the U.S. and same for female So we're going to be using a function.
And you find that function norm in PS..
Let's let's see how we're going to do men here are going to create the distribution for men here.
Let's deal with men first and then it will be just easier to then create the same wishes for women.
Once we know that approach.
All right so we're going to do the distribution.
So Norm Dauth in in Excel 2010 using an older version it's Norm interval in fact the norm in them just
do Rande brackets mean you can just pointed over here.
No yes.
No this one.
There you go.
And second edition pointed over there.
Close your brackets enter.
And this is I think is a good challenge because it's always useful to know how to work with Excel and
distributions and stuff.
So one a thousand cells go drag it down.
We started one so we need to get to 1000 and 1.
Whoa whoa whoa whoa.
I mean they're there.
That should be there.
Count 1000.
What's going on.
Oh whoops.
OK.
Yeah I forgot completely forgot you need to press a for to lock it in and look that one in as well.
So put the dollar signs.
If you're not if you're not putting it in manually if you're just pointing to a cell because if you
go out once you go down what's happening is the formula is going down as well.
You can see like that I don't want that we want it to be locked.
If you click for we'll just lock it then there's just pastes all.
I'll repeat that sorry.
I had my press conference C then I press control shift on my Windows PC and then I press down it selects
hold the rows and then I press control V.
So is this the same as redoing that operation or just like.
And so here I want to actually do rounds because nobody measures heights in that many decimal coins
so I got a two to one digit.
Just check that area.
So again consulship down Enter go just I'm just saying the shortcuts in case somebody doesn't know them
and so we can all follow along together.
If you know them that's that's great.
They are very useful.
OK.
So that's men and this is what the sample is.
And if you notice every time I change any cells if I click to enter I have to enter they all update.
So if you want to avoid that then you just need to right click copy and then you pay special and you
pays just the values like that.
Once you've pasted the values now you can see that there are no normal formulas.
If I change cells nothing happens.
We're actually going to keep the formulas because that will help us win and we want the dynamic chart.
So just keep them for now you'll see what that means.
OK.
That's it.
We supply it.
It's ready.
And let's just say the same thing for women.
So I want to say women here.
And then what I'm going to do is I'm going to copy this formula pasted in but now I'm going to replace
this so not be two but is actually four women it's B three.
There you go.
And for the standard missions for women it's three.
All done.
Copy.
Now I'm going to go to the bottom and sort of like scrolling down if I'm also going to press Kontrol
down go from here contrl shift up press enter and then we go there all popular No.
And that's pretty much it.
So now you just supply this answer or if you're doing in centimeters you supply this answer and you
supply these two distributions.
Probably if you're supplying this to your manager it's best to get rid of the formulas.
So what I would suggest is you take these paste copy put them in a new sheet and just right click pay
special and values.
As we discussed and now you can you know supply these values these are normally normally just a.
But now what you want to do is you want to actually check that they're normally distributed.
And in fact we want to build the distribution charge because like I mentioned in the Hince part of the
challenge that if you're taking this course you're probably a curious person.
You want to learn more and in like engage your brain and you wouldn't go past opportunity to create
the charge.
So this is all for the challenge.
But for now I'm just going to summarize something I'm going to create the charts and I'm sure you can
enjoy that as well.
So how do we create these charts.
How do we visualize as well let's give it a go.
Just off the bat.
Just go insert bam like one of these.
Is that a normal distribution.
Do you need to go running to your manager saying that you sent them the wrong file and or you sent them
incorrect values.
Doesn't look like a normal distribution at all.
Well what is going on here.
Well the thing that's going on here is we got to understand what is being plotted on bottom.
You just have the number of the observation on that top over here.
You see these values plotted so seventy point nine that's over there then sixty nine point two 73 points
just like zigzagging me between these values is where you have a thousand values here and it's just
plodding these values like that.
And it's a good kind of like verification that it's distributed.
Looks like it's distributed around I'll mean sixty nine point one so the mean are here if you look at
the horizontal line is six and I'd buy one and send ovations 2.9 so like up and down sometimes a bit
further up sometimes a bit further down.
But this is not what we wanted to see.
What we want to see is a beautiful bell shaped curve.
That's what we want to see.
How do we create that.
Well there are two ways.
Well first of all we can look at this and create a probability density function.
So we remember we talked about those because this is a continuous variable we would create a pre-build
and subconscious.
On another hand we don't have to because we can create we just can put these in bins and then create
a new set of pre-build dysfunction just create a b and chart so it's up to you which one you want to
do.
I'm going to do the bins simply because it's easier and more but not more important but so because this
is these are not the populations these are samples normally for samples which you do is you create them
the bins right.
If we were creating the building instruction from these like hinting towards the population then yes.
But for these that just create the beans it's just going to be faster.
OK.
So let's have a look.
All right so there is going to be two ways of doing it.
Let's start with method number one which is the Microsoft Excel or the Excel recommended one.
So the real ones are committed by Microsoft so I'm creating new tabs here and what we're going to do
is we're going to either go to a file if you're using Excel 2010 and options and you need to make sure
in the Add ins you have analysis tool packs it's probably going to be somewhere here.
Just make sure you have it enabled.
So you just click on it here and then you click go and then you'll get enabled and then you'll be here.
So once you have analysis to pack.
Now we're talking.
Now you can actually do a bit more advanced stuff.
So we need to create Albion's for so probably Let's make some space here.
Well let's Dobyns before because there are going to be shared between men and women and we're going
to start with 50 inches if you're working in centimeters and you need to come up with your own range
but just take that kind of like the very low.
You might have as a height and very very tall person.
So we're going to in inches are going to go from 50 to 100.
OK.
You go 50 to 100 and all next is just magic.
You just go to data.
You have this new button here.
Data analysis so that data analysis.
And what we're going to do is we're just going to click on that button here just scroll down and find
histogram click OK select input range input ranges Your these these values so select that I press control
shop down to get all of them like that.
And and you've been Range.
Select this range.
Voila.
Now output range.
That's where you want to put it.
By default it's going to be a new workbook or new worksheet just put output range and I will like to
put it here.
And just also check chart output so you can you'll get a chart and output and click OK and voila they
have it you've got your You've got a bin you frequency and you've got your lovely lovely distribution.
That's all you needed to do.
I mean a bit too much space.
You probably should because we're doing it this way this Excel way.
So there we go that's it.
But the history here.
And then we can do the same thing for women.
Maybe you can just make this space here.
OK.
So same thing for women.
Data Analysis histogram just need to change the input range.
There we go.
And output range.
Put it somewhere here for example and see if that works.
That's right because I move the bins I think I move the bins click OK.
All right.
Move my chart over here.
That's OK as well.
There we go.
So if you put them side by side or in fact you can just copy the site and another data element here.
No this is new select data.
There you go.
So that's the frequency so we want to rename that.
We want to name it to men and we want to add a new one.
And to call it women.
And here we going to select frequency here I like that.
Things like that OK.
OK.
And they would go see have them on one chart and that's done.
So you're going to justice charge to look a bit better but generally as we disconnected this distribution
is narrower taller.
This one is wider.
So that's how you create these.
The only problem we can see.
Now if the value if I just click enter anywhere in any cell the values update here but they don't update
on the histogram.
And that's a drawback of this method.
I would just like running short on time in this tutorial.
I will record a separate video so just check the next video and then I'll show you how to do it so that
they're dynamic and will be a bit more interesting.
You can play around with that.
So I hope you enjoy this tutorial and hopefully you also had similar results with your challenge and
I'll see you next time.
Until then have reanalyzing.