Hello welcome back to a course on statistics.
Today we got a very interesting topic.
The one teld and to tell tests and I got to say that this is the topic that I personally struggle with
quite a lot.
Just the way the intuition behind it the thinking about it and what I want to convey in this tutorial
is my take on it like I'm not an expert in statistics and not the world expert on OneTel and to tell
tests but I have done thorough research into this to help me better understand what's going on and so
I'm going to share you my understanding of the intuition behind these things and why they're different
and how this all works.
And then I'll direct you at a very interesting article I found about OneTel.
And to tell tests and you can read more there and that will help you form your own vision if if you
think that it might be a bit different to mine.
So let's have a look here we've got a one tailed test.
So this is the hypothesis testing that we've been doing all along.
And even though that we haven't been explicitly specifying that it's a one tell us that's essentially
what we've been doing we've been stating an all hypothesis which was usually something along the lines
of the number of households with I-pads used to be this has it increased or has decreased.
And so in that case in those cases the hypothesis would be no it has not increased.
So what's what we're seeing here.
No the null hypothesis.
No the number of people or households with I-pads has not increased so much less or less than or equal
to.
I don't know let's say 80 percent whatever it was and the alternative hypothesis.
Yes it has increased.
And then we would just see where our sample falls in the sampling distribution.
And if it falls in the rejection region we reject that hypothesis.
Same thing on the left would do the same if there was a left tell us if we're looking at the kind of
the opposite sort of it was increasing.
Now what to tell test is is when you want to check if the number of people or number of households with
I-pads hasn't necessarily increase or decrease.
You want to just check if it's changed.
You want to see if over time or whatever other effects or other marketing was happening if if something
had an effect that changed the underlying parameter in the population.
So you want to in this case you want to see.
All right so the number of people with a number of households with iPads it was 80 percent.
Now we want to see if it's changed.
It could be greater or it could be less.
And that's a two tailed test.
And so the essential thing and this is what I was always struggling with.
The essential thing to think is that oh well if I can prove that the number of households with iPads
has increased then obviously it has changed.
So it should be easier for me to run a two tailed test than a OneTel test because ultimately I have
two options.
I can I can just prove that it's increased or I can prove that it's decreased and therefore it's just
going to be easier for me is going to be twice as easy for me to prove the to tell test or reject the
null hypothesis and into shelters than in a OneTel test.
However as it turns out that's not the case in statistics.
It's actually harder to prove.
Hate to tell.
So what you do in a tootle test is actually you take doses.
Statistical significance of 5 percent and you have to split it between the two tells so you only get
two and a hops and here and you only get to the house and here.
And so it turns out that now when you do your calculations and you pick your sample from the population
and then you find out where that means the sample falls it might fall here or here.
Now it's much harder for you to reject the null hypothesis because the mineral might fall right over
here right next so it might fall and the 4 percent band.
And in the OneTel test you would have rejected the null hypothesis but to tell test you don't get to
reject the hypoth hypothesis because you need to the meaningful and to an Hoppus and that as the main
question of today's internals Why does it work like.
Why is it so counter-intuitive that a to tail test is actually stricter than a one tail test.
So let's have a look here Richard try understand this based on a on a real example like something odd
could happen in the real world and that should hopefully clear things up.
Let's say we are producing a drug that helps people increase their attention span.
So let's say on average in world population the attention span is about 40 minutes.
And I'm not sure of probably these numbers are incorrect because I'm just making them up.
But let's just say for argument's sake that on average a person has an attention span of about 40 minutes
with a standard deviation in our population of about 20 minutes.
So that's that's our Those are the parameters of our population.
And so when we plot these sampling distributions they will have a 40 minute mean and that there's some
deviation won't be 20 minutes of course because that's the it'll depend on the sample size.
So let's say we pick.
We want to test does this drug increase.
We specifically designed this drug to increase the attention span of people and we want to test if it's
working if it's we want to see if it's increasing the attention span of people so we have a sample of
say 100 people and we want to see if the drug has increased.
There is increasing attention span.
And so in our case and we got in that sample we got a mean of 45 minutes for the attention span.
So in our case the sampling distribution will have a mean of 40 minutes just as the population standard
deviation will be 20 divided by square root of 100 so 20 divided by 10 is to the standard deviation
here.
And we know that's the value that we've measured in our sample is 45 so it falls somewhere here on the
right.
So the question is can we reject the null hypothesis.
The null hypothesis is that no in the OneTel test no.
And so the mean of the population assuming that the drug has no effect would be like if all the people
in the world would take this drug and it will have no effect then their population would still stay
as it is it would still stay at 40.
So but in our case once it has we say it's less than or equal to 40 and the standard deviation.
And that's it.
And the alternative hypothesis is that no it's increased.
And so in that case we just need to prove that.
OK.
We just need to check if it falls into this rejection area.
But the question there is what's to say that our drug actually have a beneficial effect on attention
span.
What if our drug actually does the opposite.
What if our drug decreases the attention span.
There is no law of physics that would suggest that that is not possible.
There is no 100 percent proof that this drug cannot actually reduce attention span.
And that's what a to tell test actually.
So checks for actual implies that in cases when you cannot state with and this is again how I understand
it in cases where you can state with absolute confidence that the effect has to be on one side of the
spectrum you need to test for it to tell a test because what could have happened is actually your drug
is not just increasing but it's also it could also be decreasing the attention span.
And so that's what you need to be checking for in a.
In that case and so only situations where it can.
Again in my opinion only situations where you should do a OneTel test is where you can justify that
the why it has to be a OneTel test that it's not an option for the effect to be in either direction.
And that's that's when you do a OneTel test in Inuk in the case when you're not sure about that.
It's just safer to go over to tell test and hopefully that makes it a bit clearer or why a to tell test
is harder to prove than a OneTel test.
And that's because no one will test you.
You're kind of assuming that you have prior knowledge you kind of assuming that you're ready.
This is not even possible that this is not even an option that you just want to check that this is happening
and to tell test your.
And you don't have the knowledge or you're not allowing yourself to kind of make that assumption and
therefore you have to deal with both sides of the tale.
So again this is a very it's a bit of a counterintuitive topic but at the same time it is a very gray
area that as you can see it's easier to prove a OneTel test.
And so researchers can be prone to actually doing OneTel tests just to get that P-value and to get their
research published and to get the research correct.
I'm not saying that all researchers do this but it can be a problem.
It can be a temptation to do that but it's also always important to look at what's going on what's actually
going on.
What do you need to be testing and what kind of preexisting knowledge and assumptions can you have and
can you make.
And we'll see an example of this in the next tutorial when we're looking at an actual analytics challenge.
But for now if you'd like to read more on this topic we'd like to direct you to this blog it's called
OneTel versus to tell tests.
Does it matter.
Is by Alex or cat.
Here's the link.
You will notice that it is for advertising for like ads on digital ads and stuff like that.
But at the same time all of those hold the same concepts can apply for it can apply to any type of problem
is just an interesting read in a while like it is because Alex actually interviewed quite a lot of specialists
in the area and got their opinions and there's a lot of opinions there.
So in this tutorial you just got my opinion and have a look there and you'll find out find when many
more opinions and help.
Hopefully that will help you develop your own understanding of what tell'd and to tell us.
And definitely we'll practice this in the next tutorial so that will help you even further solidify
that knowledge and I hope you enjoyed this tutorial and look for the next step.
Until then happy analyzing.