Hello and welcome back to the course on statistics.
Today's a quick tutorial to introduce the normal distribution.
So let's dive straight in.
Here is the normal distribution.
This is what it looks like sometimes called the Bell Curve but that's a bit of a stretch because there's
a lot of distributions that have the same shape.
The main definition of the normal distribution is its equation.
That's the equation for the probability density function so it is a continuous distribution as we can
see where they're going to go into detail that's just to say that there is an equation that describes
distribution.
And as you can see it includes Sigma.
So our standard deviation Sigma squared variance or standard deviation squared.
And it also includes myu which is our center our median what these numbers mean here are the probabilities
of a random variable which is following the normal distribution to be to actually end up like are coming
from one of these areas are to be being in these ranges.
So remember we spoke about the probability for it like for a continuous distribution.
We help build the density function hence the P over there.
You can't say exactly that the probability of being over here or picking a random variable that's going
to be here you cannot tell what the perimeter of that is because we're going to be zero.
But you can tell what the probability of a certain range is.
Well and when you see images of the normal distribution you'll see that it's usually like broken down
into these ranges already so it's if me the mean here is zero.
In this case it's zero.
But you could it could be immune so it's totally fine if it's not center on the earth center on me.
Then this formula will still apply and then from myu you go right like standard deviation.
Remember we said you can add standard deviations to your mean because they're the same units or you
subtract one standard deviation so the probability of a variable falling between zero and one standard
deviation is always going to thirty four point one percent for normal distribution or Usually what people
say is probability of a variable falling between minus 1 second deviation and one second deviation is
sixty eight point two percent probability of falling between minus two standard deviations and two standard
deviations is ninety five point six percent and the probability of falling between minus two standard
deviations and two standard vision.
So in this whole area here is about 95 percent and so on.
So those are a given for you and me and we'll discuss more about the standard or the normal distribution
further down the course.
But the question is why is it so popular why is it so so amazing what's so great about the normal distribution.
Well what's great about it is that it comes up a lot in the world and things are just just happened
to be distributed normally.
And there's actually a reason behind it.
While some of these things there's a reason behind it so for instance here you've got an example of
what height the heights of a man on the left and heights of women on the right.
So you can see that there are approximately normally distributed.
These are 20 year old people and so the more people you have in your decision in your sample the better
it will approximate to a normal distribution.
And there's there's lots of other events for instance.
Here's one I thought you would be interested to know that the probability density function of a ground
state in a quantum harmonic oscillator is exactly normally distributed so I just read that out from
Wikipedia but it just stands to say that this is maybe an approximate normal distribution but they are
things in the world.
For instance in quantum mechanics which are exactly normally distributed which is just mind boggling.
Like why would it be exactly normally distributed.
Very interesting.
When I mentioned that there are some things that we can explain why it's happening this way.
That's when we apply the Central Limit Theorem.
The central limit theorem is something we will cover often this course it's very exciting very exciting
topics one of the most powerful if not the most powerful theorems in mathematics in the whole of mathematics
and that is exactly because it deals with the normal distribution.
And when you combine the two central limit theorem and normal disruption it kind of explains a lot of
things that we see in the world why they're normally distributed and therefore why we're able to really
progress further with research and lots of these things because we can leverage the normal normality
of those things so that's yet to come in for a down discourse.
It will be very exciting.
But for now there's a quick quick introduction to the distribution.
And yeah so now we can move on for the rest of the trolls in the section.
Hope you enjoyed this trial.
And until next time happy analyzing.