Hey guys it's Kiril here.
I just thought I'd quickly pop into the course.
I hope I'm not disrupting your flow.
I just wanted to show you an example of how values can be used or misuse or create ambiguity just like
what we talked about in the previous tutorial.
So here I went to the pharmacy in Australia and I bought this just to show you.
So have a look.
Is it cold right.
It's day and night and here on the right.
Let me show you just here on the right you can see it says clinically proven.
And then here it says what does it say clinically proven to shorten your call.
So you see that purple sign over there.
Clinically proven to Schorno cold.
That's that's awesome but that's exactly what we're talking about.
They've proven that it shortens the cold but by how much.
There's no there's no mention of the magnitude of the effect if you look at this whole box.
If you look at the back of the box this is like barrooms anywhere you look on the box.
You won't find how what the effect is.
They just they've proven you know they got a p value of less than 5 percent or less than 1 percent and
you know that's it's just like as we are doing the hypothesis testing part of course you know they've
proven that it has reduced or it is lower for for people who take this medicine but what's the magnitude
of the fact is no mention of that so that's what you're going to be careful of.
And you know like things like this it's marketing it's it's you know it's a catchy term and it's ok.
Like I guess if they want to just sell the product and then maybe if they're diligent about it they
can follow up on another website they might have someone more information about this.
But in business of course when you're the one making the gain the insides and creating that or like
deriving insights and communicating them and some people are relying on your insides to make business
decisions you have to be very careful about OK it's slower or is greater but what does that mean.
What is the what we're after and what does that mean like in terms of the magnitude of the effect and
how can we apply this in terms of operations or whatever we're estimating.
So there you go just be careful with these values if you use them wisely.
They can totally serve your purpose and really be a very powerful tool in your toolkit.
And I'll Accorsi on NEXT.
Until then happy analyzing.