Hi,
guys.
Welcome backs In this video,
we're going to discuss option buttons,
and sometimes they're cold radio buttons,
so option buttons enable us to create lists.
However,
unlike the list boxes,
for example,
where only one list box would contain the whole list in case of option buttons.
If you've got a list,
you need to ah,
sign an option button to each item in the list.
Okay,
so let's check here the option buttons that I've got here,
inserted on the sheet.
If I right click on that PCs option button on,
I go to former control.
I'll see that it on option button would have only one,
ah,
inputs that you need to give to it,
which is the selling.
And if we check the selling here,
it's the Selby 20 in the analysis time,
okay?
And,
ah,
if we check the option button Okay,
we will see that in the analysis.
Stab in Selby 20.
It's got the number once it's produced the number one in the selling,
and if we check laptops,
it's produced the number two,
and if you check tablets,
it's produced the number three.
The reason for that is that the option button for PCs is the first option button that has
been inserted on the sheet on This is why it produces the number one and the second one
here.
Laptops has been inserted second in order of insertion on the sheet.
This is why produces number two and tablets has been asserted.
Third,
and this is why produces the number three and so on and so forth.
So let's see how we can insert an option button.
We would need to go to the developer.
Tab on the ribbon will click on Insert on.
Then we will click on Option Button.
We will dro our option button here.
Then we're going to right click on it and click on Edit Texts were gonna name that Mobil's
for the fourth item in the list.
Now I'm going to right click on it to format it,
and what we will see here is that Excel as recognized.
I've got already option buttons on this sheet,
and they are assigned.
The selling could be 20 so it's actually assigned at the cell link of B 20.
In the analysis,
stab to the fourth option,
but of inserted for Mobil's,
so actually was Excel was smart enough to determine that I've already got option buttons.
So,
um,
you know what most probably need this option button to be.
Ah,
having this selling here the same selling as the previous three.
Okay,
so a press OK here,
and I'll check the option button for Mobil's,
as you can see her because it was inserted as the fourth option button s.
So it's produced the number four here on the selling.
Another way to create an option button is by copying and existing one.
So I'm gonna select the my Mobil's option button here by right clicking on it and then left
clicking on the edge.
And then if I press my control key,
you'll see that there is a plus sign here appearing on my cursor.
And if I,
uh,
press my left mouse button and drag this option button and then you can see her that by
pressing my control and my left most click,
I can put it anywhere on the sheet over.
If I also in addition to my control and left mouse button,
I pressed this shift key on my keyboard.
I can make sure that I can Onley copy it ah,
aligned with with the original one,
either horizontally or vertically.
Okay,
so if you press your shift while pressing your control and left click,
you can make sure that it's aligned with the previous option button.
And now I'm gonna release my left.
Most click as you can see her.
It's been copied,
and it's got the same name as the original one that we've copied from.
If we right,
click on it and go to former Control if you consider that it's ah,
been given the same cell link as the previous one.
And if you check that option,
button the new one here,
you can see area that it's producing the number five on the selling because this is the
fifth option button there's been inserted on the sheet.
I'm gonna delete it because we don't need it anymore.
You can also copy several option buttons at the same time.
So more than one option button you can right click on one of them and then,
while pressing your shift key,
you're going to right click on the others year to select them on.
Then you're gonna press your control key,
and you're going to see this plus sign our new cursor,
you're gonna copy them by dragging them whether you're left,
click and while pressing your control key.
And if you need them to be aligned either horizontally or vertically with the previous ones
,
you compress your shift key as well.
In addition to your control.
Unless Les Miles Button,
you're gonna release your left click here and there you go.
They have been copied.
And,
of course,
they're going to be linked to the same cell link just as we copy the single option bun.
Okay,
I'm gonna delete them now,
guys,
because we don't need them.
One more thing I need to explain here is that sometimes when you insert an option button
because Excel considers your objects to be in different liars.
So sometimes when you insert the option button,
it would be in the layer in the very back.
So I mean,
I've inserted the option,
but in here,
But in this case it was in the layer that is in the front.
However,
let's put it in the layer that is in the very back by going to order here and then put it
on centre back.
So sometimes,
if you sometimes when you insert an option,
but it would be in the layer in the very back.
So if you try to put it on top of your chart here or in top of an object on top of a shape
,
for example,
any other object,
it would be in the very back,
so you won't be able to see it.
So in this case,
what you need to do is to right click on it and go to order.
And then,
uh,
you're going to bring it to front.
To this way.
It would be in the layer in the very front on your,
uh,
off your sheet here and you be able to put it on top off another object,
which in this case,
is the chart.