one more thing I need to show you is that weaken group option buttons together so that we
can deal with them as one unit so they can be moved together.
For example,
is one unit or copy together as one unit as well?
How we can do that is by selecting all the option buttons.
So I'm going to right click on one of them here and then press my shift key and then right
,
click,
right click,
right click on the others here.
And then I'm gonna go to the format top on the ribbon.
I'm going to click on the group,
but in here,
I'm gonna click group again.
Okay?
And now,
as you can see her,
they have been grouped together,
okay?
And they can be moved as one unit together,
and we ca Nhan group them as well by following the same steps.
Except we click on one group instead of group.
Okay,
I So one more thing I want to show you is how to align the ocean buttons if they are
scattered.
So when I'm going to do,
I'm gonna scratch them.
I'm bright clicking here on my tablets and dragging with my right click on.
Then I'm going to click on move here.
When I get this menu menu on,
I'm going to do the same thing with my PCs.
And now I'm going to select my Mobil's option button here would by right clicking and
pressing on the edge here.
And because this is the first option button there has been selected all the other option
buttons.
I'm just selecting the other ones here,
Um,
and all the option.
Other option buttons will be aligned to,
ah,
to this Mobil's option that I'm gonna line to the left edge of the Mobil's option button so
they'd be all aligned vertically to that.
It's left edge going electric on format here on the ribbon.
And then I'm going to click on a line and then press a line left.
And now they they have been all aligned Teoh,
the left edge of Mobil's.
There are also other options here for a line center.
Align right and you know,
different options.
Feel free guys to experiment with them.
Another option is well.
That you can do is that you can distribute them vertically.
Ah,
and this is to create equal spaces between them.
However,
these equal spaces are created between their top edges and their top,
the top edge of one of them and the bottom edge of the other here.
So this is why,
actually,
there isn't unequal space between oldest circles here,
so all the circus don't have equal spaces between them.
So what you need to do in this case is to select all of them and give them,
um,
a unified size.
So I'm going to give them,
give them a size,
for example.
But off half an inch by an inch,
So now they all have the same size.
Okay,
I'm gonna click on a line again,
and then I'm going to click on distribute vertically.
And now,
as you can see here,
all the circles have equal spaces between them.
Okay.
Okay,
guys.
So I'm gonna select all my option buttons here by pressing the control key.
And while pressing the control key,
I'm going to right click on each of them.
And then I'm gonna left click and try to drag them.
And as you can see here,
I can put them just about anywhere on the worksheet.
They can move freely.
Okay?
and there is an option here that you want to show you.
I'm going to go to the former tub on the ribbon.
I'm gonna click on a line and then I'm going to click on snap to grid.
Okay,
on.
And as you can see here,
there is ah,
some sort of ah,
green lining around the shape here on the borders.
So that means that the option is turned on.
And if you try to move them this way,
if you try to move your option buns after ah,
selecting snap to grid,
you can see here that they cannot move Freedy as they were doing previously.
They need to be aligned to the the Excel grid,
so they need to be aligned vertically here to a column,
for example.
Okay,
s So this is another option that you can use while moving your ah,
your option buttons or your or any shape actually in excel to make sure that it aligns with
the grit.
Okay,
so thank you guys for watching this video and please follow me on to the next video