Hi,
guys.
Welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss group boxes.
So group boxes enable you to create a different groups of option Dutton's so that each
group would have ah,
separate selling.
So,
as you can see here,
I've got to group boxes.
And in each one,
I've got three option buttons,
okay?
And each group of option buttons housed in a group box have a different cell link.
So,
as you can see here,
the first,
uh,
group,
it has this the selling for the one for that selling yellow,
as you can see on the second group,
has ah,
selling quid that cell in blue.
Okay,
so this is useful if you want to create,
like,
two different filters on your charts,
like you'd have ah,
filter for the region and other filter for the product type,
for example.
Okay.
And of course,
we have explained how you can control charts with option buttons on the previous video,
so I'm going to show you how you can do that.
First of all,
you're going to go to the developer tab,
you're going to click on insert,
and then you're gonna click on this icon here for group books,
The one having X y Z on it.
And you're gonna draw your group bucks by dragging with your left most button on.
Then we're gonna insert an option button here,
and I'm gonna assign ah,
link cell to it.
I'm gonna great click and click on formal control,
and I'm gonna put a selling for it here and now.
If you click that option button,
it gives us the number one.
And this is ah,
separated from the others.
And as you can see here,
although this is the seventh option,
but the husband inserted because it's in a group box of its own and the others are in group
box of their own.
You know,
Excel starts counting again from one on the linked seller on the selling.
Okay,
You know,
if you insert the other option button here Ah,
and if you right click on it,
you will see that Excel will automatically pick up the links sell here or the cell link.
OK,
it will pick up the same cell link as this one eyes the one that this one had.
Okay,
this is because you have inserted it in the same group box.
So Excel was smart enough to know that because the 2nd 1 was inserted in the same group box
that you need to ah,
link it to the same Ah,
cell or two you need to make it uses the same cell linker.
Okay,
so this is guy guys,
how you can use group boxes to create different groups of option buttons.
So thank you,
guys for watching this video and please follow me unto the following.