Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to speak about slicer.
So slicers are actually user friendly filters and the enable us to filter are pivot tables
and thus adding interactivity to our dashboards this way,
because we can filter the data that is shown on our pivot tables.
And this data would be linked to other elements in our dashboard and thus changing the data
appearing on our dashboard,
changing the numbers on our charts and so on slicers are only available starting from Excel
2000 ton.
Now let's see how we can insert a slicer.
So you need to select any cell inside your pivot table and then go to the analyze tab on
the ribbon,
click on insert slicer and then select which field in the pivot table you would like to
filter.
So here,
for example,
I'm going to select the country because I want a filter my pivot table using the country on
.
I'm gonna get the same slicer that I've got here on the right hand side,
which is the one filtering the country's.
So if you click OK,
here,
you're able to insert a slicer that filters your countries So now you can change your
countries here,
and you can see here that whatever countries you filter for here on the slicer are
reflected on the pivot table here.
And note also that the filtration on your slicer works,
even if that particular field is not put as a filter field on your pivot table,
so you can see here the country is not.
He filter field on the pivot table,
and still the slicer works,
so I'll just delete that one because we've got a similar one here at the top.
Now let's speak about slicer formatting,
because you can actually change the colors of your slicers so you can select your slicer.
Go to options here,
and you can select a different color for your slicer.
You can also change the color of multiple slicers by selecting one of them president
control and selecting the other and selecting a different color.
As you can see here.
Also,
if you click on this arrow here and you can click on new slicer style,
you can create your own custom slicer style,
the own colors,
your own everything.
So feel free to experiment with these options because you can color the slicer and make it
suit your own branding.
You can also make your slicer control multiple pivot tables.
So here at the moment,
this particular slicer only controls this pivot table here on the left and we get another
pivot table here on the right.
This pivot table is called pivot table two,
and this one is called pivot Table one.
So if you right click on your slicer and click on report connections because here that this
Leiser is connected only to pivot table one if you check pivot table two and click OK,
you're gonna be able to control both.
Pivot Table says you can see here when I do a change on the year the year gets changed on
both pivot tables and you can do the same as well for this one so as to make the country
change on both off them at the same time.
However,
please note that in order to make a slicer control multiple pivot tables,
you need to have all the pivot tables having their data source from the same source,
so they need to all have the same data source,
so they need to be all casing from the same table.
OK,
so I've got both these pivot tables here.
They're getting their data source from this table here on the left.
If it had been the case that each one of them had a different data source,
you will not be able to control them using the same slicer,
at least without involving V v A and without having some code to do it for you also,
you can actually select multiple items on your slicer at the same time.
So here I'm selecting the year 2012 I compress control and select 2013 as well.
So now on filtering with the data for both 2011 and 2000 and 13 You can also use the shift
key to select multiple contiguous years or multiple contiguous items on your slicer.
So here I'm selecting 2011.
If you press the shift key and select 2013 you will select everything from 2011 till 2013.
So all these contiguous items You can also select multiple contiguous items by clicking on
dragging.
So if you click 2011 and drag while clicking until 2013 you're able to select all these
contiguous years.
You could also remove all the filters by clicking on this red button here the clear filter
button,
and this will actually select all the items on the slicer.
So currently we're selecting all the years from 2011 to 2014.
Because we've removed any filtration,
you could also remove their headers.
So basically,
as you could see previously,
there was no red button here.
And that is because this slicer had its header removed so you can remove its header by
right clicking on the slicer,
clicking on slicer settings year and then until the display header button and click.
OK,
this removes the headers,
and this could be required sometimes because you're filters are pretty obvious.
So here it is obvious that 2000 of in 2012 13 and forcing our years,
so maybe you don't need the year header and the slicer looks sleeker this way and also here
on this slicer,
we could remove the Hatter for the country because it is very obvious that Australia,
Canada,
the UK and USA are countries.
You could also,
of course,
change their sizes using this handle here.
So you congee just Ah,
expand them and shrink them.
And you can also go to the options tab here on the ribbon after selecting your slicer to
make them have multiple columns.
So,
as you can see here,
there's an option for changing the number of columns.
So here you could have two columns.
You can have three columns.
So if you have a lot of items,
this could be useful for you.
And this also enables you to have or you filters or isn't Lee beside each other so you can
shrink your slicer after having multiple columns trinket like that,
and have your data arranged in a horizontal fashion instead of a vertical fashion.
Okay,
guys,
So that sit for slicers?
Thank you very much for watching this video and I'll see on the next one.