Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to speak about pivot charts.
So first of all,
let's see how to insert a pivot short.
So to insert a pivot chart,
you can click inside your table or your data clicking on any cell in your data on.
Then go to the insert tab on the ribbon here and click on pivot chart,
and then you're going to click on Pivot short again.
And now,
as you can see here,
your table or your data range is ah labeled at the moment.
Okay,
so you can click,
OK,
and you private chart is going to be inserted on.
Also,
you're gonna have a pivot table inserted with your pivot short,
and then you can start populating your pivot chart so you can put the country here on the
the categories access,
and also you can put the order amount for example on the values.
And as you can see here,
both the pivot table and the pivot short are being populated with the data.
Another way to insert a pivot chart is to click on any cell inside your data and then go to
the insert tab here on the ribbon Click on recommended charts and you'll find that
recommended charts Button Onley in Excel 2013 and 2016.
So if you click on that,
you can see here that you've got some suggested charts here and all these charts the are
having two headed arrows in almost a 90 degree there.
Um,
these charts axity are pivot shorts.
Okay,
so this logo here having to had it arrows means that you're going to insert a pivot short.
So here,
if I click Okay,
this one will insert a pivot chart.
This is a some of your butt country.
This is meaningless.
Actually,
no,
I don't want the order.
I d by country as well.
Maybe the units sold by country soul Insert that one and click.
OK,
as you can see here in a new sheet,
a chart husband inserted with a pivot table as well.
Ok,
one more thing I want to tell you as well is that pivot shorts and pivot tables are
connected.
So actually,
each pair of pivot chart and pivot table is interconnected.
So that means that this pivot chart is connected to this pivot table.
So as you can see here.
If I filter on Australia,
for example,
on the pivot table,
My selection off Australia gets reflected on the pivot short.
But if you check the other pivot table pivot chart combo,
this has not been affected.
The this combo Although it's reading from the same data set from the same rayo data from
the same table,
it's not been affected by the filtration on this pivot table.
OK,
so here we can filter for Canada as well,
for example and the pivot chart is gonna be affected here.
But actually the other pivot table pivot chart combo,
it's not gonna be effective.
Okay,
so that's something to note as well.
One more thing I want to talk about here,
which is actually what distinguishes a pivot chart from a normal chart is actually field
buttons.
So,
as you can see here,
there some buttons on the chart.
Okay,
these field buttons can allow us to actually filter are pivot chart and this effects are
pivot table as well.
So I conforto here for Canada,
for example,
and this effects both the pivot chart and that pivot table.
OK,
And if you would like to hide or on hide this field buttons,
you can right click on a field button.
Okay.
And you can either hide just this one button here by clicking on hide value feel button on
chart,
or you can hide all field buttons on charts.
If you click on this,
this is gonna hide all that fueled buttons on the chart.
If you would like to own,
hide them again,
just select your chart and then go to the analyze tab on the ribbon.
And here you can actually untech the hide.
All and all of them will be,
uh,
on hidden okay.
Or you can actually hide them one by one.
Ah,
by actually unthinking the show.
button of each of them.
OK,
so show this if you want ticket is gonna hide it.
Okay,
so that's how you can use feel buttons and hide and a non hide them.
One more tip you'd like to tell you as well is that when creating dashboards usually are
gonna have your pivot tables and pivot charts on different cheats because you would have
your pivot tables on your analysis sheet,
for example,
and you would have your pivot chart on your dashboard cheat or on the sheet that would be
actually facing your customer or the interface of the dashboard.
So if you'd like to move your pivot chart,
you can select your pivot chart on press control and X on your keyboard for for cutting.
And then you can go to another sheet and paste that using control and V on your keyboard.
You can also select your pivot charts.
That's another way to move it.
And then you're going to go to the design tab on the ribbon click on Move chart,
and then you're gonna actually move it to another sheet.
So,
for example,
if I want to move this to sheet five,
and then I click OK,
and you can see here that has been moved to Sheet five.
OK,
so that was an introduction about pivot charts.
Thank you very much,
guys,
for watching this video I'll see on the next one