Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to speak about form controls.
So form controls are objects that are available in excel that enable us to change some
parameters or some values.
And based on these changes that are done with form controls,
other values would change as well.
Like you would have this form control linked to a cell,
and it would help it.
A number in that cell and then a formula would be linked to that numbers whenever that
number changes.
That formula changes.
And this room that could be opening some values to a charge to this enables you to control
the values in charts,
as we will see later on in the course.
So let's see.
The most common form controls are available in Excel These air not all the form controls,
but they're actually the most commonly used ones.
So we got our button with our combo box,
the spin button,
the scroll bar,
the shock box,
the option button and the list box.
And we're going to discuss all of these in detail in the upcoming videos.
So to get the form controls,
you need to have the developer top on the ribbon in your excel enabled.
And to enable the developer top.
You can simply right click here on the ribbon anywhere in the ribbon and then click on
customize the ribbon here and then under the customize ribbon top here under the main tabs
,
you'll have the developer top here.
Just check it and click.
OK,
Ok,
so this was a quick introduction to from Controls Guys on the upcoming videos were going to
discuss them in detail.
So thank you very much watching this video and I will see on the next one.