Okay,
guys.
So now we're going to speak about the check box form control.
And as you can see her as I take an antic the check box here on the left,
the orange Siris for average,
it appears and disappears,
as you can see here.
So,
actually,
the orange Siris for the average sales for 2014 it is linked to this check box.
Is Aziz You can see on also in this cell here if you check it.
When?
When this check boxes checked the cell up.
It's a true.
And when this check boxes unchecked,
the cell opus a false.
Okay,
so this cell as well is linked to the check box,
and this is actually how you create the interactivity.
Okay,
guys,
let's see how you can insert a check box are going to go to the developer top on the ribbon
here and click on insert.
Okay.
And then you're gonna select the check box.
Here is the check box shape here.
You're gonna click on it and then left.
Click and drag to dro your check box.
Okay.
So you can see here.
It's been inserted with a default name.
You can Ah change its name if you want.
Okay,
so I'm gonna call it my check box,
for example.
Okay.
So Ah.
Now,
in order to create the link with the cell,
you need to configure the check box.
Okay,
So going to right?
Click on it and click on formal control.
Okay.
And as you can see here,
this is the window for formatting.
Your check box.
Um,
you can give it a three D shape boy.
Just checking this three d shading option.
Okay,
this is just a aesthetic option.
And now you can actually create the cell link through this box here so you can just click
on this blue button and then select a cell,
and then this cell will be linked to the chuck box and outputs a value of either true or
false,
depending on whether the check boxes checked or not.
Okay,
so if you check it,
this cell will help it.
It true,
if you on check it,
the cell would output a false Okay,
So using this information and the fact that it alpa's a true or false in a cell,
you can link a formula.
Okay,
That would actually be willing to that cell and depend on the value of the cells of the
cell value is true.
The formula would give us a certain result.
And if it is false,
then the former they would give us another result.
So if you can see here and the cells here representing the average,
you can see here that the formula in old the cells is basically the same.
And you can see her that it says if the value of cell K two is equal to true,
then give me the average.
And if if otherwise,
OK,
and other ways could be full,
sir,
could be any other value.
Okay,
then give me a hash and a okay.
It's gonna give us a hash and air.
This is the hash and air.
This is produced through the n A function.
Okay,
there is a function in excel that is called an A that you could use to produce the harsh
and a her Okay.
And this hash and a error is actually what results in the line disappearing.
Okay,
the line for the average sales.
so if you check that here,
you consider that when the line disappears this is because there is a hash and a we cannot
use zero,
for example,
because if we make we make the formula produces zero in case of fools instead of the harsh
and a error this actually would not make the line disappear would just make it appear at
the bottom here.
Okay,
so Ah,
you need to use the hajj and a in order to make ah,
this line serious for the average disappear.
Okay,
so this is how you can use the check box guys to create interactivity to your dashboards.
So thank you very much for watching this video and I'll see on the next one in all of the
cells is basically to say,