Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss another form control,
which is the list box.
Okay,
so the list box is basically a form control that allows you to put items in the list and
toggle between them.
Select any one of them individually.
Okay.
As you consumerism,
selecting the different items I their sales and units sold get plotted on these two charts
.
Okay,
so each item select,
I get its sales and its units sold.
Okay,
so we're going to see how this works.
But before doing that,
we're going to see,
first of all,
how we can insert a list box.
OK,
so we're going to go to a developer tab on the ribbon click on insert on,
then choose the list box here,
and then we're going to click on it and then click on and drag to draw away.
OK,
so let's check It's formatting how to format it.
I'm going to right click on it and click on format control,
OK?
And ah,
you can see her.
There is an imp a trained and there's the cell link.
The import ranges basically the range of cells that contains your items.
Okay,
so is the range range of cells that would contain your list basically so that you could
generate a list out of that range of cells.
And there's also the selling,
which is basically the cell that you're gonna output three orginal position of the item
that you're going to select in.
OK,
so we're going to see that in action and for the selection type,
we're only going to bother with the single selection type because the multi and extend the
need vb a code to run we're not going to bother with.
That is outside the scope of the course.
And there is also the option for three D shading,
which gives it a bit of a three D.
Look,
it's an aesthetic option.
So I'm gonna click council here.
I'm gonna bleat my list box.
I'm gonna check the configuration off this list box that I've got already up and running
year.
And as you can see here,
we've got an import train.
So to check that we can see her that in the analysis sheet get the impetus train jizz cells
before to be seven,
and we've got also the cell link.
It's actually Selby,
too,
As you can see here,
it's It's this cell here.
Be to this is the cell link.
And what this selling does is basically contains the order position of the item that we
select.
So as you can see her,
we've selected here PC's,
for example,
you consider that is gotta one.
If we select laptops,
this is the second item isn't in the list.
We're gonna have it too.
If was elect ablest,
we're gonna have a three and so on and so forth.
And this number is very useful because you can use it with an index function,
for example,
to get the name of the item that you selected,
for example.
Okay,
so putting a number here is is very useful,
and this can be used with lots of look of functions,
and it can be very useful.
Okay,
So one more thing is,
actually,
as you can see here,
when you select one of the items Onley,
that item appears on the chart and actually the rest of the items disappear.
So let me just explain to you the mechanism behind that.
So,
um,
these two charts here the sales reads from this range the sale stores here is the ah items
in the chart.
And these air the months and their values.
OK,
and the units sold.
It reads from this range Basically.
Okay.
And as you can see here,
I've set up the four minute here,
for example,
on the sale.
Start to check if,
ah,
if actually the number beside the item here.
So you can see here that on the items have got some numbers,
which is basically the ordinance position in the list.
Okay.
And I've set up actually the for minister,
that he would check that.
Ah,
the number of the item is equal to the list boxes selling value.
Okay.
And if that's the case,
then return some data from the sheet they scold,
rotated.
Let me just on hide that for you.
The row data sheet.
As you can see here,
it's reading its values from this sheet.
Okay,
so this is basically the shed that contains the source values,
and this is basically analysis.
Shed the intermediate sheet,
and this is basically the presentation sheet or the dashboard cheat.
Okay.
You remember guys when you spoke about the structure of a dashboard containing sheet for
road eight.
Another one for analysis and the 3rd 1 for your dashboard to output it or to show it to the
customer.
Okay,
so this is the analysis sheet here.
It's basically it checks if the item here is basically the one that you selected.
And if so,
it gets the value from the road data sheet,
and if it isn't,
it gets zero,
or it actually helps zero in the cell.
Okay,
So because the PC's is the items selected at the moment,
it's not opening a zero,
but here is actually out putting a zero.
But why is there not a zero?
They're actually blank cells.
Well,
the reason for that is that I have changed the formatting of the cells.
OK,
so I'm going to right click,
click on form.
It sells to show you that.
And as you can see here of change the formatting of the cells to show a blank value in case
you get a zero.
Okay.
Well,
um,
number formatting is a big topic,
and it probably needs a video all by itself.
Okay,
but,
um,
I'm gonna just make it shorter for you.
This part here the first part represents how Excel would deal with the number if it's
positive.
The second part here The general also represents how Excel would deal with it if it's a
negative,
and 1/3 part is how it deals with it.
If it's zero on the fourth,
but is how it deals with it if it's a text.
Okay,
so I've actually put put it to deal with it if it's zero to make it to give me a blank
value.
And the reason I'm doing that is because a blank value will just not show any labels on the
other items that are not selected.
Okay,
where is if you actually put it as a zero?
So let me just change that to zero just to show you here.
If you put it a zero,
for example,
you're gonna get zeros on the data labels here,
as you can see for the other items that you haven't selected.
Okay,
so this is to allow me to have the data labels for the items that are not selected.
Not so have zeros,
but to be blank.
OK,
so I'm actually just going to switch it back here,
my guy.
And the same goes for actually the chart at the bottom.
Okay,
I'm actually planning to make another video or by myself for number formatting cause the
big topic there needs to be discussed in and have a video all by itself.
Okay.
And the reason also I haven't used the hash and a that we used previously is for the same
reason.
If you use the hash and a,
it's going to appear on the daily data labels and you can try it yourself.
Okay,
so you can just try to open a hash and a or the n A function instead of a zero,
you'll see that it will appear on the data labels.
OK,
so this is kind of an exercise to do.
And one more thing I need to tell you as well is that the list box?
If I right click on it and click on form and control,
it actually can have a list through a named range instead of just ah range of cells.
OK,
so actually,
I've got a named range that I had created before.
It's called list Strange.
Okay,
so far,
right click again here.
Quicken format control for right list range of the same spelling.
It's actually it actually can read it correctly,
and it will still have the correct items in the list.
Okay,
so that's perfect.
Thank you guys for watching this video.
If you have any questions,
leave them in the Q and A section.
Thank you very much for watching this video I'll see on the next.