Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss another application for this crowbar control,
which is the scrolling list says he could see here.
I've got a list of names.
This list contains 10 names.
Okay.
And as you can see here,
I'm able to use a scroll bar control toe scroll through more than 10 names,
actually.
So I've got 100 names,
actually behind the scenes,
and I'm able to use this crowbar control here to scroll through the 100 names in Onley.
10 records.
Okay.
And as you can see here,
the values of the records are changing.
Basically.
So let's see the road data behind that.
Since you can see here,
we've got the on this road data sheet here.
We've got the 100 names,
Okay,
Got 100 records,
and I've created actually an I.
D column.
OK,
so it's calm that I've created here,
and all that does is that it increments by one.
Okay,
just counts the names.
So is get numbers between one and 100 is just counting the names.
Okay,
you can either create a calm formula or you can just,
you know,
type one here.
And then when you drug that you know,
excel,
we'll give you the option to fill the Siri's year with with the one from between one on 100
.
So it's really up to you.
You can do it using any method that you would like.
Okay.
And,
ah,
let's go to actually the explanation sheet here to explain how we have done that.
Okay,
So to do that,
you need to create the same columns as your road eight up plus the i.
D column.
Okay,
that you created on the road data.
And also,
you need to have a scroll bar control inserted.
Okay.
And then on the i D.
Column here,
you need to type a one,
and then you can type a formula on the second row here on the just to sell below it.
OK,
which is the starting number for the I d.
Plus one.
And then you can drag the formula to the lost row here.
Okay.
To the 10 throw.
So you've got 10 rows or 10 records and you're gonna be able to display ah 100 names on
these 10 records and the reason of done this plus one formula is that we're gonna have this
crowbar control connected to the cell here,
having the idea of one which is Selby to.
And then when this crowbar control increments numbers these numbers as well will be
incremental did with it,
okay?
Or these numbers will basically offset be offset by one.
And then,
you know,
this number will be offset from this number by one and so on so forth.
So when When the i d.
Contains 20 for example,
this one will contain 21.
And then this 1 22 and then this 1 23 and so on and so forth.
Okay.
So after inserting our score,
bar control,
we would need to configure it.
So I'm going to right click on it here and click on format control.
And ah,
first of all,
the current value,
you could put it as one.
Or you can put it at as any value will change anyways,
okay.
And then the minimum value is gonna be a one,
because this crowbar control is gonna be connected to Selby too.
Okay,
So you'd want our minimum value to be a one,
because this is the minimum value and Selby to and this is actually are released.
I d number.
Okay,
so this is why it is the one.
And then the maximum by value is gonna be 91.
In our case,
if you've got 100 records.
The reason for that is that if this is 91 than the following one is going to be 92 93 94 95
96 97 98 99 then 100.
Because so because we have got a total of 100 records.
Okay,
we would want this to be 90 ones that the other nine cells would add up to.
Ah,
100 Basically.
Okay.
And then the incremental change is gonna be a 10.
So that's every time you press on the scroll bar buttons.
This number,
this idea number would be incriminated by 10.
Okay.
And then the page change is gonna be 10 as well.
Which is when you click in the middle of this crowbar control.
Okay.
And our cell link is gonna be cell B two,
okay?
And get a three d shading his roles are gonna click.
OK?
And as you can see here when we use the scroll bar control the numbers on the I d get
incremental because the first number gets increment id here by 10 and then the other
numbers air linked by formulas so they get incremental by one,
as you can see here.
Okay,
so the next step here is to actually look up the names from the road data worksheet.
So to look up,
the names were actually going to use this.
I d.
Number here to look up the names and actually phone numbers and country and city and street
address from the road data tables were going to use a V look of formula.
Okay.
And we're gonna look up the i d number.
Okay?
And we're gonna actually absolute the column part because we need to drag the formula to
the right,
and then our table array is going to be this stable here.
Okay?
And you can also use a dynamic range and put that table and Anoma cranes if you need to
allow for any expansion and our column index number.
Okay,
our column index number is gonna be basically in this case there for looking up the name.
It's gonna be too.
And then the range look up is gonna be an exact match.
So free closer brackets and press enter is you can see her.
We're able to look up the names and when we scroll through the names air changing.
Okay,
So for the phone number,
it's the same for men.
Except that we need to change our column in X number two or three and for the country need
to change it to a four and so on and so forth.
So we need to change the column.
Index number.
Okay,
So a better trick to use rather than just changing the column index number manually for
each column is to actually used the columns function.
So I was We've learned on a previous video the columns function.
What it does is that it counts the columns in a range.
Okay,
so on the name column here,
you can use the columns and actually highlights columns.
A to be.
I'm just gonna close my brackets here,
and you can actually absolute just the first part off the columns formula here.
Okay.
So I'm just gonna absolute the first part,
which is column A and I'm gonna leave Column B two B relative.
So in this case is gonna count Columns eight to be on the name column.
However,
on the phone number column,
the countings going to be expanded to be from columns A to see because the reference on the
ending column part is relative.
It's not absolute,
so it's not fixed.
So it's expanding.
And if if I expend the formula here or if a drag it to the right,
you can see here that the reference for the ending column is expending.
So as you can see here,
this is a better way to do it,
actually,
rather than just manually typing the column index number as we've learned on a previous
video.
OK,
so actually,
as you can see her weaken,
try our list.
And it's working absolutely fine as the the example that was seen.
Okay,
so now we're gonna discuss as well another possibility.
So what if we need to allow for the expansion off the list?
Okay,
so what if we need to allow the user to,
like,
add more than 100 names to the roadie to list?
Okay,
so how do we allow for that expansion?
So I'm gonna go back here to my explanation sheet and I'm going to right click here on my
scroll Bar Control.
And let's say we put the maximum value to be 200 instead of 91 let's scroll through the
names and see what's gonna happen.
So as you can see here after the 100th name,
we've got actually hash and a error.
So the reason for that is that the I d names are actually incremental ing,
and they're going past 100.
And we're doing the look up using V look up and were not able to find the I.
D.
Number 104 for example.
And this is giving us an error.
So actually to kind of mitigate that and make sure we allow for the expansion as well
without getting these errors,
Okay,
because the user's seeing the hash and a er is not gonna look good.
is that we're actually gonna put an if air for the four minute here for the V look of
formers who can put in if error and then we're gonna make the the cells display a blank
value instead of the hash and a error.
Okay,
so in case of having an error,
we're going to display a blank value.
We're actually going to do that.
As you can see here is displaying a blank value,
which looks,
ah,
lot better than the hash and air.
Okay,
so when When the user is crawling through the list,
I don't see any names than the list is done.
This is the limit for for my name's basically and this looks much better.
You can also type something else.
Which is,
for example,
end of list A swell.
You know,
she can type that make it end of list or something.
the possibilities are basically endless here.
Ah,
the possibilities are infinite.
Utkan apply whatever idea you would like basically OK.
And one more thing off course to note is that the i d number should be hidden.
Okay.
When the user is crawling through the list,
Actually,
this is the form that's gonna appear to the user gonna hide the I d.
Number guys.
We're just gonna have name,
full number,
country,
city and street address,
and the user is gonna scroll through the list this way using this crowbar control.
So this was an explanation and how to create a scrolling list using the school bark control
.
Thank you very much,
guys,
for watching this video and I'll see on the next one.