So the workload for the cafe are increasing in a very complex way.
The architecture must support connectivity between multiple devices and be highly available and salt
tolerant.
So we are going to look at how we can connect your remote network with a side to side VPN on either
side to find a highly available solution that can enable you to a security connect on a premise network
with your VPC.
You can use Internet protocol, security, IPV six, and you can also use encrypted virtual private
networking.
We're going to provide you with encrypted tunnels, better VPN connection and you will be charged per
connection hour.
You could also use with that configuration two times of routing that is dynamic understood.
So with dynamic routing there is a software control how that bucket going to be traveled from one point
to another with this static routing, the buckets have a fixed the static they need to jump from one
place to another.
When you connect Libyans, you can create an virtual private gateway and then you will have multiple
connections connecting a customer gate with no connection to your remote network with a direct connect.
This is another choice.
If you have an on prem datacenter and you want to connect directly to the address region in the country
where you are located, then you can provide you with a physical connection, a physical wire between
the enterprise region data center and you datacenter.
It is dedicated in the private connection with a capacity with that one gigabit per second or thing
gain gap per second, which is extremely fast, especially when you have, for example, your backup
solution storage.
They are in the on premise and you have services in the cloud.
Then you want them to speak with each other.
When you can use direct connection, you can use it in a hybrid environment where you have part of your
infrastructure on prem, part of your infrastructure on the cloud, when you want to transfer large
data set, when you have any working performance predictability, and when you have a security and compliance
feature, you could also extend on a premise network using disconnects where you can create multiple
VPN location, and those are locations where you connect your own aircraft.
This is a way to make your infrastructure highly available because you can also create a direct connect
backup VPN connection so that if the main connection fails down, you have a standby or above can one.
You can also make sure to have a critical workload distributed around multiple on a premise data center
using direct connection when you have multiple connection connecting your cloud with the on premise
center.
Now when we create the BBC, we speak already and we say this is a virtual private network and you need
to transfer data between those two resources that you have in your bio certified.
But that's how you can do that if you have, for example, multiple VPC and there was one for production,
one for testing, one for that.
How you will do that, you can use what we call a VPC appearing.
So in this recipe we are going to do the same.
We have a 1 to 1 networking connection between two bases without any gateway, without any VPN connection,
and the other with a separate network allocation.
And we have a highly available connection without having a single point of failure or a bandwidth bottleneck.
When you have multiple devices are connected with the same gateway, that's good.
We need to process everything.
So this is going to create a bottleneck.
Now you have all sorts of like always a stage on the global backbone, which is an advanced feature
because this means the traffic between two BBC will happen in a private connection, not in a secure
connection.
You can establish a recipient by going I'm going to into that all the time and so have, for example,
the destination within the same VPC will be going to the telco.
And if you want to go to the second VPC, you are going to use that.
So on this dimension, which can be the parent connection, beefy x1, DC X1, now you could also have
multiple being in connection which are restricted.
So amongst the thing, so what you can do is you have also very busy guys, you can also pin them together.
But remember peer to peer connection is between two bases at a time.
They are not.
This is not the actual connection and this is.
Like a famous examiner question.
So if you want to be an easy one with a BBC, one with the BBC to visit with the production, if you're
really busy with the press, this does not mean that you have access between there and the production.
We are two totally separate or maybe two totally separate connections.
When you connect monthly, really busy, consider those networking design only connect.
Essential really is a mixture of your solution and scale.
This is an example of a building on my side and resources and this guy would love.
We will create every recipient and connection.
So if you recall what we did in Lab six, we actually create VPC and then we have like also the shared
APC and we have told In Love six that we are going to use the option VPC later on.
So in this particular map, we want to create a picture and connection and that we visited and in connection
will happen between love, privacy and the shared beauty lab.
So as you can see here in the diagram, we have my sequence instance in the set of the APC and want
to pair it with our application server in the lab APC.
So it is now installed on the task and we will do in number five, we will go to the this and in my
interview this account, I would like to access the VPC console and from there we to create everything.
Right now I would like to move this to TAB so I can navigate easily between them.
So let's go to the beginning connection and you want to create a fitting connection following the dummy
territory called the lab.
Now the VPC that we want to request is going to be the lab and this is the IP address of the lab.
BBC We want to select another VPC in my account, or you can also add another VPC.
And I don't know that I can.
If you have better machine do so the acceptor will be the shared VPC and you can see that it has a different
idea of I can address and just create that connection.
Now after this finished, we want to go and select an up here and from the action we want to exit the
request so we are going to go to the connection.
The next is from action.
We want to exit the request because basically we have the requester and the ex that are from the same
account.
So we need to do this a step here now we need to configure tunnel active and this now will take us to
the round table and in the last public routing and for the last UPC, we want to send that out.
So we add about for the IP address of the shared with the and this is basically going to be the path
that we take every time we want to communicate with the share.
So in the last public image, double check guys, because it is very important to do this correctly,
we go to drag.
It is and we add to this IP address and this is going to be the destination for this.
It should be the connection that we just created, the lab and a change in this step.
Number 14, we want to select the shared VPC announcement and in that VPC about and we want to edit
that out.
And now we put Path to the last VPC.
So it's going to be the other direction of the communication.
So in the shared the BBC about they have been quoted around it is an add around and make this pointing
to the lab privacy and this is also will be the connection that will just be in the three.
And then I want to test the VPC pairing.
So we need to go to the easy to and from the easy to we have our application server.
As you can see, the applications that is in the instances is located in the lab, VPC in the public
subnet.
And we want to check that this love ABC is basically enabling us to access that.
So if you go back to the network section, they are going to give us a few configuration settings for
the database.
So we need to go and open the obvious as well.
That's all going to mutate and fund that a new tab.
We want to go to the obvious and basically retrieve the endpoint.
So to go to the and then to the to the select and eventually now go back to your database server.
And in the settings we want paste the inventory disappears now that this is his name is called inventory
and the username is going to be admin and the password is going to be lab.
So click save and you can see I have access.
So basically by this we finished the lab.