Welcome to Edelweiss.
Cloud Architecting.
In this module, we are going to have a look to the course objectives and to the overview.
And then we will study the café business case that we will use in our practical lab and challenge labs
to begin.
It is very important to have an understanding of the period exquisite for this course you should complete
by now the eight of us, the cloud practitioner course or similar level of knowledge of Amazon Web Services
such as you pass the Edelweiss Certified Cloud Practitioner Certificate Exam, or you completed the
Canada Practitioner Essential Course, or you completed the Edelweiss technical essential course.
In addition to that, we would like you to have a generic I.T. knowledge and I.T. business knowledge
in this course.
The solution architect.
We are going to study 15 modules.
We will start by an introduction about a cloud architecting.
Then we will study how we can add to the cafe business a storage layer, a compute layer, a database
layer, and how we can create our networking environment in us and how we can manage to connect multiple
VCs in the cloud.
Then we will look to securing user and application access, implementing and elastic and highly available
architecture and automate your architecture using a cloud formation.
Then we will look to caching content and building decoupled architecture and microservices and serverless
computing.
In module 14, we are going to do a planning for this massive and we will take multiple exercises and
labs in order to study how we can build highly available and highly scalable, fault, tolerant architecture.
In the last model, we are going to look at the certification process.
So the cafe business use case that we are going to use to build all the exercises now and guided and
challenged are based about a fictional business case.
This business case provides us a way to explore the cloud computing services and to build for real in
the keynote.
This scenario is intended to provide an example of the real world application of technical concept that
you will learn.
Frank and Martha opened the cafe and the bakery that they had.
It's a start from a retirement dream.
They were not yet ready to live out their retirement around the house, and instead they wanted to do
something that included their love of baking and supplemented their income.
They enjoy interacting with people in their neighborhood, and they also like to support the community
events across town with their baked goods and cafes.
Frank and Martha recently decided to open their cafe at the base of their flat, their daughter Sophia,
and a local school student, Nicole, help out and work at the cafe.
Since they opened the cafe, they have experienced an increase in local businesses and they also sometimes
receive inquiries from people who travel through the area.
So the cafe owner and stuff, we have a frank the owner, we have the Martha, the owner of the cafe.
We have Sophia, the daughter of a Frank and Martha and Nicole.
We have the cafe employee.
We have also Olivia, which is an A.W. Solution architect who recently moved to the downtown area,
and she frequently visit the cafe and enjoying talking with Sophia.
And they will start to elevate the technical architecture of the cafe based on adding multiple layers
to make the cafe website and store highly available and highly scalable.
We have also Matthew, which is a system administrator and an engineer, and we have faith, which is
a developer experience with this programming interface in the coming lab and exercises, you will gain
a hands on practice of building and ADA US services and they will have two different types of lab.
We will have the guided lab and the challenges in the guided lab.
They provide you with a step by step instructions.
We will provide you with a step by step instruction to help you gain experience in creating and configuring
resources in the different services area.
And the Challenge Lab will present you with a new business requirement that are based on the evolving
needs of the cafe.
Both loves the challenge and the guided lab.
They will enhance your technical skills.
You will be able to explore more about our services and you will train yourself to build in the cloud.
This course helps you to prepare for the ADA Certified Solution Architect Associate Exam.
So after you did to the foundational level, the cloud, the practitioner and you must have for example
by now the cloud, the practitioner, it is the time for you to move forward and to study for the solution
architect exam.
Let us move now to study the will.
Architect architected the framework.