Now clashing with Sessions.
Clashing with Sessions is very important to understand this specifically when you have an auto scalar
and load balancer running behind your web server.
So you want to make sure if the user to speak with a specific session, that session data can be captured
in order to allow our load balancer to route request to those the specific server that manages the user
session, we could use a client file cookie.
That's the old method which are of course effective and they can speed up retrieval of sessions and
they have few.
This advantage is I want you to know these disadvantages and keep them in your mind the loss of the
sessions data when you have an instance failure or when the instance is terminated or declared to be
amazing by the load balancer are replaced by the easy to administer.
So you will lose everything.
The second one you have a limit to scalability because this is are subjected to uneven load distribution
and increased latency.
And instead of a sticky session, what you can do is to process a decision.
These are in a distributed cache and in this case, even if the server declared it to be unhealthy and
that server is basically replaced by an scalar, you still have decision data saved on that caching
layer and there is multiple times of elastic cache that you can use and they are very important because
normally they will ask about an index.
So in this example here we store a session estate for an online gaming application.
I can see we have a player going to send a request to elastic load balancing and the elastic load balancing
to speak with two web servers.
In our multi easy deployment.
In the middle, we have an Amazon Dynamo DB where we cast the user data and this is separated from the
game server itself that we have it there serving the game application.