In this, we will do lap five, which is build your DB server and interact with your DB using applications.
And now let's go to this scenario and understand what we are going to have for today.
So basically what we have, we have a web server which is basically this is what we create in the last
lot.
This is what we create in number three.
And now we want to add a new component to this architecture where we add basically an art of this and
that are the we will test that our web server interact with it.
So the first thing we need to do after starting the lab and exiting the console, you can see the console
is here with me.
All of this to a second screen.
And this is will enable me to basically have more freedom in the creation process.
So now in the first task, guys, we want to create a first a security group.
So we want to go to the easy to.
Or even you can go and find security group in the VPC.
So go to the VPC.
And from your VPC, you have security group.
Now in the reflection in step number seven, we want to create a security group.
And the name of the security group will be a DB security group.
And the description is going to be to permit access from Web security group.
And this is neat.
You need to be careful here because you need to disable the default VPC and you select the lab VPC alone.
Then you need to add a third and this is will be basically my sequel, Aurora.
You can search for it.
My sequel, Aurora, which opened 40 3306.
And in the custom part, we want to basically.
In the custom parts, we want just to basically enable a specific security group called the security
group.
So from custom, click here in the box, you can find that there is a Web security group there.
Now, why do we need this security group or why we want to enable just only the security group?
If you open your easy to and you see that you have a Web server here, that web server use that security
group.
So we are saying here we only allow the traffic coming from this web server to go to the RTA.
So we only want to allow that web server to access our are there.
So we created the security group.
Now, let us move to task number two.
So we need to go to the ADRs console from the ADRs console.
We want to create a subnet, a group.
Now the subject group is basically just only a way to control where these are.
They will be placed.
So basically we want to make sure that our audience, based on their love and instruction.
And if you just review the lab and guys goes the diagram, you will see that they want us to launch
start Argus in the private subnet one and the private subnet too.
So we want to follow these.
In order to achieve that, we need to create and out of this, this mean go to the obvious console,
go to the subnet to group, create ADB subnet group.
Now this is should have the name, which is if you go back to that instruction, the audience should
have the name DB something to group.
And the description will be ad lib something to group again.
We need to launch this in VPC now in the lab.
VPC They are saying in the lab instruction, guys, we need to select basically two availability zone,
which is US East one A and one B and this is a due to the fact that our audience will be only last in
those two private subnet in East one and East one and one B.
Now, the next thing they are saying, it is step number 60.
And we have to select the subnet which are 10 to 0, the one zero and ten 20.30.
So let me show you why fit so you can understand in the future what you are doing.
This is that in particular, if you go to your VPC and to your subnet in the last VPC, you have four
subnets, you have private subnet one and the private subnet two.
Now look to the IP address for the private subnet to extend that 0 to 3.
And subnet one is standard 0 to 10, which means I want only my database to be in a private subnet one
and the private subnet two.
So let me go back.
Select ten 0.1.0 and ten 03.0.
And then they click on it create.
In Dusty three.
Now we need to go back to our database solution and we create a database.
Now we need to select.
My sequel.
That's a strange.
They have removed my sequel from the page.
Now we're talking my sequel.
And now from my sequel, we want to make sure that this is basically.
The test.
Now in.
Our sitting.
We want to keep it as a single, easy deployment.
Now the database identifier will be lub db.
Let me be.
And the master reserve name is going to be.
Main.
The password is going to be a lot.
That's.
Password and then that guess password again.
Now that these are the default for is clear.
Now if you switch between the create and sender create the sender create are going to give you too many
options.
Close this now the first single we love the be main love password.
Now for the instant machine they want to use the best every class, including three classes.
Now the love is asking you to use these three macros so you can see here I have selected or given ttt3
macro by default.
We need to in the source configuration we need to disable.
A few checkbox, which is, for example, enable the storage or scaling.
And in the connectivity now part we want to select our last VPC and this is will select by the default
DB subnet group.
Now for our VPC security most a student they do this mistake.
They keep the security group of the default there and then they choose the DB security group, which
is the one I create in this task, number one.
So we select the DB security group D select the default, and then we need to add additional configuration
give.
Our database.
A name.
We will call a club because we need that name for later on.
So we disable enhanced monitoring and automated backups and encryption.
And that's all for this database configuration.
So again, guys, it's going to be standard to create my sequel.
This test, it's going to be labeled as the main password.
The password instance, the three a micro T for the storage unit on purpose in the VPC in the DB subnet
group to the existing security group, the DB security group and select the default and then give the
database a name because you will use this in the connection and we'll see you later on and then click
on the create.
Normally, guys, this will take a few minutes for the debate to be ready.
So we want to wait now from the creation to make our TV available.
Now, once this finished, I need to go to my easy too and my Easy Too has an application in that web
server.
That application, we are going to use it.
So I'm going to copy the public IP.
I'm going to use that application to connect to my out of this.
Just add this so you can see that as an order step here we are going to put to the endpoint the database
name, the username and password, and this is what we are going to do in the step number for.
This will go to my out of this.
Now, normally, this could take up to 4 minutes, guys.
So we need to wait for that to finish.
Okay.
As you can see now, my database is available so I could see that the status has been changed from creation
to available.
Now click on up DB.
It will give you a quick information about the connectivity and the security, the port we open in which
VPC we have created this ah, this subnet and with subnet as well with security group.
Also if you go through the configuration, you could get for example, the database in a sense and the
DB name.
Now if you go back to your website, we need to now to provide this information, the end point, the
database, the username and password.
So let me go back to connectivity and I will copy the end point and I will paste it here.
Now the database name, if you notice, the database name is called Lab.
So I'm going back and fill up here.
The username is man and the password was the password.
Click Submit.
You should be able to check that you have a correct.
Connection between the website and your database so you could interact with your database.
You can remove record, add a new record like test, for example, one, one and one at me dotcom.
And submit.
Just to make sure you have basically a correct configuration between your web server and the are there.
So that's will be all for five.
Thank you for seeing this.