So we can go into this lab which has a scale and load balance your application.
And we know from the previous classes or from Lab five, the last thing we did was basically to create
the scenario.
We create a web server with a security group that is speak with a multi easy deployment of an art of
this.
Now we want to basically make this architecture beside it is highly attainable.
We want it to be load balancing and auto escape.
So this means we are going to add application load balancer because this is our server and we will add
as well and a scanner and then we will move the chipset of about a from the public subnet to the private
subnet to give it more and excellent air of security.
So the first thing we need to do, guys, in this lab is to create an am I from the current AC two that
we have.
So if you look here, we have our we've said about that we create in lab five and that web server is
offering demo application.
So that demo application is used by our end user and we have an of the ask as well.
And in the past we connect from this out of the S to from this web server to the audience.
So the first thing we need to do, guys, is in task one is basically to create an M and that's M I
will be passed to the auto to.
So basically every machine created by the auto scanner will offer the same application that we can see
here in that with Sarah.
So to create an am, I select the which said about itself, go to action and then from action, go to
image and template and to create an image.
We need to call this image that would say, what am I?
And the description which is the love I.
Am I?
Four.
With seven.
Now this is will take a few minutes.
So I'm going to click Create and I will move to the next stuff.
So in Tasks two, we want to create a load balancer and we see from the class that there is a three
times of load balancer because we are a load balancing application.
Then we need to create an application load balancer.
So click on to create a load balancer.
Selector and application load balancer.
Now, this application load balancer, as you see from the diagram, is going to be an intermediate
facing because it will operate in the public subnet.
So we call this a lab PLB.
And it will be an idea for now in which the BBC wants to operate.
This will be operated in the lab, VPC in the lab, BBC.
We have two availabilities on one A and one B.
Now, this should be the public subnet one, and this one should be public suddenly two, because we
are saying that this is a Internet facing yield bonanza.
Now we need to remove the default security group.
From the security group dropdown box, we select the Web security group, which means that load balancer
is going to accept the traffic at Port 80 and it will be forwarding it to this target group.
So we need to create a targeted group.
And this is will open a new tab for us.
Now, this targeted group is going to be called.
Choose a targeted group.
It will be an easy to in a you select in instances to target a group name.
It will be basically a lab.
A group.
And then we need to operate that automated group in the lab, VPC within a CTP one, and it will send
a health check my step as well.
And the last thing we need to do is to click next.
Now these are not going to be registered or available because this is the web server one and this is
the bastion host.
We don't need any of them.
So we click on it, create a target group.
Now go back to the load balancer page refreshed.
And this is now we show you the guitar group that we just created.
Now the next step is to create a load balancer.
So once you click at this stage here, you will find that you have created an application load balancer
and a targeted group for that load balancer.
Okay.
Now, the next thing is to create a challenge configuration and auto scaling.
So we want to go to the lunch configuration.
We click on it, create a launch configuration that will be the lab.
Config.
Now which image?
We are still waiting for our army to be ready.
So as you can see, that's sad.
But am I the one I just decree?
It is that you can verify this as well from going to the senses.
And there is an MRI and this is the aim.
I just decree it myself, which is a copy of the content of the etc. that offers this application here.
Now the instant start is going to be in this exam, but it's going to be three medical.
So I'm going to select t three dot micro here and choose.
Now we do not have any spotting instances or a profile role.
We only need to worry about the security group because this is offering us our servers.
So we need to make sure we open.
With a security group.
We are going to select the Web security group.
For the security group.
And then we need to choose.
And existing keypad.
It will choose the aquarium key click knowledge and then create.
But we have now a lab configuration for the O2 scaling.
The next thing is to create basically or two skin and you can select the last configuration or you could
go to auto scan any group from this tab.
Both.
They will work from action.
Just click on to create an auto scaling.
We will call this a lab or to scanning a group.
Click now next.
Now this will operate in the lab.
VPC So make sure you are not selecting the default.
VPC Now when which availability zone we need to select or to create those or to scan in Google.
Now go back to the diagram, guys.
Once you are also scanning in a practice solely for practicing and creating more easy to an instance,
we want an easy to in a sense created body that we're just going to be a group to be placed on the private
subnet.
We don't want it to be too placed in here in the public subnet.
We so we need to be careful about our choice.
So let's go now back and we select the private subnet.
One.
And the private subnet to and the next.
So now with the next step, we need to attach it to a load balancer.
And we have an existing load balancer, which is the last LP.
So we need to select that and then we make sure that that LP is activated.
And then we have to enable the group metrics.
Then the next that is that capacity is going to be two, the minimum is two and the maximum is going
to be six.
And now we need to basically select the target group which the target type utilization, 64, 300 seconds,
which means one minute.
Then no notification for the tag.
We need to put a tag name, love and then a click mask next and then create an auto scaling.
The next thing you will see now, the auto scaling will start to basically put and create the designer's
capacity to make sure that we have two instances.
So you could go now and see that the easy to will have two instances and initialization.
So if you go to the instances and refresh this page, you will see that there is a new instance created
by the scalar called love.
In a sense, one and two.
You could now stop the observer just to make sure that the load balancer is not getting any traffic
from the web server.
And now let's go and just the load balancer.
So select the load balancer and this and lift the DNS name and then put the DNS name into any browser
and load that to be this which will basically create.
The demo application that we have.
And at the location we can load tests which basically run a script on the web server to generate some
secure load.
And then you can see from the auto scaling activity that it will start to create more AC two instances
to meet.
The demand.
As you know, that this will get all the information from iCloud.
So if you go to the cloud, you will find that there is a new alarm just to raise any green.
And that alarm is basically showing that the target.
Group of goats.
Getting a group is an okay status and the capitalization in greater than 60.
So you could keep monitoring between loading that this closed the page of the load balancer basically
to check that there is a new AC two instances or deleting any situation instances when there is no no.
So this is pretty much what we need to do in lab six.
Guys, just keep it running for a few minutes and monitor the cloud.
And that's all for the Cloud Foundation class.
Thank you for seeing this video and see you in the next one.