Goes to another video about hosting a website in Amazon.
Seth Rogen The idea here that you have a static website and you want just to put it in, etc., in order
to serve your customer.
So let us get into it.
We really first create a bucket.
Now let me get this bucket, any website, and I will give it the date of today just to give it a unique
name in the database region, USA East.
Now the new changes in the zone, etc. a console is basically this object ownership.
So in the previous version, we don't have access list enabled or object ownership.
So we need to make sure to finish this up successfully to enable access lists for the object.
And we give that the ownership of the bucket to be able to change the object ownership and then we will
block all public access.
We would disable that, then we acknowledge and then we can enable the bucket versioning from here.
It could also add tag if you want, and you could also add a server side encryption.
If you are storing sensitive data in this bucket.
Now click on Create Bucket.
The next thing is to select the budget you just created and then go to the properties and all the way
down.
Go to static website hosting and enable.
And once you enable this, you can basically point out that this is to host a static clip site and the
name of the index document that you are going to use.
And this website in my case is going to be a history.
You could also specify an error page just in case.
If there is any issue on your website, you can't extend to your customer an error message.
Click on Save Changes.
Once you do that, you will be able to get a new.
Link for your website and you can see now it's give me 4034, which means we don't have permission to
view the website content as of yet then existed.
We have like a demo application, a demo static website that I'm going to share with you in the description
to try to slap out.
You just click on upload.
Add phones and let me select a small index of three seven.
Fly with JavaScript and a styling file.
Just a click open and then click on upload.
The next thing is going to be after you upload the files you need to select them and then you go to
action and then make public via ACL.
Now, if you did not select an object in the creation of the bucket, you would find this option not
available.
So what you could do is to make it happen is basically to go to the bucket itself.
And from the packet there is a permission and the permission that is an object ownership here.
You can edit that in order to basically be able to make your object public.
The next thing is to go now to the bucket to set it to the.
You are told that we well, it's given to us in a three at first page and you will see now I have a
nice static website with a nice map where I basically offer for my customer to visit my business.
Thank you so much for seeing this video and see you in the next one.