As you grow the number of work load that's done in the US, you must be able to scale your network across
multiple accounts and VPC to keep up with that growth, you can use VPC peering to connect pairs of
the bases.
However, it can be operationally costly and difficult to manage a point to point connectivity specifically
that each the pieces need to make a specific point to point connection.
The same IP address that you use for BBC A is not going to be repeated in the same in the second VPC,
which is BBC me.
If you cannot centrally manage those connectivity policy, it will be very, very difficult to keep
up with multiple connection.
So when you have an unappealing connectivity, you must attach your VPN to each individual VPC and this
solution can be time consuming to build and very difficult to manage when the number of the pieces grows
into the hundreds.
So it is very important to consider how large your environment might become over time and how will it
in the scale and how you will organize your VPC to solve this problem.
You can use the as a transit gateway, which can simplify your networking margin.
So what is the U.S. Transit Gateway?
Transit Gateway is a service that enables you to connect your VPC and on premises and networks to a
single gateway.
So it will be a single hub of connection.
It is a fully managed, highly available with the flexible routing services.
It can act as a hub for all traffic to flow through between your networks.
You can connect up to 5000 VCs and on a premises in 30 minutes with a single gateway.
So let us look to a scenario where we have to connect multiple VPC to connect multiple PS.
VPC is using LW as a transit gateway.
Consider this scenario You want to fully connect three devices in your network.
You learn how to deploy the transit gateway and the three VPC with non-overlapping IP address and make
sure to remember that guys in the exam, those non-overlapping IP addresses must be in a single region.
You then attach the transit gateway to these VPC.
So the first step for connecting multiple PCs is to create a transit gateway.
That is, transit gateway will act as a hub that you can use to interconnect your PCs.
And on premise data center is a transit gateway in this case will need an elastic network interface
which are deployed into that subnet.
So as you can see here in each VPC, when VPC two and VPC three, we have a specific network interface
that we are going to use.
You must ensure that every availability zone that is part of the VPC has that.
E and I now after you do attach DE and I, the next step is to add a route to the VPC roundtable to
send the traffic which can be destined for other devices in the network.
To that, it's on that gateway.
So you can see here VPC three routing.
We are saying the IP address in the 0.0.0/8.
The target is the GW Transit Gateway.
If you notice here that this network, the ten 20.068 included in it everything we need for the others
to either block it has the IP ten .2.0.0 and in the 1.0.0 you must now configure the transit gateway,
our table to routed traffic to the connected VPC.
In this table, when you create a transit gateway in that default transit gateway routing in each note
in the transit gateway must enable the transit gateway to send this traffic distance for one of the
VCs to a corresponding attachment.
So you can see now in the transit gateway at all table, we are saying if you want to reach ten .1.020
slash 16, then you need to go to VPC, attach one if you want to reach standard 0.23.0.0.
With this nice 16, the VPC will be in the VPC attach three.
You can use the ABC Transit Gateway to connect to multiple, multiple VPC.
You can also use it to achieve isolation in your VPC environment.
In this particular scenario, you want to connect your VPN source to your VPC environment.
You want also to prevent your VPC from directly connecting to each other, leaving the VPN to decide
if this traffic from one DBC has to be forwarded to another by sitting.
Up the table in a proper way, the transit gate where you can prevent information sharing between those
the ABC.
So as you can see here in this diagram, we have a VPN connection and we want to update the rail table
in the transit gateway to send to send all unknown traffic to that VPN connection.
In this particular scenario, we are going to put in the transit gateway at our table for any other
IP.
The target will be the VPN connection.
So this is how you create an area as a transit gateway and achieve a VPC isolation.
In this activity, you have finally PCs that you want to connect to each other through a transit gateway.
You can go and start to think what routes are necessary to add each of the VPC at our table to enable
for connectivity and what routes are necessary to add to the transit gateway are all table to enable
full connectivity, and you will find that in the VPC three, for example, we are going to say any
traffic, the distance to the ten 000/a goal to to to the transit gateway because this IP is the address
summarization for all the peaks that we have in this diagram.
You can also look that in the transit gateway at all table, we are going to specify each VPC subnet
IP and we specify the VPC attachment to be the target of that traffic.
Now what about if we want to connect our RBCs to a supported US services?
The first thing you want to think of is VPC endpoints, and this is really important.
For the example, they would love to ask about BBC endpoint all the time.
A VPC endpoints enable you to privately connect your VPC to supported services and to VPC endpoint services
that are powered by a US private link.
The endpoint, which are powered by the private link, include some services, and those services might
be hosted by either a customer or even as part of the VPC.
Endpoints do not require an internet gateway or not device or a VPN connection or ADX direct connect
connection.
In instances in your VPC do not require a public IP address to communicate with resources in the service,
and the traffic between your VPC and other service does not leave the Amazon network.
Those endpoint are virtual devices.
They are horizontally scaled, redundant and highly available endpoint.
Allow communication between instances in your VPC services without imposing availability, risk or bandwidth
constraints in your network traffic in either use.
There are two types of VPC involved.
There is the interface endpoint, which is an elastic network interface with a private IP address.
That IP address serves as an entry point for the traffic that is distant to a supported service interface.
Endpoints enable you to connect to services that are powered by a WAC private.
You normally the owner of the service is the service provider and there is the principal who basically
create the interface endpoint.
You are the service consumer.
The second time is the gateway endpoint.
The gateway endpoint is a gateway that you specify as a target for a route in your table, and the route
is for the traffic that is distant to support the services like Amazon Acidity and Amazon Dynamo, which
are supported both by Gateway, End Point and VPC endpoint.
Guys, there is no hourly or data processing charge.
You will be billed for each hour of that.
Your VPC endpoint remain a provisioned in each of these zone regardless of the state of its association
with the service.
The hourly billing for your VPC endpoint will stop when you delete it, and the hourly billing will
also stop if the endpoint service owner rejects your VPC endpoints attachment to their services.
For doing this, make sure you understand the two types of BBC endpoint and make sure to remember that
Amazon AC three and Amazon Dynamo TV are supported by a gateway endpoint, not an interface endpoint.
How you set up an interface and want to set up an interface endpoint.
Follow these general steps from the Amazon VPC console.
Specify the name of the service endpoint services or the NWS marketplace service you want to connect
to.
Then choose the VPC where you want to create the interface endpoint you.
Specify more than one subnet in different zone.
Doing so helps you to ensure that your interface endpoint is resilient to availability zone failures.
Choose a subnet in your VPC that will use the interface endpoint enabled by domain name system for the
endpoint.
If you are going to use a gateway and this will enable you to make a request to the service by using
its default DNS name.
Specify the security group to associate with the network interface and that security group rules will
control the traffic to the endpoint network interface.
Primary sources in your VPC.
If you do not specify a security group, the default security of the BBC remember that it will be the
VPC itself security group which will be implemented to the BBC.
End Point.
This is an example about how you can use the VPC when you create an interface endpoint.
The endpoint is specified DNS hostnames which are generated that you can use to go in, engage with
the services and either a service and as marketplace partner services and also a private DNS option
which can be enabled by default.
In this example, you will see that the hosted zone contains a record set for the default DNS name.
Now just remember here the hostage zone is the Route 53.
So if you are not familiar with the concept of hostage zone, go back and see the demo doing the Route
63 and how you can create a hostage zone and configure DNS record.
So in this particular scenario, the hostage zone will create a record set for the default DNS name
for the service.
For example, you can call it a kinesis built us east one, but Amazon did com which resolves to the
private IP address of the endpoint network interface.
And this enables your application to make requests to the service using its default DNS hostname.
And this allow your existing application to make requests done either a service through the interface
endpoint without requiring any configuration changes.
In this example, there is an interface in endpoint for Amazon Kinesis data stream and an endpoint network
interface in subnet.
Number two, private DNS for the interface endpoint has not been enabled and in instances in either
subnet can send a request to Amazon Kinesis through the interface endpoint.
Using the endpoint is specific DNS hostname in instances in subnet, one can communicate with Amazon
Kinesis HCM over that public IP address.
There is also another example where you can use a private DNS for the endpoint, which can be enabled
by the same way any instances in either subnet can use either the default DNS hostname or the endpoint
the specific DNS hostname to send request Amazon Kinesis data stream through the interface endpoint.
So by this we finished module seven.
So make sure to review those guys before you go to the Solution Architect exam, which are the on premise
network of the cloud connecting VCs.
You connect with these in the cloud by using a VCP and describe how to scale devices in the the and
how to connect VPC to supported in the US said this is.