Another video about cloud computing.
And now in this video, I'm going to explain the process of accessing abortion hosted from a Windows
machine.
So the first thing we want to do is to go and search for putty, a software that we need to download
to our computer.
Now.
Then we need to install putty.
And the process of an installation.
Just click next, next, next and then finish.
Then we want to go and open potty.
Just to see if it is working in a proper way.
Now go back to a w.
S and copy the public IP address of your version host.
Now, if you notice that this partial host is using a keypad name called FOC Key.
Now, this is for the people who are using the aquarium labs in the academy.
You need to go to the details and download a PPK file.
Now go back to your party.
And what's the username easy to use at the public IP of the bastion host of the easy to in the sense
that you want to connect to the go to connection increase the keep alive just basically to keep the
session alive for 60 seconds if you are away and in the off now we go to cross and get the baby care
fine that we just download to our download folder click open and now click accept.
You are now connected to the bus host.
So this is the process that we normally use to access any easy to machine with the public IP address
from policy in Windows.
Now if we want to access a private instance which is in a private subnet similar to what we have in
the Capstone project, what we need to do, the process is very simple.
We need to get again the Bulgarian key or the PPK file for that that you see through.
And you notice here that the web server and the Bastion host both use the same key.
Then we need to go to our project.
And download the key.
If you did not download the key before or in the previous step, you could go back to the AWOL details
and download the key.
Once we have the key downloaded to our computer.
Now we need to go to page and software that should be installed by this tool and we open it.
It will appear to the lower right corner beside the time in view of machine.
Now the process to connect to the private server will be simply done by configuring what we call such
passes.
So right click on the agent, add a key and then select that up user.
A fine.
No, it didn't go to potty.
And now from 40, we want to get the IP address of the bus in hospice because this is the only easy
to innocence with a public IP address that we can access.
Then we will put DC to use it at the public IP address.
You could also save that session, so you don't need to keep configure it every time you open 40.
Then go to assess it.
Now, this time we're not going to select the PPK file from here.
Only we need to allow Agent 40.
So check that.
And now this will allow the patient to pass the keys to the police session and you will be able to connect
to the question.
Host.
Now the next step is to access the web server, which basically has only a private ip address.
We need to go and copy the private IP address of the web server.
Then we go to the potty session and we put the command as us head, you see to the shooter at the private
IP of the web server in the private subnet and click enter.
Now you'll notice here that this is not going to work.
Why?
Because if you go to that web server and you check the security group, you will find that we never
opened the SSA to traffic to arrive to this.
Easy to understand.
So we want to basically create and add the new rule and then we will only allow the traffic to come
from the bus host to add an extra layer of security to our private instances in the cloud.
Now press control C and now repeat the command again and you will be able to connect successfully to
your private instance.
You could do alerts and you could do many things here.
Thank you for seeing this video and see you in the next one.