Another service that we can use is called a WAC Cloud Train.
It is a service that enables us to governance, compliance and audit of our A WAC account with the Cloud
Israel Trail.
You can monitor and retain account activity that is related to actions across your enterprise infrastructure.
With Cloudtail, it provides us with an event history or an account activity, including actions taking
through the ideal assignment console as the key or the command line interface.
This event history simplifies the security analysis and the resource change tracking and troubleshooting.
You can discover and troubleshoot security and operational issues by capturing a comprehensive history
of changes that happened in your address account.
You could also use Amazon even to bridge with Event Bridge, and that's no known before as Amazon iCloud
Watch Event.
You can define workflows that run, you can define workflow that run when it detects event with a cloud
literally records.
You can basically integrated with an Amazon event bridge.
You can define workflows that run when in the events that can result in security issues.
For example, you can create a workflow to add specific policy to S3 bucket when a cloud display logs
an API call that makes the public bucket the bucket public.
With a cloud trial, you can record important information about each action, including who made the
request to services, use the action platform and the parameters for the action and the response elements
that were retained by the end of this service.
The service also helps organization to meet the compliance and any auditing requirements that they must
adhere to with organizing users.
You can create an image group and we see once we put all users in the group, we can assign the same
permission to all members of the group to create a group that reflect a job function, for example,
like the advocacy group, the developer group.
You can basically put all users there and you assign the same permission to all of them.
With I Am, you can use a resource based policy, as we can see here in this example.
And based on that, you can see that this bucket has two main directories.
The home has a subdirectory for each user where they can store individual work, and the shared directory
has a subdirectory where a different team can store content.
If a new team member joins the organization as a developer, for example, you can take three action
to grant them the open access you need to add the new user to the item in group for developers, and
this group has an IAM policy already attached to it which can grant access to the example bucket.
Share the developer folder.
Then you need to create the US directory for that user and you attach and I am policy that you grant
access to the directory for and then you use it.
In this case, the new user will access both the right that actually is granted from the group and his
own personal directory with I role.
You can enable to define a set of permission to access the resources that are a user or a service needed.
However, the permission are not attached to an employer or a group.
The permissions are attached to a role, and that role is assumed by the user or by the service.
When a user assumes all the user prior permission are temporary forgetting address returns, temporary
security credentials that the user or application can then use to make a problematic request to a using
IAM role.
You don't need to share a long term security credentials for each entity that requires access to a resources
for service like Amazon, etc. Applications or services can be assuming the role to get access to a
specific service.
For example, to read or write assist.
Oh, let us show you how you can create an easy to profile and you will assign a role for an security
that's a create a democracy to and this is your tool.
I will use it mainly to access a necessary bucket, to list the bucket, to list the object inside the
bucket, and also to copy a demo file to that associated bucket.
I will keep everything to the settings, to the default.
I will add the tag.
I will call this demo of easy to to assign three and then I will configure a security group I need only
to enable the search part because I would access this easy to from my computer.
Now the easy two is ready.
So let us go now and create a bucket.
It is go to SS3 and we will create another.
Just to show you guys how the AC two could have a read and write access to unnecessary books to create
a demo market.
Again, this is will be a demo and to give it a unique name in this region.
So I'm going to call this cut photos, for example, too easy too.
And they will put the date of today.
And Happy New Year to you all.
I will keep that ACL to be enabled for the package owner and that will enable versioning as well because
I'm going to use and show you in the future video how versioning could be used to protect accidental
damage.
Now we have the bucket created.
So let's go back now to our 82 and we will download the PIM file and that being five, we will use it
mainly to access the easy to avoid search.
And from the AC two, I want to copy a file to the AC three.
Lets me download the PIM file.
If you are using a which account to do this demo, just to create a new PIM file for your AC two and
download it and give it to permission.
Search Mode 400 or you is Potti the link for my pocket video for the Windows user.
Let us go to the easy to and get the public IP address again for Potti user, it's the same.
You will use the same IP address in Potti click on yes.
Now we have access to the AC to what we want to do now is to check that we have access to the bucket
list secret file before touch demo.
This is we create a file and I will open the file in Nano and this is like file a demo file.
I will put some, some text in.
This is like this is a file to show the easy to to AC three and we will save now let us do now an Andreas
etc. copy copy them on the text to AC three and we will specify the bucket name.
You could go back to us three and copy the bucket name at this stage if you don't have it.
So let me open necessary in a new tab and this is my demo bucket.
I will copy the name and be careful here guys.
It's the name of the bucket not to the air.
And you can see there is a permission error.
We don't have the correct permission to be able to write to this bucket, even if we do a WC S3 unless
this means we don't even have a permission to S3 as a service.
Not only that bucket in a specify so let us go now to I am in I am there is a role created it's called
my activity role creation of the role is above the level of the cloud practitioner.
So we will show you this later on in the solution architect.
You can see here we are giving an easy to in a sense a full permission over and SS3 from the JS.
All we need to do now is to go to the AC to and from the ACTU.
We will basically modify the IAM role and we will assign the My AC three role to it.
It's the last one there in the menu and click on Save.
Now let us try to copy the demo file again to AC three and you will be able to see that this file is
obviously copied successfully.
It has been uploaded to us.
Three can go back to us three and check.
So the file is there and we can view it as well in the console.
Let us upload now a cat photo from my computer.
And the point here, I just want to make sure not only I can write to this activity, I could also list
any new object.
Remember AC three, give you give you half consistency for a new object and read after right consistency
for updated object.