Another feature that is supported with AC three is called Cross Origin Resource Sharing, and this is
also very important for the exam.
So course defines a way for a client with applications that are loaded in one domain, let's say your
domain and let's call this for example, a W i.e. once the user inside your page a click on an external
domain or a different domain, let's say Facebook dot com if cause not enable that kind of action will
be blocked.
But in SC three, you can allow this kind of behavior, which is the cause and once you allow it at
the client side to the application of your asset.
Three, This will allow across origin access to your Amazon asset resources.
Now how you would do that in a specific bucket normally course configure as an external document with
specific rules that basically identify the following the origins that you will allow to access your
bucket, the operation with a history type method that will support for each origin.
In this example we have put pause and delete are allowed for going to a domain called WWE example dot
com, which could be configured using Amazon Route 53 to be another SC three bucket, for example.
And the last object is operation is specific information.
Now why we sometimes need to refer from an AC three a bucket to another S3 bucket in order to cover
two domains.
For example example dot com and your domain name system should be a record and w w w dot example dot
com is another protocol.
So most likely you will end up creating two buckets to cover both.
One contains the actual website and the other you only use it with causative referring and configuration
just to point to the WW dot example dot com and let us now understand how we can host a static website
using the guided lab of module three.
In this lab we are going to create a bucket in Amazon S3 We will upload a sample content to that bucket
and we will enable access to the object and we update the website.
We have multiple use cases besides hosting a static live site, and the third use case is to use a three
bucket for stair storing data for computation and analysis.
And most likely this is will come with machine learning and big data.
So those large scale analytics projects such as financial transaction, clickstream analysis, media
transcoding, Amazon necessary can support this workload because of it is ability to horizontally scale
and enabling multiple concurrent transaction.
So for example, the diagram here is showing us an Amazon elastic compute cloud, easy to spot deflate
and those are basically created when the bid price for the spot instances is low or when an Amazon or
a cluster elastic MapReduce or cluster is spun.
After the compute capacity is available, the role and a process data is extracted from Amazon S3 and
also from another data source.
So the data is run through compute algorithms that integrate and transform it.
The result will be a processed data that will be loaded into different Amazon S3 bucket.
In this case, the data has been processed and the compute capacity is terminated to save one cost.
Finally, analytics tools such as Amazon, a quick site might be used to harvest meaningful insights
from the process data.
So this is just only one simple scenario how you can employ Amazon, etc. in a big data and machine
learning project.
You could also use it for backup and archiving of the critical data.
And this is very important also to understand because S3 is highly durable and scalable, it could work
very good for data, backup and archiving tool in this scenario.
Here, data is backed up from one on premise data center and also from a large number of Amazon, easy
to in instances running in a year, you can move long term data from Amazon S3 standard to storage to
assist re English in the process.
We will discuss now when we study Iglesia, but in fact this is will give you a reduced cost for those
objects and S3 will be able to move your data based on the usage pattern so you can specify to move
your data to Glazier, which is an archiving solution after 30 days or 60 days or 90 days if those data
are not accessed.
I know that Amazon, as the three objects that you can configure guys is to achieve higher level off
in your ability.
Is it cost?
Regional replication and the cross region application will allow you to basically copy the content of
all unmodified objects.
Pay attention to this guides all modified objects.
You copy those modified updated deleted objects to a replica in another ancestry bucket in another object
that are uploaded to the bucket in one region will be automatically copied to another asset, three
buckets in that other region.
And lastly, what is the data consistency model in Amazonas?
Three And seriously, this is very important for you to keep in your mind before Dixon Amazon S3 provide
us with read after right consistency for pots and all in you objects.
So any new object upload to AC three, you will read it after you write it.
So imagine the same objects.
There is two person one writing to that object and one reading from that object.
In this case, the previous version of the object will be retrieved.
The second option is eventual consistency for all the right pot and delete in all regions.
So that applies for all existing objects, not a new object.
In this case, if somebody trying to read the file and somebody is trying to write to the file, in
this case the right operation go first and then the read.
So if you put to an existing key a subsequent read my system, the old or stolen data or back dated
data, Amazon S3 achieves high availability by replicating data across multiple servers within the data
center.
So if there is a post request and it is a successful request, your data will be safely stored.
The information about this changes must replicate across multiple Amazon facility, which might take
time.
So the process to write and you object to Amazon etc. and immediately, unless the key is in that object,
until the change is fully propagated, the object might not appear in the list.
But if you have a process replaces an existing object and immediately tonight to read it until the change
is fully propagated and isn't necessary, we give you the previous data if the process deletes an existing
object and immediately try to read it until that process of deletion is completely and fully propagated,
Amazon etc. might retain the deleted data.
So you see the difference.
You need to pay attention to that.
So in summary, a city has to consistency with read after right for a new object and plots, as will
also give you eventual consistency for overrides.
So if you delete the object, most likely somebody's trying to read it.
He might get that deleted content.
So a process deletes an existing object and immediately lists keys in its buckets until the deletion
is fully propagated.
Amazon etc. list also those deleted objects.
Now how about storing data in Amazon?
As we said, Amazon S3 has multiple classes and the first class is the S3 standard, which is for frequently
access data.
You could also move your data from the standard one to Amazon S3 standard, any frequently accessed
class with the standard, any frequent access guys.
It's offer you all the benefits of Amazon S3 standard, but it runs on a different course model to store
any frequently access data such as an old digital images or older look files.
This will give you a three day minimum storage fee apply to any data placed in the SC three standard
i a another I can answer from this is called the Amazon S3 one zone infrequently access data.
In this particular class, it is suited the customer who want a lower cost option and who do not need
the availability and resilience of the AC three standard or AC three standard infrequent access.
So you need to pay attention to that.
If you use this with your disaster recovery plan, you need to pay attention if you are moving your
data backup to a31 zone and frequent access.
Remember, this is going to give you a cheaper cost model, but at the same time is not guarantee.
If the whole zone is not available and you need to recover and restore your data, maybe your data is
not available.
So you have to be careful whether you need to use one zone or standard infrequent access multi zone
for the exam.
Also they refer to ac3 standard I a on infrequent access sometimes with the multi zone just to the.
Distinguish this, that this is not one zone.
Now about the intelligent theory.
This is designed to optimize the course by automatically looking to your usage pattern from the SD three
standard and moving your data to a lower cost model, which is the intelligent theory.
This is very good for small monthly monitoring and automation fee per object.
This is basically will give you a good access pattern and at the same time you will be able to retrieve
your object and they also have a better durability.
Also, we have something called Amazon S3 Glacier or deep archiving.
Now remember, this is a C3 class which is designed mainly for data archiving.
You can store any amount of data at cost that are competitive and to keep your costs low.
You can also move those data from a central glacier to S3 Glacier Deep Archive, which is another lower
class of storage.
You can look at it as a cold storage at the same time when you put your archiving solution in a glacier.
You have a three different retrieval model.
To reduce the cost, you have to expedite retrieval, which make the objects available to you in 1 to
5 minutes.
You also have the standard retrieval, which an object retrieve may be between 3 to 5 hours, and you
have finally the bulk retrieve, which can complete within 5 to 12 hours.
In general, Amazon Glacier Deep Archive is the lowest cost.
This storage class in Amazon S3 is more suited for long term retention and digital preservation.
However, the data is stored across at least a three geographically distant availability zone and they
are protected by 11 nines of durability and the object can be restored within 12 hours.
So remember guys in Acetylene Glacier?
We have expanded the standard and bulk in deep archive.
We can get the object in 12 hour.
It is the lowest and achieve it.
Let us look now to something called the Amazon S3 Lifecycle Policy, a lifecycle policy.
You can control how your objects will be moved from a class to another.
You define a rule, and that rule will take action over the data.
So, for example, you want to move all the objects that you don't access in the last 30 days from ac3
standard to Amazon S3 standard, any frequent access.
And then you want to move the object from Amazon S3 standard, infrequent access after 60 days, you
want to move them to Amazon S3 Glacier and then you want to delete them completely after 365 days.
Now what is the course model in Amazon SS3?
Now with Amazon S3, you pay only for what you use and there is no minimum fee.
There is four course components that you need to consider when you want to use Amazon.
S3 is storage class, so you pay per gigabyte for the all objects that you store panel and each class
of object or storage class has its own pricing model per region.
So from one region to another, the cost could be different.
Now, when you transfer the data from AC three to the Internet, you need to pay for all parts copy,
post, list, get and select.
And the lifecycle transaction is including data that when you move the data from one class to another
and also data retrieval request, when you request to retrieve your data from a glacier, you also need
to pay.
However, there is no charge when you approach your data and when you want to transfer the content of
the bucket from Amazon S3 to cloud to front or to another service in the same region.
And there is no charge as well for any delete and consider liquids.
So when you delete an object or you cancel the upload of an object, there is no charge.
So keep this in your mind.
Now, before I forget, guys, also you need to pay.
If you transfer the content from AC three to another AC three in another region, you have to pay.
So to move data from Amazon, AC three to another parts, you can use the management console and we
will see this now in the demo.
Or you could use the command line interface similar to what we see here in the screen.
You can use the command NWC, AC three copy just dot text and this is will be copied to AC three, the
name of the bucket slash, also the name of the object because you have to specify this name because
this is basically the key for the object and this is how it will be stored physically in etc. You could
also use third party tool or W as tools and as the key to uploading large object as we would see like
multiple.
Part of loads accelerated the transfer.
You can also upload multiple art of the objects, especially when you have a large object.
We say the necessary a single object could be four terabyte.
In this case you can upload it all at once.
But this will never happen.
Using a drag and drop to the interface though, you have to use a tool or a third party tool or Amazon
and you can have the ability to pause a resume also similar to the any cloud storage tool that we use
normally.
You can pose at a zoom at any time and it give you an improved throughput.
However, there is something called Amazon S3 transfer acceleration, which is a better tool to speed
up the upload and this is will deal with your bucket via enabling fast and easy data transfer if you
are in which make it available in the locations of a cloud different and this is will be globally distributed.
So the data once it's uploaded to the AC three transfer acceleration, it will be routed to Amazon S3
over an optimised network path.
Now when you can use Amazon S3 transfer acceleration, when you have customers all around the globe
and you want to upload locally or centrally from multiple customers distributed in multiple countries,
when you want to transfer a gigabytes of data or terabytes of data across continents in a regular basis,
and when you have, for example, a very bad bandwidth and you want to upload files to Amazon S3 over
the Internet, then it is much better for you to use them as an asset re transfer acceleration, which
will I will show you now in the next demo now.
Lastly, sometimes you want to migrate to the cloud and you have a large object in beta white scaled
it.
In this case you can use a service.
It's called a W as is snow mode.
Snowball is a data transport option that does not require you to write any code or to purchase any hardware
to transfer your data to Amazon.
S3 All you need to do is to create a job in the management console and a snowball will be shipped to
you.
So there is no physical hardware that will be shipped to your data center, to your office, and you
will post the data in it, and then you put it back and you ship it back to Amazon.
So all you need to do is to attach it to your local network and to transfer the file directly into it.
And then you ship it back to your as closest region or to the nearest Amazon facility and the data will
be transferred into your account.
If you have large amount of data, what you can get is this no mobile even larger than the previous
one, which is the snowball.
It is snow mobile.
It is a data transfer option that operate in exabyte scale.
And exabyte is a 1 million terabytes or 1 billion gigabytes.
It should only be used to move extremely large amount of data into a w.
A snow mobile is a 45 foot long shipped container that will come to you in a semi trailer truck and
you can transfer 100 petabyte of data here.
It's normal.
So if you ordered this feature or this service to your on premise data center, it will use as multi
layer of security designed to protect your data include as well dedicated security personnel, GPS tracking,
alarm monitoring and 24 over seven video and also an optional security escort, ADT encryption with
256 bit encryption key.
And you could also use it as CMS keys to encrypt the data.
And it is designed to ensure both security and full chain of custody over your data.
So the last thing for today, guys, is choosing a region.
And we discussed this before.
So just to make sure we understand how we can select the best region for our application.
So first, you should consider data privacy law and your regulation and compliance requirement data
you storing in the US is subject to the law of the country and the locality where it is is stored.
Second, the proximity to your customer base and the latency, which is a very good and crucial factor
for your business, then it is the difference between using closest region and the forest.
Region is very small, but even a small difference in latency.
You can impact in your customer experience also the availability of service in that region and the cost
effectiveness because costs vary between regions.
So for example, at2 medium will cost in the.
Region to cent per hour, but in the Frankfort region it will cost 1.5 cents per hour.
So the last thing we want to do to understand a city is the challenge lab for creating a static website
for our cafe.
So they mentioned that they want to create a website, should also provide customers with business details,
the location of the store, the business hours and their telephone number, and they want to create
this first website for the cafe.
You will take the role of Nicky in this activity and work to produce the result that everyone back as
the cafe hopes you can deliver.
So the task are very similar to the guided lab, but here you will be given a code that you need to
extract it.
You create a three bucket to host your static groups like you upload the content to it and you create
a bucket policy to grant public re access.
And then you need to enable versioning on that AC three bucket and you need to set up a lifecycle policy
and you will enable as well across region replication.
So the find that a product of the lab will look like this.
You will have the cafe website served from one Amazon S3 bucket and the data will be replicated to another
S3 bucket.
Thank you for seeing this class, which is adding a storage layer for that, Kathy.