Now AWB support Containerisation.
But first, what is a container?
A container or a method of operating system virtualization that enables you to run an application and
its dependencies in a resource?
Isolated the process.
By using container, you can easily package an application code configuration dependencies into an easy
to use building block that deliver the environment and consistency and operational efficiency and developer
productivity and vision control.
So in enterprise we have multiple container services and they are supported Docker.
But what is Docker?
Docker is a software platform that packages software such as application into containers.
Docker is installed in each server that will host the containers and it provides simple comment that
you can use to build, start or stop a container.
Docker is best suited as a solution when you want to standardize the environment, reduce conflicts
between languages, stack and versions, and use containers as the service.
You can run microservices using a standardized code deployment and require a portability for data processing
in a WAC.
There is multiple services that support containerization and the first one is Amazon Elastic Container
Services, as we are going to see in the next demo.
It gives us the ability to manage our container and you can launch one or more a W as easy to in instances
and you will install Docker engine in each instance.
Then you will use the Amazon Elastic Container Service as a highly scalable, high performance container
management service that supports Docker containers and enables you to easily run your application on
a manage the cluster of Amazon.
Easy to instances in Amazon Elastic Container Service, we can launch up to tens of thousands of Docker
containers and second monitor their performance and manage their estate.
And we can also casual containers by using a built in casual or a third party scheduler, for example,
like Apache, Ms. OS or Blocks.
There is also Amazon Copper, an API service which support and open source copper NATI software for
container orchestration.
Copper Nati can work with many of containerisation technology, including Docker because it is very
popular in the industry and it is an open source project.
A large community of developers are using Copper Natty.
So Copper Natty enable us to build and deploy and manage the application at scale.
For this reason, we have the ADA as Kubernetes service.
So you can look at your application as a set of containerization that you need to manage in the cluster
with Amazon, Elastic Copper, Natty Service, you can manage those Kubernetes application and Docker
containers as a cluster Amazon Elastic Container Service automatically manage the availability and the
scalability of the cluster nodes that are responsible for starting and stopping containers.
You can schedule containers on a virtual machine.
You can also store cluster data and other tasks.
The last thing is the Amazon Elastic Container Registry, which is very similar to Docker Hub with Amazon
Elastic Container Registry.
It is a fully managed Docker container registry that make it easy for you to store, manage and deploy
Docker container images.
It is fully integrated with Amazon Elastic Container Service where you can store, run and manage those
container images for your application and you can specify the repository and the task definition that
you want to use.
In the next demo, we are going to explain each of those three component to support containerized application.
So let us look to the Elastic Container Service.
So when you go to the item use and you look for elastic container service or you select it from the
menu, this is will take you to the elastic container.
I've said this and we can see here we have Amazon, it has a container service cluster task definition
and this is where we can create the elastic copper that is service.
And this is the Amazon Elastic Container Registry Service, which is very similar to Docker Hub, which
is a very popular container registry where you can put your images and these images will be available
for the community.
Now in Amazon Elastic Container Service, the first step is to create a task definition.
So when you go to task definition and you click on it, create a new task, you have to select whether
you are going to run it in a gate, which is an enterprise managed infrastructure and it is a serverless
computing or an Amazon managed elastic container said this easy to select for this demo Amazon two and
then we click on the next.
So for task it is called this first task.
We don't have any role or any network mode that we need to worry about.
All we need to do is to add a container.
You have now two options whether you add the container from Docker hub like WordPress this WordPress
here, or you can basically add another service, let's say in Docker to help you want to run engine
X, so let us now run MDX in container settings.
You know, if you are familiar with Docker, you can pull this image and you run it as a container in
your machine.
But in this case here, I'm just going to run it as a test in container services in either these.
So let me call this engine and you need to pass the image.
Now, the image in this case is going to be engine X and this is will be the latest and is going to
get get me the latest image of engine.
You can specify hard limit like for example, 102 or 256 megabyte of memory.
You can also do port mapping between the host port and the container port like port 80.
You can specify a health check, you can specify an environment variables, and furthermore, you can
define the whole container using JSON format, which is the most common way.
When you want to configure, for example, a task in the U.S., you better configure it as a JSON formatted
task.
So in this stage, we managed to create a task and the next step we need to have the family of the task.
Now, the tasks family.
In this case we are going to put this container.
If you notice here, we are going to put this container in elastic container service so you could go
back to the engine and you specify what exactly you want to run in this task.
So now I created my first task and the next thing is I'm going to create now a cluster to create a cluster
in Amazon.
And as a container service you could go to the clusters and create a cluster.
You could go also to the get started, which can give you a tutorial of how you can create a sample
app or engine, whether you want it to be in elastic container service or FortiGate.
Now in my case, because I have an already a task that I already define, I want to click on it, create
a cluster and the option here we could create and it working only or we could create an easy to Linux
and it working or easy to add windows.
In our case we are going to select Easy to Linux Networking click next.
I will call this my first cluster and I want to run it on an demand or on a supporting instance.
I will keep it On-Demand and from the instance type, I need to select the T two micro because these
are the three tier one.
So T two micro is going to be more than enough number of instances here I will select one and the size
is going to be the root.
EBS volume is 30 gigabytes.
I don't need any SSL key and in the VPC we keep this to the default with elastic container.
I've said this will create a new virtual private now and then.
In the container instance, I am I to specify if I have a specific I am I want to pass now click on
create and this is need and I am role which is the lab role here and I'm going to click on to create.
So this is going to create the cluster and this is will take a few minutes for creating and launching
the Elastic Container Service and the EC2 instance you could go.
Go back now to your services or you open the elastic container service and then you tap.
And here you can see I have previously created a cluster and this cluster is basically running on FortiGate.
So I could basically run my same task, which is endemic in this FortiGate cluster.
So let me show you how to do that.
Once I have my elastic, elastic container service ready.
So I'm going to run my first task.
That is not a visioning and all I need to do is just to run that task.
I have to select the last type and this is going to be Linux.
You could go to the first task itself and create from it a modification.
So you can basically copy a new version of it and you can make this elastic container service to be
running in gates and in Linux operating system.
And don't forget to have passed the correct role.
Now remember here we are going to have version two, which is the one we are going to run in Floodgate
and version one we are going to run in and I will specify the memory, the minimum CPU.
And then here I need to specify the mapping of my port and here I just need to expose post eight because
engine is working at both ends.
So now first task three is going to run in my farm gate cluster.
So I'm going to go to the default in the task and I will run as a new task, make sure this is a three
and I need number of tasks here.
One I could put here as long as I need as many as I need, this is going to be the default to cluster
and then I will run the task.
As time is floodgate, I have a task.
This is Linux and the cluster VPC is going to be this VPC and this subnet and this subnet and the security
group.
I could edit the security group and I enable port 80 and then I'm on the task.
So the task will be running now and you will see after a while that this task is going to be run as
a service in the target.
It was you go back to cluster, leave this pending here, go back to the cluster and go to the first
cluster.
No micro cluster is really I could go now.
I run my elastic container service, but this time I will put version two and this will be running at
task.
As you can see here, it is not running.
So I could look to the task definition and I will find that the MDX is running at this port.
So if I opened this port I could see now this is welcome to Engine X and this is running from elastic
container.
I've said this, if you go back to my default, which is the fog gate, you will find that my task is
also running.
But this time it is task version three.
If I select it, this is will give me a public IP address and this public IP address and it is give
me a public IP address.
And if I open this public address at Port 80, I should be able to see MDX.