So how you will keep your fleet updated when you have an entire massive large infrastructure, how you
can use and utilize the cloud formation in order to keep those updated resources matching your requirements
and your business.
Well, there is a few other services that can help us.
Even if you use an infrastructure service, even if you use an infrastructure as a service tool like
either risk defamation to create and maintain your resources, it will be very helpful to have another
tool that you can use, for example, to address the ongoing needs of the configuration management of
your company.
These needs can happen both after the infrastructure, our provision or after that infrastructure is
up and running, either because Systems Manager is a service that addresses this challenge in the system.
Manager is a management service, is designed to be highly focused on automation, enable the configuration
and management or system that run on a premises or in will.
The systems manager enables you to identify the instances that you want to manage and then define the
management task that you want to perform.
In those instances, assistant manager is available at no cost and it can manage both your Amazon easy
to and on your premises resources few task that you can accomplish using the systems manager, collecting
a software inventory, applying operating system patches, creating systems image, configuring Microsoft
Windows operating systems.
So in the system manager, you can use it to update, manage and configure a fleet of AC two instance.
And there is multiple commands that you can do via the system manager agent in an AC two or even if
you have it installed on a premises server or a virtual machine, that systems manager agent guides
is being installed by default in most Microsoft Windows servers.
Am I and Linux am I in the U.S. like Ubuntu and Amazon Linux?
You must manually install it in the agent in another.
Easy to understand if you are using another scale or different operating system, a cloud formation
works very well with defining of your cloud resources and integrate fully integrate with the system
manager for automating within the guest operating system, another service that you can use and normally
they ask about it in the exam.
It is the ops works, it is a service for configuration manager.
You can use it to automate how easy to instances are configured to deploy and manage is different versions
of ops work and you need to understand the functionality of each one for the ideally as ops works for
automate Jeff is a deployment software is a very famous deployment software in computer science guide.
So you need to integrate.
If you have an existing Jeff in your infrastructure, you can fully integrate with Upwork.
So it's fully managed the automate server.
We provide workflow automation for continuous deployment and automated testing for compliance and security.
The second version of ops work come with Puppet, which is another large enterprise deployments area,
but it is widely used in the industry.
So Ops work for Puppet Enterprise provide us with managed puppet enterprise, server and slew of automation
tools that provide workflow automation for orchestration, automated provisioning and visualization
for traceability.
You can define configurations for your server in a format that you can maintain and version like application
source code.
The last one is called Atelier as Upwork's Stacks, which is a configuration management service that
helps you configure and operate the application of all kinds and sizes.
By using Jeff, you can define the application's architecture and the specification of each component,
including package, installation, software configuration and resources such as is storage.
So in this example, we demonstrate how a basic application might be managed using it.
We are also working stack and the fundamental unit of creation in almost all of the stack application
is a stack.
After the stack is created, you can add multiple layers to that a stack and you can build it out as
a set of interacting layers of related functionality.
In this example, we have a group of application servers, runs in an application server layer, and
the application run behind an elastic load balancing which can be defined using a load balancing layer.
So these include a front in the back end with the support of a relational database system which is also
can be defined in the database.
Out of this layer you can refer to multiple chef recipes if you are going to deploy and use Upwork in
an enterprise and the production environment.
Last thing is the ops work also work with cloud formation so you can use the two technology and they
complement each other.
You can use a cloud formation template to create the resources of your infrastructure, including VPC,
for example.
And you could then use another SQL formation template to create the UPS work that that will be deployed
in that BBC.
So both in the rest of the formation, the stacks are created in your account and you can use the ops
work to manage the application in section five of the dimension of your infrastructure.
We are going to look through that beanstalk and we have discussed Beanstalk before.
So just to quickly to review it, you can manage the infrastructure around application deployment,
which is a difficult task, it will be a time consuming and you might have a lack of consistency.
Elastic Beanstalk is another idea as compute service option.
It is a platform as a service offering the facilities for that quickly augment the scaling and management
of your web application.
It supports multiple languages like Java dot net, BHP, not just Python Ruby.
Go and look.
All you need to do is to upload your code to the Elastic Beanstalk and it will be deployed automatically
using one of those web servers, Apache Engine, X Passenger Homer and the alias, the infamous Microsoft
Web server.
In this example here, we can choose two types of embodiment.
When you work with Elastic Beanstalk, we can have a single instance which enables you to launch a single
easy to an instance, and it does not include load balancing or automatic scaling.
The other option is, as you can see in this example here, you can launch multiple easy to in instances
and this is will come with load balancing and ultimate scaling and you can refer back to the elastic
means or configuration page in order to monitor the scalability and the availability of your application
and to tweak to tweak it as well by defining the minimum, the maximum and the desired capacity of your
auto scaling.
It's very important to choose the right automation solution that suits your infrastructure needs.
So there is multiple services that are discussed in this module that can help you to achieve high level
of automation and flexibility in running your infrastructure as a code.
So make sure to review the Elastic Beanstalk, which is an easy to use application service for building
web applications along after work, which enable you to integrate current deployment and integration
services like Jeff and Puppet, both Elastic Beanstalk and Observer provide the higher level of service
than authoring and maintaining your address confirmation template to create the stack.
Remember as well, you can use TerraForm as a third party tool which is fully integrated with Adobe
Services.