You could also use what we call an individual security token service or a WAC as these.
So what is a WAC?
It is a web service that enables you as a to have an IM user, federated user or application to assume
an I am role that they want.
When you use the I assume role operation for that as user or role of that WAC as this API, you will
invoke that API call from the status and the Web service returns to you the temporary limited privilege
credentials that were requested by the IM user or the user that was authenticated through the Federation.
The example policy allows an IM user to assume any role that is defined in device account number as
long as the role name starts with, for example, this here in this slide.
You can also have a role based access control.
You can consider two different approaches to access control, the role based access control and attribute
based access control.
And these are really important.
For example, in role based access control you use historically on a premises and in the cloud users,
you want to grant explicit access with a set of preconfigured permission.
So for example, if you have a database administrator, network administrator and developers, you have
one or more network administrators who are also developers.
You would not create any new policy to grant those permission.
Instead, you can add those users to both roles.
This approach is familiar and has many advantages.
However, the problem is that the poor the person who maintains the permissions in this model might
find it that they must consistently update the permissions files to add access to asserting role each
time any you resources is a create.
Before you consider the second approach to permissions control, you should understand the tagging feature
in a WAC enables its customer to assign a meta data to their ideally as resources and identities in
the form of tax.
Each tag is SMB label that consists of a customer defined key and an optional value.
Tags can make it easier to manage, search for or even filter those resources.
Tax have many practical uses.
For example, you can create technical tags to identify that a resource is a web server, part of a
specific project, part of a specific environment like testing, development or production.
You can also create business tags to identify the department or the call center that this resource should
be built to.
You can also set security tags such as an in an identifier for a specific data confidentiality level
that are resource supports.
You can create up to taxpayer resources and these resources, each tag key must be unique and each tacky
can have only one value tag.
Keys and values are case sensitive.
Now let us look to attribute based access control so we know now that we can tag that resources.
So let us now understand how attribute based access control will work with attribute based access control
you can use to create a general permissions rules that is scaled with your organization.
And I am users have attributes that you created and applied to such as one or more tags with resources
also have an attributes like matching that tags that you also applied to the resources in this approach,
writing permissions is very straightforward the policy checks to see if an attribute that is applied
to an employer is also applied to the resources that they want to access.
When you create new immune cells and in new account resources, you apply the correct tags to the users
and to the resources.
So this is an example of applying an attribute based access policy to your organization.
In the first step is to create an identity such an item user or an email.
All these identities must have the attributes that will be used for access control purposes.
For example, you can apply the team developers and the project unique contact to the manager user required
attributes for a new resources.
You should create policies that enforce the rule.
You could require that a project attribute and a team attribute are applied to any resources when it
is created.
Configure Access Permissions.
Based on the attributes.
For example, see that an employer has the project equal unicorn and team equals disclose protect.
If that you are trying to access a resource that has matching value for the same two tags, then the
policy will allow the access.
Otherwise the policy will deny access to your configuration.
For example, you could try to create an Amazon Aurora database, in instance, without the required
tag.
In this case, the attempt should fail.
So I creating a database instance again with the required tag, and in this time you should be able
to create the resource successfully.
And you could trying to access the database instance as that Maddie used them.
Your access should succeed.
Okay, so with extending authenticated user, you can use identity federation because it are support
identity federation for delegated access to the WAC management console or the API Identity Federation
or external identities are granted secure access to the resources in your account without needing to
create an item user.
There is four primary steps that is needed.
When you use an identity provider to create a temporary credential for a user or application.
Identity Federation can be accomplished in one of three ways.
The first way is to use a corporate Microsoft Active Directory, for example, or a custom identity
broker application.
In this case, each option of those will use a WAC as tests.
The second approach is to create an integration that uses security assertion, markup language.
And this will be a third approach where you can use a web identity providers such as Amazon, Cognita,
Facebook, Microsoft, Google and so on.
How you can accomplish identity federation.
Using an identity broker in the process include the following steps.
I use that to access an application and the user interface there.
Use an idea and password and submit them.
Then the identity broker received the authentication request and then communicates with the corporate
identity store, which might be a microsoft Active Directory or a lightweight directory like an L dub
server.
If the S indication request is successful, the identity broker make a request to establish a status.
And this is why I told you guys go and make sure to understand the steps and how it can give you a temporary
security credentials to access the application.
The user application received those temporary individual security credentials and redirects them to
the address management console.
The user did not need to sign in directly and NWC with a different set of credentials insisted the process
only have a single sign on implementation or ISO because we use a single sign on and this single sign
on is recognized by the identity broker.
The user application could also use the same temporary address security credentials to access the address
services if the IAM policy document allow it.
If you want to integrate it with community session markup language, then the process involving the
following a step a user in your organization navigates to the an internal portal in your network.
The portal also function as the IDP, the identity broker, which can handle the as a as a trust between
your organization and the identity broker.
In this case, I authenticate the user against the identity store, which might be an elderly observer
or Microsoft Active Directory.
The portal received the authentication responses as an as a assertion from the identity broker.
The client forced the SML assertion under the assigned endpoint for us and and the endpoint communicates
with us this and it invokes the assumed role with SC al operation.
And normally they ask about this role and how exactly a third party with an open a standard can exchange
authentication and authorization data between an identity data broker and a W.
S services.
In the last step.
In step number five, the client received a temporary element of security credentials, and the client
is redirected to the address management console and is also authenticated with the temporary entry as
security credentials.
Now you might be saying both identity federation using S.M. L and Identity Federation with an identity
broker sounds very complicated and very hard to implement.
I can agree with you.
And the solution for that is Amazon need.
Amazon is a fully managed service is to provide us with authentication, authorization and user management
for both web and mobile application.
Amazon Community provides us with Rip Identity Federation, and it can be used to as the identity broker
that supports IDPs that are compatible with Open ID connect, and they have a federated identities integration.
So you can use identity provider like Amazon, Facebook, Google or any third party as well.
You create user pools.
So the two main component of Amazon communities are the user pool and the identity pool, a user pool.
And this is very important for you guys to understand.
A user pool is a user directory in Amazon community, it will be in NWC.
Users can sign in to a web or a mobile application using Amazon Community and they can also federate
through a third party identity federation, a broker, and in this case, all members of the user pool
have a directory profile that can be accessed through an SDK.
Now the identity pools enables the creation of a unique identities and a permissions assignments for
those users.
With an identity pool, users can obtain temporary credentials to access data, services or resources.
Identity pools can communicate with Amazon, incognito users pools, social sign in with Facebook,
Google and log in with Amazon.
And even you can use an open ID, which is an open source framework for authentication and authorization
to connect to your application provider.
So this is an example how you can employ Amazon Cognita In this scenario, the goal is to authenticate
a user using Amazon Cognita and then to grant that user access to another AWG service.
In the first step, the user signs in through an Amazon Incognito user pool and after they have been
successfully authenticated, receive user pool token.
The app exchanges the user pool token for elderly as credentials a through an Amazon community identity
pool.
And finally, the app user uses those credentials to access other individuals services.