All right.
In this section, we are going to look to multiple accounts.
There is two architecture pattern when you're using a WAC.
There is the multi VPC pattern in a single account and there is the multi account where a VPC in each
account will be related.
You can use a WAC to support different teams and departments in your organization and you can choose
between those two partnering to isolate and separate the resources that each team uses in the multiple
virtual private cloud or the multi VPC account in a single AWG account.
You have a centralized control and management with a minimum overhead where you could choose to use
a single Adobe account.
And normally we use them when we have a small organization where we tend to create multiple accounts
for these organization.
Now the second pattern, when you have a customer, they want to use their separate accounts and you
will have an account for div and production and each they usually associated with their own consolidated
billing.
This multi account powertrain enables them to separate different type of resources and provide them
with some security benefits.
If your business maintains separate environments for production dev and test, you could configure three
AWG accounts and have one account for each environment.
If you have multiple autonomous departments, you could also create a separate account for each organization.
So using the multiple accounts is more efficient a strategy than creating a single WAC account for common
project resources.
So those common resources might include domain name system, Microsoft Active Directory Content Management
System.
You could also separate accounts for the autonomous subprojects or departments.
This strategy enables you to assign permissions and policies under each department or project account
and grant access to resources across all accounts.
There is a few challenges for managing multiple accounts.
You must determine how to effectively manage security across all your accounts.
And if you replicate the policies that you define across all accounts to ensure consistency, it could
involve custom automation or manual effort or both.
You might be consistently asked to create more accounts which take time to manually create these accounts.
It's also might be difficult to track all the accounts and the purpose of each account.
It can also be very challenging to check and track the costs of each account in a large, big enterprise
organisation.
So you might also want to achieve that kind of centralized control, which is needed to ensure consistency.
FWC offers a service that is designed to address these management challenges, and this service is called
Italy's organization.
This organization is an entity that you create to consolidate its central view, manage all your A.W.
s account and you can determine the functionality of an organisation is through the feature of that
sit by you and you can enable them to access a specific service.
You can manage the money policies for multiple accounts and you can do service to create the groups
of accounts.
And then you can attach policies to a group so that the correct policies are applied across the accounts.
You could use the organization API to create new accounts and to add accounts to group.
Those policies that you attached to the group are automatically applied to the new account.
You can also set up a single payment method for all the accounts in your organization.
And this happens guys using the alias organization.
With Consolidated Billing, you can see a combined view of charges that are incurred by all your accounts,
and you can manage the use of the services at the API level.
You can apply a policy to a group of accounts that will only allow IAM users in those accounts to read
data from S3 bucket.
So here's an example of either organization.
So we can see that we have multiple accounts each account.
They have an access to a specific service so we can create an organizational unit for the internal I.T,
for the engineering, for the dev and for production.
Each organizational unit can be assigned to an account, a specific member or user or a group account.
And now you can define a service control policy that will apply a specific permission restrictions to
specific member accounts.
Then you attach that service control policy to the root or the organizational unit or a specific account.
So pay attention, guys, that the service control policy is going to be attached or it could be attached
to a root or organizational unit or a specific account.
There is a few characteristics for the service control policy.
It will enable you to control which services are accessible to IAM, user or the group of user.
If you have a specific policy that you want to apply across multiple accounts, it will be much easier
to define those policy inside of this control policy and then replicate those permission settings into
IAM policy documents in each account.
The Service control policy should be used with.
I am policies that are defined in each individual account and you can think of the service control policy
as providing general boundaries on the services engine repair automation that users should be allowed
or denied access to.
Then you can use I am policies to set more examples of access that are specific to each individual.
You can also through the service control policy that a block or deny access to a certain services.
And you can also define a service control policy that allow access to asset services.
You might decide to create a service control policy that enforces that tagging of resources.
By doing so, your tagging strategy for access, control or cost allocation can remain effective when
in your resources are created in your account.
And this is will take us to the challenge lap controlling individuals account access by using IM.
So after speaking with Matthew about the cafe's infrastructure, Sophia realized that she must address
some basic security concerns about the way that the cafe staff has been using the AWB accounts.
The cafe is now large enough for the team members who build, maintain or access.
Applications on AWB are specialising into roles such as developer or database administrator.
They haven't made an effort to clearly defined what level of access each user should have based on their
roles and responsibilities.
So what are the tasks that we want to do in this lab?
First, we want to configure an image group with policies and IM user.
We want to look in as Nicole and testing the access of that user.
Then we will configure an IM for database administrator user access and they want to log in as a database
administrator and resolving the database connectivity issues if there is any.
We will also use the I Am policy simulator for debugging, creating and troubleshooting a custom.
I am policy with the aid of the visual editor.
The final product of this lab is going to look like this.
You will have.
An App developers group and Adobe Admin a group.
We want to make sure that both user Olivia and Nicole they have a proper access using the proper IAM
policy.
And don't forget the cafe rule which needs to be attached to the AC two instance.
So you will use the cloud nine with easy to, in a sense, as a dev machine.
Then you only create a production machine out of this first easy in this sense, and then you will share
it with another user to see if they will be having the proper access to the ADRs where the media DB
is currently running.
This lab should take you about 80 minutes by this we finished module eight, and in this module there
is a few things you need to pay attention to.
We want to explain the purpose of the identity and access management users, groups and roles, the
difference between roles and users.
You should have the ability to describe how to allow user federation within an architecture to increase
security.
You want to recognise how in the organization service control policies increase security within an architecture
in a large organisation.
And we want to describe how to manage multiple this account and how we can configure and users.