[Autogenerated] databases are a fundamental piece
of nearly every web application.
They are an efficient tool to store and retrieve data quickly that have been in
use with any type of application for a long time installing and managing
databases introduced a completely different set of considerations to the
software development life cycle that can often be randomizing and time intensive
updates to software performance tuning, backups,
all of these necessities for database health require a lot of work
and can sometimes require hiring someone completely different to a
team just to manage this concern.
Luckily this need is not unique and is required by enough companies that amazon
has provided a solution relational database service allows you to easily create
and configure relational databases running on ec.
Two instances these database instances are managed by a W.
S in which they handle many maintenance activities that you can
configure some of the tasks they perform our operating system
and minor version database upgrades,
periodic backups and system health monitoring.
Combined with quick creation and easy configuration RDS is the
best solution for working with databases in AWS.
When you create a database instance on RDS, it creates an ec two instance.
Under the covers installing an appropriate operating
system and database engine because of this,
you choose the size of the ec.
Two instance that is powering your database This turns out to be very
important since an underpowered Ec two instance won't be able to process
queries very well and will impact your upstream application.
Therefore,
think carefully when choosing the instance type that will power your database,
you do have the option to change the instance type once the database has
been created in response to increased load but from my experience that
change can be a time intensive activity.
The data inside a database is sometimes the real value of any company.
So it's incredibly important to keep it safe, secure and available.
There are few features that RDS provides that enable this.
The first feature is periodic backups of your database configured by default.
RDS will take a backup of your database daily during a
backup window that you can choose.
The backup can be stored from one day up to 35 and using this feature,
you can restore your database back to a certain
snapshot in case your data gets corrupted.
The second feature RDS provides to make your data more
available is multi AZ deployment.
AZ standing for availability zone,
if you turn multi AZ deployment on for a given database AWS
will create a replica of your database and another
availability zone in the same region.
If for some reason one availability zone goes down or
your specific database goes down.
RDS will automatically fail over to the instance
and the other availability zone, ensuring your database experiences.
No downtime.
The last feature I want to highlight with RDS is the ability to create a
read replica of your database this is essentially a copy of your
database that is not being used in production.
The copying of data to this replica is done with eventual
consistency so it won't impact the production database.
Read replicas are perfect to let analysts and developers query
data without impacting the customer experience.
Read replicas are different from multi AZ deployment and that
the read replica will never be failed over to. It is only for non production usage.