[Autogenerated] for our Pizza Lovers application we want to create and
configure a VPC to deploy R E C two database and Alaska cache
instances into for the purposes of this course.
We're going to create a simple VPC with two public subnets.
We will subsequently launch all instances into one or both of the sub nets.
This diagram shows a rough architecture for what we're aiming
for throughout the rest of this course.
In this clip we're going to lay the groundwork and
build out the VPc and submit layer.
We'll start in the AWS management console, go to the VPc dashboard.
The first thing we'll take a look at is the resources by region section.
You may notice something a little odd here.
It looks like you've already got a VPc some sub nets and
other resources that someone created.
In truth,
this is a default VPC that is pre existing when you create your AWS account.
We could easily use this default VPC for our resources
but where would the fun be in that?
We want to make one from scratch to get the full experience so ensure
your in the correct region you want to be working in.
Believe me,
I confused myself switching regions all the time at work
then click the launch VPc wizard button.
Our first option is to decide what kind of VPC
configuration we want amazon to start us with.
Here's the private public subnets set up I mentioned and you can also see
options to create a VPc with a VPN connection will pick the configuration
that is pre selected and the easiest as well.
A single public submit click select now.
We've got more details to enter the first is the IP cider
block for the resources created in this VPc.
This is the range of IPs that will be assigned to
created resources For our purposes.
The 10.0.0.0 block is fine.
Now let's give this VPc a name to distinguish it from the default VPc.
Obviously it'll be named Pizza Vpc.
So enter that here.
Now we'll configure our public, submit.
The cider block for the sub Net is a subset of the V p c
block which will be 10.0 dot 0.0 slash 24.
This basically means the resources launched in this sub net will
have a range from 10.0 dot 0.0 to 10.0 dot 0.2 55.
For their I P addresses for availability zone,
you may see something different than I do since our regions might differ.
These availability zones are basically data centers that have superfast
connections to each other but are physically isolated,
deploying two different availability zones is done to
add redundancy in case of a disaster.
We will end up adding another sub net after this Wizard is done
which will be in a different availability zone.
So select the first availability zone that you have available
in this drop-down for the sub net name.
Let's name IT Pizza Sub Net.
A The other options will stay as they are and now click create
VPc after the wizard has done its magic.
You'll be at a confirmation screen saying you are ready
to launch instances into this VPc.
The routing table the VPC was created with currently
doesn't have any way for instance,
is to connect to the internet so we do need to add an entry to
the routing table to allow all traffic to go through an internet
gateway into the public internet.
An internet gateway is basically just a connection to the internet.
There isn't really any configuration beyond that.
In the VPc list, select the I.
D.
Next to Pizza VPc and then in the details section,
click on the link under route table.
This will take us to the round table used by our VPc.
Click on the routes tab here is the single entry that says any IP address
referencing our local VPc cider block should resolve locally.
Let's make a new entry.
So click edit routes and then add route In the
destination field will put 0.0.0.0/0, which basically means anywhere.
Then in the target column, expand it and select the internet gateway option.
You should have one result available to select here with an I D.
Starting with I G W.
This is the pre created internet gateway for your VPc,
click on it and then click save routes.
Now we've configured our VPc to let outgoing traffic reach the outside world.
We will be launching our application using auto scaling groups
and so I want us to get some experience deploying into multiple
availability zones because the sub net can only exist in a
single availability zone.
We will need to create more subnets to deploy into different availability zones.
Let's add one more public,
submit to cover another availability zone in our region,
click on the submit section on the left of the screen,
then click create sub net first,
you'll select the VPc where the sub net will be created in the drop down,
select Pizza Vpc.
Next give the, submit a name, enter Pizza dash,
submit dash, b in the availability zone.
Drop down,
select a different availability zone than the one that you selected
with the sub net that we created in the VPc wizard.
Now the cider block is pretty important since we don't want the IP
ranges to be conflicting between the two subnets here,
enter 10.0 dot 1.0 slash 24.
This will give us another different set of 255 I P addresses
that are different than the other sub net.
Now click create sub net.
If you remove the submit IDE filter in the sub net list,
you should now see both Pizza sub nets that we created and you
can see that they're IP ranges are different.
There is one more thing that we need to do with subnets.
Both of our public subnets have the auto assign public
IP address is setting configured to disabled.
This means that if resources such as ec two instances are launched in that
submit they will not get a public IP address assigned to them.
If we leave it as it is,
we would need to add a nat gateway to our VPc to enable these
instances to connect to the outside internet while the way that we
have it is the most secure way to set up your sub net not
assigning those public iP addresses,
it does introduce a problem for us and that's cost nat gateways are
really expensive and so I want to avoid creating one in this course
instead will enable public I P addresses for our subnets and that will
make sure that our instances have them,
they'll need this later specifically when they're connecting to S3 now
this does make those ec two instances less secure,
it makes our VPc less secure because then those resources are accessible from
the outside internet because of the public IP address but it's going to be
more convenient for us in this course so just keep in mind the security angle
when you're doing this in the real world,
go ahead and select the first Pizza submit and then select the
actions drop-down and select the modify auto assign IP settings
option Check the box for enable auto assign public I P V four
addresses then you can click save,
that's all you have to do now un select that first,
submit and select the other.
Pizza, submit and just follow those same steps.
This is going to configure it so that when we launch any instances
or resources into either one of these sub nets,
they'll be automatically assigned public I.
P addresses and they'll be able to connect to the outside internet,
which is going to be a lot easier for us in this course now we have a VPC with
two public subnets in different availability zones were all configured and
ready to begin creating instances in these sub nets.
B P C is much deeper than what we've been able to cover here,
but you should have a good grasp on the basics and feel comfortable trying out some more complicated configurations by yourself.