[Autogenerated] there are a few different ways to access AWS and in
this course we're going to work with all three.
The first we'll look at is the web console.
If you've already created an account with a W S,
then you've already seen this console,
it's the first screen you're introduced to after logging
in and it can be a little intimidating.
Although AWS has made great strides over the years to
improve the experience in their console.
If you don't know what you're looking for,
then you're likely to get more than a little lost.
The best way to find a service to get started with
is to use the search bar here.
You can also view all the services available by clicking here or here
At a current total of 174 available services in Aws.
I'd suggest just sticking to the search bar.
The console is where you're going to spend a lot of time
configuring and creating resources.
It's a good tool and doesn't get in the way of working with a WS.
Each service has its own dashboard and configuration options.
We won't be able to cover all of them in this course,
but there is a consistent taxonomy and logic that all
the console dashboards follows.
So moving between them and learning a new one isn't that difficult in this
course will likely be spending about half our time in the web console since
the visual representation and structure of most of the service
configuration options are best in the console.
I feel it's one of the best places to get your feet wet with each service.
Oh, and one last thing.
Make sure you're using a modern browser to get the best
performance out of the Web console. In this course, I'll be using Firefox.