[Autogenerated] we've learned some of the concepts of RDS.
So let's move on to the AWS management console to
make our own database instance.
Here's the RDS dashboard over on the left side of it is the dashboard menu.
You can see options for things like databases,
snapshots, submit groups and many many other things.
Let's make our Postgres database now.
So click the create database button.
There are two main methods to use when creating a
database instance Standard create and Easy,
create the Easy create method,
removes many options when you're creating the database.
Makes a little easier but it actually makes it
where you can't do certain things.
I honestly don't use Easy create much because I usually actually need
the options that it removes for simpler setups.
You know, it could probably work but I don't really recommend using it.
So leave standard creates selected here.
Next we'll choose our database engine.
For this course.
We're going to use PostGres.
SQL a popular open source relational database engine, click the Postgres option.
You can then choose the version of the database engine because we want to
stay in the free tier for this course as much as possible,
choose one of the 12.
versions.
The T two micro instance type we want to use isn't actually
available for any higher versions than that.
The template section will automatically set some
recommended configuration options for you.
You will be able to change them later.
Unlike with the Easy create method but it will at least reduce
the number of options that you have to choose.
So select the free tier option here.
Now we'll start configuring the database many of these options are
already pre defined in the demo code so just make sure that you're
following along with the values that I'm entering.
So the code works first we'll give the database instance a name,
enter pizza dash DB here,
then create a master user name and password that
you use to log into the database.
Instance,
use postgres for the user name and password all lowercase for the password.
I know very secure.
Now for the instance, type or instance class as they're calling it here,
it should already be configured with T two dot micro
because of our free tier template selection.
Next is storage storage.
Doesn't really matter for a demo.
We're not going to be using more than 20 gigabytes.
So just leave it as it is.
And then you can skip down to the connectivity section.
We do need the database instance to be in our Pizza VPc.
So select that from the VPc.
drop-down then select the radio button for Yes, in the public access option.
This gives a database instance,
resolvable DNS to the outside internet It basically makes it so we
can connect from somewhere other than the VPc Now in a production
setting you'd want this to actually be No,
because you want it to be more secure but for the purposes of this demo project,
we want to get access from our local development
environment at least in the beginning.
So um once you've got everything running in AWS you
could probably change this to a no next.
We want to make a new security group for the database instance.
This will make it easier to configure specific rules for the database instance.
And for our application instances choose to create new option under
VPC security group then named the security group.
Pizza Dash R.
D.
S.
Dash S.
G.
When this security group is set up,
it's going to create a single rule for the database,
giving access to your current IP address on the database port.
It looks it up with the browser.
This will make it really easy and convenient for us
to connect in the following video.
Now scroll down to the larger additional configuration section and expand it.
We will want to have an initial database set up for us by a W.
S.
So enter Pizza underscore Lovers into this field and
that's all the options we need to select.
So scroll all the way down and click create database.
This database creation can take some time but you can view the
instance in this list as it's being created just to kind of check
up on the progress Now in the next clip we're going to connect to this database instance