[Autogenerated] while most of the AWS services can be
interacted with over typical TCP connections.
Amazon also provides several software development kits
to make interacting with resources.
Even easier,
these s D K s are maintained by amazon developers and released
in popular programming languages like java,
.NET Javascript,
ruby and Objective-C Each SDK provides a robust API that enables you to
interact with services and resources inside your code base.
The documentation for each sDK is large,
simply because of the volume of interactions you can perform with every service,
we won't have enough time to cover even the majority of services in this course,
so we'll just focus on the most used ones in order to
connect our local code to the cloud.
We will need to use an AWS access key to properly configure
the SDK to access our account in the cloud.
This configuration will be used implicitly by both the SDK and the AWS cli tool.
In this course, we are going to be working with a no Js web application,
so we'll be using the javascript SDK to extend the application into a W S.
The SDK APIs are quite similar between languages,
so moving to a different sDK after watching this course shouldn't be a big stretch