[Autogenerated] now that we have access to our instance.
We need to update and install some software.
If you have disconnected from the instance,
connect again with the command SSH dash I path your PIM file E C
two dash user at elastic iP of your instance.
Now the first thing we'll do is to update any
packages in here that are out of date,
run Sudo yum update and then why if it prompts for an installation,
the next step is to install node on our instance so
that we can run the demo application,
we'll need to update our repositories and the yum package manager and then
install it that way in the ec two instance prompt enter this command which is
long and will sound really weird if I actually read it to you wait for it to
finish and in the following prompt, execute Sudo yum install dash y.
Node.js once that completes you should have knowed installed.
So let's try it out by executing node dash V and you
should see a node version output.
Now that we've updated our instance,
we're ready to transfer over our demo application code,
we will use SCP for this transfer,
this is installed by default on Mac and Linux for Windows
users SCP comes with open SSH so if you've already installed
open SSH then you have SCP as well.
If you're still logged into the instance we do need to log out first.
So type exit at the prompt and it should return you to your system prompt
before we copy our Pizza Lovers files to our ec two instance,
let's make sure and delete the local node modules folder.
This holds all of our no dependencies and it takes up about 60
megabytes copying this over is going to take extra long so we'll just
re download the dependencies from our instance.
Once you've deleted that folder entered this command SCP
dash R dash I the path to your PIM file.
The local path to the demo code E C two dash user at the ec two.
IP colon slash home slash easy to dash user which was also really long.
This will copy the contents of your local Pizza Lovers folder to a Pizza
Lovers folder that will be created on the ec two instance.
It will take some time to copy the files over.
Remember we have a micro instance so the CPU and network
performance are very low network intensive activities like
downloading or uploading may take a while.
Once it's complete,
go ahead and log back into the instance with our SSH command when logging in,
you will be placed in the ec.
Two user directory which is where we copied our demo application code two.
Change directories into the Pizza Lovers directory with the command cd,
Pizza dash Lovers.
The next step is to install the no dependencies into this folder.
So run the command npm install when it finishes we can start
our application up with the command in p.
M.
Start now the output message will say the app is running at a 10 dot x.
IP but remember this is the internal IP Open up a browser window
and enter the elastic IP then colon and the port 3000 hit go and
you should see Pizza Lovers load up.
Hold on.
Is this pizza lovers running on an ec two instance?
Yes, it is.
You've successfully deployed your first application to AWS.
Congratulations, go ahead and make yourself a pizza to celebrate.
Now that we've got an app running successfully in ec two, let's make it scale by setting up a load balancer and an auto scaling group.