[Autogenerated] sometimes you may find yourself deciding between RDS and a
relational database or dynamo DB and a non relational database.
I found myself thinking through this before as well and there are a
couple of aspects that RDS and dynamo DB are opposites on which
should help you decide which to choose.
RDS like a typical database can be used for many different purposes.
Putting data in and getting it out is very efficient.
One aspect of relational databases is the strict schema of the data being stored
when you're developing and adding properties to your data.
This schema constraint can become frustrating as I've experienced.
Dynamodb on the other hand, is extremely flexible with how your data looks.
You can add a new field at any time and put it in a table with
data that have different schema as long as your primary key is
there Dynamo won't complain.
This flexibility obviously speeds up development time and
makes it easier to iterate because of this,
I like to say that Dynamo DB has strong storage
flexibility on the other side of this however,
is querying the data to get data out of a database,
you typically need to give it some factors to look
for enquiring relational databases.
Excel and structured query language or SQL is
perfect for getting data out however, you need it.
The strict schema of relational databases actually make it easier to query data.
DynamodB however is not very flexible with querying data.
Getting out items by primary key is fast and easy but trying to query
based on other properties becomes very difficult.
You can create secondary indexes on other properties of your data,
but again it's just matching an ID.
You'll quickly find that RDS has the strongest query flexibility.
So to me this is a deciding factor between these types for a given dataset Do
I need storage flexibility or do I need query flexibility?
For storage flexibility?
I would choose dynamodb.
If I'm only ever pulling data out by I.
D.
Then I don't need query flexibility and can opt for dynamodb.
But for query flexibility I'd go with rDS strict schemas
can make it more tedious to work with.
But if I need to do range queries or query on multiple properties, RDS is going to be the best choice.