[Autogenerated] imagine getting that call at two a.m. You know the one I'm
talking about your manager shouting through the phone that the production
side is down and why did his boss have to call him?
Wondering why the ceo couldn't access his product.
It's a pretty bad situation right?
Being aware of the status of your application and resources
is a vital part of deploying any application to production
and especially in the cloud.
I doubt you want to manually watch your resources,
which is why CloudWatch might end up being one of your favorite.
services CloudWatch is a service that allows you to set
alarms for various metric thresholds.
Some examples are CPU usage on ec two instances provisioned
throughput for dynamodb tables or billing estimates by setting
an alarm and adding a notification.
CloudWatch will send out an alert anytime the alarm is triggered.
You can easily configure where the alert should be sent to using the
simple notification service and at 10 cents per alarm each month you
can add as many alarms as you'd like to ensure you're notified
anytime something eventful happens,
notifications can be sent as email sms http requests and
more cloudwatch alarms don't stop.
It's simple notifications however,
you can also configure an alarm to trigger an action
when a certain threshold is passed.
This action-based response is available for ec two
instances and auto scaling groups an example would be if
the incoming network requests to an ec.
Two instance pass a certain threshold then you could trigger an auto scaling
group action that adds another ec two instance to the group.
In fact auto scaling groups use CloudWatch under the covers
to trigger their own scaling actions.
After setting cloudwatch alarms,
you can rest easy knowing that your application can auto scale as needed and, if any other operation needs your attention that you'll be notified swiftly.