[Autogenerated] amazon Simple notification service,
also called SN S is an integral companion to CloudWatch allowing
you to easily push alerts to a group of notification endpoints The
main structure in S and S is the topic.
A topic is used to create a unique amazon resource name that
can then have notifications sent to it.
Once you subscribe to a topic with an email or sms number,
any notification sent to that sNS topic will then be communicated to your
subscribed endpoint In this way you can easily organize notifications in a
simple and extensible way before we create our first alarm,
we should set up a notification topic and subscribe to it with the
notification type for this example will set S and s up to send us
an email topics are region specific and can only be notified by
alarms in the same region.
We will be creating a billing alarm and since those are only
available in the north Virginia region,
we should switch into that region before we create our
topic in the top right of the console, click the region.
Drop down and select U.
S.
East in Virginia.
Once the console has refreshed,
click into the Universal search bar type SN s and then hit
enter once the results have come back with the simple
notification service option at the top,
we can use this wizard to create our topic.
Since this is going to be sent to your email, let's name the topic.
Admin underscore email now click next step you can enter something for
the display name if you like but it's not required.
The rest of the page are different optional configurations.
We don't need to change any of these.
So click the create topic button now at the topic screen you
should see a subscription section and this is where you'll
be able to manage in points.
Subscribe to this topic.
Let's subscribe to this topic with our email click on create subscription.
The drop down for protocol will show you the types of
endpoints that can subscribe to this topic,
choose email in the end point field.
Enter an email you'd like the notification sent to.
Once you click create subscription,
a confirmation email will be sent to the email entered,
click the confirm email link in the confirmation email and the
subscription will be updated to indicate it's active now our
email is ready to receive notifications. Let's set up our first CloudWatch alarm.