[Autogenerated] in this clip will configure some settings for our distribution,
navigate to the cloudfront dashboard in the distribution list,
you can see the distribution we created with the status of deployed,
which means it's ready to go click on the ID link and will be
taken to the settings for this distribution.
You can see there's quite a few tabs here and that demonstrates the
amount of control you have over this distribution.
The general tab has many of the settings we configured
for this particular distribution.
The origins, tablets,
the origins that are providing content for the distribution,
you can see the one that we created but you can also see that you can create
more than one origin to be used with this single distribution.
That means you could have multiple applications,
responding and cash behind a single cloudfront URL the behaviors tab shows
the default behavior we configured in the previous form,
you can create different caching behaviors for different path patterns.
We've got general caching set up for application but I'd like to have a
different behavior for our pizza routes since they should not change ever
click on the create behavior button will start by defining what path
pattern this behavior will be for we want for these settings to apply to
any pizza our site serves.
So enter pizza slash asterisk.
The elastic beanstalk load balancer is the only option in the next origin
drop-down so select that the rest of these options should look familiar since
we configured them in the distribution creation screen,
select redirect http to https.
In the allowed methods we only want to cash the get
method for getting pizza pages.
So leave it as is for the cash policy.
I want to set a higher T tl so click create a new policy name the policy.
Pizza Lovers Pizza cache Now in the minimum T T L let's be more aggressive.
Set it to 7200 seconds which is two hours now we do still need to pass on our
cookies since we want to keep our users logged in session.
So select include specified cookies and the cookies,
drop-down and add that Pizza for life cookie peas,
Easy for life.
L Y f E.
Now click create then in the distribution page that we were on,
click the refresh button next to the cash policy and select
Pizza Lovers Pizza cache Now click create Creation of a new
behavior means the entire distribution must update and this can
take another 10 minutes or so.
In the meantime I wanted to show you some of the
statistics and data that cloudfront gives you.
Click on the cache, statistics, menu option on the left.
This page gives you plenty of data on how your distribution is performing.
It is really helpful when determining if your distribution settings are
appropriate at the top are filters that allow you to choose time ranges and
distributions to view data for this chart is my favorite.
It shows you what percentage of responses came directly from the
cloudfront cache which they call hits and what percentage of requests
had to be proxy seed to the underlying origin,
what they call mrs.
There are also errors which are requests that the distribution
just couldn't find any content for like 404s.
These hits and misses are important because the more hits you have
tells you that your cloudfront distribution is doing its job and
it's responding correctly to request,
thereby reducing the latency for your users.
Another useful set of data I found is the popular objects report,
which shows you the most requested endpoints for your distribution.
Using the number of hits and misses.
You can use this data to optimize your distribution for speed.
Now the cloudfront distribution should be finished updating.
So let's take a look at what we've done back in the distribution list copy
the URL under domain name for the distribution we created,
paste it into a new browser and hit go.
Pizza lovers should load up normally now running behind a cloud front distribution and everything should work as expected.