[Autogenerated] with CloudFormation you can automate the creation
of infrastructure but with elastic beanstalk you can automate the
deployment of your application.
Elastic beanstalk will handle scaling monitoring and any other resource
provisioning required to get your app to run efficiently in a W S.
All you need to do is upload your application code to elastic
beanstalk and it will take care of having the correct os and
platform installed for your application.
It differs from CloudFormation in that CloudFormation will
provision new resources but doesn't necessarily care what
is running on those resources.
Elastic beanstalk is purely dedicated to running your application.
Elastic beanstalk has a few key structures that it uses to organize itself.
The first is an application,
think of an application as a parent container for a
logical application like Pizza Lovers.
Each application must select a platform to deploy on such as Java no Js or
python An application has references to many different application versions
which are basically different versions of your code.
These versions are stored in S3 and can be used to deploy new versions
of your application or roll back in case of an emergency inside of an
application are one or more environments.
An environment has independent configuration values for the am I an use
instant size auto scaling configuration and more an environment will have an
application version deployed and running on it.
You can have multiple environments and an application with
different application versions deployed to each.
The best use case that I know for having multiple different
environments is if you want to have a production environment
and a development environment.
both are logically running the same application, just different versions of it.
You can easily deploy an application version to the
production environment after testing and validating that
code and the development environment.
Through the process of creating an application and an environment,
we'll see a lot of the options that you're able to
configure an elastic beanstalk. So let's go do that.