[Autogenerated] Let's create an application and elastic
beanstalk and deploy Pizza Lovers.
This process is going to be much less painful than the
process we've been following until now,
elastic beanstalk is going to take care of all of that for us.
Go to the elastic beanstalk dashboard in the AWS management console will set
up an application and an environment at the same time.
So click the create application button, let's name the application.
Pizza Dash Lovers.
Now scroll down and in the platform drop down select node,
then select the highest version of node available now in application code,
select the upload your code radio button.
It expects a zip of our entire application so we need to zip it up.
You can do this however you want but I'll use the zip
executable in my command prompt back in the console,
click the choose file button and select the zip file you made and uploaded.
Let's give this application version a name that will make it easier to
identify if we ever need to enter first release.
Now click the configure more options button so we can
continue setting this environment up here is the
configuration screen for your environment.
It's basically the same as the configuration options you'll use
after the environment is already created first.
We need to ensure the application is in our Pizza Vpc.
So scroll down to the network box and click edit in
the VPc drop down select Pizza VPc,
then select the checkbox to give the instance is a public
iP Next select both of the sub nets that are available
and then you can click save.
Now we'll attach the Pizza E C two S.
G.
Security group to the instances,
scroll to the instances box and click edit at the bottom.
You can see the two security groups section, select Pizza E C two S G.
And then click safe.
Next we'll configure the key pair and roll for the instances.
Go to the security box and click on edit in the ec.
Two key pair.
Drop down select pizza keys and then in the I am instance role.
Drop down select Pizza E C.
To roll.
Now you can click save.
We still need to configure the environment to create a load
balanced auto scaled group of instances.
You can see in the capacity section that it has just
configured to launch a single instance.
So click edit in the capacity box now change the environment type.
Drop down to load balanced.
We can leave the instances at one and one obviously there won't be any
scaling up or down if we leave the max and men at the same value but
the load balancer will allow us to configure some more things and how
are elastic being stalked more closely look like our manual load
balanced configuration.
Go ahead and click save.
Now we need to configure the load balancers so go to
the load balancer box and click edit.
The load balancer is initially configured to route from port 82.
Port 80 on.
Our instances are instances.
Will be listening on port 3000.
So in the process is section select the single
process and then click the actions.
Drop down and select edit, Change the port to be 3000 and then click Save.
Now the load balancer is all set up, so go ahead and click save again.
Now we've made all the changes we want to so you can click
create app at the bottom of the screen,
elastic beanstalk is going to create all the resources needed for your
application environment and deploy the code to the Ec.
Two instances in reality,
elastic beanstalk is using CloudFormation to accomplish a lot of this.
If you navigate to the CloudFormation dashboard,
you'll see a new stack created by elastic beanstalk
which has the status create in progress.
Go back to elastic beanstalk and select the pizza lovers environment.
You should still see this command line, looking output,
listing the events of the environment creation. This will take a few minutes so let's prepare something else for our application