[Autogenerated] an AWS account can be a dangerous thing.
If you think about it.
If it's your personal account then you've got your credit card attached to it,
a vulnerable position to be in.
If it's a company account then there are likely resources
that could cost the company a lot of money if administered
incorrectly anyway you look at it.
An AWS account needs to be secure and maintained
correctly at the base of your AWS account.
Is the root account.
If you just made a new account or open the account yourself
your account is likely the root account.
This means that all services are available to you to modify billing
information is visible and users can be managed.
Obviously this is a very powerful place to be and you should keep this in
mind when you're logged in as Root because of this.
There are some amazon suggested best practices that we will
set up over the course of this module.
Multi factor authentication shortened to M.
F.
A.
Has long been the industry standard for secure
authentication of online accounts.
Multi factor means that there is more than one way you will authenticate the M.
F.
A.
Provided by AWS ensures the user knows a specific
password and also has a specific device.
When M.
F.
A.
Has been activated,
you'll need to enter your password as well as an
authentication code from your M.
F.
A device.
This authentication code refreshes every 60 seconds which is what
makes the second form of authentication very secure.
The password part you have already taken care of for the device AWS allows
you to either use a hardware device or a virtual one.
I won't assume you have a hardware M.
F.
A device lying around but it's likely that you do have a smartphone.
There are plenty of multi factor authentication apps available in the
app store or google play So find and download an M.
F.
A application of your choosing.
I personally use Duo mobile and it works great with AWS.
Let's walk through setting up M.
F.
A.
On your account from the AWS console,
click on your name in the upper right hand corner and
then select security credentials.
Now expand the multi factor authentication section and click the activate M.
F.
A button.
Select the type of MFA device.
You'll be using select virtual if you're using a smartphone
in the next screen you'll see a large Q.
R code and here's where it gets a little tricky for me to guide you.
Since every MF A app has a different flow for adding a new account.
But basically you want to scan the QR code with your F A.
app and then you'll enter to authentication codes
from the account created in that M.
F.
A app This may take some time since you'll likely have to wait for
the new code to refresh and once both codes have been entered MFA
will now be enabled on your root account.
Let's try it out.
Sign out of your account via the menu and the top right of the console,
then click the sign in to the console button here,
enter your usual email and password.
Now you're presented with a new screen and this is where you'll
enter the authentication code from your M.
F A app, get the code from your app,
but make sure it is the most recent code Some apps
automatically refresh the codes, but some require a manual refresh,
enter your code and you should be allowed into your account.
Now the MFA has been enabled, your root account is much more secure than before.
In the next few clips,
we will do a few more things to make your usage of AWS more secure for you and your users.