[Autogenerated] Hi, This is Greg Golightly and welcome to optimizing costs.
Cost optimization is an area where you really need to know how things work,
because what you don't know could be costing you a lot more than it needs to.
We're going to start out talking about some common mistakes when it comes to
cost optimization and how you can avoid making those mistakes.
Next, we'll discuss the tools AWS provides to help you optimize your costs,
including savings plans.
AWS Cost Explorer AWS budgets and AWS Trusted adviser will point out some
cost management benefits to using AWS organizations.
And finally,
we'll review some key principles that can help you take a
proactive approach to cost optimization.
The five common mistakes we're going to look at our e C.
To instance type are two instantiation Easy to volumes and snapshots,
Zombie Instances and S3 storage class.
AWS has several different instance types from general
computing to hardware accelerated computing.
If we compare the largest general computing M 5 24 x large with
the largest accelerated computing P 3D n 24 XL,
there is a significant difference in the hourly on demand
price for a region about $4.60 an hour,
versus $31.21 an hour at the time of recording.
Be familiar with the different instance types,
including new ones that error released on a regular basis.
And make sure you're using these appropriate
instantiate type for your compute workload.
Within each instance, Type E.
C two offers a variety of instantiation XYZ.
For example,
let's take a look at the M five instants XAML e Notice
the range of sizes from 2 to 96 V.
C.
P apps and from eight gigabytes to 384 gigabytes of memory.
Theon demand difference in price for this region between an M five
large and an M 5 24 extra large is 48 times,
which corresponds to the fact that the 24 XML has 48 times
as much resource is as the M five large.
Choosing the right size of instance is a function of
the workload you're trying to run.
If you don't know how much compute resource is you need for an application,
you can enable CloudWatch monitoring on your PC to instances and get basic
CPU usage and with some customization set up memory usage.
It's important to choose the right size for the job so you don't pay for.
Resource is you don't really need.
The other thing to be aware of is tendency.
AWS offers dedicated hosts where you are the only
customer on a given physical machine.
As a result, this one small change can dramatically increased costs.
Since you're paying for the entire machine.
For an M five dedicated host, you'll pay about $5.7 an hour.
Dedicated hosts are not something you would generally use
unless you have a specific need for one.
Other AWS services like RDS also offer different sizes for different prices.
So be aware of the options for the AWS service you are using.
When you launch and C two, you can choose from different volume types,
solid state or hard disk, and there are also options within each type.
For example, in a certain region,
these options can do range from $25 to $125 per month for a one terabyte volume.
Choosing the right storage for your disk performance needs can impact cost,
especially if you have a large number of easy to instances.
Another thing to be aware of with E C two volumes is
that you are charged for volumes.
Even when you're easy to instances off, Let me say that again.
You can turn off your easy to instance and not pay the hourly compute charge,
but you will still pay for the volumes you have provisioned.
For example,
suppose you have a one terabyte GP two volume on an easy to instance that
will cost you about $100 per month in most regions.
Whether you use the easy to or not,
you also pay storage costs for any snapshots you have taken.
It's important to provision only the storage you
need for your easy to instances,
then have a strategy to keep track of and delete volumes and
snapshots as they're no longer needed for your workloads.
Zombie instances are instances that error provisioned in your account.
They may be running or stopped,
but no one has ownership or knows what they're doing.
Other than costing you money each month utilizing a combination of proper I am
permissions tagging and multi account management can help you avoid zombie
instances setting up a clear lifecycle for resource is,
and adding in some automated enforcement can help your accounts from
being overrun with zombie instances and volumes.
Some services can do also be turned off or scaled down during off peak times.
Suppose you only need certain resource is during
business hours or 40 hours per week.
By turning them off outside of business hours,
you'll be cutting your bill by about 75% depending on how frequently you
access your objects and how fast you need to retrieve them.
S3 has several different storage classes to match your use case.
For example,
here are four of the six storage classes offered at the time of recording.
Notice the difference in first by latency for
retrieval from milliseconds two hours,
as well as the minimum storage duration charge from no minimum to 180 days.
If you stored 100 terabytes of data for one month in an AWS region,
this would be the cost.
Notice the difference in cost between standard and Glacier Deep Archive.
If you used S3 standard for everything,
you could be paying almost 23 times more than you
need to for long term backup data.
Choosing the proper storage class for your use case can make a big difference in your storage costs