[Autogenerated] Hi, everyone.
My name is Craig Google lightly and welcome to my course designing for
complexity on AWS I am a senior software consultant.
Figuring out how you're going to use AWS to implement your
solutions can quickly turn into a complicated mess.
If you're not leveraging some key tools and best practices to
manage organizational complexity in this course,
whether you're just getting started or trying to
unravel and existing implementation,
we're going to cover how you can design for complexity on AWS,
using the proper tools so that your organization can have the capacity,
security and availability you need.
If you're studying for the AWS Certified Solutions Architect professional exam,
you're in the right place.
Some of the major topics that we will cover include
using AWS organizations I am users, groups,
policies and Rolls Federation and single sign on
and cost optimization strategies.
By the end of this course,
you will be able to implement the best options for setting up a secure,
compliant and cost effective A W s account structure for your organization,
and have a solid foundation for your exam preparations.
Before beginning the course, you should have a basic understanding of AWS.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn about managing
a W s for your organization with the designing for complexity on a W S course at Pluralsight.