[Autogenerated] Hi, This is Greg Golightly.
And welcome to designing for Complexity on A W s
setting up your A W s organization.
With the help of our fictional company, Globomantics.
We're going to take a look at some real problems that can happen
when you don't plan for complexity and how AWS organizations can
help you solve those problems.
Globomantics opened a single AWS account a couple of
years ago to try some things out.
They liked what they built,
and it just seemed easier to keep using the same AWS account.
Since then, several different departments error.
Now,
using the account for a variety of internal and external facing applications,
let's take a look at some of the challenges they're having.
With this set up every month, development is hearing the same thing from finance.
Why is our AWS bill so high?
Not all of the activity in their AWS account is research and development.
There are some production systems running that error generating revenue,
and there are lots of sales, support instances and customer proofs of concept.
But allocating costs to the appropriate departments
and projects is a major challenge.
It's just not possible to tell the difference from the current AWS
Bill Finance just sees E C two's S3 buckets,
LBS and a big check to write each month without clear visibility and ownership.
Many resource is are getting for gotten like,
easy to instances that have been running for a year.
But no one knows why,
and hundreds of terabytes of snapshots and volumes that
aren't attached to any running instances.
No one is optimizing for cost because they're not even aware
of the current spend for their project.
Separation of environments and user management is another pain point,
like when one developer accidentally deleted another
projects production environment.
Since everyone is in the same account for development,
testing and production, everyone is an admin,
and several departments are even sharing a single user and credentials.
It's difficult to tell what resource is belong to which department, and it's easy to accidentally delete the wrong thing.