[Autogenerated] Hi.
This is Craig Google lightly and welcome to managing cross account access.
Let's dive into more detail about different strategies for using
multiple accounts within your AWS organization and how to manage
cross account access using I Am Rolls will then see how resource
based policies differ from roles and how you can also use them for
cross account access.
With AWS organizations, you can go from a single,
messy account with several potential problems to multiple AWS
accounts grouped by organizational units.
For example, suppose you had a couple of different applications,
each with a dev stage and prod account.
You also have several individual sandbox accounts.
How do you manage access to all of these accounts?
Do you have to create users in every single account?
So now each person in your organization might have 10 different I am users.
Nope.
You can create all of the I am users in one account.
Let's call it security,
then use I am rolls to manage access to other accounts in your organization.
This allows you to define exactly who is allowed to access each A
W s account and what actions they can take.
Let's go over some terminology with cross account access.
The trusting account is the account that owns the
resource that needs to be accessed.
The trusted account is the account with users who need to access the resource.
In the other account,
you can use an I am role to allow users from one account to access.
Resource is in a different account.
The I am role will have to policies attached to it.
First, the permissions policy, which defines what access the user of the role,
will have to the particular resource.
And second, the trust policy,
which lists trusted entities who can assume the role in order for a
user in the trusted account to assume the role,
they must be given permission to assume the role by
a policy in the trusted account.
Let me say that again, without both of these policies correctly in place,
the user in the trusted account will not be able to assume the role.
This trust policy allows all users in this trusted
AWS account to assume the role.
This is the policy attached to the role in the trusting account.
To state which principles can assume the role in the trusted account,
you'll need to decide which users can assume the role
that the trusting account has granted.
One way to manage this is to create a group in the trusted account,
then attach a policy to that group,
which allows members of the group to assume the role.
This allows you to move users in and out of the group, whether they need to assume the role or not.