[Autogenerated] setting a password policy for your I Am and Federated users
is very common for different compliance requirements.
You can set the policy for I am users in the AWS console,
and for Federated users you'll need to manage that in
whatever identity provider you're using.
Along with password policies is the use of a multi factor authentication or I M.
F A device.
You can even create policies to deny certain actions
unless the user has authenticated with M F.
A.
You can monitor if users are logging into their AWS account,
how older credentials are and whether or not they have used
access keys that have been issued to them.
You can also view which rolls error being used to help
determine if you should remove any unused rolls.
Let's take a look at how to set password policies for I am.
Users will also see how to configure multi factor authentication for
your users and check on the frequency of user access and roll usage from
the I am dashboard Select account settings.
From here, you can set the password policy.
You can see the different options from password length to what
type of characters to reuse or expiration set Whatever suits your
organization than save the changes,
I'll go ahead and enforce a minimum 15 character password.
Now if I go to one of my users and try to change the password.
If I don't include enough characters, I won't be able to change it.
Notice how the apply button is grayed out.
Once I've entered enough characters,
then I can change the password to configure Emma for a user,
select that user than under security credentials.
Select Manage Under assigned MF a device here,
you can set up the M F a device that you'd like to use.
I'll go with virtual MF a device,
then follow the necessary steps to configure that MF A
device once you've correctly configured it,
select Assign MF A.
When you select users,
you'll see a list of all of the I am users forgiven
account as well as how old their access,
key and password are.
When you select an individual user under security credentials,
you can see when they last signed in,
as well as any access keys they have when they're
created and when they were last used,
you can deactivate and activate the access keys from here,
as well as remove an access key altogether under roles,
you can see the different roles that error defined in your AWS
account as well as when they were last used.
Keep in mind that there could be a four hour delay from when roles
error used to when they show up on this dashboard.
This is a helpful way to see what roles are being used and
what roles are not being used and maybe candidates to just be removed from your account.