[Autogenerated] If you find yourself with excess reserved instances,
you can actually sell those on the reserved instance.
Marketplace.
There are several steps you need to take to qualify as a seller.
See the AWS documentation and you'll be paying AWS a commission on the sale.
But the fact that a marketplace exists to sell any reserved instances
you don't need any more may help your risk assessment.
When deciding whether or not to use reserved instances in your
organization to purchase reserved instances,
you'll simply do that in the AWS console.
Each option will list whether it is being sold by AWS or a third-party.
Let's go to the AWS console to see what this looks like.
Go to E.
C two, then reserved instances here will select purchase reserved instances.
This screen presents you with different attributes,
filters that you can use to search for available,
reserved instances that you can purchase.
I'll go with these defaults than select search.
Here you can see the different options for purchase.
One year, three year No upfront, partial up front,
all up front,
this particular search showed all of the reserved instances
from this search are being sold by AWS.
If I change it to t two Nano Notice how Now there is a third
party seller that is selling an all upfront standard reserved
instance that has 19 months left on it.
They're asking $47.50 and they have six available.
You can sometimes obtain a reserved instance at a discounted
price from a third party seller or a different term length that
may be more suitable for your situation.
When you decide what you want,
you can add it to your cart and complete the purchase.
I don't actually want to purchase that right now, so I'll go ahead and hit delete.