[Autogenerated] Let's add a resource based policy to an S3 bucket that
allows all users in a different trusted account to list the bucket
contents and download objects in the bucket,
will then create a policy to allow users in the trusted account
to perform both actions and see what happens when either the
resource based policy on the bucket or the policy over user's in
the trusted account changes.
I'm in the Globo app Deva account in the S3 console.
Let's go ahead and create a bucket so we can add an object to it.
Then we'll attach a resource based policy to the bucket that will allow
access to users from another account will create the bucket.
I'll call it com dot Globomantics app.
One.
We'll go ahead and accept the defaults and create the bucket.
Let's add an image to the bucket.
I'll add this green check mark image.
Next,
we'll need to attach a resource based policy to allow members of
another account to list the bucket contents and download objects
in the bucket will go to permissions, then bucket policy.
Here is a policy that allows members of the security account to both
list the bucket and get objects from the bucket notice under resource
that we're restricting it to only this bucket and objects in this
bucket will save the policy.
And now we're ready to switch over to our other account.
Here's our security account notice.
The account number is the same one that we listed over in the policy.
We're going to create a policy that allows access to that
bucket that's been shared with this account.
This policy will allow all actions that have been granted for this
particular bucket and the objects in this bucket.
We'll review the policy.
We'll call it Access Shared Bucket and give it a description.
Again.
You'll want to come up with some sort of naming
convention to organize your groups, create the policy.
And now let's create a group that we can attach this policy to
and add users so that they have this access.
I'll call it Access.
Dev's Bucket will select the policy that we just created.
Now let's add User one to this group.
Let's Le Guin as user one.
To see this in action, I'm now logged in as user one.
In the security account.
Let's go to S3.
You may be wondering Why are we seeing an error?
I thought we have access to this.
What we're seeing right here is the S3 from the security account user.
One doesn't have any permissions to view the S3 bucket in the security account
in order to view the S3 bucket from a different account,
will either need to configure the CLI or use a direct URL to list
the bucket in the other account there were interested in To access
a bucket directly from the console.
Simply type S3 dot console dot AWS .NET amazon dot com slash
S3 slash buckets slash the name of the bucket in our case com
dot Globomantics .NET app 0.0.1.
Here we can see the image that was uploaded and download.
The image here is user to in the same security account.
Let's try to access that bucket directly with this user,
since this user has not been given permissions in its own account.
Even though the resource policy grants access to all users in this account,
this user has not specifically been given permission by
its own account to access the bucket.
Suppose you changed your mind and no longer wanted to allow
users in the other account to download objects from the
bucket but only list buckets.
You can modify the resource based policy on that bucket and remove
the gett object action from objects in the bucket.
We'll save our changes now if we go back to use er one and refresh the page.
We can still see the item, but notice that the download button is disabled.
This is because the resource based policy no longer
grants a download permission.
Great job.
You've seen how you can organize multiple accounts in your AWS
organization and use rolls to manage cross account access.
You've also seen how resource based policies are different
from rolls and where you can use resource based policies to
allow cross account access.
Next, we're going to cover using federation and AWS single sign on, including Amazon cognito.