[Autogenerated] Let's go to the AWS console and take a look at where you can
access the pricing history for spot Instances will launch a few spot instances
so you can see the options that can affect your price.
And we'll look at the spot instance Adviser,
which can help you decide which instances to use for spots.
Let's take a look at easy to spot instances in the AWS console.
Under instances, Select spot requests.
First, let's check out some pricing history for spot instances.
Here you can select the operating system instantiate type and date range
to see the spot price in various availability zones.
For that configuration,
let's make the date range a little bit bigger and see
prices for the M five large we can see,
the most recent price has stayed at two cents.
When we go back, we can see that it got up a little bit higher than two cents,
but not much.
This represents a significant savings over the on demand price of 9.6 cents.
Let's take a look at some other instantiate types.
As you can see, there is a wide variety of spot instances available for purchase.
Let's take a look at the P 38 XML notice in the US East to see availability
zone that the spot price is the same as the on demand price.
This would indicate that there is no excess capacity in that
particular availability zone for this instantiate iPod.
Remember also that pricing is region dependent.
Let's switch regions and take a look at the pricing for this
same instance in this region noticed the U.
S East one B availability zone had a couple of different events where
the spot price was the same as the and band price.
This region also has one availability zone with no excess capacity.
The U.
S East one F as the spot price is the same as the on demand price.
Let's go back to the Ohio region and launch some spot instances.
Select request spot instances.
Then here you'll select what type of spot you want to create,
whether you need the same instant size and availability zone
or if you're a little bit more flexible for instances of any
sign in any availability zone,
you can also select the defined duration where your spot
instance is guaranteed to stay active between one and six
hours in one hour increments.
Keep in mind that this option will cost you more thin regular spots,
but it may be worth it for reduced complexity in your application,
I'm going to go with flexible workloads.
Next, you can select a launch template that has everything pre configured,
which is what I'd recommend for using spot instances.
But for this demo, I'll quickly go through some of the options.
Let's change the instance.
Type to M five large.
I'll keep the default VPC with any availability zone,
and I'm not going to specify a keep error because I won't be
logging into these instances for capacity.
I want to launch three instances.
Notice how you can also specify a certain number of V C P use.
Then AWS will automatically launch various
instantiate types to match that request.
Here's an example of other instance types that have similar V CPUs and memory,
as well as the spot price for each.
For the three instances I'm requesting,
it's estimated that I'll pay about 6.2 cents an hour as
opposed to almost 30 cents an hour.
If I used on demand,
I'll acknowledge the warning because I don't need the keep error,
and we can see that the spot request has been submitted.
Once you start using spot instances, you can take a look at the savings summary.
In this case, I'm paying six cents instead of 40 cents.
You can view your spot instances from the spot Requests page or with
your normal instances menu here we can see that I was allocated three
our four large instances since they're similar to the M five large and
that all three are up and running.
Once you're done using your spot instances, go back to spot requests.
Then you can select the fleet and under actions, select cancel spot request.
When you cancel the request,
you can also have it terminate the instances I'll hit confirm,
and now the request is canceled.
If I go back to instances,
we can see that the three instances are shutting down and terminated.
Here's the spot instance Adviser.
You can select a region and configuration.
Then it will show you several different instance types the average savings
over on demand and how often those are interrupted by AWS.
This can help you decide what types of instances you should use as spot
instances based on your CPU and memory requirements,
as well as how often those may be interrupted and what you'll need to do in
your application to handle those interruptions gracefully.
Congratulations.
You now understand the cost savings options with reserved instances for easy to
as well as other AWS services that offer reserved models.
You've seen the reserved instance marketplace and that you may
be able to sell your reserved instances to other AWS customers
if you end up not needing them.
Finally,
you learned how spot instances work and how they could
drastically reduce your e C two spent.
If you're studying for the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Professional exam.
Best of luck in your preparations. I hope you have found this valuable and thank you for watching.