[Autogenerated] how and welcome to the spring Framework Spring Data Mum Body.
Because here on parasite manga, TB is the most popular nautical database outer.
And for good reason.
It's cross platform.
It's mature, It's fast, it's scalable.
It works with every technology stack from dot net to Java to know GS,
and the different supports transactions,
something very rare in the know sickle world.
So if you're developing Java applications using spring,
I want to learn how to effectively use among body be in your projects today.
Then this course is for you.
My name is Don Job Jonah.
I'm a sneer, softer developer,
and I've been working with Mom going to be for the past seven years.
So to say I'm excited to host this course would be a big understatement.
In the first module will see how to connect a spring
application to an existing mongo server.
More precisely,
we'll see what we need in order to get our
development environment up and running,
then would go through a quick recap off some basic Mongol concepts.
After that,
our shoe that dependence is needed for working with more body be in spring.
Then we'll discuss Mongo date annotations and connection
properties and see where they come in.
And finally,
we'll have a demo in which we create a spring application
and connected to among were to be severed.
That's right.
By the end of this module,
you'll know how to creating Configure a spring application toe work with Mongo.
There are some things that you should be familiar
with before starting the scores.
First of all, you should be comfortable writing job applications.
Then you should have a basic experience using spring and spring boot.
And last but not least,
you should have at least some basic familiarity with Mongo TB.
Getting up and running with Spring and Mongo is pretty pretty easy.
Luckily for us,
the guys developing the spring framework have done a terrific
job at integrating these two technologies.
The first thing that we need to do is prepare the development environment.
Then we can create the name this people's application.
After that,
we can add the spring date among go to be starter
dependency in the palm dot xml file.
Then we can define the connection properties,
and last but not least,
we can apply the manga annotations to control how persistence is done
Those are the five steps that we need in order to create spring
application that can talkto among a server,
and that's what we'll do in this module.
The development environment is pretty standard.
You need Javadi eight or higher.
I'm not going to be server.
In my case,
I'll be running my mom go to be server locally and less
banal istan I D are using you Tell J,
but you can use whatever idea makes you comfortable.
I also want to mention the manga graphical user interface
is if you have a Mongol to be server,
you can surely execute commands using the command prompt or terminal.
But I think it's more practical to have a graphical user
interface to exact comments and see welcomes.
There are two Monk, a graphical user interface.
Is that a particularly love Mongol compass,
which you can find it on the monkey Beside and Robot Pretty both have free to use versions that can use right away