[Autogenerated] I think the time has come to discuss about Mongo.
Document references in this module will start by understanding what
document references are from a mongo to be perspective.
Then we'll create them in spring using at D B ref.
After that, we'll talk about the spring manga lifecycle events,
which are pretty useful hooks that allow us to create
features like a skating or auditing.
And we'll finish with a demo in which will implement document references
and cascading in a spring application that uses Mongo TB.
But let's start with the beginning.
Let's discuss about Mongo Darkman references.
Well,
a documented reference is just a way to link together
multiple documents that are somewhat related.
Mongo D.
B is a nautical database, therefore, for most cases,
that a normalized model where the date I stored in a single document is optimal.
The idea is that if you try to minimize the number off
relationships between your documents,
other parts applications stand to be complex,
and sometimes it's pretty difficult to achieve this.
Let's look at an example.
We have to bank transactions stored as Mongolia P documents.
They all have I D s amounts and customer information.
The customer here is an embedded mongo document.
Re duplicate this information throughout every bank
transaction documents that we safe.
Let's imagine that sometime in the future, the national I.
D number for John Doe is going to change.
Why do you do then?
Well, we have no single entry for John Doe,
so if you go into a bank transaction update the national I.
D.
Number, This won't propagate throughout the rest of the transactions.
All we can do is scan your document and we're refined.
John Doe, update the national the number with the correct value.
That's one problem that we have to face when we're not
using relationships in this case.
Ah,
better approach would have bean to separate the customer from the bank
transaction and store them as two separate documents.
We can save the customer as a mogul to be document.
In our case, you have John Doe.
It has an I.
D.
And the national I.
Number.
On the other hand, when we were working with bank transactions,
we have another month would be document and we link the bank
transaction to a customer via the idee property here.
Customer I d.
Is equal to the I D property of the customer document.
That's a simple manual reference that can apply in manga TB databases.
Now, if you try to update the national I D number for John Doe,
this will get propagated toe every bank transaction
because the bank transaction is no longer responsible for
keeping those fields up to date.
In my body be we have two types of relationships between documents.
Manual references.
This is what you saw a little bit harder.
We are using the idee field of a document in another document.
The second approach is to use the D B refs.
You can think of deep breaths as manual references on steroids.
You can link documents together by using the i.
D field collection, name and database.
Name the B ref killing documents across collections or
even across different databases, something that we cannot achieve.
Using manual references to resolve the refs,
the application must perform additional queries.
The Mongol BB drivers don't that automatically for you.
Luckily for us,
spring date among _____ be handles this scenario and
fetches their little document for us.
Also,
be aware that cascading is not supported using the B refs if
you have a relational database background,
you might be tempted to think that deep you're f you
know is some kind of foreign key, and you can perform joins with.
Well, Debrief is a very simple construct,
and the relationship capabilities that Mongo __ offers us are nowhere near as
powerful as what we get from the relational counterparts.
That's not the reason why we have no sequel databases,
but it's good to know that you can use references to ling.
Documents were appropriate.
A debrief is not.
Something very special is just a sub document with some specific fields.
The 1st 1 is Dollar Sign Ref.
This contains the name off the collection where the link document resides.
Another one is better sign i d.
As the value of Di di field off the reference document and optionally,
we can also have dollar sign Gibby the name for the
database where the reference document.
Besides, we can get an example.
We can see that the engine here is a d B ref.
It has the three properties that are assigned ref
Another sign I D and dollar sign.
Gibby, let me show you how you can interpret the breath in this case,
his engine resides in a collection called Engines.
This is given to us by the dollar sign riff property.
Then this particular engine that we're looking for has the following
i d as defined by the dollar sign I d property.
And also this engine can only be retrieved from the a t M mongo database.
Be aware that the order off these fields in the engine sub document is very,
very important.
In orderto have a d b ref from a mongrel TB perspective,
those fields need to be in a particular order.
Dollar sign, riff, dollar sign I d and the other side to be If you mix the order,
you won't get a document reference.
And last but not least, be aware that deep breaths are not smart.
Don't expect relational database capabilities out over the beer. If instead, think of it as a man, a reference with some benefits