[Autogenerated] Now that you understand document
references from a Mongol perspective,
I think it's time to look at them from a spring data perspective.
And the best way to learn how to create document references in
spring is by looking at the real example.
Let's start with this class.
The aircraft class is an entity with a document,
and he has a NY D field Awesome.
It also contains on engine as an embedded document,
and we know it's an embedded document because we see no
additional annotations over here.
If you want to make a link between aircraft and
engine using document references,
there are a couple of changes that need to take place.
First of all, we need to add the at dpuf annotation toe our engine property.
That's the first step.
You see this?
It means that engine is not an embedded document.
Engine aircraft are related.
This is the only changed out we have to do on the aircraft class.
But you also have to do a couple of modifications to the engine class.
The engine is also a document,
so we need to add the corresponding annotations to it.
In our case, a document and at I d.
That's pretty much it.
We now have a document reference between aircraft and
engine implemented at the framework level.
Let's see how we can use it.
If you remember,
mobility be doesn't pre fetch document references for you
in my body be apartment reference is just a sub document
with ref i D and D B properties.
Luckily for US, Spring Data Mongo.
Debbie does some things for us,
and the most important one is that it fetches documents
annotated with a debrief automatically.
This means that each time create a quay for aircraft,
the engine property is going to be populated with the actual engine values.
So not riff idea.
Maybe, but the actual documents or the framework is going to do that.
Documents fetching for you, which is a great thing.
Let's also discuss inserts.
Let's assume you're creating a new aircraft.
Then we're assigning a new engine to it,
and you call the insert method on the aircraft repositories.
If you've been using relational databases,
you would expect that at this stage both the aircraft and the
engine documents should be inserted in the database.
But it is the case in Mongo.
You won't get an error after executing this coat.
Which is a good thing, however,
engine is not getting saved in the engine collection.
What I'm trying to say here is that Cascading does not
work with __ riffs on Save by Default, so you have to do things differently.
The easiest fix is tau actually saved the engine.
First, assign it toe aircraft and then insert the aircraft,
so you need to save the reference document first and the parent document.
After that,
the at the Bureau of Sanitation can also be customized in order to
let the framework know how to fetch the documents.
For us, it can use either eager loading or lazy loading.
Now, by default, Addy be ref is struck the framework to perform any girl out.
You can change that by modifying the lazy property off the
ATI brief annotation and stated to truth.
In this case,
the sub document is loaded on Lee when one of its fields or methods is accessed.
Now, this is not something you normally used by default,
but it's pretty useful for bi directional references in
orderto avoid cyclic dependencies.
In this case, if Engine also had a document reference back to aircraft,
then setting the lazy property to true would be very helpful.
Let some of the capabilities that we get in spring when using at the B ref.
First of all, Maddie bereft equates document references.
It uses eager loading by default,
but this can be changed by modifying the lazy property.
The spring framework fetches the reference document for
you and populates the Java object.
You don't have to do anything in this regard.
Cascading on Safe is not available by default,
but luckily for us,
you can hook into Mongol lifecycle events and implement cascading yourself,
and this is what we'll discuss in a few moments.
Until then,
I also want to highlight that you should pay attention to
queries when using related documents.
Let's look at this example.
We have a new aircraft and this aircraft has an agent property.
In this case, we haven't embedded document.
Then, in an aircraft depository, you can search all the aircraft,
for example, by the Max Power property on the engine.
And again, is that Cory annotation like we do over here?
If engine war, a document reference,
then the queen that the post story would not work and this makes sense,
right?
If you're losing tbe refs,
then we don't have a sub document in the engine properties
that we have a riff on I d and the D B.
So filtering can't really work as you saw.
Duckman, referencing in Spring, has both pros and cons.
As always, it's up to you, the developer, to modern your data and meet your particular application needs.