[Autogenerated] not that we have the thrilling place.
We are ready to create mongo integration tests in a spring application.
The first trees that you're going to have to make is whether
you're going to use and in embedded among without a base or a
stand along with other bees.
They both have pros and cons.
However,
if you opt for the embedded approach will have no dependencies whatsoever.
This means that you can set up your local environment easily,
and it can also meet a great with CSC pipelines very,
very fast.
You also get faster tests.
However, this is not an official Mongol product,
and therefore it's not quite integration testing because
you're not targeting a natural Mongol database,
but rather a custom implementation off it that runs in memory.
If you opt for a standard on approach,
you need a dedicated mongo database for testing purposes.
You increase the complexity of the receipt's in the environment.
In your local environment.
This was meant to run a little bit slower,
but we will discover how your application behaves
in production like environments, and this is pretty pretty important,
all right.
And if both have pros and cons,
what should you choose running tests with an embedded
database or with the standard on one, and that's a good question.
Based on my experience.
Alger Command that you start with an embedded database first
and gradually progress to a standard on database before
shipping your application to production.
I recommend this approach because it worked pretty well
in the projects where I was involved.
Before we look at an actual test,
I want to talk about the AT data mongo test annotation.
The sanitation can be used on classes that will contain
your manga TB integration tests using the sanitation will
disable full auto configuration,
but apply partial auto configuration for the Mongol
related components like suppositories,
the Mongol template and standing off classes annotated with at document.
And I think we're ready to look at some actual examples.
We'll start which running tests using an embedded database.
The first thing that into set up is to get a
dependency on the embedded mongo server.
We can achieve that pretty city,
but adding this dependency to a poem that XML file you want
the d e flapdoodle in bed mongo artifact.
Do note that a sculptor dependency is test,
which means that the embedded database will be
available when you're running tests,
but it won't be available at runtime at front time.
Your application will connect toe on actual mongo database,
Go one specified in the Application Properties file,
for example.
We cannot create our first this class.
We're going to call it database integration tests.
Not is the special annotations that you used.
We have at data mongo test.
We also have at extend with spring extension.
That's class.
This instructs the Janet five runner to use the spring test context and
optionally we can add on at category in rotation.
Now we can other wire the Mongo template.
And remember, we can do that because we have the at Data Mongo test annotation,
which gives us some auto writing capabilities.
We can inject mongo related components, and my uncle template is one of them.
Before we run a test,
we need to set up some test data in clear eat afterwards so
that each test can start from a clean slate.
That's why we have the before each and after.
Each methods the 1st 1 he asserts.
Some aircraft authority embedded mongo database.
Notice that gene it at before each annotation.
The 2nd 1 just drops the aircraft collection
entirely of us clearing the database.
These methods are going to be executed before and after
each test that we define in art a street.
The test itself is pretty.
Is it right to create a new method we annotated with math
test and then we're using the mongo template to find all
the aircraft in our database.
Assuming that we care free, we can then use a certain equals free.
And our result.
That's how easy it is to create a Mongol to be integration test in spring.
So why'd you seven The process is the following You fire up the test.
This in turn starts the embedded Mongol database in memory.
You populate collections with something's data in Archies
aircraft you execute and a service.
And finally you clear the embedded among without a base.
It's worth mentioning that the embedded Mongol Debbie server he
started only once when the first test is executed.
Now let's see how we can run tests using a standard on batteries.
Well, first of all, we have no dependency on the embedded.
That's a base model, so we can just go ahead and write their test.
But before we do that,
we still lead the way to specify what database we're going to use for our tests.
And that's why we have this test configuration.
Not is the at test configuration annotation here we can declare beings that
are going to be available for auto wiring in artists only equate among otb
factory being where we specify the test database.
Mongo your eye.
Then we quit a mongo temperate being and passing the factory declared above.
So what we get is when we got a wire the Mongol template.
It will point to our test database.
The database integration tests class is almost identical.
The only difference is the at import annotation where we are importing
the beans defined in our test configuration class.
And we need to do that because when we oughta wear the Mongol template,
we want to point to the database as specified in there.
I hope you noticed.
How is it is to switch from one embedded at the base toe stand?
A long one?
This are being executed in a similar fashion.
You find out the street which in turn is going to connect your actual database.
We're goingto cooperate.
Sometimes data executor test and clear the database pretty much the same flow. Except we're not starting an embedded database in memory.