[Autogenerated] as sad as it may be,
sometimes we need to remove documents altogether from our collection.
Delish in also has many facets.
We can read a single document.
We can delete multiple documents.
All we can delete the entire collection again.
I think the best way to understand Edition is to look at
some examples we have free airports in or database to for
France and one from Turkey.
Let's see you want to delete the stubble airport.
We're grabbing it from the database and then we can use the remove
method on the Monga Temple class to remove it.
After executives method, we will have just two airports in our collection.
We can also remove multiple documents or perform a batch.
Did it?
The recipe should be very clear by now.
We define a query.
We're adding a criteria were filter or the airport where the country
is France and then we can use the fight old and remove method passing
the query and the airport class type.
The outcome off this execution is going to be this.
All the airports in France will be deleted and we're left with a single airport.
But what if you want to remove all the airports from this
collection we have multiple ways to achieve is,
for example, we can create an empty query,
acquitted without criteria.
This will effectively select all airport in that collection,
and then we can use, find all and remove to execute this dish in.
And of course, we'll be left with an empty collection.
However, I think it's much more efficient.
Just drop the collection all together.
You can do that using the Mongol Template ____ collection and
then pass in the type off the document.
Congratulations.
At this point, you're able to perform the basic crowd operations on a monk,
a database in a spring application, you learned how to query,
how to create out a bit and how to delete documents. But the discussion here is not over until we take a look at Mongo converters.