[Autogenerated] I bet you're pretty eager to write a first test in
this demo are going to implement mongo integration tests in spring
applications so far up your ID's and less recent cult before right
in the line of code Rito,
figure out what parts of our data access layer I was trying to test.
The obvious candidates are the repositories and the generic Caskey listener.
The airport depository extends Munk reports story,
but adds no additional methods.
Therefore, we don't have to test it flight information.
Boy's story, on the other hand, adds free additional methods.
They are all good candidates for writing integration tests.
However,
I think the most fragile method is the last one because it
needs a quarry defined as a string toe work.
And this can be very era prom,
So we're going to write on integration test for it.
We can also test ordinary Caskey listener.
We want to make sure that when you save a parent document,
the channel documents are saved if they do not exist.
So we're going to add a second test for dysfunctionality.
Now we have to decide if you want to use on embedded at
the base or a standard on database.
We'll start with the first approach to use an embedded database.
We first need to define the dependency in the bomb dot xml file
notice the scope of the dependency is test.
This means that when we execute tests, the embedded database is going to be used.
But when our application rising production a really database is going to abused,
which is exactly the kind of behavior that you want we can all right,
our first this class, we'll call it not our base integration.
This not these the annotations present above.
We have at data mongo test.
This enables us to use mongo related beans and oughta wear them.
Mogul template, airport depository and flight information.
Post story are good examples.
We don't have the at extended sanitation.
We're also importing the data base.
This configuration class, let's take a look at it.
A database this configuration is annotated with at test configuration and it
defines one additional being the generic cascade listener because legendary
Caskey listener is not among component the spring test context cannot use it
by using solely the at data mongo test.
So we need to define it here and use this configuration.
Remember,
at data Mongo test makes Mongo related beings available
for other wearing not other components.
Before we write our first test,
we also need to make sure that our databases properly clean and initialized.
So we need a before each and then after reach method.
Let's start by implementing the before each.
This method is an idiot with at before each, we define free airports.
We save them tow are embedded database using the airport poised,
very civil method.
And then Rick,
wait some flights which we again save using the flight
information report story When our tests are executed,
this data should be available for them, but we're not finished.
Also need to clear all the other base after each test is executed.
For that,
we can use the after each method is method is annotated with the gene it at
after each and the method implementation is participle.
We're using the model template to drop the airport
and flight information collections, thus emptying our database.
Let's create a test for our fight information report story.
You want to test that defined by mean l Kraft number
of seats method works as expected.
We're going to use 200 as the minimal number of seats.
Then we're going to call the method on the flight information post story,
and we're going to serve that a single flight matches the criteria.
If we look at our visitor,
we can see that we have one flight which has an aircraft that has 280 seats.
So this flight should match our criteria, lets out a test for a generic.
Ask a listener.
Mister, we're defining two new airports Bucharest in London.
Then we're creating the new flight information and we're using Big
Krista's departure in London as this nation.
We are then saving this light using the insert method on
the fight information repositories.
We want to test that our flight or saved in the other base,
but also that the two airports were saved in the airport collection were already
to run our tests and we can see that both tests succeeded.
Looking at the logs,
we can also see that these deaths were executed
against an embedded mom without a base.
Let's go ahead and try to run the same tests on a standard on database.
To achieve this,
me to delete the embedded among without a base
dependency because you won't need it anymore.
We'll connect to an actual Mongol.
Armies also need to update our that our base days configuration going to define
a mongo temporal bean that is going to connect to our test that always and we
add in this two B's one for Mongo to be factory,
which contains the connection to our __ tests.
That always and the 2nd 1 for the Mongol template,
which uses the factory find above hard disk less remains the same.
There is no modification that needs to be done.
We're here.
We can now execute artists again and see the outcome,
and that this best I wanted to use these two approaches because
I wanted to highlight unimportant aspect.
It's extremely easy to switch from one in bed,
among without a base to an actual moon without a base.
He took us like 30 seconds.
That's why I'm recommending that you start with the embedded approach
first because it would speed up your development and then before we
ship the production switch to an actual man without a ways in order
to test for that oxes layer. In a more realistic scenario,