[Autogenerated] I think it's time to put the slides down
and start to write some coat in his demo.
We're going to implement the monk Oh operations.
But this time, using report stories,
we're going to look at queries using the query methods,
he asserts.
Updates and it's let's get to it.
In order to implement Mongo operations using report stories,
you first need to create one.
I created the flight information depository under
the parasite Airport Management.
That D be package off course is an interface,
and it extends Mongol report story off flight information and string.
Remember,
flight information is the document that you're
persisting in our among with database.
I also added the ad repositories rotation to make spring aware of _______
do notice that I did not provide any query methods.
I want to leverage the building functionality off the Mongol report
story to perform most of the manga operations.
The first thing that I want implement is the database Cedar Runner.
This time, it doesn't use mongo template.
It uses the flight information repositories.
We declare it is a private field and we're injecting it.
The other constructor,
the seat method creates the data that you want to insert in our database.
More specifically, we're creating six instances off flight information.
Now I want to insert them into the database,
come them and print them on a screen.
The coaches will look like this.
Were first grouping all the flights into a list.
Then you know what we serve them.
We can call the insert method on the report story,
and passing the flights is will execute a batch,
insert toe counter documents in the collection,
the King's the Count method on this depository,
and to print them, we can use the final method on the report story interface.
And we can pass in a sort of definition,
in this case, around to sort by the Partridge City in ascending order.
And then we print the flights we are inserting, we're counting on.
We're printing all the flight information documents without
writing a single line of code in our flight information
repositories To finish the cedar,
we also need to implement the empty method to make sure that all the
prison documents are deleted when the application starts.
Of course, this is a very simple called to the little method under reported.
For instance, now you're ready to fire up the application and see this outcome.
The application finished him against the output on the screen.
We have six flights known database and down below.
We can see them ordered by the departure city.
Great.
Now let's switch to the application.
Rather, the application runner also implements Commander around the interface.
It is said to execute after the cedar.
Hence we have at order set it too.
Then we have to inject the flight information,
re poised to refuel the constructor.
And we're good to go.
The features that you need to implement our the following.
We need to find the flight by Deion printed.
We need to find a flight by D and delayed by 30 minutes.
We need to remove a five biting.
We need to find all the flights by departure and destination.
And we need to print all the flights for the minimum number of Cities 200.
Let's go ahead and implement these methods in order to find imprint of five i d.
We can use the fun buddy method on our flight information boy
story find by a deed eaters and optional.
So, in order to actually get our fight information in tow.
Call the get method and then we can pass it for flight printer,
utility class to delay.
Fly better two minutes when you to update the duration property.
So we need to find the flight.
And again, we're losing the fine by de method.
Then we need to I've dated the values in our case,
the duration men,
and we increase it by 30 and then you can call the same matter on the report
story by passing in the updated flight toe identify body.
We simply call the report story did by the method and passing the appropriate i.
D.
All of this was done using the built in functionality
off the base report story interfaces.
Now, in order to find all the flights body parts,
gin destination or or the flights where the minimal number of seats of
the aircraft is greater than a particular value,
we need to modify our flight information
repositories and adding some query methods.
We need to add two new methods to enable the fitters,
so find all flights by Departure city In Destination city,
we can use the query method conventions.
So we're returning Callisto flights.
We have to find their perfect.
Then we are filtering by departure city and destination city,
and we're using exact value for departure and destination,
then tow.
Find all the flights where the minimum aircraft number of
seats is greater than a provider value.
We have to dig into a sub document now.
A good way to do this is to use the ___ query annotation and filter
the number of seats property off the aircraft field.
Then we can pass in the dollar GT Pfister,
which stands for greater than or equal,
and we have to configure it to take the minimal number of seats as an argument.
That's what dollar sign zero stands for before we tell these
methods in the application on a component.
I want to give you a tip in working with Mongo queries because
you have to write them in a mongo query Syntax.
The best way to do it is to test them first in an I D or in the Mongol council,
and that's what I do.
So I've taken the exact model query that I've written in the depository.
I've pasted it in Mongol Compass,
and we can replace the dollar sign zero with an actual value in this case,
200.
We can then click on find, and we can see that our filter is working.
Now I can copy paste it back into a depository because you know,
it's perfectly fine in order to finish the application honor who
need to call the methods that we just added to our flight
information report story After we called them,
We pretty are put on the screen.
And now I think we're good to test the outcome off our
entire application and we can sit.
Y'all come over here after receiver has finished,
we're grabbing a fight by its i.
D.
We're updating a flight were deleting the same flight.
And then we're printing the flash somebody to Barcelona and then all the
flights by the minimum number of seats greater than 200.
And the filters appear to be working.
So Arquit methods are doing the correct job.
Awesome.
Before I finish is,
the more I want to point out how easy it is to use repositories.
We've written seven lines of code in the repository interface,
and we get so much functionality out of it,
I highly encourage you to use them because they're a great solution. In most cases,