[Autogenerated] in this module.
We talked about the importance off testing the data access.
There you learned that database integration tests
should be down for complex queries.
Life second events and wrappings.
Milton methods on repo stories or mongo template should not be tested.
Should always try to keep your test stable and always populate
and cleared the database after each test.
After all, you want predictability in your death.
The last journalist she strived to start with an embedded at the base and
progress to stand around one just before we ship into production.
As you saw, it only takes 30 seconds to make this transition.
Bravo.
You reach the end of this course and it has bean Amazing journey.
You learned how to get started with spring and Mongo.
You discovered how spring mongo annotations and crawl operations work.
We talked about it boy stories and how they can help you to create dinner code.
We also looked at docking references and left second events,
which helps us to implement cascading.
We took a look at that immigrations and how to implement them properly.
And finally, who discussed about integration,
testing and how we can increase the quality of your applications.
You now have all the skills needed to start creating enterprise
applications with spring and nobody and I mean it.
Go to work and find out if there are any projects involving mongo to be,
because you'll be able to tackle any challenges not coming your way.
If you want to take your skills to a new level,
if it also invest in learning more about Mom will be.
There are two great courses here on Parasite that can help with
that introduction to Mongo To Be and Munger to be
administration both by Nouri Halperin and no,
forget it.
I'm a social guy.
If we want to get in touch, you can find me on Twitter or Arlington,
and we can also check out my other parasite course salad.
Softer design principles in Java, but the next time, have a great day and write Amazing coat