[Autogenerated] in his module.
You saw that that immigration's are a normal part off.
Every software application that goes into production should try toe
automate the migration process as much as possible.
Don't rely on manual scripting because in the long run they won't work,
and they will only give you headaches and pain.
You have the option to either create your own component or
to use an existing migration framework.
If you opt for the letter approach than Mongo.
B is a migration tool that integrates nicely with spring and mom will be.
At this point,
you might be asking yourself if you should use an existing
framework or create your own migration tolling,
and the answer is, it depends.
If you create your own migration components,
then you have complete control over the functionality.
You can meet every aspect of your migration requirements.
However, you do need more time to develop it,
and you saw that it's not very trivial.
If you just interesting framework will save time.
You focus on the business logic instead of infrastructure code.
But some applications might need more features than
any given framework can offer,
so we have limited control on the migration process itself.
In the end, it's your choice.
Either option works fine for certain scenarios,
and you don't have to use Mongol.
Be as a framework.
You can research and find other frameworks that might be better
suited for your own particular needs have just among Kobe because
I've used it in some production applications,
and I was happy with the outcome.
Now we'll go for migrations.
Toe Aristotle, who said that quality is not an act.
It's a habit.
Every application that you ship the production
needs an extensive set off testing.
You should always try to test the persistence layer off your spring application.
And luckily for us, it's not very difficult to create integration.
Testing for spring applications that use Mom will be as a persistent store, and we learn how to do this effectively in the next module.