[Autogenerated] it's time to get our hands dirty and write some coat.
In his demo, we're going to implement, assert,
update and greet operations in a spring application that targets Mongo TV.
We're going to look at single operations they
regard to tackle better operations,
and we'll wrap it up by implementing some custom converters.
Let's get to work before we get started.
I'd like you to know that I have removed all the flights from our collection.
We're going to start with an empty collection.
I also made another change in the Application properties file.
I've have added the park looking for a monk, Oh, temperate component.
This will allow us to see how method calls among go template get
translated into mongo to be queries very useful for trying to
understand what's happening under the hood.
The first thing that won't implement is a database cedar who want
to make sure that when the application fires up,
it pre populates some items into the database.
In our case, a couple of flights,
the databases that implements command and runner,
which means that spring is going to execute it after your bootstraps.
We also have an allocation here at order with the Valley one.
We're using it because you want to make sure that this is the first
commander runner that spring is going to execute.
This would ensure us that we have data in our collection when
we run other features of the application.
And, of course,
we have the wrong method in which we're calling empty and seed empty to
remove all the priests in documents and seat toe Adan Nuance.
Let's start with seed.
We are defining a couple of flight information objects over here using centers.
So nothing fancy.
And now we want to insert all of these documents in mongo.
Maybe wanted to do it is like this.
We can insert them one by one.
As you know, it's not very efficient,
but I want to show you how that Logar works.
So let's go ahead and fire up The application of the application
started and we can see we have six entries from that log.
Each one telling goes that a new document has been inserted,
which you have six round trips to the database.
So not very efficient.
Of course,
you can replace this with any sort All co we're
grouping all the flights in a collection,
and then we're calling Insert all on mongo template.
If you run the application again,
we'll see an improvement in how queries are being executed.
And here it is.
We now have a single round trip to the database,
and it is illustrated by this log over here asserting
Mr Documents containing six items.
Brilliant, but we're not done yet.
We have not implemented this empty method.
We need to delete every document when the application
starts so that we always start fresh.
We can delete them on by one, but as he so it's not efficient.
So we're just going to perform a more efficient removal.
We're going to call daily movement on the mobile template,
and we're going to pass in on empty quality,
acquitted without criteria.
This would effectively match all the documents that we have in our collection,
not as we have the sedan in place.
Let's go to the application runner again.
This implements commander runner, and it has at order with the value of two,
because you want executed after we have items in our collection.
There are two requests that we have to implement.
The 1st 1 is we need to mark all the flights to Rome as delayed.
So this probably looks like a group update.
And then we have to remove flights with the duration less than two hours.
Again, this kind of looks like a batch, you know,
did it the best in temperament batch of it is to call the update Muti
methods are monk a template for that in Italy Final query.
And in this case, the criteria is the destination city,
which must be a courtroom.
Then we create another object,
and we said that is the late field to be updated to the
value of truth they were calling the update.
Muti mattered,
passing in the query update object and the Fight information class,
we are doing something similar with the removal of flights
that have a duration off less than two hours.
We're building a query, and the criteria is duration less then 120 minutes,
and then we're losing the final remove method to remove
the flights that matched that quick.
After running the application, we can see that everything worked as expected.
The database is they're taking first,
so we're removing all the distant documents in the collection,
then we're asserting six documents.
After that, we have a batch of it.
We're calling update using the Querida two discussed earlier,
and the update object we're setting is delayed.
Too true.
Then we're performing a batch.
Deal it.
So we're finding documents using the duration less than 130 minutes.
And then we're deleting those documents from the collection.
Awesome.
In the first collection,
aircraft are stored as embedded objects in the flight information document.
They have a model, and they have a number of seats.
We have requests that aircraft should really be stored
as a string HQ concocting a ting.
Both the model and the number of seats.
How the implement is well, of course, using custom converters,
I created a new package Parasite Airport Management,
that Debbie and I have added two new classes.
Aircraft Gibby Read converter and aircraft BB right convert.
Let's start with the right.
Converted.
It's a simple class that implements converter.
The sources aircraft.
The destination is drink, and the convert minted.
Just concocting is get model and get number of seats.
The databases are converter is also pretty simple.
It's implements converter,
but it's time the source is string and the destination is aircraft.
You have a convert method,
and here we're splitting that string by that special character.
And then we're building a new aircraft object,
and we are turning it pretty, pretty simple.
The last step is to actually register our converter.
We can register converters in any class annotated with that
configuration because you are in a spring with application.
We can also register them here.
We define the new being.
We're creating an empty list off converters.
Then we're adding the aircraft reader and the aircraft writer converter on.
We're turning and ministers off Monk,
a custom conversions passing in the converters that we have just created.
Let's honor it up and see if this made any difference.
If you go back to Mongo Compass,
we can see that the aircraft field isn't are serialized as a strength,
and this means that our converters were successfully registered.
Before we conclude this devil, I want to make an important remark.
That database, either that we implement it is by no means production ready.
Sure, it was great for demos, and he does his job,
but it's not suitable for production.
We'll see a better alternative once we explore that.
Ah, migration's later on. In his course,