[Autogenerated] all right.
Time for a quick recap in his module.
We looked at document referencing in Among really be We have two types
of references in Mongo Manu References or D B refs.
I think about the breaths as manual references on steroids,
the spring framework.
Thus things under the hood to make our experience with using the B riffs easier.
For example,
fetching off the reference document is handled by the spring framework,
which is a great thing cascading on Save is not implemented for the virus.
Luckily for us,
we can achieve this by hooking into the spring mongo lifecycle events on
before safe or on the phone convert our great hooks.
To implement this, we also looked into manga life second events,
which are a great way to add valuable logic.
Innkeeper assistance moments, security,
auditing and cascading are good examples off watch can achieve if you
hook into these events before we conclude this module.
I also want to know once a couple of things in the Mongol documentation.
It states that for nearly every use case where you want
store a relationship with into documents,
use manual references, the application can resolve those references as needed.
Also in the Mongol documentation,
it stays that if you need to reference documents from
multiple collections or multiple databases,
then should consider using the breaths.
It seems like the Mongol documentation doesn't want us to
die ourselves with relationships a lot.
Instead, they want us to use the no sequel approach.
We're in bed documents into one another.
Now, based on my experience, I kind of have this recipe.
First of all, Start by designing your data without relationships.
Stay true to the no sequel philosophy.
This should be your number one go.
If this can be achieved, then I would recommend that you use Deb.
You're F,
but only if you implement cascading on safe and you
don't create bi directional references.
That's because Spring offers some features out of the box.
We have population off the related documents,
and if you permit cascading,
you also get that so it will make your life working
with the application a lot easier.
And last but not least, you should consider manual references.
I think you are now ready to work with spring
applications that you smuggle baby,
you know how to configure these two technologies together in the hot
implement code operations and how to relate documents together.
However,
there are still some things that you need to
consider in production applications.
One of them is that immigration's.
I've seen no application in my career that doesn't use that migrations. So in the next module, with tackled other immigration's in Mongolia be.