[Autogenerated] it's time to get our hands dirty and write some code.
In his demo,
we're start by creating a simple spring with application and connected
to a mongo database for import the new dependencies.
Then we'll have the connection.
Parameters will apply the annotations that we just learned,
and hopefully our application should connect to an existing Manco server.
Let's write some coat.
Where do we go?
We want to create a brand new spring application well,
to start that spring that I'll I selected a maid from project our languages.
Javon.
The spring with version is 2 to 1 of which is the latest version up until today,
and I want to create a project.
The group would be pro site,
and the artifact will be airport management actually generate and we'll have ah,
brand new empty spring with application that can start to work against.
I took a generated project, and I've opened it in intelligent.
As you can see right here, we just have the bare minimum dependencies.
Basically, we have a dependency on spring starter and spring with starter test.
I also took the Liberty to create a couple of classes to speed things up a
little bit the airport management application class,
his annotated with US promote application and is the spring application and two
point it read around the spring application around method.
I've also created this class called Application Runner,
which implements the command line runner interface.
This exposes the run method his spring.
Every class that implements the command Liar,
honor interface will get executed automatically
after the application bootstraps.
And I want to use this kind of concept to write our use cases.
Then we have our domain and you want to manage flight information.
So I've created a couple of classes.
The 1st 1 is aircraft in.
This class has two properties Ah,
model and number of seats along with some Gethers.
Then we have flight type, which is an imam,
internal or international, And then we have our main entity,
which is flight information.
Now,
flight information contains various properties that are of
interest for people working in airport management.
We have an idea.
We have departure and destination the flight type.
If the flight is delayed, the duration of the flight,
the departure date,
the aircraft and we also have some or did information here created at so
when this flight information was created in our system,
Then we have a stomach constructor and a bunch of getters and centers.
So pretty standard stuff.
We are now ready to connect its application to a mongo
server on Let's Apply the principles in the steps that we
discussed earlier on in his module.
The first thing that you need to do is you two other
dependency for spring daytime.
I'm gonna be so go ahead, opened upon not xml file.
And we're adding a brand new dependency,
a dependency on spring boots, starter data,
manga TV.
We'll kick save.
And now we have all the dependencies needed toe work with mongo to be.
The next step is to add the appropriate annotations
to the flight information class.
Let's do that.
Flight information is our main entity and wantto persisted as a monk a document.
Therefore, we annotate this class with a document.
I also want to change the name of the collection.
I want to save all flight information in a collection called Fights.
Then I have marked the idea property as the I D field off
this flight information class departure city and this nation
city have also been modified.
I think their property names are a bit along.
Therefore, I have renamed them to departure,
and destination was in the at field annotation.
I also an update them with at Indexed because we'll probably do a
lot of filtering around departure and destination.
And finally,
I have marked the created at field with a transient
created that is an audit information.
We need it in our program, but you do not want to persist it in Mongo.
This object is not ready to be saved in a mongo that always
I just opened up Mongo Debbie Campus,
a free graphical interface that helps you to navigate Mongo dippy
databases and execute queries against them.
My Mongol instance isn't star locally on local host Port
27017 That's where we need to connect.
The server is not protected by credentials because it wants on.
My local developed machine.
Lets out this information in the Application Properties file.
The Application Properties file is located here.
Under the resource is Father.
Let's write the necessary properties needs to connect to
Mongo to be we have local host as the server.
Port 27017 which is the default port and the database,
which is airport management.
We don't have any security on his database,
so we don't need to pass in credentials.
We can also use the shorthand version and get rid of the properties above.
We can use spring data Mongol de Bure I and embed everything over here.
So let's go ahead and start.
Its application application is running and I want
to highlight his line over here.
Opened connection to local host Pour 27017 This is a
success message telling us that we have established a
connection toe among were to be severed.
At this point, I could have entered the demo.
However,
I can help myself from wanting to write something in this mango database,
So let's do that.
I opened up the application runner class and I want to
modify it to insert something in Margo.
I want to insert an empty flight.
I replaced the content, and now our application runner looks like this.
We want to inject Margo template in the application.
Rather,
constructor mogul template is like the main class that
executes query against databases.
More on that in the upcoming modules, then in the run method.
I created an empty flight,
and I used the safe method on the Mogul template to persist it.
Let's go ahead, start the application and welcome.
Going back to Mongo Compass, we can see that a new database has been created.
Airport management Airport management contains the collection in flights,
and his collection most likely has the document that we just inserted.
And here it is.
You have this document with an auto generated I D and some basic information.
So what just happened?
Well behind the seas, when we used Margaret Template and the safe method,
it automatic generated a database for us,
the fight collection, and then it inserted that empty flight into the database.
If you already had an existing database or collection,
those would have been used.
Instead, however,
you can see the power and all the things that the Spring Data Mongo Debbie library Thus for us, I think it's pretty amazing