Hi and welcome back to this e-mail because now that we have implemented all the attention mechanism
we are ready to create office big parts of the transformer which will be the encoder.
Again we'll have a quick look at the paper right here.
So let's see this architecture.
Hey.
This is the block we will focus right now.
So we will call and then call the layer just this small parts right here.
While small actually it's the most important one but this sequence of operations will be called and
called a layer.
And we will have in order to build our encoder to add the embedding the positional encoding and as many
times as we need the and causal layer.
So a quick reminder why we need to do is to first apply a motorhead attention right here then to add
the results to the inputs and to the playing on and then just apply some regular linear functions using
the dense layer and again use these small adds and known sequence at the end you will see some drop
outs between the operations.
This is just a standard way to train our networks.
We forget some weights during the training so that we avoid all the fitting.
Now that carving heads how it will work.
Let's get back to coding
and we will start by class and call the layer which inherits from the Layer class as per usual.
So let's define the unit function self and what we will have as inputs is this sorry f f and four feed
forward networks units which are the number of units that we will use in the forward spots that we just
mentioned earlier just after the attention and the Kennedys imports and the number of projections for.
So let's just call it no approach for the attention mechanism.
And finally the dropout rate that we mentioned before.
So now let's call the super we applied to any cogent layer and self and call the Inuit method for mates.
So let's make sure we could.
We will be able to use the vile boats later in the code.
So self that's fit for network units but nuts just units will be good enough f f and units we'll get
some guess I'm quite hungry f f in units self that's no projection equals then the projection and for
the last one self that drop outs is equal to drop outs that we Hotz as parameter here we are we will
for sure needs the build function because we will need dimension of the models and many thing that we
don't have when we just create the objects and call the layer.
So here self and input shape as before we don't know exactly right now what we will use.
So let us first try to define the call function and as we go through the process we will build what
we need to build in the appropriate methods just above.
So call will need self.
Of course we will get inputs.
We will get the mask that we will apply in the Motorhead attentional layer and training which is a parameter
that is either equal to False or true.
And it basically just says to objects if we are in the training phase in this case it will apply the
drop outs so that we don't other fits.
If we are not training it will not apply the job because we want to get our whole architects working
at 100 persons.
What we will do is that we want to do the first step which is to apply a multi heads attention to the
inputs.
So in this case let's be sure about that.
We can see that in this motel attention some layer.
The key is the values and the queries are all the same.
And they are all just the inputs we get right here.
So we can say that we send inputs inputs inputs and finally we give it's the mask.
So we use the self had attentional layer let's define it for I hate self that's multi heads.
Attention will be a multi heads attentional layer and self tuts number of projection.
This is all we need to to give.
So it's well defined.
Now we will use some dropouts here and there.
So let's apply one right now self that's dropouts.
1 attention and training will be given by the training perimeter right here.
And then let's apply the norm that we so the sum and the norm that we mentioned before in the article
so attention equals self.
That's known one applied to the sum of attention and the inputs we had before.
So let's just declare those two layers that we are using right now.
So self that's dropouts.
1 Sorry equals layers.
That's dropouts and the rates is just self.
That's dropouts and self that's no one equals layers.
That's like a normal normalization.
And let's say that the normalization will use epsilon equals 1 e minus 6.
This is just a standard one.
You can try other accidents if you want to.
Trust me this one will do the job.
Now we have the feed forward parts that we want to deal with.
So let's say that all outputs will be equal to self.
That's tense one which is the first part of all feed forwards process attention and then we have to
apply the second one.
I forgot t self that dense two of our outputs.
We apply a small about just as before.
So another one about two of outputs and finally we apply the set and the norm as we did before so known
to apply to two outputs plus attention that we computed before.
Let's now just define those those different layers that we used self.
That's dense.
One Equals layers that tense units equals.
And this is where we use self.
That's f f and units and as they say in the paper we will use activation equals
value and the second part of the fit forward phase is another dense layer.
This time we want to go back to units equals self.
That's the model and this is where we realize that we need this model and that we can only get it in
the build method.
So let's just define it right he said that the model equals inputs shape and that's along the last dimension
and the next layer that we want to define is drop outs right here.
So itself that's true about two equals layers that dropout rate equals self.
That's that's drop outs.
And finally the last one well actually let's let's be lazy and copy this one and just change this one
by a two.
Here we are.
The whole process has been rewritten so I think the outputs afterwards we are looking for at the end
of an encoder layer so we can just return outputs and I guess these and call the layer is ready to be
used.
So as we said before now we are ready to create the whole encoder using the encoder layer.
Same thing.
This inherits from the layer.
Class def in its self.
And now we will have a certain number of parameters to build this layer.
So first thing is number of layers.
So this is the number of time we will repeat the called the layer inside the layer.
If I find units will we will just pass to the encoder layer.
Same thing with the number of projections and for the drop outs we will need the vocab size because
there is an encoding phase at the beginning of the encoder an emerging face sorry at the beginning of
the encoder.
So we need to know what is the size of the vocabulary in order to do the embedding and of course the
model to tell the imaging which will be the dimension of our words.
At the end of this process let's be fancy and given name to layer with name equals encoded so that's
it.
That's all the parents as we will need to build our encoder as usual.
Let's call super and call the self and this time we need to pass the time it's a name because name is
something that belongs to the lower class.
So we have to say to the layer class that the initialization is made with this name right here.
Let's define all the valuables that we will need later.
So self that's number layers equals no layers.
Self.
That's f f.
And units equals f offend units.
Self that no protections equals to the projections set ups drop outs.
You guessed it equals drop outs and self.
That's the model finally equals D.
Model and we'll see later for the different layers we need to define it's easier to start with the cold
methods and to see along the way.
What we'll need to define before so def call it using self and we get the inputs the mask and again
the training to see if we need to apply the drop outs.
So first thing we had to do in the encoding phase and call layer is to apply the embedding itself.
That's embedding that we will define matter of inputs then it's a detail that they say in the paper
but at this point we multiply by T F dots math that's askew all t t costs self.
That's the model T F that's floats 32.
So this is just a small normalization.
This is detailed in the paper when they say how the train is so let's quickly have a look at this here
in the emptying of self Max they say in the embedding layers emitted by those weights by square roots
of D model.
So that was the reason of this small multiplication right here.
Now let's apply all that positional encoding layer.
So outputs outputs equals self.
That's pause and coding of all inputs.
Because the way we built the position and coding layer is that it returns the sum of the outputs and
the positional encoding.
So this will work fine and outputs equals self.
That's dropouts.
Just to tell you about before before applying all the encoding sub layers outputs training.
So now we need to apply the encoder layer a certain number of times the best way to do that is to have
actually lists of layers so that we can go through each with a loop.
And this is what we will do right here.
So for let's put it in the middle.
For I in range self.
That's number of layers.
We will simply call out outputs equals self.
That's encoding layers No I and we'll apply it to outputs with this same mosque again and with a training
parameter.
And here we are.
We have applied the encoding sub layer as many times as we need.
So let's just return the outputs and the last thing we have to do of course is to declare all those
layers that we used in the input method.
So let's proceed.
Self that's embedding will simply be layers.
That's and Beijing with us parameters the vocab size and the dimension of the model.
So we need to tell the embedding layers.
What is the size of our vocabulary.
So what.
What is the maximum number that is used in the tokenization.
And of course the dimension that we want to achieve with our module.
So that was for the embedding layer.
Now we use a positional encoding layer that we created just before.
So let's say that this is positional sorry and coding we did not need any time to for this one.
Then we used a dropouts.
Let's quickly define its layers.
That's dropouts rates equals dropouts.
Then we have all our encoding layers.
So as I said the best way to do that is to create a list of encouraging layers so encodes a layer.
F and units you know it's perfect.
We use the number of projections and finally we need to give it the drop out rate and this is done for
something that we don't need in range no layers.
So this is operation right.
He just creates a certain number of encoding layers and this number has been given by the number layers
valuable.
And actually we just realized right here that we almost don't need those valuables anywhere else that
in the end it functions so we can actually get rid of a lot of things here.
So basically we can get rid of all those valuables as all we need outside of the in its method is the
model right there and the set number layers right here.
And so we just have to keep those two.
And and that's it's so perfect.
We have all anchored already.
Now we can go to the second big parts of the transformer and build the decoder.
And when this is done we will finally be able to build the whole architecture.
So let's waste no more time and get into the decoder.
See you soon.