Hi guys and welcome back to this tutorial.
We are now ready to start coding all can stretch are using the transformer.
And of course the first step is to import all of the dependencies that we will use later.
So first we will have to import the standouts named by library as NPR.
As always we will perform some mathematical operations so we will import this one too.
Then for the data proposed to seeing as we are dealing with strings we will hugely need these re whatever
library which is really useful when you want to clean or to perform any operation on strings.
Mostly when you need rig X and we will need some.
We will come to that later.
Then during the training we will wants to use the time model just to know how long each a box will take
during the training.
And finally we will use this one that is related to Google collab.
It's actually used to get all files from the Google Drive.
This is what we have set up in the previous tutorial.
Thanks to this one we will be able to load our data in all notebook.
Second group of libraries that we wanted to import of course are are the ones related to tensor flow.
So we will do something that only works on Google collab which is to to ask Google collab to use a specific
version of tensor flow.
This is how we write it.
So we asked tensor for version to be two point X which is the latest version.
If this doesn't work well too bad we'll just pass by.
Everything should work perfectly fine.
And now we are ready to import tens of flow as T F as per usual containing tons of flow we will also
use a lot of layers just to make life easier.
We will imports tens of flow that cure us from denser flow that cures.
We will import the latest model so we won't have to write intensive flow that cures the layers that's
dense.
For instance we will just be allowed to write letters that dense.
This will make our code more readable and cleaner.
And last but not least.
Doing all data processing.
We will have to talk a nice or sentences and this is something that will be done through this library
intensive flow data sets.
TFT s which contains these very useful tool which is the chicken either and
perfect.
Now we can see that the right version of tensor be selected and that we are ready to go to the next
phase.
See you soon.