Hey guys.
And welcome back to this tutorial.
Now that we have imported all the dependencies that we will need we have to import the data.
So we want to load the files that we uploaded to our Google drive into our notebook.
We will do this the same way as we did for the CNN so we will use the drive module from google docs
call up just like so we will ask the notebook to have access to devices in all personal drive.
So drive that mounts and we will announce this in content slash drive.
And if we compute this we get this you email well that we have to click and a new page opens.
Well we have to pick the google drive outcomes that we want to use.
We just have to allow Google to access to everything the needs and the other codes that we can just
copy right here busted there and to wage beats.
And here we are the fires have been mounted.
So if we go too fast here we can see that now there is this tri folder.
When we have access to my drive so we can have access to all the files that are into our personal Google
Drive.
And that's what we are going to do right now.
So let's create a new coding block so simple as that with open so let open the first file that we need
instead of writing the whole path by myself.
I would just go through the exploit.
Right.
Right here.
So projects transform the data.
We will first load the English data sets.
So right click copy but whoops sorry.
Right quick copy path here.
And here we are as simple as that.
We have the path that is just correctly given to the open function.
We will say that we will only read this file we want.
We don't want to modify it so mode.
Reading is enough.
And the encoding of all files is in UTF Dash 8 which is quite standards in Western languages.
So this file is open.
We say that it reads it will be open as f.
So in this block we can have access to the file just by using F and this is what we do right now.
So we will create the valuable Europol on this call.
English equals f that.
So.
So now in Europol English we have the whole the whole corpus in English as a huge string and we just
want to do the same thing with the four files.
So let's just copy blasts here.
It's not in English.
The second one will be in French
Let's copy pasta one more time and yet I hate and change the name of the five right here.
So first one non breaking underscore prefix copy that's
and busted right here.
And finally all we have to to do is to change the name of the valuables right there.
So here it's in French.
And this one will be called non underscore breaking on this code prefix and this go in.
Let's copy that and passed it's right.
That and this will be in French.
OK.
Let's run that's and hopefully it will not take so long.
And here we are.
It took a few seconds but we can test it right now.
See if we want to print you or Paul English and let's say the first's 50 characters resumption of the
session backslash but session I declare resumed the session I guess.
So it seems to work perfectly fine.
Here we are.
We have all the files we want the corpus the none breaking prefixes into all not the end we all just
really to process all that and to work with it.
See you soon.