Hi and welcome back to this A.P. course.
So let's start with the first detail of the architecture.
After the attention mechanism and the one we will deal with right now is the positional encoding.
So what is it.
Let's have a quick look at the architecture that we can see in the paper.
So we already notice that there is these huge encoder he and decoder there.
But each one starts after an embedding layer with a positional encoding so we can see that there is
a plus because we add to the embedded words what we call a positional encoding.
So why do we do that.
The thing is that's with CNN so conversational neural networks all our innards recommend to all networks.
The order of the woods had an impact on the process for instance with the convolution on the networks.
The fact that we use a small filter that goes through the whole sentence it means that's words that
are close to each other in a sentence.
Will it be in the same filter.
So the order of the words has an importance and an inverting two words will change the outputs of all
CNN Just because two words might maybe not appear anymore in the same filter.
And for the audience and of course the fact that we feed the words one after another gives a real importance
to the order of the woods words but here for a transformer it's not the case anymore because we computes
the attention mechanism in a global way and we give the same role to each woods.
So for instance let's say we don't use a positional encoding and let's say we have an English sentence
as input for all and codes and we want to translate it into a French sentence so the inputs and the
output of all decoder will be different sentence.
So let's imagine that we invert the first and the third words for instance in our initial English sentence
in all set attention mechanism we will just again invert the first and the third element of the sequence
because words that were previously related to the first elements are not related to the third elements.
So when we we compose the sentence at the end of the attention mechanism we we compose it's in the third
element instead of the first.
So we just keep the inversion and same thing for the first elements instead of the third.
So basically at the very beginning in the inputs of all coda if we inverts the first and the third position
it will just keep this inversion throughout the whole encoding phase.
Now let's see what happens in this multi attention sub layer.
We have a French sentence here and in the output of this sub layer each elements ie.
As we said before is made of all the elements from the output of the encoder and we we compose them
according to how they are related to the elements from the French sentence.
So if in the initial sentence so we thought that the inversion the first element of our French sentence
was related to the first elements of the English one and that the third then in the attention mechanism
in the outputs we will get for the first elements and lots of the first elements of the English sequence
and not a lot of the third elements of the English sequence because the first elements of the French
sequence is really similar to the first elements of the English sentence and nuts to the third elements
of the English sentence.
But if we inverted the first and the third elements of the English sentence then it means that's all
first elements of the French sentence is not related to the third element of the English sentence and
that the first one.
So when we will make the attention mechanism right here as output for the first elements we will get
a lot of the third elements of the English sentence and not the first but the third elements of the
English sentence right now was exactly the same thing as the first elements of the English sentence
before the inversion.
So basically at the outputs of this sub layer we get exactly the same thing as if we hadn't made the
inversion.
So basically any inversion in the order of the words of the input sentence will have no impact because
in this operation right here we will just get the elements that are important for us with no regard
to where they are in the sentence.
And that's a shame because in all language of course the place of the words in our sentence has an importance.
So we would like to find a way for all transformer to have an idea of the positions of the words in
our sentence.
So let's add a positional encoding so numbers after the embedding layer that helps keeping track of
the positions of the words and what they do in the paper.
Is that the use of the sine and the cosine functions in order to compute those numbers.
That's the one to us.
So there is not a lot of intrusion to explain right here because in the paper they say that they tried
different numbers and the idea is just to add something as a numbers that will be different for each
position in the sentence and for each dimension of the embedding so that we lose the symmetry between
each position.
So basically what we will do is that for each dimension of our embedding which is represented by the
number I we will get assigned all the cosine function with respect to the position in the sequence.
So here there is a graph some visual representations of some of those functions for different dimensions.
So if we take for instance the fourth dimension of all embedding if we go through all the positions
in a sentence of length one hundred we can see that we have a certain sine functions that has a certain
frequency.
But if we go to another dimension like dimension 6 we again gets the sine function with respect to the
position in the sequence but the frequency has changed.
So in all matrix representing our sequence we are a different number for each position in the sequence
and each dimension in all embedding.
So that was it for the positional encoding there is nothing really complicated or magical about that.
It's just a tool that we had to add in order to give importance to the order of the words in all sequence
because the attention mechanism is very global and is symmetrical with respect to the positions of the
woods.
So that was it for this first little step.
We are almost done with explaining the transformer so we're getting closer and closer to implementing
it.
Let's finish this.
In 2014 the next section and see you soon.