Hello, guys, first of all, I welcome you all to Discourse on Ruby.
Thank you so much for enrolling.
My name is a marathon and in discourse, we are going to start on with the basics of Ruby and advance
towards the upper tropics, slowly taking everyone along, maybe a beginner and intermediate level programmer
of Ruby or the one who knows a lot about Ruby.
So even if you have no knowledge of programming, even then you can continue this course as this over
each and every thing.
You need to start on with your journey of programming for the big N, I have given each basic concept
you need to know to start on with a ruby programming for the ones who have some little knowledge of
Ruby before this course is going to take them to a professional level coder in Ruby.
For the ones who have a lot of knowledge and Ruby, this course is going to help you a lot as well as
this contain many new things that are included in Ruby as well as I have created many applications that
will surely help you a lot.
So this course is basically for everyone.
So if you want to learn Ruby and become a programmer and Ruby, then congratulations, you have come
to the right place because this is the platform.
This is the course that will help you learn Ruby from beginner level to advanced level.
So in the next, Dorio will start on with the introduction to Ruby and you will see how powerful and
effective language Ruby is.
And that's why you need to learn Ruby, if you are from a programming community or you want to join
it in the programming community.
So that's it with this tutorial.
I thank you again for enrolling in discourse and I again, thank you for watching discourse and I will
see you guys in the next Dorio.