Hey, guys, what's up?
This was a marathon, and I welcome you to another detail on this course on Ruby.
And in this tutorial, we are going to be covering every function, the reject function, the select
function, and we are also going to see the land function.
So we will start on with the reject function.
Now, it is a hash class matter which returns a new hash, which consists of entries for which the block
return false.
So if you talk about the syntax of this, it is hash dot reject.
You have to specify the key value pair and you didn't specify a condition.
Now for the key value pairs on which this condition is met, those values are going to get rejected
and go out of the scope.
And the remaining values which are not going to meet these conditions are going to return as an output
to this reject function.
So we will see examples.
And then you are going to understand that which values are going to get rejected and which are going
to be returned.
The second function we are going to cover in this tutorial is the land function.
LENTE is a hash class method which gives the number of key value bearers in the hash.
So simply it is going to return the land or whatever hash you specify.
And it has a very simple syntax.
All you have to write and hash.
Stotland no arguments are needed over here and it is going to return to you with the length of whatever
hash you specify.
The third function we are going to cover in this tutorial is the select function select as a hash class
method, which finds the area from the hash based on a block condition.
And if you talk about the syntax of this, it is hash tag, select key value pair and the condition.
And for whatever key value Paris, this condition is going to be true.
It is going to return those values and the remaining values are going to get discarded.
Not to select and reject function are totally opposite each other in the reject function when the condition
what our key value bearers meet, the condition, we specify those values are going to get rejected
and the remaining are going to be returned to us as an output.
Whereas in the select function on whatever key value pair, the condition is going to be true.
Those values are going to be redone and the remaining values are going to get rejected.
So for the reject function, whatever is going to be returned as an output is going to be rejected in
case of select, whereas in the select function, whatever is going to be printed out as an output is
going to be the part which is going to get rejected and the reject function.
So don't need to get confused in simple words.
These two functions are opposite of each other.
Whatever is the output of the select function as the rejected part of the reject function and whatever
is the output of the reject function is the output of the select function.
So let's move on to some examples and then you will know more about this.
So let's move on to Adam.
So we'll start on with the simplest of all, we will first cover the land function, so for the land
function, well, you can simply write and you can write inputs.
Length of it is, and you can use interpolation and that you can just ride it idot.
Lent her on it and it is going to return you with the land.
So over here, the land of is true, which means that it contained two values or you can say two key
value pairs.
So for me, it is going to be three and four C. It is also going to be three.
So that is what is how you can get the length of a hash.
And Ruby now moving towards the main part of this tutorial, that is the reject and the select function
starting on with the first one, we will cover the reject function.
And as I told you that you have to specify a condition on a key value pair and on whatever condition
the key value pair is true, those values are going to get rejected and the remaining values are going
to be returned as an output.
So first, let's just make all of these at a simple syntax.
Or you may say a single syntax is remove this right entry into the will here.
And let's just remove this as well from hell, let's just specify the value for this as well.
That is 200.
All right.
So now everything seems good.
So now let's use the reject function on these three hashes.
So what we will write is that we will write in put.
Rejected.
Or you can just ride in values.
Remaining are so values remaining after the rejection are basically going to be whatever is going to
be the output from this reject function, and that is what is basically going to have a conditional
hell.
And in that condition, you are going to have a key value bill.
To try and key.
And value add in this key value pair what you are going to read and you are going to specify a condition
now that, for example, the first condition is that if you want to specify a condition on this key
so let's say I just read it key is less than, let's say B, so if key is less than you have to specify
a call as well.
All is just get it a bit so that you can see the complete nine.
All right, good enough.
So let's just run it now.
And you can see that it has returned the value be done, that now we have applied this condition on
this AOL, which has two values, a hundred and be two hundred.
So we have ritenour here that you have to reject those values, all those values which have a key that
is less than be so in this case, for the values in this hash, Huskie is less than B is only.
So this is going to get rejected, not the remaining value.
Is this value with the key B?
So that is what is remaining and that is what is going to be returned as an output to us.
Now, for example, if you just try it for this bill here and if you use the very same condition, but
you just wait and see or here now for the key to be less than C, the two values that are remaining
are A and B. So if you just run this, the output is going to be only C, and if you just specify B,
run, this output is going to be B and C as well.
Because for the key to be less than be the only key value pair, is this a hundred.
So that is going to get rejected.
The remaining values are B and C, B 200, C three hundred.
And that is what is going to be printed on your output screen.
Now you can also specify a condition on the value as well.
So let's just add a line space over here.
And in here, we are going to ride in boats.
And what we are going to right away here is that we are going right and values.
Remaining are and coalition, and we are going to use the very same veto to reject.
We are going to have a key value built here as well, a key value, but this time the condition is going
to be specified on this value.
So we are going to write and value is less than 200.
So is it a bird or underscored?
And you can see for whatever the values are, less than two hundred.
They are the two hundred and see three because we are using here and the values that are less than 200
over here is this basically this hundred overhead.
That is the key.
So this value here is going to get rejected due to this condition.
We have specified where the remaining values over here are be two hundred and thirty three hundred and
that is what is going to be the output right over here.
So not only you can use the key as the condition, but you can also specify a condition on the value
and all those values that satisfy the condition.
Or you can say whatever key value pair that satisfy the condition.
We have specified those values are going to get rejected and the remaining values are going to be printed
right over here on your Adam Bruckner.
Now, moving to the second function we are going to cover is the basically the third function we are
going to cover after the London project.
We are going to cover the select function.
So here we are going to add a line so that you can later see the difference as well.
Output's.
With the.
Reject function.
All right, so these are the outputs with the reject function, just remove it from here.
And just at a space of a hill.
And we are going to ride in boats.
Outputs with the select function.
All right, so what we are going to do is that we are going to just copy this from here pasted right
over here.
And what we are going to do is that we are going to use select over here.
Selek over here as well.
The remaining is going to be the very same, your crime bureau Talagi value Biraki is less than valued.
Less than 200 runit.
And as you can see over here, that you have got the output with the reject function and output with
a select function as well.
And if you just noticed right over here on the bottom there is that the output are totally opposite.
Now, as you can see that the value that was rejected over here in this fusspot, was this a call and
Hundert, because this was the value that was less than B, so the reject function rejected this and
returned the remaining value.
That was B, two hundred.
So sorry, we are considering this A, B and C are going to get redundant.
A hundred is going to get rejected.
Now in the select function, whatever was rejected out here, that was a hundert.
That is what is basically the output of this function.
And what was the output of this reject function over here is basically what is rejected right over here,
as you can see for the second output.
You can see that you have got the two hundred and eighty three hundred because we were comparing comparing
there by value and B, 200 and 300 were redone.
And since the value of it that was hundred was less than 200.
So that was what was the value that was rejected because it suggests it satisfied the condition which
we have specified right over here.
But here.
Since the only statement that satisfy this condition is this a hundred, so only that statement is what
is going to get printed and the remaining is going to get rejected.
So what is the output over here is what is basically rejected out here and what is the output over here
is basically what is rejected right over here.
So that's why I told you that these two functions are what are totally opposite to each other.
The output of one is the rejection part of the other and the rejection part of one is the output part
of the other.
So I hope you have understood how to use these functions and what was basically the difference between
the reject and the select function.
So I guess that's it for this tutorial as well.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.