Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another tutorial on discourse on Ruby.
And in this drill we will be discussing about the DOT and the double calling operator.
Now, you call a module method by preceding its name with the module name and a right, and you reference
a constant using the module name and two columns.
Now, the two columns is basically a unary operator that allows Garstin instance methods, class methods
that are defined within a class or module to be accessed from anywhere outside the class or module.
Now remember that in Ruby, classes and methods may be considered as constants too.
Now you need to just prefix the double column constant name with an expression that returns the appropriate
class or module object.
If no perfect expression is use, the main object class is used by default.
Now the double column operator is basically going to be a part of future tutorials when we will be discussing
about classes and objects.
But we show you a quick example and a look of how they are going to look.
Let me just move on to item.
Now, in the previous stories, you have been discussing a lot about the dot operator and you have been
using a lot of the dot operator in the previous tutorials as well, when you were using the bell and
functions that were the predicate function.
For example, if I just remind you of an example, then we be able using if a number was or do not,
we just use five dot odd and a question mark and then we use bots around this code and it will generate.
So that's where basically the dot operator is used to reference a method call.
Now, if you talk about the second operator, as I told you, that it is used to reference a constant
using the module name and two columns now the double calling operator as a tool use and in the operator
that allows constant instant's methods and the class methods that are defined within a class or module
to be accessed from anywhere outside the class are module.
Now, I don't want to go into the coding part of that because it is a kind of complex coding and that
has to be the part of the future tutorials.
But for now, you need to know the basic introduction and you need to know the description for what
call an operator is going to be used for in the future tutorials.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next Turrill.