Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Truby.
And in this drill we will talk about the bag methods we have in early.
Now, before we talk on about bag methods, we have to have a little background of a certain method
and how the original value does not change for that.
So, for example, we have, let's say, a variable X in which we have let's say.
Something like human capital, a i r, as you can see, that you and our capital, Roger and I are are
in the small cases now what if I write in votes?
Export down gays now donkeys is a building method that is applied on strength and what to do is that
it convert this entire string into donkeys as if I just run this goat.
You can see that the entire name is now in donkeys, as you and also in donkeys is.
But what if I write in books X after I have donkey Usted if I just run this goat?
You can see that even though I have done guessed it on the previous line.
But still when I printed out the normal character, I have got this you and this over here.
So this means that the original character has not changed.
It has only changed.
Should that letter when I used it in that specific line.
So for this, it is going to print out you and I in smoggiest, but it hasn't made any change to this
variable X and when I write in BoSox, it is going to have this E and you in capital case.
Now, what if you want to have changed the string?
What if you want that you and I should always be in the markets and you want that change, but you have
applied right here to be on the strength.
So what you will do is that you will just add an exclamation mark over here, run the score, and now
you can see both the outputs that you have got.
Umea, you are in small games.
And then again, you have got you are in the small case now.
That is what is called a bag method.
And they usually modified the object that they are being called on.
So this exclamation mark means that now the donkeys is going to reference to the object, which means
it is going to refer to the object or you must say the location where this X is located.
And it is going to make that change on that object's location.
So that change, which we have applied right here, is now going to be applied on this variable X and
this variable X is actually going to change.
So that's why I want after applying this change, I write inputs x o'haire.
You can see that I still have Umea.
You are in small cases now.
Bag methods always remember, ends with an exclamation mark and it often modify the object they're called
on.
So whatever you have, for example, you used up this method, then you can specify an exclamation to
make it a bang method and then that change is going to be made to the object.
You will be calling it on.
So.
Nowadays, programmers have learned that using the bang method has a number of disadvantages and they
should usually be avoided unless there is a very, very good reason for it.
So when you are using bang methods, always use them with caution.
We mostly mentioned this method because you might see them used elsewhere.
So I suggest you don't use them unless there is a very good reason to use them.
So because you don't want a variable actual value to get change and you don't want a reference to the
location and change that value because you might be using that value somewhere.
But if you want a value to change everywhere in your code, then you can use this exclamation mark,
which will make it a bang method and it will change the original value.
So that's how you can use the bang methods.
You can use them on any kind of method.
You can use them on, let's say, uppercase or undiscovered.
And as you can see, that now Umea are both in caps.
And there are a thousand of methods which can be normally applied on string, and after adding an exclamation
mark at the end of that, they'll become the bang methods and they will make whatever change you have
applied on the original string.
So I guess that's it with bang methods.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you guys in the next oratorio.