Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Ruby.
And in this story, we are again going to be covering two functions.
And these two functions are going to be the last we are going to be covering on HaShas.
So the first function we are going to go over here is going to be the delete function and then we are
going to see the March function as well in this tutorial.
So to talk about the delete function, it is a hash class matter which deletes the key value pair and
it return the value from the hash huskie is equal to the key.
So if you talk about the syntax of this delete function, it is hash tag or delete.
And in the parameters you have to specify the key, what you want to delete and the output is going
to be whatever has been deleted by the delete function.
The second function we are going to cover in this is the merge function and it is a hash class method
which combines two hash arrays and their contents, as you can just see it by its name, it is going
to merge to hashes.
So hash one dot merge and in the parameter you have to write in the name of the hash you want to merge
hash one with.
So let's say its name is hash tag.
So hash and hashtag are going to get merged by using this March function.
So let's see an example for how to delete and how to merge.
To hashas, so we already have got these three hashas in front of us, which we have been using from
the very first tutorial and O'Haire, what we are going to do is that first we are going to use the
delete function and delete certain values.
So we are going to write in votes.
Deleted.
Key value pair is.
Interpellation and interpellation, you are going to write an idiot deleted from.
I want to give something so you have to specify the key here.
So since we are using the syntax, so we are going to write in column AOL, which means that I want
to delete this 800 entries from here, run this ad, as you can see, that it says deleted key value
pair.
Is this handwriting try will help.
Now, if you want to, let's say just in something more Willhelm, that is both.
Delete.
The and you're going to use interpellation and from V, let's say I want to write and beat or delete.
And let's specify.
Let's say, see Ronda's and it is going to return the value that had been deleted, that is three hundred
in this case, just simplify this also as delete a.
Not enough to specify a call over here as well.
All right, now, for example, you specify something that is not a part of it and you want to delete
it.
That's supposed to run it.
And you can see that it has done nothing, which means that nothing has been deleted due to this function.
So if you have, let's say of that, never specified to something in this B, so you just write in the
wall here on this, it is going to also return nothing, which means that nothing has been because the
value that has been deleted is nil.
So that's why it has returned.
I this key value pair has been deleted.
This is no more a part of it.
For example, if you want to check, it puts.
You want to check if this has been deleted or not, so you can just write in the dot.
Include and you can just specify Colin V0 here.
Not like this, this has to be in the end, but.
Just remove it from here, Bestival, here, run this and you can see that it has now returned.
Also in this case, this key value pair has been deleted, but it has done nothing.
As you can see, nothing is printed out here because the value that was in B was nil.
So that's why nothing was printed over here.
But this B is no more a part of this hash B, so that's why when you write in B, not include anyone
to check if this G b exist and this has to be or not.
So it has redundant false.
So that's how basically the delete function work for a normal values and for the values that has nil
in them.
So moving on to the second part of the story, that is how to merge two areas sorry, hash errors.
So let's say we just remove one of them and let's say these are the two areas I want to marginalize.
Just change the values for them as well, since it has this value A and B and this has the value ABQ.
So let's just change it to C, D and finally with changes to E, so let's change the values for this
as well.
Let's say this is three and this is four hundred and this has to be five hundred.
So we are going to write in towards.
Maajid.
Hash Tachira.
Is.
Interpellation and you're going to ride in it or merge and in the parameters, you have to ride and
beat her on this and you can see that you've got the March area.
If you just move it over here, you can see that you've got a single arrow that is a hundred two hundred
eighty three and four hundred and eighty five hundred.
You can just storage in a variable as well like this, for example, you can just ride in something
like equal to this stuff over here.
And this is going to be stored in that.
All right, so now what you can do more about here is that, for example, you've got similar values
of a hill that's a tree and it is a similar value.
Let's see, the value for that is also Hundert.
Now, if you just run it now, it is going to treat this 800, which is specified right over here as
a single value because now these two are merged and are a single hash area.
So that's why you cannot have a same repeated if you repeat the same key in a same hash than what it
is going to do is that it is going to only take one in two regards.
So, for example, it has a different value than which value it is going to consider.
Is it going to consider the value of our hash in the most or it is going to consider the value for hash
B in the most?
Run it and you will see that you have got the area, which is the.
So the merged area since we are merging B with it.
So whatever is being merged, those values have a higher priority.
So that's why this is going to get a higher priority and this is going to get merged with this merged
and in output.
You have got this a 200.
This is what is going to get neglected in a simple way.
So that's how basically you can merge errors and some science behind this that what is going to be printed
if the key values are the same.
So I hope you have understood both of these functions and you know how to use them now.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial as well.
Thank you so much for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next Dorio.