Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another detail on this course on Ruby, and this is basically
going to be the last tutorial in which we will be discussing about operators.
And in this drill, we will be discussing about operators, presidents and Ruby.
Now, we have already covered operators, presidents and Ruby, but that was a very, very, very brief
introduction now in this story.
And what I've done is that I almost added every operator and I have actually categorized them as well.
So starting on with the description part, the first and the utmost precedence is given to the constant
resolution operator that is represented with the double calling, which we have discussed just in the
previous drill.
Then we have the element reference and the element set operator.
Now you can see on the left side, then we have the exponentiation that is for the double starick.
Then we have the not the complement, the unary plus and minus that are basically the method.
Names for the last two are plus at and minus and then we have the multiply, divide and modulo.
Then we have the normal addition and subtraction.
Then we have the right and left bitwise ship, then we have the bitwise and then we have the bitwise
exclusive are and regular are, then we have the comparison operators, then we have the equality and
Bacterin match operators.
Then we have the logical and then we have the logical ah.
Then we have the range operators that include both inclusive and exclusive and then we have the ternary
if then else then we have the assignment then we have to check if specified.
Simbo define which we have also covered in the previous tutorial.
Then we have the logical negation, then we have the logical composition.
So the previous operator presidents we have covered we do then we have not covered all the operators,
but now since we have covered all the operators.
So I found it necessary to cover the Operator Precedent's again.
And I think that you would have understand Operator Precedent's very much now than before.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial as well.
And that's it with the introduction to operators as well and Ruby.
So that's it with this tutorial as well.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.