Hey, guys, what's up?
This is American, and I welcome you to an editorial on discourse on Ruby.
So far we have covered the value and we have covered the do while loop.
So for both of these loops, which we have covered so far, they are used when you are unknown about
the number of white Russian programs should undergo because you are uncertain about the condition and
you don't know how much that condition is going to it right now.
For example, you know the number of iterations for what you want to execute your code.
And in simple words, if you know the number of cycles before the loop is initiated, then what you
can do is that you can use the FA statement.
The far loop is used in conjunction with arranger's.
Often for each element of arrange a block of statements is executed and the statements are executed
with and keyword.
Now it also again has the doki word, which is again optional.
So if you talk about the syntax of this, it looks something like this.
You have the fakie word, then you have the condition, then you have the doki word.
Then you can simply write in the statements you want to execute for that specific number of iterations
or a specific number of cycles, and you have to terminate it with the end keyword.
Now, here, the condition is basically that you have to write in a variable which is going to store
the value of the counter.
Then you have to use the word and then you have to write in the check.
And the check is basically where ranges are going to help you out and you already have the word Granges.
So I don't have to explain what changes are over here.
So how this is going to be all implemented, I guess if I just go over some examples, then it would
be much more easier for you to understand.
So I will move on to Adam and in here we will have a very, very, very simple Ruby program using for
a statement in which what we will do is that we will just print out some numbers from, let's say,
zero to nine, so that what we have to do is that you are going to use four.
And after that, you have to specify the condition.
And as I told you, that the condition is something that you have to write in a variable, let's say,
is the variable.
Then you have to use the English word and then you have to write in the range.
So what we are going to do is that, as I told you, we are going to write in the number from zero to
nine and you can just write and do what is optional if you don't want to write and you can just write
and then the end is going to be generated by default.
When you click, enter and you're going to simply write inputs.
Hashtag and you're going to write an Iowa held, so antipollution is going to simply help you out to
print out those numbers.
If I just run the score and then explain what's going on over here, as you can see that you have just
got the numbers from zero to nine.
Now, what's going on over here is that this range is basically going to help you iterate this loop.
And this is basically what is the number of times this loop is going to get outrated.
So this lubow here is going to iterate from zero till nine for the first time when it has the value
zero, it's going to start on from the zero.
Zero is going to be stored in this very evil eye after the statements are executed.
Once this value is going to be incremented automatically and it is going to then assume the value one.
So I is then going to equal one.
So that's why, as you can see, that zeros printed on the first case, then we have got one.
After that it is going to have two, then three, then four and so on until nine.
Now up to nine is reached.
I will have the value nine, it will print it out and it already know, as I told you before, that
the fourth statement is used when the number of cycle is known before the loop is initiated.
So you already know the number of cycles this loop is going to go through.
So that's why after eight equals nine, this statement is executed.
Nine is going to be printed and it is going to automatically terminate this for a loop using this end
statement.
And it is going to come out and you can just check it out outside.
Before you run it, and as you can see that it says outside the far loop, so this is how basically
for a loop can be used, you can do more jobs over here, for example.
I would have, let's say, outside here, a variable, let's say some that is going to equal to zero.
And in here, what I'm going to do is that I'm going to ride in some equal to some plus I and I is going
to be incremented automatically.
Whereas if you just recognize the value and do a loop and that we have to increment the counterassault.
But in this case, the counter is going to be incremented itself so you don't have to increment the
counter.
The IRA is going to be zero for the first case.
It is going to equal to zero zero.
In the next case, it is going to be zero plus one.
Then it is going to be one platitude and it's going to be three plus four and so on till nine.
And you can just ride in like something the sum from.
Zero.
Do not like this, it's going to be zero to nine is.
And you can just ride in hashtag some random score and you can see that it stays the same from zero
to nine is forty five.
So that's how basically you can have things done inside a for loop if you know the number of cycles,
you can do a whole lot of things in between these.
But for now you have to keep it simple.
So you, you only need to know the syntax and how basically the counter is incremented itself and for
where you have to use Richardo.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next Dorio.