Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a and I welcome you to an editorial on this course on Ruby.
And in this tutorial, we are going to see that how hashas can be parsed as arguments to a function.
Now, there are several scenarios for this.
It's it turned out that in Ruby, if you call a method and pass in a hash as the last argument, it
is acceptable to write the hash without the curly brackets.
So if you follow this rule and you sprinkle in a few key value pairs, Ruby will interpret all of the
key value pair as one hash, because you know that to separate two arguments, you have to specify a
common between and to specify two different key value pairs.
You have to also specify a comma in between.
So if the parameter that is passed to a function is hash and you have, let's say, multiple key value
pairs and that are the first argument and you have got some other argument after that.
So that is going to generate error.
If you want to pass a hash as an argument to a function, then that has to be the last argument, because
the first arguments that are, for example, a string integer or any kind of data type that are going
to be treated as the first, second and so on arguments.
And the last argument is going to be treated as the hash because it is expecting the function is going
to only expect one more argument.
And you have got three, let's say, key value pairs of well here.
So all of these key value pairs, the editor will interpret itself as a hash and it will treat it as
a hash.
So startled with a very simple example in which we have got only one argument and we pass that argument
as a hash.
So it is going to be something like, for example, if to start on with.
Defining a function, let's say.
X is the name of the function and is expecting only one argument, A.
And in this function where we're going to do is that we are going to write and puts it on glass, so
it is going to print out the glass, which means that if it is a hash, this over here is going to print
out hash in the output added.
Now we are going to also write in, puts it to print out the hash, whatever it is.
And we are going to just end this function now down here where we call this function X, what we are
going to do is that we are going to specify these brackets.
If you don't specify them, it is even going to work.
And in here you are going to specify a call and one.
We call in to see Colin Tree.
And let's just change.
This name to be and this one to see and this one to these, because we already have this perimeter as
air, so we won't specify any value of having the KIA.
So let's just run this code.
And as you can see, that puts it on the glass has printed out cash, which means that this argument,
which we have passed into this function X has been treated as a hedge.
That's why puts it on the glass, has printed up cash here and puts it has printed out the entire hash,
as you can see, be one, two and D three.
Now, let's say you have to pass in two arguments.
So what is going to be the case for this function now?
So what you're going to do over here is that you will specify.
One more argument, let's say B and down here, you're going to ride in boats.
Beat out glass and you are going to ride in boats as well.
And down here, what you are going to do is that you are going to let's say the first argument is a
string.
So we are going to ride and we'll do a hell.
What a comma here, and the second argument is going to be this hash will run this court and you can
see that you have got string, then you have got a string which has to be printed, which is stored
in this, put it out and puts it up.
And then down here, the second argument that is going to be stored in this parameter over here is the
hash we have passed into this function.
So what's Broadcloth is going to print up hash and Buzby is going to print out that hash.
So this was the second scenario in which you have to send in two barometer's to a function in which
the first parameter is something other than a hash and the second parameter is a hash.
Now, the third scenario here is that what if you want to, let's say, just remove these brackets from
here?
So I will just remove these brackets from here, help run this code.
And the same output is going to get generated now.
Now, for example, if we have, let's say, three arguments, A, B and C and downhill, we will write
inputs.
Searoad class.
And we are going to ride in both Seela Hill and down Hill, where we are going to do is that we are
going to specify a third argument as well.
And let's say the third argument is, again, strength.
So we are going to ride in hell here.
So apparently it looks completely fine.
But as I explained in the Terry board, that when you want to pass in a hash to a function, then that
has to be the last argument of a function or a function is receiving only one argument that that is
completely fine.
But if it is receiving multiple arguments, then the hash has to be the last argument or else it is
going to generate an error message and see how it is going to generate that error message.
As you can see that it has generated an error message that says a Syntex unexpected.
There's this and this.
So what's basically going on over here is that it is treating this to be the first argument that is
going to be stored in this.
Then it is treating this as the second argument that is going to be stored in this be.
And it is going to treat this as a hash, that it is going to consider this as the third argument and
it is going to store it in the sea.
And this is going to consider it the fourth argument.
And that is where the error is going to generate because it is expecting three arguments and we have
passed in five, because if you don't specify the hash to be the last argument, then these oakhill
each get each key value pair is going to be considered as a separate argument to this function.
So this is totally not acceptable.
Here you have to specify if you want to specify, let's say, a third argument still here.
And what you have to do is then that this hashomer is going to be the last argument you can just write
in hello here on this court.
And that is going to run completely.
Well, as you can see, that string is whatever is stored in error, which is worse than your court
will go ahead.
And you have got a string again, Hallowes, a string.
And then the third argument is a hash and you have got your hash rate or held.
Now, for example, we want to enclose this in curly brackets and want it to be the second or let's
say the first argument we want, and we want some arguments after that as well.
So if you just enclose this in these brackets and we just remove this from here.
And we placed the third argument, hello, Hill, or underscored that it is going to run completely
fine because now we have enclosed this in these curly brackets over here.
And as you can see that the first whatever is stored in it is the glass of that string and the word
over here is boiled.
Then we have got the second argument as a hash and then you have got your hash right over here and you
have got the third argument, a string, and then you go to hell over here.
So if you want to.
Boss in a harsh as an argument to a function, and also you want that not to be the last argument and
you want some arguments even up to that, then you have close that hash Anarkali bracket.
You can then specify, let's say, multiple hashes as well.
For example, if you have got a fourth argument over here, you will just copy this from Hill Bastida
Hill.
Just change their names to F and G and downhill, sorry, uphill, we are going to specify the fourth
argument and downhill.
What we are going to do is that we are going to ride in boats, dot class, and we are going to ride
in boats to run this.
And it is going to work perfectly fine.
This is how you're here and you have got this over here.
Now, one more scenario here is that if you want to pass in only two arguments and both these arguments
are hashes, then what is going to be the scenario in that case?
So I will just remove it or two arguments.
We will just remove these two from here as well and we will just remove these from here as well.
All right, so for now, if I just run the school, it is going to not work and it says it has something
unexpected.
The integer expecting the string content or the string deb or something like things like that.
So if you just remove these arguments from here now.
And now run this good, it is again going to not work, so if you now again remove all of these from
here now run this good, it is again not going to work as it says, wrong number of arguments.
The given argument is won and expected arguments are, too.
So you cannot pass in two hashes to a single function that has to be won.
So we'll just remove this.
We will remove this from this and now it is going to work perfectly fine.
So these are some of the scenarios in which you can pass hashes to a function.
Now, for example, you have got.
Something that if you just like this movie in a bracket, a hill coffee, this is a comma Binsted again.
E, F and G are the keys now if you, let's say, just enclose them.
In these round brackets and now run it and it is not a game going to work as it says something like
Ruby syntax error expected, Gomaa expected this and things like that because it is expecting that bracket
to come right over here, not up to that sword.
Or I guess we have just you just try trying this now, run this and you can see that it doesn't work
with the same syntax error because.
Because it is expecting this bracket to appear right over here, so if you just place double, will
remove this from here.
And just remove this as well, and I'll run it now, it is going to run perfectly fine.
So these were some of the scenarios in which you can toss in a hash to a function, you know, when
to when you want to pass in a hash, not as the last argument.
And you have to include it in curly brackets.
You cannot pass in to to a single function.
And if you want to pause in a hash to a function and you don't want to and you want it to be the last
argument, then you don't need these curly brackets.
And moreover, you can just ignore the wrong brackets as well.
They are not necessary at all.
So I hope you now know all of this.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial, and I guess that's it with this section as well.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next section with some more interesting topics.
So bye bye, Dylan.