Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another detail on this course on Ruby.
And in this tutorial we will be discussing about some maths constants and some maths methods.
So starting off with the maths constants.
So now and if you're familiar with the background of mathematics, which I hope you are so you must
be familiar with the value of pi.
You must be familiar with the value of each and many other constants which have a constant value because,
you know, for the value of PI, it is always going to be equal treatment 14 and for the value of E,
it is going to be two point seven months.
So these are the values which are basically constants in maths.
And that's why in Ruby they're also known as maths constants.
So we will be doing some examples of maths constants and we will be.
Seeing how the value of fire and is going to be generated in Ruby, so let's just first discuss some
Ruby math matters.
So starting on with the ARC, cosign the math dot, a course is used to calculate the arc cosine.
And then we had the math dot Ecorse with an exclamation mark as well.
So we also have the hyperbolic arc cosine.
We have the arc sine, we have the hyperbolic arc sine, we have the ARC Tenjin and in that we have
the 18 that takes an X argument, then 18 to takes X and Y arguments.
And you know, if you're familiar with the math background, you know what is going on in here, then
we have the hyperbolic arc danger, then we have the arc cosine talking about some more methods.
We can calculate the cosine of a function of any kind of value we have.
Then we have the hyperbolic cosine, then we have the sine, then we have the error function, then
we have the complementary error function.
Then we have base X of the Iler Theorem, then we have the normalized fraction and exponent.
And for all of this description, you can just see the method on the left side as well.
Then we have the hypotenuse, then we had the floating point of value that is corresponding to Mandisa
and Exponent, then we have the hyperbolic sine, then we have the square root function that is used
to calculate the square root of a value.
Then we have the tangent, then we have the hyperbolic tangent.
And I guess that's all we have.
Yes.
So let's move on to some examples now before we move on to examples.
If you guys don't have any idea of these functions, then this means that you're not familiar and are
not good in mathematics, because these are some of the very, very, very basic things you must know
in mathematics.
If you don't know about any of these.
So I just suggest that you go on and search what is sign hyperbolic.
What a sign, what a square root, what it's danjean and things like those before you start on with
this tutorial.
But I hope that 99 percent of you knows about what is this, because this is just a basic concept of
mathematics.
So starting on with the maths constants.
So let's move on to Atom.
And here are what we're going to do, is that you have to simply write in math, Dot.
By but you don't have to use the dot operator, you have to use double calling operator.
Now, why do you have to use this double calling operator, because in the description of double calling
operator, I told you that the double calling operator is basically used with constants and since fire
is a constant.
So that's why you have to use this double call in here.
And you also have to specify bots run this.
And as you can see that the value of PI is generated.
That's three point one four one five nine three.
Then you can also calculate some values for other constants that includes E!
And you also, again, have to use this to call an operator because E is again a constant press order
and it is going to generate the value of E, which most of you are familiar with.
So that's the value of you, which is again, a constant.
So that's what constant you can just print out the value of any kind of constant using this method.
Now, let's move on to the maths function we have discussed right at the top here.
So let's just discuss some very basics of them.
So let's say we want to calculate the costs of, let's say, some value.
So let's move on to Adam and let's say we want to calculate.
The Matt.
DOD costs, which is basically the Syntex for that you can see right over here, and what you have to
do is that you have to specify brackets and specify the value for which you want to calculate the cost.
So just press all are, but you have to use the pots as well.
My bet, Aldar, and it is going to generate the cosine value for this 90.
So if you specify, let's say, one to Hill press Aldar and you can see that it has generated five four,
which is the cosine value.
I don't know how it is calculated.
Some of you must have the tables that contains the cosine values and that teaches you how to calculate
cosine values.
But you don't have to go to them.
You have your calculators nowadays.
So that's the cosine value that that's how cosine values are actually calculated.
If you want to calculate, let's say, the sign of a value, just specify.
And Aldar and zero point eight four is your answer if you want to calculate the tangent and order.
And that is going to be the answer.
If you going to do something, let's say something a bit more complex.
That is, let's say arc cosine.
Going to Adam and let's just type in a sign, Aldar and one point five seven is going to be the R cosine
of this one.
So if you want to, let's take a look at the square root of a specific value, just type in security.
Let's dive in 16.
Aldar and 4.0 is going to be the answer since sixteen four is basically put into four is 16.
So that's why the square root of sixteen is equal to four.
And that's how you can use any of these maths function on any of the value you want to use.
So I guess you are good to go and use any kind of the previous functions in your examples and you can
use any of them to calculate or go on with any kind of maths calculations, either be the constants
or the maths functions.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I will see you guys in the next tutorial.