Hey, guys, what's up?
This is American, and I welcome you to another to Dooralong discourse on Ruby.
And in this tutorial, we are going to be covering two keywords.
The first one is the breaking word and the next one is the next keyword.
Now, you already have seen the usage of breaking word, but in this area, we are going to explain
it a bit more.
So the break statement can be used to terminate a blog that is defined by the while, the dual.
The far loop are the case statements now more often this vague statement is basically used with almost
the Do I loop or the Bilu for the loops that are basically endless and you want to just terminate them.
So, for example, let's say you have a program in which you have to generate random numbers between
a certain range and you want that of a certain number occurs.
Where you have to do is that you want to terminate that program.
So, for example, you have a value that is basically something that you write.
And just while true.
So this is a loop that is basically an endless loop that cannot be terminated by any kind of condition
because you have written and white dujayl.
So all you can do is that you can just terminated by using the brake statement.
Now what do we have to do?
Is that, for example, you have.
Some are, that is.
Going to have a number and what it is going to store is basically going to be our random number.
And we are going to ride in 30 in here.
So what it is going to do is that this is a building function that is used to basically generate random
numbers between a certain range.
So for this case, what it is going to do is it is going to generate random numbers from zero to 30.
It defines the minimum range itself, which is zero.
And this is the maximum range which we have specified right over here.
So what we are going to do is that we are going to simply print out the numbers you're going to write
in our will here.
And what we want is that if.
This hour, at any instance, equal, equal to, let's say, 12.
Then what we want is that we want to break out of this statement, so will help zipped, right.
And for that and for that and.
Just run this court.
So you can see that it has just for one four, one, two, and now the reason that this is all scrambled
up is because we have to specify an online space to just have a Puzzo Hill.
More on this now.
Oh, my God, that has generated many of the numbers.
Was just remove this from here and let's just use pozole here so that every member is in a separate
line and as you can see, that it has generated a lot of numbers, as you can see, that it has from
starting on from 423 22 to and a lot of numbers and a drop.
This loop has basically ended.
But as you can see, that this was a loop that should never have ended.
But since we have specified a condition that at any instance, if a random number 12 is generated,
we want to break out of this follow.
Now, wherever you use this break, you are to either it be the wire loop, either it be the do while
loop, either it be the loop, either the give statements.
When it sees this break, you would it is going to just come out of the call and it is going to execute
the statements which are right.
Or.
So for example, I just write in.
Outside the value.
So if I just run the score, you can see that it says outside the loop, why look after a very long
time?
Because it has generated this drove over here, as you can see.
And after this, it has printed it.
It checks the condition now are is equal to three.
So it is spread out and now it will start printing the statement outside this value.
Now, for example, if I just remove this from here and just write and put.
Hashtag are for this O'Haire as well.
Well, just let's just change it to something like R plus one.
And run the scoreboard, you can see that it is now going to be an endless loop, as you can see that
it is generating numbers that are random numbers from zero to thirty, and this loop is never going
to stop.
So all you have to do is that you have to do something like.
That should basically stop the flow, so you have to not use this O'Haire, you have to ride in Bracho
Hill now run this code and as you can see, that it will now stop at some instance.
As you can see that whenever the stroke comes, it is going to just stop and it is going to say outside
the wall.
So this is how basically the brake statement can be used to just exert some loop, which is basically
an endless loop.
So then comes the next one.
That is the basically next statement.
And the next statement is used to skip a part of the loop and continue on with the next iteration of
the loop.
Now, it can be used in combination with the Falu and the value.
Now, for example, we want to print a list of numbers that cannot be divided by a certain number,
let's say two without a remainder, of course.
So what do we have to do is that we'll just remove this from here.
And we will have.
Why loop?
That says while a number is less than, let's say 50 and we will initialize some Numbulwar here as well,
that is going to start on from zero.
This is the starting limit.
This is the ending limit.
So for this, we have specified this loop to and so this is not now not going to be an endless loop.
So let's say we have no equal to none plus one, which is the counter, which is going to ensure that
this number is incremented.
So at some stage, this condition becomes false.
And this statement that is puts outside the wire loop gets printed.
So in here, what we have to do is that, as I told you, that we want to print a list of numbers that
cannot be divided from two starting on from zero to 50.
So what we have to write a number here that if.
The number.
Modu.
Equal, equal to zero.
So what do you have to do is that you have to just skip that statement and you have to just write in
and.
And you right in the end for this as well as well as you have to print the numbers to just write in
print or just use pot so that everything gets printed on a separate line.
And you have to write a number here.
And this ad has to be in small letters.
I guess that's good enough, let's just run the score and as you can see, that it has printed the numbers,
which are basically not divided by two.
So it has printed all the odd numbers for me, starting on from one till forty nine and then it has
printed out outside the BILU.
So for example, if you have let's say no to equal equal to one here, which means that now it is going
to print on equal numbers starting on from two to 50.
And after that, since we have a condition, we have an increment control here.
So that's why it is going to just go out and it is going to print out outside the vile little.
So that's how basically you can use the break Keywood and you can also use the next key where the break
is going to just.
Make you come out of the loop and the next statement is going to skip certain outputs which have to
be printed, all you can say that the next statement is basically going to skip a part of the loop and
continue on with the next iteration of the loop.
So I guess you have understood both of these.
So I guess that's it with this story.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next Dorio.