Hey, guys, what's up?
This is American, and I welcome you to attend a tutorial on this course on Druzhba and in this tutorial
we will be discussing about Ruby now, Ruby block, words that are also called closures in other languages
are definitely one of the coolest features of Ruby and are the chunks of code between traces are between
the two and that you can associate with method in locations almost as if they were parameters.
A ruby block is a way of grouping statements, and it may appear only in the source adjacent to a method
called The Block is written, starting on the same line as the method calls last parameter or the closing
parenthesis of the parameter list.
The code in the block is not executed at the time it is encountered.
Instead, Ruby remembers the context in which the block appears.
Either at the local variable is the current object and so on, and then it enters the method.
The Ruby standard is basically to use braces for a single line locks and do and for multiline blocks,
keep in mind that the braces Syntex has a higher precedence than the do.
And Syntex braces have a high.
Presidents do has a low precedence.
If the method and location has parameters that are not enclosed in parenthesis, the precise form of
a block will bind to the last parameter, not the overall invocation.
The do form will bind to the invocation.
Now we have a saying that any method can be called with a block as an implicit argument, instead,
the method you can call the block using the word with a value.
Also, as you will soon learn that Blocks can have their own arguments.
There are many methods in Ruby that I over a range of values.
Most of these iterators are written in such a way as to be able to take a code block as part of their
calling syntax.
Now the method can then yield control to the block during execution as many times as it is necessary
for the iteration to complete.
Once you have created a block, you can associate it with a call to a method.
Usually the code blocks passed in two methods are anonymous objects that are created on the spot.
Now a method can be invoked using an associate block one or more time.
Using the Ruby yield statement has any method.
You want to take our block as a parameter.
You use the yield keyword to execute the block at any time and how to do all that stuff in which you
will be calling a block inside a function using the key yield keyword.
That will be a part of the tutorials where we will be discussing about functions.
So to talk more about druggy blogs is that if you provide a code blog when you call a method, then
inside the method you can yield control to that code block, suspend execution of the method, execute
the code in the block first, and return control to the method body right after the call to jail is
made.
If no code block is present and jail is called, then Ruby is going to generate an exception message
for you.
You can provide parameters to the call Tagil.
These will be passed to the block.
Within the block you list the name of the arguments to receive the parameters between vertical bars.
Now, one thing you need to know right here is that the code in the block is not executed at the time
it is encountered by the Ruby interpretor.
Instead, Ruby remembers the context in which the block appears, and it then enters the method.
A code blocks return value is the value of the last expression evaluated in the code block.
This return value is made available inside the method, and it comes through as the return value of
jailed.
Now, if you talk about a block variables, you can have variables that will be associated with the
blocks as well.
So let me give you a quick example for how blocks look using the do.
And because for the Brace's, you have to wait for till we reach the part where we will be discussing
about functions.
So let's go on to Atom and let's say we have a variable that is X equal to 10.
And in here, what we have is let's say we want to execute, let's say a certain statements, let's
say five times.
So what we would do is that we will write five times.
Do.
As a told you that if you want to give any kind of expression and pass values as an argument to a function,
you have to specify those in the vertical brackets.
Let's say I want to specify X Hill.
Then you press enter, you will automatically seen that you have been moved a space ahead right here,
which means that a block has been automatically static for you.
Now, what you want to do over here is the let's say you want to say hello.
Gollan, and let's say you want to use this hashtag brainteasers over here, and you know what?
It's this you have covered this in the previous tutorials and let's say I want to specify actual hill.
I moved out of block or road into a hill, which means the block has now been ended.
Now, this is basically the blogs that starts with the do it and with the anti word, and this blog
is going to be executed five times now outside the blog, what I'm going to do is that I'm going to
write and puts.
Hello.
And I'm going to write an editorial.
Let me just run and then I'll explain what is going on in here.
As you can see on the screen, it says hello.
Then it says zero.
And it's the one then institute and it said three.
Then it said before it has been run five times.
Then it says hello.
Then at the very end now in the above block, a new feature is being used that is known as the block
local variable.
In short, the block local variables.
She's a block from manipulating variables outside of its scope.
This prevents a block from unintentionally clobbering any variable outside its scope.
If you don't want to global variable, use the block local variables for the variables your block creates.
The syntax for a block local variable is quite simple, but a semicolon after the normal block parameter
list then list the variables you want as block local variables.
For example, the block takes to variable in and use uses to locate variables X and B, the parameter
list would look like something A comma, B colon x y, which means that is going to equal to X and B
equal to Y.
So for this, for example, I want to specify something today.
So I'm going to write an E and I'm going to specify colon X, which means that is going to equal to
X and now you can use a oakhill.
So that's how it is going to be done.
So that is going to stop it from clobbering any variable that is outside the scope of this block.
And in this case, since X is outside the scope of this blocks, there is going to stop it from clobbering
that variable.
But as you can see over here, since I have used X or here.
And so we're here as well, and you can see that it starts on with a zero, which is which means that
the loop is executing for the zero time, which means the first because.
It starts off with zero and the zero indicates the first iteration, this one indicates the second iteration
to indicates the third iteration, three indicates the fourth hydrogen and four indicates the fifth
operation.
When you go outside the block of the code Windex, it is going to make it equal to 10.
So that is how basically you can use blocks.
And that was just a basic introduction.
All you need to understand, O'Haire, is this thing.
It starts on with the two, ends with the end keyword.
And you can write multiple lines of code in between this.
You can just write in any number of lines of code.
Right.
Or here you can specify anything right here.
So that's how blocks are used in Ruby.
If you did not understood the code.
It's completely fine because all you need to know is that what our blocks how are they called, how
parameters are passed through the blocks and how iterations can be made at the block.
Now, there is a concept where you will be using the Gillard keyword to call a block from inside a function,
but that will be discussed when we will be covering functions in the next sections.
So I guess you have to wait till then.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next Auriel.