Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to an editorial on this course on Ruby.
And in this story, we will be discussing about the Ruby Dimes function.
Now, the times function in ruby red, duns, all the numbers from zero to the number we have specified.
It generates the given blockbusting in the increasing values from zero up to the given limit we have
specified if Knoblock is given and enumerator is returned instead.
Now the syntax is simple that you have to specify the number dot and then we have to specify times.
Now it will receive some argument and that will be the function will takes the integer, which the numbers
are written, and it will also take a block.
Now the return value is going to be the function that will return all the values from zero to the number
itself, which we have specified.
So wasting no more time on talking, let's go on to ATM to see some examples for how it is going to
be done.
So, as I told you, you have to specify a number.
So let's say we have a number that is equal to, let's say five.
And what we want is that we want to generate a sequence of number from zero to this number.
So what we will do is that we will write in num dot dimes.
Now it will receive and some arguments.
The first argument is going to be.
The value in which the each value is going to be get it each time, so I is going to contain the values
each time.
And these are going to be the curly brackets, not the wrong brackets.
So just remove this from here, specify in between this.
All right.
So the second argument is going to be about printing the value each time.
So I for the first time is going to be zero and it is going to be printed.
And the third argument is going to be a space after each iteration.
So after zeros printed, a bit of space is going to be included.
Then one is going to be printed space, two space, three space for space and finally five is going
to be printed.
So I guess that's good enough.
What do you have to do more is just add a footsore here so that it gets printed right out here.
Press order and you can see that zero one, two, three, four or five has been printed right on your
screens.
So we just specify, let's say, 10 O'Haire press Aldar and the values from zero to 10 are going to
be printed, right.
Or well.
Now, for example, if you have nothing, O'Hare, press Aldar, then it is going to generate error
message for you because it don't have any kind of variable in which it can store the value one at a
time.
So when this code is run, this is basically a block away hill and this block has three things to do.
The first thing is that it stores in the first value zero and it print zero on the screen and then it
adds a space in the second edition, it get a one, then it print the one on the screens and add a space
and so on it goes still then.
And when Dennis printed this block exists and it moves out and since it finds no line of code outside.
So that's why it generates simply the output that is zero.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine and 10.
Now, what if we have a negative value, let's say well, here, let's say we have a negative five over
here.
This code is going to remain the very same, just Aldar.
And you can see that you don't have any kind of sequence, as I told you, that it is going to start
on from zero and move to the number we have specified.
But in this case, we have specified a negative value so it don't move back since zero is the lowest
value it can print out.
So that's why when minus five, it's a minus five over here.
So it ran only one time, it took minus five.
And as an input it printed it out and it just exited out of this block.
So that's why no other kind of number is going to be printed if this is going to be a negative value,
whatever value you specify, for example, minus 10 is the value press orda and minus 10 is simply going
to be printed.
Nothing else is going to be printed right over here.
Let's say we have minus one press Aldar and minus one is only going to be the end, but not even in
the case of minus one.
Zero is going to be printed because it in simple words, if a number is negative, no other number is
going to be printed.
Other than that number.
But if a number is positive, then a sequence of numbers starting from zero to that number is going
to be printed on your screen.
And that's how the Times function is used in Ruby.
So I guess you know how to use the Times function now.
So I guess that's a bit dictatorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.