Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Ruby and in this story,
and we are going to be, again, covering Dougie was the first one is going to be the real key word.
And then we are going to go on with the really tricky work now, starting on with the first one in Ruby,
the redo statement is used to repeat the current iteration of the loop redo always is used inside the
loop and the redo statement basically restarts the loop without evaluating the condition again.
So, for example, if you just look on with some example of that, for example, we have a follow in
which we have a variable eye and we want to have a loop from zero to nine.
So what we are going to do is that if, let's say some certain variable color, for example, we say
that if I is equal, equal to, let's say five, then we what we want is that we want to redo things.
And what do we have to do else is that we have to just.
And this.
And this for lap as well, and we also have to just print out numbers over here, so we are going to
let's just have both.
And we are going to write in the numbers, so we're going to write in the hashtag nine.
We are going to just copy this from Hill Bastida Hill, and we're also going to add a statement, boats.
Reto statement.
I do.
Yes, we have missed the last sign of war here, my bad.
We have to get this like that.
Just do it like that.
Run this code.
And as you can see that you have got zero.
One, two, three, four.
Then you have to I is five.
After that, the flag was set to true.
So that's why I you and came back with the value of this conditional hail was true.
But since the flag is now Drewes so that this condition over here is going to be false, it is going
to just come out, it is going to end, it is going to put the value.
It is going to go back now because since it has not encountered the value of Preto because the flag
was fall.
So that's why it is going to incremented the gun now and that GUNDRY is now going to equal to six.
But as it can do for the first condition when the flag was false, it has.
Encounter the value of equal to five, and it has the right to implement it on that.
So that's what I equal to five and equal to five are printed twice hill.
So that is what is basically the purpose of real and if you just reuse a redo without using a flag,
then it is also going to create a never ending loop.
So you always have to use a flag when you're using the redo statement.
Then comes the second key word we have to use in this tutorial.
That is the retries statement and two that is used basically to repeat the whole loop I had written
from the start.
We have to use the retries statement and read statement again is always used inside the loop.
So to implement that, just remove this from here.
And what you have to do is let's use the do I look this time and you've already come on with come up
with the syntax of the times and you know how this works.
What do is that?
It executes something again and again.
So 10 times what do we have to do is that you have to do a variable that is, let's say I and we are
going to just begin that and begin basically what to do is that it starts a blog of good.
And then what we are going to write and we are going to write in votes.
And we are going to just see the cycle numbers.
We're going to write in Psycho.
No, I.
And after that, what we were going to do is that we are going to use race if.
I is greater than I do, and what Raise is going to do is that it is going to basically raise a kind
of exception, nobody's exception, that is going to be a part of the future tutorials into that.
But for now, you need to know that whenever this phrase is used and a certain condition, as it is
implied with that, then for whatever condition this raises use, it is going to raise some kind of
message that is going to tell us that basically this condition, which you have specified with this
rescue work, has been met.
So what we are going to do is that we are going to.
We already have used this, we are going to just move out of this, we are going to ride in rescue and
rescue is basically going to deal with whatever has been raised over here.
So we are going to write an.
Retrial here.
And what retrial is going to do is that if I just run the score, you're going to understand yourself,
as you can see, if I just.
Move up the top here, you can see that you you have starting on from Secretary Secretary Hagel through
secretary, you have got a whole lot of secretary, which is basically going to be an endless loop and
it is going to just keep running and running and running.
So what's basically going on out here is that it started on with this big key word since this I at the
first instance was going to equal to zero.
So that's why I cycle number zero is going to be printed, which is going to be at the very top.
But since this is going on, I guess I could not show you.
Yes, it just scroll down back again.
But if you just stop this and just go on to the top, you're going to see cycle number zero.
Then you're going to see cycle number one.
Then you're going to see cycle number two after that, when this condition is met, which means that
it is greater than two for the value of AI, which is going to equal to three, then what it is going
to do is that it is going to continue on with this retreat and cycle.
Number three is going to.
Get branded.
Infinitely.
But if you specify a condition with it or just use flags again or whatever, it is going to actually
stop.
So that is what is basically the purpose of the redo and the retry.
Key words in Ruby.
And again, you are going to be seeing a lot of these in the future stories as well.
So I guess you have understood them now.
So that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much for watching.
I'll see you guys in the next redrill.