Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another to on this course, on Drooly and in this territorial,
we are going to be covering two functions.
The first one, it's going to be up to function and the second one is going to be the down two functions.
Now, if you talk about the up to function, then if you need to come from a specific or low value up
to a higher value, then you have to use the updo method that is used for an integer value.
Now, a block argument may optionally be used if you want to display the value.
On each kind of iteration, now, if you want to use the down to function, then the down to function
is going to count down from a high value to a low value.
And you can use the same thing.
That is the block argument optionally if you want to display the value at each iteration.
So I guess that's enough talking.
Let's go on to attempt to see how both of these are going to work.
Now, what do you have to do?
Simply is that you have to write in the low value you want to start on with.
Then you have to specify don't need to specify up to then in the brackets, you have to specify the
value still what you want to.
I traded and you have to specify then and then you have to specify the block, as I told you, which
is optional if you want to display the value at each iteration, since I want the value to be displayed
at each iteration so I could use a block of our or to just specify do.
Click, enter, and the blog code is automatically going to start and is going to be automatically generated.
Oakhill And you have to specify these vertical bars specify in this.
And I, as usual, is going to take the first value and add each iteration.
What it is going to do is it's not ideal, it's AI.
And what it's going to do is that it's going to print out the value for AI.
Now, just run this code, and as you can see, that it has printed out zero one, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10.
Well, you need to do Ohare is just add.
A bit of space around the squad now.
All right, we have got certain error.
Yes, because we can specify this oakhill.
What we can do is I guess we can add a space downhill.
All right, so it's looking pretty well now you can see that you have zero one, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
If you don't want to use any of these, you can just specify Bootsie.
And that is going to make job a bit more easy and it is going to display each output on a new line.
So that's how the updo function can be used.
So you can see that it started on with the lowest value you have specified, still the highest value.
Now, if you want to reverse this order, what you can do simply is that you can convert this updo into
down to run this code.
All right, so nothing was printed because this value is already larger than this value.
So what you have to do is to specify Denoyer and zero over here verandahs go now and now.
The output is going to be generated as ten, nine, eight, seven, six, five, four, three, two,
one, zero.
Now, if you specify the updo function on this, where this value is a smaller value and this value
is a larger value or underscored, and yes, it's up to run this code.
And as you can see, that nothing has been printed because this value is greater than this value.
So while using the up to and down two methods, you have to keep this in mind that when using the updo
method, this value that is in the brackets should always be greater than this value so that something
is generated on the atom or on their output screen.
And when using the second method that is the down to method, this value should be less than this value
as it is in the case.
As you can see that the output is generated because if you specify, let's say, 20 Oakhill run the
score, then you can see that nothing is generated because this value is greater than this value.
So this is basically what is going what you are going to see and you have to be careful about.
So I guess that's it.
What the up to out function and that's it with this tutorial as well.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.