Hey, guys, what's up?
This is American, and I welcome you to a new drill here on discourse, on religion.
In this tutorial, we are going to start on a date and time.
So in Ruby, we have the time class that represents the dates and times.
It is a thin layer or the system date and time functionality provided by the operating system.
Now, this really will make you familiar with almost all the vaunted concepts that are related to date
and time.
So let's start on with how to get the current date and the current time.
So to do it, there are basically two methods.
The first one is using the new and the second one is using the null function.
So let's say you have an object over here.
So let's say the name of the object is time one and you just write in time.
And as I told you that this time Ohare is the class which is going to be used to get the time.
So you're going to write in time Dot knew.
And what time Dot New is going to do is that it is going to get you the time and downhill.
When you just ride in boats.
And let's say you say the current.
Time is interpellation and right in here, are you right in time, one dot inspect, so if you just
run this code.
You're going to see that it says the current time is 2020, 05, 03, you can see that this is the dead,
this is the time and this is, I guess, the formidable hill.
So this was basically the first method of how to get the current time in Ruby.
Now, the second method is using the no method, and that is something like time to equal to time dot
now.
And in that you are going to write in votes.
Current time is.
And you are going to use the time to object now and you are going to write an INS.
Back around the squad and you can see that it has generated the now time, as you can see, that it
has the second time that has been generated using the now.
So these are the two method using which you can just get the current date and the current time.
Now, there are certain components that are associated with dead.
And so how to get the components of a date and time.
So for that, you can also use the time object to get various components of date and time to show you
how that is going to be done.
Let's just remove this stuff from here and you can see that you have an object over here.
That is time.
And we have created it using the new method.
Well, here now to get the components of a time, what you can just write and you can just for example,
if you want to get the year of the date, you can just write in time, dot your around this code and
you can see that you have got the year for this.
That is 20/20.
And now let's say you want to get the months so that you can just write in votes time, dot month on
this and you can see that you have generated the man that is the fifth month.
Then to get the day you are going to just write in time.
Dot, they run this.
All right, you have to write in what's with it as well.
And I'll run it.
And you can see that it has generated there.
That is the third day of the fifth month of twenty twenty.
Then for example, if you want to know the week, it is so far that you have to write in votes.
I'm not there, that stands for the weekday, and it is going to tell you that which day of the week
is going on, if you just run it, you can see that it is zero, which means that today is Sunday.
So that's why it has generated zero here.
Then, for example, if you want to know the year of the day that which day of the year is going on,
you can just write in first time dot y day that stands for the zero day rallies.
And you can see that it is the one 24th day of this year, 2020, that is going on.
And if you want to know the hours, what you can do is that you can simply write in Dot Harward, Time
Ronda's and you can see that it is the 22nd hour, which means that it's it is 10:00 at 9:00 night time.
This at this moment right now then if you want to know the minute and you can just write in time dot.
MINUT Ronda's, and you can see that it is the fifty fourth minute or ten, which means that the time
now is 20 to 54 and if you want to know the seconds, you can also do that using the time object.
You can just write in time dot s.E.C.
That's tenth or second round the score.
You can see that it is the fifty fourth second.
If you rerun this code you can see that now it is 48.
You can see that the seconds has changed.
All right.
If you want to know the microsecond you can also do that or they are just right in time dot you seconds
where you stand for micro Ronda's and you can see that, you can also see the one four zero one nine.
All right.
So this is the microsecond.
And if you want to know the zone as well, you can also do that for this.
You have to just slide in time, Dot.
Zone around this code and you can see that it is the Pakistan standard time which is going on right
now, which is the zone in which I'm operating.
So as you have seen the output, you can do a lot of stuff using the time glass, which in which we
have created an object.
And using that object we can know year demanded the we did you did the are the minute, the second the
microsecond and the zone as well.
So the next thing we need to know about time and it is about the time, UTC, the time, GM and the
time that local functions.
So basically these functions can be used to form a date in a standard format.
So how that is going to be done, let's just remove this from here.
And we are going to write in time dot local and in the local, you are going to pass in certain parameters
and those parameters are basically going to be the year.
Then you have to specify the month and then you have to specify the date.
So let's say the year 2020 and the month is 5th and the date right now is three.
So these are the three parameters which are going to get passed into this local function.
And I guess that's good enough.
Let's just save it in a variable.
X and down here, just write in votes X or underscored, and you can see that you have got 20 20 zero
five zero three.
You've got this one here and you've got zero five zero zero.
So this is basically the local time at this time.
And then you can also specify more parameters of a hill.
And you can also use the UDC function as well.
So, for example, if I just write in time, DOT, UDC and in the U.S., you also have to pass in certain
arguments.
So those arguments are, let's say the first, then you have to specify the date, then you have to
specify sorry, the month first and then the date.
And then you have to specifying the that you have to specify, let's say, the time as well.
So let's say at the time at this time is.
Nine, 20, now run this.
All right, we have to output that as well, so let's just right in what you will do time dot UDC and
now right in Portu I run this and you can see that you have got nine 20 as the time and you can see
that the data is very same.
So right here, since we did not pass the time to the local function.
So that's why the time was zero zero zero zero zero zero.
But since in this case, we have lost in the time that is nine 20, this is the ah, this is the minute.
So that's why we have got this.
You can also pass in the seconds, which is going to be the sixth argument of this UTC function as well
as this local function.
So now you must be thinking that what is going to be the format in which these parameters are going
to get passed into this local function and this UTC function.
So all of us remember that you have to start on with seconds, then you have to write in minutes, then
hours.
Then the day than the month.
Than the year, than the weekday than the other day, then the SDD and finally the zone.
So if you just remove this from here and let's say you create the time object again, we'll.
Dime new and then you're right, and values equal to dime dot to underscore as which means that we are
converting this do not to us but to air, which means that we are converting this to an area.
And right here you just right in the.
Values run this code, you can see that you have got this, so the format I just told you in here,
this is basically the second.
This is the minute.
This is the hour.
This is 22.
This three is the day.
This five is the month.
This is the year.
And after this, this is the weirdest incise.
I told you this is Sunday today.
So that's why it is a zero here.
And this is the year today, which is the 124 day of the year.
Then this is the I as DSD, which is false at this time.
And then we have finally got this zone, which is the Pakistan standard time.
So this is basically the format in which things are going to get executed.
Now, as you can see that you have got an area in which you have got all this stuff over here, so what
you can do is that you can pass this very same area to the time dot UTC or time dot local function instead
of writing that stuff, which we have been passing.
So how that is going to be done is that you have already created this.
Now, right here in place of this, you can just write in votes.
Dime dot UDC and in the parameters you are going to pass in the values, but you have to write and Starick
as well, values run this code and that is going to generate the things for you.
You can see that you have got the UDC this time as the zone.
You have got twenty three zero zero zero zero seven as the time and you've got this data will help.
Similarly, you can pass it to the local function as well.
You can just write in local law here or on the school board and you can see that it has also generated
some output right over here.
So instead of just passing the parameters and just remembering the format, what you can do is that
you can simply store it all those things in an area and then you can pass in that area using these esoteric
object.
Right.
Or help.
Then we have the concept of time zones and the Daylight Saving Time also here.
So you can use the time object for that as well to get all the information related to time zones and
daylight savings and how that is going to be done.
Or there's just remote desktop from here.
And as you can see, that you have created the time with the object and now what you can do is that
you can just right in time.
Dot zone, and that is going to do your job, just write and post with it Ronda's and you can see that
you have got a zone in which you are operating, the zone in which I am operating as the Pakistan standard
time.
And what you can do is that you can do a lot of stuff more where you can just write in inputs.
Time dot, UTC, underscore offset, and if you just run the scoreboard.
You can see that you've got this offset and UTC is zero 2nd offset from UTC, so that's why you got
this eighteen thousand over here.
And then what you can do is that you can just now right input's time zone around this code and we already
have done that.
You don't have to do it again.
It has to be as DSD, Ronda's and as you can see, that it was false in the previous case as well as
well as it is now, then you can just see if it is true or not.
If it is true, for example, this will help them.
If this is true, it is going to return.
True.
But this is not an it is going to return false and it is going to be true if the T is in the UTC time
zone around this.
And as you can see, that it has generated false, which means that the time is not in the UTC.
Formidable Hill.
And you can also convert to the local time zone using the local time function, so you can just right
in time dot local time, right in boats with it.
Now, Ronda's you can see that you have got this as the local time, you converted to a local time zone
and you can also convert back to UTC time zone for that.
You have to ride in time.
Don't GM time.
And that is going to do your job right, and post with it.
Now run it and you can see that you have got the UTC time zone now.
Then you can also return a new time object in the local zone, for that you have to write in votes time,
dot.
Get local around the school, and that is going to return something and as you can see, you have got
this output as well.
So more what you can do is that you can also return a new time object in the UDC the same way you have
done it in local.
You will use the very same format you tried and time don't get.
But in place of local, you have to write in UDC Ronda's and now you can see that in place of this you
have got the UDC time zone.
So this is the local time zone and this is the universal I guess this is this abbreviation is something
like universal time, something like that.
Then comes the concept of formating times and it's in Ruby.
Now there are various ways to form a time and date.
So how that is going to be done, just remove this from here.
For example, you can convert the time to string four that you already know, a method to convert things
into string that to underscore so you can just slide in both timed out to underscore S Rhondda score,
and that is going to convert your string sorry, your time into string.
And this is the time that has been converted into string.
Then you can also know the current time or that you have the right inputs time dot c time that is going
to print the current time.
Or underscored, and this is Sunday today, the month is May, and you have got three years, the date,
this is the time and this is the year in which you are present.
So this has said time is going to just bring the current time along with the day that man time and a
lot of stuff.
So one more is that you can also bring the local time for that.
You have to write in time, dot local time, run this and that is going to bring the local time.
Then you can also have both Stiehm Dot SDR.
Halftime time, so that is going to PRENDA stirring up time and I guess we have got some kind of.
Yes, we have to pause in certain parameters for that as well.
Now, as you can see that your God this time, Abargil, and you have this plus we have got this year
than we have got this month and we have got this did.
So are you going to do that?
You can also tell the format.
You can also change the format in which this these things are going to get appear.
So, for example, we are going to just write in, let's say first we want to know the year before that
I'm going to write and why.
Then you have to ride the separator, that is going to be a dash, then you have to ride in the months
of for that, I want this to show up, then dead separator, then finally the date and just add a space.
And after that, you are going to specify the permit for the time.
So let's say I want to just press the hours and the column is going to be the separator between time
that I want to know the month and the call and that is the separator.
And finally, I want to know the seconds.
Now, I just find it, as you can see, that I've got this output a hill.
All right, we have got certain with this this has to be the person did sign, so that's why we have
got this and we're here now.
Run this and you can see that now we have got the things in the format you liked.
Now you can also change the format as well, for example.
And this will help you first.
Want to know the date, let's say.
And after that, you want to know the month.
And up to that you want to know the year so you can just change it.
Now, run this and you can see that now you've got was the date, then the month and then the year.
So this staff time is going to help you to set the things according to your needs.
You can just set the pattern in which you want things to pop up.
So this is how you can just form it date and times according to your needs.
Now, whatever you have specified in these parameters, O'Haire, this person and this person, be this
person, Twi and all of these, these are basically known as the Formating Directorate's.
Now, these directives are a lot and these are all used using this function time.
S-T are FDM and some of these are one of them is the person and it is basically abbreviated for the
week they name.
And then we have got also our capital and that is going to print on the full weekday name.
Then we have got this B that is basically the abbreviated month name.
Then we have got A capital B that is also used to print the full month name.
The person B is going to generate the output, for example, for January.
It is going to generate only Jan.
But if you are using the capital B, then what it is going to do is that it is going to give you the
complete form.
The same goes for the small and capital is small is going to print.
For example, if you have small A and let's say you have sended today, then it is going to print on
only son for Sunday.
Then if you have capital then for Ascender it is going to print completely.
And that is what is the difference between capital and small capital B and small B, then you have one
more.
That is the person C.
And the person I see is basically the preffered local date and time representation, then you have the
person which you already have used that it used to show the day of the month.
Then you have this person, which you also have used, that is going to bring the order of the day.
Then you also have a person did sign with a capital and that is going to give you the order of the day,
but that is going to use the 12 hour clock.
As you can see that right over here where we are using this percentage Achuar here, you can see that
it is using the format of 24 hour clock.
That's why we have got this 23 over here, right here.
If you use a percentage, I and if you just replace this each with a capital, I just remove this from
here and now run this good.
You can see that now the format has been changed to the twelve o'clock and now the time is eleven point
twenty three.
It is going to be eleven but now it is going to be P.M. Then you have got a percentage sign with Jabe
that is like this and it is used to represent the day of the year.
Then we have got the person and which we already have used that is show that is used to show the month
of the year.
Then we have the percentage of capital M as well that is used to show the minute of the R, then we
have the percentage B that is used as the Meridien indicator that is known as the M r.p.m..
So when you are using percentage I, what you can do is that you can also use this Meridien thing over
here.
So right here you can just write in person B, just remove this from here.
Now run this code.
You can see that you also have got this yaml here.
So this is 11 18 B at this time.
Then you also have a percentage with a capital S., which you already have car that is used to show
the second of the minute, then you have got a percentage you that is used to show the weak number of
the current year, starting with the first Sunday as the first day of the first week, as you have already
noticed, that when we were just printing on the day before today did, then it was printing on zero
because it is Sunday today because sun starts with zero and then we have a percentage W that is used
to show the weak number of the current year, starting with the first Monday as the first day of the
first week.
Then we have a person with a small W that is used to show the day of the week, then we have a person
with a small X that is Reckford a representation for the date alone.
No time.
Then we have a percentage with a capital X that is the opposite of that.
That is used for the preferred representation of the time alone.
No date in that.
Then we have a percentage Y that is used to show you're without a century.
Then we have a percentage.
What a capital y which you already have that is used to show the year with a century.
Then we have got a percentage with a capital Z that is used to show that time zone name.
And then we have got the person person literally that is the literal percentage character.
So these were basically some of the directives that are basically known as the formating directives
for this SDR time function, which you can use to just print out the time in your own format, in whatever
format you want and whatever things you want to pop up.
You can just specify them as parameters to this SDR time function.
Then comes the last topic for this tutorial that is about the time arithmetics, you can perform simple
arithmetic with time and how that is going to be done.
Let's just remove this from hell and let's just do it with now.
And right here, what are going to do is that you can just fly in for its time on this and it is going
to bring down the time good enough.
Now, what you can do is that you can also know the past time.
You can also know the future time, and you can also calculate the difference between the future and
past time.
So to know the past and what you can do is that you can just have a variable past.
And what you can do is that you can just ride in time or you can just name it as the sea.
You double our current time so that it is much more accurate to what it is doing.
So we are going to ride in current time minus.
And let's say you just want to subtract 10 seconds, so that is going to generate the time that is at
10 seconds ago.
For example, if you just write in Hundert so that things are much more clear.
So 100 over here and then what you can do is that you can just write in votes or he'll run the score.
All right.
We have got some error with this.
That says undefined local variable or method time.
Yes, my bet you have changed it, though.
Well, we also have to change it over here now on this.
And you can see that the current time is twenty three.
Twenty one forty two.
But you can see that the past time that is before 100 seconds was 23, 20, 02.
So this means that hundert seconds were basically subtracted from the current time.
And this is the current time and this is the time.
That was 100 seconds ago.
Now you can also know what is the future time travel that you can just create a variable that is named
as future and you can just ride in the current time lapse.
And you can just add Hundert this time and you can just ride inputs.
Future around this, and you can see that you have got 20 for now, so this means that hundred seconds
have been added to this and this has been generated.
Right.
Now, you can also know the difference between these two.
That is the past and the future.
For that, you can just write in a variable that's a difference and that variable is going to equal
to future.
Minus past, so you can just ride in boats.
Difference run this code, and that is going to generate the difference that is 200 because the current
time was subtracted Hundert seconds before and then the current time was added that seconds also.
So that's why the difference was one hundred.
That makes it equal to two hundred seconds.
So whatever you are going to add, whatever you are going to subtract the answer and the things you
are going to specify right over here are basically going to be in seconds.
And this output has also been generated in seconds as well.
So that's how you can perform simple arithmetic with the time as well.
So thank you so much, gas, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.