Hey, guys, what's up?
This was a marathon, and I welcome you to another Dooralong discourse on Rubaiyat and this strategy,
and we are going to cover the introduction to exceptions in Ruby.
Now, it is likely that you have already encountered exceptions in your Ruby programs, but you may
not have a complete understanding of where these errors come from.
To begin, we will discuss what an exception is, as well as various types of exceptions.
And there are similarities.
We will then introduce several basic techniques for handling common exceptions using when they occur
in your code.
At the last, we will explore raising your own exception and using custom exception classes.
So exception is something like this.
So as you can see that it says today we are going to learn about handling exception.
So pretend this to be an exception.
Your code for this, when it gets angry at your incompetence like this, now you are going to learn
how to catch them.
So this was just added for amusement purpose.
And it also explain what an exception is.
The code is going to throw the exception and then you are going to get that exception.
So exception basically is something like this, so the question is that what is an exception now?
An exception is simply an exceptional state in your code.
It is not necessarily a bad thing, but it is the ruby way of letting you know that your code is behaving
unexpectedly.
If an exception is raised and your code does not handle the exception, your program is going to crash
and the Ruby will provide a message telling you what type of error was encountered.
So if you look at this picture, it basically gives you the easiest picture of what exception handling
is.
So as you can see that the person is running, but then he sees a kind of rock that comes in his way.
So you can not just go on directly because it is going to hinder his spot.
What he's going to do is that he's going to just adopt an alternate path to reach his destination.
So this Ohare is basically called an exception and the alternate body is going to take to reach to his
destination.
And that is what it's called an exception handling.
Then comes the hierarchy for the Ruby exception, and Ruby basically provides a hierarchy for building
classes to simplify exception, handling, in fact, the exception names that you see when your program
crashes suggested better, which you have often seen in the previous tutorials as well, are actually
classes, names.
The class at the very top of the hierarchy is known as the exception.
Class exception has several subclasses, many of which have descendants of their own as well.
So right here you can see the complete hierarchy of the Ruby exception classes.
So as you can see that at the top, you have got this exception and from the exception, you have got
this fellow the no memory under the system except the system stack her.
And you have also got this signal exception and you have got the script error.
And finally, of course, the standard error that are basically the subclasses of this exception, glass.
Now, some of these have descendants as well.
For example, this script error glass sublist from the last exception has three descendants.
That is Lord error, syntax, error and not implement error.
Similarly, the signal exception subclause has the descendant interrupt and the standard error subclass
has a lot of descendants.
Argument, error, eyehole error or error index error.
A local jump at a name at a no method error range error.
The flow domain error.
Regular expression error runtime error security error system call error system independent error.
The error, the error and a zero division error.
So these are basically some of the descendants of those clouds and that this the no memory error, the
system existed.
The system stack under these four classes basically did not have any kind of descendants right.
To a hill.
So let's take a moment to briefly examine some of the clauses in the hierarchy and think about when
you might encounter them.
So if you have been writing a ruby code for any length of time, it is likely that you have already
seen some of these exceptions raised in your program and you have already seen them in the previous
sections, editorial as well.
So have you ever pressed controls to exit out of a program?
Doing so actually raises an exception that is wired to interrupt glass, which you can see right or
help.
Then a syntax error, as its name suggests, will be raised when Ruby tries to execute the code containing
invalid syntax, this probably looks familiar.
If you have ever mistakenly left DSF or end of at the end of a method or any kind of class definition.
Then you've got a system error which is raised in the case of a stack overflow, you may have seen this
exception if you have run a recursive infinite loop in your program.
And finally, you have got the standard error that has many recognizable descendants.
That is argument error.
Error, the zero division error and the no method error and that are all the common exception that our
children and grandchildren of the standard error class.
So you can have an explanation of all these on the Internet and you can just have a look at all of these.
So one of the question is that when should you be handling an exception, most often the errors you
want to handle are the descendants of the standard error clause that was introduced right here.
These exceptions may be caused by a wide variety of circumstances, including unexpected user input,
faulty type conversion or dividing by zero.
Generally, it is relatively safe to handle this exception and continue running the program.
Now, why not just handle all kind of exception?
Doing so can be very dangerous.
Some exceptions are more serious than others.
There are some errors that we should allow to crash our program.
Not important error, such as no memory error, the syntax error and the load error must be addressed
in order for our program to operate appropriately.
Handling all exceptions may result in masking critical errors and can make debugging a very difficult
task.
So in order to avoid causing unwanted behavior itself, it is important to be intentional and very specific
about which exceptions you want to handle and what actions you want to take when you handle them.
The action you choose to take when handling an exception will be dependent on the circumstances, for
example, including logging the error, sending an email to the administrator or displaying a message
to the user.
Now the question comes how to handle an exceptional state.
Now the answer to this is basically exception.
Handling that comes with a begging and rescue blog, the Syntex, of which you can see right on your
screens now using a bug in the rescue blog to handle errors.
You can keep your program from crashes if the exception you have specified is raised now in this index,
the Syntex, the program will execute in the rescue clause rather than exiting the program.
If the code on line number two raises a type error, if no exception is raised, the rescue clause will
not be executed at all, and all the program will continue to run normally.
Now you can see that online 3V specified what type of exception to rescue, if no exception type is
specified, then the all standard error exception will be rescued and handled.
Remember not to tell Ruby Rescue exception the last exceptions, because if you tell Ruby to rescue
the exception exception, it will rescue all the exception down the exception class hierarchy, which
is very dangerous as explained previously.
So it is it is possible to include multiple rescue clauses to handle different type of exceptions as
well.
That may occur in your code.
For example, you can see the syntax for adding multiple rescue right over here.
You can see that.
Alternatively, if you would like to take some action for more than one type of exception, you can
see that on line number five for here that we have just tried rescue and we are right in the argument
error.
So here basically we are having to kind of catching errors now here, right over here, up to the beginning,
we are going to write the code for which we are expecting some kind of error.
And if I type better or the argument error occurring, that code than that is going to get caught right
in this object over here.
And whatever action you perform, you can just write in a statement of a head that is going to just
generate a message that you have got an error over here or you can just handle it right over here.
So this is also helpful because you're going to find out that what type of error occurs, because for
the specific rescue blog, the specific error is going to get handled.
So I guess that's it.
Let me give you a very quick example for the Syntex we have just covered, so I will just move on to
Adam.
So we will create a beginning of a hill.
Just click, enter, and right here you are going to write in the code for which you are expecting some
kind of arguments.
For example, let's say in this whatever code we are going to write and we are going to check if any
number is being divided by zero.
You know, that division by zero is not possible because it is going to generate infinity, which is
not just accessible by any kind of calculator, will help.
So, for example, you just write an X equal to ten divided by zero.
You know that this is an error that is going to generate a message that is going to be zero, a division
error.
So let's just try it here.
So let's just write an X equal to ten divided by zero.
Run this code and you can see that it says it is a zero division error.
So this zero division, as I told you as well in the introduction part, that this is basically a class
and this is basically you can say it is the descendant of a subclass of the exception class.
So since you're expecting some kind of error with this or what you will do is that you will put this
good in the beginning block so that it does not generate error and it is going to get handled in the
rescue blocks.
Right.
Well, here we are going to write in the same statement then divided by zero.
And now we are going to create our rescue blog and we are going to specify this thing from here to we
are going to write in zero.
División.
Error.
So this is what we are going to specify and inhale, we are going to just write inputs then divided
by two, so we are going to just correct that.
So if any kind of division is done by dividing it by zero, that is not going to get executed and this
statement is going to get executed.
Just and this Abargil around is good.
And you are going to see that it has generated five in the previous case, as you have seen, that it
has generated the error that says the zero deviation error.
Now, let's say I divide it by five horrendous code.
AirTran, perfect.
Now let's just write in votes Xolo Hill now run the score.
Now you can see that it has generated do so in the case where the big blog has all the gold.
That is correct.
So this blog, O'Hare, is not going to get gold in that case.
But in the case where you have got an error, which is basically going to get handled by the very same
descendant of the subclass of the exception clause, then it is going to get handled right over here.
So, for example, if I just write in type error over here.
And now I run the school, you can see that it has now generated me the error because that type error
does not handle this kind of error.
That is division by the department is four different things.
So to handle this specific error, you have to specify the specific class for which that error is going
to get generated.
So in this case, let's say we create the multiple rescue blocks, as I've told you before.
So let's say we create one more over here.
That is the zero, the region.
Error, and this time we are going to just try and put.
Zero division error is handled, and right here we are going to just write in votes.
Type error is handled.
Hill, so I guess that's good enough.
Now let's just run this code and now you can see that since we have got to rescue a lot in which we
have the zero division error for which the error has occurred in that big and long.
So that's why this division error is going to get cold and this is going to get printed.
Now, let's suppose that we have got some type error.
Now, you know that if you have, let's say, a statement that says you lost a string and in which you
just write in.
Q If you just run the score, it is going to generate error and it's strings can not be converted into
integer, and that is known as the type error.
Now we already have a rescue blog for the type error.
So if you just remove this from here.
And ride to a hill after this, what we are going to do is that we are going to specify one more variable
in which we are going to ride in to Las.
Kumalo Hill, and now we are going to write in votes, why are we here?
So if I now run to school, you can see that it says zero division error is handled and this should
also get called.
But the reason that it is not called is because the error occurred right over here.
It just jump over here, it handle this and it just move back, move out of this class over here.
So if you just put this away here at the top.
And now run this code, now it is going to generate the message that says type error is handled so wherever
and big and log where the error is going to get handled, then it is going to just move out of that
bag and log.
It is not going to execute the other statements in that specific block.
So after this statement is executed, it is going to just look for the rescue blocks and see if the
type error is being handled.
It was so it just printed out this statement over here and it does not execute these three statements
right down here.
So that's why in the previous case, the type error is handled here, was not printed.
And now in this case, the zero división error is handled, is not printed right over here.
So I hope that it is clear you now know how to implement the beginning of rescue block in Ruby.
So in the next story, we are going to cover more on exception handling.
So stay tuned for that.
So for this to drill, that's it.
Thank you so much for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.