Hey, guys, what's up?
This was a manhunt, and I welcome you to another on this course on Gooby and in this Dorel, we are
going to cover the introduction to regular expression.
Now, a regular expression is basically a sequence of characters that define a search pattern mainly
for use in pattern matching with strings.
Ruby regular expression that stands for ruby red X for a short help us to find a particular pattern
inside a string doofuses this of a ruby regular expression are validation and passing a ruby.
Regular expression can be used to validate an email address and an IP address to.
For example, if you think about an email address with a ruby regular expression, you can define what
a valid email address looked like.
In other words, your program will be able to tell the difference between a valid email address and
an invalid email address.
Ruby regular expressions are declared between two Forbert slashes to differentiate them from other language
syntax.
The most simple expressions match a word or even a single letter.
So if you talk about the syntax for this regular expression, it is as simple as this.
You have to write in just the two slashes and in between your expression you want to search for in a
specific string.
So I guess the best way to explain it would be to go to the editor and give you some examples.
So I will go on to Adam.
And to give you a very simple example for how this is going to work, let's say if you want to check
if a string has a regular expression or not.
Now, we can also check if a string has a regular expression on or not by using the match method.
Now, how that is going to be done.
So we are going to use the match method and in the parameters, we are going to use the regular expression
thing.
So let's say we specify in a condition and we write in a statement, let's say that is Hello World,
and we just write in the match statement with the string.
And the parameter is what we are going to do is that we are going to write in the expression with which
we want to match this string.
So let's say I want just write in Hello Hill.
So I want to check if hello is a part of this hello world or not.
So if it is or if it is not, then what it's going to do is that it's going to put on match.
That's what it is going to do, is add it is going to put.
Match not found.
Simple as that, just and this safe condition.
Run this code and you can see that you have got this Majaw here, which is this which has been printed
because Halo is a part of this halo world do here.
Now, if you just replace this to let's say.
Blah, blah, blah, or just write in single time, run this and it is going to say that match not answer.
That is how the simplest form of regular expression can be used.
You are going to see a regular expression match a certain string or not.
Now, you can also check if a string has some set of characters are not.
Now we can use a character clause which let us define a range of characters for the match.
For example, if you want to search for a vowel, then we can.
What we can do is that we can use the OR for the match and where we are going to store it.
That is where we are saying that we want to check if a string has some set of characters and not because
you are basically some set of characters.
So we just remove it from here and we will, let's say, define a function that is, let's say, well,
since you want to check for all the way here.
And it is going to receive the string, would you want to check with the sequence of character that
is new in our case?
So here we will define the sequence.
So how do you define a sequence?
You are going to specify an equal do.
Then you have to specify this magician, Mark, and that is basically what is going to define a sequence
of characters using the regular expression.
Then you are going to use the syntax for the regular expression as well over here.
And then you are going to use the array concept over here as well.
And now you can just write an API or you you don't have to specify any any kind of comma in between
all of these letters because it is going to treat each letter as a single sequence.
That's why it is called a sequence of characters, because each is going to be treated separately,
is separate, is separate, is separate.
Same goes for all.
And you now.
Now, what do you have to do is that you have to simply end this function.
Now comes the part where we are going to call this function and we are going to just write input.
So whatever is basically written from the function gets printed over here.
So we are going to write in votes.
That is the name of the function and we are going to pass in the string right from here.
So let's say our string is a world over a hill, so just run this code.
And it has generated one o'haire, which means that whatever string we have passed on to this function
was contained.
Whatever is written over here at the first location, as you can see, it is the zero location.
This is the first location and since or Izabel.
So that's why you can see that it has printed one, because it is saying that whatever sequence of characters
you have specified in this regular expression, and since it is a sequence of character, because we
have specified the area concept here as well.
So whatever string you are going to pass in, it is going to tell you the location of the letter, the
very specific letter at which this match, this sequence matches this string.
So this is the first location where we have got this, OK, that is available.
So you can just write in one more example, let's say here and now you can see that you have got to
also let's see what is going to be the result or help run this.
And you can see that it has generated two, which means that it is going to generate the output for
the first occurrence of the letter that is going to find a match.
So that is a that stands at the zero one two second location.
If you want to get something like more Abargil than what you can do is that you can use the Duyn statement
over here as well and you can use the do each so that for every iteration it is going to check if a
sequence of f a string here, the letter of a string sorry, matches this sequence over here and it
is going to then print all of these.
So I just decided to you you have covered the foreach again and again in the previous tutorial, so
it's for you to implement it over here.
So now what if we have certain like Barela and we are missing the oakhill here, which means that we
have got no what was in the strings we are putting in to the function Wawas that is basically designed
to check if a sequence of character matches the strength.
So if you just run it, it is going to generate nil, as you have seen, that the space has just increased,
which means that it has generated new in that case when no sequence, no sorry, no match is found or
held.
So you and I know how to match a complete word, or you can say a complete string.
And you also know how to match a string with a sequence of letters.
So I guess that's with the introduction.
But you know how to implement regular expression now.
So in the next tutorial, we are going to move a bit towards the intermediate part and learn more on
regular expressions.
So stay tuned for that.
Doriot for now.
That's it.
Thank you so much for watching.