Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to an editorial on this course on Aruba.
Ruby So in the previous to Dorio, what we have done is that we have completed our installation of Robotham
on six point five, as well as we have completed the installation for Adam.
Now, what you see on your screen is Adam, as you know now, what we need to do is that we have to
install Adam and Adam Orender is basically what is going to help us run our Ruby code.
So to install a new package where you have to do, is that just going to install a package?
Open the installer?
And this is basically the install package window type of thing, all you have to do is that you have
to just type in Adam II, front runner up to just wait before it is searching for the package you have
just entered in the search box.
All right.
So here at the top, you can see Adam Runner dewpoint on point one, which is the latest version.
You can see the number of downloads and you can see its description that says it runs scripts inside
of Adam.
So all you have to do is just click on this install button.
And what this Adam is going to do is that it is going to install Adam runner on your system, which
means that it is going to allow and run the scripts inside of Adam.
So as you can see that it says installing two point seven point one failed.
Let's just try again.
All right, so you can see that now Adam is successfully installed on your system, and it is also enabled,
as you can see, this disabled button where you can disable it or you can just uninstall it and you
can just go in and configure some kind of settings for Adam Orender as well.
So now what you have is that you have got Adam and you have got Adam Orender installed, which means
that now you can run scripts inside of Adam.
So how all this is done, that is a part of the next tutorial, because in this section, what we were
supposed to do was to install things, set up things.
So we have done that.
So I guess that's what this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next oratorio.