Hey, guys, what's up?
This is American, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Ruby and in this story of
what we will do is that we will give you an overall taste of object oriented programming.
Not all of the topics will be covered in more detail in the editorials to come, for which we will just
discuss the introduction in this tutorial.
So what is basically object oriented programming now?
Object oriented programming, which is often referred to as up in short form, is a programming paradigm
that was created to deal with the growing complexity of a large software system.
Now, programmers found out very early on that as applications grew and complex in complexity and size,
they become very, very, very difficult to maintain.
Now, one small change at any point in the program would trigger a ripple effect of errors due to dependencies
throughout the entire program.
Now, programmers needed a way to create containers for data that could be changed and manipulated without
affecting the entire program.
Now, they needed a way to section off areas of code that performed certain procedures so that their
programs could become the interaction of many small parts as opposed to one massive blob of dependency.
Now enter.
We will first introduce some of the terminologies.
Then we will just dive into some examples that will be the part of this tutorial.
So starting on with the first concept that is basically related often to object oriented programming,
that is encapsulation.
Now, encapsulation is basically hiding pieces of functionality and making it unavailable to the rest
of the code base.
It is a form of data protection so that data cannot be manipulated or changed without obvious intention.
It is what defines the boundaries in your application and allows your code to achieve new levels of
complexity.
Ruby, like many other languages, accomplishes this task by creating objects and exposing interfaces
to interact with those objects.
Another benefit of creating object is that they allow the programmer to take on a new level of abstraction.
Objects are represented as real word nouns and can be given methods that describe the behavior the programmer
is trying to represent.
Now, if you just look at the slide, then you can see that it is a very simple example for how encapsulation
is going to work.
You can see that whatever are the properties of a car, they have been encapsulated in a block and the
outside world cannot basically access it.
And any kind of error that is going to occur in this block of accord is not going to basically alter
any kind of code outside the block.
And moreover, no one is going to change any kind of data in this block unless we have given some permissions.
So so that is also going to increase security.
That is also going to just reduce the bugs as well.
And it is also going to contain the bugs and it is also going to contain the code.
And it is also going to help you to just assemble your code so that, as you can see, CA is going to
be in a separate container.
If you have, let's say, an apple, then the properties of Apple are going to be in a separate container.
If you have, let's say, some housed in the properties of a house are going to be in a separate container.
And let's say you are talking about yourself, then your name, your age or hide your weight.
And a lot more information about you can be just stored in a single container.
So that is also going to help you to organize your code so that when someone tried to read your code,
he can just easily understand what is going on in this code.
Because if you just write in Kawahara, you write in the model at one end of the code, then speed at
this end of this part of the code and let's say engine, add this part of the code and lets the speed
limit right over here.
So that is very, very, very difficult to find out.
But if you have encapsulated the data you are using the concept of encapsulation, then it is going
to get very easy for your user as well as for you to manage your code.
Then the second concept you often will come across an object oriented programming is the concept of
polymorphism.
Now polymorphism is the ability for data to be represented as many different types.
Óli stands for many and MAFF stands for forms, not object oriented.
Programming gives us the flexibility in using the president code for a new purposes.
Now, the concept of inheritance is basically used in Ruby, where a class inherits the behavior of
another class referred to as a superclass.
This gives Ruby programmers the power to define basic classes with large visibility and smaller and
smaller subclasses for a more fine grained detail behaviors.
Another way to apply the polymorphic structure to Ruby programs is to use a module.
Now the modules are similar to classes in that they contain shared behavior.
However, you can not create an object without a module a module and must be mixed in with a class using
the include method invocation.
This is also called as a mixin.
And after mixing in a module, the behavior declared in that module are available to the class and its
object.
Now we will see the examples of all the above mentioned terms in the action in the following tutorials
as well.
And we will see the mixin right here in the studio at the very end where we will be studying modules.
Now, if you look at the slide, you know, you can see that polymorphism basically is just classified
into two types.
The first one is the compile time polymorphism.
And then we have the runtime polymorphism and then the compile time polymorphism is again divided into
dupa, that is operator overloading.
And then we have got the function of a loading and then in the runtime you have got the virtual functions.
So all that is going to be a part of the following tutorials.
So you don't need to worry about that for now.
You just need to know the introduction to polymorphism.
Then comes the most important questions, which is going to be asked in object oriented programming
is that what are objects?
Now, throughout the Ruby community, you will often hear the phrase in Ruby, everything is an object.
Now, we have avoided this so far since objects are a more advanced topic and it's necessary to get
a handle on basic ruby syntax before you start thinking about objects.
Now, it's not even strictly true.
Not everything in Ruby is an object.
However, anything can be said.
To have a value is an object that includes numbers, strings, arrays and even glasses and modules.
However, there are a few things that are not objects matters and blocks are two that stands out now.
Objects are created from glasses and think of glasses as moles and objects as the things you produce
out of those moles, not individual objects, will contain different information from other objects.
Yet there are instances of the same class.
Now, is it all you that everything is an object in Ruby?
Now this apple is an object.
Nisga'a is an object.
This mobile is an object.
And finally, this house is also an object.
So as I was telling you that you can think of the glasses as models and objects, as the things you
produce out of these models.
So let's say you have a glass apple and then this object over here is basically going to be what is
going to be produced out of that individual object.
Let's say this apple, this car, this mobile or this house will contain different information from
other objects.
Yet there are the instances of the same glass.
Now, if you just see an example of two objects of the string glass, which you already have covered
in the previous structuralists as well, you know that if you just write in a string and use the object,
that is the dot glass with that, then it is going to return string, which is basically the class for
that.
And similarly, if you just write in worldclass, it is going to also return string.
Now, in this example, we use the glass instance method to determine what the glass is for each object.
As you can see that everything we have been using from strings to integers are in fact objects which
are instantiated from a glass.
Now, we will dig deeper into this very soon in the following tutorial.
So for now, you need only understand what our objects.
Simple as that.
Then comes how you have to define a class, so Ruby defines the attributes and behavior of its objects
and class is you can think of classes as the basic outline of what an object should be made of and what
it should be able to do to define the class.
We use this index similar to defining a method.
We just replace the death with the class and use the naming convention to create the name.
We then use the resulting word and to finish the definition, as you can see right over here.
Just in place of the DCF, you have to write and see the balance and then you have to write in the name
of the class.
Now, this human this can be anything over here.
You can just write in anything, then write in Ohara, you can use the statements.
And finally, to end this, you have to write in this.
And now they see and this is going to be in small cases then if you talk about the calling board, then
you have to write and the variable basically in which that object is going to get store and you have
to write in the name of the class and you have to write in.
Now, this is basically going to be object.
So in this example.
Basically, we are creating an instance of a human class and we are storing it in the variable that
is name as John, which you can see right over here.
So now we have an object.
We will say that John is an object or you can say the instance of a class human for which we have created
it.
Now, this entire workflow of creating a new object or instance from a class is called instantiation.
And we can also say that we have instantiated an object that is named as John from the class human,
not the terminology.
An object oriented programming is something you will eventually get used to.
But the important fact here is that an object is done by calling the class method new.
Now, to visualize what I am talking so far, let's just consider this example over here.
As you can see, that defining and creating a new instance of a basic class is very simple.
But before we go any further are showing you how to create more elaborate classes, you have to learn
the concept of modules.
But before we go on with modules, you just have to understand this diagram.
You can see that you have this human class and from here you can create as many as you want human objects.
So in this case, we have got three human objects in which you have the first object as John and you
have this board and then you have this bit.
Now, this using this object over here, you can just initialize name to the john.
You can initialize edge to John as the very same.
You have that car over there and you can just assign properties to that.
Now, in here, you can see that you have another object that is the human object as well, which is
just belonging to this class.
But you have just changed the name of the object and you also create it with a new object.
You will just write and bob equal to humanoid new and then using this object, Ohara, you can just
initialize the name and you can just initialize the age for this object.
Then you can have another object and you can have hundreds of objects if you want to from this very
single class you have created.
That is the human class.
So now let's move on to the concept of modules.
And as we mentioned earlier, modules are another way to achieve polymorphism in Ruby.
Now, a module is a collection of behaviors that is usable in other classes, which makes sense.
A module is mixed in to a glass using the include method and location, as I told you before.
So let's say we want our human glass to have a dog method, but we have other classes that we want to
use.
A speak method would do.
So if you talk about the syntax of modules, you can see it right over here.
You have to write in module, which is a building keyword.
Then you have to write in the name of the module, which can be anything.
So let's say in the example, which is going to just follow after this syntax, the name of the module
is going to be dog.
And in that we will have a function that is going to be, let's say again, dog.
And in here we are going to receive a variable and we are going to just print it out and then we are
going to be using this module inside our class.
So how that is going to be done, let's see an example finally of this.
So we just move on to Adam.
So let's say we will define a model, right?
Well, here's we are going to write in model and let's say the name of the model is Dog and in here
we are going to define a function that is going to be dog.
And this is going to receive an argument.
Let's say the argument is X..
So right over here, what we are going to simply do is that we are going to just print out this, not
this.
We are going to just print out this X over here.
And then what we are going to do is that we are going to end this function and we are going to end the
model as well.
Now, right after this, we have initialize our model.
Now, what we are going to do is that we are going to initialize our class.
So let's have a class that is the human class.
And what we are going to do over here is that we are going to basically include the dog that we have
initialized right over here as a module.
So it has to be in capital.
And finally, we have to end this glass as well.
Then comes the part where we are going to just have our object, so let's say the name of our object
is John and we are going to ride in human dot Neil.
So when you just ride in human dornier, which means that you are about to create an instance, or you
can say that you are about to create an object for this class human, which has included a module that
is named as dog.
So then if you when you have initialized this, then what you can do is that you can use this, John,
here to basically use this module right over here, since it is a part of this class, since we have
used the include method invocation of a.
So if you just ride in John Dot Doc.
And you just write in Hello, Hill.
And you just underscored you can see that you have got that right over here now, if you just talk about
the sequence of code, what's going on over here is that for us, this line is going to get executed.
That is, John, equal to human God knew this score over here is then going to execute and it is going
to see that this class human has a module that is included in it that is named as.
So it is going to just have all the properties of this module.
So now it has an access towards this function.
So this means that we can now access this dog function using this object, John, or you can say the
instance of a method that is named as John.
So when you write in John Dot Dot and you also have to pass a parameter since it is going to accept
a parameter over here.
So let's say the parameter is a string.
That is hello.
We just passed in, we just printed out and you can see that that has got printed out over here.
So that is basically the sequence of how things are going to get executed.
Now, if you talk about modules, you can also include them in multiple classes as well.
So let's say you have one more class over here.
And let's say the name of the class is this damn human being a here and in here, we are going to use
include Danquah here.
And finally, we are going to end this function of a hill.
Now, since this human and this human being both contains this dog, which means both these classes
have access to this functional hill, which means that whatever instances are going to get created for
both these classes, they will have access to this function using the instance created.
So if you just create an instance for the second class, let's say Bob is the second instance for the
second class that is human being.
So we are going to write in new.
So this means that an instance for the human being class is created that is known as Bob.
So now using Bob, what you can do is that you can just call in the dog method and you can just pass
in a parameter.
Let's say the world is the parameter this time around this and you can see that the world is also going
to get executed.
So in this example, both the human object.
With which we are calling John, as well as the human being object with which we are calling Bob, have
access to the dog instanced method.
Now, this is possible through mixing in the muddy with dog.
It's, as you can say, that copy pasted the dog method into the human and human being glasses.
And that's why you were able to access the dog method using the instances of the class, human and human
being.
Then you can use the module's concept to have a method look up.
So for example, you want to call a method.
Now, how does Ruby know where to look, for that matter?
Now Ruby has a distinct look apart that it is going to follow each time a method is going to get called.
So let's see our program from above to see what the method lookup part is for our human laws so we can
use the ancestor methods on any glass to find out the method.
Look up chain so we will have this modulo had modified a bit.
So what we are going to do over here is that we are going to use that interpellation over here.
We are going to read, write and hashtag here.
And similarly, we are going to have this class humor and we are going to have the class human league
board will have this dog dog.
So the squad over here is going to remain the very same.
And what we are going to do as is that we are going to just change this stuff over, help.
So what we are going to write in, we are going to write in puts.
Human Klaus.
And sisters, so that is just for formality, Bess's and what's now going to get printed is basically
going to be something different.
So what you can do is that you will just remove this from hair you don't want.
You don't need to actually create any kind of instances.
Now, all you will do is that you will just write in and sisters of a hair.
And that is basically something that is Beldin.
And finally, what you are going to do is that you are going to ride in boats.
Human being.
The lost ancestors and you are going to write and human being.
Dot.
And sisters, and you're also going to use sports with that so that they get printed out as well.
So you're going to ride in boats with this?
You're going to ride boats with this.
And we don't need any kind of stop right over here.
So we will just remove this from here.
So if you just run this code.
All right, it has generated our output, but it also has generated some kind of error that says on
initialised constant human being.
And I guess, yes, we have to just make it a capital B, as you can see right over here now run this
school and now you can see that you have just disappeared that error, and you have got the human glass
ancestors.
You can see that the human glass ancestors are right.
This and just writing in puts human ancestor.
You have got human, you have got dog, you've got object, you've got Gernon and you've got basic object.
And then you've you talk about the human being class ancestors.
You have again got the human being, which is the name of the class.
What then you've got the function which you have right over here and you've got the object as well.
And you've got Col.
Then you've got basic object.
So basically, the dog module is placed right in between our custom classes that are human and human
being and the object class that comes with Ruby, so inheritance, you will see how the method lookup
change is going to work out when working with both Mixin and the class inheritance.
So for this detail you have covered mixin.
So when we will be covering inheritance, then you are going to see how Mixin are going to work on with
class inheritance.
So whatever we have covered, this means that since the dog method is not defined in the human class
or the next place it is going to look for is going to be the dog module.
So this continues in an ordered linear fashion until the method is either found or there are no more
places to look.
So I hope you have understood the concept of modules and how they are going to get used and how you're
going to just check for the ancestors of a single class and how if they are interlinked with the modules
using multiple classes, that is the concept of make sense how they are going to get around the ancestors.
Ohayon.
So I hope you have understood all the stuff.
I know it was a very interesting tutorial and the next story like come on with more interesting stuff.
So for now, that's it.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.