Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to enter the DORELLE on this discourse on Truby and in this story
we are going to cover the introduction to erase.
So what are errors and why are they used in almost every programming language you will come across?
So in Ruby areas, let you represent a list of data in your programs.
Once you have data in an area, you can sorted.
You can remove the duplicates from that data.
You can reverse its order.
You can extract sections of data, or you can search through the errors for a specific data you are
looking for.
You can also convert an area to a string.
You can transform one array of data into another, and you can also roll up any area into a single value.
In this section, you will explore some of the most practical methods Ruby provide for working with
that data that is stored in areas.
As you work on with this section, you will come across some maps that end with an exclamation mark.
These methods often have side effects, such as mutating the original value or raising exceptions.
Many methods you will use in this section have a related method.
With this affects, you will also come across methods that end with a question mark and these methods
basically return zabulon value.
Now you have Goertz some methods with exclamation mark and question marks in the previous sections as
well.
So I guess that won't be a problem for you in this section as well.
Now there are a naming convention that is used throughout Ruby.
It's not something that is enforced at the program level.
It's just another way to identify what you can expect from any kind of method.
So a method is always named after what it is supposed to do.
So you will come across many of those.
So let's start our exploration of areas and array methods by looking at how to basically initialize
an area and how to access the elements of an array in this tutorial.
So we will move on to our editor, Adam.
And in this story, we will restrict restrict ourself only to how to initialize an area and how to access
the elements of an array.
Now, in the previous sections, you have already covered how to initialize an area because there were
some topics that were associated somehow with these errors.
So in this tutorial, we will discuss all of that in detail.
And if you have any kind of that, I hope that those doubts will get cleared away.
So let's say we have an area that is named as X and in that area, let's say you have got a lot of members.
So always remember that when you have to initialize an area, you have to store it in a variable.
So just initialize that variable.
And this variable over here is no more than going to be a simple area, but it is now going to contain
an area.
And to initialize an area where you have to do is that you have to write in these square brackets and
the square brackets are basically going to contain the values that are going to store in this area.
So you can initialize any values, you can specify integers, you can specify string, you can specify
fluid, any kind of data that can be specified in an array.
So to start on with, let's say we have strings over here.
So let's say our first string is a.
Then we have Godbee, then we have Godse, then we have got God, and finally, let's say we have five
elements A, B, C, D and E.
Now, basically, this is going to be an area and to know the location of every element in an area,
you can just start on by counting from zero from this side.
So this is basically the zeroth location of the area.
This is the first location of the ARACY is stored at the second location, disturbed at the fourth location.
And this is basically the location.
So you have to start out with zero zero one, two, three, four.
I guess that was four, not five.
All right.
Now, this is basically how you can initialize an area now to access the elements of an area where you
have to do.
Is that if you want to print it out as well, you can just write inputs and you have to write in the
name of the variable in which this area is stored.
You can write in the square brackets again.
And for example, you want to, let's say, access a very specific value.
So what you can do is that you can write the position of that element, what you want to print out in
these square brackets.
Right over here.
So let's say I want to print in the first element, and I know that the counting starts from zero.
So I'm going to write in zero or here, which is the location of this area here in this area X..
So just run this code and you can see that it is going to get printed on the adumbrated the right over
here.
Now, if you want to access the first element, just write in one, run the school and B is going to
get printed.
Now, there is one more interesting concept about how to specify negative numbers of a help.
Now, let's say you have this error and it has, let's say, a lot of elements.
Let's say F is also a part of it.
G is also a part of it.
That is also a part of it.
And let's say is also a part of it.
Now, for example, you want to access this element now instead of you start counting from here like
zero one, two, three, four, five, six and seven.
So it will take a lot of time if you start counting on from this starting location.
Now, if you have a variable which you want or you have an element in an area you want to access and
that is very near to the end.
So what you can do is that you can just start counting from this site.
But remember, when you count, starting from the backwards side, then what you have to do is that
you don't have to start with a zero, you have to start with a minus one.
So this is the minus the one location, this is the minus two and so on.
Whatever is going to be the location of this eight.
So if you just write in minus one over here, then it is going to bring this for you.
You just run this code.
You can see that it has been printed right over here.
If you just write in minus Dule Hill.
Run the score, you can see that this Ohara is going to get printed.
Now, there is the question that why we don't have a minus zero, because if you are familiar with rational
numbers, you know that rational numbers starts from zero and then last one minus one, plus one plus
two, minus two, plus three, minus three, because zero can not be positive and negative, both because
zero is just a whole number.
So you have to have zero on its own because we have a zero location on which we have got this.
So if you just write in zero, well here it is going to print this over here, not this from here.
So if you want to start something printing from this backward side to what you have to do is that you
have to start on with minus one.
So minus two over here is going to get this printed over here.
Now, one more thing you need to know about here is that what if you want to, let's say, bring the
first element or you can say just the last element of this area, then you have Beldin functions for
that.
You have got the first function and you have got the last method that is better than method that can
be applied on the elements of an error.
So to bring the first element where you can simply do is that you can write inputs, you can write an
X, which is the variable in which this error is stored, and you can just write an X dot first, run
this code and you can see that it is printed out the first element for you.
So this is a very useful function that instead of typing X zero, you can just write an extract first
and that is going to look a bit more professional and to print out the last element than there is one
more method for that, that you can just write an X dot last, run this code and you can see that the
last element that is AI is going to get printed.
Finally, when you access an element that does not exist.
What do you will do is that you will often get a but if you want to get an error message instead, you
can use a function for that.
So let's start on by.
For example, if as you can see, that it has almost eight to nine elements, so let's say if I write
in 15, I know these are not 15 elements here on this score.
And you can see that I've got nothing.
But if you just notice, again, if I just write in one over here on the score, you can see that I've
got this.
But if I just write in 15 O'Haire around the score, you can see that a line space has been created,
which means that nil has been returned from this statement of here that is executed over here.
So if you don't want this to occur, because if you are running a very extensive line of code and you
have to have an output, which is also going to be very, very, very extensive.
So then this thing, Ohara is going to create a lot of problems because in this program we are only
running a single line.
So that's why we can simply see that nothing has got printed.
But if you are printing, let's say, hundred of more things on the item runner and you're also running
this piece of code over here, then you are not going to get what is going on over here and you are
not going to see that if the value of this has been printed or not.
So for that, you have got a function that is known as fetch method.
And what that fetch method is going to do is that it is going to generate an error message for you so
that you can know that whatever was there has not yet printed.
So you can write and fetch.
And if you just write in a value that is present already, let's say one, run the school, then you
can see that it is just fetch the value of the first location from this area.
And you can see that B has been printed.
But if you write in 15 O'Haire now run the school, you can see that you have got an error that says
index 15 outside of error bounds and it is known as index error.
So if you're running an extensive code, then you can simply get an error message and you are automatically
going to understand that what I'm trying to access is basically out of the scope of the error bound.
Now, this vetch function can also receive into argument and now what is the purpose of that second
argument?
Now, if you just noticed this error over here, you can see that it is a very long error.
And if you are running a very extensive program, then such kind of long errors can be very fuzzy.
And it is basically very difficult to look for the exact message, which is right.
Well, here you can see that it doesn't show from here, but you have to scroll down and things like
that.
You don't want such a large area to just generated.
All you want is that you want a simple message.
Let's say you can just write and there's a hill and you guys just create your default error message
and you can just write in.
Out of bond.
Run it and you can see that you have simply got out of bondable if you just have an element, O'Haire
underscored.
You can see that that element is going to get printed.
But if you have got something that is out of bond, you can simply generate your default message instead
of that very big and confusing message.
And that is going to be.
A lot more easier than the previous error message, and you are going to simply know that you have accessed
an element that is basically out of bond and that element is basically not present in that area.
So I hope you have understood how to fetch elements from the area, how to match the first element,
how to find the last element, how to fetch an element using the fetch function, how to generate your
custom error messages, using the fetch function.
Now, what do you need to know where here is how to retrieve multiple elements?
Now there are times you might want to grab a subset of values from your area instead of just a single
element.
If you specify a starting index followed by the number of elements you want, you will get a new array
containing those values.
For example, you can grab the middle two entries from an area which is right over here.
To do so, what do you have to do is just remove this here right in the square brackets and it is going
to have to arguments.
The first argument is going to be the value from which you want to start on.
And the second argument is going to be the value, which specifies the number of elements after the
number of after the element, which is specified as the first argument.
So, for example, I want things to start on from location number one, which means this both here and
after this.
B, I want to bring two elements.
So if I just run the score, you can see that I've got A, B and C. So it starts on with the first element
and after that it is going to print on two elements.
So the first element was this and the second element was this.
If I just write in three, you will run the score.
You can see that I've got the seed of our here, which means that I printed out three elements, including
this first location over here.
So that's how basically you can have access multiple elements from an array as well.
Now you can use the slice method, which is a building matter that can be applied an area as well to
do the very, very same thing.
Now, for example, you've already got this area here that is X..
Now, what if you want to do this very same stuff using the slice method?
So what you can do here is that you can just remove this from here.
Right?
And slice and slice function is again going to have the two arguments, which has the very same logic
as the previous logic, which was in the square brackets.
All you've tried to write in one to run, Ron is going to get printed just right in Trio here.
ABCDE is going to get printed.
The slide method also basically returns a new area because whatever this is is now a new area.
It leave the original area unaltered.
However, if you use the slice method with an exclamation mark, the original array will be changed
as well.
And you have covered the method with the exclamation mark.
And you know that when you use the exclamation mark, what methods then?
What it is going to do is that it is going to also alter the original area as well.
But if you don't want the original array to get Eldard, then you don't have to specify an exclamation
mark.
Then you have a method that is a method and the take method let you grab the specified number of entries
from the beginning of an array.
So instead of specifying this first argument, which specifies the location from which you want to start
printing, so if you don't want that, you just want, let's say, the four first four elements to get
printed.
And you always want to start on with the start of the era.
And let's say print, let's add two elements up to that, three elements up to that.
So you can not use the slides matter.
You can use you can just write in zero here.
But there is a specific method for that, which is known as the take method.
And the method takes only one argument.
Let's say if I just write in three, you will run the score, then it is going to print the first three
elements.
So by default, the government is going to start on from the zero allocation and it is going to print
the number of elements which is specified as an argument of here.
Since it is three you has it is going to print the first three element.
If you just write in four over here, it is going to printed the four elements.
That is A, B, C and D.
So I hope you have understood all of these.
You know how to access the elements from an area using a lot of methods.
And you also know how to just retrieve multiple elements from an area as well.
So I guess that's enough with this tutorial.
In the next iteration, we will see a lot on errors more.
So I hope you stick on to this section and learn everything.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.