Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another detour on this course on Ruby uninvested.
We are going to cover the introduction to models and make sense what you already have covered in previous
tutorials.
So starting on with a module's so as you know that modules are a way of grouping together, matador's
classes and constant, Modie would give you two major benefits.
The first one is that modules provide a namespace and provide name clashes.
Secondly, modules implement the mixin facility.
Now modules define a namespace, a sandbox in which your methods and constants can play without having
to worry about being stepped on by another method and constant.
Then if you talk about the syntax of using modules, then it is very simple.
You already have seen this is right in the name of the module, the name of the module.
Then you have to write in the statements which you want to use in this module that can be either matters,
that can be classes, that can be variables or anything.
Then you have to just end this right or here.
Module constants are a name just like class constants with an initial uppercase letter, or you can
just make the entire letter as uppercase.
The method definition looks similar to module methods defined just like last methods.
As with class method, you call a module method by preceding its name, with the module, name and spirit,
and you reference a constantly using the module name and to Colon's lightless methods.
Whenever you define a method in a module, you specify the module name followed by a dot and then the
method name.
Then comes the concept of mixing in Ruby, which you already have Guillard.
So when a class can inherit features from more than one current class, the class is supposed to show
multiple inheritance.
But as you know that Ruby does not support multiple inheritance directly.
But Ruby modules have another wonderful use.
At a stroke, they pretty much eliminated the need for multiple inheritance.
Providing a facility that is called as makes sense makes and give you a wonderful controlled way of
adding functionality to classes.
However, there are true power comes out when the code in the mix and start to interact with the code
in the classes that uses it.
So let me give you a quick example of how to use, make sense and implement the concept of multiple
inheritance in Ruby.
So that is, I guess, something new for this tutorial.
Just move on to Atum.
So let's say you have two modules, the first module is Module A, and in that module you have, let's
say, two functions.
The first one is a one.
Just and this.
And then you have a two.
Just and this as well.
And the model as well, and then let's say you just copied this from here.
And you passed it again, so let's say you have this now as the.
And the objects for this be are going to be B1 and B2, so the functions are B1 and the second function
is B2.
All right.
Now, after initializing these modules, would you have to do is that you have to initialize the class
as well.
So let's say we have a class as well that is, let's say named as X and in that Class X, what we are
going to do is that we are going to include the two modules.
So the first module is a module and the second module is the module B, so I guess I misspell this.
It has to be include, include, include, include me, so now I have included both the modules and
lets it in this way.
Here I have one more function that is, let's say, as one analyzes and this functional here as well,
this and this class as well.
And down here, what you are going to now do is that you are going to create an object for the Class
X..
So what we are going to write in is that we are going to write in y equal to.
Export news, so this has created an object for the Class X, which has two modules added, the first
one is module eight and the second one is Monu will be.
So now if you just write in y dot a one.
Why adopt a two?
Then why not be one?
Why not the two and finally, the method that is present in the class itself, that is just colored
by that as well.
So if you just run this code, it is going to run perfectly just at Put's at the start of February one.
Not with this, but with this.
With this as well, with why the one?
What I'd be do and find any wide eyed assessment, just trying to score it, and as you can see, that
it has now run perfectly.
So basically what's going on over here is that the module consists of the method one and two.
Module B consists of the method V1 V2 that simple include both the modules and the the class can access
all the four methods, namely A1, A to B and B2.
Therefore you can see that the class sample inherits from both the modules test.
You can say that Class M x o'haire basically shows multiple inheritance oramics and so that is how basically
you can implement.
Multiple inheritance in Ruby using makes sense, so that was just a basic introduction about modules
and makes sense, but you have already covered that.
But the purpose of this tutorial was in the next iteration, which are going to just follow on in this
section, are basically going to be related to modules and mixin.
So I thought that this tutorial should be added to just refresh your concept about modules and sense.
So in the next drill, we are going to start on with some new concept that is going to be nested modules.
So stay tuned for that.
Thank you for now and I'll see you guys in the next aureole.