Hey, guys, what's up?
This is American, and I welcome you to an editorial on this course, Ruby and in.
We are going to be covering two functions that can be applied on strengths.
The first one is going to be the string split function.
And then we are going to see how to find the largest number and a specific string.
So talking about the first one, we have this string split function.
So basically taking a string and splitting it with the help of a delimiter is a very common task in
Ruby.
A string split function basically divides a string into some strings based on a delimiter, which return
an array of these substrates.
So if you talk about.
The syntax of this split function, we have this right over here, it is Trenda split and then you have
to write in the number that is going to be the delimiter.
So the string split function basically takes an optional second parameter as well.
That represents the limit.
If you talk about that second parameter, if that limit parameter is omitted, the trailing Mulford's
are going to be suppressed.
If the limit is a positive number at most, that number of pages will be returned.
For example, if the limit is one, the entire string is going to be written as the only entry in that
area.
If it is something greater than one, let's say two.
So it is going to divide that area or you can say a string into two elements.
Then if that limit is negative, then there is no limit to the number of pages written and the trailing
motives are basically suppressed.
So let's move on to the second part before we go on to our Ed, so the second one is how to find the
largest word in a specific string for this.
The split function is going to help us out again.
It is going to split the number.
Then we are going to use the sort of function that is going to sort the area starting on from the long,
shortest number to the longest number.
And then we can apply the reverse method on that.
And all that is going to be covered in a quick example, which I will be covering just now.
So we will just move on to our item.
So starting on with our first function, that is the string split function.
So to start on with a very simple example, let's say we have a simple string that is hello and we want
to split it.
And Brackett's, you have to specify the arguments to force.
Now, let's say I do not specify anything as an argument over here.
I just have a Puzzo here are underscored.
And as you can see, that it has split the number as and it has returned to an area to me.
And as you can see, that it has split the complete word each by string.
As you can see, that edges separate here is separated.
And I've got this L and this and then this over here.
So, for example, I want to have something like let's say I want to specify some number over here.
Let's say a one.
Iran discord, and it is going to return this split, this hallow word over here as a complete stranger
will help.
Now, if I specify, let's say, to O'Hare or underscore, it is again going to specify this hello,
help.
Now, what is the reason behind this is that it split the number based on this whatever argument we
are specifying and implementing on this number we've had now since this, too, is not a part of this
item alone.
So that's why it is joining me, the complete string.
Now, if I just specify, let's say, the word from which I want to splitted, for example, I want
to split the string starting on from this.
So if I just specify Etoile.
This go down, as you can see, that edge has now been separated, which is before and after.
I have got this Al, which is now a separate string o'haire, for example, if I just specify L'Oréal,
run this code.
And as you can see, that it has split the string.
And as you can see that it has skipped basically both the EL, which we have right over here as it has
here.
And as you can see that it has achey then Espace and then this.
All right.
Over here.
Then if you specify, let's say, the last thing that is or here, run this school, and as you can
see, that is no more a part of this and it is right over here printed on the screens.
So we can have regular expressions as well.
We can have the string characters by itself as well.
So, for example, we want to do it with a regular expression.
So let's say we have these.
Do Backslash is here and you can see that it has returned achievable all right, O'Haire, which means
that it has spread splitted it completely.
Every character has been separated by itself.
So if you want to specify some word oakhill so let's say I just tried Anello here and a plus sign will
help.
Ronda's going out, as you can see that I have E or if I do not specify this plus Hinohara, you can
see that I have got an extra space over here.
If you want to admit that base you can just write in a plus sign here on this code.
And as you can see that it has h e or No.
Basically what this means that it means that you have to add L with L'Amore, which means that you can
just write and double over here as well and it is going to return you with the same output as well.
So if you just write in, you will heal.
And as you can see that you have got ATCH and Wahib.
So the same thing you are doing with the quotation marks, you can do it with these backslash and that
will coalesce the regular expression delimiter.
Then comes the second part of the split function that deals with the second parameter, we can specify
and as I told you, that that second parameter basically represent a limit.
And if that limit is permitted, you have already seen the result that the trailing now are basically
suppressed.
Now, if that limit, we are going to just specify if it is a positive number, then at most that number
of features will be written.
For example, if you just specify one, it is going to return the same entry which we have used as a
string.
If the limit is negative, then there is no limit to the number of rules written and the trailing those
fields are going to be not suppressed.
So let's just specify the second argument.
So let's just change the string to something so it is more workable with let's say it is a number.
Now let's say one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
So this is our number right here.
We want to use this.
So what we are going to do is that we are going to just remove it.
And in a previous case, if you let's just specify for where here, run this gaudens, you can see that
four has been skipped.
And then we have got this five, six, seven, eight right over here.
And we have this extra space being added.
I would be dead explaining in a short while.
So, for example, what I want is that I want to split it with four, but I want to return it as a single
string.
So what I'm with.
Right.
And I'm going to place a comma.
I'm going to just write in one over here, run the score.
And as you can see, that it has returned the entire string over here, which is one, two, three,
four, five, six, seven, eight.
Now, if I just write in to Abargil.
Roundest Gordon, as you can see, that it has redone two strings one, two, three, then it has skipped
four and then it has returned five, six, seven, eight, nine.
The previous case that you have seen that I've in one and run the score, you can see that four is still
available here and why it is available here.
That will also be explained in a short while.
So, for example, I want to, let's say, skip the space, which is present right over here between
one, two, three, four and five, six, seven, eight.
So does the split function apply on spaces as well?
So let's just try out at a space over here or underscore.
And as you can see, that it has been applied on this base as well.
And as you can see that after the space, it has been split it into two strings.
One, two, three, four is a separate and five, six, seven.
It is a separate location of the area which has been retained by the split function on the string we
have specified.
So these examples were the shortest and the simplest, and in my experience, these were the common
usages of the string split function.
So when you start to go beyond the short and simple, you will find some behavioral oddities with the
string split and it will always be with the regular expression delimiter.
So, for example, you have this string one, two, three, four over here and you just specify the
split function.
Not on these anymore, but you just write in.
Let's say this as one O'Haire underscore and as you can see that you have got two, three, four.
Now, the expected output was that it should have returned to three, four over here just by skipping
this one, as you have seen, one I would have just written calling a real one in between this one discord.
And as you can see, that it worked in the same way it has returned to space.
And then two, three, four.
Now, the expected output, as it was in the case of Halo, it should have returned.
This two, three, four as an output and not this extra space that has been added at this stop.
So what is the reason behind this now?
This internally, this string split function only uses the regular expression delimiters.
If you pass in a string delimiter, it will escape for regular expression and it will be then turned
into a regular expression.
So this expression right here basically works something like it is this one, two, three, four dots.
Bledsoe is just copy this.
Instead of hair, and it should be one, two, three, four dots and in the brackets, what it is basically
it is a regular expression and it is a new regular expression.
And in between these bracket, what it is, it is basically a regular expression, dot escape, and
it is basically escaping this one as a character.
So what this O'Haire, basically, when we write something like this, what it is basically doing is
that it is treating this as this statement, which is for you as simple as that.
But in the background, it is running this entire statement over here that is a regular expression new
and then it is creating.
Another insider that is regular expression that escape, and it is escaping the character one, and
it is printing two, three, four for you.
Now, if you talk about the delimiter, I am referring to a regular expression, delimiters internally.
That is what the strength plate uses.
So the string split keeps track of five important pieces of information.
The first one is the string itself.
The second one is the result array, which is written as an output.
The third one is the position marking where to start matching the string against the delimiter, which
is basically the start position and that is initialized to zero.
The fourth is the position marking where the string matched the delimiter and that is the position matched
position and it is also initialized to zero.
Then the third thing is the position marking the offset immediately following where the string matched
the delimiter.
Another string split operates in a loop.
It continues to match the string against the delimiter until there are no matches that can be found.
It performed the steps on each iteration.
So what it do is that the first step is that it start from the start position, match the delimiter
against the string.
It said the matched position to where the delimiter matched the string.
If the delimiter does not match the string, that it breaks the loop simply, but it creates a substring
using the start and the matched position of the string be matched and it push this substring onto the
result array, which you can see as an output.
And then it said the start position for the next iteration.
So if you talk about this very example we are covering right now.
What is going on over here is in the first loop, the start position is initialized to zero.
So I'm going to just ride in over here so that you can see more what I'm talking about.
So the starting position is going to be initialized to zero then what it is going to.
And this is basically the first loop.
I'm going to also write in.
First with him.
So in the first lub, the first thing that is going to be done is that the start position is going to
be initialized to zero.
Now, the delimiter is going to be matched against the string that is one, two, three, four.
And the delimiter over here is this one.
So the first match occurs with the first character, as you can see, that we have one is a delimiter
and one is the very first character of the string.
So the first match occurs with the first character, one which is at position zero.
Now, this sets the matched position to zero as well.
So whenever it finds a match, it is going to look for the position of that match.
So in our case, since this is Bush's position number zero, this is position number one, this is position
number two.
This is position number three.
So our match with this delimiter is find found at position number zero.
So it is going to have a variable match position and it is going to initialize it to zero where the
match is found with the string we have specified right over here.
Now a substring is created using the start and the matched positions and it is pushed on to the result
array.
Now this gives us the start and which translates to zero zero, which returns an empty string.
So what I'm saying Ohare is that what it is going to do is that it is going to give us a string that
looks something like.
Start, comma, and and what it is basically is that it translates to the string that is one, two,
three, four in our case, and it is basically going to be like zero comma zero.
So that is basically an empty string, which it is going to return.
And that is basically why it is having this extra space right over here.
So the start position is now going to be reset to zero for the same.
It is not going to be zero.
It is going to be one.
So they just copied this from here or here and in the second loop.
The state position is now going to be one.
The second loop is going to start, start is now one, the delimiter is going to be matched against
the remainder of our string, now the remainder of a string, as we can just specify the will here and
the remainder string that is remaining is two, three, four.
Since one has been matched, it has been escaped, and now the remaining string is two, three, four
over here, no matches found to the loop is just finished.
A substring is created using the star position and the remainder of the string and it is pushed onto
the result.
So since in our first case, this was basically what was kept.
So this return, basically the zero were here.
That is basically an empty space.
So since the star position and matched position was zero zero, so the star position is going to have
this extra space and then the position at which the loop ends is basically going to be the remainder
part.
So it is going to return to three four as the second.
If you just write and let's say to Oakhill, then run the score.
Then as you can see that it has written one, then it is written three, four, and now you must be
thinking that why it has not added any space now.
Now the reason behind that is that since the match is found at the second step now, so we don't have
the zero zero right over here since the matched position is now one and the star position where it starts
is basically also two.
So that's why and the remainder that is remaining is three four now.
So that's why it has not returned an empty space, not over here.
And this is also going to be to over here and the remainder is something going to be like one and then
a space and then three, four because two has been skipped.
So that is going to add the space over here.
And if you have got this one, three, four over here.
So I hope that you understand that why it is adding this space when the match is found at the first
position and why it is not adding a space when the match is found at some other position.
Now, there are hundreds of ways in which you can use a regular expression to use the split function
on strings.
But since we have not covered the regular expression, stop till now, so I don't want to get you confused.
So all you need to do is stick to it now.
And I hope that you have understood the basic running of how a split function works normally and how
it works with the regular expression, considering this only example we have covered.
So moving on to the second part of the tutorial that deals with how to find the largest number in a
given string.
So the first thing here we are going to do is that we are going to initialize a sentence, that arrow
that is going to have certain words, and then we are going to split that in which we are going to split
it in a way that every word is separated and in a form of an error.
Then we are going to find the length of that area.
And after finding the length of that area, what we are going to do is that we are going to apply the
start function on that area.
And since the start by a function, as you know, that does not accept any kind of parameter.
So that's why we are going to use the reference operator over here.
Then what we are going to do is since the start by a function start, the number starting from the lowest
to the largest number.
And in this case, we want to find the largest number.
So we are going to reverse that error so that the largest number is at the starting position and the
lowest number is at the end position.
And then you can just output the zero location of that area and that is automatically going to have
the largest number in whatever sentence you have written.
So starting on, we will have, let's say, a variable, let's say.
Sentence.
And the sentence is, let's say, hello, this is a new tutorial.
So this is the sentence we are going to be using.
So what we are going to do now is that we are going to have split function and this split function,
we are going to write and we are going to write in the sentence, not split.
And you know that to split a function by having every word separated, you can just add a space over
here on this court and you can see that you have got no kind of errors.
This means that this has now been separated as a list of errors.
So you can just write in votes split.
We'll hear more on this.
And as you can see that you have got this entire sentence.
Every word has a separate location in an area now.
So you can just remove it for now.
And that was just to check out.
Now, the next thing you need to do is that you need to find the length of this area you have created.
So to find it, we are going to have a variable length.
And we are going to just apply it on this function, so we are going to write and split.
Dodd lent.
And that is going to do our job on this, and it is running perfectly till now, the next thing you
need to do is that you need to now sort this out.
Right now, you are going to apply to start by a function on this.
And you know that the by function basically arranges elements starting from the lowest to the largest.
So what we are going to write about here is that we are going to write in sort equal to.
And what we are going to start is basically, again, going to be displayed functions, so we are going
to write and split.
Dots are underscored by sort by a function is going to be used and we are going to use the reference
operator over here.
So we're going to use the and a calling and we are going to write in the land.
So we want to sort it, tell the entire area we're going to sort it by land so then we can just write
in a hail.
So we have to reverse it because it has started it's starting from the lowest to the largest, we wanted
to be from the largest to the lowest.
So we are going to just reverse whatever has been started over here.
So we are going to ride and start, not reverse Colin.
Exclamation mark, sorry, this is not a call, and the next thing you have to do is that you can just
write an.
The largest number is basically what is the reverse zero position, so you can just put.
Largest underscored, and you can see that the largest string has been redone, that is tutorial in
our case.
As you can see, that this word has the largest land.
If you just, let's say, cut off some words from here.
And now, the largest word, as you can see, is this halo here around the school.
And as you can see, that you have got this halo now as your output.
So that was how basically you can just print on the largest number from a given string.
So the large print, the largest number, it does not have a specific function.
You have to use certain functions to get the largest number of words.
You have to have this sentence.
Whatever here is, you have to split it.
Then you have to find the land.
Then you have to apply to start that function and to start by land.
Then you have to reverse that whatever has been sorted out.
And then the zero position basically contains the largest number and then you can just simply print
it out.
So I guess that is clearer now, if you want to let's say the smallest number than that is very easy.
What you can do is that since you know the length of this, so you know that it contains zero one,
two, three, four or five elements, or you can just write in five here.
Now, it is not large as it is the smallest number.
And smallest O'Hare as well.
Can run the score and you can see that is basically the smallest number, which is right over here.
So that's how you can use the split function, the land function, the side by and the reverse function.
All these forward to get the smallest and largest number in a given string.
So I hope you have understood the start by function.
You have an answer story.
The first function we have covered in this tutorial, a split function and how to find the largest number
in a given string.
So I guess that's it for this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next Attrill.