Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to an editorial on discourse on and in this story we are going
to cover about exceptional objects and we are also going to see some brilliant methods.
So exception object are just normal ruby object that we can give useful information from.
Ruby provides building behaviors for these objects that you may want to use while handling the exception
are in the part of debugging.
So let's take a look at the Ruby exception handling objects and how they are associated right over here.
So if you have a look at these syntax right over here, which in which you have the very same index
from the previous case, but now what you have is that you have got this stuff over here extra.
Now, whatever error we have specified error, that is the type of error, so here we are handling standard
error on, you know, that standard error has a lot of descendants.
So whatever error from the standard error class is going to get.
So this is going to get handled right to hell.
And this thing over here means that that is going to get stored in an object that is known as E..
So this is Syntex in the above code is going to rescue any kind of standard error and store the exception
object in the object Ebbie have specified.
Now, some useful instanced method that Ruby provides are the exception, message and exception.
Backtrace, which returns an error message and a backtrace associated with the exception, respectively.
So if you just have a look at the example, and since we are using the standard error, so all these
errors, any kind of error that is going to get occurred right here is going to get executed because
all these are the descendants of the standard error laws.
So let's just see an example of how this is going to get executed.
Let's move on to Adam.
And what we are going to do is that we are going to ride in the big block and big and block.
What we are going to do is that we are going to have any kind of error that is basically a bot or the
descendant of the the standard error subclass.
So let's say we have the same error that was the division by zero error.
So we have it right to here now in the rescue block.
What we are going to do is that we are going to ride into a hill, the name of the class.
So we are going to ride in standard.
Error and after that, what we are going to do over here is that we are going to specify an equal designed
this well and we are going to specify an object right to held.
So what this object is going to do is that now it is going to store the.
And now this object is going to help us do a lot of things.
For example, if you want to know the error message so you can just write an IDOT message and message
is something that is building.
Just write in and run this code and you can see that it says divided by zero.
So it on message has printed us a very sober message, which was a very lengthy message, a two lane
red message printed.
But now we have stored it in an object E and when we write an e dot message, it has printed as a very
simple message that says divided by zero.
So we are going to understand that whatever code we have written in the log, we have got some kind
of divided by zero over there.
So we are going to just check it out and remove any kind of division that was done by zero.
So if you just replace this one, this is going to run perfectly.
So now if you just replace it by zero and the second one we have that is very important is the backtrace
Abargil.
So now I just run it, you can see that it is giving me the backtrace of the file in which I've got
this program store and it is basically giving me all the trace of where this error has occurred.
So that's how basically you can use the object concept over here.
So in this code right over here, the code is going to rescue any type of standard error exception,
including all of its descendants and the output.
And it is going to output the message that is associated with the exception.
Object code like this can be very useful when you are debugging and need to narrow down the type or
cause of the error.
You may also choose to be more specific about which type of exception to handle.
But remember to never rescue the exception class recall that exception object are just normal ruby object
and the different exception types such as argument error and the no method error are actually class
name.
Therefore, we can even call object class on an exception object to return its class name as well.
So, for example, if I just ride in your Class A or underscored, it is going to give me the class
for which the error has occurred and now you know that zero deviation error is basically the standard
of the standard error.
And standard error is basically a subclass, which is a part of the exception clause that is at the
top, which I just recommend that you should never use.
Now comes some of the bold and methods you can use, with exception, handling the first one is ensure.
Now, you may also choose to include an insurer clause, in your opinion and rescue block after the
last rescue clause.
Now, this branch is the branch that is going to get executed always whenever an exception was right
or not.
So when is this basically useful?
Simple example is the resource management.
The code which we are going to about to do is basically demonstrating some working.
So whether or not an exception is raised or not, this stuff that is written in the insurer clause is
going to get executed.
So let's say we have, let's say ten divided by two.
So you know that it is not any kind of error.
We run discord, so it is going to run perfectly.
And right now here we are going to write an insurer and an insurer because we are going to just write
in votes.
This code is.
Always executed.
So if you just run the school, you can see that it says this school is always executed, as you have
seen, that this over here is now true.
This Ohare is not going to get printed, but this statement is still printing that says this quote is
always executed.
So now let's say we have an error message over here.
Now we run the school and now we are also going to get this rescue blog executed since the division
by zero has occurred.
So it is going to give us the IDOT class, which is a zero division error.
And it is also going to execute the inshore blog that says this code is always executed.
So if there are multiple rescue clauses in the big and rescue blog, the ENSURE clause serve as a single
exit point for the block.
And always it allows you to put all your clean up code in one place as seen in the code right here.
One important thing to remember about ensure that it is critical that this code does not raise an exception
in the code within the insurer clause raise an exception.
Any exception raised earlier in the exception of the big and risky block will be masked and LIBOR debugging
will become very, very difficult.
For example, if you just write in 10 by zero over here, which means that an exception also exist over
here and that is going to generate an error message for you.
So that is going to make debugging very, very, very difficult for you.
The second key word we have in Aruba is the retrack keyword.
So we will introduce retry briefly, but it is unlikely that you will use it often using read write
in your big and rescue blog, redirects your program back to the big instatement.
This allows your program to make another attempt to execute the code that raised an exception.
You may find a retrial useful when connecting to a server, for example.
Beware that if your code continuously fail, you risk ending up in an infinite loop.
In order to avoid this, it's a good idea to set a limit on the number of times you want to retry to
execute that code.
Retry must be called within the rescue block as seen more often.
So, for example, we have got this error over here.
Now what we want is that we want to retry, to run this code.
Now you know that this code is never going to get executed because you have got this extra B, something
that is not a part of this.
So what you will do is that right away here, let's say you just write in Retry.
Now, retry means that you want to run this very cool piece of code again and again.
So using retry is going to get this code executed again.
So for now, we don't need this object Abargil.
So if I just run this code, then as you can see, that is just executing, executing and executing.
And it is going to keep executing because now we have created an infinite loop and by infinite loop.
What does that mean is that, as I told you, that this code over here is never, never going to get
executed.
So since this is not going to get a good.
So this is this rescue block is going to keep, try and keep try and keep trying, keep trying for an
infinite number of time.
So to stop it, just write some statement on this code so that this stops right over a hill.
All right, so this just this as well, just write and.
Inshore block.
All right, now, what we are going to do to limit the retries statements is that we are going to introduce
a variable that is going to actually limit the number of times a piece of gold is going to get tried
to be executed.
So right at the top, you are going to create a constant and that constant is going to be the retry.
Limit, and we are going to initialize it to, let's say, a tree, so we only want this code to get
executed to our we want to try this code three times to be more specific.
And in the beginning, log what we are going to write and we are going to write and attempt.
Equal to attempts.
Zero.
So actually, we have initialized the attempt equal to zero, and whenever this retry log is reached,
what we want is that we want the attempts.
To be incremented by one so increments is going to get incremented by one whenever this rescue block
is reached and whenever this exception is raised right or held.
So with the right now, we are going to specify and if condition as well, so we are going to retry.
If the attempt is less then the retry limit, which we have specified right at the top, that is three.
So if you don't run the score, you can see that it has actually ended because it tried the court.
It tried to run it three times, but since it does not work.
So that's why it just returned the whatever was a part of this entire block.
And that is written right to a hail.
Now, you must be thinking that if a piece of God is wrong, as you can see, that X equals zero is
a code that is going to raise an exception, that what is the purpose of retrying this code other than
just wasting our resources of the program?
No.
For example, you have a piece of code in which you want to try to connect to a server.
Then a reader is going to be very useful.
In that case, it is going to retry and it is going to keep attempting to connect to a server.
Now you can just of limit this retry limit to infinity so that it is going to keep trying to connect
to the server until and unless it is connected to the server.
But you can also limit that connection request.
You can just limit it to five so that it is going to try five times to connect to the server.
So in that case, it is going to be very useful.
But what about cases like these in which you have something like this?
So for example, right here, let's say you have a variable that is y equal to two and let's say or
not, let's just make it to zero.
So now let's say you have then divided by Aweil.
Now, as you can see that it is straight away a kind of an error that is going to get caused by the
zero division error.
That is a part of the standard error.
And it is going to just retry and it is going to just print me the spots in Chock-a-block.
So if I just run the score, you can see that it is just printing me this in block right over here.
But what if I want to correct this quote, so if any kind of error occurs right over here in this standard
error?
So what I want or let's just be very specific and just use the zero.
División.
Error, so whenever a zero division error occurs, what we are going to do is that we are going to change
the value for why let's say I just change the value it for it to be to and write off the list.
I just write in puts why I will not want to help.
So for the first attempt, it is going to just initialised attempt to zero, it is going to try this
good o'haire since this is an error, it is going to get caught, right?
Well, here it is going to change the value for what you could do.
And it is going to increment the attempt, which is now going to get equal to one and it is going to
retry since the condition over here is true.
Now, when it retries, since we have changed the value of Y, so that's why this statement over here
is now going to get through and this statement over here is going to generate MI five.
And after that I'm going to get this as an output that is in CHOCK-A-BLOCK because this is going to
get executed all day.
So if I just run school now, you can see that you have got five and you have got an Chock-a-block Aubagio.
So that's why the retry can be useful in such cases.
So that's it with the two key words we have to cover in this tutorial.
And also, you have learned the concept of the exception objects, so I guess that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I will see you guys in the next oratorio.