Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another tutorial on discourse on Ruby.
And in this story you'll continue on with arrows and in this story all basically we are going to cover
two interesting topics on Erra.
The first one is to be how to get a random entry from an area.
And then we are going to see how to find and filter elements of an area.
So to start on with, the first stopping is getting a random entry from an area.
Now, you might be working on a game of chance, let's say, or maybe you are writing a program that
picks a contest winner.
Or maybe you are, let's say, just tossing the toss and you want to see whether our hat scheme or at
the game and you want that to be random.
Not those kind of things require some kind of random value.
Not a common solution is to put the possible choices in an area and select a random index to get a random
index from an area.
You could simply generate a random index between zero and the last index of the area and use that as
an index to retrieve the value.
But there is a very easier way to do the very same thing.
The simple method in Ruby is going to grab a random entry from an error and make the job simple for
you.
So let's just create a random error in which we are going to create a.
Possible set of outcome we want to expect so we are going to write in X equal to this error and let's
say we want the answer can be either let's say.
Head or it can be.
So these are the, let's say, two possible outcomes, so what you can do over here is that you can
just ride in boats and start sample, run this code and you can see that had has been generated, run
this again.
Tail has been generated again, had again had you can see that it is basically generating random values.
Now you can have multiple over here as well.
Yes.
Let's say we have got yes.
We have got another one here then we have got maybe a here.
And then we have got, let's say, ask again, a, which is basically a primitive version of a magic
eight ball game.
So if he run this one O'Haire here, so you can see that you've got maybe if you just run it again,
you can see that you have got a different output running again and you have got maybe.
So basically the sample function is going to generate random values for, you know, the sample method
also accepts one more, an argument over here as well that return an array of random entries.
So if you happen to need more than one random entry, you should just supply that number and the argument
and you will get the number of entries you have specified in that argument.
So, for example, right over here, what we want is that one, two entries to get generated.
So you can just write in brackets, Soheil, and you can write in the number of entries you want.
So if you want to outputs to get selected randomly from this area X, you can just write in to run this
and you can see that you have got a note and you have got is these are the two random entries that has
been picked up from this area.
When you run the score, if you just run it again, you can see that you've got Knyaz again.
And if you just run it again, you can see that you got maybe energy.
So what this is going to do is that basically it is going to get random entries, which is going to
be the number you have specified in the arguments.
Now, the next topic we are going to cover in this drill is how to find and filter elements of an array.
No.
One, you are looking for a specific element in an area you typically ETrade or its elements until you
find what you are looking for.
But Rubiera provide several methods specifically designed to simplify this process of searching through
areas.
If you just want to see if an element exists, you can use the include questionmark method, which return
true.
If the specified data is an element of the area and it is going to return, false at the specified data
is not the element of an error.
Now you have already covered that include function in the previous sections as well, and you know that
to include function is only used to check if a certain entry exists or not and it is always going to
return a boolean value.
So if you just write an X dot includable here, a question mark over here and what you can do is that
you can just write in the value you want to check since it is all individual.
So you have to check it.
Indira's so let's say I want to check if it has.
X, Y, Z, in it or not, I was just trying it, and you can see that I've simply got false as doubt,
but because X, Y, Z is not a part of it.
So if I just write a novel here, run the score, you can see that I have got Drew Oakhill, which means
that no is a part of that area.
So this was basically the only check if a certain element exists or not.
Now, how to basically find a value and then to filter it out from, let's say, a set of values.
What you can do is that you can just use the find method.
Now, the fine method locates and return the first element in the area that matches a condition you
have specified, because that is what is called finding and filtering.
So, for example, to identify the first entry in an area that contains a lot of values, you could
just use the each method to compare each entry and you can stop iterating when you find the first match,
which you like.
So you have, let's say, an area in which we will just specify simple values, which are a part of
the previous tutorial as well.
A, b, c.
The.
And let's say so, these are the values, so we will just remove this from here and what we will do
here is that we are going to create a variable and we are going to store Nelnet because this is what
is going to have the value.
So down here, what we can do is that we can write in X dot each and that each function is basically
going to compare each value with every element of that area.
So we are going to write an X dot each.
We're going to write and do.
The bar is here and we are going to define one more variable over here that is going to contain the
value one at a time.
So it is going to be, let's say, Wiwa Hill.
Downhill, what we are going to do is that we are going to ride in if.
Dot include Questionmark, and we are going to write in, let's say we want to check if it is a part
of this area or not, what we will do is that we are going to write in preserved equal to.
This wire was held, which we have initialized so downhill, not this.
And right here, what we can do is that we can just write and break statement, because we what we want
is that for the first match, which is found, we want to just come out of this loop.
So we use the break for that.
Just come down and the if statement just come down and the do statement.
And that has to be r e.
S.
Now, you just run this code.
And I guess you have to just try and put somewhere.
So just write in votes are, ah, yes, here, run the school and you can see that you've got that element.
So for example, you don't have that element.
Let's face that element.
Run this go and you can see that it has printed out nothing.
Now, whatever you have done, it is a very big thing.
What are you going to do is that you can do the very same thing using the fire to function.
And that is going to be much more easier than whatever you have been doing in these three deadlines.
So just remove it from here and you can just do it in a single line using defined functions.
So we are going to write an ar e equal to.
Ex Dawid find and the find function is B is to be something like in this curly brackets and in that
you have to write in the value where you want to basically store the first element for the first iteration,
second element for the second and third element for the third address and so on.
And right here what you can do is that you can write and y dot.
Include.
Questionmark and in the brackets, you can write in the value you want to search for.
That is the value down here, or you can just write in print Daria's and that's all it will do.
The very same job which was previously done from three to 10.
So just run the score and you can see that it has been printed.
If you just write an F over here, run the score, you can see that nothing has been printed.
So the find function is going to basically simplify things for you and it is going to locate and write
down the first element in the area that matches a condition you have specified.
Now the find executes the block.
You provide for each element in the area.
If the last expression in the block evaluates to true, the fine method returns the value and stops
writing.
Not if it doesn't find anything, then after that attrition through all of the elements, it is going
to have done nothing.
Then you have got a select method as well.
The select method works in a very similar way, but what it do different is that it constructs a new
area containing all of the elements that match the condition you have specified instead of just returning
a single value and just stopping.
So if you have this very same program right or here and instead of this find.
You use the select function of a hill or the rest is going to be the same, you've tried and while here
you tried inviting you to ride in this, just run the code and you can see that you have got an area.
You can see these brackets of a hill, but it is an empty array because nothing was fulfilled.
Well, here, the condition is false.
It's right in the statement so that it is true.
Run the score and you can see that you have got an area.
Now, in the previous case, it was just retaining that element and it was not an area to return.
The select function where it is different from the previous one is that it returns basically the error
of whatever elements are satisfying a specific condition.
Then you have got one more method, that is the reject method and the reject method is also used for
finding and filtering, and the reject method basically returns a new area that is containing elements
that don't match the condition.
So you can think of it as a filter that remove elements you don't want.
Now, if you just have an example in which you have this very same area and you use instead of the select,
you use the reject function, then what it is going to do is that it is going to return an output just
opposite of the select function, because what the select function do is that it selects the value that
meets the condition and return those rejecting all the other values.
But what reject is going to do is that it is going to reject the values that specifies the condition
and it is going to return the remaining values.
So basically, that's what is totally opposite of the reselect one.
So if you just run the school, you can see that the condition that was satisfying over here was this
a just removing that, rejecting its value.
It has redone the entire remaining area.
That is B, C, D and E, so select and reject both returns, a new area leaving the original value
of the area unchanged.
However, if you use the select and reject what the exclamation mark, the original area is also going
to get modified, then you have also got the find all method that is an alias for select, but there
is no find all matter with an exclamation mark.
In the next story, what we will do is that we will have a look how to sort the values of an area.
So I hope you have understood why I've been telling you so far.
I hope you have got the select matter.
You've got the reject method.
You know how to find elements and build the elements using the find function as well.
So I guess that was all with this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next Attrill.