Hey, guys, what's up?
This morning, I welcome you to another tutorial on discourse on Ruby and in this story, and we will
start on with the functions that can be applied on ranges.
So in this story, we are going to be covering two functions.
The first one is going to be the include function and the second one is going to be the size function.
So starting on with the first one, that is the include function on ranges that include is a building
method in Ruby that returns a boolean value.
True, if the given object lies within the given range else it is going to return false.
So if you talk about the syntax of this include function, then it is going to look something like this.
You have to write in the name of the range in which your range is stored.
Basically that is going to be the variable in simple words.
Then you have to write in DOT include a question mark and then you have to write in the value you want
to check if it is included in the certain range you want to check or not.
Now the function except an object, and that is basically the value.
So moving on to the second function, which we are going to be covering in this tutorial is the size
function.
So the size is also a building function in Ruby that returns the size of the range.
It returns basically the number of elements in the range in simple words.
Then you have this index, right?
Well, here it is going to be the name of the range size.
And this function accepts no parameter.
And the return value of this is going to be the number of elements as a dojos.
So let's just practice both of these in our ED.
So let's move on to Adam.
And the first function we are going to be practicing is going to be the include function.
Now, you have already covered this in the previous tutorials as well, so just give a brief overview.
So let's say we have this range that is going to equal to zero then.
So it contains no from zero to 10.
Now, we want to check that if a certain number exists between this range or not, you can just write
inputs range.
That is the name of the variable in which the range is stored.
Not you can write and include a question mark and then you can write in the object, which is basically
going to be the value you want to check in.
So let's say if I want to check if it exists in between this range or not, run this and it is going
to return.
True, because it exists between this range.
And then if you want to check in for a number that does not include in this range, then you can just
use the same context and just write in a number that is not in this range.
So let's say 12 is at that number underscored and it is going to return false as you can see.
Ohayon and previous to drill, I had told you about some of the.
Menville, or you can see the custom.
Ranges you can create, so for example, we have, let's say.
A, B, and we have this range.
Deal.
And now if you want to check if, let's say, a C is a part of it or not, then you can just run the
score.
And as you can see, that a C is a part of this range.
So it has returned true.
And 12 is not a part of it.
So that's why it has returned false as an output error on that.
I'd rather know, for example, if you want to have range, let's say from two to seven, then it is
not a necessity that you have to start a range with zero.
You can have this range start from any number and end at any number.
So now you can check for, let's say, five, run this and it is going to return.
True.
And 12 is going to return false.
So that's how basically that include function can be used to check for the normal number ranges.
And for that example I just gave you.
Then comes the second part of the Dorio that deals with the size function.
So as it told you, it is also going to be a simple one.
All you have to do is just remove this from here right in both.
Range, dog size, and it will have no arguments, just run this code and as you can see, that it has
generated six because from two to seven, we have got six elements.
That includes this two and this seven over here as well.
So that's how you can have any range and you can simply check the number of elements in that range.
So I guess that's what this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.