Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Ruby.
In this story, we will cover multi-line strings in Ruby.
Now, the previous tutorials were we have been covering so far, you have come a lot across a single
line strengths, so that is not an urge to repeat the single line strength topic here.
So I decided to go on directly to the multi-line strengths in Ruby.
Now, there are various ways to create multiline strengths in Ruby.
So let's start on with the simplest of all.
So the first method is to specify the.
Square brackets and in the square brackets, what do you hope to do is that you can specify a number
of strings, each separated by a comma.
So let's say.
I can just write in First Flustering.
And I have to specify a comma click enter, and here I can now enter a second string.
So let's say it is going to be second string.
And let's say in the third line, I have one more string that is third string, and you're going to
have something like one plus one as well here, that is going to be the fourth string.
So now the simplest way to make it a multi-line string is to use the method that is building that is
named as joint.
So just specify a dot and then join.
And what you have to specify in this bracket is whatever comes in between these strings.
So I want this string to print out on the first line, this to print out on the second line, this on
the third line and this on the fourth line.
So how this is going to be done is that I have to specify.
This thing over here, so that a new namespace space is added up to each string is printed.
All right, so all I need to do now is to run this code, so to do that, what I have to do is that
I have to simply specify both Sohel Aldar and my job is done.
As you can see that I have fostering second string, third string and one plus one right here.
And this method joint has basically helped me to print all of these strings.
And this is basically now called a multi-line string in Ruby.
So this was the first and the easiest way to create multi-line strengths in Rubinow, the second method
is to use a dog strength.
Know how it is going to be done is that you have to just remove this.
These brackets from here.
And you don't need to join anymore, so you already have the strength that is the first string, second
string, third string and one plus one over here.
So what I can do is that I have to actually enclose all these strings together, knowing the previous
method and close them using the square brackets.
Now, in the second method, which is using a dark string, would have to do is add up to initialize
a variable that it's X and I have to store all these strings in this X.
Now, how it is going to be done is using less than less than sine and I have to specify a variable
maybe be let's say I have to specify why.
So you have to specify Dadua, which indicates the starting and then you have to come out of this blog
because when you click enter, you can see that the cursor is just ahead of the line.
So you have to press backspace so that it moves out and to y, which indicates the ending of this loop.
You can just specify something that would be much easier for you to indicate or you can just use Y as
I have used.
So you have to specify Dashty that indicates the starting of the string and Y is basically going to
indicate the ending of this multiline string.
So now all you have to do is that come out, write in votes and why not y it is going to be X because
all these values are basically stored in this X, so just for us all plus R and as you can see that
the output is generated that says flustering, second string, third string and one plus one.
So this is basically the second way in which you can have multiline strings in Ruby now coming towards
the third method, not Ruby also supports a shorthand syntax in which if you want to have no interpolation,
then you can use a person designed with a small Q And if you want interpellation, then you can use
a capital cume where the person did sign.
So how it is done.
So let's start on with what we want.
No interpolation.
So what we will do is that we will have a variable that is going to be the very same that is X and it
is going to equal to Alperstein Design and Akiem.
So just remove this from here, we will have a person did sign and we will place a small, you know,
small unit as a W is used in the case where you want no kind of interpellation to have.
So you specified.
Now the round brackets just remove this bracket.
And plays this bracket over here, this is going to indicate the ending and now you already have both
a run this goed.
And as you can see, the output that is fostering and it's a second string, the third string and one
plus one, so this is basically the third method through which you can have multi-line strings in Ruby.
Now, the fourth method comes with interpolation.
Now, how it is going to be used is that all you have to do is that you have to change this molecule
with a capital.
Q and your job is going to be done.
Just click Aldar and as you can see or hear that it has your string, that superstring second string,
third string and one plus one.
All right.
So now there is a variance index that is for interpellation, which can also be used to have multiline
strings in Ruby.
What do you have to do is that you have to just remove this from here, run this good.
And all right, it says it has got some kind of error.
All right, so the error message says that syntax error and it says unexpected things and expecting
end of input, which means that I guess this space cost problem and as you can see, that as soon as
you remove the space, the color of this bracket changes from Y to create it.
You can see that when I specify the space, this turns into white.
And when I remove the space, it turns back to green, which means that you don't have to add any kind
of space or hail.
So just run this code.
And as you can see, the output that is for string, second string, third string and one plus one.
Now, the only reason I make a such kind of mistakes is I can simply remove these mistakes because I
try the code once before I teach it here.
But the purpose to make such a mistake is so that I tell you that what kind of mistakes can occur here
and what kind of precautions you have to take while coding.
So in this case, as you have seen, that you don't have to specify a space right here in between this
person design and this bracket else, it is going to generate error and it is not going to read this
bracket.
So that's why I make such kind of mistakes myself so that you will be able to see what kind of errors
you don't have to make, because if you specify a space here, you run your code, you will see that
everything is fine.
What is the problem with my code?
But the only mistake you would have done is that you would have specified this space over here.
And it is a very minor mistake.
And such kind of mistakes are very, very, very, very difficult to find.
So I hope you have understood that.
So these were some of the basically methods through which you can have multi-line strings in Ruby.
I guess those were five of the methods.
And I hope you have understood those methods.
And in the future tutorials, we will be needing these methods to have multiline strings so you can
use any of them there.
If you want to have multiline strings and that you want to have interpellation, then you have to use
the percentage capital Q format.
If you want to have no interpellation, then you can go on with the small.
Q I guess.
And then if you want to have a normal multi-line string, then you can go on with the first and second
method.
So these are the method you will be using a lot in the future tutorials.
So the purpose of this tutorial was to just give you a representation of how to represent multiline
strings in Ruby.
So I guess that's it with this story.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next Dorio.