Hey, guys, what's up this summer, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Aruba.
And in this story, we are going to see that how to put things on the screen directly, which means
that how to output things the very same way we just write them.
So there are three methods for doing it.
The first method is sports.
Now, the sports and the print command are both used to display the results of the evaluating Aruba
code.
The next method is the easy method, like sports, the outputs, the next, along with a new line character.
But it also includes double quotes around text that has been outputted.
And the third one is spread, which is a tool.
You is the very same lightbox and the print method is to put the same text on the screen as written
in the parenthesis.
So let me just show you the difference between the three methods.
The port's method basically pulls the string on the screen and also adds a new line space, whereas
in print method, if you want to add a space, you have to specify it yourself using the backslash and
whereas the ping outputs the next, along with a new line character.
But it also includes double gorz around the text that has been outputted.
So let me just show you a quick example of how all these three are going to work, so I'll just move
on to my compiler, that is Adam Brunner and Ohare.
We are going to start on with the first one that is the Put's method.
So you have to just write in votes and then you have to specify these columns and then you can just
type in any string.
For example, I want to just type in hello and then let's see wood.
So I'm going to just press on last hour and that is going to print my output now.
For example, if I want to put in something else over here like Bode's.
And I'm going to just step in and.
Fellows, so hello, World and Fellows does not make any sense, but does it matter?
So as you can see that what Woods has done is that it has automatically added a new line space after
the second one.
So I haven't specified Backslash and Oakhill, but it has automatically added a new line space for the
second course I have specified.
Now, the second method that is the best method, if I just replace words with B and now press all plus
are you can see that the same thing has been printed.
But as you can see that double courts have been added and that is what is the difference between bots
and beep so.
New space has been added without a backslash and the very same posted, but as I told you, the difference
is that Democrats have been added around a string, which means that basically the whole part of this
is brain dead.
So now, if I replace both of these with the third method to output string on the screen, that is Sprent.
Now, all plus are you can see that the double courts are missing as well as the new line space is missing
here as well.
As you can see that and phallus is printed right after this word is printed and no line space has been
added over here.
And that is what is the difference between the three matters.
Now, if you want to specify a line special here, what you have to do is that you specify backslash
and.
And that is going to do your job, so just press are and as you can see, that deadline has now been
added, but that is the line space that has been added due to this backslash.
And whereas the other two methods do it by default.
And if you're using print, you have to do it yourself and you have to add this backslash number here.
So that's how basically output can be generated on the screen the very same way it is on the ATM runner.
So I guess you have understood the three matters to put strings on the screen, so I guess that's it
with this tutorial.
Thank you so much, gas, for watching.
I'll see you guys in the next Dorio.