Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another Dooralong discourse on Ruby.
And in this story, we are going to cover a very interesting topic that is lambdas.
Now, you already have covered blocks in the previous tutorial and you know that blogs are such an important
part of Ruby.
It's hard to imagine the language without blogs.
But lambdas who love lambdas, you could go years without using one.
They almost seem like a relic from a bygone age, but that's not quite true.
Lambdas have some interesting tricks up their sleeves once you investigate them a little in this jittery
little start on what the basics of lamda usage and then move on to some more interesting advanced usages
of Lamda in Ruby.
The main thing to remember about LAMDA is that they act like functions, blocks and trucks have their
uses, but neither of them behaves 100 percent like a real life function.
But lambdas do.
So what is a lamda now?
Olenna is a way to define a block and its parameter with some special syntax.
You can save this lambda into a variable for later, use the same way you can do it for a function call.
So the syntax for defining Lambda is right here.
You have to write in a variable you attriting that equal to and a dash, then the less than sign and
then you can define just a block, the very same do kind of block.
And in this you can write the number of statements you want to define.
So.
And one more thing you have to do over here is that in the same way, when you initialize a function,
you define some lines in it.
It does not work directly.
You have to call that function.
The same goes for a lambda as well.
When you define a function, something like this, you have to call it as well.
And when you call it the code inside that block of lambda is going to get executed.
So let's just see how this index is going to get implemented.
So we will move on to Atem.
And let's just define our very first lamda functional health, so we are going to name it as New Lamda
and we are going to write an equal design, a space, a dash and a lesbian sign.
And after that, you're going to define a blog.
And in that blog, you are going to write in the code.
You want to be the part of Lambda.
So I will just write a single line saying that this is.
Our first.
Lambda, simple enough for underscored, and you can see that it has run without any kind of error.
Now, one more thing I already told you is that the same way you have to call a function to execute
the code that is in that function, log the same way.
You have to go do it for a lambda as well.
You have to call it this lambda.
Now, how are we going to call it?
We are going to call it using the dot call.
So you have already covered that call and you know how it works.
So all you have to do is that you have to use this variable new lambda here in which you have stored
this lambda right over here.
So we are going to write a new.
Underscore Lamda.
And with this, we are going to write in don't call, that's enough, just write it.
All right, so I guess we have this extra hour here now, it seems perfect Dronett now, and as you
can see that the cord inside the lambda has been executed and saying this is our first lambda.
So as you have seen that defining a lambda one to the good inside it, just like defining a method,
won't run the method.
You need to use the call method for that.
Now, there are other ways to call Alamdar as well.
It's good to know that they exist.
However, I recommend that you stick on with this call function for the clarity purpose, but for the
sake of knowledge, I'll just tell you all of these methods now.
We already have this lamda here.
The first method you can do is that you can just use the dot com function to call it.
Now, the second you can use it that you can drive in DOT and you can write in these brackets, just
remove the skull from here, run this.
And it is also going to run, as you can see, that it says this is our first lambda.
This was the second way to call.
The third way to call is just remove all of these and put the square brackets around this.
And you can see that it is also run.
And it is saying that this is our first lambda.
The fourth function is that you have to write in DOT and triple equal to science and that is also going
to work or on it.
And you can see over here that it says this is our first lambda.
So basically, these are the four ways in you in which you can basically call a lambda function.
But I just suggest you that you stick on with the very first one that was the dot com because it is
something more appropriate and something more programmatic.
Now, Lambda can also take in arguments, which is now, again, something more interesting, and it
is the very same way as functions do.
So for a lambda to receive some kind of arguments, you have to specify those arguments.
That has to be done right away, held up to this equal to Dash and Leavesden sine you have to specify
the round brackets in that brackets.
You have to write in the variable in which you want to store in whatever value is going to be passed
and from the calling area.
So for example, let's say I've got only one parameter.
Let's say X is that parameter.
So I'm going to write an X and the value that is going to be passed in from the calling card is going
to be stored in this X.
And what I want to do over here is that I would just write and put.
Ex.
Starick X. So what it is going to do is that it is going to multiply X with X, that seems, I guess,
good enough.
Now, right here off the skull, you have to pass in the value, let's say three is the value run scored.
And as you can see, that tree has been passed over here.
So that's why three was multiplied with three and nine was generated, which you can see right here
on the Ademir and their output screen.
So that's how basically you can also pass in arguments to a function just the same way you do with a
function.
Now there is one more property of lambdas.
Ohare is that if you pass the wrong number of arguments to a lambda, it will raise an exception, just
like a regular method.
So basically lambda enforce the correct number of arguments.
So for example, you have a lambda to just remove this and we will just do it with the lambda, which
is basically the second way to initialize lambdas.
So we're going to write an equal to Lambda and and the brackets Ohare here we are going to write in
the vertical bars in which we are going to write in the arguments that is going to get receive and we
are going to simply write and puts X Starick X over here again.
And here we know that now this function o'haire that is Landow Wahib basically is expecting on the a
single argument.
So you could just write an error call and do not pass any kind of arguments.
What it is going to generate is error message that says wrong number of arguments given zero, expected
one.
So this is basically the same error which is going to get generated if you are using a function and
you pass in the wrong number of arguments.
So this is also known as the argument error.
So now if you just pass in to over here, run this, it is going to generate four.
So basically, this is in this example, we got to concept.
The first concept was how to initialize Alamdar with the lambda keyword.
So this was the second way to initialize a lambda.
And we also see that how lambda enforce the correct number of arguments.
Now, if you in the next story had been covering the box, you will see that they do not enforce the
correct number of arguments.
But lambdas does do as you have seen.
One more property of Lambda is that Lambda also support the default arguments.
As with function, when we create a lambda function with default argument, it is going to accept those.
And if you don't pass a value, then it is going to treat that that argument basically as the value.
So right here, if you just write an X equal to let's say to.
And we don't pass in any kind of value from here, we just remove this now, as you can see that it
is expecting one argument, but if you don't pass that argument, it is going to treat this as the argument
that it is going to generate the result for you.
But if you pass in the argument, let's say three is the argument on this, then nine is going to be
generated because as the very same with functions, the argument that is passed in from the calling
area has a higher precedence than the default argument.
The default argument is only going to get used when you don't pass in the argument from the coiling
area.
Then it is going to use the default value.
One more thing is that the redone keyword also works exactly the same, how would you would expect it
for a lambdas to work?
So maybe this sounds like a small thing, but if you have ever tried to use the red line inside of a
Baroque, you know, it won't work.
And we will also covered that in detail in the next tutorial as well in the proxy tutorial.
So if you consider this very same example and instead of boats, we just ride in Radogno here, then
you know that basically the return is going to return the result into the area from where it is.
Also, this is where it is going to return the result.
So here we are going to write an X equals aerogel, which means that whatever is going to Raddon is
going to get stored in this X around this code.
And you can see that it has generated no error.
All you have to do now is just write inputs X, run this and you can see that nine has been printed,
which means that Tree three was written right from this lamda here.
It was stored in this variable X, and when we just write and put sex over here, it has printed out
the result, which means that the written statement works very fine with lambdas in the NextRadio.
You will see that when we do the same stuff for the box, it won't work because the written statements
does not work with Prox.
Now, lambdas are also lawyers and what our lawyer is the most simple way to think of a lawyer is a
function that can be stored as a variable and that has a special ability to access other variables local
to the scope it was created in.
Now, what does it mean to be able to access other variables local to the scope the LAMDA was created
in?
Let's take a look at this with the help of an example.
So for that, just initialized a variable right at the top here.
Let's say it is with the variable cume.
So let's say the word over here is hello.
All you have to do is that we don't need any kind of arguments over here now.
We don't need the written statement as well.
We all we need is that we have to write inputs and we have to write in queue will help.
So we don't need this as well.
We don't need this as well.
We don't want to pass in the argument as well.
So if you just run this score, you can see that Halo has been printed, which means that you can use
the variable inside of a lambda and the lambda basically access any kind of variable that is even outside
its block.
But since it is global to lambda, so that's why it can see this variable in whatever is stored in it.
And when all is right, in particular, it gets printed right over here.
Now, as you can see, that this has got branded, but what if I changed the value of Guno?
So if I changed the value of down, downhill and right in oil to a hill and now I just call in it or
call around this and you can see that now what has been printed?
So this means that if I change the value in the variable, the lambda is going to see the new value.
So that's why Lambda Ruby lambdas nondisclosures, because if you change the value, it is going to
get the change value when you call the lambda again.
Now lenders are given a special name that is Jianlian.
Now one of the truly rare things about Lambda is the variety of ways we can call them.
Now, you have already covered the ways in which we can call in the lambda.
But one more thing you need to know about that in booking is that how do you pass an argument using
those methods?
So we will just go to one of them here.
So you know that one way to call is this call method.
The other is to use this ID or this column right over here.
So you'll just remove this from here.
We don't need this.
We don't need this as well.
So we will just pass in a value.
Let's say two is the value you want to pass.
And so right here you are going to use the very same sendek.
You are going to write in the variable and you're going to write in, put sexo here, run this code
and you can see that two has been generated right here.
So this is the basically way in which you can call, you can pass in the value using the other method.
So, for example, you are using the other method that was about the square bracket method you can just
write in to and the rest is going to remain the very same.
Run this and you can see that you have got these two over here so you can use all those method and you
have to use the very same syntax for Lambda right over here.
Then Lambda also have Beldin carrying gerring is a cool technique, used a lot and functional programming.
It's a way to let you create new functions from existing functions.
It's easy to understand when you see it in practice.
So to give you an example of this, let's just remove this from here and we will have a function that
is going to be a lambda and that is going to add two numbers, actually.
So it is going to receive in those two arguments which are going to get added to and be Ordos argument.
And we are going to write in a hill or it's a class B.
So to call this function, you can just write an add call and you can just pass in the two arguments
that are, let's say two and three Ronda's and you can see that you got five will help.
Now where the scoring comes into account.
Abargil, we are going to create one more.
Function a variable that is going to be increment and we are going to create a new function from this
very lambda that has been created, but we are not going to create any more functional here, but we
are going to use the concept of carrying Ohio.
So we are going to write an add, which is going to be the variable in which this lambda is store.
And using this, we are going to create a new function.
We are going to run an ad dot Gary Dot called.
And we are going to pass in a single variable that will help.
So what that is going to do is that then when I scurrying to create more specialized functions, that
is incremental here, it simply is going to add one to any given number.
So if I just run the score, you can see that it hasn't generated any kind of output because I have
not called this function because as you can see, that I have used the Pscholka whatever help.
But this call basically is for this function.
Now we are going to use a call for the increment as well as we are going to write an incremental call
and we are going to pass in the parameter to this, let's say 100, is that there are meter run the
score and you can see that one or one has been generated.
Now, how one one has been generated is basically that this hundred Abargil is added with this function
of a hill.
So down here, if you just write an adult call simply and write in, let's say three, four over here
around the score, it is going to be the sound over here.
Again, this means that now we have got basically two functions.
The first one is using this add variable and the second one is using this increment variable.
And this increment variable function is you is basically using this lambda function right away here.
And it is using this line of here because it is treating this as the first argument.
That is it.
And it is treating this as the second argument B and it is adding those two numbers.
And as you can see, that one one has been generated right on the Adam Brunoro will.
Now lambdas are basically a special kind of proc.
You might have noticed that in all the good examples we have been running so far, whenever I have defined
a lambda function, I got a broken read on that because Ruby implements lambdas as a kind of proc.
So a lot of things I have shown you in this article can be done with Brocks as well as lambdas.
So we are going to cover progs in the next redrill.
And I hope that if you have understood lambdas, then Brocks understanding is going to be much more
easier.
Now we have been using one more Syntex in the very first examples of this very same tutorial, which
was something like this.
So basically when you use this index and such kind of lambdas are known as Snabe lambdas, and when
you use this kind of lambdas, then you can just call it the professional Abdus.
And these are basically the Stube lambdas.
So I hope that you have understood all these concepts.
There were a lot of things about lambdas which we have covered in the story.
I hope you understood that we have covered the very basics way in which you can use lambdas and we have
covered many advanced things about lambdas as well.
So I guess that's it with this trattoria.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next material.