Hey, guys, what's up?
This was an air horn, and I welcome you to another drill on this course on Dhruva.
And as in the introduction of the section, I told you that we will be discussing about operators for
the first type of operators.
We are going to be discussing are the Artomatic operators.
Now, Artomatic operator basically take numeric value as their options and they return a single numeric
value.
The standard Artomatic operators are basically the additions struction, multiplication division and
some others that are listed right on this slide or held.
So on the table, you can see that we have got, I guess, six operators, the first one is additional
operator four, which is plus.
And to use it, you have to specify it between two options then is the subtraction.
Then we have the multiplication, then we have the division, and then we have the modulus and then
we have the exponent sign finally.
So I guess that is a very simple thing, 99 percent of you know about what I'm talking about.
So let's just see some examples and just wrap this topic.
So I'll just move on to the Adam compiler here.
So starting on the very first one is the boat's operator.
So I just write in boats.
And we will specify.
Addition operator.
And then we'll just dive in boats and let's say that we want to add two numbers, so let's say the two
numbers are five and then we specify plus operator and then six.
So that is going to do our job and it is going to perform that.
Even if I just press all plus Arawa here, as you can see that it says addition operator and some for
the two operators has been printed successfully.
Now to talk about the second operator.
We will just move to the next line.
Will just put.
And it is basically the subtraction.
And we will just ride in boats and they will just say, let's say nine minus and then six and pressing
all plus are going to give you this corrected some that it's three.
Then the next one is the multiplication operator.
So just specify multiply Woodhill.
New line thoughts, and let's just say I want to specify five, Starick, six, or Starick is basically
use for multiplication press or Pessah, and it is going to give you the product of the two numbers
then Duduk about the fourth one, that is.
Division lies just divide two numbers that specify that I want to divide, let's say 30 divided by,
let's say six.
So Press or Pessah and it is going to give you the divided some.
And analysts thought.
The next one that is the power operator that is also known as the exponentiation, so we will just write
and.
Power, and then we would just specify boats and let's say I want to give three.
Due to slow press, all plans are and it is going to give you nine, which is three to raise to the
power to.
And then the last one is the modulo operator that is going to basically give you the remainder, so
will just ride in Rimando Hill, ride in boats, and let's say you want to divide the number that does
not divide successfully.
So they just ride in 14, divided by five, and it will have the remainder.
So just press all plus R and four is the remainder after dividing 14 by five.
So basically, he does a very simple concept, you have added two numbers subtracted, multiplied,
divided Diegan, the power rest with respect to some other number, you have also taken the remainder
after dividing the two numbers.
So if you talk about the Ruby division operator, then it has certain things in it, more so let's just
remove all this stuff from here.
But it will help now, as you can see that if you just press all this, ah, this is the divided sum
that has been divided very successfully because it has got no kind of remender with it.
Now, what if you put in.
Some number, let's say, that does not divide successfully, let's say 14 divided by five, as we did
in the previous example.
So now plus all plus hour and it is going to give you two, which means that it has truncated the remainder
part.
So what if you want to, let's say, divide a number, let's say thirty point zero and you want to let's
say divided by, let's say five.
Again, press alters are and it is going to give you the sum in decimal point.
As you can see that this is in decimal point.
This is not in decimal point.
Even then, it is going to consider this one and it is going to give you this answer in floating point
number.
Or you can say the decimal point number.
Now, what if both of these are, let's say, a decimal point, not all plus are, and it is going to
give you the very same answer, that is six point zero, the answer that is in decimal point.
Now, if you want to talk about the unary operators over here, so we will just be using these.
So, for example, you want to type in the last 30 and let's say you want to add it.
Well, let's say minus six, so if you just remove this from help, remove this and just dive in.
Entrances and press orders are added, you can see that it has given you 24, which means that it has
considered it as a negative number.
This as a positive number.
It has put the brackets on these numbers by default and generated the answer for you.
That is twenty four an hour, for example.
This is a negative number.
And let's say this is a positive number, so you don't have to add anything.
Go ahead.
Is going to treat it as by default Kressel plus hour and it is going to give you minus 24.
And now let's say both these numbers are negative press.
All plus are it is going to add these two numbers, add a negative sign at the start and give you minus
36 over here.
Good enough.
Now, for example, you want to, let's say, multiply unary numbers.
For example, I want to add a stereo here.
Let's just shorten this number to five and now Breus all plus are, and as you can see, that it has
generated 30 because minus minus equals to plus and six plus five security.
So the Ruby compiler, the Adam compiler over here is smart enough to understand all the signs and perform
these arithmetic operations for you guys.
So I hope it is very much clear.
It is a very easy concept.
Almost 99 percent of you know what I'm doing.
But I have just done all of these to you in the programming language.
So that's how Artomatic operators are used in Ruby.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.