Hey, guys, what's up?
This is American, and I welcome you to another general on this course, on Dhruva.
And in this story, we are going to see how to raise exceptions manually and how to raise custom exception.
So far in this section, we have discussed how to handle exceptions that are raised by Ruby in the previous
good example.
We have had no control over when to raise an exception or which error type to use.
It has all been decided for us by our editor.
Handling an exception is a reaction to an exception that has already been raised.
So now let's just switch Argyris and explore how you can exert more control when working with exceptions
in a program.
Now, Ruby actually gives you the power to manually raise exception yourself by calling the Colonel
Rescue.
Are this allow you to choose what type of exceptions to raise and even set your own error message if
you do not specify what type of exception to raise and Ruby will default to the runtime error, that
is a subclass of the standard error.
Now, there are a few different index options you may use when working with RES, so to raise an exception,
what you can do is that you can just write and raise.
And you can just ride and type error.
Dot knew, and if you don't specify the error message, then it is going to get generated for the runtime
error and if you just specify a letter, you can just write in something.
Is Rongo held so you can just create your own custom messages as well?
So in this right over here, the exception type will be default to our runtime because none other is
being specified.
So let's just create a program in which what we are going to do is that we are going to raise our own
exceptions so we will create a function.
That would be used to validate the age of a person.
So we are going to name it as well, that age and that age is going to get received in the arguments
of this function and in this function.
What we are going to do is that we are going to raise an exception.
And that exception is going to be.
Invalid age, so it is going to erase the message of invalid age and we are going to set the condition
for the race as well, that unless.
Someone is from, let's say, zero two or let's just say 20 to.
60.
So let's say this is the job criteria for a company who hire someone and the hiring condition for that
company is that the age of the person should be between 20 and 60.
So that's why we are going to write in unless 20, till 60.
And this is a range, you know, and we are going to write and include a question mark.
We are going to write in age.
So whatever age we are going to pass into this function, it is going to check if that is included in
this range over here.
If it is not, it is going to raise an exception that is going to be named as invalid exception.
We're going to just end of a function right over here.
Now, what we are going to do is that we are going to create our biggest block and we are going to write
and begin.
And in the beginning, what we are going to do is that, you know, that we write the code a hill for
which we are expecting some kind of error to just get outputted.
So we are going to just call the function in which we are expecting any kind of error.
So we are going to call validate age.
And right away here we are going to pass in the ID.
So let's say I just pass in 61.
As you can see that it is not a part of the range.
So it is going to raise an exception and whatever exception is going to get raised over here is basically
going to get caught right in this rescue block.
We are going to specify.
So we are going to just write in as runtime.
Error, and we will just specify object for that as well.
And when you now write in votes.
IDOT.
Message, then what message is going to get printed is basically this message which we have raised when
this condition is not met.
So just and the statement of him now, if you just run the school, you can see that it has generated
the message that says invalid message.
Now, if you just specify some valid age, let's say 40, which is a part of that range, so you can
see nothing happened because this could run perfectly.
No kind of exception was raised with this code, which is a function which has been called right over
here.
This condition was check this exception was not raised because this condition was true or help.
So if this condition is false, you have seen that when I specified the age to be one, it has generated
the message.
It has stored it in that object and it is printed me the message as well.
So here we have placed the valeted age method in the big and rescue blog.
If an invalid age is passed into the method, a runtime error with error message invalidated will be
raised and the rescue clause of our big and rescue blog will be executed.
So that's how in Ruby you can raise exceptions manually.
So now moving towards the second part of this tutorial that deals with resetting custom exceptions.
Now, in addition to providing an exception classes, Ruby, allow us the flexibility to create our
own custom exception classes as well.
So, for example, you can just create validate each error class and you can just include it in the
standard error by just using the concept of inheritance.
So for that, what you can do is that you can just write in something like.
Gelhaus.
Well, he did.
EJ.
Error, so here we are creating a class and we are going to just write in the less than sign and we
are going to write and.
Standard error, oakhill.
So this means that basically we are creating inheritance Tanigawa here, so this means that this is
now a child class or you can say the descendant of the standard atter class.
So you can notice O'Haire that are custom, exception, class valeted.
Each error is a subclass of an existing exception.
This means that the valeted H error has access to all the build an exception object behaviour's ruby
prewired, which include the exception message which you have covered and the exception backtrace which
you also have covered.
So as discussed earlier in this section, you should always avoid masking exception from the exception
clause itself.
And there are system level exception.
Clauses concerning this exception is dangerous and will suppress very serious problems in your program.
So don't do it.
Most often you will want to inherit from the standard error class.
Now, when using a custom exception class, you can be specific about the error of your program encountered
by giving the class a very descriptive name.
Doing so mean it in debugging.
So let's alter our this example which we have already cover and use more descriptive custom exception
class.
So we are going to place this over here at the very top over here because our code is not going to see
this class over here and it is not going to treat this as the subclass of standard error or this very
good because this was at the top.
This is at the bottom.
So this has to be at the top so that the entire code can see it, because, as you know, that's sequential
order of execution is followed in Ruby programs.
So right to here, what changes we have to make is that in place of this, what we are going to write
in, we are going to write in the name of the class.
We are going to write and validate H atter place a comma.
And after that we are going to specify the message that is invalidated.
Just move it a bit right over here.
So we are going to write invalidate each error that is the name of the class, or you can say the name
of the error that is going to get generated and we are going to specify the message which we want to
get generated whenever this error is going to get generated.
And we have to specify the condition.
And now O'Haire, the messages, the changes we are going to do is that we are going to now be very
specific because runtime error is something that is very, very, very general.
But now we are going to get very specific and we are going to for example, if you just talk about standard
error and you are talking about division by zero, then that is something that is general.
But if you talk about a rescue blog that is going to just only gatch the zero división error, then
that is something that is specific.
And the reason behind just adding this concept of raising custom exceptions is to become is to just
move on from general concept towards the specific thing.
So we are going to write and validate, etc. we held.
And just run the school to see if any kind of error is there is none, let's just change this age to
something that is not a part of the range.
Let's just say it's sixty one.
Run this code and you can see that it has invalidated age.
So as demonstrated in this example, you can raise and handle custom exceptions, just like any build
an exception that truly provides.
So basically now this validate age error is a descendant of the standard error clause and it is also
a part of the exception clause since the standard error is a subclass of the exception clause.
So now you can become a more specific rather than being so general.
So I guess that's it.
We have covered how to raise exceptions manually and outraise how to make custom exceptions as well.
So I guess that's it with this section.
That's it.
With exceptions.
And I will see you guys in the next section with a more interesting topic.
So thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next section.