Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to an editorial on this course on Ruby.
And in this story, we are going to cover the second part of class as an object.
So in this tutorial, what we are going to do is that we are going to cover about class methods.
We are going to cover about class variables.
We are going to cover about constants.
And we are going to learn more about the self object, which we have used in the previous tutorial of
classes and objects, part one.
So so far, all the methods we have created were basically the instance method.
That is, there are methods that perform to an instance or object of the class.
Now there are also the class level methods that are known as the class method.
Now class methods are the methods we can call directly on the class itself without having to instantiate
any object.
You have not implemented any class method at this point, so let's do that now.
So when defining a class matter, we pretend the method name with the reserved word that is s a dot.
So to do it, what you are going to do is that you are going to just write in the name and you're going
to write in self.
Dodd and let's say the name of the class is, let's say X, and what are you going to do in this is
that you are going to nod this right over here and.
Right.
And you are going to just.
And I am.
X and you're going to just end this function, right?
So if you want to call this class method what you are, you are going to do is that you are going to
use the class name and you're going to write in the name of this function of a house.
So we will just remove this from here, define our class.
That was class, human and.
Right.
Well, here we are going to pass this.
We are going to end this war here and write down here.
What we are going to do is that we are going to write and.
Human dot x run this code and you can see that you have got no kind of errors now to print out what
is going on since this rally is going to get right down to a hair just right.
And put human dot x and you can see that it says I am X..
So why do we need a class method for this?
Now, this example is a little contrived, but class methods are where we put functionality that does
not pertain to individual objects.
Object contains states.
And if we have a method does that does not need to deal with states, then we can just use a class method
like our very simple example we have seen right over here.
So we will take a look at a more useful example in the future to Dalt.
That will be a part of this section.
So moving on to the second part of this tutorial that deals with class variables.
Now, just as instance, variable captures information related to specific instances of class, we can
create variables for an entire class that are appropriately named as the class variables, not class
variables are created using to add the symbols and to create a class symbol that is going to belong
to a class method that is going to view that variable.
Where you are going to do is that you can just create the very same class which you have that is human.
And what you are going to do is that you are going to define the constructor functions.
We are going to write and initialize.
And in here, we are going to initialize our numbers, so we are going to write in double at the rate,
which means that this is now going to be a class variable and we are going to write in number.
Of.
Humans plus equal to one, so whenever this class object is going to get created, this number of humans
variable that is now basically a class variable, it is going to get incremented by one.
Finally, we have to end this function and we also have to initialize this right here inside this class,
but outside these initialize function.
So we going derive at the rate, at the rate, which means that the initialization of a class variable
and we are going to write an.
Number of humans equal to zero.
Now, down here, what you are going to do is that you are going to create one more function.
That is going to be using the Selke, which means that this is a class method, so we are going to write
in self doubt total.
Number of.
Humans and right here, what we are going to do is that we are going to ride in at the rate of a dread.
Number of humans, so this means that it is going to return the number of humans to the place from where
this function is going to get called, and what you're going to do finally is that you're going to go
outside this class, just remove this stuff from here and you're going to write inputs.
Human Dawid.
Total number of humans, so if you know just one, the school, you can see that it has generated zero
because for now, no kind of object has been created.
And when no object has been created, this means that the initialize function has not been called.
And this Ohare is basically printing this value, which you have initialized right to here.
That is right over here.
It is being written right over here and it's getting output due to the spots we have placed right over
here.
Now we are going to create two objects.
So let's say the first object is human one, and that is equal to human dot new.
And let's say we create one more object human to that is going to equal to human dot knew we are going
to just replace this with equal to sign.
Now, since we have initialized to object, this means that this initialize function has been called
twice.
So if you just now repeat this line over here, just copy this base, this over here and now run this
code.
Oh, this is not what we expect.
This means that the initialize function.
Yes, I guess I missed an area here.
My bad.
Now run this code and you can see that you have got this two over here.
So we have basically a class variable that is called as Aderet Aderet number of humans, which we initialized
to zero.
Then in our constructor function, we increment that number by one.
Now remember that initialize function gets called every time you instantiate an object, we add the
new method.
This also demonstrated that we can access class variables from within an instance method.
Finally, we just return the value of the class variable in the class method.
That was the total number of humans.
Now this is an example of using a class variable and a class method to keep track of the class level
detail that pertains only to the class and not the individual objects.
So then comes the concept of constants that are related with classes and objects.
So when creating classes, there may also be certain variables that you never want to change.
Now you can do this by creating what are called constants.
You define a constant by using an uppercase letter at the beginning of the variable name, while technically
constant, just need to begin with a capital letter.
Most grubbiest will make the entire variable as the upper case, and that is going to what is called
a constant in Ruby.
So if you use something different Abargil so we will just remove this stuff from here.
And we will remove this stuff from here as well, and right here we are going to specify age, so we
are going to just write in human underscore age and we are going to make it equal to twenty five, let's
say, and we are going to use the attribute accessor.
This means that we are the we are setting the getter and setter methods.
So right here, let's say it has two attributes, that is name and then it says age.
So we are going to limit human age, it is going to be age and then you are going to define the constructor
function that is initialized.
I hope I've spelled it correctly this time and it is going to receive into arguments.
First is the name, second is the age.
Then right here you are going to use the self object because you know that if you don't, then it is
going to treat it as local variables, which is exactly what you don't want.
So you're going to write and s dot name equal to an.
And you are going to ride and self doubt age equal to a and now where you are going to do is that you
are going to ride in a esoteric.
Human underscore.
So this variable over here is going to be constant, so we are going to just minimize it to a small
number since it is going to get multiplied and that is going to form a large number.
So that's why it needs to get minimized.
So that is going to be h equal to we missed and equal to as well.
And now we are going to end.
The constructor function, the initialize function, sorry, and downhere, what you're going to do
is that you are going to end your class as well.
That has already been ended.
Now, what you're going to do is that you're going to write in, John, equal to.
Human don't know, and you're going to pass in to values, the first one is going to be the name and
the second one is going to be the H.
Just press enter and just ride in boats, John Dot H Ronda's God and you can see that it says dooby
dooby dooby dooby dooby dooby, which is I guess not what we wanted.
And the reason behind this is that we have quoted this in string because what hearing is going on,
I guess this concept should also be explained now.
Inheritance, we are passing this as a number and right over here we are just multiplying this by five.
So this 25 is going to get repeat five times.
So I guess this was also an interesting concept.
So you can see that twenty five has been printed five times.
But we don't want this.
We just want twenty five right over here.
So we would just remove this from here and we will write twenty five right over here in as an integer.
Run this now and you can see that it is twenty one.
Now you must be thinking that John was just I guess 25 years old back in the previous tutorial and now
he's one twenty five.
So let's just make John a bit young.
So that's just right in five O'Haire and that's twenty five now.
John seems morea.
So how do we use the constant that was human age to calculate the age and human errors were when we
created the object.
That was basically John Oakhill.
Now note that we use the setter methods in the initialize method to initialize the Aderet name and at
the rate each instance variable given to us by the attribute accessor method, we then use the age getter
method to retrieve the value from the object.
Now the human age is a variable that will never change for any reason.
So we use that as a constant.
It is possible to reassign a new world to a constant, but Ruby will throw a warning.
So if you just write in, let's say.
Human age equal to that same sex run good, you can see that it has changed the value.
Now, John Edge is 30, but it has generated a warning that says one already initialised constant previous
definition of human age was here.
So that's why you should not be doing this, because it is a constant you can change the value.
But as you have seen that it has generated the warning message for you, then you have to underscore
this method, which you have been covering a lot in the past as well.
Now, the two instance method basically comes line into every class in Ruby, and you have already covered
it with every glass in Ruby in the previous tutorial.
In fact, we have been using it all along.
For example, suppose we have the same human glass from this example we are covering and a John object.
What you can do is that if you just write an.
Just remove this from here, run this code and you can see that you have got a very strange tangle here.
Now, what's happening here is that the puts method automatically called the to underscore s on its
argument, which in this case is the John's object, which you are printing right here.
In other words, the ports, John, is equivalent to ports John Doe.
To underscore as the reason we get this particular output lies within the to underscore smattered in
Dubai by default, the two underscore smattered, retains the name of the objects glass and an engorging
of the object idee.
So this was the name of the object sorry, the glass.
And then it is basically some kind of encoding of the object itself.
Now you have to know the way here that the puts method call to underscore.
As for any argument, that is not an area for an area.
It writes on separate lines.
The result of calling to underscore is on each element of the array.
Now does this weekend at a custom to underscore as method to our human class or writing the default
to underscore as that comes on with a ruby.
So we will just make a change right in this class.
We are going to add a function that is to underscore as that is basically going to override the custom
or you can say the default to underscore this method.
So right here, we are going to write in this.
Sorry, the name is Antipollution, and you can just write a name.
And he is you can just ride in this and you can ride in years old just the longer there's a bed so you
can see what's going on.
Yes, I guess that's much more visible now.
So let's try this court again, run this.
All right, we've got an area that is expecting out of it, but yes, that is my very common mistake.
I do a lot more on this now, and you can see that it says the name is John and he is years old.
Why have not it printed Eje now?
It will print.
Now it says he is 25 years old.
This five four had this.
The very same stuff is being created.
But the difference over here is that now in place of what's John over here, which it should have just
printed out an encoded ID as well as the name of the class.
Now in place of that, what we have get is that we have overridden the method.
Now, as you can see, that we did not have called the to underscore estimated to here.
But if you just as I told you before, that if you just write and put John over here by default, you
are actually calling this thing over here.
If you now are underscored, you can see that the output is going to be the very same.
But if you just remove this from here, the output is still going to be the same because this two underscore
this method is basically present by default over here and that is going to get output it by default.
So there is another method that is called as B that is very similar to the Put's method, except it
does not call the two underscore s on its argument.
It calls another building Ruby instant method that scholars inspect.
Now, the inspect method is very helpful for debugging purposes, so we don't want to overwrite it.
So if you just remove this UTSA from here, run DeJohn, run this and you can see that it has printed
out a lot of things and that is basically what is used for debugging purposes and that is basically
calling inspect method by default.
So we don't want to inspect method to get a word in because it is a very useful method.
Now this output implies that Björn is equivalent to bots John Dot inspect.
Now, besides being called automatically when using boats, another important attribute of the two underscore
as method is that it is also automatically called in string interpolation.
Now, we have seen this before when using integers or errors in the string interpolation.
So let's just remove this from here.
And for example, you have an area that is one, two and three.
And if you just write in votes AWOL here score, you can see that it is printed out the area for you.
But if you use the string interpolation concept of a hill, for example, if I just remove this from
here and I just write and put.
The.
Idabelle are.
Arie.
Does not.
Conten.
Hashtag.
X, not X, is what is going to get passed in, so you can just define it right over here.
You can just write an X equals five, since we cannot parse it, since we are not using any kind of
functions over here.
So if you just now run this code, it says the one, two, three area does not contain five.
Now, here are the do underscore X method is automatically called on the area hateable our area object,
which is right or here.
And it is also going to get passed on the X integer object.
I repeat, if you hear that to underscore this method is automatically called on the air, the blast
area object as well as the X into your object.
We will see if we can include our John object and a string interpolation.
So you can just use the very same concept and you can just print out John and you can just print out
is it for example, if I just press control that several times so that my previous score is visible?
Yes, right over here it is.
And what you can do is that if you just write and.
It's and you just ride in quotation marks and you just write and the name of the object that is John
and you just run the score, you can see that it says the name is John and he's 25 years old.
Now, I guess the reason behind this is there's just remove this for now and now run this and you can
see that it has not worked on it.
Now, in summary, the two underscore is that it is also automatically called on the object.
When we use it with bots or when we use it would strengthen the position.
This fact may seem trivial at the moment, but knowing when to underscore, as method is called, it
will help us understand how to read and write the better object oriented called.
So finally, moving on to the final part of this tutorial that is about the self object, now we have
talk about the self earlier, but let's try to dive a little deeper so you can understand exactly what
self is and how to understand what it is.
Referencing to the self can refer to different things that depend on where it is used, for example.
So far we have seen two clear use cases for self.
The first one is that you have to use self and calling the CETRA methods from within the class.
In our earlier example, we showed that self was necessary in order for our change and for method to
work properly, we had to yourself to allow Ruby to disambiguate between initializing a local variable
and calling a central method.
And when we use the self method, it was when our output was generated and then our ED was not recognizing
that name, height and weight, not as a local variables, but as a setter method variables.
And it was just printing out of our output.
The second use case is that you can use self or class method definition.
So let's play around with self to see why the above two rules are going to work.
So just remove this from here.
And we are going to have our attribute.
Accessor, and that is going to now have three variables that were basically the part of previous tutorial
that were name, height and finally weight.
And down here, you are going to have the initialise function as well, that is going to receive entry
arguments and edge and W, not W and in this way you're going to ride and you're going to ride and so
dot name equal to and and you're going to ride and self-taught.
Height equal to edge, and you're going to ride and so self-taught with equal to W and you are going
to finally end this initialize function and down here you are going to have one more function.
That was also a part of the previous tutorial.
That was the change in full function and the change in function also received in three arguments that
were an Etch W.
And in this function, what we were doing basically is that we were doing this stuff over here, so
we will just copy it to save a time and we will just to try to help.
So it is about maybe going to end up not hijikata edge and subducted equal to W..
And finally, what we are going to do is that we are going to and this change in function as well.
Finally, we are going to have our display functions.
We are going to write in self sorry def display and in the display function.
What we are going to do is that we are going to use interpolation this time.
So we are going to write and depletion and we are going to write and self dot name.
We are going to ride in Whit's.
Get interpellation.
We are going to ride and self-taught wait.
And is.
So, Dr. Height.
Doll, good enough.
Let's just move it over here.
So it says whatever a name.
So let's say the name is John.
So it is going to print at John.
It's, let's say 30 gidgee and it's 12 feet tall.
So this is what we want to print on.
Let's just end this, because this is the most common error we often encounter.
So this time we will not have that error because we have just removed the.
Just added this a.
Now, before we go on with the calling card, let's say we have one more function that is less over
here and in this function X, what we are going to do is that we are going to just write in self or
help just end this function of a here and now.
What we are going to do right down here is that.
We are going to create the objects, we are going to write in, John, equal to.
Human dog knew and the parameters we are going to pass, the three values this is expecting, so we
are going to write and John, we are going to write and the height of John.
So that is 12.
Inches.
And finally, we are going to write in the vein of John, that is, let's say 30 Kaiji.
So if you now just run the scored.
You can see that it has worked perfectly.
Now, what you need to do is that you if you just write in the you just write in John Dot Axler here,
you just run this code.
You can see that you have got a very different thing, your code, the name of the class than you have
got the object ID.
Then you have got the inspection of a hair that says name to John height equals 12 inches and we're
equal to thirty 30.
Now, the reason behind this is that we are actually calling this self right from here.
So that is something that is very interesting from within the class now, from within the class, when
an instance method uses the self, it is referencing the calling object.
In this case, that is the Johns object.
Now, therefore, from within the change in method calling self dart name acts the same as calling John
Daudt name from outside the class.
You can't call John Dort name inside the class Tolson's.
It is not in the school.
Now we understand why using the self to call instance method from within the class works the way it
does now.
The other place we use self is when we are defining class methods.
So I hope you understood.
So I will just remove this from here and now we will see that how the self is going to work when we
are dealing with class method.
So let's say you have the same class that as the human class.
And in this class, what you're going to do is that you are going to define a function that is going
to be defined by itself.
So you're going to write in self taught, let's say, x sohel.
And you are going to simply end dysfunction, this function will have nothing just and the glass as
well.
Now when selfies pretended to a method definition, it is basically what we are doing is that we are
defining a class method.
So we talked about this earlier in our human class method example.
We defined a class method that was called a self doubt, total number of humans.
So that method return the value of the class variable that was number of humans.
So how this was possible.
So to have a closer look at that, what you can do is that you can just write an.
Both so for here.
And what you can do is that you can just go create an instance for this class, let's say, John.
Equal to human, don't you just run the score and you can see that you have got the name of the class
so you can test it in the RV just by passing the above code into the RV and typing in human test.
You can see that using self inside a class, but outside an instant method refers to the class itself,
as you can see right here on the bottom runner.
Therefore, a method definition prefixed with self is the same as defining the method on the class that
is def self, not the method name that is equivalent to self.
Human dot, the name of the method.
That's why it is called as a class method, it's actually being defined on the class.
To be clear, from within a class, there are two conditions.
The first is self inside of an instance method reference references the instance object that called
the method that is the calling object, therefore self doubt, which is the same as John Godwit in our
previous example.
The second scenario is that south, outside of an instance method, references the class and can be
used to define class matters.
Therefore, def self not name is the same as Def Human Dawid name and the name of the function.
In our example, we can see that self is a way of being explicit about whatever program is referencing
and what our intentions are as far as behavior itself changes, depending on the scope it is used.
And so pay attention to see if you are inside an instance, method or not.
Self is a tricky concept to grasp in the beginning, but the more often you see its use, the more you
will understand object oriented programming.
If the explanations does not make any kind of sense, just memorize the two rules I have explained.
I will just revise that for you.
The first rule is that if you are inside an instance method and self is basically inside an instance
method that is basically referencing the instance that is called on the method that is the calling object.
The second rule is that self outside of an instance method references the class and can be used to define
class method.
So to summarize, this, basically, class is an object, particleboard, a lot of information about
classis object and object oriented programming, but you are becoming much more proficient in the language.
So you are able to digest more and process more complicated material.
Now you're growing as a ruby programming.
This is where things finally starts to get fun.
So in this tutorials, what we have heard is that we have seen how to initialize object with a new method.
For instance, variable keep track of an object, started learning how to attribute methods, generate
the getters and setters using instanced method to perform operation on our objects.
Then we have covered using class methods to perform operation at the class level.
Then we have seen assigning class variables to relate specifically to our class than we have seen assigning
constants that never change to perform operations in our classes.
Then we have seen how the two underscore as method is used and that we have been using it implicitly
all along.
And then finally we have seen how and when to use s.
So if you are you have never seen before this, these two tutorials should have been a doozy.
But so we need a lot of practice to truly understand it.
Don't skip anything.
Object oriented programming is a very important piece of fundamental knowledge that you will need to
truly understand ruby codes and frameworks like Ruby on rails.
So I will just applaud exercise for you, too, as well, so that you can just knowledge it into your
brain and fingers and you can see that how you are going to implement that.
And in the exercise of you have got any problems, you can feel free to ask and I'll be more than happy
to help you out.
So I guess that's it with the glasses and object parts and the next tutorial, you can start on with
the concepts that are related with object oriented program that are in that inheritance and polymorphism
type of things.
So that's a good class as an object.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you guys in the next Dorio.