Hey, guys, what's up?
This is American, and I welcome you to another tutorial on discourse on Ruby and in this story.
And we are going to have a comparison of three key words, which you can use with module's.
The first one is include and we are going to talk about extent.
And then finally, we are going to talk about prepend.
Now, you already have scored one of them.
That is the include.
So basically, Ruby provides a feature to attach a specific behavior or method in the class using these
three key words.
If we include a class with a module, it means we are bringing in the modules method and instanced method.
If we extend a class with a module method, it means we are adding the matters which are added to class
itself and are available at class level three pending the module using the prepend is similar to the
include one.
So let's start on would include.
You are going to have one example and we are going to try all of these three or three key words with
that.
So let's say you have a module that is named as a wish, and in that module you are going to have a
function, hello and in that helo function, what you're going to simply print is that you're going
to write inputs.
Hello.
Simple as that.
And just after that, you can just add this statement over here and this module as well.
And now what you're going to do is that you are going to create a class Aubagio that is going to be
a person because a person is going to watch someone hello.
And right down here, you are going to use the first one that is included.
So you're going to write and include Wesch.
And in this class, you're also going to have one more function that is going to be the readings function.
And in that greetings function, you are going to just have someone with a greeting that is going to
be, for instance, let's say have a nice day.
Simple enough.
Let's just end this and this will help.
So in this example, basically, the wish is included in the clause, if you look at the ancestry change
of this dispersant laws, we can simply see that the module is present between the class and its ancestors
so we can call methods defined in the class instances.
So what you will do is that you will create an object and using that object, you're going to just write
in person.
You are now using this object.
You are going to write an.
Hello, Oakhill.
So as you have covered only about include, you know that this function is basically an instance of
this class.
So if you just run this code, it is going to print on Hello, Writable Hill.
Now, if you talk about extend that in contrast to the include, including a module using extend does
not in insert the module in the ancestral chain due to which we cannot call the module method from declasse
instances.
Instead, Ruby inserts the module in the Singleton class of the person.
The Singleton class is a class where the matter only for the specific class are defined, so the methods
defined in the class are not going to get accessible to any other class, for instance.
So in place of this, we would just write in, let's say, extend, and as a total unit now, it is
not going to be a part of the ancestral change, which is the function.
Hello.
So now if you just have this sort of a hill and if you just, let's say, try to run it, you can see
that you have got an error that says undefined method call for this and that is named as no method error.
And the reason behind this error is the very same, as I told you, because this extent is not going
to.
Insert the module in the incestuous chain due to which one we call it the module method on the glass
instances, they are going to just generate an error message.
Then comes the third keyword we are going to have in this tutorial as the prepend keyword.
Now, as I told you, that it is also similar to the include, except that instead of inserting the
module between the class and its superclass in the chain, it will insert the module to the bottom,
which means before its class itself.
When we call a method, for instance, it will look into the module method even before looking to its
class.
So if you have this very same example and you just write and.
Prepend of a hill.
And you have all this stuff over here now, if you just run this code, you're going to see that you
have got this Hello Hill.
This is when the object calls the hello method.
It initially searched you wish in the interest to change and it is going to print hello for you right
over here.
So this is what is basically the difference between the three keywords.
The prepend and include are almost the same, whereas is the extend one is basically something that
deals with the Singleton class and does not deal with the ancestral chain.
So I hope you have understood all of these three and I hope you've also understood the difference between
them.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you guys later.