Hey, guys, what's up?
This is American, and I welcome you to another Dooralong discourse on Ruby.
And in this territory, we are going to be covering two functions that can be applied on hashas.
The first one is the key and the second function is the Haski.
Now starting on with the first function, that is the key function.
Now it is a hash class method with checks whether the key corresponding to the value is present or not.
And if you talk about the syntax of this, it is very simple.
You have to just write in hash.
Dokki a question mark, which means that you want to ask the compiler a question that whether a key
exists in a certain thing or not, which is going to be a hash in this case, and then and the parameters
you have to write in the Q, which you want to check whether it exists for the corresponding value or
not.
The second function we are going to cover in this tutorial is the Haski function and the Haski function.
Also check if a certain key is present in a function or not.
And it has also a very simple syntax.
You have to write in the hash for what you want to check it.
Buggy's president donadio to write in the Haski and then in the specific hash you want to check, which
is not present or which key is present.
You have to write it as a parameter, do this function.
So let's see some examples of how this works, actually.
So you have already got three hashes out here.
You've got a variable, a variable, B, a variable.
C the variable.
It contains two key value bearers, the variable B contains a single key value pair and the variable
C contained three key value pairs.
Now, starting on with the first function we are going to cover in this tutorial is the key function.
So what are you going to write in that you are going to check if for a corresponding value key exist
or not?
So you're going to write inputs.
You're going to ride and hash key from interpellation is going to be used and you're going to ride in
a dart key question mark and the parameters you are going to ride in the queue, which you want to check.
So, for example, for air, you want to check if this exist or not.
You can just ride in a hill and you can just run the score and it is going to return either true or
false.
So for this case, since this guy is present in this variable air, so that's why it has returned.
True.
So, for example, for the second one, you can just ride and hash.
A key from.
Interpellation is again going to be using are you going to try and be Dorcy Questionmark and for example,
do you want to check if B exist in this or not?
Run this code and it is going to return false because V, which is Aqeel here, is not a part of this,
because here we are referencing to keys and for the first case that it was present and the second case,
key GB is not present as a part of this variable.
B So that's why this has returned.
True.
And this O'Haire as return false and similar, you can just apply it for this function as well.
Now the second function we are going to cover in this tutorial is the housekeeping.
And as I told you about this Haski function that also checks a certain key exist in a pair of key value
pairs are not.
Now, in the first tutorial, you have seen the way of how you can initialize a key value pair and that
you have enclosed the value in quotation marks, but not this.
In the second case, you have enclose the key in quotation marks, but not this.
There is a third way to initialize this hash o'haire in which you can just write in a colon and you
can just write in that.
You can just write in the.
Calling 200, so this is basically the third way of how you can initialize a key value pair for a hash
in Ruby so you can just change all of these Hundert and you can just remove this as well.
You can just write in a hundred.
Be 200 and you can just ride in the value of your seats, 300, as it was in the previous case.
So this is basically the third way of how you can initialize hashes in Ruby.
But if you run this Iraqi for this and for example, this condition number two is again true as well.
So apparently this condition seems true.
But if you just run this code, you can see that board, the values are false.
Now, the reason behind this is that whenever you are using the key or the ASCII function, then it
does not accept this syntax.
But for example, which was, for example, if you just consider the case when we were covering our
first tutorial, then for that we were using, let's say for a you can just write and Airaud each.
Do for a key value pair.
You can just ride in boats.
Hashtag.
Is interpellation value, and you can just write an of a comment this out for a little while.
Run the school and you can see that it run perfectly fine is Hundert B is 200.
So this means that it is accepting this syntax.
But if we just run it for this O'Haire, that is the key function.
Run this code.
You can see that it has generated false walls, which means that this is not accepting this as a key
for this function.
Moreover, if you use the Haski function Aubagio that is has and a squawky.
Has underscored Kiowa Hill, let's just use as underscore your here as well and has in the Skalkaho
hair as well or underscored and for that it is again going to generate false and false.
So this means that the key and the hash function does not accept the syntax, which we have changed
right away.
But this is a syntax basically, which can be used to write in the values for hashes.
So we will just remove this from here and we will change it to the previous syntax over here.
That is a download then be do on that and you have to change this as well.
You've tried in a equal arrow, equal arrow as well, and then this as well.
This as well.
The value for me.
Equalized and signed, and finally, the value for the sea equal has been signed.
Now, if you just run the score, you can see that it has generated true for both the cases.
If you just write and let's say Bohle, which is going to generate falls, apparently, and it does
as well, it generated falls.
So to use the key and the Haski function, you have to notice in mind that you have to also always use
this index to initialize hashes in Ruby.
If you use the other syntax, which we just use, you have seen that generated false false, which means
that it was not accepting this ASCII.
So when you searched for this in the previous index, it return false when you search for B, the previous
index at return false.
But in this case, this is going to return.
True.
And this is going to return false.
So that's how basically the key and the Haski function works and for which index it works.
You have also seen that.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next Dorio.