Hey, guys, what's up?
This is American, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Ruby and in this story,
and we are going to see how to open and close and existing files in the previous tutorial.
We already have created two files.
The husband was violent and the second one was files.
So in this story, we are going to see how we are going to open and then how we are going to close those
files, which we have already created.
So if you talk about the syntax of how to open a file that is right here, you have to write and file
equal to file dot open and you have to write in the name of the file you want to open.
And then comes how to close a file that is as simple as file dot closed and the file is going to get
closed.
So let me just show you how to implement both this practically.
So we will want to add them.
And you can see that we have already created these two files.
So here we are going to do is that we are going to create a variable, let's say we are, and that is
what is going to contain the file.
So we are going to write and file.
Door open and here we are going to specify the name of the file.
So let's say we want to open this first file.
We are going to write in file dot the 60.
We will run the school and the school has run successfully, which means now this file is open in the
background.
So you must be thinking that the file has not popped up because this is what is not going to happen.
What is going on that the file is now open in background and in the NextRadio will when we will be seeing
how to read and write to a file, you can see that how we can just open a file and it will be open in
the background.
We will just added that file.
And when I just go into the documents folder and open that file, you will see that whatever text we
have written are written over here is going to be shown on the file of what they are.
So the file is not going to pop up.
It is going to just open in the background.
So now when this command gets executed, your file has been opened.
Now what you can do is using this variable.
You can just close the file as well.
So you can just write in variable dot, close around this code.
And now the file has been closed successfully.
So whenever you have to perform the reading and writing operation, you have to do it right over here.
If you want to perform the reading, you have to do it over here.
And if you want to perform the writing, you have to do it right over here.
This has to be hash tags for comments.
So this is a part of I guess the next tutorials will be the next tutorial, we are going to see how
to read and write a file.
And if you don't open a file and try to perform the reading or writing operation, it is going to generate
an error and tell you that you have tried to read or write to a file which is not opened.
And then why is this O'Haire important?
Why is it so important to close a file?
Because the file is going to be opened in the background.
It is going to for sure occupy some space or to free up that space and to allow that space to be used
by some other useful operations.
You have to close the file so that the space becomes free.
So that's like closing a file is very important after you have opened it, because apparently it doesn't
show up, because apparently the things that are showing up, you can just simply go on to the right
bar and you can just click this gross error and you can just close this.
But if you don't have something that is showing up and is running in the background and occupying some
space, then it is a must thing that whenever you have open this, you have to close this as well.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial.
In the next iteration, we are going to see how to read and write to a file.
So stay tuned for that.
Thank you so much for now and I'll see you guys in the next rhetorical.