Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Dhruva.
And in this story, we are going to be covering the difference between the equal operator and EQR.
Now, you have covered both of these operators in the previous tutorials, but in this tutorial, we
will strictly be talking about the difference between the equal operator and the equal operator.
Now, the big nearest to Ruby are often confused by the fact that object class defined three methods
that are related to equality.
The first one is this equal operator, the second one is the equal operator and the third one is the
equal you operator, which you have also covered in the previous tutorials.
Not of all of these three, the one that is the most easier to describe.
Is this equal you a operator.
And what it do is that it implement what's commonly known as a reference equal equality check, not
the method that is equal.
It only returns true if its receiver and what is the receiver that is basically the object upon which
the method was in court.
And the parameter, the object, which we are referring to are the same object.
Now, for example, we have, let's say X, and that is equal to, let's say, a variable that is let's
say.
ABC and then let's see what we have, is that the right way, equal to, let's say, X?
And then what we want is that we want to check if both of these are now equal or not.
So we will write in that x DOD equal question mark and we will write and why what we specify as a possible
here or underscored.
And as you can see, that it has returned true.
Not both the double equal operator and this equal el operator, it implements the value quality check.
They are not interested in whether two variables point to the same object in memory, but it checks
whether two objects are equal in terms of their values or not.
For instance, let's say the table and table might very well be two completely different string objects,
but they are quite obviously the same as far as their value is concerned.
So let's say if we have.
Let's say you want to have, let's say ABC and we want to check it with, let's say, the equal operator.
I want to check if it is equal to ABC or not, and we will specify Oportunidad.
Run this and it is going to actually return false to us then if you.
Youth sports.
And let's say you want to check if ABC.
Equal, equal to ABC, so the.
And as you can see, that it has returned true now apply the same for the third operator that is ABC
Dot, EQM, Al Questionmark and.
Right.
And ABC are on the court and it also return.
True.
Now, what's not immediately obvious is why are there two different matter that seems to be doing exactly
the same thing?
Now, the answer is very simple.
The equal is meant to be used as a strict version of double equal.
If there is a need for such a strict version that is equal.
Most prominent usage is probably probably in the hash class where it's need to test the test member
for equality, knowing the object class equal that it is synonym with the equal operator.
Most subclasses continue this tradition, but there are a few classes that provide a different implementation
for equal numeric types.
For example, perform type converging across equal but not across equal.
So, for example, if you just remove this from here and use numeric classes of a hill instead of just
simple strings, then for example, we have, let's say, one equal equal to one run the underscored
and it is going to return.
True.
Then apply one dot equal on numeric operators.
Let's add one dot equal.
And right in one run, this code and it is again going to return, true, then you have codes one dot
you you will and write in one run this code and it is again going to return.
True.
And as you can see clearly from this example, that equal four in the glasses require both object to
be instances of the same class, apart from having equal values to return to.
Now.
Hopefully, I have managed to make the difference between equal operator and a clear so that some fairly
esoteric matter that's not totally understood by even some fairly experienced Hruby programmers.
That is the difference between the operator and the operator that how it works with the numeric classes
and how it works with the strengths.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.