Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another drill on this course on Ruby.
And in this video, we are going to cover some concepts that are related to object oriented programming.
And in this tutorial specifically, we are going to talk about inheritance in very detail.
Now, in the previous year, we talked briefly about inheritance.
And inheritance is when a class inherits behavior from another class.
The class that is inheriting behavior is called the subclass, and the class inherits from is called
the superclass.
Now, we can use inheritance as a way to extract common behavior from from classes that share that behavior
and move it to super classes.
This let us keep logic in one place.
So let's take a look at an example of inheritance.
And first, we are going to talk about the class inheritance.
So what we are going to do is that we are going to extract the module.
We are going to create for the super class.
We are going to create and we are going to use inheritance to make that behavior available to the subclasses
of that superclass we are going to create.
So let's say the name of our super class is, let's say class human.
And in this class, human, we are going to call a function.
You're going to sorry, not call a function.
We are going to define a function that is how low that is going to return a value that is let's say
hello.
Let's just end this function.
And this glass and.
Down here, what we are going to do is that we are going to create two classes that are basically going
to get inherited from this class because this class over here is going to be called as these super class.
And down here, we are going to create the child classes for this super class.
And let's say we have got two classes.
Let's say the first class is.
The M..
And to inherit this class from this class, what we are going to write and we are going to write in
the less than sign and we are going to write in human.
So if you just have a look at a common thing over, you can see that it says human is greater than male.
So this means that this is the superclass and this is the child, because a father is always bigger
than his child to explain it in simple words and just and the statement about him and create one more
class warfare.
Let's say the second class is class female and it will also have this lesbian sign.
And you're going to write a human just and this class will hear.
So now what we have here is that we have a super class.
Then we have two child classes.
So this is first class.
And we have this female here that is going to be the second child class for the super class that is
human since we have written human evil here.
So now what you can do over here is that if you create an object for this male class or this female
class, then what you can do is that you can access any kind of methods that are a part of this super
class will help.
So, for example, if you just ride in John equal to male.
Dortch New.
And let's say you have got a female as well, so we will create a class for female, let's say Jennifer,
equal to female dot news.
So now we have got two objects.
The first one is for the middle class and the second one is for the female class.
Now, what are you going to do is that we are going to write in votes.
You're going to write in John Doe, doc.
And right here, you can just ride in boats.
Jennifer Dodd, doc, now, as you can see, that basically the doc is a method from the superclass,
and as I told you, that when a class is inheriting some class, then it also inherits all the feature
of that class.
So this malfunction and since it is being inherited from the super class human and since the human has
this function that docs so this function dog is also going to be a part of this function.
And using the object of the class meal, what you can do is that you can access this function right
over.
How similar is the case with the female class?
It is also being inherited from the human class.
It also inherits all the future and all the functions of the superclass human.
So that's why using the object of this female class, what you can do is that you can access this dog
method, which is a part of the superclass overhead.
So writing Devonport's John, the dog here is going to bring on Halo and writing inputs.
Jennifer Doko O'Haire.
It is also going to print hello.
So if you just run this code, you're going to see that you have got.
Hello.
This is for the object of the middle class and this is for the object of the female class.
So what we are doing here is that we are using the less than symbol to signify that the middle class
is inheriting from the human class.
This means that all of the methods in the human class are available to the middle class for you.
We also created a new class that is called As Female that inherits from human as well.
We have eliminated the dark matter from the middle class in order to use that dark method from human.
When we run the school and we see the correct output, both classes are now using the super class humans
dog method.
Now, what if you want to use the original dog method from the middle class only?
So for that but you have to do is that you have to add it back and see that what happened for this.
So in the middle class, what we are going to do is that we are going to specify this attribute excess.
So here and using this attribute excess, what you are going to do is that you are going to define and
variable over here.
Let's say a name is that variable.
Now, down here we are going to create the constructor function for this main class.
We are going to write in, initialize and in here it is going to receive that argument that is going
to get assigned to this name.
So for that, you can use the self object.
You can write in self name equal to end, and that is good enough.
Just end this function and the class has already been ended.
Now, what you can do is that you can define the function right over here so you can just write in the
doc and in this doc.
What you can do is that you can write an.
Self-torture name, so you are just printing out the name and you see.
Hello, Oakhill.
All right, so just end this function as well.
And that's good enough, just call us now and let's just add a statement right over here so that you
can see what output is being printed object of John and I do.
Here we are going to write in votes.
Object of Jennifer.
So now what you have to do is that you have to also pass in an argument since as you can see, that
you have got a constructor function and you know that this new o'haire for the middle class, since
we have created that constructor function in the middle class.
So for that, when you are going to call it, it is going to call the constructor function.
And we have a constructor function right here, which is expecting an argument.
So right away here, we are also going to specify that argument, because if you don't do, for example,
if I just run it now, you can see that it has generated an error that says wrong number of arguments,
as you can see right over here, wrong number of arguments.
The given is zero and expect it as one.
So that is known as the argument error.
So are you.
Here we are going to pass in that argument.
That is going to be the name.
So let's say it's John.
Now, run it and right over here.
Now you can see that it's his object of John and it says John says hello, object of Jennifer, and
it says simply hello.
So in the middle class, we are basically overriding the talk method in the human class because the
Ruby Check.
The object class first for the method before it looks in the superclass.
That means that when we wrote the code for John Doe Dog, it it first looked at the John's class, which
is male.
It found the dog mattered there and it used it when we wrote the code for Jennifer the dog, the Ruby
first looked at the Jennifer class, which is female.
It did not find a dog method there.
So it continued to look in the female superclass that is human.
It found a dog method in the human class that is the superclass.
And it used that.
So we would talk about this method, look a lot more in-depth in a bit.
So right over here, so that was what you can just call it the priority basis.
So if a function is present in the class itself for which the object is created, then that function
is going to get used.
But if you have a function in the superclass and you are calling a function and that does not exist
in the class for which the object is created, then the function for the superclass is going to get
used.
But if there is a function in both, as you can see that we have got a talk in mail as well as a talk
in human.
But since this is the parent classes is child class and we are creating the object for this middle class.
So that's why when we write in talk, this over here is going to get access.
But for this female class, we don't have any kind of talk.
So the second priority function that is for the human class that iStock is going to get access.
So inheritance can be a great way to remove duplicate education in your code base.
Now there is an acronym that you will see more often in Ruby Community that is dry.
This stands for Don't Repeat Yourself.
It means that if you find yourself writing the same logic over and over again in your programs, then
there are ways to extract that logic to one place for reuse.
Then comes the use of the super keyword now Ruby provide us with a built in function that is called
a super that allow us to call methods up the inheritance hierarchy.
When you call super from within a method, it will search the inheritance hierarchy for a method by
the same name and then invoke it.
So let's see a quick example of how this is going to work.
So inhale.
What we are going to do is that we will just remove this from this stuff right from here.
We don't need this and this has to be indented right over here.
All right.
So now we have got this dark abargil.
We will just remove these from here as well because we don't need them as well.
We don't need the object for Jennifer for now.
So we just remove that as well.
Just remove this as well so that things are much more easier to understand.
All right.
So now what we have is that we have human class, then we have a middle class.
And finally we are creating an object which do not accept any kind of arguments now.
So, right to hear what we are going to do is that we are going to make use of these superguy word.
So instead of the self-taught man, what we are going to write and we are going to write and super says
hello.
Now, what is going to be done using this?
Now, when you write in, John, equal to Milhaud knew the object for John is going to get created.
It is going to check in the middle class if it has any kind of initialize function since it has not
said is going to just move on to the next line.
Now, when you write in, John, that it is going to look for the talk method first in the middle class
and since it is going to find that talk function.
So that's why it is not going to go for this dial function.
But here comes the part of this super keyword.
Now, when it moves into this dark function, it seems that the first time that encounter was the superguy
word.
And when you see the super key word, what it is going to do is that it is going to just go towards
the superclass, it is going towards the superclass, and it is going to print everything that is a
part of the superclass.
After it is done with all that stuff from the superclass, it is going to come back and continue on
its execution rate from here where it has left the superguy works.
That is going to bring down says hello, Octodad.
So if you just run the squad for now.
You can see that it says hello, says hello.
Now, the reason behind this is super is going to get going.
It is going to go right to a hearing since this was whatever was received.
So it is going to just have this Abargil, since we have got the Spottswood that so it is going to rent
this.
Hello.
Only after printing that it is going to come back towards the middle class and it is going to finally
print says hello.
Now let's say we have one more statement over here that say let's say my name.
So if you now run this, you can see that you have got first my name, then it says hello, says hello.
And let's say you have a statement right up to this as well.
That is that said, Territorials, run this now and you can see that you have got Ulmarra and you have
got tutorials as well.
Now you can see one more important thing, Oakhill.
You can see that this line, Abargil, which was used over here that has been eliminated.
Now, the reason behind this is that basically this statement over here is going to print on whatever
is going to get written from the function and the written statement.
If you just remember functions then in that you have a word about written statement and you know that
if you don't use the written word, then it is going to return.
Whatever was executed for the latest execution since the latest execution over here is there.
So that's why this is not going to get printed.
So if you want that to get printed, you have to just remove this line from here.
Ronda's and now it is going to run.
It is going to say my name and then it is going to say hello, says hello.
So we'll just remove this from here.
And right over here we are going to write in my name.
Now run this and now it says Homeira says hello to all.
So in this example, we have created a simple human glass with the talk instance method, we then created
the male which subclauses human, also with a dog instant's method to override the inherited origin.
However, in the subclause dog method, we use super to invoke the dog method from the superclass human.
And then we extend the functionality by appending some text to the result.
Another, more common way of using super is with initialised.
So let's see an illustration for that as well.
So in this human class, what we are going to do is that we will just remove this dog function from
here and we are going to use the attribute accessor again.
And we are going to write a name that is going to get received and right away here we are going to have
our constructor function, that is what initialise.
And in that, what you're going to do is that you're going to just assign the instance variable that
is at the rate of naming which name you can write in subdomain.
But since here we are using the concept of the instance variable, that's why you have to write in at
the rate of nameable here.
Just end the statement Abargil.
And in the middle class, what you're going to do is that you are again going to have your initialize
function over here.
So we will not have this over here.
We will have.
Initialise Ohayon.
And in the initialise function, what we are going to do is that we are also going to receive an argument
for this middle class initialize function as well.
That is going to be Dekalog.
So in place of this, we are going to simply ride in super.
Not with a capital as with a small s and after that, what are you going to do is that you are going
to initialize the value of what is working to write in color.
Equal to culo, good enough.
Now, what you are going to do is that you are going to just move down and ride to a hill.
What you're going to do is that you are going to create one more object.
So let's say the person you are going to call in, let's say he is a brown person.
So you're going to ride in, John.
So you want to know the color for John.
So if you are going to ride in John, equal to male dot knew and in the parameters.
You are simply going to pass in the glow for that person.
Let's say he's brown, so that is going to get brown and you are going to now not right in this of her,
because this is what is not needed since the initialised function is the constructor function.
And that is going to automatically get called when you are creating an object.
So let's just run this code.
All right.
My bad we have to initialize nameable here and now run this code.
Now it has been executed successfully.
So the interesting concept we want to explain is basically the use of super in the middle class.
Now, in this example, we are using super with no arguments.
However, the initialize method where a super is being used takes an argument and adds a new twist to
how super is invoked here.
In addition to the default behavior, Super automatically forwards the argument that purpose to the
method from which super is called add this point super pass the color argument in the initialized defined
initialize function that is defined in the subclass to that of the human super class and invoke it.
That explains the presence of at the rate of name equal to Brown when the John instance is created.
Finally, the subclass initialize continues to set the color instance variable.
Now, when called with specific arguments, the super the specified arguments will be sent up the method
lookup chain.
So let's see an example for this as well.
So down here we are going to create one more function.
Sorry, not a function at last.
We are going to create a class that is students and we are going to inherit that from the human class
as well.
That is the current class for that as well.
So in this, what you are going to do is that you are going to have a constructor function and in that
constructor function, what you are going to do is that you are going to receive in two arguments.
The first one is going to be the age and the second one is going to be the name.
Now, in this constructor function, what we are going to do is that we are going to write in super
and we are going to pass in the name.
Right, talk to this super glass now, since we are having this initialize function from which we are
calling this super.
So this is going to call the initialize function for the superclass that is basically this initialize
function in which we are passing in the name.
And that name is going to get received in this argument right over here.
So right down here, what we are going to do is that as what age we are going to simply define it with
the instance variable and we are going to end this function.
We are going to end this class.
So in the calling pod, what we are going to do is that we are going to write in students.
Don't know, and we are going to pass in the age that is, let's say 20 and we are going to pass in
the name, let's say the name is Mitt.
And now if you just run the school, it is going to execute very successfully because now this functional
o'haire disclosable here, that is students that is being inherited from the superclass human has initialised
to worry about.
The first one is the edge and the second one is the name and to initialize the name.
What it has done is that it has gone straight into the middle class writable hill, sorry, the human
class.
Let's just remove this from here because it has no usable here now.
So what it is doing is that it is calling the initialize function for the superclass and it is passing
in the name which we are passing.
So the name is first going to get passed into the student class right over here and the initialize function.
It is going to have this received in its parameter over here.
But since the first line says super, that is going to call the parent class and the parent class.
Since the constructor function is expecting one argument, that argument is going to be the name.
We are going to pass it and that is going to get initialized right over there.
And we are going to initialize the age right to a hill and age is going to simply get initialized.
But for the name, the job is going to get complex because the super supercute is being used over here.
So this was very similar to our previous example, with the difference being that Super takes an argument
against the past in argument is sent into the superclass.
Consequently, in this example, when a student class is created, the past and name argument that is
made in response to the super class and said to the advocate of name instance variable, then comes
the concept of mixing in modules.
Now another way to dry up your code in Ruby is to use modules.
Now we have already seen a little bit of how to use modules, but we will give a few more examples of
Ohayon.
Now, extracting common methods to a super class like we did in the previous section is a great way
to model concepts that are naturally hierarchical.
We give the example of humans.
We have a generic super class called human that can keep all basic behavior of all humans.
We can then expand on the model a little bit more and have, let's say, a bi subclass of human.
And we can imagine the entire class hierarchy to look something like the figure we have explained in
the previous tutorials as well.
So what we have shown or what they are, is that pure class based inheritance is what is basically you
have a parent, then you have a child up to that.
You can have multiple child as well.
So if you remember, the goal of this was to put in the right behavior in the right class.
So we don't need to repeat code in multiple classes.
We can imagine that all fish objects are related to humans that live in the water.
So perhaps a swim method should be in the fish class.
You can also imagine that all boys object will have, let's say, warmblood, so we can create a method
that is called as warm blooded now in the boys class and have it return.
True.
Therefore, the female and the male object will have the access to warm blooded method which is automatically
inherited from the boys by the female and male classes.
But they don't have the access to the methods in the fish class.
This type of hierarchical hierarchical modelling works to some extent, but there are always exceptions.
For example, you put in, let's say, the swim method in the fish class, but some boys can swim as
well.
We don't want to move the same method into humans because not all humans can swim.
And we don't want to create another swim method and male because that violates the dry principle for
Gunnarsson such as these.
We would like to group them into a module and then mix in that module the classes that require those
behaviour.
So it'll give you an example of this.
What are you going to do is that you are going to create a module that is swimmable and whatever class
is required, that module, you are going to just use them there and whatever.
I don't require them.
You are going to not use them or whatever.
So, for example, let's say you have got modular Wajir that is swimming and in the swimming module
you will have a function that is swim.
And in here you are going to ride.
And I am swimming.
Just endless function.
Andy, and finally end this module as well, and then you are going to have this class human, but this
class human is now going to contain nothing.
So we are going to just write in something like this or to just write and let's say a call of a hill
and then you can write in this end of a hill right at the top hill.
So we're going to just write an and help.
So this was our last human we have just emptied that glass.
We don't need anything Cohill.
So now let's say we have the glass of the fish and let's say it has been inherited from human glass
and since all the fish can swim.
So that's why we are going to write and include.
Swimmable.
Not swimmable, but we are going to ride in swimming, which we have misspelled, I guess.
Well, hell, that is going to be swimming, something like this.
And right over here, we are going to use that now so we can try as I am I n g.
I guess that's just about correct, and we are going to just end this fish glass with him.
Now we are going to have our boys class and we are going to have a female class as well.
Or you can just write and.
Lost boys, and you are going to ride and human here, since this is being inherited from the human
class and in that class, what you are going to do is that you are going to just end this war here.
You are going to have your class.
Female Bahir.
That is, let's say, inherited from the boy's class, and you're going to just end that over here as
well.
Now, what you are going to do is that you are going to write in class.
Men.
And you're going to ride in is extracted from the boy's glass and what you are going to do is that you
are going to ride and include.
Swimming in that.
And you are going to finally end this war here.
And now don't hear what you can do is that you can use the fish and the male objects because they can
swim, but objects of other classes won't be able to swim because the middle class that is being inherited
from the boy's class includes swimming.
So that's why all males can swim now and all fish can for sure swim.
So you are going to ride in, John.
Equal to.
Mail dot new, and that is going to create an object for the middle class right over here.
And to create an object for the first class, you are going to, let's say, a name of fish that is
normal and you are going to write an.
Fish not new, so that is going to create an object for the fish.
And finally, you are going to create an object for the female class as well.
That is going to be Jennifer equal to.
Female daughton, so we have created three object, the first one is John, which we have created for
the middle class, then we have created Neval for the first class and then finally, we have created
Jennifer for the female class.
And I hope that you have spelled it correct.
Yes, we have.
So the next thing you have to do is that you have to call in the same function for all of these.
So if you write in.
John Dodd, swim, run, this underscored.
All right, it says that the glass module name must be a constant model, assuming, yes, I guess this
should be a capital S..
So I guess that's one more thing added to your information.
The name of the module should always be a constant should.
So it must always start with a capital letter or it should be the entire capital letter.
So just change all of these swings to a capital s capital S..
Give it a rest now.
Run this and now you can see that it has run without any kind of error.
Just add a box with it.
Since we are returning a statement, as you can see, that this is what is basically being redundant.
So now run this and you can see that it says I am swimming.
So all kind of mails are basically now allowed to swim because we have included this module swimming
in the main class.
So that's why when we created the e-mail object and call it the swim function, using that object we
have got, I am swimming now if you use it for.
The fish glass that was created using animal objects.
We are going to write animal swim around this and it is again going to say I am swimming.
And finally, if you create it for the female class, which was Jennifer Dodd swims.
But since, as you can see that we do not have any kind of module that is named swimming included right
over here.
So if you now run the score, you can see that it has generated an error that says undermind method
swim for female because female is a not not a part of this.
So using modules to group common behavior allow us to build a more powerful, flexible and dry code.
Now, one more thing you have notable here is a common naming convention for Ruby is to use the Abels
to fix on whatever verb describes the behavior that the modulars model.
And you can see this convention with our swimmable module.
Likewise, we could use we could name a module that describes, let's say, walking as walkable.
Not all modules are named in this manner.
However, it is quite common and it is also a good approach by a good programmers.
So whenever you are writing your code, always do things that do that thing.
So, for example, if you are doing this for a swimming thing, so you have to name this modular swimming
and you have named this function as swim so that someone who is reading your code can easily understand
what is going on, because if you just name it to walking and in here you will create the object walk.
And right here you are writing and I am swimming.
So that is just going to be absurd.
You can do it.
It is going to run perfectly, but that is not a part of a good program.
So this is basically a suggestion only.
So in this story so far, we have covered about inheritance and we have seen how to use module's with
that now to talk about inheritance versus module's, now that you know, the two primary ways that we
implement inheritance, the class inheritance is the traditional way to think about inheritance.
One type inherits the behavior of another type.
Now, the result is a new type that's best suited to specialize is the type of the superclass.
The other form is sometimes called as the interface inheritance.
This is where mixed in modules come into play.
The class does not inherit and from another type, but instead inherit the interface provided by the
mixin module.
In this case, the result is not a specialized type with respect to the module.
Now you may wonder when to use class inheritance versus mix.
And here are a couple of good things and suggestion you can consider when evaluating these choices between
makes in an inheritance.
The first one is that you can only subclause from one class that is about class inheritance.
So you can only subclass class inheritance from one class, so you can mix in as many modules as you
would like for interface inheritance.
So if you're dealing with single classes, then what you can do is that you can use in class inheritance.
But if you're using makes sense, then what are you can you can do is that you can use the interface
inheritance concept.
Then the second suggestion is that if there is and is a relation, the last inheritance is usually the
correct choice.
If there is has a relation interface, inheritance is generally a better choice.
For example, a male is a human and it has an ability to say.
And the third suggestion is that you cannot instantiate modules.
Modules are used only for name spacing and grouping common methods together.
So as you get better at object oriented design, you will start to develop a feel for when to use class
inheritance and when to use mixing in modules.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial in the next drill, we are going to continue on with inheritance
and we are going to see about method look apart and a lot of other things.
So for this tutorial, that's it.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.