Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another tutorial on discourse on Ruby and in this story.
We are going to be covering two more functions related to Arranger's and Ruby and that are going to
be new and the last function.
So starting on with the very first function we are going to cover in this tutorial is the new function.
So the new is an invalid method in Ruby that returns a new range of numbers.
And if you talk about the syntax of this, it is very simple.
It is range new and object now and here we have to specify two objects.
The first one is going to be the starting from where we want to start on the range.
And the second one is going to be the last where you want to end the range.
So basically this new function helps you to create new range.
And that is also basically you can just call it a new way of initializing and range in Ruby and how
it is going to be done.
We are going to discuss that after some time.
So moving on to the second function explanation, that is the last function now.
The last function is very similar to the first function, but it is something that returns the last
number and arrangement.
So the last is an invalid method in Ruby that returns an array of the last elements.
And here we have an object.
If that object is not mentioned, it returns the last element only.
But if this object over here is given, for example, we specify three, then it is going to return
the last three elements of that certain range.
So if we just move on to our editor, then we will be much more able to explain what is going on in
our health.
So starting on with the first one now, in the previous two years, you have seen that we have created
Rangers' like you have just right and range equal to zero nine, and that created a range for us.
Now there is one more way to create a range, and that is using a function that is called as the new
function.
So you're going to just write and arrange all that, just make it branch one and it is going to equal
to Grainge Dot new.
And in here you have to specify the starting element of the range and the ending element of the range
separated by a comma.
So if you have to write in four and you have to write in a coma and then you have to write an ending
element for this range, and if you just write in votes or arrange one over, he'll run this code.
And as you can see, that you have got a range that is from four 12 that you can see that you have specified
a comma over here.
But since you have created a new range, that's why it has inserted that this dot out for you by itself.
And it has created a range from four to 12 over here.
All you can do is that let's say you want to access you want to check if a certain number exists between
this range or not.
You can just write in range or you can just you to put one over there to see if it is working or not.
So you can write in votes range one dot.
Include and you can just check a number, let's say six, which is a part of this range or underscored,
and you can see that it has returned.
So this has created a new range for you.
So this is basically a new method in Ruby that is going to allow you to create ranges other than the
normal way in which you have been created in breeding ranges still so far.
So moving on to the second function, that is the last function.
So you just remove it from here.
We will create a simple range.
Now that is from zero to nine.
And as I told you, that this basically works the very same way as the first function.
So if you just write in range.
Or just use boats over here, boats range got lost, and if you don't specify any kind of argument,
would it run the school that is going to print you the last element that is nine Iraqis.
But if you specify, let's say four were here, then what it is going to do is that it is going to return
the last four elements that are going to be nine, eight, seven, six.
So if you just run the school, you can see that you have got nine, eight, seven, six starting on
from six till nine.
So that's how you can use the last function as well in the very same fashion as you have used the first
function.
So I guess that's it for this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next trattoria.