Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Ruby.
So in this story, we are going to be covering the operators presidents in Ruby.
So.
Starting on with the first one, the very first president's.
In any kind of operator, expression is given to bullion not.
Bitwise complement and unary plus the second president's is for exponentiation, the next one is for
unary minus.
The next is for the multiplication division and modulars.
The next is for the simple addition and subtraction that is the arithmetic, addition and arithmetic,
subtraction.
The next is for bitwise left shift and bitwise right shift, then comes the bitwise and and after that
we have the bitwise are all the bitwise czar.
Then we have the ordering that includes the greater than less than greater than equal to less than equal
cosigns.
Then we have the equality, the federal matching and the comparisons operators.
Talking about some more, we have the bullion and then we have the bullion or then we have the range
creation and the bullion flipflops, then we have the conditional operator that includes that.
If then else type of things, then we have the exception handling modifier, then we have the assignment
operator.
Then we have the best variable definition and that includes the defined.
Then we have the bullion, not then we have bullion or and and finally we have the locks.
Now what do we mean by operators precedence over here, which means that if you have any kind of expression
in which you have multiple signs or you can say that you have multiple operators, then which operator
is going to be given the higher precedence and executed first?
That is basically the sequence which I have showed you.
So let me give you some examples for this, for that, I'll move on to my compiler at home and here
we are going to write in a simple expression that is boats.
And we are going to let's say dipen five plus six.
Minus, let's say nine, then divided by two, then add another nine in it, and then let's say multiply
it by two, then add.
A one in it and then finally subtract, let's say, 12 from it, so apparently if you calculate this
10 Cohill.
That is six plus five, equal to 11.
Let's just make it simple, so let's just make it three so that five, let's not treat it before.
So five plus four nine nine minus nine equal to zero, which is not good.
Let's just make it to something like 18.
So make it 14.
So 14 plus four equal to 18, 18 minus nine equal to again nine nine.
Divided by 19, divided by nine, divided by two is going to be equal to four because that part is going
to be the decimal board and then you add a nine in it.
So that will make it equal to 13 13 multiplied by two to 26, then minus one from a 25 and then sorry,
add one in to that.
It is going to go to 27 and I guess 15 is going to be the answer if you talk about the apparent and
the sequence twice calculation.
But if you press all plus are, the answer is going to be twenty one.
Now that is because it has followed some operator precedents.
Some operations are performed at the start, some operations are performed after that, and the very
same operator precedents have been followed, which I just showed you on the slides.
So that's why 15 was not generated.
And you have this 21 hour hail.
Now, I leave it up to you to calculate why it has generated 21 by following the operator precedents
I just showed you, so that is basically how operator precedence is going to follow.
And in the future, tutorial is going to be covering more topics that will include the conditionals.
We will be.
Talking about more operators and many of the steps that, let's say, include the Boolean and ignore
this orange and assignment operator, the conditional, the flipflops, then you will also come to know
that how these follow a certain sequence.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.