Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Ruby.
And in this tutorial we will be covering the topic.
Bradgate matters.
Now, if you go on to the Internet and check on with the list of the matters on strength's, you will
see that almost every method ends with a question mark.
Now, what's up with that?
Now, what you will notice about those methods is that they will only return to kinds of output.
It will be either true or it will be either false.
Now, that is what is basically called predicate method in Ruby.
Not quite sure why, maybe because of the historical context of programming.
So always remember that Bradgate methods that end with a question mark will either return true or it
will return for us, for example.
Now, if we talk about some examples, for example, if I write in our airports and I want to check
if a number is either even or odd, for example, I just type in one dot odd and run this code.
All right, I forgot in the question mark, you always add this question mark over here, since I am
asking this question that if it is if this one is odd or not.
So I have to add this question mark.
And on the screen you can see that it is true since one is an odd number.
So if you just write in for here and you know that this is not odd, so it is going to return false
now since four is even.
So, if you use the even method over here, run the score and you can see that you have generated destroyable
here.
And if you use one over here and now run the score, you can see that false has been generated on the
output screen now.
All these methods I have showing you this makes them read like a question, which is pretty cool.
Now, you can ask if a number is between two numbers, you can go on and use predicate methods on strings,
you can use the predicate methods on areas.
Now, how these are going to be used on strengths and errors, that is going to be a part of the future.
Dorians, when we will be covering the methods on strings and when we'll be covering all about areas.
So that will be covered in the future sections.
For now, all you need to know is that what are practical methods?
Let me just give you one to two examples more now.
For example, I want to know if a number is between a certain range or not.
So, for example, I want to know that if five.
Dot.
Between.
A question mark, and I want to know if life is between one to 10 now, obviously it is.
So if you just run this God, you can see that Drew is generated on the output screen.
Now, if I just change this to for, let's say, and now run this quarter, you can see that falls has
been generated.
So these methods are basically called predicate methods in Ruby Bradgate.
Methods are going to be also covered in the future tutorials when we will be covering about strings
and errors.
So you will come across many things about Bradgate methods in the future tutorials as well.
The purpose of this tutorial, as I told you, is only to give you a basic introduction to predicate
methods.
So I guess that's it when this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
I'll see you guys in the next Dorio.