Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Dubea.
And in this tutorial we are going to see how to read and write to a file.
Now, in the previous tutorial, you have covered how to open a file and how to create a new one.
So in this story, what we are going to do is that we are either going to open the existing file or
we are going to create a new file and then we are going to perform these two operations on those files.
So let's get to it.
So if you talk about the syntax of these, so talking about reading it is something like file equal
to file dot new, which means that in this case, a new file is being opened.
You can simply write and follow up and write the name of the file as well.
But you can do this job over here as well.
Now to create a new file.
Why?
It is important because if you want to read a file, then you have to write in this are over here.
If you don't if you want to open a file and you have created that file before and you have created that
file with W Mutawakkil here instead of this Arawa over here, then you will not be able to perform the
reading operation over here, because in order to perform the reading operation, this are over here
is very much so.
It is a better approach to either create a new file.
If you want to read that, if you want to just open that file, then you must ensure that the file that
has been created before has been created using this hour more.
If you want to perform the reading, if you want to perform the writing, then this has to, which I
will cover in the next slide.
Then what are you going to do is that you are going to create one more variable content.
You can just write in any name over here and then you are going to write in this name over file dot
reading.
Now, this is not the part of the syntax over here since a file can be read using many, many functions.
So you will write the name of the function right over here.
So that's why I've written reading over here.
Reading is not a function at all.
There is a function known as RE.
There is a function on a system read analogue which will we will be covering, then we will get to the
examples part.
So that's why I've read and read reading over here and then you got to write in the number of characters
you want to read in.
Next come how to perform the writing operation, and it is like finally going to find that new file
name our place and the same logic.
That if you want to open a file, then you must ensure that the file has been created before with this
hour plus more, or you can just write in as well, because, you know, the hour plus is basically
a combination of reading and writing.
So if you have created a file before in the hour plus mode, then you can perform the reading as well
as writing on that five.
So you want to create a new file, just write an hour plus.
Or if you want to only perform the right thing, you can just write in him.
And then again, writing is not a function.
There are a lot of function through which you can perform the writing.
So that's why I've written writing O'Hara and and how you are going to write in the next you want to
print or you want to insert or you want to write on to the file you have created.
Right.
Or help.
So let's move on to the example spot.
And first, what we will do is that we will perform the writing operation and after that we will move
on to the reading part, because whatever we will have written, we are going to then read that in the
second part of this tutorial.
So we already have got these two fires of hell.
We have got files and files, but both have been created in the W mode.
So what we are going to do is that we are going to just change the name of the files so that we have
the files which we want to create in our mode.
So we will use the plus mode, which stands for reading plus writing, and we will change the name of
the file here to file.
Just riding.
Riding a wave while riding.
Dati is going to be the file will just remove this file from here, we will create this to be filed,
then we will have a variable through which we will open this file to writing.
Writing or he'll just remove this for now, we will just run the score and we will ensure that the file
has been created.
So if you just go home, all right.
So we have got some errors.
That's why the file was not creating.
It says file writing is some kind of error, OK?
It is.
Let's change the mode and then try and let's try it and just run this now and not run perfectly, let's
just see the file has been created.
Yes, it has.
It was not supposed to create an error with the R plus mode.
I guess there is some problem with the editor, maybe.
So you can just try it on your editor.
If it works then it is pretty cool if it doesn't just change the motor and then it is going to work
as you have seen.
So if you want to write to a file and you are creating a new file, then after creating the new file,
you also have to open that file as well.
So we have just written a variable.
We are equal to file dot open and now the file has been opened.
Now we can just perform the reading or writing operation, but first we will perform the writing operation.
So you just remove this from here.
And right after this, we are going to profounder reading, sorry, writing by.
All right, so if you just write and file dot, right?
Then you have to write in the name of the file, so you're going to write and fire DOT writing, which
is the name of the file.
And then the second barometer is going to be the data you want to store in that file.
So we are going to, let's say, just right and Dada's Dawid.
In the file.
So that's good and others just move it a bit ahead around this code and it has run perfectly.
So now what you need to do is that you need to go on to the documents and you can see that you have
got this file writing O'Haire created.
Just open it and it is going to ask you that in what you want to open.
It is just open it in notepad and you can see that you have got this that are stored in the file and
it has been printed right over here, as you can see.
And we have written it right from here.
Now in place of writing the name of the file over here, which is basically opening the file.
You can just use this over here, because we have also written this line of work here so you can just
write in via our in place of this and to ensure that this has all just change this line and right in
second that are stored in the file or on this code.
Go ahead, open the file.
Open this and you can see that now it's a second that are stored in the file, so you can also use this
variable right over here to basically write data to a file because it has this line file open.
And if you just write in the name of the file, then basically you are writing this line right over
here.
So you can for a simple purpose, you can just use the.
Variable in which you have stored this stuff over here, the next thing is if you want to write an error
to a file, you will have to convert it into a string first.
So if you have this right over here, you can just write in the name of the file, which means opening
a file.
So we use the very same variable over here.
Just remove this from here.
And what we are going to do is that we are going to specify an error.
So an error looks something like this.
Let's say it has three elements one, two, three.
So we are going to use the design method with this and we are going to join them with a separator.
So that separator is going to be a new line space.
And after that, we are going to do is that we are going to specify mode as well ahead.
And the mode is going to be.
Now, what does this mean?
What here is that we want whatever data is to be read anywhere.
We want that to be appended.
So we just run this code and it has run successfully.
Now, all you need to do is that go on to your documents folder, open this file right in and you can
see that you have got this one, two and three right over here.
So just delete this file because this is not what is required every time you run this code, if you
now just rerun this code.
Go on back and you can see that you have got this file.
Hey, I just see that.
But that is one, two, three.
You have got that output.
Now, if you want to append something more to this file, because in a previous case, you might have
noticed that whatever line we print, that was actually overridden.
So now if you just write in file dot.
Right.
We are let's say you just ride in.
Now above.
Lines are part.
Of an area.
And we are going to specify the third argument as mode and we are going to specify the mode as a round,
this could go back, open this file and you can see that you have got this, that the above lines are
part of an area.
So now the data has not been actually overwritten.
Rather, it has just been appended to whatever code we already have in the file.
So that's how basically you can just use the mode of operation of a here to append data to a file.
Now there is one more way in which you can also write to a file, and that is known as the system.
Right.
So if you just remove this line from here for now, so what you're going to do is that you are going
to.
Right.
And that's why I asked why this system.
And after that, what are you going to do is that you are going to simply write in the data here so
that say, how old is the data?
And right over here, you don't have to use this file.
Well, here we are going to use the variable in which you have opened this file.
So we are going to write in via our DOT system or.
Right.
Or if you don't want this as well, you can just use this file variable over here as well.
So you can just write and filed our system.
Right.
Or underscore it.
And it has run perfectly.
Just go open this file and you can see that you have got this HelloWallet over here since we did not
use the append over here.
So that's why the previous data was overwritten.
And you have got this.
Hello, would or help.
So after doing all the stuff related to writing, you can just simply write in variable dot clause here
on this.
And this will basically close your file.
And closing a file actually means just freeing up the space, which can then be used for other useful
purposes as well.
So I guess that's it for writing.
Now, let's move on to the second part of the JUREL that deals with how to read files in Ruby.
Now, there are multiple ways of how you can just read files in Ruby.
The simplest of all is you can just write and file trade.
So we already have a file names while writing, so we will just remove this from here.
So what we will do is that we will simply open this file that is variable equal to file dot open and
we will open the file file writing, not the XDA.
And now we are going to perform the reading operation on this.
So what we are going to do is that we are going to use this variable.
We are and we are going to store it in the reading variable.
So we are going to write in reading equal to variable rate and in the variable rate, we are going to
write in the name of the file.
So we are going to write and file file writing the X, D and downhill.
What we are going to do is we are going to just write in votes.
Reading and Octodad, the file is going to be closed as well.
Now what's reading is going to do is that it is going to just print out any data that is stored in the
files.
So why it is going to print out?
Because this reading variable contains variable Dautry and it contains all the data that is written
in this file.
Now you must be thinking that this file was created in the W mode.
Now W would also allow you to just read the files as well.
So if our place is not working in your editor, then W is going to have the privileges of the reading
and writing as well.
So if you just run this code.
All right, so it says it has got some kind of error and no implicit conversion of string into dijo.
All right, my bad.
This should not be a part hair, because since we have written, we are so it knows that it has to open
this file.
You don't have to specify this as a parameter with the read function as well.
So now just run the score and you can see that you have got the hello message, which you have written
on to this file file writing in the previous example.
If you just open this file over here, you can see that you have got only this text over here which
has been read successfully using the read function.
Now, there is another way of reading that as well.
If you are working with a file that has multiple lines, you can either split the file that are used,
that read lines method.
Does the job method remove the new line characters as well?
But in a sense, in this case we have got only one line of data, so we cannot implement that either.
Just write in the syntax for that.
So if you want to try that as well, you can just try it as well.
But that what you have to do is that you have to right and this in place of this what you are going
to right.
And you are going to write in the name of the variable, that is are you going to.
Right.
And we are red realigns.
Map malfunction, which you already have created, have covered in the previous story as well, and
you are going to use the material here and what you know, what is the purpose of Trump over here?
Trump is going to remove any kind of line spaces that are going to get created in this file, whatever
you are going to try to print.
So if you don't just run this code and it says undefined variable or a local method, TRUMP All right.
It has to be dot.
And then it has to be Chope.
And according to here as well.
Now run this code and it is going to bring down HelloWallet.
So in this case, if you would have multiple lines, then those multiple lines also would have got printed
right over here.
And after that, you can just write a post rating and you also have to close the file as well.
Now, if you want to process a file, a one letter at a time, you can also use the for each method
for that.
But since in this case, we also have only one line.
So that's why we can use it.
And you already have used the average method so you can just try it with this function as well.
So what you can do is that you can just write in something like.
File dot for each.
And in the Parameterize, you are going to write in the name of the files, we are going to write and
file writing and then what are you going to do outside of here is that you are going to create a blog
and in the blog you are going to have these bars in which you are going to specify the variable in which
you want to store one line at a time.
And after that, you wanted to print this line as well.
So it is going to store one line, print it out, store the second line, print it out and so on.
It is going to keep doing this Tingo here as well.
So if for that purpose, what do you have to do is that you don't need any of these as well, just run
this code and it says no such file or directory.
All right, you have to ride in the exterior here.
Now, run this and you can see that it has printed how the world has seen the very similar, if you
would have multiple lines of warhead and those multiple lines would get printed over here as well.
One last method you need to understand of how to read the file is the SLA is good.
It is very similar to the NSW Right, which you have covered in the writing part.
And what you have to do over here is that you have to use the previous index.
So we will adjust price controls at multiple times.
We will just remove this from here.
And in here, we are going to just write and content equal to our dot.
System, right, and up to that, we are going to ride in the characters you want to point out.
So that's the biggest ride in five of us here on this score.
And it is going to only bring the first five characters of our file, which we have here, that is filed
right across the street.
So this is how you can also just read a file in Ruby.
So these two are, I guess, four to five ways in which you have understood how to read a file and you
have understood also to the two to three days of how to write to a file as well.
So I guess that's enough with this.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial as well.
That was an extensive tutorial.
But in this, you have understood all the ways in which you can read or write to apply.
So I guess that's it.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next Dorio.