Hey, guys, what's up?
This is American, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Ruby.
And in this story, we are going to start on with the introduction of every kind of operator we have
in Ruby.
Now, the first kind of operators we have in Ruby are the Artomatic operators.
Now, you've already covered arithmetic operators in the previous section, so I won't go into the detail.
I will just give you a quick recap of what our Artomatic operators in here will be.
So there are basically, I guess, one, two, three, four, five, six kind of Artomatic operators
in Ruby starting on with last.
That stands for additions and it add the values on either side of the operator.
Then we have the minus that is used for a subtraction and it subtracts the right hand upper end from
the left hand operand.
And then we have the starick that stands for multiplication and it multiplies values on either side
of the operator.
Then we have this backslash that stands for division and it divides the left hand operand by the right
hand option.
Then we have this person did sign that is used for the modulus here and it divides the left hand operand
by the right hand operand and returns the remainder to us.
Then we have this double starick that stands for Exponent and it performs the exponential.
Ah, you must say the power calculation on any kind of operator.
So moving to the second operator, that is the comparison operator, so there is an operator, start
on with the two signs, what checks if the value of two operands are equal or not?
If yes, the condition.
Right, Don Strew.
And if not, it returns false, then we have this exclamation mark equal to that standard for not equal
to.
And it checks if the value of two options are equal or not.
If values are not equal, then the condition becomes true.
So it is basically opposite of what is going on with the first operator that is equal to the next operator
is the greater than sign and it checks if the value of left print is greater than the value of the right
of Brent.
If yes, then the condition becomes true, then we have the less than sign with checks of the value
of the left or print is less than the value of the right to operate.
If yes, than the condition becomes true, then we have the greater than equal to that checks if the
value of the left or print is greater than or equal to the value of the right operand.
And if yes, the condition returns true and if not, the condition returns false.
Now these are some of more comparison operators.
We have the less than equal to sign what checks if the value of the left or print is less than or equal
to the value of the right to operate.
If, yes, the condition returns true, then we have this less than an equal due and greater than sine.
So you can say that basically equal to sign is encapsulated in greater than less than science.
So it is called the combined comparison operator and it returns zero if the first operand equals second
one, if the first operand is greater than the second and minus one if the first operand is less than
the second.
So it is basically a combination of this.
Less than equal to and on the previous slide, the greater than equal to operator, then we have the
triple equal operator that is used to test equality within our when clause of a case statement.
And this thing is basically going to be a part of the future tutorial when we will be covering about
the case statement.
Then we have the dot edu el questionmark that returns.
True, if the receiver and argument have both the same type and equal values, then we have the equal
question mark that returns true if the receiver and argument have the same object idee.
So now let's discover some quick examples that are related to the comparison operator, because we have
already covered examples on Artomatic operators in the previous tutorial, so we won't waste any kind
of time on that.
So let's move on to Adam.
All right, so we will start on from the very first that is this equal to equal to operate or we have
already covered it in the previous tutorial as well.
So let's have one more example.
So we are going to write it supports five equal equal to, let's say six.
So as you can see, that it is not true.
So if you just run the score, you can see that it has generated false.
And if you write in something that is equal to this, run the score that is going to return.
True, then you have this not equal to.
And as in the description, you can see that it is very opposite of this equal to equal do.
So if you just want to add and use the exclamation mark over here and now run this code, you can see
that it has generated false because they are both not equal and not this not equal to is going to return
true if they are not equal.
So if you just write in a condition where five and six are not equal run underscored, now it is going
to return true for you.
Then we have this greater then and then this less than operator.
So if you go on to Adam and see if five is greater than six, then as you can see that this condition
is not true.
So if you just run this court, it is going to return false.
Then if you use the other side that was less than run this code, it is going to return.
True, because now six is greater than five, which is the left operant in this case.
Then you have the less than or equal to operator.
So, for example, if any of the condition is met, either if it is less than this are either five is
equal to the third check for these multiple conditions.
So if you just run this code, this is going to return.
True, because five is not less then, but it is equal to this statement.
Ohayon.
So if you just type in, let's say, six or hill or underscored, you can see that again, it has returned
to now five is not equal to six, but five is less than the six.
So if both the conditions are false.
For example, if I just put a greater than sign here.
Now, as you can see that both conditions are false, five is not greater than six and five is not equal
to six.
So if you just run the score that you can see that false is generated on your atama and there and same
goes for the other one that was greater than now in this condition.
You can see that this statement is true.
So if you just run, the score through is going to be generated on the output screen.
Now moving to the next now you have already covered this.
So now let's talk about this.
This is a very interesting operator, or as you can see that it says it is called the combined comparison
operator, and it returns a zero if the first operand equals second.
Now, let's just check for this condition.
So let's just make this make it equal, run this code.
And as you can see, that zero has been generated on your Adam there because it says that if left,
operand is equal to the right to operate, then it is going to return zero.
The second condition says that it is going to return one if the first operand is greater than the second
operand and minus one if the first operand is less than the second.
So in our case, if you just type in six Oakhill as can see that this condition is basically true.
So if you just run the score, it is going to return one.
And if this option is greater than this option.
So, for example, if I just type in someone over here, run the score, then it is going to get done
minus one on my output screen.
So that's why it is called the combined comparison operator.
And you can check all the three conditions less then agreed to then and the equal to with this combined
comparison operator.
Then we have this triple two equal to that we will be using in the future tutorial when we will be discussing
the case statement.
Then we have this dot equal question mark that return true if the receiver and the argument have both
the same type and equal values.
So now let's just check it.
So we are going to write in six dot e q o questionmark and we will put six, so if you just run code,
it is going to return.
True, because both these six are equal and they are all the same.
A data type.
If you just write in six point zero over here or underscored, you can see that false has been generated
since both these are if you apparently look at them, they are true.
But since this does not equal two conditions, says that it has to be equal in number and also in the
data that now this statement over here add returned false because they are not of the same data type.
This is an integer and this is a flawed value.
Now, finally, we have this equal question mark operator and it returns true if the receiver and argument
have the same object, i.e. now in the previous tutorial, you know how to calculate the object idea
for a certain number.
You have to multiply that number with two and then you have to add one in to it.
So if you go on to Atem.
And now all of us remember that two elements are going to have the same object if they are the same
number, because if you use any kind of other number, if they are multiplied by two and one is added
to them, it is going to return a different kind of result.
So the same number.
So if you write an you.
You, Eleanor Hill, and that is going to be the very same, just run the score and Drew is going to
be generated.
If you just write in over here or underscore that is going to return false, because if you just look
at them, six is going to be multiplied by two, which makes it equal to twelve.
One is going to be added to them.
So that makes this O'Haire 13.
So this is going to be 13 and this is going to be multiplied to 14 and one is going to be added to them,
which means that it is going to be 15.
So the object is here are not equal.
That's why it has returned false on the atom runner.
So that's the end of this.
We have covered all of our operators.
We have covered examples of each.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next story a little bit.
We will be covering some more on operators in Aruba.