Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Ruby.
And in this tutorial, we are going to be covering two more functions.
The first one is going to be clear and then we are going to be covering the lead.
So starting on with the first function we are going to cover in this tutorial is the clear function.
But Clear is a string class method in Ruby, which is used to make the string empty.
Simple enough talking about the syntax of this, it as simple as that string, not clear what you have
to write to get the string clear.
And the second function we are going to be covering in this story is going to be the delete method in
Ruby.
Now the lead is a string class method in Ruby, which is used to perform at lead operation returning
the given string or it is going to return if the given string was not modified.
Talking about the syntax of this, it is string to delete and it also has the parameters and hair string
is the given in the given string and parameter list are the specified characters and what it is going
to return is it is going to return if the string is not modified as it is going to return something.
So let's move on to the examples and see how these work on our atom's Ed.
So here we are.
So starting off with the first one we are going to go in this tutorial is the clear function.
So let's say we have a string.
That is something like this, so we're going to do just try and put a lid on this and you can just see
the output in just a while.
Yes, it has this output that is strong, but if you just right in a hill.
But it's not clear or underscored now you can see that an empty space has been created.
Right, a hill.
Now, this empty space is created because now it contains nothing if you just ride and puts it down
here.
So if you just run this code now, you can see that now an additional third space has also been created
because the first spaces for this line and the second space is for this land, because now it contains
nothing.
So that's how basically the clear function works in Ruby now moving towards the second part of the editorial
that deals with the delete function.
So for that, we also have to have a string.
So let's say we have the same string.
And now what we are going to do is that we are going to apply the delete function and we are going to
just write in the characters we want to delete from it.
So we are going to write inputs, you know, delete, and then we are going to specify the parameters
that are going to contain the string which we want to delete.
So here we have this as extras.
We are going to just write in geological.
Run the score and you can see that both the GS have been missing now now, for example, if a G is right
over here as well.
We now run this code that G is also missing from here.
So this is basically over here is use this function to lead is to delete a specific string wherever
it occurs in a certain character.
So let's say we have a sentence that is something like this.
And if you just run this code now, you can see that wherever it finds a G, it is going to delete it.
But I guess I did not have any kind of video here.
Let's do it for J because we have got a lot of JS, so just run it and you can see that average is disappeared
from here.
Similarly, you can do it for words over here, for example, if you have like Jamm.
Let's say it is, man.
Then you have, let's say, BI's.
Let's say Apple, then let's say jam, jam band jam, so you have got a lot of jams over here.
What you want is that you want to just delete the jams from here.
So instead of just doing like this and there's a lot you can simply do is you can write and put it right
in the character you want to delete from this string.
Just run the score and you can see that jam is simply missing from the scenes.
So that's how basically the delete function works in Ruby.
And for example, you enter something that does not exist over here.
So, for example, I just ride in guava will help run this goat.
You can see that it has it is going to just delete the strings and it is going to now treat it as single
letters and it is going to delete all the is it is going to really use it is going to delete all the
guy that is going to be so it works something like this.
So for example, in all of this, we do not have any kind of zadow here.
So let's just enter.
Is that O'Haire around this code and you can see that you have got the very same string as we have written
right over here.
So that's how basically the delete function works in Ruby, that is to delete a certain string certain
characters from a specific string.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much, gas, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.