Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another detail on this course on Ruby.
And in this tutorial, we are again going to be covering to function.
The first function is going to be the actual function.
And the second function we are going to cover is going to be the any function.
Now, starting on with the first function we are going to cover in this tutorial, is the equal function
now?
Equal is a hash class method which checks whether the two hash areas are equal or not.
If you talk about the syntax of this, it is very simple.
You have to write and hash one if not equal, and the hash with which you want to compare hash one,
you have to pass that hash.
If you simply call it hash to you can just pass it as an argument and it is going to compare those two
hashes.
The two hashes are equal.
It is going to return.
True.
And if they are not equal, it is going to simply return false.
The second function we are going to cover in this is the any function now any is also a high hash class
method which checks for the presence of a patron and it passes each element of the collection to the
given block.
If you talk about the syntax of this any function, it is also very simple.
You have to write in hash dot any.
It accepts no argument, and if the hash is not empty, this function is always going to return.
True.
So if the block ever returns a value other than false or nil, it is going to return false.
But if it return anything, it is going to return.
True.
So far, hashes that contains no value of keeping it is going to return false for every other case.
This function is going to return.
So let's just see some examples of both these functions in our editor.
And you will understand much more what I'm talking about right now.
So starting on with the first function, that is the function that is going to check if the hashes are
equal or not.
So we already have a set of hashes over here.
So let's just initialize this B and have another value.
Two hundred over here so that these two are equal.
Now, what you can simply do is that you can write in votes.
A and B.
Equality returns.
And you can just use the interpolation of a here and you can just ride in it or EQM a question mark
and in the parameters you can just pass and be.
So just run the score and you can see that it says it and the equality returns.
True, because they are true, as you can see, that you have got the same keys, the same values.
Now, for example, you just change of value over here.
For example, both A and B have 100 value over here, whereas the B contains 200 over here.
Run this now and you can see that it returns false.
So basically it not only check for the KeIso here, but also check for the values that are stored in
those keys.
So, for example, let's say we have this 200 over here, but we have, let's say, some different ghiorso.
In the previous case, the difference was due to these values which are stored in this case.
And for this, we have the keys different.
Now run it.
And it is again going to return false.
So do.
So for this function to return true.
What this should have that both these hashes should be equal in the key values as well as in the values
that are stored in those keys.
So for this to return true, this has to be B as well run.
And you can see that you have got true right or whatever.
So this is how basically you can just have this now, for example, you have, as you can see, a video
here, but you have got a CEO here as well.
And you want to compare it with C, let's say run this and you can see that it has returned false since
this is a part of this completely and this is basically a subset of this.
But since this contains an extra value, so that's why it is going to return false as well.
So talking about now, the second function we are going to cover in this tutorial is the class function,
which checks for the presence of a patron.
So if you just use the any function over here and any function exceptional arguments or just leave it
empty and we are going to write in and the.
Not envy anymore.
A.
Veteran returns just run it.
You can see that the ephedrin returns true because it has certain values.
Similarly, you can just ride in boats, Bacterin.
Returns interpellation, and you can just ride and beat out any question mark bracket's run and you
can see that it has also, I don't know, for example, I just remove the statements from here.
So this means that C is empty.
So if you just write in votes C.
Badran returns schtuck and you can just ride in C dot.
Any question mark run and you can see that it has returned false because since as a told you that each
element of the collection is passed to a given block, and if the block ever returns a value other than
false or nil, otherwise it return false.
So in this case, it has returned nothing.
So that's why it has returned false and false has been printed right over here.
So if that trend is not present, this function Searoad and is going to return false.
Now, for example, we have, let's say, the Syntex difference over here.
Run this and this is again going to return true as well, so the pattern doesn't matter on the syntax,
it matters if hash returns something when it is sparse or not.
So in both these cases for and B, it returns something.
So that's why it returned drooler here.
But this return nothing.
So that's why false was printed right over here.
And basically that's how you can use both these functions in your Ruby code.
So I guess you have understood them.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial as well.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next tutorial with some other functions on HaShas.