Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another long discourse on Ruby and in this story, and we
are going to cover Mattituck apart now that you have a grasp on both inheritance and Mixin from the
previous Dorien.
So now let's put them both together to see how that affect is going to help us in the method look apart.
So recall the method.
Look, a part is the basic order in which glasses are inspected when you call a method.
So let's take a look at the example we are going to cover right over here.
So what we are going to do is we are going to create a multiple pots.
We are going to create a workable then we are going to create a swimmable and we are going to create,
let's say, climbable module.
So let's just create them and then I will explain what's going on.
So first, we will create a module that is walkable and in that walkable module, we are going to create
a function walk.
And in this function, we are going to just write and I am walking and that is going to get returned
to the place where this module is going to get included and called this function is going to be so just
endless function and this module create one more module.
And the second model is, let's say, going to be.
Swimming and this also has to be a capital W, like we have discussed in the previous tutorial, so
let's say you have a swimmable module and in that swimmable module, you will have, let's say, a function
swim.
And in that function where you're going to do as you you're going to simply write.
And I am.
Swimming and this function and this module will create one more module that is, let's say, climbable,
I guess I have misspelled that it should be Clim and be a BLT, but enough and that what you're going
to do is that you are going to create a function that says I am.
Climbing.
And this function and this module, so what we have done is that we have created three modules.
The first one is work in which we have a function walk.
Then we have created the swimmable module, which which we have a function stream, and then we have
created the climbable module in which we have a function line.
Now, what we are going to do is that.
Down right here, we are going to create our glass, all right, to a hill.
We are going to create our laws that is human and in that class human, the first thing we are going
to do is that we are going to include one of the modules that is, let's say, walk people over here
because a human can walk.
And in here we are going to define a function that is stuck.
And in the dog function, we are going to write and I am human and.
I can.
Doc, simple is that this fella is going to get written just and dysfunction and this class human as
well.
So now we have got three modules and one class.
We have mixed in one module into the human class.
The method look part is the part a ruby takes to look for a method.
Now we can see this part with the ancestor class method, which you have already covered in the previous
tutorials as well.
So write down after using this class.
What where you going to do is that you are going to write inputs.
Human class.
Method.
Look up and right here you are going to write and put human dot.
And sisters and just run this code and you are going to see that it says human lives matter, look up
and then it says human, then it says more capable than it says object and going on.
Then it says basic object.
So this means that when we call a method of any human object, the first ruby look in the human class,
then the lockable module, then the object class, then the kernel model, and finally the basic object
class.
As you can see, the hierarchy right over here, which is the physical hierarchy of an object calling.
So it is going to first look into the class, then it is going to look for any kind of modules.
Then it is going to go into the object, then the content and finally the basic object.
So right down here after this, what you're going to do is let's say or just remove this from here,
you have just seen the output.
So run this and we have got no errors.
So right down here, what you're going to do is that you are going to create an object and you are going
to have human dot Neuzil object is basically now about an object of the human.
And using that, what we are going to do is that we are going to call into talk function.
So just write an object.
Dot, dot.
And you have to also write and post with it, run this code and it is going to say I am a human and
I can talk.
So Ruby found the dog method in the human glass and looked no further because it does not have to,
because we have specified the area for which it has to have its look up.
Now, if you just ride in puts.
Object Dot Volkova here.
Then what is going to happen over here is that Ruby is going to first look for divorc instance method
in human, and since it is not going to find it there, it is going to keep looking in the next place,
according to our list, which is the walkable module, as you have seen the hierarchy.
Let me just printed out that hierarchy so I can just explain.
You are going to just write in votes Human Dawid.
Ancestors on this.
And let's just remove this for now and now run it so when you write and puts.
Object dot walk you what it is going to do.
Is that what Ruby is first going to look for, divorc instance method?
According to this hierarchy and according to this hierarchy, it is going to first look for it in the
human class.
Now, if you just go into the human class, you can see that you have got no kind of walk method of
a hill.
So it is going to then move on and it is going to then look for the Vork method in the walkable module.
So since it is going to find it.
What they are.
So that's why the search is going to end right over here.
And it is not going to look into this object going to the basic object things over here.
So now if you just run the school, you can see that it says I am walking, and basically all this happened,
according to the hierarchy at Facebook Hill, did not find it.
It looked here, found it, printed it out right here that says I am walking.
So now if you just write in votes.
Object dot any kind of object to a hill which is basically not included right here in this class of
a hill.
So if you just ride in, let's say we have two other modules that is swimmable and flammable in which
we have the same incline function, respectively.
So if you just ride in, let's say, Swimmable Hill.
Run this, you can see that it says undefined method, same for the human flow and you can see that
object tracking.
Now, the reason behind this is that when we write an object starts June 1st, it is going to look into
the human class.
It did not found any kind of swim method in that class that is human.
Then it is going to look into the lockable model.
It is not going to find any kind of swim method or they but it is going to find the work that it is
going to print.
And I am working then for the hard.
It is going to look into the object.
It is not going to find anything.
Gladio then it is going to look into the car that it is going to not find anything here as well, and
then it is going to look into the basic object where it is not going to find that as well.
Because if you remember the introduction tutorial to object oriented programming, I told you that when
you are creating an object, you are actually creating a blueprint of a class, so a blueprint of a
class since it does not contain anything.
So that's why it is going to generate error.
That says undefined method because it did not find any kind of that matter.
So it will be basically a traverse all the classes and modules in the list and did not found a swimming
method.
So it through an error.
So let's add another class to this code right over here.
And this class will inherit from the human class and mixing in the other two modules, which we have
not included yet in the human class and those module, the swimmable and the climbable module.
And we are going to include that into the child class of this human class.
So I do a hill.
We are going to create our next class.
That is class male, and that class is going to get inherited from the human class and that what you're
going to do is that you're going to simply ride in include you are going to include the swimmable and
you are going to ride and include.
The line below here as well, so that is climbable and you have to just end this class as well.
So now if you just want to print on the ancestors, let's just remove this from here and just write
and put m..
Dot ancestors'.
So if you just run this code, you can see that it has a lot of things over here.
So whenever you are going to call in any kind of method with this Milawa here, what that is going to
do is that first it is going to look into the middle class, then it is going to look into the climbable
module, which is right over here.
Then it is going to look into the swimmable module, which you have included right over here.
Then it is going to look into the human class that is basically the parent class, or you can say this
super class of this middle class from which this middle class has been inherited.
So the fourth place where the hierarchy goes is the parent class.
Then it is going to look into the valuable module.
Now, the reason it is going to look into the valuable module is because the class human contains this,
since it is going to look into the human glass.
And when it looks into the human class, it is also going to find include walking over there.
So it is also going to look into the valuable module.
So this Melda ancestress also has this module now included over here.
We have not included it over here, but since it is being inherited from the human class.
So that's why it is also going to look into the buckyball module, then it is going to go into the object
kernel and basic object.
Finally.
So you've seen the output now there are several interesting things about this output.
First, this.
Tell us that the order in which we include modules is very important.
Ruby actually looks at the last module we included first.
As you can see, that climbable as far then we have got swimmable after that.
So this means that in the rare occurrence that the modules we mix in contain a method with the same
name, the last module included will be consulted first.
The second interesting thing is that the module included in the superclass made it on to the method
lookup part.
This means that all the mail object will have access to not only human methods, but also methods defined
in the valuable module, as well as all other modules mixed into any of its super classes.
Sometimes when you are working on a very large project, it can be very confusing where all these methods
are coming from now by understanding the method lookup.
But we can have a better idea of where and how all available methods are organized.
So now if you use now, if you just create an object for this middle class over here, let's say the
object is X or just write an X equal to Mayardit new and let's say now you try to just access any kind
of method with this Exalogic.
So if you just write an X dot swim now, run this code, it is going to get executed successfully.
Just add a post to see if the output is being printed and it says I am swimming.
Then if you just write and thoughts.
Dot, Clim, run this and it is going to say I am climbing, and even if you just write and extort Volke
or it is also going to print on, I am because in the ancestor hierarchy of this middle class, we also
have got the model of lockable included.
So it is also going to look into that and it is also going to print that Ohayon.
Now, one more interesting stuff over here is that this male hierarchy basically contains everything
that is a part of this super class, but the super class hierarchy still does not have this stuff over
here.
So if you have this very same object created for the human class of a hill and if you just remove this
from here or underscored, it is going to work perfectly since we have the module included.
But if you use any of the other modules, let's say you just try and climbable here on this code, it
is going to still generate error because the.
Ancestors, if you just write and goats.
Human ancestors.
Rhonda Scott, you can see that, all right, you have to just remove this from here.
And now I guess that's good.
Now run it and you can see that the hierarchy of the human class, even though we have got this middle
class, which is inheriting this, still does not have.
So this answer, one very important question about how the child class is going to include everything
from the parent class right to a hill, but the parent class is not going to inherit anything from the
child.
So this means that the child class know that it has a parent of which any kind of property it can use.
But the parent does not know that a child for him has been created, which has some kind of functionality
which he can use.
But since he does not know that a child exists, so that's why he can not use any kind of functionality
for that.
And that's why the ancestral hierarchy, as you can see right over here, does not contain anything
that is a part of the class.
But if you just print on Foote's.
Male Dawid ancestors run, you can see that you have got everything that is a part of the parent class
as well.
So that's how things are going to work on where matter look apart.
So we have already seen how modules can be used to mix in common behavior into classes.
Now we will see two more uses for modules.
The first use case we will discuss is using modules for a name spacing.
In this context, name spacing means organizing similar classes under a module.
In other words, we will use modules to grip related classes.
Therein lies the first advantage of using modules for a namespace.
It becomes easy for us to recognize related classes in a record.
The second advantage is it reduces the likelihood of our classes colliding with other similar named
classes in our code base.
So here's how we are going to do it.
So we will just control it.
Backspace and we are going to create a module in which what we are going to write and we are going to
write in humans.
So this is going to be the name of the module.
And in this module, we are going to have our glasses.
So let's say A can be either male or female.
So we are going to create a middle class and just ended and we are going to create a female class.
And we are going to just end that as well.
Now, in this function, in these classes or here, we are also going to create similar functions.
So let's say in this middle class, we are going to have a dog function that is going to receive an
argument that is sound.
And what we are going to do is that we are going to write and be.
And we are going to use interpellation and we are going to just print out sound, I just use pot, Sawhill.
And just and this function first, so I just click, enter and this function.
Good enough and right here in this FEMA class, what we are going to do is that we are going to create
a function that is, let's say say name, and it is going to receive an argument that is going to be
the name and it is going to have the very same type of code that says put.
And it is going to use interpolation and it is going to print out that name and dysfunction.
The class has already been ended just and the module right over here.
So now we have got Amodio Human in which we have got two classes that are either male and that is either
female.
So we will call the classes in a module by appending the last name to the module name with two columns.
So to do it, what you're going to do is that you are going to write in the name of the object and you
are going to create this for humans and then males.
So what you're going to write in, let's say X is the name of the object and you're going to first write
in the name of the module.
So that is humans.
Then you're going to specify to Collins, and after that, you're going to specify in the name of the
class in which you are basically in, which is a part of this module, and you want to access it and
you want to create this object for that class.
So let's say we want to create the first object for and we're going to write and Dot knew then we are
going to create one more object for Y.
So we are going to write in y equal to humans, to Collins, we are going to write and female dot new
and that is going to do our job now to just access these methods that are the talk and say name for
the male and female respectively.
What you are going to do is that you are going to write an X dot doc and you are going to pass in any
kind of argument.
Let's say hello to keep it simple.
And then for the second one, you are going to write and why not say, underscore a name and you are
going to pass in some name.
Let's say John is the name.
So just run it and you can see that you have got hello for the first one and John for the second one.
So that is basically what is the first use of using the modules.
As you can see, that what you have done is that you have actually just you can see that you have boxed
up the properties that are interrelated because humans can be male or female.
So that's why you have just encapsulated that in a single module, humans.
And now to it says that you have to also specify the name of the module and then specify double Collins
and then the name of the class for which you want to create the object.
So that was basically the first use the second use case for module's.
We will look at is using module's as a container for methods that are also known as the module methods.
Now, this involves using modules to house other methods.
Now, this is a very useful technique for methods that seems out of place within our code.
So let's use our humans module to demonstrate this stuff over here.
So right up this, what you're going to do is that you can define any kind of function, but you're
right and self interest in DOT and let's say the name of the function is to keep it as simple as that.
And just let's say it is going to receive an argument that is going to be a number.
And that number, what you can do is that you can just write in a number.
Starick.
Strike two, so that is going to be what is done with the no just end dysfunction.
And now since you have defined this inside a module and not inside a class, which is inside a module,
so to just access it, just remove this from here, you can do is that you can just write an X equal
to humans dot func, just passing a value.
Let's say two is the value.
Run this code and it has executed successfully.
Let's just write inputs with that Ronda's and you can see that you have got four to do was for.
All right, now, if you want to add the name of the module's to look at more specific as well, for
example, you have, let's say, a function that is also a part that is that has the very same name
and is a about of more function as well.
So to call it, you can just write in this phone call.
But to do so, what you can to keep it more specific.
What you can write about here is that you can write in humans and in place of this dog object, what
you can do is that you can specify two columns of a hill and you could you have to just write in the
name of the object, the name of the class, a double column, the name of the function and the argument
that is going to get passed into that function, run this code and that is going to give you the very
same output.
But the suggested way is to use a dot right to a hill.
So I hope you understood that so these are basically the three use cases or you can say uses of the
modules mixing with inheritance, then comes the last concept we are going to cover that is related
to inheritance is about the private protected and public.
So the last thing we want to cover is something that's actually quite simple but very necessary.
Right now, all the methods in our middle class are basically public methods.
A public method is a method that is available to anyone who knows either the class name or the objects
name, how these methods are readily available for the rest of the program to use and compromise the
class interface.
And that's how other classes and objects will interact with this class and its object.
Now, suppose you will have methods that are doing work in the class but don't need to be available
for the rest of the program.
These methods can be defined as private.
Now, how do you define private method?
We will use the private method call in our program and anything below it is going to be private.
Unless another method like protected is called after it to negate it now in our middle class, we have
one operation that take place that we would move into a private method when initialize an object, we
calculate, let's say we will calculate the males age in middle years.
So let's refactor this logic into a method and make it private so nothing outside of the class can use
it.
So we'll just remove the modules from here for now.
So we will just remove this from here and we will also remove the female function from here.
So let's say we already only have this malfunction of a hill and let's say we want to calculate the
age.
So right away here, we are going to have a very constant variable and that is going to be male and
the score years and whatever age is going to get passed and we are going to multiply it with this male.
So let's say that is for.
And we are going to receive that, and so we are going to have a tribute accessory to just have the
access to the getter and setter function.
So we are going to have the name as well as we are going to have the age.
So we are going to use the constructor function to initialize the values over here.
So we are going to use.
Initialise.
And that is going to receive two arguments, the first one is the name and the second one is the age,
and we are going to write and self Dodd name equal to and and we are going to write in self doubt,
age equal to it.
Now, you can always use the at the rate of conceptual help, but to do it, that is going to generate
the very same output.
So you can use any of this.
So just end this function of a hill.
Now, this is a constructor function and down here, what you can do is that you can create the function
that is going to calculate the human errors and what you are going to do, that you're going to make
it private.
So just write in private wahib.
And now anything that is written after this is going to be private.
So we are going to write in def and the name of the function is going to be human error since it is
going to calculate human years.
And in dysfunction, you are going to just write an H starick.
Made years good enough.
Let's just end this function and this class and now what you can do simply is that you can just call
this.
So just remove this from hell and let's just remove these spaces so that everything is visible.
All right.
Now, right down here, what you can do is that you can create an object, John, and you're going to
write in M. Deutche new just in the name.
And just pass in the it's now since we are calculating the military, so that's why we are going to
do this in five so that it is going to multiply with this force so that generate a 20 that is expected
out before us.
So, no, I don't hear what you can do is that you can write in John Dodd human underscore years.
But if you now run, this could.
You can see that you have got an error that says the method which you are trying to access is a private
method.
So we have made the human errors a human interest method private by placing it under the private method
call.
Now, what did what is it good for then?
If we cannot even call this from outset by just using the object?
Private methods are only accessible from other methods in the class.
For example, given the very same code, what we will do is that to access this human ear, what we
will do is that we are going to create one more function.
So right down here, we are going to have def.
Disclosed function and in the disclosed function, what you are going to do is that you are going to
write an.
Self dot.
Name.
Is.
The name of the function.
And.
Right, and there are human.
Years.
So justice and dysfunction.
And now what you're going to do is that in place of this, you are going to just write in John Dodd.
Disclosed or undisclosed?
So the address is private.
Yes, because we have done it also under the private, so this discloser is also now a private matter
and you can not access it right now like this.
So we'll just remove this from here and we will just remove it from the stack.
So it is not right down this tag that is private.
So now it is disclosed function is no more private.
Now this code and it is going to run perfectly just at ports to see the output here on this code.
And you can see that it says, John, is a 20 human error.
So we have actually used this human year function by calling, by just using it inside a function that
is not private.
And we have actually accessed a private method using a function that is inside the glass.
So we are going to call it that is closed function, and that is going to help us access the private
method inside the glass human.
Now, you have to note one thing, very important number here, that in this case, we cannot use cells
with this human years.
Now, the reason behind this is that the human method is private.
Remember that self, not human, is equivalent to John Dawid human years, which is not allowed for
a private matter.
If you just recognize or remember the previous to realise.
I have told you that if you don't specify cells, then basically we are referring to the name of the
current object, not the name of the method you are referring to, since we cannot access this private
method with DeJohn object.
So if you just write and self-doubt years away, then it is like writing John Dodd human erasable here.
So that is what is basically not allowed.
Therefore you have to just use human ears.
In summary, private methods are not accessible outside of the class definition at all and are only
accessible from inside the class when called without.
So as of Ruby two point seven, it is now legal to call private matters with a literal self as the public
and private methods are most common.
But in some less common situations we would want and in between approach, we can use the protected
key word to create protected methods.
The easiest way to understand protected method is to follow two rules.
The first rule is from inside the class.
Protected methods are accessible just like public method, whereas from outside the class, protected
methods act just like the private method.
So if you talk about an example, we will just remove this stuff from here.
And here we are going to create to function, the first one is a public matter.
So we are going to name it ACBL that stands for public.
And in this, what we are going to write and we are going to write in, will this work?
And what we are going to add with this is that we are going to ride in self.
Dot, the name of the function that is every al and we are going to just end this function.
Now, what we are going to do is we are going to create the protected variable and downhere, whatever
you are going to create is going to be protected.
I have already told you the rules.
So if you just write in death, e, r, b, c, D, that stands for basically protected.
And inside this function where you're going to specify is that you're going to write.
And yes, I am a protected.
Method, simple enough, just end this function.
And the glass has already been and so if you see the above code, it is a little complicated.
So we will create a human story, a male object, and we are going to test this thing over here.
So we will just remove this from here.
And we are going to create an object and we are going to write an.
To new and we are going to write an object.
DOD, and we are going to use the PBL.
So what this is going to do is that it is going to go into this PBL function, is going to see the statement,
will this work?
And then it is going to go into the protected matter.
This is not going to be it is going to be the PR.
So it is going to have the stuff that protected that is going to call in the protected matter because
right directly you cannot use this protected matter, as I've told you that the rules as well.
The first rule was that you cannot access it directly from outside, but from inside you can access
it using the Southmead.
So from outside of the class, protected methods are just like private matters.
And from inside the glass, protected matters are accessible, just like public matters.
So we are accessing the protected matter that is protected from inside of a function that is a public
function.
So if you just run this code, it has unsuccessfully just write in votes to see if the output is generated.
Yes, it has.
And it says, well, this works.
And after that, the the RTC has printed.
Yes, I am a protected matter, as you can see here.
Let's just add a space and now run this and you can see that.
Will this work?
Yes, I am a protected method and that was what was actually required.
So the above lines of code shows us that we can call a protected matter from within the class, even
with self.
So what about outside of the class?
So if you try to access this, you just write in B or C, D, O'Haire run this code.
It is going to generate an error message.
This demonstrates the second rule that we cannot call the protected method from outside of the class.
The two rules for protected methods apply within the context of inheritance as well.
Now there are some exceptions to this rule, but we want to worry about that.
Yet protected methods are not used often in practice, and that knowledge is not transferable to other
languages.
So if you remember these two rules of our protected methods, that should be good enough for the time
being.
That comes the final topic we are going to cover in this tutorial that is accidental method or writing.
Now it is important to remember that every class you create inherently subclasses from class object,
the object class is built into Ruby and comes with many crucial methods.
So, for example, if I just remove this from here, so let's say you have a class that is named as
parent and in that class you have a method that is so high and that you are going to just write in votes
high from.
They're glass and just dysfunction and this glass and doing says that you're going to ride in parent,
not super glass, and if you just run this good, you are going to see that it went perfectly just at
post over here on this.
And you can see that it says object.
Now, this means that methods defined in the object class are available in all classes for the recall,
that through the magic of inheritance, a subclass can override a super class method as well.
So let's say you have.
A child close to a hill puts a class that is named as child and that is being the child of the parent
clause, and in that you have the very same function that is deficit high.
And in that you have, let's say, the very same thing.
But you are going to just write in votes.
I am.
Or you can just say hi.
Hi.
From the child class.
Just and this and this, and now if you just create an object for the child class, so if you just write
in child equal to Child Dot knew and you just write in child dot and to score high.
Just good, it is going to say hi from the child class and it is also going to generate a warning that
says already initialize the constant child previously definition of this, whatever child was created.
So.
It is going to give you the output and it you can see that it is printed high from the trade.
Now, this means that if you accidentally override a method that was originally defined in the object
class, it can have the far reaching effects on your core.
For example, send is an instance method that all classes inherit from object.
If you defined a new set instance method in your class, all object of your class will call your custom
send method instead of the one in the class object, which is probably the one they mean to call objects
and serve us as a way to call a method by passing it a symbol or a string which represent the method
you want to call.
The next couple of arguments will represent the methods argument, if any.
So let's see how send normally works by you making use of our child plus.
So what we are going to do is that we are going to create one more objects.
We are going to ride in sun equal to child dot new and we are going to ride in sun dot send.
We are going to specify a colon and we are going to write and say and a score high run this code.
And you can see that it says high from the child class.
So let's see what happens when we define a send method in our child class and then try to invoke the
object send method, because as you can see, that we don't have any kind of send method here yet.
We are getting this out because this is the standard method that is from the object class, that is
a class.
So in this class over here, if we define the function.
Sen.
And we just let's say a write in puts.
Send method.
Are the child glass are just right in the hill.
And let's just end dysfunction as well.
And now, right down here, what you can do is that you have already created your object that is sun
shining with a child on you, and now you can just ride in sun docent and the very same thing.
Just run this code and you can see that you have got an error.
Normally, we would expect the output of the scroll to be high for a child, but upon the running we
got a completely different result.
That is about the wrong number of argument given one and the expected number of arguments are zero.
So in our example, we are passing send one argument, even though our Aurlien Sand method does not
take any kind of arguments.
So let's take a look at another example by exploring objects instance of method.
Now, what's what this handy method does is to return true if an object is an instance of a given glass
and false otherwise.
So let's see that in action.
So let's say we we will have a class object that is the very same right over here.
But now we are going to use the instance method over here.
So we are going to ride in Sun Dot.
Instance underscore of our question mark, and if you just write in votes with it.
Run is good.
All right, it is again saying that it has got some kind of error.
Yes.
Because we have to remove this function from here now.
Run it.
All right.
This is wrong.
Number of parameters for the instance of Matadi.
Yes.
We have to specify the name of the class as well.
So if you just write Angiulo here, underscore it is going to generate Drew.
And if you just copied this from here.
And just a hair in place of child, we write the name of the parent class, Randy Scott, it is going
to generate for us.
So now let's over write the instance of method within the child class.
So what we are going to do is that we are going to write in depth.
Instance of and in that method, what we are going to do is that we are going to simply write inputs.
Fake instance.
And just and dysfunctional here and now, if you just execute the statements, right, a hill.
Just remove this from her underscored, it is going to generate an error that is also about the wrong
number of arguments.
So they said this, said that one object instance method that is easily overridden without any major
side effect is that to underscore method, you will normally want to do this when you want a different
string representation of an object.
Overall, it is important to familiarize yourself with some of the common object methods and make sure
to not accidentally overwrite them, as this can have devastating consequences for your application,
as you have seen right over here, that when you try to override the building method of the object instance
of or when you try to override the method send, that was also a part of the same object building class.
So that is going to have a devastating effect and it is going to generate errors because those are the
methods that are going to be called in for the object class.
So I hope it is clear and these are basically all the concepts in very detail about inheritance.
So I hope you understood inheritance in the next story.
And we are going to come up with a new topic, so stay tuned for that.
So that's it for this tutorial.
Thank you so much for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next aureole.