Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to an editorial on this course on Ruby.
And in this story, we are going to cover the difference between length, gown and size.
So it is going to be lean towards discount or size.
Now, one of the major problems newcomers to Ruby experience is that there are often quite a few ways
of doing the very, very same thing.
For instance, you can obtain the number of items in the innumerable class using three methods.
It is either by using the enumerable count or the method length or its earliest size that such classes
often provide.
So, for example, you have a set of elements, let's say X equal to one, two, three, four, five.
So what you can do is that you can have multiple methods to obtain the size of this.
So for example, you will write and put X dot land.
You can simply use X dot size and then you can also use X dot count.
And this, I guess, has to be in small run this court, and as you can see, that you have this five
obtained for this extra land for the boats with this as well.
Run this.
Do you have this five again?
Again, for the boats with this round the score and you have this five again.
So you have obtained the count of this variable X over here using three different methods, that is
land, size and count.
Similarly, you can have this very same method applied on hashes, areas and strength.
So for example, you have, let's say, a string over here and you have, let's say my name in here.
Then when you just run this code, then X Stotland and exercise is going to generate a count for you.
But the string sorry, this extra count is not going to work.
Let's just run and let me show you.
And as you can see, that you have this five five, but you have got missing one output.
If you just have this commented out on the score, then you can see that the error message has just
disappeared.
Now, X.com won't work because String's does not include the innumerable class.
So now you have got three methods.
So which one you should be using when you are given some kind of scenario in which you have to generate
a count?
So basically the length is a method that is not a part of it.
No, it is a part of a concrete glass and it's usually running in constant time.
That's as fast as it gets, which means that using it is probably a good idea.
Now, whether you should use the length or size is almost a matter of your personal preference.
Personally, if you ask me, I would recommend you go on with size for collections that include the
hashes and every kind of things, and you should be using lente for string, since for me objects like
hashes and stacks don't have a length, but they have a size.
Conversely, it's perfectly normal to assume that some text has some length anyways.
In the end, if you are invoking the same method, so the semantic distinction is not important, then
the innumerable count on the other hand, is a totally different beast.
It's usually meant to be used with a block or an argument and it will return the number of matches and
innumerable.
For example, if you just have the previous scenario in which.
You have one, two, three, four or five, let's say six, seven, eight as well.
Then, for example, if you want to have the count applied on it, so we'll write in votes x dot count
and you want to, let's say, just run the score and you can have the number of variables in this.
But what if you want to have only the even number printed?
So accurate count is going to help you out because it is from the innumerable glass.
And it's usually meant to be used with a block or an argument, and it will reduce the number of matches
and an innumerable.
So, for example, you want to know the number of your numbers in this, so what you can do is that
you can specify and you will specify a colon and you will specify even and a question mark, which means
that you are asking a question.
And the question is that tell me the number of even numbers that is in this X, and you want only the
count to be generated for those even numbers for underscore.
And as you can see, that you have got four, which means that two four six eight, these are the four
even numbers.
So that's why we have this four over here.
Similarly, if you want to know the number of odd just right in order here, Randi, score.
And again, you have four because you have one three five seven as the odd numbers over here.
Similarly, if you want to know a specific number over here, let's just open one or underscore.
And the answer is going to be one, because we have only a single one of here.
For example, if you specify three one zero here, more on the score.
And as you can see, you have got four now.
So you can, however, invoke it with any argument and it will reduce the size of the innumerable on
which it is invoked.
Now, as you have seen, that if you got no argument over here, you run the school and then you're
going to have the number of elements in this variable X.
Now, there is a performance implication with this thought to calculate the size of the innumerable.
The count method will traverse it, which is not particularly fast.
Some classes implement and optimized version of count in terms of length, but many don't do this.
The takeaway for you is that you should avoid using the count method if you can use the length or if
you can use the size.
But always remember, Count is not going to work on strength.
So I guess that was the difference between the three methods.
And I hope that I have cleared the doubt of what should you be using when you have got a situation in
which you have to use one of them.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.