Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a manhunt, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Rubia.
And in this tutorial, we are going to see how to rename and delete a file in Ruby.
So if you talk about the syntax for renaming, you can just write in for that new name of the file more
than what you want to open it.
Or you can just rename an existing file as well.
The symbols indexed for that as you have to write and file, not rename.
You have to write in the old name and then you have to write in the new name of the file, which to
which you want to rename it.
Simple as that.
Moving on to the deleting syntax, you have to just write and filed or delete and the name of the file
and that file is going to get deleted.
So this is a very simple tutorial.
Let's just move on to some simple examples as well.
So what we are going to do is that we are going to just rename files.
We are going to write and.
File Dot Greenham, and we are going to rename a file right from here.
So let's just rename this file Sohel.
So just go back and file, start the expertise.
And the second parameter we are going to specify is renamed DOT the run this code.
Cool back over here and you can see that files has now been replaced with renin.
You can also create a new file and also rename it and there's going to be the very same.
Next thing is how to delete a file.
So to delete a file, you have to just write and file, dot, delete and in the parameters you have
to write in the name of the file.
So let's say we want to delete this file over here.
So we are going to write and file dot the city around this code and says no such file or directory.
All right.
This line has to be removed because it is, again, trying to rename a file that is files it ought to
do, which is now no more a part of the folder.
We are working it, so let's just remove it from this code.
And now it has run successfully.
Just go back and you can see that the file dot is actually missing from here.
So that's how basically you can delete a file in Ruby as well.
So this was a very simple tutorial in which you have understood how to rename and delete a file in Ruby.
So I guess that's it for this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I will see you guys in the next tutorial.