Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Ruby.
And in this video we are going to be covering to function.
The first function is going to be to each function and then we are going to be covering the dick function.
So starting on with the first function of this tutorial, we have this each function, which is a hash
class method which finds the Nasdaq value, which calls block once for each key in hash by passing the
key value pair as the parameter.
So if you talk about the syntax of this, it is hash dot each and now you can pass in three type of
arguments.
The first is that you can just pass no arguments.
This means you can just keep these brackets empty and no parameters are to be passed to this function.
The second parameter is that you can pass in the value and the third parameter is that you can just
pass in the key.
And for all the three scenarios, the output is going to be something different.
So we'll try that later.
But before we will discuss the second function, we are going to go in this tutorial that is the dick
function.
Now, this is a harsh glass method which finds the nested value, which is specified by the sequence
of the key object by calling dig at each step.
So if you talk about the syntax of this, it is hash tag.
And the parameter that is going to be parsed is going to be the hash value.
And you have to pass in the hash value here as the parameter to this function.
So now let's see two examples.
Each of of each of these functions, we have just code.
So we've will go on to our editor.
So the first function we will cover is that each function.
So we already have three hashes over here, A, B and C. So what we will do is that we can just use
the first Syntex on this, which means that we are going to use the empty brackets index for this.
Then we are going to use the key index for this be hash and then for the C hash.
We are going to use this index for the value.
So let's try all of these one by one.
So we are going to write and hash in.
Each from.
Interpellation Abargil, and we are going to ride in a dart each.
And the first index was to keep these brackets empty, so let's just run the scoreboard and as you can
see, that you have got an enumerator and you've got an address that is basically pointing towards the
location of whatever restaurant.
Now, since it is an enumerator, that's why it has got these values right over here.
You can see that it has got enumerator will help and you have got an address Oakhill, which is, I
guess, a sixteen bit address right over here.
And basically you have got this hash right over here as your output now to try on with the second one,
you what you can do is that you can write in votes.
Hash the each from antipollution, and you can just write and be dot each.
And you have to specify these curly brackets over here again and you have to use a parameter right over
here and these bars over here, that is going to be key.
And you don't have to you have to use now the interpellation concept over here against to right and
puts.
It right in hashtag pugil.
And these are the closing brackets for the first one, and these are the closing brackets for the second
in the position right over here.
So just run it.
And yes, it ran perfectly.
You can see that this is the output that is Starick a hundred.
And then you have got hash each from column A, this area here and hundred right over here.
Now, what is basically going on over here is that for me, we have got on the single value that is
a calling, Hundert.
So what it is doing right over here is that it just grabbed the key for the first one.
That was it.
So the key here was, is it right in the value for that hash?
So that was basically this right over here that is handed it printed out the keepers.
And the second thing it printed out Starick it and this one handed right over him.
Now to use it for multiple values.
For example, you can just add certain values over here.
Let's say we have a value be two hundred Abargil and let's say we have a value see 300 over here.
So for now, we will just remove this so that it don't create any kind of fuss over him.
And we will just elongate it a bit more so that you can see the complete line.
All right.
So now let's just run it.
And as you can see, that not only you have got all the values right now or you can say that you have
got an area of all the elements you have in this hash right over here.
That is the C hash.
You have separated all the elements, a hundred, B, two hundred and three hundred.
And whatever you have got right here, here is basically the set of keys along with the values.
That was basically also the syntax we have used in the previous tutorials as well.
So this is basically what is going to get printed when you use the key right over here.
Now, the third thing, what you can do over here is that you can use the value over here, which is
basically the third way to use this, each function right over here.
So what you can do is that you can just write and Cohill.
You can you see it on the edge of a hill and what you have to do here is that you have to specify the
value of a hill and you have to specify value here as well.
So let's just get in the mud so that you can see completely the line right over here, run this.
And it has generated the very same outcome.
But now you must be thinking.
Go ahead.
And what was the difference between the previous one and this one?
Because this is simply a variable.
The compiler does not know that.
We are actually referring to the value of this, be this or whatever are the values that are reference
to this.
We have specified in these hashes right over here.
So they are the very same.
But basically these are the two different ways you can use this.
Each function, the first one is for the key and the second one is for the value.
So basically the output is going to be the very same.
It is going to be generated very, very, very same output, as you have noticed right over here as
well.
But since.
There are certain variables that basically points to what is going on.
So that's why for the key, it was doing it for the key and for the value.
It is doing it for the value.
So that's why the variables names are different.
But they are doing the very same job as it did in the fall when we used the kill here and this valley
right over here.
We have specified it is doing the very, very same job.
So that's how basically the each function can be used in three different ways in Ruby.
So I hope you have understood all these three.
So now moving on to the second part of the tutorial that deals with the take function.
And as it told you, that this method finds the nested value, which is specified by the sequence of
the key object by calling the dig at each step.
So the syntax for that was hash tag.
So we already have three hashes over here, A, B and C, but you have to do simply is that you can
use.
The big function on all three of these, one by one, so we will use it for different keys so far,
let's say, for this hash will use it for this key, for this hash, we will use it for me and for this
hash.
See, we can use it for the key.
So let's try this right input's.
Hash tag interpellation, and you can write an it or dig for now, we will just leave these brackets
empty with them later and let's say for the second it is going to be hash B.
They come into play on the deck and finally for the third one.
How she digs.
Some interpellation and you can write and see Dot Dego held.
Just it and I guess that's good enough.
Now, what you can do is that you don't specify the brackets, we miss them.
So now let's say for the first one we wanted for the key.
So we are going to write in column A if in the case you are using the previous index in which quotation
mark has to enclose these guys over here.
So for that index, you have to also write hash it enclosed in quotation marks over here.
But in this case, since we are using this index for these simple columns over here so you can just
write in a column, as you have also seen in the previous tutorial, and we were covering the key and
the Haski function, it did not work when we specified in the quotation marks and by using this index.
But when we were using this index, we use the key as this and then the GUI and the Haski function work
and it returned to.
So that's why when you are using this index, you have to use this column if you already know this.
So for the first hash, we have used the first E column ÁLFHEIÐUR for the second list, use the second
one, column B and for the third, let's use this turkey.
That is column C.
So let's just run this record, and as you can see, that IDEX from Hundert has been it from two hundred
and hash seeded from three.
And so basically the big function is a function that is used to extract the value or you can fetch the
value.
But this is a different way of fetching the value from the hash we have specified right at the top helm.
So you can just change it.
For example, you can just try and seal here and you can see that it has now fetch the value for see
if you write in something that is not a part of it.
For example, if I just write in deal here, Ronda's, you can see that it has just generated empty
o'haire.
It has not generated any kind of error, which it would have in case of fetch function, which was I
guess, Genard form function.
But in case of dig it did not get done any kind of error, but it returned nil value as a w that this
finds the nested value which is specified by the sequence of the key object by calling dig at each step.
So it is calling dig at each step.
And for this certain key we have specified right over here that is calling the let's say so for this,
it is going to generate Dignidad dig out the value and it is going to bring that out on your output
screen and for a value that is not a part of it.
It is going to keep digging till the end of this hash.
Since it has three values, it is going to take its three values and after that it finds nothing.
So it is going to return and it is going to and just print out an empty space rather than printing out
or returning an error message, which it did in the case of fetch function.
So that was it about these two functions.
And I hope to use them in Ruby, so I hope you have understood them.
So I guess that's to do with this tutorial as well.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.