Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another Dooralong on this course, on Ruby, and in this part
of the section we will talk about the flood control in Ruby.
Now, we will define several methods that will enable us to control the flow of Ruby program.
Conditionals and loops alter the flow of Ruby program conditionals are the key words that execute a
certain statement under a specific condition, whereas loops are the block of programs that are executed
multiple times.
Now, when you run a program, the statements are going to get executed from the top of the source file
to the bottom one by one in a sequential order.
Now, if you talk about some of the flow controls, you have them right on your screens, starting on
with the F, which is a conditional statement.
Then we have else and else which are used in combination with the Elseworlds.
Then we have the case statement, which is also, again, a conditional flow control and we have the
until, which is a key word.
Then we have the break, which is also going to control the flow of code.
Then we have the volume, then we have the for loop, then we have the each which is again used in combination
almost with four, and it makes also a loop.
Then we have the next and then we have the ruby.
Do you.
So all of these basically are key words which are going to control the flow of your code and how it
is going to control the flow of your code that you are going to see on from the next drill, where we
will discuss all of these in detail one by one.
So that's it with this drill.
Thank you so much, guys.
We're watching and I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.