Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another Dorelle on this course, on Ruby now since we are
covering object oriented programming.
So from this material, we are going to start on with a new concept that is polymorphism, not in Ruby.
One does not have nothing like the variable type as there is in other programming languages.
Every variable is an object which can be individually modified.
One can easily add methods and functions on every object.
So here the object oriented programming plays a major role.
Now there are many pillars of object oriented programming in every programming language like you have
covered inheritance, you have covered encapsulation.
Now one of those spillar is known as polymorphism.
Now, polymorphism comes from the Greek word that is basically a combination of two words.
The first one is Poli's, which means many or you can say more, and then the second word is more.
That means form or shape.
So in programming, polymorphism refers to the ability to use functions or methods in different ways
for different objects or data types.
Having the ability to use the same method in a different way, depending on the data input, is very
useful.
In Ruby, it greatly decreased the need for ugly long if statements.
So, for example, if I just give you an example of how polymorphism has basically helped produce the
ugly if statement.
So let's say you have a class or a hill that is named as.
Person and in that last, let's say you have a constructor function.
That has two arguments which are going to get received over here.
First one is first, then it is going to have lost.
And here we are going to receive the first name, the last name.
And finally, we are going to receive the age for the person.
So and here we are going to use the instance variable and we are going to just initialize values over
here.
So we are going to write in first name equal to first.
And.
Second name or just say last name.
Is equal to last, and finally, we are going to specify age is going to equal to age.
Just and this constructor function over here now, we are going to add one more function that is going
to be the birthday function.
And in this function, what we are going to do is that we are going to increment the age every time
the birthday for a person comes, the age is going to get incremented by one for that person.
So we are going to write and add the rate of age plus equal to one.
So this means that it is going to get incremented by one whenever this birthday function is going to
get called just and dysfunction, and we are going to have one more function, which is going to be
introduced function.
And in this function where we are going to do is that we are going to use if statements now, so we
are going to write in the type equal equal to.
Students.
Then what it is going to print on, it is going to print puts.
I am.
Student.
My name is you're going to use Interpellation Abargil and you're going to write and at the rate of.
First underscore a said, he's going to say, my name is this, and he's also going to specify his last
name.
So we are going to just add Aspasia here.
Interpellation and we are going to specify the age for sorry, not the age, but the last name for that
person.
So we are going to write any last name over here.
And this is going to be, I guess, a small Ambulante also specified right at the start.
So that it is it is an instance variable oakhill.
Good enough, the next thing we are going to do is that we are going to have Alcivar here.
If the type equal to.
A teacher, then what it is going to do is that it is going to print on this very same statement over
here, so we will just copy the statement from here.
And we are going to just base this statement right to a hill.
And now he's going to say, I am a teacher.
My name is this, and this is going to print out the first name and the last name as well, then let's
say he is a parent.
So we are going to specify one more elusive condition.
So that is going to be as if.
Type is equal, equal to a parent then what it is going to do is that it is going to simply print on.
The very same statement and but now this is going to say.
Berrendo Hill is just a get in a bed so we can see the complete tangle here.
Now, I guess we can have a look by just making it a hill good enough.
And now, finally, let's say we have these tree types.
So let's say finally we are going to specify in condition that nothing is true.
What it is going to do is that it is going to ride and puts.
My name is and you're going to just right at the rate of.
First name.
Along with that, you are going to ride in at the rate of lost and to a name.
All right, good enough.
And I guess, yes, we have this extra overhead.
This does not have to be a part of this.
And now it is going to work perfectly or we need to do is that we need to just end this if condition
and this function and finally end this class as well.
All right.
So after that, what we are going to do is that we are going to create an object for the person class.
And then through that, we are going to call in the introduce function and we are going to specify some
kind of type.
So we are going to write in, John.
Equal do person Dot knew, and and here we are going to specify three parameters that are going to get
passed to deconstruct a function of the class person, and the first argument is going to be the first
name.
So let's say it is, John.
Let's say the second argument is DOA.
And finally, we are going to specify the age that is 20 or so.
Now, using this object, John, we are going to do is that we are going to call in the introduce function
and then introduce function.
We are going to specify the type.
So let's say the person is a student.
So I guess that's good enough.
All we need to do is that we need to run this code.
All right, it is executed and it says, I am a student and my name is John Doe, so I guess you can
see the output clearly.
It says I am a student and my name is John Doe.
Now, the since the person the type you have specified a student, so that by this conditional here
was true and it has printed on I am a student and my name is John Doe.
Now if you just specify, let's say a teacher will run the school and it is going to print on.
I am a teacher and my name is John Doe.
And let's say if you specify nothing of whatever is specified in the if condition, let's say if you
just type in, a worker will run this code and it is going to simply say, my name is John Doe.
Now, you can do it like that, but as you can see that it is a very, very mixing type of thing and
it is a very difficult thing to do to understand it.
It is very simple, but.
Do write down, you can see that how complex it is it now with polymorphism, what we are going to do
is that we are going to eliminate this ugly if statement by creating multiple classes that all have
the introduce method in them.
We are just going to change what the introduced method does for each class.
So that is what is basically called polymorphism with inheritance.
So all of our different types of people that are students, parents and teachers are the person and
they share similarities like names and birthdays.
We don't want to eliminate the person.
Class are the common methods.
We are going to add class for each type of person that will inherit the person class.
Then our new classes will inherit the common methods from person, but will have a customized method
that is going to be named as introduce.
So what we will do is that we will just remove this stuff to help and we are going to have our constructor
function as usual, and it is going to, as usual, receiving three arguments.
The first one is the first name.
Then we have the last name.
And finally we have the age.
And we are going to initialize all of these three parameters using the instance variables.
Now, after that, what we are going to have is that we are also going to have the body function.
So I should not have removed that has just created very quickly age.
Plus, equal to one now, whatever is going to be common between all the classes that a student, teacher
and parents, that is going to be a part of this person class since all the other classes that a student
class, the teacher class and the parent class, which we are about to create, are basically going
to get inherited from this person class.
And you know that when a class is inherited from some class, then it inherits all its future as well.
Now, since birth is a feature that is going to be a part of every kind of class.
So that's why what we will do is that we will just create the birthday function right over here.
So, yes.
And this functional hill.
And we are going to create the introduce function over here as well, and using the introduce, I'm
going to just write and put.
Hi.
My name is and you're going to write an.
First name.
And you're going to write and last name as well.
So just in this function, the class has already been ended.
Now, what we are going to do is that we are going to create our three classes.
So the first class is going to be the student class.
Then we are going to create the teacher class.
And finally, we are going to create a parent class.
And all of these classes will have the method that is going to be the introduce method.
So down here, let's just create our first class that is going to be the student class and this class
is going to get inherited from the person class and in that, we are going to simply have function introduce
and in that function what we are going to write inputs.
I am a student and my name is Interpellation First and a school name Aderet, because it is an instance
variable and you are going to specify.
The last name as well, good enough, let's just end this function.
And just and this glass as well, so it is a very simple looking glass, so let's just copy this glass
from here and we will paste it twice over here.
So the first one was for the student.
Now we are going to create the same thing for the teacher class.
So we are going to write and teacher over here and now here we are going to just replace this with a
teacher.
So he's going to say, I am a teacher and my name is this.
And then the third class is going to be for the parent.
So that is going to say that I am a parent and my name is first name, and then he's going to specify
his last name as well.
Now downhill, what we are going to do is that we are going to just create the object, but this time
the object is going to be created for this specific class.
So if you want this stuff for the students or what you are going to do is that you are going to do this
for the student class.
So we are going to just pass in the three parameters that as the first name, the last name, then the
edge.
And when you now right and Johnboat introduce, you do not need any kind of parameter is now around
this code.
And it is going to say that I am a student and my name is John Doe.
Now if you do this very same for the feature class or underscored, you can see that says I am a teacher
and my name is John Doe.
But let's say if you created for the parent class, that is the person class, for example, if you
just write in person over here and now run this code, now it is going to simply say, hi, my name
is John Doe, because now this function of a hail.
Is going to get executed now.
For example, you have these glasses and let's say if you don't have an introduce glass in one of these,
for example, you just misplace misspell this or that is introduced over here and you create an object
for the glass over here.
And now run God, now he's going to say, hi, my name is John Doe.
Now, as you have covered the hierarchy in the previous tutorial where we have covered the hierarchy
of the object class, and you know that first it is going to look for the introduce function in the
teacher class.
But since you can see that it has no kind of introduce function of my hair because we have just added
a deal here.
So that's why it is going to then move on towards the parent class from which this class teacher is
inherited.
And in that class it is going to find introduce function and he's going to print out.
Hi, my name is first name and last name.
So that is what is basically called polymorphism in which we have a same.
Function you can see introduced in the child glasses as well as independent glasses.
So this was a very simple example of how polymorphism can be used in Ruby and how polymorphism can be
used along with inheritance.
Now, there is one more very important concept relating to polymorphism is that how do you use polymorphism
using duck typing now in Ruby, the focus on the object capabilities and features rather than its glass.
So a duck typing is nothing but working on the idea of what an object can do rather than what it actually
is, or what operation could be performed on the object rather than the class of the object.
So I tried my best to create an example of myself.
But on the Internet, on a website, I found a very beautiful example of Doug typing, of using polymorphism,
using duck typing.
So I would just explain that example to him.
So we'll just remove this from here, we will be prejudiced and what we are going to do is that we are
going to create two classes.
The first one is going to be the whole class.
And in that hotel class, what we are going to do is that we are going to have multiple functions.
The first function is going to be the entrance function.
So whenever a customer is going to enter the hotel, we are going to call on this function and we are
going to just write in.
A customer.
Entered the hotel, all right, to just end dysfunction and then what we are going to do is that we
are going to have one more function that is going to be and.
And that function is going to be the type and the type function, we are going to receive an argument
as well that is going to be the customer.
And here we are going to write in customer a DOT type.
So this is going to get written and we are going to just write in the end statement of a hail.
Now, right up to the time we are going to create a room function and in that room function, we are
again going to receive the argument that is the customer.
And and here we are going to write in customer dot room just.
And this.
And finally, and this class as well.
And right down here, what we are going to now do is that we are going to create a class with two methods.
So that last name is going to be single.
And in that class, what we are going to do is that we are going to create two functions.
The first one is going to be the type function and the second function is going to be the room function.
So these are basically this function of a hill, which we are calling right from this hotel function
right over here.
So the first function is type the second function is going to be and we are going to define them over
here.
So we are going to write in-depth type.
And in that function, we are going to write inputs.
Room is.
On the.
Flaugher.
Simple enough, just and this and the second function is going to be the room function and in that room
function, we are going to just write in votes.
Per night stay is.
Let's say 50 just and this will help.
And this all here as well.
Now, what we are going to do is that we are going to create another class that is going to be the class
couple.
And in that class, what we are going to do is that we are going to define the very two same function
that are the type and the room.
So we are going to just copy this class from Hill.
They stood over here and we are going to just rename this class to be the couple's class.
So when a person is single, then this class is going to get used and one person comes in a couple and
this class over here is going to get used.
Now comes the job of creating an object where the whole story lies.
So what we are going to do is that we are going to write an.
Hotel equal to hotel.
So we have basically created an object of this closable here that is at the top of a hill.
So now what we are going to do is that we are going to write and puts.
This visitor is single, and right after this, we are going to use the glass that is for singles,
so we are going to create an object for that.
So we are going to write in customer equal to and the name of the class, as you know, is single with
a capital S..
So we are going to write and single.
Deutche new.
And then what you're going to do is that using this object that has been created over here, we are
going to call it the two functions.
So we are going to write in a hill.
Door type, and we are going to pass in the argument that is customary now, as you can see, that the
hotel object is basically created for the hotel glass, which is right at the top here in which we have
the type function, as well as the room function, which also have been overridden in the two other
glasses.
That is the single glass and the glass.
So basically we are using this object with the type and we are going to call in the type function.
And we are going to pass in this as an argument that is the customer object that has been created for
this single class, and we are going to also call in the other functions.
So we are going to write in a hotel room and we are going to pass in the same very argument that is
customer.
Now, what we are going to do is that we are going to also do it for the other one.
So we are going to just copy this face to the wall here.
And we are going to write in this wisdom is.
Or you can just ride in this visit these visitors, and this has to be these these visitors.
Ah, in a couple, and now what you're going to do is that you're going to create an object for the
couple over here and this here is going to remain the very same.
So if you just run this code, you're going to see very interesting things that will help.
So the first thing it says is that it says the visitor is single and then it says the room is on the
fifth floor and the per night state is five thousand.
Then it says these visitors are a couple.
And it's again says the room is on the fifth floor and the night state is five.
Now, what's going on over here is that basically this glass over here, that is the hotel glass is
basically being used to excess there.
So when you just write in, everything from this is going to get extracted.
But when you are using this object and creating the object and now you are using this object to call
in type and you are just writing in customer will here.
And as you can see, that it is basically going to expect an argument over here.
So that argument is going to get passed over here.
This is going to get executed and it is going to now go on in customer time now since we are calling
it and passing in an object over here.
So that's why now it knows that a glass single also exists in the single glass.
It is going to look for the function type and as you can see, that it is right over here.
So it is going to bring down the room is on the fifth floor or similarly, when you execute this statement
over here, hotel room and again, you are calling this with the hotel object and you are passing in
the object for the single glass of a hill.
So first it is going to call the room function that is present in the hotel clause.
So it is going to come right over here in the room and it is going to receive the object here in the
parameters.
And now in here it knows that a class name and a single exists because now it has the object.
And as I told you before, that the object is basically a blueprint of a class.
So since it has received the blueprint of that class, so now it can access the functions of that class
as well.
So now it knows that it has a class single and the class, when it goes into it, he knows that he has
to call this functional Mahara.
He's going to search for the function room over here and it is going to find that function and it is
going to print out the permanent status.
Five thousand and the same logic is going to get executed for this stuff over here.
So in this example, the customer object basically plays a role in working with the properties of the
customer, such as its type.
And it's true, and this is a very beautiful example of polymorphism as far as the duct taping is considered
with polymorphism.
So this is how basically you can use polymorphism using the duct taping.
So now you know how to use polymorphism with inheritance, with objects and also with duct tape.
So I guess that's it with polymorphism.
So thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I will see you guys in the next tutorial.