Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another drill on this course on Ruby and in this story.
And we are going to cover one more topic that is related with object oriented programming, and that
is method or writing now in object oriented programming method or writing is a language feature in which
a subclass can provide an implementation of Obamacare, which is already mentioned by superclusters.
Implementation of a method in the subclause replaces the implementation of a method in the superclass.
So you've already covered that.
This concept, which we are about to cover in the previous Giorgio's, but in the previous Dorians we
did not specify the name which is associated with this concept of all that is method to writing.
So let's discover a very simple example of this.
So let's say you have a class A.
And then in this class, you have a function which just sprints out both.
Plus eight and just and dysfunction and this loss, and then let's say you have a class B that is inherited
from Class A and that you have a gain of function.
And this time the function prints on both.
Class B and the function and the class, and now if you create an object for the Class B school, for
example, if you just try and be equal, do vetoed Nunzia, this means that an object for Class B has
been created.
And if you just write and B, dot A, run this code, you can see that it is printed out Class B now
as you can see that this Class B is basically a child class of this class.
And you know about the class hierarchy, class object hierarchy.
And you know that this class will help contain both these functional board, the functions that are
named with the same name that is er will help.
But in this case, since you are creating an object of this class B, so always remember that for the
last for which an object is created, that class functions are given a priority over the super classes.
In other words, the method in the Class B has overridden the method in Class A.
For example, if you create this object for Class EOWA here.
Then if you run the school, then as simple as that, it is going to bring down velocity because the
class aid function, it does not know that A Class B function, which is by its own name, also exists.
So for that it is simple.
The or overriding concept does not lie there.
But for the child class, if you create an object and in there, if you have a function that is also
a part of the upper function of Waddill, then that is basically known as function.
Or you can say method overwriting.
So that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you guys in the next territorials.