Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Ruby.
And in this drill, we are going to start on with the flow control, key words.
And the first key word we are going to cover is the if statement.
Now, if key word is used to check up an expression is true or not, if it is true, a set of statement
is going to be executed.
Now, the statement can be a single line or it can be a compound statement.
Now, a compound statement basically consist of multi-line statements that are enclosed by a block.
And you know that a block is a code that is always enclosed by the end.
Key word.
Now here we can also use the then word, but the key word is basically optional.
So if you talk about the syntax for how it is going to use so this is basically the syntax for that,
you have to specify if then you have to write in the condition, then you have to write and then but
this Denoyer here is optional.
If you don't want to use it, even then it is going to act in the very same way, but it is only added
to make it look a bit more handsome.
So if you want to specify it, just specify it.
But if you don't want to specify it, don't do it.
And after that, when you click enter, you are automatically going to enter a block and that block
you are going to write in the statements that you want to execute if this condition is true.
So whatever condition you have specified here, if it is true, then the statements you have specified
over here, it can be a single statement or it can be compound statements.
Those statements are going to get executed and all the statements starting on from that then and then
ending on with this and keyword.
All those statements are going to get executed if this condition is true.
Then we have as if statements in which basically we are using multiple ifs and the syntax for that is
right or here you can write and if you can write in condition number one, then you can write in the
statements you want to execute a condition.
No one is true.
Then you can write an E Alekseyev that stand for else if which means that if the first condition is
not true, then you want to check in the second condition.
Then the second condition is true.
You want a set of statements to get executed and when you want to end it, you can just write in and
O'Hare.
So these are basically also called s multiple if statements, but in programming it is called S else
F then you have the L statement that is also used in combination with the F condition and you cannot
use if condition alone.
You also always have to use it with a condition so you can as you can see right in F condition, number
one statement to execute, then you can write and else if condition number two you can write and then
you can then write the conditions you want to execute.
If condition number two is true, then you can write an S and then you can write in the statements to
get executed and the statements to execute it in the else block are going to get executed in both.
The condition above are false and you can just use elsewhere the signal condition as well.
And you can use the Aylsworth three conditions as well, but you can not use it alone.
You always have to use it whether if condition.
So we have to talk about the syntax of all of the three.
Keywords that are basically associated with if the first one is if it's self, then you have the Alsup
and then you have the Wolski word.
So let's just try all of these three on our ED.
So let's move on to Adam.
And what we are going to do is that let's say I want to calculate, let's say the result for a student.
So let's say we have a variable that is Moggs and let's say the marks of the students are, let's say
85.
So what I want to do away here is that I want to specify if marks are greater than, let's say, 80.
Then what I want is that I want to put.
You have.
Secured.
Good marks.
So simple enough, so if the Moncks, which you have entered over here are greater than 80, which means
that if this condition is true, then it is going to execute this statement right over here that says
you have secured good marks and you can just ride in and out here, run the score.
And as you can see, that it is processing it.
And as you can see that it has printed out, you have secured good marks because this condition right
over here is true.
So, for example, let's say this condition is not true, which means that it is, let's say 70.
Now, this marks are not greater than 70.
Run this discord and.
Yes, it is, again, greater than 70, you have to write in something bigger.
Sorry, my bad.
So to right in 91, this good.
And as you can see, that it has existed, but you can see that nothing is being printed because this
condition was not true.
It came out nothing after that.
So nothing was printed on the atom there as well.
Now comes the then key word, if you want to use the Denki, whatever hair you can ride in a hair underscored,
nothing is going to get printed, make it through, let's say, 80 around the school and it is going
to print out.
You have secured good marks.
So this denki whatever hair is optional, this is going to print in both the ways either.
If you specify then a hair and if you don't specify the no hair even then it is going to get printed,
which means the if condition is not dependent on this Denki word.
Now, secondly comes the elusive key word that is basically used if you want to check in multiple conditions
now, for example, you want to check in for, let's say, more tanks than you can just ride in.
You have secured.
A great.
So if the marks are greater than 80, what do you want to do is that or let's say just make it 90?
So if the marks are greater than 90, then you want to write and you have secured a grade, then you
can write an E as I f.
I'll save the marks if there are greater than, let's say, 80.
Then what you're going to do is that you are going to put.
You have.
Secured the great.
Then you can check on for one more condition, let's say, if.
The marks are greater than, let's say, 70.
Then what you're going to do is that you're going to put.
You have secured.
Secret.
So I guess that's enough.
You already have this and O'Haire, so just run the score and as you can see that it is printed out.
You have secured the grid because this condition over here is true.
That is Mok's is greater than 80.
Now, one thing you need to know over here more is that this condition over here, as you can see,
is also true because 85, which is what is stored in this box, is also greater than 70.
And this condition over here is also true.
Then why did it only printed it out?
This it should also have printed out this as well.
But as you can see that since it is a single block which start on from this if and it ends on with this
and keyword.
So that's what it is basically a single kind of thing.
You can just call it a single block.
So if any of the conditions over here is true, for example, since this condition was true, this was
also just skip this and it starts on to check the second condition now when the second condition was
true.
So what it did is that it printed out whatever was in the statements of this second keyword.
It printed out those because the second condition was true.
It printed out.
You have secured the grade and it will simply skip all the lines after that.
So this means that it did not even check this third condition, because since it has found the result,
it don't have to check for any other condition.
So this statement over here did not even get executed.
So if it did not get executed, so that's why you have not got you have your cigarette on your screen.
So always remember that if you have multiple if you are using the elusive oakhill.
So if one condition is true, all the conditions after that are simply going to get ignored, even if
they are true.
So that's why you have this output out here.
Then comes the third key word.
That is the Wolski word.
And you are going to also use it in this blog.
So you're going to just write and else click, enter and you can just write in both.
And you can simply ride and you failed.
So if his marks are less than 70, which means he failed.
These are not the marks you are going to get failed on, but let it be so.
Just run the score and it is going to bring down the second same output.
So let's say we enter something which is less than 70, which means all these three conditions over
here are false.
So now run the score and it is going to print out.
You fail.
So if all the conditions above the EL statement are false.
Then whatever the condition is, whatever statements you have written in the else block are going to
get executed, so you can call it a mini block for this.
This is the major block in which all these statements are present.
You can call all of these as many blogs.
Then this is going to be the first milblog.
This is the second block.
This is the third block.
And this is the fourth block.
So the fourth mini block, which is for the LS Keywood.
And whatever statements are in that mini block, those statements are going to get executed if all the
statements above that are false.
Now, one thing over here is that can you specify one more elusive after you have specified this so
you can just write in, for example, as if Mark's.
Let's say we write an equal equal to 60, which is true.
You are going to write in votes.
You secured.
Sixty, let's say so run this code now, and as you can see, that it has generated an error message.
That is because the URLs should always be at the very, very, very end after, as you cannot specify,
or else if you want to use another Allsup and you want to use if you want to check on with another condition,
you have to just move out of this blog and you have to create a new blog with this if and statement
over here.
So I guess that's clear with the if saeki what we have covered if condition we have covered El-Sayed.
That is basically the multiple FS condition and we have used the L word as well.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much guys, for watching.
I'll see you guys in the next Derryl with a Newquay word.