Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to an editorial on this course on Ruby.
In this tutorial, we are going to be covering a very interesting topic that is about parallel assignment.
Now, Ruby supports the parallel assignment of variables which can be done in a single operation, and
therefore you can declare several variables to the left as an assignment operator and several variables,
several values to the right, which are going to be treated as the values to the operator, as you have
just specified to the left of the order of the values to the right must be the same to the variables
on the left.
So let's just go to a very quick example for this, and then I guess that will be more easy to understand.
So I just want to add to more here and let's say I want to specify three variables and assign three
values to it.
For example, I want to let's just say that I want to use a then I want to specify be the one to specify
C, and I want to make them equal to, let's say, Ruby.
And a coma.
Tutorials.
And let's say the third one is instructor.
So if I just now print all of these one by one puts a.
Both B and C and just press all plus R, then you can see that it has printed me all of these Scruby
tutorials and instructors.
So instead of just doing a sequel to Ruby and then on the next line be equal to Oriels and then on the
next third line writing sequel to Instructor, you can just use the concept of parallel assignment,
which is supported by Ruby, and you can assign all these three values, the values in a single line,
which is basically called parallel assignment.
So the order of the execution here is very important.
Now, whatever the first value over here is, it is going to be assigned the first value, which is
quite easy to understand, I guess.
And the last one is going to be given the lost value and so on.
If you have any number of values, the sequence is going to be followed.
Now, what's important about here is that if there are three values over here, it is much that you
have three values over here or else it is going to generate error.
For example, if I just remove one from here or plus R, then you can see that it has only given me
the first two that it puts and puts me because C was given no kind of value.
Now, for example, just specify a comb, our hair, all our hair, then it is going to give me an error
because I have specified some special hair, but I haven't specified any value now.
But if I just simply put this.
Quotation marks will here, all plus are then it is going to give me some output because now it is going
to treat this as nothing of value that is equal to nothing.
So basically a value is given, but that is nothing to that's what a simple space is pretty dry to here,
as you can see on the output screen and both be dead.
Nothing.
So if you can specify some value again, that was I guess to Dorio see as it was.
And plus all plus are all the three values are right over here.
So that is basically the concept of parallel assignment, which I guess was very simple to understand.
So I guess that's this tutorial as well.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next Attrill.