Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Ruby.
And in this story, we are going to see how to reduce the error to a single value.
Now, when you are working with a set of data, you may find that you need to roll up the data up into
a single value, such as, let's say, count some results, result.
One way you might do this is using a variable and you can use just the each method to just do your job.
But there is one more way that is Beldin and Ruby.
But first, we will try on what the regular one that is using the each method.
So we will define a variable that is some that is going to equal to zero.
And in here we are going to define an area that contains, let's say, these four elements, one, two,
three and four.
We are going to call each method on this.
And you know what?
The each method do it actually iterate over all the elements and do some job on it.
And what is going to be that is going to be whatever is specified over here.
We are going to write a number here, which is going to have the first value.
And what we are going to write in here is going to.
Some.
Less equal to whatever that number is and down here, what you can do is that you can just try and print
some Joe, just run the score and you can see that you have got the sum that is one plus two equals
three three plus three equal to six and six plus four equal to ten.
So what's going on over here is that for the first iteration, it is going to take one into the numbers.
So a number is going to equal to one and the sum is going to equal to zero after that one.
This attrition works.
What it is going to do is that it is going to add the sum to the number.
So the sum is now going to equal to zero plus one and it is going to equal to one in the next iteration.
The number is.
And it's just moving up in the next iteration, the number is going to be two and the sum is going to
be now one, which has been updated, and now the sum is going to equal to one plus two, and that is
going to make it equal to three and so on.
It will go till the last iteration, until it has got the last result that is done.
So to do this very same job, what you can do is that you can use the reduced method as well.
Other reduced methods, it rates out an entire area and it keep running total by executing a bindery
operation for each element.
The reduced method accepts an initial value for the result, as well as a block with two local values.
That is a reference to the result and a reference to the current element.
Now, inside of the block, you specify the logic to compute the end result.
Since we want to sum up an area, we will initialize the result to zero and then add the current value
to the result in the block.
So how that is going to be done, let's just do it with the help of an example so we don't need this
because the initialization is going to be done by the reduced function itself.
So what are you going to write in?
You are going to write in a variable, let's say, out that is going to store the results.
So that is going to equal to one, two, three for the area which you want to sum up and you don't need
to reduce.
Sorry, you don't need each O'Haire you need to reduce over here.
So we are going to write and reduce.
We are going to just remove this from here.
And what we are going to do is that, as I told you, it contains two variables.
And in that the first variable is basically the reference to a result and the second one is a reference
to the current element.
So those elements are, let's say r e.
S.
And the second one is the current element.
So what we are going to do over here is that we are going to write and are as plus equal to the current
value.
So that is what is going to just do our job.
All you need to do is that you have to write in out of a hill.
And if you just run this code, you can see that you have got tenure here as well.
Now, you can also initialize the starting value as well if you want to.
You can just write in zero, which is going to be the starting value for.
You can see that you have got the very same outfit, so if you use this, if you don't use it, it is
going to work properly if you plan to initialize the result to zero.
You can just admit the argument and just passed the blog.
This will automatically send the result, the first value in the error.
So if you don't just don't do it.
What it is going to do, it is going to treat this as the first value.
But if you just do it, it is going to have no effect because zero added to anything always generate
the very same zero.
So the reduced method also in the reduced manner.
You also specify a binary method or a method on one object that accepts another object as its argument,
which it will execute for each entry in the area.
Now, the REDUCE then uses the result to create a single value.
For example, when you just try to Placita in Ruby, you're actually invoking the plus method on the
integer two so that if you just write in two plus two, that is two dot plus two.
So that is basically calling the plus method on this too.
So Ruby uses some syntactic sugar so you can express it as two plus two in the simple way.
Now the reduced method lets you simplify and specify a binary method by passing its name as a symbol.
That means you can pass the colon and plus to the reduced method to sum the error.
Now, how that is going to be done, it is going to simplify this job ahead.
That is to sum an error as well.
So all you have to do over here is that you don't need all this stuff over here.
Just remove it from here.
And all you have to do that, you have to write a column and you have to write and plus sign of how
the rest is going to be the same, just run the score and you can see that you still have got the 10
hour hell so you can use the reduced to do more than just add a list of numbers.
You can use it to transform values as well.
Remember that the reduce reduces an error rate to a single value, but there is no rule that says the
other single value cannot be another array.
Now, let's say we have a list of values that we need to convert to integer, but we only want the values
that can be converted into integers so we could use the reject function of our hair, which you have
covered in the previous tutorial, to throw out the non American values and then use the map to convert
the remaining values to integer.
But we can do it all in one step with the reduced function is out now.
Use an empty array as the initialization value, then in the block, convert the current value to an
integer with the integer method.
If the value cannot be converted to an integer, that integer will raise an exception which you can
catch and assign a node to the value.
Then take the value, put it in an array, but only if it is not nil.
Now, to try out the code, what you can do is that just remove this from here.
We will have an error in which we will have integer as well as we will have string.
So that's where the reduced function is going to work and it is going to only just have those number
that are integer as well.
We are going to do is that we are going to rescue the values that are there.
So we are going to just write and.
One.
Do.
Three, and let's say then comes a value that should not be a part of this.
And finally, we can have four, we going to have five.
So this is basically the area we are going to use.
I guess we just missed this exclamation.
Well, here now it is perfectly fine.
Now, what you can do over here is that you can just use the reduced function of a hill.
So what we are going to do is that we are going to write and integers equal to.
X dot reduce.
And with the reduced, what we are going to do is.
We are going to specify these brackets over here, which means that this is an error, so we're going
to rewrite and do just click enter the end is going to get generated.
And over here, what you can do is just specify these.
And you can just write in every.
And current.
Then you can just ride and the value is going to equal to the class integer that is a built in word
you can just ride in the current value.
So it is going to actually get each and every every value, one at a time, and it is going to check
it if it is an integer or not.
So if it is, what it is going to do is that it is going to.
Rescue, no.
And finally, we are going to push the elements into an area that are basically.
The elements that are in danger, so we are going to ride and value and we are going to use the unless
well, you don't know.
So if the value is no, we are going to push it and we are going to ride an area where hell.
And I think we have a problem here, that's why this is not color, that's purple.
Yes, I call it the problem.
My bad.
You have to write this as the wrong bracket is not the curly brackets of hair.
And you can see that you've got this will help.
So all this is perfectly fine.
All right.
In here, is that right?
Writing puts in teachers will help run the school.
And you can see that you have got the elements.
What you want to point out, one, two, three, four, five.
You can see that it has been simply eliminated.
So to explain what's going on over here, basically we have defined an area which is a combination of
numbers as well as we have got this area here, which is an alphabet number.
So are you going to do is that you are going to have this in digits about how you were going to write
in the extra traduce for that?
And what what is the use of reduced function is it is going to convert the entire area into a single
value, so.
What is going on over here is that we have used an empty array as the initialization value, which is
right or held so reduced basically whenever as in the previous case when I was just summing up the numbers,
if you just remember, I just tried and reduce and then end the brackets.
I just right in zero.
And that means that I want to start the initialization value of zero.
So when you write in reduced and these empty brackets.
Well, here's what this means, that we are using the empty array as the initialization value, then
what in the block we do is that we convert the current value to an integer with the integer function.
So what's going on over here is that it is going to take the current value that is going to be for the
first iteration.
One, it is going to convert it into a string.
And if the value cannot be converted into dijo, what it is going to do is it is going to raise an exception
which you can catch and assign it Danielle values to be just right and risk, you know, if that value
is not is not able to convert into strength.
So for this value, when the attrition number four is going to get executed for this block over here,
we know that the current value then can not be converted into an integer.
So instead, to raise an exception, what you can do is that you can just rescue that exception and
you can just ride and rescue Nullable here.
And you don't need to worry about this.
Go ahead.
That is going to be a part of the future tutorials when we will be covering the exception handling.
But for now, you only need to understand that in order to not raise any kind of error message, because
we know that it cannot be converted into integer.
So that's why we have just right in this so that no kind of error occur and do the error message.
We will just assign a no value.
So after all, this is run, what we will have is that down here we will have the X.
Zero location.
We will have one then soon we will have the entire values, but for this ex as three, which basically
contains this area here, because this is a zero for second and third location, what we will have is
that we will have unsalable help.
So this line, I hope you understood this, we have a signed we have converted the numbers into strengths,
not in the strings, we have converted them into integers and we have assigned a new value to the.
Elements which cannot be converted into strength, so extreme malcontents Miller and the rest of the
contains one, two, three, four or five, respectively.
Now, if you talk about this line, what's going on over here is that after converting numbers into
strengths, what we will do is that we will take the value and put it in the area, which has been written
right over here.
And that is going to be this array, which is initialized to zero for now.
So what we are going to do is that we are now going to push the values and what are those values those
values are going to be?
This will help.
But since we know that we have also got this extra unit over here and we don't want this value to get
pushed into the area we are creating.
So what we are going to write and we are going to use the Wolinsky whatever here and we are going to
push elements into the area unless the value is now.
So for this this statement is not going to get executed and this is not going to get pushed into this
area.
So just do this, add up to that just right in this here.
Right in over here.
And it is going to have the area that is the number excluding the SOHEL.
So final nodes, whenever you have a list of elements that you need to convert to a single value, you
might be able to solve it with a reduced function, as you have seen in this tutorial.
So I guess we have covered a lot for this tutorial.
I will see you guys in the next tutorial with some more interesting topics.
So by VITELLIN.