Hey, guys, what this is a marathon, and I welcome you to another Dorel on this course, on Rowby
and in this story, we are going to be covering the case statement in Ruby.
Now, the key statement is a motive, a broad statement, just like a switch statement in other languages.
It provides an easy way to forward execution to different parts of the code based on the value of the
expression.
Now, if you talk about the syntax of a statement, it looks something like this in which you have got
three main keywords.
The first one is the case.
You are then we have the one keyword and then we have the.
Eliscu word now.
The first is the Kierski word now it is similar to the switch key word in other programming languages,
and it takes the variable that will be sent that will be used by the one key word that comes, the one
key word.
Now, it is similar to the Kierski word in other programming languages.
It is used to match a single condition.
There can be multiple one statements into a single gay statement, as you can see or hear as well.
Then we have the key word, which is similar to the default key word in other programming languages,
and it is optional and it will execute when nothing matches.
So as you can see or hear that you have to first write in the expression, then it is going to check
that expression with the one key word.
So it is going to check if expression one is whatever expression is mentioned, then this code, which
is in the block of expression, one is going to be executed.
If this expression do is through, this quote over here is going to be executed on and you can have
any number of expressions that will hear what you want to check.
And if none of these expression is true, then you're going to have this Eliscu word, which is optional.
And if you want to run some good, if none of the expression is true, then that is going to be run
right over here.
So basically, this is how you are going to use the syntax for the case expression.
So moving now, head to the flow diagram, which shows the execution of how God is going to be executed
in a case expression.
So here you can see that it is going to start on with a case expression, then it is going to check
for this one block one.
If the condition over here match with this expression of wahad, this block is going to end.
And if it is not, then it is going to move on.
And one block two after it has checked, one block to it is going to see if it is true or not.
If it is, it is going to end or if it is not, then it is going to go on and check one block three.
And if this one block three is true, it is going to end.
And if it is not, then it is going to go on and check this out.
Now you're going to have any number of bent logs, as I told you earlier, and you can have this one
block, only a single one block over here as well.
So it is going to check it in a sequential order.
And whenever it finds a match, which is true with this expression, so it is going to end.
And if it is not, if all the logs are not true, then what it is going to do, it is going to check
on with this else can be as blog and in the block, we don't have any kind of conditions.
So that's why it is always going to execute this block if none of the conditions in the logs matches
what the is expression.
So let's see some examples now for how all this stuff is going to be done.
So let's move on to our compiler, Adam.
So let's say we have a system in which you want to, let's say, calculate the GPA again, but this
time we have to do it using the statement.
So we are going to write in, let's say, grade equal to and let's say I enter 90 over here.
So now what I'm going to check is that what is going to be the grade for this?
I'm going to have a clear statement in which I will write in grade.
And this grade is basically what is going to be the expression, I will hear that I'm going to write
in when and I'm going to win.
Let's start on with 90 itself.
So it is going to be 90.
What I want to do is that I want to put.
A great.
Then we will have another one condition in which it will be eighty four days it will put in.
Be great and then we will have another one.
For 70, which is going to put.
Sigrid, so finally, we are going to end it up, and if I just run the score, that you can see that
it has printed out a great deal here because the expression over here is equal to 90.
So it is going to start checking and it finds the match with this very first variable that is 90 for
change this variable to 80 run this code.
Now you can see that I have got big red over here because the second one expression over here is true.
Now, now we can also add an else conditional here, which is going to, let's say, puts.
Everyday, if it is not either a 98 or 70, so let's say it is 65.
This discord and it is going to print on F grade now, this kid's expression or this statement is not
good for calculating GPA type of things, because, for example, if I just under, let's say, 75 or
undiscounted, is going to still have this grade because it does not match any three of these.
But it is something other than these.
So it is why that it has printed this.
But our grade over here, you can use ranges over here, but that is going to get a bit more tricky
for you.
So the best is to use the F condition.
If you are a calculating GPA type of things.
Guess expression is also going to help you a lot in many other things.
For example, you want to have matched strings, then it is going to be good.
But if you are dealing with numbers, then the best scenario is to go on and use some other thing.
For example, we have, let's say.
Some domain here.
That is, let's say.
U.S. so.
Not on this condition, it is U.S..
Just let's end this up.
All right, so now the expression over here is going to be demand and we want to check in certain demands.
For example, the first one is the US itself.
And for that, it is going to just print on America.
And then we will have another case expression, let's say G.R..
And for a G.R., it is going to let's say print.
Germany, and then it is going to have another one, for example, it is České, and for that it is
going to print.
Slovakia for the final one, it is going to say.
Unknown if non-match is found, it is going to be arraigned on unknown, if you just run this court,
it is going to have America because the domain over here matches this case.
Expression, if you use something like, let's say České run the score, it is going to have Slovakia.
So give statements are very helpful if you are having something to match on with strings.
So in this program we have basically a domain variable and we need a value for the variable from the
command line when we use the word statement test for the value of the variable.
There are several options.
If the value equals, for example, to you, as you have seen, then America's string is printed to
the console, as you can see over here as well.
So that's how basically this statement can be used in your Ruby programs.
So I guess that's it.
What this jury.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next Dorio.