Hey, guys, what's up?
This is American, and I welcome you to another drill on discourse on Ruby.
And in this story, we are again going to be covering two types of operators.
The first operator we are going to be covering is known as the Ruby Ridge operator.
Now, sequence arranger's in Ruby are used to create a range of successive values consisting of a start
value, add an end value and a range of value that are in between those two values.
Now, in Ruby, these sequences are created using it to arrange operators that are listed right in front
of you.
Now the two dot form creates an inclusive ranch, whereas the three dot form creates a ranch that excludes
the specified high value.
So to start on with the first one, it creates a range from starting point to end point inclusively,
whereas the second one creates a range from start point to end point exclusively.
So we will be discussing examples of that.
But before that, we will discuss about the second type of operator we will be covering in this tutorial
that is known as the defined operator.
Now defined as a special operator that basically takes the form of a method call to determine whether
or not the best expression is defined or not, it returns a description, string of the expression or
it will return nil.
If the expression is not defined, not the defined operator can be used to check if a variable is defined
or not.
What is the scope for that variable?
It can also be used to see the method, let's say, if a method is defined or not.
And what is the scope for that matter?
It is a local scope.
It is a global scope.
Whatever it is, it can also be used with the superguy world and it will check if it can be called or
not.
And it can also be used with the yield keyword and it will return.
True, if a court block has been passed, when you will be using it with a yield keyword.
Now, with every kind of method I have explained, I have explained for you just usage as the first
one is the variable that we will be discussing in this tutorial.
Now, the other three uses that is with a method, then with the superguy word and then with the yield
keyword, all these three will be defined in the future tutorials when we will be discussing those specific
topics.
So how that is going to be used right in here that we will be seeing with the help of an example.
So starting on with the range operator, first we will see how range operators are used.
So we will move on to item.
And now in addition, we are going to do is that we are going to specify a variable equal to one dot
dot then.
So when you specify two dots, this means that you have to specify this range.
That is the lower, lower number.
Then you have to specify the higher range and then you have to specify all the numbers in between this.
So what are you going to do is that you are going to write in inputs a.
Dot.
To underscore a soldier's press control, sorry, Aldar, and that is going to run the court for you.
And as you can see or hear that you have only written one daughter, 10, and you can see that it has
generated numbers from one to 10.
That includes the lowest number, the highest number and all the numbers in between that.
Now, why have you specified this to add this to a means to error?
Because if you just remove this from here, an error message is going to not generate, but it is going
to generate this as it is now.
If you want that, if all to all the numbers do get generated and printed on the atom or their screen,
you have to specify this to underscore.
And as you can see, all the numbers are going to be printed.
Now, as I told you about the triple dot that is going to display the numbers exclusively, what it's
going to do is that it is going to include this lower range, but it is not going to include the higher
range.
Run it.
And you can see that 10 is missing from the scenes.
It is going to display the numbers from one to nine and exclude this number.
That is the highest range, no.
So now moving on to the second topic that is about the defined operator, so let's say we have this
A that is equal to, let's say 10.
So what do we want to do is that we want to check if this is defined or not.
Now, this is a small.
You can simply see that is defined.
But if you are making a huge website, let's say on Ruby Andrius, then what you have to do is that
if you want to check if a certain variable is defined or not, then you can easily check that and you
can also see what is the scope of that variable.
So what you're going to do is that you're going to write in a dot defined and a question mark are underscored.
All right.
It has generated an error.
This has to be placed after this, not with a dot.
So you specify a hole here.
Run this.
And as you can see that it has generated the message that says local variable.
Now what?
It has generated local variables.
This means that a variable is present there and it is present with local scope.
This means that this is good and is a local variable.
Right.
Well, now, for example, I specify below here, run the school.
You can see that nothing is printed on the screen because this B is not defined anywhere in the scene.
So automatically you will come to know that B is not a variable anywhere in your code.
So that's how you can check if a variable is defined or not.
And you can also see certain description about that variable.
And in this case, as you have seen in the previous case, want to specify ÁLFHEIÐUR, run that code.
You can see that you have.
Printed the message local variable, which means that is equal to then is a local variable and it is
defined in your code so you can do the same for methods, you can do it for the super keyword and you
can use it with the yield keyword as well.
But that will be a part of the future tutorials when you will be discussing those topics.
So I guess that's it.
What this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching and I'll see you guys in the next tutorial with some more operators.