Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another tutorial on this course on Drillbit and in this trattoria
we will be covering about substituting strength and we can use two methods to replace strings in Ruby.
The first one is the same method and the second one is the GitHub method.
Now, the GSA basically applies the substitution globally, whereas the sub applies the substitution
to only that instead.
So it is also called as substitution locally.
Now we can use strings or regular expression as the argument to these methods.
With special course, you can insert part of the match into a replacement.
Now, regular expressions can also be used to just use the replacement of the strings.
But since regular expression is going to be covered in the future tutorial, so we will go over those
substitutions later.
For now, we will just deal with the sub and sub that are going to be dealt normally.
So let's say we have a variable that is X that is equal to, let's say, some guy table.
Now with that table, what we are going to do is that if you use sub and you use an exclamation after
that, then that is going to be called an inline replacement.
Whereas if you use normal sub, then this means that it will return another string in these calls.
The first argument is replaced with the second argument.
So, for example, if I want to use a sub right here with this X2, I'm going to add an extra step.
And if I use an exclamation, this means that I'm using an inline replacement.
And what I'm going to do is that I'm going to specify two strings over here.
The first thing is going to be the string that is a part of this, which you want to change.
For example, I want to change the.
With.
Let's say.
Ari, or just make it, Ari, so.
Let's just run the score.
But before that, we have to store it in a variable.
That is why equal to extra substitution and what we have to do is that we have the right inputs.
Why?
So that we can see what's going on.
And as you can see that we have got our Ebele instead of Déby because they got replaced with our.
Now, this was called an inland substitution.
If you just remove this from here, then it will return another string.
So if you just run the score, it is going to return the very same output.
But when we were using sup and exclamation mark, it replaces in line and the sub method, which we
have used right now, it returns another strings.
So now basically, what is the difference between the sub and the sub?
Now the sub method basically replaces just the first instance of a string with another, whereas the
G sub replaces all the instance of a specific part.
So jism is closer to a replaced string method and sub is conceptually a replace for string method.
So what I mean over here is that, for example, if I have table Chilwell.
Well, let's say I have the same strength table table over here and I'm using extorts up with that and
I want to replace the air with our A run the score.
And as you can see, that I've got only are a value for the first one and for the second one, I have
the Dibella as the very same because and it hasn't replaced that for me.
Not I have let's say another variable.
In which I have Z and I will do.
X dot Gizab now, which is a global substitution and I write and 88, which is the string I want to
replace and I want to replace it with R a and I will just write inputs that run this code.
And as you can see on the second line that I've got RB and R a, b, e.
So that's why I said that GitHub is close to a replace string method where a sub is conscious and conceptually
I would replace fostering method because as you can see that when this replacement was applied, it
was applied only on the fostering.
That's why it is called as the replace fostering method.
And when you apply the Gizab, it replaces it for the entire string.
That's why it is called as the replace string method, and that's why it is also called as the global
substitution.
Because when Jesus is used, it checks for every kind of DNA that is available in the entire string.
And wherever it finds the DNA, it is going to replace it with the array.
But in case of substance, it is a local substitution.
So what they do is that it only when it finds the first occurrence of the DNA, it is going to replace
it with RNA and the rest is going to remain the same.
Now, what if let's say we have something like.
Let's say are a something like any kind of word that is before that.
So if you just run that code, you can simply see that you have got Oraibi for the first string and
Dibella as the same.
So it is going to search for the first occurrence of the and it is going to replace it with R.E. and
then the submitter is going to just exit.
But for example, it is going to keep searching for any kind of DNA in the entire string and it is going
to replace it.
So that's basically how Sub and Jessopp are used to substitute strength, and I guess you have also
understood the difference between the two.
Now, regular expressions can also be used in this scenario.
We can specify a regular expression as the first argument to Sabantuy sub and the regular expression
meta characters can be used, but that is going to be a part of the future tutorials when we will be
discussing regular expression for now because you don't know what our regular expressions.
So you want to understand if I do it in this tutorial.
So we will cover it in the future tutorial.
So for now, you only need to understand what is sub what is just up and what is the difference between
the two.
So I hope that you have understood it.
So I guess that's it for this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.