Hey, guys, what's up?
This is a marathon, and I welcome you to another long discourse on drugs and in this story that we
are going to cover six to seven functions that can be applied on areas.
And those are going to be very simple function.
We are going to just see how to find the land of the function, how to pop an area, how to push elements
into an area, how to shift unshaved, how to lead, how to can get it right.
So it is going to be an easy tutorial.
The complex steps have already been covered in the previous tutorial.
So starting on from the land function.
So for now, first we have to initialize an area.
So let's say it is one, two, three, four, five.
All you can do to find the land is that you can use the land function for that.
So you can just write an X dot land around this code and you can see that you have got the land to be
five because it contains five elements right to a hill.
Then you can also use the drop method as well.
And the drop method basically returns the element after the end elements of the area.
So if you just write in X dot drop over here and just specify, let's say do over here, you run this
code.
So every element of this, too, is going to be redone and every element above this is going to get
dropped.
So that's why we have got three, four or five right over here on the output over here.
The next method is basically the method and the method basically permanently remove the last element
of an error.
So what Bob is going to do is that it is going to simply just remove the last element.
If you just run the score, you can see that it has just printed out five.
And down here, if you just write and put X on the score, you can see that now five is missing.
One, two, three, four is a part of this.
So Bob basically deletes the last elements permanently from an error.
Then comes the push method and the push method basically allows you to add an element at the end of
the array.
So if you just write an X, don't push write in six as a parameter, that is going to be the value that
is going to get pushed into this just right.
And puts X run the score and you can see that you've got one, two, three, four, five, six, or
you don't need this to be multiple times.
Just remove this or on this and you can see that you've got one, two, three, four, five and six.
Then you have another method you can use on areas that is the and method to talk about the shift method,
it basically permanently remove the first element of an area and return this element.
So it works the very same way as Bob.
So if you just write and start.
Shift over here, run the school, you can see that it has already done the first element.
So what is the difference between pop and shipped is that the pope is basically used to just delete
the last element permanently, whereas the shift is going to remove the first element permanently and
it is also going to return that element.
Then you have this unshaped method that will allow you to add an element to the beginning of an area.
And it is the very same as the Bush.
And the difference between these two is that Bush is used to add an element at the very end of the array
and the shift is going to add the element you specify as an argument at the very start.
If you just run the school, you can see that zero has been added at the very start of this function.
Then we have the delete and delete add.
So if you talk about the delete the delete method basically removes a specified element from an error
permanently.
So if you just use the delete, it will help.
Right in the elements, just say to run the score and you can see that it has returned the element that
has been deleted, then we have the delete add method that allows you to permanently remove an element
of an error at a specified index.
So if you just use the delete, add to a hill and just use the second location that is going to remove
this tree from here or underscored, you can see that it has returned to the elements that has been
deleted at the specified index.
You have given this function, then you have got the last function we have you are going to cover in
this tutorial that is the can get function now two can get two arrays.
Where you can do is that you can simply sum them up, as you have seen in the previous tutorials in
this very same section as well.
But one more way to do is that you can use the concat method and the concat method basically append
the elements from an error to the original error.
The concat method can take in multiple errors as an argument which will in turn append multiple arrays
to the original value.
So let's say we have one more.
So we can just ride an X.
Dog can get.
And the brackets, you can specify as many number of errors you want to get.
So for now, if it is right and five, six and seven or just make it to six, seven, because we already
have this six, seven.
So if you just try and put X around this goal, you can see that you have got one, two, three, four,
five, six, seven.
Now you can have multiples as well.
So you can just write in one more and you can just specify eight, nine in that round that's going on.
You can see that you have got one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine.
So you can pass in any number of areas you want to can get.
And that will begin can concatenated to this area, which you are using over here.
Now, one more way you can get areas is to simply add them up.
And you have already covered that in the previous tutorial, so I don't need to discuss it over here.
So these were some of the very simple and basic functions that are associated with areas which you need
to know because this may help you out in the future advanced sections.
So I guess that's it with this tutorial.
Thank you so much, guys, for watching.
And I'll see you guys in the next territorials.