Hello, everyone.
Sowing the seeds of learning how to make products in Java today, we are going to learn how to make
our download manager back in Java.
So on your screens, you can see the title of the project, an image attached to it.
So the title of this project, says my download manager.
So by honing that idea, I hope you have gained like or what have you about what actually we are going
to make today.
So we are going to make our download manager by writing code in our I.D. and the download manager is
going to be based upon Java language.
I no other frameworks we are going to use by making this download manager.
It is going to be made simply encode Java so that you made your on your screens.
Yes.
So this is the interface which is going to like open menu based link and click on the download button.
Initially, there will be nothing here.
Currently, we are having two links pasted on.
The download is taking place, but initially there will be nothing.
Just you have to like paste.
This is a input text free.
You have to like paste the link link.
Also like stupid controlling should be pasted in this input text field, and then you have to click
on the download button in order to make their download start.
So this is the frame which is made using frameworks that toolkits of Java.
We call it the AWB string and we are going to use that.
Those name works only by making this project.
So this is the title of the frame.
Like this keratosis file?
So this is the title bar of this name there.
In the second part, we are having input text fee and then also in the main table for we have basically
a table format, which is having several rows and columns.
The rules are going to contain the names which we are like wishing to download, and the columns contains
details about the download, which is taking place like the details of each, specifically the details.
Seems like this is the other column.
This is the size column.
The size is going to be displayed in megabyte, we call it, and we saw the size is going to be displayed
off that file in megabytes.
So we have currently two files, one bit of a starting point in Temby, and the second one is forty
four point eighty nine and so on.
And these so the target column is like an important column.
We can see that it is showing that the how much the download is completed like we have of progress,
but we're just showing the progress in percentage.
So once the download is stagnant, no Agnes Ma starts from zero percent and upon the time when the download
is completed, it shows 100 percent like a completed status.
So basically, these are all columns are linked in a way.
Suppose that the size is going to remain c a menu item is going to remain the same, but all the L the
S columns are going to like Vati are depending upon each other.
So the progress if increases, then the status will like.
When the download started, the status bar is sure that the downloading once the download is completed,
the status bar will show completed or if any and like libraries.
So it is going to show that status like a status of this download issuing some edits so that will be
displayed in this status bar.
Also, yes, we have Paul and the Zoom option.
We are like having separate buttons for pausing, resuming, cancelling and clearing us like individual
columns.
We have to select that column and.
Then in order to play, pause, cancel the download all clear the like role from the table.
So we are having buttons for that also.
Now I was talking about that, these are linked.
So suppose that initially the donor started from zero percent, then the remaining time is going to
be like supposing it is taking minutes, so their time will be like this Red Hat, that's two minutes
and elapsed.
Time is going to like display zero.
Like initially, we have no elapsed time, just not meaning time revision.
Once the progress bar increases six percent, then elapsed time is going to increase and remaining time
is going to like decrease.
And they are like linked to each other.
They lapse time will increase exponentially on the remaining time, a decrease in that manner only.
Also the average spin.
So it is totally dependent upon your bandwidth of your network.
Like, suppose you are having a bit of what the bandwidth like.
So the average speed will be shown good.
And if the network is like bandwidth will be low and the speed speed is sure showing that in kilobytes.
Also, we have our speed column and the average speed column.
So speed column is the speed at that point of time, and the average speed is the speed like the total
is divided by the total time elapsed.
So speed is like the total size divided by the time.
So what is the this we feel now is this blog showing.
Also, this column is for this critical condition, and this is for the inset speed calculation of that
instant only.
So OK.
In the next five days in this, we have a company to download like this link is pasted and the download
is completed.
So these buttons are automatically like disable them says as we have selected columns and the download
is complete there, so there is no point of pausing resuming the download.
OK, so here we have pasted the link and the download button highlights up on clicking this add download
button.
This download is going to start.
So we have this download completed the sizeable five MP.
The progress here showing hundred percent complete saw this status is showing, so the remaining time
is zero.
Like we have no remaining time.
The download is already completed and elapsed.
Time is 16 seconds.
So now you can also like like calculate what is the total dine in this done so every ping if it is a
complete package.
So this download manager is a complete package of everything.
We have a progress bar, we have up speed, we have average speed, we have elapsed and remaining time.
And this dude does, of course.
So yes, this is the like us.
They are then another window off their download manager with just showing the complete download.
Now in the next part, we are going to like this because the specifications so the specifications of
this project is this is basically a download manager and reactivating this with the help of Java.
So it is a software that is managing downloading files from anything.
So we are like good taking links from somewhere and then pasting it to her so that everything is on
the web.
We are just like taking that link and pasting you to and then the download is starting.
So OK, so this download manager is just a tool of downloading things from the web to your specific
system on which the download manager is running now for after the download, you can then share those
files and things become portable.
When you download it, then you can share anything with external drives also so that download size could
be anything.
This is going to download everything there and it is using the app.
You are getting the connection for downloading files so that as they like the links containing as you
connection I, it will be wasted here in order to download the files.
So the features of this download manager, we have already discussed that we can pause the download
to resume their downloads according to our convenience.
Like, suppose that we want to bother download extra, then we have to like, go somewhere.
Then we can pause then and then again, come back and resume the download according to our needs.
Also, we can like cancel and download in the middle of the progra process.
I suppose that we have mistakenly started downloading the wrong side, so it is not like necessary to
wait for the download to complete.
We can cancel it any time in order to stop the download.
And this is, of course, agnostic user interface application meetings hour.
So it is our best window interface application.
You can run this application on your next stops by creating a separate type, and it is simply going
to act like any other download manager.
You can open this download manager link and then start the download off your files, and we are creating
this user interface with the swing controls.
So swing is our framework of Java that we are going to study about.
So in the next part, we will be discussing that what are actually the concepts we are going to learn
while making this project before making any project?
It comes in our minds that the what actually I am going to learn after the successful completion of
this project.
So after this, a successful completion of the project, we will be having a good grasp on object oriented
programming in Java as we are going to.
I use the object oriented programming very deeply in this project.
Everything will be around classes and objects and methods.
We will be like declaring glasses or declining functions, accessing my thoughts and objects with keywords
and so on.
And also, we are going to use this ring with these frameworks of Java in our very extensive manner.
So everything is going to be like the convene with the help of string anything WTC unless.
So we are going to use companies offering the same goods, such as Flame Jeep and menu bar item.
Jim Martin and so many more life components of in library we are going to use by making this project.
Also, this application is made in core Java.
We have not used any complex like tools instead of gold java.
So yes, this is going to be a cool Java application made from scratch on your side.
So functionalities of our download managing app.
We are also going to learn how each of the functionality works, how we can play, how we can read the
balls that are downloading, how we can clear the specific column, how we can like cancel specific
download from the middle, how the UI travel connection works.
Like everything, we are going to learn about this download managing application and of course, in
that and object are part of object oriented programming in Java.
So obviously we are going to learn handling classes and objects in Java.
So I hope you all must be excited about the making this project on your own.
So in the next part, we will be understanding the wording of this application and then we will directly
jump start the programming section in our ideas with no delays.
So see you in the next little walking and the programming section.
Thank you.