So we are going to start a new project, which is basically Java email application, and you can see
immune system, which is already planning just being sold.
So if you know there are different email APIs to send e-mail, which is basically based email, I'm
going to send you two for that purpose.
I'm going to use different protocols, some APIs which are really stable at the moment.
So sometimes you are going to develop some bigger way back for a company or country one company, which
means that they are having some administrative error for each and every employee, but to send e-mail
in that condition.
You can create some microservices for that purpose.
So it's not exactly microservices, and I'm just going to replace server deployment from just application.
So this is it our project title, which is basically Java email application.
So the project name change, basically we're going to develop email system Hussain and receive emails
using Java.
So receiving messages quite a of job while doing this because of I'm going to use your Gmail as my media
server.
So there may be some authentication error, some things so we can say, Oh, there may be some handshake
SSL errors.
So we need to recover from that.
Issuing mail is not a very tough job, but it's very complex.
By learning, using Gmail because it's not very open source, we actually feel you can try and other
means.
It's also relevant and there are different.
So much for that purpose.
My assertion uses I'm going with German because it's very simple.
And what if you want to use 100 percent open source mail and you can find everything code you can use
transdermal on ProtonMail also, which is 100 percent open source mail systems.
So you can do that or if you want to use another, you can use your own individual.
If you have, you can use that also for this deployment.
So our project team, the immune system to send and as you mentioned, first ask is sending in a present.
We will see how we can receive automated shootings, hours of new technology and not using your personal
technology and using Java as my munising backing as it's already planning on.
So I'm using your disposal for printing part, or we can say, efficient for printing bar.
So step software development.
This project set up how we are going to set up our project first and different rules.
We are going to use your word, the dependency injection, everything I've can hear.
Then some Java basics mortgage today, some TV protocol here.
Then what we it is, we May six Java.
So less dependency related application and deployment on this, or what is the final straw?
So that's it about our project aim and everything.
So let us see application requirements.
GCP pages.
Finally, just be here, I mean, genuinely just images, but consider I am oh accessing the and also
see us as fallible move stuff I used to create some of us for this human.
Sending mail is very easy.
And we to create some Java libraries I'm going to use here.
Then Gmail account, you should.
How do you e-mail account or any here seem to be somewhere you have permission is.
I will tell your client since you needed that then job.
Six to create classes and everything you need to understand that Java Oops concepts object oriented
programming themselves because I'm not considering only one class to read or saying that I'm to create
some different classes and I'm going to use some oops concepts here and some software deployment concepts.
Why I'm doing server deployment concepts Deployment of control is very easy task for it.
But you should understand well, when developing, you may get it this so you still understand what
it is.
Then JDK 16 and some of my independence is also we are going to use.
I am referring principally because it's very useful ID.
By injecting dependency, it will automatically assume that mining dependencies and everything.
If you comfortable with that idea, you can proceed with that idea.
But I'm consulting with individual differently.
The last few server or conjectural.
I've definitely seen that bomb exploded because you can change your password directly of.
So no need to post it again and again for changing this without mentioning the domain on that server,
you can easily put two buttons on.
So these are the application requirements.
So let us see what are the functional requirements.
So what is the difference between application requirements?
Application just for development, but functional requirements are useful to create some classes, everything.
So I'm not going very deep in that part, but you're the what are the functional requirements?
So just be pages and documents literally front, I'm creating here and then I'm not here using any database
to store such emails.
But in real life, what happens?
Actually, all that emails that we saw them so well back in my database to store their emails in their
database.
I am not using this because this is very pragmatic considering an email application.
If you want to create a database, also, you can go with that or you can develop on cloud also like
Google Cloud or Amazon.com.
There are different solutions available on the internet.
You can use more and what do you do for that database consideration?
Because email is not the biggest big.
There are files on, so there are images, so you can use that moment because it's very advanced database.
So for my purpose, I'm consuming only text and everything here, so I'm not using any database you
GSP page or these pages basically when sending ends and mail post.
Then connecting that logic.
It is a country and having some serious look at business, subject body of me, everything.
You can use with GamesBeat also, in addition, I need some serious facing, some water for injuries
before being template for receiving mail.
Then your programs, which is basically your main logic behind us sending authentication by handshaking,
but I'm going to use your access to an email service Java program.
Having that focus, but here I am using Gmail because it's very easy to create that part.
And similarly, seeing films printing in Chrome console, you can do that part also.
So that's it about how we are proceeding with the functional requirements.
So let's see, how are we can set up our project for us?
So let me go to my ad first and let me configure this first.
OK, so this is my individual idea.
You can change the front end part also here.
So.
Let me ask this, because.
Customers.
So this is my idea of on Facebook, you can see here you can choose the default team, say everything
here.
Well, I say blue light team.
So I hear you and see your previous projects, if you already could not even take care planting.
I'm using your endangered limitation.
Well, you can use community additional going to know who it is.
And there are plug ins and everything here before dealing with anything.
Let me tell you.
Oh, goodness.
Yet I'm specifying again and again, which are very important here.
First is download Smart Tomcat, which is HomeKit Server Plugin, which is very useful and right to
download this material.
It's not community preferred, but it's very useful when developing this and my event, which is already
developed.
But try to, if you installed already, try to update this plugin, which is we are going to use.
So just go to projects.
When you go to the projects, you can check your new projects, click on new projects.
So do 16 loan for me, it will take time to.
But this.
So it will be interesting to.
Oh, so as you can see previously, you can see this, well, not the previous employer before you can
take this window and then go to the Java Enterprise if you are using.
So not only 20 different communities, and you cannot see these things.
So just go with Java and you're going to add it later that part.
But my preference, if you're using this, you are going to create Java internalization.
Give the name here.
So.
Insisting on speaking for me.
So some you will face these errors.
I looking at this, OK, so the.
Let me give you the name as Evelyn.
But be patient.
Email application, you know, location, then verb application, if you cannot see any server, no
application server, go to new.
And to hear from get server and directly, I'll let no, don't get nine point 4.8 status symbol.
And you can use that click here Réplication or Tufnell in two language della G-Unit and James Grootboom,
as you would.
So I'm sitting here.
You mean 16 percent even to the knee.
So I'm using to think it will automatically detect, if not, you have to act the dedication you got
to do with this.
So.
OK.
It will take time to know that, okay, I know it's loaded.
Click next.
It will ensure that our aid even to this only because after this, Jakarta has started, so this index
is different.
Time is near to Java.
It wasn't.
Click here we proclaim on what you can do is instead of putting the weight profile, you can use it
at this web socket and the subject.
So that said, we are going to do this.
You know this on?
Not anything, not we are doing this here.
You can use your pin validation also, but it's not required.
Looking at your profile, you can see everything there.
But.
And so need external Web services also, if you want to add, you can add, but I'm adding you.
Don't add anything.
Link think.
So it will create default conduct for you with some index dog days if you find some solid funds.
So you are going to believe that phrase because these are not index orders, be as it is, but another
points.
We are going to delete that.
So.
This is all we can say about the project, so it will automatically create the system level project
as your requirements.
Sometimes it may take time because of some loading issues and everything because it's very useful and
it's takes time sometimes to develop everything.
So now it's loading.
It's preparing what works best for me.
So wait for some time.
It will automatically get written for me.
So as you can see, it's processing for pollution, which is we are going to need that because we are
not required for that purpose.
So we just require in these largest feed and solar plants, which are I'm going to create in the next
two billion.
But in this trial, I'm just focusing on the setup.
We are going to set up and some solid concepts also.
So let me tell you, what is the phone vortex?
This is a dependency injection, I'm using your mavin as my colleague Mark, and I'm using mine.
So beautiful thing off moment.
I don't regret any of it.
We are going to fully use that phrase through everything.
As you can see, this is my loaded.
And you can see here my main concern.
So let me minimize this part.
So this meaning don't use consumables.
Oh, and this is my hello solely.
So this package and here you can see, is that a scene if you go to these are the museum.
If I mean, look, that could just mean you can not see because it's currently loaded and mixing everything.
But if I go to Java, you can see in the compound, which is basically application park, you can see
this email and everything.
Oh, so email application and everything.
So I'm going to believe this later because I'm not interested in that part and then follow all the web
containing part.
So it's importing all the mounting gear.
Because no one is just leaving dependency injection won't dependency as a in the pond or examined,
and it will create everything for.
So indexing, as you can see, you know, once it's loading.
It will default polygamy.
So, ladies, loading, it's not loading.
Just go to your Tomcat and elite configuration.
This is the running configuration.
So hope you can see this.
So I did this file.
Then.
He deployed to redeploy.
If you want to change, I'm going to be dangerous.
So I am doing you because if it is caused by my service, so I'm going to change this.
I'm going to need apply here.
So as you can see, this planet is and that you are in the danger.
If you want to reject your application, is there any more innocuous, always correct or no?
Just click here then.
So now it's indexing, it will decline to suit analyzing.
Oh, so cute.
And so it started building.
So in this council, which is basically the download council, you can see that he's executing and incident
in the moment dependencies.
So while doing this, William does let us see what they do.
So as you can see, these are the property of Marvin, and this is the dependencies is asking, like
Java XO Ltd.
So I haven't mentioned any Java.
No, Tim here.
I just add this.
I mean dependency.
So it will take only dependency from the internet and it will mean you mean this GW is Jupiter files
also tasking.
So it's doing all these things on their own in the Mavin.
So I am using your my been because of these, because I don't want to download energy to play specifically,
John.
I do love this.
I can just do this bond auction so more people can use it here while developing these such cases as
initially.
Well, this is doing one regression me default from system to system like someone is using on other
words, and I'm using another way, so it will be useful for developing this part also.
So currently it's building and it will take time to build everything but.
Will this complete now you can build this conflict successfully, so for the first time building, it
will take time after that, it will not take time to build it because we are just adding the files so
it will compile the building next some one minute.
And is it going?
So as we're going to see and if we go to the service currently, it is not started, but it's building
on.
So for the first time building, it will take time.
Well, after that, it won't take time at all for the building focus.
So as you can see, it's finished now.
I'm going to do the service and it's running and its output is going.
So it's creating everything it's of being able to and or sometimes you may get some news.
Not any of the team.
You just try to stick and wait for something to deploy everything, as you can see connected.
This is what we do electromagnetically creates over for me.
So wait for something it will automatically deploy server for.
So as you can see, these are the starting over again, she these are the local news these.
And now you can see these are gorgeous.
This is the GST page for me.
And if I click, Hello, solid.
I can go to this hello, hello, world junior, basically my soldier.
So my so.
So what is running now?
Let me.
Will all this over, so as good as this thing looks on my system, sometimes it may take time to.
This needs to be on board.
And now I'm what I'm going to make it easier.
You can do this pretty little and you can clear out this disputes when it is.
Because there's no more required to.
Forest Service.
And you're going to delete this common good example, also seen for videos, and we're dying in degradation
and hope you understand this part.
I mean, even the basic stuff, so let's everything.
So in the next videos, let us also consider some this dependency injection.
Also, I read a few.
Thank you.