Hello, everyone, I hope you all are doing well.
And let's start this day with a new project in Java.
The title of this project is school payment system.
I hope you can see it on your screen.
This is the output that the program outputs.
Or we can say that this is the result of this project we are going to be today.
So like this, banging with the specifications of this project and then start explaining the project
what actually the project does.
So coming to the project specifications, hey, it is listed that this project manages everything about
school funds.
Are you going to see that school's money?
Basically, it is a money management system for the school.
Yes, like in our school, we have to pay the salary to the teachers, collect the fees from the student.
And there are many other expenses.
So, so in a management system, that's been the main aim is to gather all the funds and then distribute
it to the required ones in a very managed way.
And the aim of this project is to keep track of the student audiences.
And one fee is already paid who I know, who are not who have not paid the fees like this.
Also, we have to keep that track that which teacher has paid in his hour, her to study, which teacher
is left to be paid his or her salary.
Sitting at a right angle, you have a school, you have beaches, you have students and you have other
employees also in this project.
We are going to consider school as a main body and that expenses only as the teacher's salary.
Of course, this is not the only expense a school best, but in this project we are discussing the basic
concept, so we will keep it simple by the expense of the school as their teacher's salary and not earning
as the fees paid by the students.
Yes.
So let's start back on learning the concept behind this project before making any project.
You must wonder what are the consequences of learning this project?
What are the significant features of Java or any other project you are going to build?
What are the significant features of that language?
We are going to learn by making this project and you are doing no wrong as we want to make any project
just for the sake of learning the concept of language and not making the project is the best way.
I think it is that or it is the main way to learn the concept of any language we are going to make projects
in.
So, yes, let's dig.
I dig into what this project actually teaches us.
So the first one is object oriented programming in Java.
Second one is bending Java apps.
Part one is Gauzere.
Like your Dorian?
So, yes, this project is a tutorial which we are going to see two core Java concepts to afford.
One This Java School Funds Management System As I told you, we are going to manage the funds of our
school.
So, yes, in Java, we are going to learn our school fund management system project.
And the main feature off Java we are going to learn in this project is classes and objects in Java.
This example, as the first feature, is object oriented programming in Java.
So that is no object oriented programming without classes that object.
We have classes, objects and methods that makes the programming of the project very, very convenient.
So let's take a look at what actually object oriented programming in Java is and what types are that
feature?
So this is the official site of WPC schools, and you can learn very good concepts on this site.
So I am open about Java Ops and we're going to take a look at what Java is.
So yes, OB stands for object oriented programming in earlier we have basketball oriented programming,
which was the.
Conventional way of programming.
So let's differentiate between ferocity on programming and object oriented programming in a quick way.
So in project programming procedural programming, we have a certain method.
But in object from programming, we have to create objects that contains both data and methods.
And the main difference between procedure programming and object oriented programming is that real world
data handling in object oriented programming that is data is handled by prosody prosecutors broke down.
There is nothing about Real-World data handling.
Yes.
And the features of object oriented programming or procedural oriented programming are listed here.
We know that UPS is faster and easier to execute, and the structure of the court is ready.
There are defined and very clear in object oriented programming in ops, that is.
There are many features like inheritance data handling, data binding and with the help of the inheritance
weekend, be to recreate the class with the help of inheritance without writing it again and again.
So yes, this is called as dry.
Don't repeat yourself.
We do not have are already mixed classes in our program again and again.
We just have to call that class and had it is everything will be applied at just one click.
Yes.
Let's take a look at the core concepts of object oriented programming.
We are going to learn in this project.
So we have classes on the object.
Let's take the example of what class and objects are.
Plus, suppose Asiedu is a class.
We all know about food.
The type of foods we eat, like we have apples, bananas, mangos, guavas, etc. So we can consider
food as a class and object, as some as a member of the class.
Yes.
So object as a member of the class and it is a real world object, is a real world entity.
We can define the object as it is a member of an entity.
So coming back to the project, but in this project, we have three Java classes we already learned
about what classes are.
And in this program, in this project, maybe will have to be Java classes.
They will be schooled at Java B, just not Java and students Java.
So yes.
In the execution part, I can't explain what this program is doing.
So we have created a school, suppose that the school answer yes, one lakh, ten thousand rupees,
but even so, yes and schools should spend for the sanity of teachers they can.
So the schools will give salary to the teachers, receive the fees from the student, and the whole
year funds will be distributed instead, to me suppose that each student has to pay for your one lakh
rupees to the school.
Yes.
So this is the fee structure of the school student have to pay one rupees by the end of the school.
So from the one lack of fees from each student, the school has to pay the teachers so they will learn
how, with the help of Java, they will distribute the salaries and the students fees and then receive,
well, what about the money?
What?
What is the fund left in the school at the end?
So let's start with the coding execution back in the next review.
Thank you.