Hello, everyone.
So in this series of learning, making projects in Java today, we are going to make a new project in
code Java.
So on your screens, you are seeing a layout of this application.
Basically, this is the interface of the application.
We are going to me.
So this application is headed as must make of the three name.
So I hope by listening to the title, you must have.
Yes.
Must have built a references about what we are going to make today.
So this is basically a game made in Java code in this game.
We have to treat this nie and make it grow longer and longer.
The game continues until you're free to bust me without hitting.
And now I'm second.
So let me give a quick introduction about the application.
We are going to make today.
So in this, we have a player support.
The user is the player.
I'm going to play this game in his or her next stop.
So the player is going to control our dart us grid or any object like in this, we have Apple.
Yes, this is that Apple from which we are going to create destiny.
So this object is inside this border plain and we have to treat this 3.8 snare with this.
Now then the snake will move forward, and if this object reaches an apple, it will leave a trail behind,
like if the snake will eat this apple, more dawn will be added to the body of snake.
And later, this object will shift to any other place in the flame.
So we are going to obey this main window.
And once that snake hits any obstacle like the wall is an obstacle, that snake itself is an obstacle
here.
So when the snake hits this, this, this or this side window or it sells, then the pop up will appear
saying that the game is over in another common scheme.
A snake has a specific length.
So there is a moving tail, a fixed number of units of a drum head like suppose there are three units.
And the last part is that they saw after hitting this apple, this naked little our tail behind its
head, and it will continue until the game is continued and not over.
The player loses.
And the game is over.
So this pop up will appear, then the obstacle is greater.
And the game is finished.
So I hope you understood this game.
If you are a 90s kid, you must have played this game in your keypad phones.
And by making this game, will it make you nostalgic about playing this game in your head in your childhood?
So let's get a quick idea about what are the specifications of this project?
We are going to make today.
So talking about the specifications of the project, as I already told you, there will be a player
which will control their door with the help of is our keyboard.
So your keyboard has four navigation buttons up arrow down, arrow left and right now.
So the player will control the snake with the help of these four buttons only so that dot square object,
then suppose that we have an app on her is inside the border plain and we have to make the snake with
the help of our keyboard so that appeler objects inside the frame.
So as the snake moves forward, it leaves a trail behind resembling a moving snake.
Basically, there are images with the snake this consist of, but it will look like there is a moving
snake and you think the apple and blowing?
But no, we are just adding images after the bin and again and again until the game is not over.
The player loses when the snake advancing to the screen border obstacle on itself.
So if the snake hits the screen border and if like, suppose?
That's Nick Hicks, this border screen border audit says then the game will over.
So everybody is of hope willing to make this project on their own.
So before starting to make how this project is, let's get a quick idea about what are the concepts
we are going to learn by making this application.
So what will you learn heading off this?
So before making any project, you must wonder what we are going to learn by making this project?
What are the concepts that I will gain in my mind after making the project, which I am going to start?
So you are not wrong?
We must think that what actually is this project actually going to help me to?
Not to my knowledge in Java or any other language in which a project is going to be made.
So let us start the concept, which we are going to learn in the project.
So the first point is object oriented programming in Java.
So what is object oriented programming in Java?
So basically, Oops in Java organizes a program around the various objects and many different interfaces.
And these concepts aim to implement some Real-World entities in the program.
Ahead of having object oriented programming in real entities, there are also many features of ops in
Java.
We are going to use in this project like inheritance hiding polymorphism and next cetera in the programming
section, which you will see later.
Apart from object oriented programming, what are the other factors we are going to learn by making
this project?
So after the completion of this project, you will be able to make an amazing application using just
gorge availabilities, not any complex libraries, but just simply for Java libraries.
The snake Ofelia freed the snake game is built using cadaver AWP and strong libraries and packages,
so the app is built above NWT and answering only.
Let us take a quick look at what it would be answering are inevitably answering the news to develop
Windows based applications in Java and WD is an abstract Windows toolkit that provides radius component
classes like Enable, Button Text, et cetera, social window components on the screen.
All the classes on the part of Java Dot WP package, which we will see in the programs section later.
On the other hand, swing is the part of Java foundational classes that is based on the top of AWP and
written entirely in Java.
Let's suppose that it is interference of any other language, then we have to learn that proposal.
But no, that's not the.
The project is just making Java and the library, which we are going to use, are also made in Java
only.
So while talking about the pulse of learning how to make this project, there is a main feature which
I'm going to tell you about now.
So we are going to make this game from scratch like we have to write the code, make that project from
the beginning in our compilers and write each function component classes methods one by one with explaining
what this party is doing and what that part is doing and everything.
We are not going to leave a single point while making this project.
And this is the main part of learning this project.
So building such an interesting game of your own from scratch?
Yes, you are hurting me, right?
This interesting game we are going to make from scratch.
Also, the classes and objects are the main part of object oriented programming in Java.
When that is all that is nothing without classes an object.
So yes, apart from all the things that classes and objects are also being used while making this project.
So I hope you all are excited to start making this project with your own.
So come on, let's switch into the coding section and start their coding class and learn how to make
function components, classes, libraries and package with our own.
See you in the next week.