Hello, everyone.
So today we are going to learn a new project in Java in the seeds of learning Java projects.
So basically, this application is a bank loan made in Java and we have named it does not end.
So in this application, we are going to learn our very own notepad application in our system.
And that tool in Java.
So using basic Java concepts and libraries, we are going to create a very, very beautiful notepad
application with multiple features inside it.
So this notepad feature contains a file on it and a head working in the navigation panel.
This is the about page of the notepad application that Bob Page gives us a quick intro of this application.
We are going to me so this I have said it as conventional logic 2.0 so we can see that it is an appropriate
version of the conventional notepad.
We are going to use like we are using from many years in our system.
So yes, we are going to make a note five also on my own in Java with a very simple, hard coding.
So let us take a look at this application and what expenses.
So this is no page off their mobile application or we can see there's no data.
Also, this is the home page of the noted down application.
The homepage consists of the title bar that no and no.
This section that's now found contains various options, it says.
So let's take a look at the specifications of this project.
So we are going to make a notepad.
And this is the mean specification of this project in this note that your user can input text, right?
I think it fits and you stay on the screen and you will get output as a at the time output on the screen
of the user.
The note Batalon contains features such as file editors and so on.
Even after writing the text document, the project we are making, the document we are going to read,
you can see it printed copy the files of the text pasted anywhere in the text is very rare to be on.
And there are so many other interesting features.
This app consists off so we can also save our text, which are which we are writing.
We can open.
You can even open the invasive document that there's no human inside our system in this notepad.
So I hope you got an idea about this project light apart from editing, saving copy pasting it.
You can even open files from our system unedited also and save it after everything.
So that is no foundation that you have the right fix had only and then say you can also use an inbuilt
document and that could be edited.
Also, so let us take a look at what concepts we are going to learn after completing this project.
Yes.
So the first question may arise in your right mind.
So when to make any magic man?
What will be the consequences of this project?
We're the let and element concept we are going to learn after making this project.
So one note on this question is very material concern.
One can arise.
We are making unpleasant sense.
Let me give a quick explanation about the concepts behind this project.
So my project is made in abstract, and I think of our abstract in the book is the part of the job,
our foundational classes.
So AWP, it does have to be a big ask.
So yes, even it is a standard APR for providing a graphical user interface.
So I didn't need them.
So yes, we are going to make this note that I would have been doing.
Does this make you want to getting off me?
I'll take my application in a separate lingo.
So with the help of AWP, we are going to build this debate at the right of the application and it gives
the right a good experience to the users of the application.
But a good experience to the user using this interface as it will open in a separate window.
They can perform their task and there is no smooth confirmation.
Yes, knock on friction between the program and then rendering masses of the application as we see.
So it was designed as a common circumstance for UI design that would work on a variety of.
But the program is written in Java.
So this is, of course, what you do with Marinol complex languages and libraries involved.
As I said earlier, since Java is being used to the good, the problem.
So you will be going to learn a Java notepad known application to make will.
No, no.
Yes.
And Java.
Then there will be classes on objects and.
Of course, you will be going to learn the applications of massive objects and methods in Java with
examples in making this project.
So yes, also this project is going to use radius components of Java swing like decoding defects, depression
expected to make deals with countries like the US companies, which helps us to apply it in our program.
Without that, I think so much of what we just have to call the companies and look what is our position
on the interface of the, you know, where the app is moving?
So you may be wondering why this Java Sea, then we are already using AWP in Java.
So the answer to this question is so that you will be right behind that extensible abstract thinking.
So basically, swimming is an extension WP API we are using in Java.
So, of course, is it is an extension.
It contains more features than more classes, which helps us to make our projects more attractive in
many ways.
So in the use of abstracting that good and strong together, we are going to build a good library for
this application and use all the components in this application.
So let me give you a quick introduction about Java AWP hierarchy is that we are going to use in this
project like let Ivan introduce the background.
SASR component can be more nimble than NC.
So let's get into it.
So yes, this is no big hierarchy.
The hierarchy of the classes are listed here, like in Snake on Java, not even repeat back into our
program.
What we are actually getting.
So we are getting a component which consists container and inside the container.
We have a window and a panel inside that window.
We have offering so.
Yes.
What a container is contained, it is a company in the way that would be contained, that is a subclass
of the company.
Yes.
As we have already seen, container is this subclass of the company Glass?
What is it then?
A panel is a complicated subclass of container.
So aligning the components.
Hey.
So they will be a disease that we have our campaign says this far is not container, which contains
Britain's best seat, stable and so many other things.
The panel in the continent's top does all that data.
So yes, this is the final.
But inside part is that Ben Bernanke does not.
10 days are titans are on of not even on border.
So, yes, no, but excluding the border.
And that is our panel.
What we know is that no.
We are going to open after running the project and we'll see in the frame of this project like me.
Ever since our does, we have the same target number and the other for the main body of the numbers.
So yes, we have given all the categories knowledge.
Yes.
Inside knowledge of this concern.
So now we are going to run the code of the program and learn how do write the code?
We are going to learn each part of the code that what this party is doing and what that part is be and
my step by step.
I'm going to create our very own fact in Java.
So without any further delays, let's start by creating a new job in our I.T..