Hello, everyone.
So in this series of learning how to make projects in Java today, we are going to learn about this
project, which is called Safety Management System.
So in this project, which is actually made in code Java, we will be learning about that.
How actually a management system works.
What are the like and what use?
And accordingly, what are the outputs attached to?
Those inputs correspond like those corresponding inputs and how actually everything works inside?
And will it be a management system?
So on your screens, you can see the opening window all for like this application, which we are going
to make today and in this application, initially, this page and open are like saying this title as
welcome to that project.
Initially, there will be two options that we will have to type either one or two.
One will be for the logging in into the management system.
If you are already existing user.
Otherwise, if you are a new user, then you have to type two in order to create a new account.
So suppose we are like, I knew you were, so we will be wishing to create a new account in this system.
So we will be choosing Choice two on heading to from your keyboard and then in the window asking for
our customised number.
So suppose that I have and then ask any random question number as one two three four.
Then after this customer number entering process, we will be asked to four entering a pin number,
which we want to register.
This is already like a security based of thing, so we have to keep our thing very private.
We have to enter our pin in ready to secure security minded manner like we do not have to enclose this
pin.
Any other user or any other, like our friends or relatives, only those people are able to know the
pin who are actually very close to you, who will be accessing your account.
So keep this in mind that this is already private, like logging in for so yes, once you enter your
customer number and your pin, then your account will be successfully like registered in this APM management
system.
So once this is registered, then the next process will be to redirect intolerable.
So we have already discussed that if you are a new user, then you have to create an account and after
which we have to log in if we are existing customer.
So once we created the account, we become automatically the existing customer, so we will be redirecting
to logging in the login process.
We will be asked for our customer number and our pin number, so we have to enter vote and we have to
remind this info in order to log in in future also.
So like, keep these things written somewhere or memorize these store credentials, your customer number
and your pin number.
So if you enter any of the wrong credentials, then automatically you will enter this system.
Like do not enter the system, you will exit the system automatically and log in will be shared, of
course.
So once you enter the correct tendencias, then you have to like select the account you want to access.
So we have different types of accounts in this event management system.
We have checking account savings account, and the third option is to like, exit this frame window
or whatever we see.
So once we add that our choice of the types of accounts supposedly enter to OK, so we have entered
to our first savings account and we enter the afternoon bulk of the savings account in this savings
and account interface.
We are provided with five options asking for that.
What are we going to perform inside our account?
Then we want to be your view that balance.
Withdraw the funds, deposit the funds, transfer the funds or exert this saving our life savings accounts
and the interface.
So suppose we want to deposit funds as we have just created our account in this system.
So obviously there is no money.
So we have entered choice three for depositing funds as soon as we enter this option, three for depositing
funds automatically.
This shows that current savings account balance is zero, which is like we are a new user, so we do
not have any deposits already to this account.
So this will be asking that amount you want to deposit into your savings account.
So suppose you want to like deposit $10000, shares Soyuz.
After this entry process, the money will be deposited into your account.
Current savings account balance will reflect the value of $10000, which is an addition to this initial
are like a dollar.
OK, so after this, suppose we want to perform any other leg test?
So yes, the second choice will be to withdraw funds.
So suppose we have deposited funds to our account then a few days later or after, like for checking
initially, we want to check that even if the withdrawals working correctly or not, we want to withdraw
some money from our leg deposited money.
So current savings account balance is really reflected every time we enter any of the choices.
It will show that you have this money and then decide what money you want to deposit or transfer anything
you wish to.
So suppose we want to like, withdraw $2000 from our savings account.
So after the withdrawal from money, the current saving account balance will be reduced.
Obviously, we have withdrawn some money.
So the current saving account balance will reflect that value, which will be like that subtracted value
from the initial account balance and the withdrawal money like the money which will be withdrawn.
So after this, our current savings account balance will be eight thousand dollars, which is very natural.
We have returned to Thailand.
So what is left?
This is left after this, I suppose in the next step, we want to like our option for this transfer
of funds.
So once we enter the default from our cue ball, the transfer funds option on the function will be activated.
So what is actually transferred funds?
So we have to firstly like select the type of account from which we want to transfer the funds.
Now, fund transfer of me to anyone, our friends, our relatives, any professional use or anything
so we can choose from which type of account we want to transfer the funds.
So we are already in the savings account interface.
So we just have to like switch to checking so there is no savings account option for all I had also.
So yes, suppose I want to like the transfer that funds from checking type of account.
So I have choose option one.
So current savings account balance will be shown.
You may be wondering that by issuing a savings account balance, I have chose this checking account
because we have no balance in our checking account balance, so it will automatically like it or it
if left enough savings account balance.
And from that only we can transfer the funds.
So mom, do you want to deposit into your savings account?
So how do we can transfer the funds between savings account and checking account?
So from the checking account, we are on to deposit our savings account.
So the current checking account balance will become $1 and the savings account balance will become seven
thousand nine hundred ninety nine dollars automatically.
This value is substratum.
We have thousand in our savings account.
We want to transfer funds to our checking account as we have no money in our checking account.
So we are like transferring funds between our own accounts right now to check the functionalities of
the system.
OK, so we are done with the transfer from the pink.
Now the next process we are going to check is New Balance.
So automatically, you balances working with every step, but that is our dedicated function.
Are these four to be on balance?
Like, yes, we have to balance nothing else.
So on pressing one, our savings account balance will automatically and if left, as we are going to
be in our savings account interface now on this process is to exit.
So we have exited this savings account interface on anything five from our keyboard.
Now again, we are back in the interface, which was like initially present at the time of the now being
like we are running this program and this was the actual on logging in.
This was the actual interface.
We were like, See?
So yes, we are done with every checking or functionality.
And our next to it will be to activate this be a management system interface.
So on hitting three.
This message will appear there.
Thank you for using this area and you will be exiting the interface of the deer management system.
Now you may be wondering that or we are going to make this project.
So what will be the core like things they will be like keeping in mind before making this project?
So this is basically a dam management system.
We have already discussed it.
So we are going to manage everything about this, a dam management system, all the functionalities
we just encountered in the previous slide.
We will be making everything on our own starting from scratch.
Everything will be done a step by step and like, we are going to manage everything about this system
of what actually this system is providing facilities.
So this is for like access in different types of work.
And we have already seen accounts checking accounts, savings accounts and other functionality is to
withdraw money, check or balance depositing money.
And also, we can transfer funds within accounts with a feature of choosing the accounts, which we
have already seen in the previous slide.
So this is the basic specification of the project we are going to meet.
These are the functionalities which we will be writing the program about.
So yes, after all this specification, but now you may be wondering that what are the concepts we are
going to learn after this successful completion of this project?
So the first thing we are going to learn is object oriented programming in general.
So after the completion of this project, you will be having a good grasp at object oriented program
and back to new object oriented programming.
It is about our life back in the real world ended.
These objects are real world entities, and we are like a learning, object oriented program, so everything
will be around objects.
My classes only now the second thing we are going to learn is to make a job application from scratch.
So everything will be done step by step.
We are going to like write a repeat of one by one explaining every part and not going to miss anything.
We are going to learn the test structures, such as hash maps, which gives out a strings and so on.
So therein lies plenty of knowledge about data structures.
We will begin in Java after the completion of this project.
The management system will be the output after this.
So completion of this project.
And of course, that is object oriented programming.
Then there will be definitely classes in object.
So basically, it is going to be what the concept, the best project that is no fancy like interface
we are going to make.
We are just going to learn the concepts, the basics and all the things about that APM management system
in Java.
And after the completion of this project, you will be mindful about all the concepts that need to be
object oriented programming, whether it be detached structures in Java and everything.
And I hope that after the completion, you will grasp our large knowledge about Java and become confident
in making projects in Java later on.
So in the next part, we will be looking up to the working of this project.
So see you in the next part.