Our project is multi-tiered system using Java.
We are going to use your Java as a language of primary language for creating a chat system using some
multi-threading concepts.
So I will tell you why we are going with multithreading in part and what is done will be trading in
the Java.
But before that, I am going to tell some basic concepts of Java.
So the Java project is based on Java, Java swing for developers and some Java multi-trillion concepts.
I will tell you why we are going with military training in each and every team.
So for this job, I'm going to reject system, so we are going to create a simple check system of the
text and everything.
We are going to create so basically take system only and we are going to create a Java Multi Trading
Europe for the jet and client transport process.
Throughout the process, I'm using client word as a user and server as a service provider.
So remember that whenever I'm using client, it basically means that the user of the system and server
is basically for the service provider of that, or we can select the nation for that purpose.
So let us see what is the project aim or what is our project in this field?
So Project Team is basically our developer chat application interface fusion using Java with two multithreading
concepts we are going to use here, and we are going to develop a chat system with some application
in professionals, so we are going to create here.
So this is all about how we are going to create our chat system.
So let us see what is over basically to be required here.
So first of all, is over it.
But before that, let us consider some steps of development for our project management team.
So first thing you should always remember is.
We are going to create your Jack system for that purpose.
What we are considering here is we are going to set up our project first.
Second is our understanding different tools, what we are going to use your then Java basic concepts
here.
We are going to use some.
Oh, and also some knowledge of our Java swing, also, you should have some Java multi trading concepts
also.
And final step is our service Anderson.
What for?
So for that purpose, I'm using here some systems, so states that our project system understanding
different tools, Java Basic Concepts, Java multithreading, Java Swing Server and code for.
So these are the six steps of our project development.
So let us see what we are going to use yet or different tools.
So application requirements, Java, basic knowledge, multithreading concepts, I'm going to tell,
but you should know some basic concepts of multithreading, motion and JavaScript.
I'm not adding more deep part of Java Swing and each and every thing and explain here.
But you should know why we are, why we using Java swing here.
So tools required first JDK for a new development, you required JDK for any Java development.
Secondly, git, but inside I'm going to use here.
You can use Community Virgin also, or if you want, you can download it into login also, or the student
achievement button is free again.
So port forwarding and system I'm going to use here is in G Rock.
So these are the tools required.
So these are the basic tools JDK also in built with some JavaScript libraries.
So no need to record another libraries.
And if you want to change your password, you will require and also your.
So these are very simple for forwarding system.
We can see if you want to.
You can use another also Google Cloud also providing such systems.
You can use it.
So these are some basic application requirements.
So let's see first.
How are we going to set up our project?
So all you need to create on this project here, as we're already here, are so this is my new project
in search of Java in Belgium.
You can see here our project and each and everything here on in my chat system, Interjet, I have some
different everything.
So first, I will explain how we are going to create inside, build command, prompt itself, and I'm
going to do some added functions.
Later, I will create another program for you and each and every team.
So these are how we can set up everything.
You just need to create new Java project in idea of recreating the new project.
It will show some different options Java EE Java Web Spring.
So you should remember you have to use on Java.
Java didn't specify your JDK.
It will automatically found that your system loaded JDK and each and everything.
So if you don't install it, you have option also to install JDK.
So download that JDK from it itself, or you can externally download from Google Chrome or any browser.
Then, after doing these steps, you want to create your project.
Mention the meaningful name for that purpose is in this with the check system and these folders are
created is that she's basically ever since folder where we are going to create here.
So we haven't mentioned it.
I told you, we haven't mentioned any libraries here, but as you can see, some libraries are already
inside this all all libraries with some important external libraries, as I told you.
And these are anything.
So these are all we can do.
So before that, I will tell you some basic knowledge of Java.
So our Basic Soldier welcomes use of three basic structure, although we can say what is the Java structure
other than bioethanol c C++ Java is very much an independent language.
So why it isn't machine independent because of these three structures JVM and Angelica.
So JVM is basically Java virtual machine.
So if you know the virtual machine, Georgian machine is also similar like that, it does not physically
exist.
Second thing is providing the runtime environment with the Java bytecode, so.
What is the beautiful thing of Java is for the clan system, but or one system like consider T-Systems
TV or computers with having separate or we can see distinct operating systems like one is using Windows
when you do Linux and using Mac.
So these are three different or is this?
But Java is machine independent language, so all three are the clients or we can sit we are the users
of our chat system.
If they have some Java platform inside their system, they can run their client.
So it is a machine independent.
Like what is the informal chat applications available in the market?
Are the machine independent?
They can run on windows.
Some are running on Linux.
Also, some are running on Mac also.
Otherwise, some Android things also.
So these are the machine independent things.
Similarly, we are going to create that.
It is also run programs in other languages, but compiling obviously JVM, remember that also for are
the main purposes of JVM Node or BI or Lotus or code verifies the code executed reports and provider
in environment.
So these are the basic concepts of JVM G-d's Java runtime environment, which is considering some state
schools, libraries java for you to accept extra.
So as I told you inside E!
So these external evidence, these are the parts of all our jihadi jawad and time environment because
these are not entirely new documents it will call while runtime environment.
So last July, Java development kit, it consists of containers are made of often plus JVM.
So these are what we consider in time, enrollment and doom.
As I told you earlier, it contains that.
Also, it consist of Java Jar wreckages, basically Java compiler.
So why do we need compiler?
We are writing them into Java, but we don't know the machine lake level language, which leads you
to an automated coder, etc..
So for that purpose compiler, which is converting all the Java program in machine learning to Java
on Java compiler is basically part of Duty Java Development Kit.
So just you download the JDK from Internet from Oracle website.
You are downloading Judy, Judy, you are not downloading Jrt your JVM.
You downloaded the JDK, which is basically all Java package.
We can see and you install that part.
So I'm using your 16 login of JDK for such purpose, but you can use integer here.
So no special judkins required for this program.
So this is a basic JVM Jihadi JDK Java basic structure.
So I am telling this again and again because if you say I'm using your Windows system for the project
development, if you want, you can use your another system also for this project development.
So Java is basically a machine independent.
So these are the basic structure of J.D. Degree and JVM.
So JVM is presenting as well because this is all consistent you.
So state libraries, Jodha files and some other on documentation on submitted consistent Jedi.
So it makes a Jedi, but developing a JDK Jedi JVM lets some Java files what we can see some other documentation
spa to which anybody can read me, for instance, on there in Java.
So these are Java compiler is very important here.
It's energetic and it makes a whole JDK.
So JVM plus Jerry mixed JDK.
Though Java is purely based on methods and classes, if you remember or if you know about sea, are
you going to see Python?
It is are not lake mutagen glasses.
Oh, I see.
Basically, there are classes, but it's not required that you should use that again.
But inside the Java, everything in Java is associated with classes, objects and methods with attributes
and cetera.
So starting off, Java is basically Mitre 10 classes.
So usefulness of this is you can easily create object oriented programming concepts in Java, and we
are going to use some object oriented programming concepts also.
So what is object oriented is basically this creative class creating that object and use that object.
So no need to required or create such a method for such classes or again and again, like you have to
check, you order an even number.
400 times.
So what are you going to do?
You can on Jake, such an ambush again and again 400 times or what are you going to do?
You're going to create a one meter to pass that number in that and just checking that number with the
same logic for even an hour.
And you can use such a method again and again.
So what is the usefulness of that is you can take that method also, and it's very use it usable less.
It's very less complex or complex if it has a very same complexity.
Also, it takes very little space in your system.
But very important thing is I is vital debugging and vital managing that it will be very useful.
So what is Java class and methods?
I'm explaining the classes this basically was in really consider this object and God has such attributes
or different attributes that dead weight, color, et cetera.
And there are some matters that I would break out of submitters.
So this object, you can create a class for that.
You can pass the attributes, liquid envelope and some methods like brown brake, etc. So basically,
classes are like Object Constructor, which is basically constructor of object, which is a blueprint,
or we can see a blueprint of our code on object.
An object in Java is basically to all classes or classes.
We don't object, you cannot use that class at all.
If you are using some different part, like there are some conditions for using classes and objects.
I will tell you in a letter, but object is called instant of class.
So we don't object.
We cannot call the class and or we cannot use that class.
Method is basically methods are declared within the classes.
It contains code of particular functions and classes who cannot specify the all the code, you have
to create methods for that purpose and you have to execute that part.
So this is all about methods and methods contain some who lose access specified, then doleful object
or classes created for that purpose, then we can use that basically.
So what is the basic thing is the hierarchy, and if considered the method for calling the classes,
you need to create object.
And using that object, you can use that methods or syntax is very easy for that purpose.
Remember, if you knows how to print some statements in Java or you remember that you have to specify
public static void, main and intended.
So it is again a method standing with the main method either department or in a job.
I could run or build whole court or project.
Other than that, you cannot use any part.
So by running any class, any method, you should invoking the mean method always, which is basically
public static void main method in, say, Java.
So this is all about limited time classes.
So before going any further, let us create three Java classes here when these are over.
So what are the needs of the client and when is the message?
So for that purpose, what you are going to do is click here, right click inside to see on this odyssey.
So sometimes it will take time to load.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to create your files, Java files, click right click on instead
of see go to new and created Java class by mentioning these various server.
So it will definitely take everything, and it will create some difficulties here, as you can see public
plus of already created.
So similarly, what I'm going to do is I'm going to mention this as a client, which is another class.
And what I'm mentioning here is new name or as a chat message because.
I want to.
Creates a barometer to pass that message and exit door.
So these are three basic structures we are going to use here.
So these are three classes we are going to use here.
In the next part, I'm going to tell you how we can proceed with this part.