Averting projected job losses in going to a one blog is a name is going to bloom and is the name given
by me.
You can choose another name, any other name.
It's not compulsory when choosing the name, but I prefer names, according to Bloom in this blog or
against the system.
What I'm going to do, I'm going to add some admins and I'm going to connect to people using Java.
Oh, also, I just want to add one on nutrition information, also giving the information page for the
solar so nearby police station.
I'm going to try some logic behind this.
So.
This project is based on Jelavic DSP jealously and the software deployment I am using here.
I will tell you what is adjacent each and everything.
So our project is a block system and we are going to create one block system platform.
We can say we took our app basically.
So we are going to use it.
So our project is.
Basically, develop a block system platform, we are going to develop a Block 16 platform.
But the people around the globe using Java technology.
So our aim is very basic, but what we are going to develop, it's very important here because we are
performing with this Java, so we need to take some on the pages.
We need to write and just be pages and JavaScript on Zoom in.
Further, considering that I am going to use some default images and some things to add and create one
beautiful UI for my website or against web application with Java or I am using your database also.
I will tell you later who I'm going to use the database and who I'm going to connected to the main database.
Just heaps of overdevelopment.
These projects where I'm going to set up my project and then understanding different tools because projects
are just not writing code, we need to mention all the libraries, each other, everything.
Then understanding different tools, what I'm going to use here or what is the different tools and will
be easier.
What is the significance of theses files to each and every team I am going to mention here?
Then some Java basics, you should know the basics.
I will teach you the Java six.
Also, what platform?
But sometimes due to time constraint and each and everything, I'm going to use some default URLs that
we, I will explain later, but use that then basic some database.
What is their database and what is the school statements I'm going to use here?
I'm going to use the relational database, no special database link and I am not going to use it.
I'm going to use your only traditional database with the relational school grounds.
Some just be basics, then Java Solid and the BBC connection and deployment of the sobero deployed on
the server so that see the work, the steps of development.
So just recall those types of development projects that understand different tools used go basics,
basics of database DSP basics, Java solution connection and deployment on the service.
So let us see the what is the teams?
I'm going to use it.
What are the requirements each and team?
So application requirements?
Oh, let me tell you, what is the application requirements?
Not always.
Our requirements are specified.
We cover goal or anything.
We need to mention the application requirements.
Also you.
So our program to display basically, I'm not going to tell you, though, that the thing is for that
purpose, I'm going to create a connection and I'm going to tell you what I'm going to do.
Yet I'm going to write just one Java audience.
What is it?
It's a pure java.
Other than this, I'm going to embedded Burgess b o leader in a human face to writer documents.
So basic knowledge, also basic concepts of the skills.
You should know the basic knowledge of Java.
If you have some prior knowledge of A, those sites will be very beneficial by developing this project
because I'm not going to explain the agenda yet.
I'm just giving the overview of this then some Java basic concepts.
Also, you hear a few million views just renting.
I'm not going to tell each and every part of it.
I will try to explain that, but I will tell you you can use your bootstrap also for debate.
But I'm not going to use here, but I'm just telling you you can use Bootstrap and Jackson's website
for log in at Amenas to learn what you can see me as a part of you.
You can use student, but I'm mentioning as admin only you can change it to the people also who log
in here.
So let me tell you, you can use it as a people also.
I'm going to.
This is for students on.
So that is calling people for admin, do administrative actions and for the common people.
These are the user or you can say you get the software application who is required.
Judy given pointed why I'm telling Judy given point eight is the glass servers, and even in our kids,
it's upwards of 1.8.
You can even detect 16's also due to what it is, and it means I'm going to use you and Oracle databases.
My relational database entries, as we said, where you can directly import to your site, you need
to check for that and you can check for it.
So actually, our application requirements?
Let's see our functional requirements.
What is the functional application I'm going to use here?
Functional requirements first is admin.
There are a few admin roles here I'm going to post was this can create and post topics to be discussed
and report, respectively in London.
So basically, it can cause the topic or report of the report.
Like some, it's it'll Zoom entries or explicit content.
You can delete that report or we can see, post and view all the topics we discussed can search reports,
and you can take unlimited any input data reports also.
So that part also you can handle.
Helping in any report to further give it to the media, except you can do or can you not previously
posted comments or strong comments on each reporter topic?
So what can we handle?
Well, what is it that they resisted?
ABC and next would exercise their knees and look at the idea, and that's very unsafe so people can
put that on and people excited is very unsafe and they can pose the picture also so admin can do that
and can conform to that police station nearby.
So I am considering this scenario, you can choose any and then so this block system is the way it can
be reporting materials for the reporting matter and for the smart city.
But also you can.
So common people can do all the reports of getting logging such and go to the police station like I
need to report the police station.
It's not very useful in a case like emergency, but you then report to this platform on.
So can you previously post your comments and post on comments you generally between you and you?
So that's it about the functional requirements.
So in the next part, I'm going to tell you the what the solid basics.
But before that, what I'm doing here is I'm going to explain all of it.
So this is mainly because once you are installed, then it means I'm using Virgin and it means you can
check for stable working, then you can look like this.
Well, there is one new window for you.
What is needed here to find a new project?
So.
Once you hit new project.
You can see this is my new project and you can see job of it.
We'll do it next.
You can choose the location.
Coming.
Blue.
So I'm putting like this going to look, you can use the Digital Library for sorting libraries.
So I'm mentioning this heat.
The next you can choose server.
I took the glasses server this next.
Don't lose anything here because we are not going to use your antique finish.
You can use jealous little faces.
You try everything you can.
That's not really matters here, but you mean what I mentioned here, so it will take time to check
everything.
It will create the next door page for you.
Keep it as it is, we are going with only GSP pages.
We are not including be just as our friend.
In part, we are going with JCP pages because I don't want to write your Java world, which connects
to the extreme.
And so I will.
And but it might just be all we can say Java code in this game, so it will be very helpful in developing
the code.
So on the left side, you can see this, and this is my good looking.
So this is the default war which created only 2.8 content supplied and everything you're going to see.
On this, you can dig the projects here.
Well, once you claim this, it will load off, I won't see the ladies lavatories.
So this package is filled with packages for you on figuration points.
If you want to add JDK, you need to install the Java X-ray load.
So let me add that Java folder inside my listings.
Let me add to Java X, which basically contains Java, because while they were living this, I understood
that my JDK doesn't contain this or does not contain these Java XDR.
So if you want, you can download it from the way it's freely available and just you don't, then it
will load that file so it will take time to load that.
Once it is loaded, you can see here that's left.
Also, you need some database connectors.
Follow whatever you need or GBC what I call GTV to connect or 09:46 according to your TV.
See on television and for my school, you need a MySpace connector.
So that's it for the setup.
If you want to check whether it's your running load, what you are going to do well, click here.
On This Morning, look likely you can see many options here, keep it clean and be.
So if your window is not opening your window, you get out so you can see the window you.
So you can use this as output.
So intriguing, because these are my quoting, and I can check out some here to look at this.
OK, so this is my outputting and you can see me successful if you want to try what you are going to
do.
Click here and then so it will move to the daily and you to see Glasby server visiting the references.
Globe is running really successful when this is when this is done, you can check.
This is my Golden Globe localist 2002.
If you're code is modular.
A defiant domestic family in a last resort and changing it to random because whatever happens or regulatory
service is also guilty, so you will move to the part that you do basically not very useful content.
I can see block ADHD and also block sort simultaneously.
More can be done and me, me, be probably not when you are doing this.
So changes do not do as I change you.
So this is my idea and the least successful.
So let's think about how we can deploy this.
Everything.
So basically just a solid liquid.
So what I'm going to do, you need to.
You don't need this index statistic, but you don't just do this.
What are you going to look like here if they just click new?
And let me.
Open this all the pages in New Jersey.
So when this is done, New Jersey change it to the next day because this is not enough.
I'll always remember indexes basically for the loading there.
And click here.
And once this is done, you can check here.
India's largest is done and it will write content for you directly letting you know using it quite hard.
Well, what I'm going to do is.
Index page.
So let me.
So as soon as Elizabeth is doing the running, you can check here and let me tell you this.
So what you're going to do is click here, delete and delete spot, so it will do so if you know what,
do this or let me copy this because I'm going.
We'll hear.
And let me run this again.
So you then stick India's or disputed GST bases and island, which is condensed Hollywood.
So that's a total we can no longer do is we don't change the index or GSP because it's a industry.
And what we can see configuration is already retained.
So this is it who I'm going to perform this.
So in the next part, what I'm going to mention here or what I'm telling you, we are going to perform
these actions.
I will explain the solar part and I'm proceeding with the functional requirements.
I will check for each and every financial requirement step by step.
And I will tell you that within this session, we are going to perform few administrative actions and
three common people actions, as I mentioned earlier with the functional requirements before proceeding
with the project.
You should have some bad knowledge about Java, and it's good.
So I will tell you what is the basis of.
So let's do the basics of GCP in the later part of district.
We'll.