In previous audio, I told you, what is this framework?
What is our project outline and what we are going to do in this COVID 19 cases and I application using
Java?
So we are going with spring application and we already have seen how we already created the spring initial
laser part on each and everything.
So I downloaded the file from that part with spring initialize it, and I'm going to open it.
So for the opening in Indonesia, India, basically this is over the front page of it.
What I'm going to do, I'm going to be open here once this is click open.
You can see all the things.
So this is my application, which is I downloaded the zip file I extracted in the design and this is
my application and clicking, Okay, here.
So you can say these are all in-browser and loading wrong.
So trust this project first as I'm opening the third party project, as you can see, I have to mention
this idea individually in Dalian is very intelligent.
It will load all the components, adding their dependencies and using external.
It will take care of it.
So my idea is opening currently, so it will take time to meet the quarantine.
So not a strike force.
So our project is mammoth project, so it will take time to load each and everything once it is loaded.
I will tell you what we are going to do.
Are basically.
So now you can.
It closed its lease.
Now you can see everything here.
So this is our project, and I'm going to package just more robust.
OK, so it is taking time to load everything here.
It will take time to load each and everything.
Once this is done, you can get your everything.
You're only.
So let me speak to my dad, but also.
It contains OK and everything.
They only.
So it is taking time to load eugenics at everything, because as you can see, there is loading bottles
so there.
While this is gloating, I will explain the repeat part.
And we can say the thing I want to explain is it is spring thing.
So as I told you, spring is a lightweight framework for your development and it's still frame work
of frameworks for different things.
So inversion of control I use what do you think was one of confusion before any projects you have seen?
Actually.
These are using some what we can see system enable dependencies.
We are adding libraries manually, but thing what we can do.
We can inject our libraries informed or experiment, which is basically properties similar again to.
So this is all about how we're going to do this.
So let us check what is the design patterns in removing their dependencies.
Consider this example.
It's easier to maintain and based on some IOC, this is class employs address, I is another thing and
I'm assigning employ at least part.
So it is basically direct dependency of between we can say employment at this, so these very tight
coupling I'm displaying directly, so what happens if I'm having Erin address?
Then there is the Iranian implique.
If there is an employee class, then at risk plus also.
But I can maintain both applications separate.
I can run employee separately, I can enter separately if there are no runtime errors.
So this is all about how we're going to do this.
So let us check what is the basic thing in this is all.
These are basically tight coupling scenarios, but using inversion control, what we can do, we can
depend use dependency injection.
What is the dependency injection in this?
We can add dependencies with some external advice in pondered example.
So it will download that dependency from the net.
Or we can see that's the real thing.
You can do.
So this is all about how we can do this, but what is the importance of this?
What is the advantages of this is it makes God loosely complete.
And let me tell you what is a loosely enforced, as you can see, class employees address employees
employee at this address, so I'm making another variable for.
So what we do, we will do it will copy that.
It is.
Copy that.
I mean, it's securing copy.
So I'm hoping that it is using this key word.
So no, there is no direct dependency we can see.
We can use the address bar here and we are putting here, and that employee is also satisfying this
idea.
So if there is an employee, we can run at risk loss or vice versa.
If there is an at class, we can execute, at least in blue glass.
So these are very good practice.
While developing any loose coupling do not maintain a tight coupling.
While you are developing the software, there are two terms are used by coupling and loop loops coupling
by creating the object part.
So or we can object.
There are some momentum we can see for the tight coupling like you have some security, online authentication
or two.
Basically, you need tight coupling there because it's very crucially important for each and every user
name.
There should be unique password or we can say of each and every user name should be unique.
For that purpose, you can use that coupling, but.
In such cases, like collecting the data, representing the data data visualization in Java, we can
use loot couplings.
So this is the basic thing of our loose coupling in springtime work.
I use the container, which is basically inversion of control.
I usually container is responsible for angel dependency.
Just injecting the dependency.
No need to use direct library.
Why we are not using directly level, we need to download it, then we need to specify the eugenics
era instead of this.
What are you going to do?
You can just do.
Oh, some are downloading that part.
Well, downloading will take my ID.
It will take everything dependency, it will download dependency, eugenics or to.
What we do, we provide the only metadata of who the container, that animal file or annotation we can
use annotations did and we can proceed with metadata.
So advantages of dependency injection is it makes Gordon news legal.
So it is easier to maintain and makes it easier to test as our testing purposes is very important while
developing any of the required one thing.
Oh, we don't want to test it again and again.
We need to maintain the loose legal, but if I'm not still employed class, we can say there are two
places we need to maintain employment and consider this scenario.
We want to implement such part, but unfortunately my testing book was all due to time constraints.
I cannot consider employee class.
I don't want to focus on in bluegrass.
I just want to test and riskless.
This is a unique distinction.
So for that purpose, we can use address class only, or we can then address class.
I mean, it is loosely open.
So this is basically of, well, efficiency of dependency injection.
So this only I'm going to explain how we are going to dependency magic, and I'm using CSU data, which
is basically a comma separated for use data or, as you know, the similar things also and in Excel,
also, we can store that data in the CHP format.
Did you basically commercial period for them?
So I'm going to use dependency to produce it as a tabular manner or we can see here the manner, room
and so forth that I'm using when to use, when free dependency.
We can say about your dependency for that purpose and for a little use, I'm going to explain that.
So this is all about how we're going to do this.
So or take time to download each and everything.
If it's your first time like me, only I just you can see this in my output and you can say this is
loading.
So it will take time to load eugenics, cetera.
So give the time to it to load everything you're seeing the data, it will take you some of them, as
this is my main project, it's not as simple and project.
It will take time for load each and everything.
If this is your first moment project, as I deleted everything related to my in my system, it takes
time to download everything so you can take the downloading and you can see shared in libraries.
You can take each and everything your.
So give it the time to this.
Meanwhile, if I win this thing, I will shake this also which flowing lagoons is downloading, which
is basically this is Android.
If I use, then some marine libraries on seeds are downloading because these files are using that,
so it will take time.
So meanwhile, this project, let us see the way we are going with some.
Spring application like we are not deploying using solid application.
Yes, we can do it, so what is the disadvantage of Soviet you need?
Instead of using everything you need a once dedicated server, you need to deploy that second thing.
Spring is a framework so you can use hibernate, and all the dependencies directly inside is dependency
already contain dependencies, things in the spring framework.
Third, and most disadvantage of kolaches.
You have to run it again and again if just because you have to reload it, at least.
And one more thing is there is no dependency injection on conception.
Oh, so you can use solids concepts and see what we can see the spring framework.
I'm feeling so let concepts like creating a steam mill file deploying in that statement, but you can
use the solid part.
But what the main thing or the people back thing we need to require?
When spring framework and thermal testing be only job lighting, you can use some celebrities and you're
going to work with that in the solid.
You have to invoke that solid response to the request glass and do very rudimentary technique against
it, and it is a very old technique to fetch their data with the data from the database.
Or we can say silver instead of this, we can use this.
This is the most advanced out of.
Plus, as I told you, it's you just struts hibernate Egypt e.g. Egypt.
These are the basic frameworks for developing any web application.
So springtime look is very helpful.
Let's bring framework provides the security, spring boot eugenics.
So these are the multiple types of spring things inside this.
As I told you, we are already developing any or we are initializing that we already installed some
direct dependencies the late spring day, then spring oh timidly for accessing the fines.
And also we added more spring application dependency also there.
So it will be very helpful for doing this.
Advantages of what we can bring.
Pre-defined templates.
Spitting print provides the template for really busy, high end technologies, so no need to required
or to write from scratch.
If you are in it working really beautifully, it will directly you do some gold related to that.
And these are some basic types, basic steps of these technologies.
So let us make an example of this.
You don't need to write a code for exhibition handling, creating connection, creating statements,
committing transaction, closing condition.
So Jollibee's is already involved that all we can do is bring framework already contains that part to
require directly queries.
So you need to write a code to exacting queries only.
So its sales a lot of duty.
Second thing, loose coupling.
As I told you, what is the logic of coupling in this dependency injection, the spring applications
are loosely coupled with dependency injected.
We are using dependency injection.
We are going to specify our libraries of what we consider, pondered and will probably examine and will
use that part it.
Again, it is easy to test.
So I will tell you where it is easy to test their dependency injection makes it easier to test application
as troops or application runs request instead of an application, but our spring training doesn't require
a server.
We can invoke our check, our application in our what are we going to see command prompt if it's working
or not, or if I'm going to deploy them.
So I need to be part of your server, but I'm by GS already.
So we're given, you know what?
We can set spring framework.
We find three defense that we need to just call it.
So it is very helpful to deploy this on the server.
So.
They're just chicken mighty, as you can see, this is very.
As shared indices are downloaded each and everything.
And as you can see, spying framework is also doing this work.
You're going to see spring blogging.
Here is my win, each and everything is installed.
So let me minimize this part.
So before going further.
Oh.
Let me check my I.D. or we can see, Oh my God, I'm going to check here is basically project structure.
I'm going to project structure because I'm in the 16th word.
If my application runs on another business, you are pushing that.
So we'll do project to project SDK.
So let me zoom out this first.
OK.
This project is decays this, so I'm using this only.
Would you like that and.
So that's what you can do if you want to change you and knitting extra.
You mentioned that also.
So this is all about how we are going with this project.
So in Philadelphia, I'm going to explain how we are proceeding with this application specific.
So this is just how we can invoke our import project in our I.D. before going to project.
Let me tell you what I'm going to specify.
I'm.
Let me know when the packages met, not only because I want to check the packages when they don't.
So inside the Sazi, I'm going to explain something here.
So let us check for further things home, homeland to explain each and everything.