So in the first part, I discussed about hope build up in different techniques.
So let us give you a site, I guess, cryptography that is more focused on Viber using Java.
So again, I'm focusing on JVM getting JDK or instead of, if you know, they're not, not very well
or link present languages like Python or somebody working on that.
But JVM is login machine so we can perform different delivery techniques on nukes and we can check that
part.
But JVM is basically java legitimacy.
It's not physically exist.
Java is made up of different parts.
JVM Guardian JDK JDK is basically Java development kit.
It consists of Guardian JVM jihadis who claim this is a new and different JVM.
It's runtime environment.
There are dependencies.
Libraries draw files that are different lengths in that division, and they will exist on your system.
It's just no good environment.
Other virtual machine, which loads calls verify schools, executes course on Excel.
And so that's a very powerful thing in Java or a digital machine.
So we need a requirement to change those parts of an existing configuration.
Never limits Java program, so that's very important.
And then this is basic things JDK, G80, JVM structure.
This is my JVM if I this.
So in this.
And so this is basically in Bagram, then.
So just like this diary and the JVM here and there are two sets of libraries and different things here.
So now let me tell you what is the cryptographic?
Yes.
OK, so before going to.
For a little fact, let me tell some.
Right.
Iraqi and what is the cryptography in the market?
There are different things like bitcoin is a cryptocurrency, if you know, to the bitcoin on to the
large point on the cryptocurrency.
So crypto is not about money currency.
The program is just basically the economy who pioneered things so highly blenders.
So let me, as I told you, Amy is doing that stops sending the data the outside world.
There are a lot of lot of 10:57 these articles on it.
These are my attackers which always want to penetrate this system more, these systems are needed.
They want to steal these information, all of this, but and we are very talented, all we can say,
intelligent persons.
They are talking in code language also always they are talking good language.
All always vigilant for that language isn't going for any.
So that's a similar thing in cryptography.
What?
What are you doing is sending this message?
So this is my message.
This some key.
With some key, so this circle is my.
Just keep sending you this being north.
This is the key to encrypt their data.
These also having this data or weekends a key to encrypt that my this part is the mine data.
These my key.
Back.
No one God knows this is the key because there is no meaning for that.
There is no meaning for that data.
So the encryption key is happening here.
So no in beach access to safe.
So in previous part, I told you what is the basic things like?
Well, what is the semantics?
Margaret is basically for the encryption, and the decryption key is seen.
These same for encryption and decryption.
So immediately, what is the encryption?
Encryption is just basically plain inside politics.
Cipher text is basically no one can read it that there is no meaning for that.
We can read that message.
There is no meaning for that.
There are some symbols on, so we can include some SGX anything data, and we can have a space of that.
So keen for the decryption and encryption is key.
Same then it's known as semantic.
Then what is also meant there is a symmetric thing that would be awesome entity.
What is the ultimate team?
What are you sending data to be?
It creates bookies, Glenys polémique.
And another one is private.
For the inclusion of it, when his public and other is private to send it back.
So what it is doing?
He's doing all he's encrypting the data using.
Encrypting their data, using this public.
OK, encrypting data, this public key, this is my public key.
And sending these key bills to decrypt that data, they might be sending some data to a.
It is decrypting that data, who is private, so as you can see that there is lot of lot of security
in this and there are different Ignace like signature in hashing, different things happen here, all
in this data.
So let me move on to some important part.
So what is the cryptography thing here?
Let me do.
Cryptography is a study of different techniques to secure data from 2018, so cryptography is not always
related to encryption on anything.
It's a big need to secure data from unauthorized entity, entity and anything.
You want it.
In computer science, we try to develop strategies and practices to protect sensitive data.
Now if you have WhatsApp on dancing input and encrypting that, what it means you're checking is not
stored as a common text or your voice is not stored as a common text is encrypted.
So most of cryptography involves very advanced mathematical functions used to are used for securing
data may be required at once things because attackers are always changing their strategies, they're
always trying to penetrate the system.
So we're requiring very advanced functions, mathematical functions.
For this purpose, the sole purpose of algorithms to develop cryptography is hide data from attacker
or middlemen.
In this article, we're going to understand this part and also you may take off your things and we are
going to do that steps.
So this is a plain text.
I played one key.
Which encryption algorithm, so for things generated, decryption would have simply been they cisgendered
it?
So what is this?
I am getting some plain text is basically your original message already.
That is Hayden.
Then from view two of cryptographic encryption algorithm.
So what are they saying?
Basically, your output of encryption, which is not really, well, like in previous thing, I really
be meeting next to say, for example, keys a piece of data or corrected bit of data when input with
plain text in encryption offsite.
But it still gives basically just encrypting and decrypting it.
If you put in that part, you will get or you will understand the lyrics for that purpose.
And so is that a piece of data which is added to the hashing function?
So I will tell you what is the hash here hashes?
And looking back, all you have to create some map of arbitrary size of data or bytes in that data in
that main data to create some mathematical functions or create some mathematical attributes for that
list.
So there are different encryption algorithms.
Equality is obviously easier to understand those who fish blowfish idea modify you make shocking.
256 is most like hashing functions of 256 bits of bitcoin is using SHA256 is really higher level algorithms.
Also, they are using.
So these are the properties of everything and all semantic encryption.
As I told you, public private key was created and they are shared to this.
So mostly the cryptocurrencies are using oximetry.
But for the simpler book with this, I'm deploying the simple new, which is basically no.
Cementing.
So now.
I'll let us create new treats here, which are very useful and let us see how we can set up our project.
So for the producer, it's very easy when you have to go to your I.D..
And choose your own I.D., you can choose anything.
I'm not forcing anyone to stick to only one, and there is a reason for that because that's not really
everyone's part.
Then I'm going to endanger this if we wanted to go you with this.
You may have received this.
So when you're when I it's.
It will take some time to open, but I mean, wait.
Let me rephrase your piece.
Plain text is basically just original message, Jordan, that you do it on YouTube from cryptographic
encryption algorithms, then the.
There is one other thing is Cipher, which is input and output of encryption.
And he is a piece of data.
All is another piece of the damages to the Haitian commission, and I will tell you what is the Haitian
later because it will not understand directly using this, but we have to check for different purposes
it.
So you need to create a new project in your own I.D..
So what I'm going to do is.
I'm going to create my new project in my alley.
So let me open my eyes.
Sometimes a good three minutes to look like assisting confirmation.
Meanwhile, let us see what is Java class, and so everything in Java is associated with classes and
objects along with attributes and.
Considering the real life example, God is an object which has some attributes such as wind blows,
etc., etc. But oh God, he's also having like, construct or blueprint of creating objects in glass
holders.
Some user defined attributes to pass values on which objects are all used to create glasses, which
has already created an invalid.
So that's how we're going to with this end user.
Though some functional Java classes subclasses is a blueprint for objects or New Orleans, and class
is something to store different functions meters in one block of code.
And this is the syntax for tickling the classes.
So the next part and how are we going to deploy it and how we can run our own in the next play?
Hope you understand.
Thank you.