We have already set up our project for Java Servlet now we will learn what Java sold.
But before that, I will summarise the first part what we learned was so in it.
What I did, I just created Java, the project with Anke, and we just built that project using Glassie
server.
So that's it.
Setup is done.
Knowing what we can do, we will learn about some Java solid.
So what we can say.
So, ladies, a Java technology to create the application, so so so we're letting Java basically dedicated
for the creating web application sort of difference between a web page or web application.
I will tell you that, but in short, I can tell you where the application is for performing a single
task like we are no more task of creating event registration portal.
So this digital application web pages for marketing and everything about that particular company and
usability anything organization, but web application is particular for that purpose.
So, so when it is API, so so it is known as API and it is using the API basically so it can use to
create APIs to provide many interfaces, glasses, including documentation and everything.
So.
So let's try to able to create a.
So if you know what this API API is basically application programming interface.
So if you want to create some interface, application programming will be used that so similarly like
that API gives you the.
Application interface with interfaces, glasses and documentation, everything, so so will it will
consist Bluetooth interfaces and glasses.
But will he be doing that?
You will understand what is the difference between that interfaces and glasses?
Both are looking similar, but both are very different concepts.
So let's see first what is solid.
Interfaces, so it is an interface that must be implemented by creating any solid.
So as the name suggests, interface it should.
So some application on interface.
Also, the class also is a class that can extend the capabilities of servers and responds to incoming
requests like hold of a pay, each working use client or we are sending something on Google.
So if we are charging something on Google, we send the request for that request.
The server, which is located on the internet like from you, send some search on Google, something
about a car and you want.
This is the request saying something.
Some information for car in that response, the Google server will send the response for.
It will certainly respond for that request.
So basically, it works like that response and response requests.
Sensibilities of the component that deployed on the server to create dynamic Web pages or an older dynamic
web page means you can change everything inside the static web pages or something.
Well, like static, you cannot change.
These are some informal do or die knows.
Web pages like company wants to know that they are all information home.
Then some about those.
And that's it for giving information in dynamic web pages like the event portal.
Or you can say Amazon Web Site is a dynamic.
You can search there.
They can edit something on that.
So this is known as dynamic pages.
So, so are basically used to create dynamic webpages and did so a web component that deployed on the
server.
That's why we need sort of audio.
Otherwise, we can use only HTML and web browser and we can create but nothing like that.
We need one server, so we created one locally.
As I told you, we downloaded the glass server to deployed oversold.
So this is all about the solid introduction.
It is just too basic.
So first, what we know that it is technology to create with replication.
So we need this API that provides interfaces and classes, so it works as both interfaces and classes,
interfaces to implement that UI, user interface and everything.
And glass, which serves as glass to extend their capabilities like, you know, the Java.
If you want to implement logic in achievement, you cannot implement logically, you cannot add something
to numbers there.
You can go through with some logical expressions that in extreme in cases, you need the back end.
So Java will provide this backing in this Java Python as well as JavaScript EU.
And so much so it is very important because it deployed on the server end, not on the user.
So that's because it will create dynamic widgets.
So let us see how it will work to the diagram.
So this is a client.
This is our client or we can sell over machine.
This is sort of a client will ask for a request or send a request.
That's how the network works.
Basically a client which means our system or we are using the next system, we are searching our mobile
phones, anything on which is available on the internet.
So this client, if I'm searching Google dot com on the internet, the Google dot com request sent to
the server.
Now what it will will do sort of what it doesn't have any application or something like that, it will
search everything.
There are some pre-built applications based on Java, JavaScript, anything.
The server will generate a big pain response, so the response is generated at runtime.
From that data, here is the data I can see this is the database, and that response is sent to the
client that so the whole network works in solid and request based on requests and responses.
So now let's see our project a bit like what is the important thing in our project?
So far, the front end part is D.M.C.
It and this is good.
I'm not using Jacir for this project.
I'm going to use a stimulant to use this.
So you should know the prior informed prior knowledge about these devices is not very deep, but very.
Basic knowledge about the stimulus is this you should know Java, so we can say Java programs basically
the what is the classes, what is the method for how will we can easily text between them, then data
or handling it in Java like little Typekit in Java?
So second parties Java Servlet, which is the main backend part we've got, which contains logical methods
and everything.
So you can see these are both are different.
So we need one link between a stimulus.
This is also the stimulant java.
So what will I can?
Well, what I will give the example like in the train.
There is the energy and there are some other compartments also in the train, like other cabins and
everything.
So to connect in June and other that could be next and everything we need to link similarly is imminent
for that particular image.
Stephen Page There should be a Java link if external pesos take input from user number in books and
print ads is there.
Some of these are.
These is the basic application.
So I want to handle this.
So how would you estimate you will tell that this female is this number and it should give that to the
next job and it will take the addition and everything for that purpose.
We need to look very simple.
So what they're going to be a big symbol is a control for.
No, we won't know for that to be a bet.
It's linked, particularly to the specific webpages.
So Solar Project contains three important parts.
Estimates its origins for 400 or anything related to the deployment siguientes Java programs, which
are basically beacons.
And also, we required very big cement of a big cement is for Lake Shore.
What I can say with a big smile, as I told you, it's linking that particular park.
So these are about the least important parts.
So let us see what is the thing.
So late before that, I mean, I want to totally go from for the web application on some application.
Is application accessible from the web?
As you can see, there are several options on mobile.
You have WhatsApp video editing as similarly on web.
There are some applications created nowadays.
You are mostly seeing them.
So basically web applications based on Java solely based on your Java script.
Python anybody like Amazon Web Services?
It's a sell for.
Web application, so web application compose of web components like solid speech filters and other elements,
instruments uses JavaScript editing.
This piece basically jealous pages.
We are going to see further what is the difference between Java, so let programs and jurisprudence.
So Web components typically executed in Web server and respond to the request.
So basically web application workflow.
Now, what is the difference between CGI, the normal requests and responses and what it does?
So let's discuss what is CGI?
CGI is basically.
Common gateway interface.
So let me go with the project, I the do for fun.
First part of our project, then I will tell you more mostly about this and everything.
So let us see how we can proceed with our project.
So as you can see, this is our project.
And I created an exotic animal first, like it's before we created the.
So that said about index or human, but what is our first pages I'm going to create?
Is log in page, so if you know the was in Texas of Yemen, you will understand this.
This is for just commenting out loud and I will.
Oh, creator, then I'm going to use one before us, I can see which I already created and I'm going
to use that to, she is just pulling all things.
So if you want, you can directly use some other cases file to provide a better environment, or I can
say better funding for your project.
So I, as you can see, I'm using, I'm using, I'm going to use this distances for you.
You can directly use this also or it is available on the internet and you can use it, usually use this.
This is basic, you know, to assist with some military one common and everything.
So let's see how we can link this.
So this is human in the title.
I'm going to give you the log in, but you can do the similar things.
This is all about over index, not A.T.M. I just use this default.
So in order to analyze our front page, I can see I use your total purchases to assist.
So I will tell you what is the significance of each tag here.
So this is for linking the other two uses.
Total loss is this I'm going to use only simultaneously to you the other night you have for our project,
then this is not enough to do the one on there.
I'm using science open science here.
Then this is mercury for the please choose the below links to log in to your account, something like
that on the web pages that scrolling.
But the important part here is I read two images on the member for the admin page for admin image or
admin logo just in for the Part B engine for participant image.
So here what I created, I'm going to create two another extreme elephants.
This is all about front end, basically a log in Yemen, which is for admin logging and that admin log
log in and they will attach to another Java.
So look, to create that logic, we will see in the further part on that.
But before that, I created this admin logging similarly for particular logging.
So that said about the individual instruments, what you need to create, you need you are going to
create two links there.
You can put links also there, but I am representing it as a button for simple scenario.
As you can see, I created button and I'm going to assume it will be looking very good for us.
So let us deploy this, as I told you, for the deployment simple steps.
You can right click there and you can.
Let's clean and we.
Now in the output below there, you can see it is clean and are doing all this to be successful, you
can see now let's do this.
It will starting glass server.
So we need a glass feature where we don't we can not deploy anything.
It will take time to blow with bootstrap and everything.
But.
So this is all about java's solid.
And this is basic, so always remember don't change in big starting statement to another fight, what
it will recreate, it will create some anomaly in this new distributed starting page, so it will proceed
with that further.
Well, now you can see this creating and deploying over on this webpage on the server, as you can see
successfully deployed.
Now I will show you that web page also.
So this is our Web page, we just theater, so as you can see, it is no leaving registration podium.
And these images, I'm alluding to the cases by default on the internet available on the internet,
you can change as you want.
And this is all about our admin login in our discussion as this is very basic, I can see and this is
investor testimony, including, as you can see, log in page, you can see here and everything.
So what I am going to show you is when I created this admin log in.
You can see the full status for 04 is not that is not fun because I haven't created any admin in what
against the Bill Finder or web page.
Similarly, for participants logging in for their videos, I'm going to tell you how we can create admin
log in and each page and how we can attach to the Java solid.
So this is all about the beginning of the setup of our five to four hour setup and everything.
So this is the landing page opening page of all of your important.
So as I can told or told you about that, this is our web page or I can see web application here.