So we have seen this is suitable for our project, so we just created one package known as the Image
Lab, and we created a class which is basically publicly specified class no.
I will explain what is our blueprint of our project.
And then I will explain some basics of classmates and objects, etc..
So let's see, let's see what is the blueprint of our project.
So Project Blueprint is considered this is a package package email app.
This is middle class and methods.
Just I created.
So this is Project Blueprint packaging the lab.
And this is email class methods and which I created before Eileen, I showed.
So now this is done, these things are done in future.
What we are going to do as we move our budget, we we will create one main class.
We will load all the methods related to this using objects, and we will execute these methods in say
this meaningless.
This is our main project blueprint.
So let us see what is basically.
Ujjwala classes and methods.
So Java class, let's see first class.
Everything in Java is associated with classes, an object without classes and objects, you cannot create
any.
Or we can say any method.
In Java.
So it contains attributes, methods, attributes that are basically what we can see plus plus plus attributes
create some environment for mating.
So for example, in real life example, you can consider Kadiza Object has attributes such as weight
and color and metadata, such like groundbreaker in something like that.
So basically, what we can create, we can create as a class which attributes which color their model,
numbers, etc. and methods can't stop that I break, etc..
So classes like Object Constructor, we can see to the object or we can constructor off the object.
Or it can be a blueprint for creating objects, so objects are basically just invoking the glass.
Classes, also, which some user defined attributes to pass values or input from user.
So we can, you know, use their different attributes also inside the glasses.
Know what you mean by objects in Java.
So objects are basically associated with glasses, but.
What is the simplest form we can say that we use a glass objective used basically.
So if you define some glass and you want to use that glass, you have to define the object as glass
is already created.
We have to only just create the object for that particular glass as we created an alternative object
of glass.
We can easily create that object.
But like glass, then we can create the object.
So this is this is all about the glass.
No lyricism.
What we are going to do in our project.
So before moving any further, I will proceed with code or project.
It is.
So inside this.
I created this class, so I need to create some methods.
But before that, we need to invoke some libraries.
So for the libraries, I'm going to work.
Import.
Java.
Don't you did not start?
I will explain what is this mean, I'm not going to use this, but I'm not currently using this, that
you're showing it is showing this, you are not using this label recurrently.
But what is the significance of this is very important.
Library Java not you do not start not star meaning in the you bill, I'm using you up all things related
to that.
What we can say is very basic levity inside Java, another steam library I'm going to use is import
Java, not are you not stuck?
It is basically Input-Output Library for invoking and taking user input.
It will be helpful library.
So.
As these done.
Our first thing I'm going to explain here is how to take user inputs in Java so you can do this scanner.
It is the by default method to begin selling a default method for taking inputs.
I'm going to use this.
So I'm going to invoke inside Glass only because I'm going to speak to the public.
So what I can do is public scan the public access to a public scanner as you can.
Have you been seen on the job?
I told you.
It's started.
So scanner, this scanner glasses belongs to this celebrity java, don't you?
By default, nobody.
As is equal to new.
Scan this index, basically this index between scanner system, which is again one when I've done by
default glasses system, which is basically a method.
So this is done now, I'm going to set up some variables here, so.
For this, I will explain.
I just put your scanner class on explanations.
No.
Sitting.
Variables.
Setting the rebels and women to set some variables here.
But.
For the security issue, we can say I was going to create some abstract in Europe.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to use.
Private here, as this is public, given I'm going to use your private.
So let us consider this private thing.
I'm going to specify posturing, everything basically first name.
Similarly, private string.
Last name.
Similarly like that, I'm going to create some or.
Similarly, department.
The beauty department or department, then for email.
Then for password.
Now, consider this, I'm going to specify all these things in the.
String metal like string as a string variable.
Now I'm going to specify it's merely capacity, which is in integer.
Capacity.
The call to I, I'm considering my report 500 500.
Then, David.
Spring again.
Alternative energy, basically.
She.
After.
It so we are done with invoking now, remember, these are the global order we can see all these streets
can be accessible throughout this class.
So in the class, I can create as much as I want for methods so I can use this throughout this class
as you can see this class and I can use throughout this class.
So we are done with creating some variables and I'm setting it to the private to.
Not you access directly, basically.
Once this is done, no one can access this.
It's expensive, it is private.
So let us see with some constructive my thoughts on what is meant, my mental --.
OK, so.
Java class we have seen, as I told you, I will tell some more about plus classes of blueprint.
We have seen two classes something like it, the functions automated in one block, basically.
Consider an example of how is a class, then it condense all details about the prototype of house doors,
windows, etc., etc. Who is it?
No one who see the object of that class sketch of this guy created this sketch.
And they know how he sees the object.
So what we are going to do is class contains all properties of that object.
So syntax to declare class class name as we created it, and I'm going to specify exit speechifying
before that.
Consider if you are not given any access to this, if I did.
By default, it will be default Texas based, in fact, we did basically public only in Java.
But if you don't specify public, private and protected protected is fully protected, you have to invoke
it's more than what we can a method for privacy and security.
So or as I told you object, we are going to create object.
I'm not created here any object, but we are going to create an object for that purpose also.
So it's basically used to call class or executed that glass.
I would also call it an instance of glasses without object, we cannot call glass, always remember
that all the glass we have to use object.
So for that example, previous example, as I told you, sketch of a glass cage off those doors and
windows are some methods that we can see functions inside this.
So this is the main method if you know that in the Java public static void mean is a default method
to execute any program in Java.
Without this, you cannot create starting the program.
Or you not execute the program or that switch off?
I created this object object, you can see object one like this and execute that object.
We are going to see in further details about dollar objects.
So no job, I'm now having nearer meetings, so I will show an I.D. basically if I want to print something
in it.
My default Methodist system.
Oh.
Now you will see the error here is still not allowed in error.
It is not.
Or involvement in inside in Nicholas, why?
The thing is, it's only defined to the matter was created to create class insert that creates a method,
then you can invoke that momentum.
As simple as that, so matters are declared within the classes.
It contains a whole code of particular functions.
Mr Contents, return value and accessibility features.
They are the object classes as object classes are created, we can easily access methods using that
object.
Main method is the foreign minister, as I told you, to run our build for or project anything.
Main method always remember public sector involvement and it's always written strings.
You cannot change to integer or something like that.
You you can print integers, but you can not return in business in seven minutes.
Packages are in the Java.
I've told you I'm against telling that it's just creating a folder and I'm storing all the classes inside
it.
Known there are two methods I use their different methods and standard laboratory methods used different
methods like I created.
I'm going to create some methods here similar like that, though you can also create some user defined
methods, basically.
It's also shows that you delete different methods.
There are some standard delivery methods that I created Scanner System, all the same standard delivery
methods that are built in methods.
And so if you want to a number even on the data, you can create some or even all the functions that
the user defined.
But I specified some library method like random system.
These are not in basically our system different methods.
So now let's move on to our good.
No, I'm I told you about, oh, let's see, how do how we can proceed with building our project.
So we created all things, you know, I want to create one constructor.
Know what constructor will do.
It will print what I want basically first thing.
Second thing it will give me the output as well as creating on itself is the light.
But I was sitting inside it.
I am going to invoke or I'm going to run only constructor, so it will not use this private string or
something like that.
It will take value from that, but you cannot change this value.
Or we can say third party cannot change this value.
Just I'm going to create so constructeur, I'm going to specify that.
You're not receiving first name, last name and everything.
That's it.
Well, I'm going to tell, like only for that, like Flushing last year, that's a.
You can change it to some other names also, but be careful about the name.
Now consider I'm going to create this as a public always remember class and constructor have same name.
So I'm going to give the constructor attributes if the name same name I always remember in the constructor.
You have to use synonym.
After that.
You need to specify something like this if this if economy are totally different.