Previous Park.
I told you I will go up against Wolves.
So bankruptcy just started dividing their day small small fragments, you can see to perform different
directions on the network.
So we are going to capture that whole package using Java.
But the first step is we are going to take our client disconnected blackboard doorknock.
So I considering here two random turns, I'm not considering they're very common plans, so I will tell
you, what is these transcend politics?
So as this is all made to work security, what we can do, we have to shape our client is going to take
the board or not.
It's online, all the more so for that purpose.
What I'm going to create, I'm going to create here one glass.
I've already created one project name as new monitor and I'm going to create one glass here as Nature
Monitor.
Nick wanted so little glass he'd enter, it will automatically create your own glass.
No, no, what?
I'm going to look at private dream.
So I'm going to declare here Keaton's source, target and source and going to.
Source.
So let me make this case, and this is my source, so I use shortcut to repeat that line Stargate.
All these not string.
So these are my full private students, or you can say private data, see it, I'm considering.
No, let me put it here.
The issue of leaks, I think, would mean.
But said Wortman certainly killed.
I mean, time and these are my.
Data base here, I'm going you.
Later.
Mostly, it's very different because I'm not going to invoke it later, so they're just going to use
it as a private.
So now I'm using here some commanding arguments to use some command line arguments.
You know, if I'm going to put arms.
So if I was if you basically arguments, you know, not lent is not going to.
Three Oh, OK.
It's not going to be what I need to perform here is I need to display a few things here I'm going to
display.
Which is basically a very common thing you can check, which is.
Warning the new system, not a dog friendly force,
compile Java all using.
Do you have a comment?
So I'm using your combined command links directly system not only don't bring in.
Then.
Use Java.
So for my team, what here is Java.
The name is Nic Monitor class, name it Monita.
But basically.
And also.
Upcoming.
I will tell you how we are going to use it then.
Sauce is so getting could make this a saucy sauce IP.
Then.
Destination IP.
All.
So this is our basic command.
If you're not using this, we are.
We have to perform this.
The street and justice, so it will return all lettings in local only if you are not performing or if
you are not opportunities.
So these things are done.
Click here to monitor.
And more, and I'm looking here and I got my object in the monitor, so you might need them.
So this is my object.
Working plus.
Object to this, what is this?
How?
Oman is going to work.
So this is how the government is going to work, we are going to use it.
So I was here seemed completely as my direct influence.
So let me get it, Embarek said.
Saws, jigsaws.
These are some things here you can use.
So simple source, safe source.
So this is very you know what?
I would kill.
Odds zero.
So what I'm going to do, I'm sitting here like my arms as long as I'm almost zero.
But this port, oh look, I will create the one six set the every elemental a year later.
But let me put this first, because it is very important.
Bargain argument is one, the humanities.
It's like editing in Java arguments, commonly not so it's started from zero one two three, and I will
create that part later and not start.
That's Maine Common Limited, so I will tell you how it's going to work on the team vehicles so you
can perform it later with six swords and everything.
So let me perform good treatments here, which is basically one, but I think you.
So again, it's in Maine, Mittleman, Oregon.
Close this meeting, if you want to use such beautiful things or brackets, you can use it in lubricants,
it's when plugging in iodine.
So let me create one.
But I won't I want to introduce sip sauce.
OK.
What am I think sauce?
Bring as?
And the critical string is now.
Same source we have seen.
So and assigning this source to sort of a method is then I need one syllable.
But before that, I need to create started method because I haven't created in this document.
So let me create one, but I will.
Started.
Which is a very common method.
It's starting method, or we can say, definitive cause unknown, most exception.
Oh, so.
Unknown.
Course, exception and exception, which is a very common thing, are you exception?
Because if there is an exception, we need to perform this similarly for this dark matter unit to Crozier.
On the Moon Horse exhibition, and you need to draw, are you exceptionalism?
I.
So now everything is done.
So let me put here when I'm writing what is needed, so I will create that part in later New England.
It me in Rhodesia.
Okay.
So if you OK, are you would happy for the timing part, and let me put it this stuff so you can create
your own time working in Java always falls to you because you never stop.
So it will invoke this command again and again and again and again, sometimes the the activity of source
and destination again.
So it's not like, Oh, we are done with some part, we need to put this of schedule.
We need to get, you know, its status.
So let me tell you how it's going to work.
We need to create one new this morning, so task, it's very.
Commenting on.
So actually, it's.
Iconic, so is not.
Let me take the it's working or not.
So.
Oh, and.
It's just because I need to.
Perform it again and again, so I need to use this, so
I will create that this last letter, which is basically a tamer task.
Oh, and the common thing is your next gig going so fast is nothing, but it's very warm.
You can see a robust team who creates soccer, sign everything boards and legal and binding that part.
So now I'm going to grill.
So let me put him.
A sane source.
So told.
The same old.
So similar winter in St. Paul and one here in FT.
Or is it going to be?
Which I already told you, we are going to quote here and
the same.
So again, but I read when?
Stargate scheme Diamond created Target and Target is equality.
So now we're done with this part.
So why more discriminating is basically over glass of glass, which is basically subclass here, you
can consider.
And currently, which he is using.
Public clergymen who do not listen to I need to invoke that part also.
So in these only I'm going to create one some plus.
And you can copy this.
West Coast.
And I will tell you what is distressed trying to find what is the extreme security and what it does
not.
Then what does?
So.
I will tell you how we are going to perform a routine like first.
Remember, it's based on does and which is going to work here.
So it's going to be shown me the error because I'm not implementing any.
Glenn Matassa had a solid middle oblique.
Boy.
So now you think it's overriding this system, so LightStream, the air support.
Simple.
In the state.
I to change this part, so I will change it later in the year, basically nothing, but I will tell
you who I'm going to put here to work and everything should be.
Oh, so.
Teacher, you.
Which is basically it's going to take the integer value of these arguments.
It should be in private, in private, and it should not change.
OK.
No, you can check this thing anonymously.
Okay, so basically arguments is always extreme, but not in digital parts, so there might be errors.
So in the next part, I'm going to implement this round metal and I'm going to declare this.
Hope you understand this.
Thank you.