We have already seen that how are we going to set up this project for online quiz project for GSP?
So it's very simple.
You have to just create the project inside your ID with the Java Virgin Enterprise Edition origin.
I'm going to use your arrival database glass office server for all or database connections, then deployment
on the server.
So before proceeding, I'm going to tell some important part regarding to this.
So what I created agenda in this HTML for the loading page loading landing page, I will add on to your.
Landing.
Beach, so this is our landing page.
I also ordered some boot straps, courses and then some images here already, and I changed this part.
So as you can see for admin, admin, log in just we have to create student log.
So in this version, we are going to see how we can do this.
So this is very simple.
And this started with seven cases.
You can see when things are created here in websites and everything you can see here.
So packages, then all things libraries also added some or all things related to this part.
So this is all about how we can create how we can set about it.
But before proceeding with our project, I'm going to specify some simple Java solid concepts and some
just concepts also.
So let's see what is the Java solid?
So Java Servlet is nothing but technology in Java, which used to create the web application.
So, so it is a Java API.
Which is application programming interface, basically, which provides many interfaces and classes,
including with the documentation part, any written source of documentation is already written.
So what is the Java so?
So you have written the external code and you want to put the data from that data.
This means you are assuming from data or your anything on the front and back to back in order you have
to able to do so.
So for writing the logic behind this, we are going to use your Java solid.
So.
So we let the user interface must be implemented for creating any solid.
And so it is also class which extends the capabilities of the servers which respond to requests.
So you can see that we are already running on the request and response types.
Similarly, so is so work to improve this regarding like databases and estimate part.
So, so it is a web component that deployed on the server, not on your client machine is deployed on
the server park to create dynamic web pages.
So what is the static and dynamic static means?
You are watching some part and it's static.
There is nothing is changing or you can see it is not showing content again and again, it's not updating.
So it's static.
Like you have created one university information page in the static without showing the card information
page static.
But if you want to add at some part in that information using not using only the code, you have to
use some simple text to do that.
Or I can say on the website you tell your how to write.
You are going to see is that dynamic with pages?
It's updating, so it's dynamically pages.
So how so works, actually the source of little on request and expense line sense response to server
and server response generated, and it's moved to the client.
So it's just like a copy of that part and saying to the client.
So, so we let you this request, dispatcher, so request, especially the interface, provides the
facility of respecting the request from another source given so little GST.
So what is the GST?
Basically, just be the Java servlet pages, as you can see.
So-so GSP contains all the things in further part.
I'm going to shoot so late and this people also.
But before that, we'll do the difference between so late and this is so let's not do your job afterwards.
There is nothing inside.
It's like you can add a steel mill course without all that part.
But this being so late are both different.
So, so it is just for connection, but more than just we just you can visualize.
You can create design, also using scissors and instrument.
So this is an interface also used to include content from other resources.
So it's a one way also servlet collaboration, or you can say there are two methods forward and include
forward to forward requests from solar to another resource, or includes all content of citizens from
Lake.
You have to add in to the same results you are using my.
Or do you want to forwarded to something you have to use for over?
Then I told you forward, like for automated request, whose gender did it seems to solve one created
the response for automated was instant, so led to I can see or I can suggest B or anything.
And under this one time to the client.
Similarly, for the included method of what is done, it's up again.
So let's say you are created to two soldiers are created or considered which emails are created or to
issuing statements.
We can create, which includes in the same page responses, generate similar responses and send to the
client.
So, so less important parts of the estimates, this is just as pretty.
Davos on program for biking and logical.
Not accessible for control.
That's it for this overlooked important part.
So as you can, if you have seen the Soviet curse, you can see it, Steve Mills added in so July.
OK.
Is it is it?
They didn't say Gela.
In GSP, what is we are going to insult Java language and say this Jamila pages, so you can see it's
like scripting language where it's pure Java language, so a Java, so litigious.
So jsp use technology is used to create web application just like solar technology.
But what is the difference between these are so let's are only job quotes, but just be as person which
contain some Java language so it can be part of an extension of it, you can see, but it provides more
functionality then.
So such as some expression languages, GSD and there are some gestural technology also you can use.
So this BBH concerns experimental tags.
Some DSP tags.
Also, GSP beaches are easier to win than you have to always remember that these are very easier to
maintain, you no need to take for every step.
Again and again in GSP, and it's providing some additional features like expedition language and custom
decks.
So let us see how we can create this space inside our ID.
So this is my idea I already created.
So, so if I could just convince all your packages, but before that, in good to the web pages, you're
just right, click here clicking you and you can see is, you know, just be.
Hope you can see the G-spot here.
One to right click here, click new and just be.
Click here.
You can see all the entity collapsing, but to just be back, so specify the name for these ones that
another dialog box is basically created when you are doing this.
So for me, let me close this and let me check what is OK.
I'm going to copy this part basically because my name is this.
Once this is done on your books, on the pages, senators and banks, will you?
You have to do anything.
Oh, then click finish.
So it will take time to create one day prepared, as you can see, just be pages created.
Let me cancel this because.
And.
OK, so this is our GST push.
Let us build our budget.
Let us see how it's so clean and first then I'm going to change here because I want to create some in
form.
We can say I want to create here.
So that is lost cleaning, Bill.
If your windows are not saying I'll put windows in watching, go to this and click or output, you can
see really successful.
Now let us run our project.
So it will take time to order the glasses server first thing when you are entering the first thing because
Java hotspot.
So what we aim is running, so we take time to load their tool and deploy all the pages on that server.
But once it is done.
No need to again and again executing this in the GST, as we are doing in Java, so that we are able
to again and again build that part.
No need to build that part again and again in just admittedly this one time and just you have to add
your code.
Then of all things are done, just click final.
And you can take.
So as you can see, it's taking time to honor.
So as you can see, all things are deploying.
So once you do done, you can see where this water is deployed.
You have is there delay of this loading because the water, then I'm using these images using through
your and I'm inserting some scissors.
So we already created this student page.
So when you play this, you can see the GSP pages loaded here.
Hello, world, which which we already created here, as you can see.
So just be patient we already created.
So I am going to change my career and I'm going to explain also that part.
So remember, these fees sometimes slow, then Java solid.
But as you can see, we can add some or exciting animations and things and say just as we have some
power to change all external codes using just.
So let's see how I'm going to change this part.
So, uh, let me.
Delivered this first.
This is ask for comment, but on.
So I'm just due to time constraint, I'm going to just use.
First, I may look cool in another file.
So I will explain that goal, but due to the angles and I'm not going to print, it's very big time
taking part.
So as you can see.
These are the H.M. quarters only.
Let me say this back to these other extremely girls only.
This, you would step see is this I'm adding and everything because for that purpose, I told you or
up I was then this is all about to see is this team move around this with student logging so.
What is this?
This more detail, and with this what I'm going to it's going to get parameters for the message, but
I it's certain that Hayden destroyed the grid.
So this is all about the large border.
Your username is invalid, your username is valid.
So after this party's done, I'm going to specify it means little to put this back.
So important part is this actually this information?
This is valid.
It's students.
And what is this all?
Yes.
So I'm going to create that part with valid student.
So this action just I'm specifying this controller and everything, but I'm going to change that part
because for previous purposes, I just created this.
But later, I will change that.
Also.
So validate student and all things here.
You can change as your requirement.
So this is all about this and the location basically now what is the location each area, which is basically
on click event.
Or to exit that part.
So let us see what is deployed by now.
On the go and click reload.
So let's go to the long information.
So as you can see, our student log in is been when not once I click it, what is happening?
It's going to the first page, no letters logging in.
So it's not.
I'm created, though, for their page here.
So if you would name your addition, it will show your user ID and password.
So this is all about the student logging in for the videos.
I'm going to tell you the GCP basics, then how we can create administrative page also, and some more
information about GCP.
And once this is done, I'm going to use some Gallup polls also to validate, as you can see, you're
using directly this validated student.
So I have to use some methods validate students and things to.
Create and regulate that part also.