Hey, guys, in this review, I am going to show you how to install and download Visual Studio code
on your Windows 10 operating system.
So let's get started.
So to start with it, just open your favorite web browser and search for visual studio code.
And the first line, which will appear here will be from Gordon Visual Studio dot com.
So we are going to click on this link, and once this website is open straight away, you will be able
to see this new download button for Windows.
We are going to just click on this, no matter which is going to download this executable file and this
executable file is around 50 megabytes.
So I am going to read for the download the complete.
Once the download is complete, open the executable sign and this will appear like this.
So you have to accept the agreement, mention her.
Click on the next button and head you will receive various check boxes for the additional tasks required
in this setup.
The checkboxes, her mention as a creative backstop icon and open with court action and open with production
in context, menu is hysterical.
So keep this check.
And also, I would like to check what clicked this checkbox created Dexter Python.
As if we have our next door Python for Visual Studio code, it would be very convenient for you to open
the app very conveniently.
Then click on the next button.
Hey, do we have to click on the install button and wait for the installation to complete?
So after the successful installation of Visual Studio Code, the Visual Studio code application will
launch on your desktop and it will look like this.
Trust me, it is the best idea for any any of the program you'll wish to run.
Look at the beautiful layout of Visual Studio code.
We have a file button, edit button, selection, button, view, button, go button, run button,
terminal health and so on.
You can click on any of the options and start.
Performing your desirable task with this application succumbing to the fact we are here to create a
Java project and I am sure you may be wondering that how you can run Java programs in your favorite
visual studio code.
So now I am going to show you step by step process to configure the Visual Studio code for running Java
programs correctly.
And I am going to also show you how you can run your basic Java program in Visual Studio Code on Windows
10 machine.
So without any further delay, let's get started.
Firstly, we have to download the latest version of JDK and to download it.
We have to visit the official site of JDK download, which is Oracle.
Now open up your favorite web browser.
I am using Google Chrome here and then open the link up on the top of the page.
This link will redirect you to the official site Oracle to download latest JDK Virgin.
So now you can see we have her download links for the gift for Linux, Windows and Mac OS, but.
So we are going to download it for Windows.
Now, select the 64 bit installer, currently its size is 152 N.B..
Clicking on the download link.
Their download has started now, wait for the download to complete.
So once the download is complete, you can see the executable file in your downloads folder, so we
have to run this executable file to install JDK in our system.
So once show that you already have this software installed in your computer, would you like to reinstall?
So I am clicking No, what do you have to wait for the installation to be completed?
And once the installation is simply, I will take you to the command.
Prompt veterans show you how Judaica is installed and what is the version it will.
Reflect, I think, yes.
Java minus minus Virgin to get the version of Java and to check whether the JDK is completely installed
in your system or not, so click Enter.
And yet you can see Java seventeen point 2.1 two years JDK is completely installed in your system.
Congratulations.
Now there is one more task that we are supposed to do before running a job program in our favorite compiler
visual studio code.
So click on the search bar and type environment here so that I two options we have to select the first
one.
Remember?
Click on the first one only.
Yes.
So after clicking on this, we have that environment variable system properties.
We have to click environment variables and then click on this bad option after clicking on this bad
option.
We have to click Edit.
Remember, we have to click edit and then we have to.
Added the environment variable for Java.
Now I will show you.
Here do you can see we have this environment stable back forever, Judy, give us?
So you must be wondering where this spot came from.
Let me show this to you.
So go to your next settings and then.
File Explorer, yes, go to your C drive.
And then program files.
Yes.
So search for Java in your program files folder, a member search for Java.
So here it is.
Yes.
So click on the Java 17 and copy the.
But.
Venue copied apart from her.
You have the best in your environment, variable edit, but I already have wasted so I will not do anything,
but you have to paste it and click on the button, remember?
Click on the OK button twice.
OK, so your environment variable is set for Java now?
That will close this step.
After successfully setting the environment variable for decades now, he had her in our visual studio
code to run on Java program.
So let's get started.
Hey, we have to create a file new file.
You may create a folder.
To run this, so I am.
So to run a Java program, we have to open any of the folder from our system.
So I am opening a new folder.
And selecting.
So the folder is open in visual studio code.
We have to create a new file.
So let me name right Halo Dark Java.
Oh, sorry, I'm sticking you to the next meeting in this.
Hello.
Not Java.
Yes.
So we have created a file with extension Java.
Remember, it is mustard and this dot java at the end of your filing?
No, never run a simple Java program to print Hello World.
So let's start writing our very first program in Java.
We have to create a class.
Name.
Hello.
Publics think would mean.
During.
Human.
So, yes, we created a class, and under the class we created a main function inside class Hello is
responsible for running our Hello World program.
Released inside this, we have to write this out.
There is a shot good also, but I don't like to write the.
Completely so that you feel it.
Comfort, ever.
Later, I will tell you about the shot, put in a separate video.
Soyuz system, door to door train, Talon is required for printing anything in Java has.
In the inverted coma contains a string hello world.
It is necessary to enclose the string inside the double inverted commas.
So yes, we have written the program successfully.
Now we are here to run this.
OK, so before running the image of semicolon after this wreck?
Yes.
Now the court is perfectly fine and we should run.
So clicking on this run button right here.
Yes.
Perfect, so we got the output.
Hello by Insider.
Permanent.
Yes.
So the court is run successfully.
And you successfully run their first Zara program so we can congratulate yourself first.
Let me tell you a most important feature of this visual studio code.
If I erase this semicolon, it automatically shows a red indentation error.
And you can click on this ball icon, which opens her.
Which shows that there is a syntax, an insert semicolon to complete block statement.
So yes, this is the most important feature of visual studio code that it helps us with our mistakes.
It helps us to clarify our errors.
So yes, you have to write your code and wait for Visual Studio code to tell you that if your code is
correct or there are some syntax, error or compilation or two.
So, yes, I like Visual Studio four for this specific feature, and there are many other features which
we will together get to know in this project cities.