Hello, everyone.
So I hope that you all have went through that introduction by email and have again like much idea about
what actually this project is about.
What are the functionalities we are going to attach in this project?
And what are the concepts we are going to learn after the successful completion of this project?
So after getting through the rough idea about this project, we are here to check that working of this
project, how actually this project works.
What are the options?
How are choosing options, navigating between accounts and everything looks?
So in this part, we are ahead.
I've been running the program.
We are going to write the program on our own, but I am here to explain this to my already written program
and a tool like check how everything is working perfectly or not.
So on running this project, this welcome to the dam project, our message will be displayed on your
screens.
And again, asking for that type of icon, like the event that we are existing users, then we will
have to log in.
And if we are like new user, then we have created a new account.
So this project shows up both.
We are a new user and we want to create a new account.
So we will be heading to options from our keyboard and on hitting enter.
We will be asked for an entire customer number.
So this is upon us.
We can choose any number.
So suppose I am using like four times nine as my custom customer number and and that happened to be
registered.
I told you about that.
These credentials are very like, Explore, does it?
But yes, they are disposable.
So we have to keep these credentials very secure and not disclose this information to anybody asking
for it, as this is about the security of our money and this is has to be kept in mind that we do not
like, share these credentials to any random person, which we are not knowing well.
So yes, after hitting and done, yes, your new account has been created, successfully registered.
So this message will appear on your window and then you will be redirected to the log in.
So if we have a press or one in the choice option, so automatically, this will be a parody.
But we have chosen the Create Account option shall dishes that issue in the past, which will be like
asked by the user that you have to register first, then only you can enter to this item like our system.
So we are like, we are having our customer number on the number already so we can like see them on.
What I have told you that you have to remember this in future if you want to log in again.
So enter your customer number and A.P. number has been entered successfully.
Now after this, we are logged in to our Ethereum system.
Now we have to select the type of account you are like we want to access.
So type one is the checking account and Typekit is the savings account.
So suppose we want to enter in our savings account on heading to and after this, this savings account
interface will open.
So suppose you want to view the values.
So initially our balance is zero.
We have nothing in our savings account balance, so we want to deposit some money.
So current savings account balance will be displayed at every step.
We have already discussed it, so amount you want to deposit.
So suppose I want to deposit $20000 to my savings account.
So current savings account balance will reflect our value of $20000.
Now, in the next step, if you will be like viewing balance, then the balance will be updated.
Now, the next step we want to perform is suppose we want to withdraw some money, so I'm hitting the.
It will be asking for the amount we want to withdraw.
So the point I want to withdraw $2000 is.
So once they withdraw $2000, then the current savings account balance will be updated to eighteen thousand
dollars, which is like going to be fine.
We have like withdrawn $2000 automatically 20000 minus times.
It is $18000.
Now, the most interesting feature is like transferring funds within the account, so let us check that
function also.
So select an account you want to transfer that far.
Stop so you want to transfer funds to our checking account as we have like nothing in our checking account.
So amount you want to deposit, suppose we have eighteen thousand dollars and we want to deposit it
current through our checking account balance from our savings account.
So the current savings account balance will be ten thousand.
Now after this, we want to exit this frame and we want to enter in the checking account window now
in the checking account interface.
Suppose we want you the balance.
So our checking account balance is updated to eight thousand as we have transferred funds from this
savings account to their checking account balance.
Now here also, we can transfer the funds to the Checking Account Savings Account balance from this
checking account balance.
So suppose we are transferring 2000.
OK, so you want to transfer funds to a savings account and 2000?
So checking account balances updated now let us check whether the savings account balance is updated
or not.
So what we had, we had, I think the savings account balance was at the last step twelve thousand.
Yes, I can see that we have the 2000 and so on hitting one.
Yes, perfect savings account balance is twenty thousand dollars, which is like walking is perfectly
fine.
We are like done with all the functionalities checked.
We have checked that, yes, non logging and registering thing.
Now after that, we logged in to our APM system, after which we have entered the savings account interface
now need some functionalities inside the savings account industries like depositing funds, withdrawing
funds, viewing balance and then at least transferring funds to our checking accounts.
So after which we have like navigated to our checking account and again, we check the balance.
We transferred the funds again from the checking account interface to the savings account, so everything
till now is working perfectly fine.
So this is an interesting project in Java that we are like switching between options.
We have this code, which reflects the object oriented programming we are having off those glasses and
inside the glasses.
Everything is like taking place.
All these steps are maintained by separate classes.
So like test was prepared rough prototype of what actually we are going to do inside this programming
section, which we will be looking in the next part.
So for me, we have to create a new project in the IDB and after the successful creation of the new
project, we will be creating a main class which will be responsible for like testing and running of
the team management system.
Testing and running, testing and running is only performed by this mean class, and all other classes
will be involved in testing and running off the lake system.
Only this mean class.
So initially we will create a mean class.
Then after that, what are the other classes we will required in order to complete this system project?
So the second class will be account class creating the account class, and this class will be like managing
everything about the types of account
customer verification, things like whether the credentials entered by the customer is correct or not.
So we have to like have two factor authentication to check that whether the PIN and the customer number
entered by the customer is correct or not.
So we will be like managing our functionality for that verification in our account class in the project.
Now that third thing we will be going to manage inside this account class will be like operations regarding
the balance calculations.
Show operations regarding balance calculations will be also managed by this account class only.
So yes, this is the third thing we are going to manage inside this.
Now, suppose that if a user enters any wrong choice from like the keyboard or the wrong option is selected.
So also, that is an exception checking like exception handling method for invalid choices, which we
are going to manage with the help of trying and blogs.
So yes, this exception handling will be performed with this account, plus one invite invalid choices
also.
So this is all about this account.
Plus we are going to pay NADA for pink.
Yes.
The third class we will be using, and the whole thing which we are keeping in mind in the prototype
section is to create creating an option class.
So option menu class we can see and this option menu class.
Will be responsible for displaying the options list, like displaying the.
List of choices.
Yes.
This is the right one.
List of choices from which the user has to select.
That's what he actually wants to do, but then he wants to log in or create account.
Then after that, whether he wants to enter to the checking account interface or the savings account,
interest rates and everything.
So yes, this is US option menu glass and displaying list of choices is the role of this option.
Menu glass and the roadside don't handle the exceptions to handle the exceptions regarding the like
options selection.
Suppose that blaster option attached to a specific choice is not entered correctly then to handle the
exceptions regarding the.
Yes, so handle the exceptions here, exceptions regarding the switch cases.
So what actually switch cases are they will be like discussing it in detail in the programming section.
Yes, exceptions regarding the switch cases will be handled inside this option menu glass.
And at last, this option menu plus will be mapping things like we have a choice and a special option
like that, do that choice.
So that is a unique choice with every keypress.
So with the help of mapping, we are going to perform this.
Yes.
Hand me correctly, I am talking about mapping.
We are going to use hash maps, the structures in order to link choices to specific options so that
on pressing that specifically, that specific option is to be performed.
So this option menu class will be going to like responsible about mapping values
and every key place.
Yes.
So we are going to map every T.
Every case should be mapped to a specific option and everything is going to be like linked in a manner
so that nothing overlaps.
Like, suppose you press key five or anything and that a key on pressing that you enter to transfer
funds internally.
So this is not going to work.
We have to map everything correctly in order to make things properly functional without any open overlapping.
So to avoid any kind of exceptions overlapping, we are going to use different types of data structures,
which we will be looking in the program section in the next one.
So I hope you have understood all the like a blueprint of this project.
Now, from the next one, we will be start creating a new project and then initializing all the classes
and functionalities related to them.
So you see you in the next part with the coding section.