So in previous videos or explanations, I told you how we are proceeding with this, so I imported this
in my.
And know what I'm going to do.
I'm going to mention some code here.
So let me go to the project's structure.
You can change the views.
Your package is also here.
You can check or you can see a project structure also.
So instead of C mean in Java, you can say this is my package basically.
So I don't want to go any further part.
So what I can do, I can just switch to the package view and inside the package you I can see the packages
also.
So this is all the things and application properties, which is basically the application things here.
So as you can see, this application properties files, you can check your.
So let me close this, and what I'm going to do now is I'm going to invoke some things here in the district.
What I'm going to mention is basically.
So before going in for their part, I need to mention one thing here, or as I told you, I'm going
to use your one csv file, which is basically from raw data files, and I'm using your one raw data
file.
It is deploying in every day.
It is updating it enabled.
It is.
I'm going to fetch data from that.
You can use any other team, but my recommendation is just check for their headers, check for each
CSP file or not.
So these are some important things.
So in this part, what I'm going to do, I'm going to mention one thing here.
So let me click this.
So, OK, so let me play this clip, Nunieh.
I'm grading Java class here.
Yeah, well, you can use this software you can buy, you name.
Well, you can go to class.
Well, let me go with click new.
York nice.
This daughter.
OK, so what they're going to do again will be accepted on.
In this application.
Can you?
Don't.
Now, what I'm going to mention is, is this really good on our data service?
So what it will do, it will create a service package with some this, which is basically our class
and it is going to fetch their data for us.
So clearly tender.
So.
What is happening, basically, it's created a service, so if they go to packaging, you can see some
of these issues created here.
These are my another package and let me.
Go with that same.
It means respond.
So this is my package of it, I can with this, and this is basically a person who I import in this
pilot.
So.
I need to mention that you are a little first.
So what I'm going to do is I'm giving up.
Your private.
That big.
You are a little basically, I would say, which is basically strong on reaching.
And the name is I'm going to specify, is my restaurant.
So you can use anything, but I already ordered some part here.
What is it that you are in?
And let me with this.
Let me mention on the date of failure, or we can say, you are here.
You can use any other thing here.
But as I told you, you new, you need to maintain the law basically to see if people check for it.
CSP before I not.
If it's not the CSP, you have to take the CSP if I'm using the raw data failure.
As I told you, I mentioned Engineer Little Project of fighting.
So why this data, religion not.
So now what I'm going to do is, oh, let me create one thing here.
Let me mention something here.
So this is basically the statistics, but I need to open this list in one location status because it's
location wise.
I need to create one list here.
So let me mention this list.
So I'm going to explain what is this?
Let me on this, basically.
And what I'm going to do is.
Let me start at these two locations starts, I'm going to explain you.
What is the useful thing here?
You mentioned it.
So this is the basic thing I mention.
Now, let me create one thing here to basically list public list.
Location start with all that, so it will get the all statistics from that.
So these are the locations then.
So I will explain later.
What I'm going to do this year.
So I'm just invoking the other and.
What I'm going to do is I need to create one method to fish that things.
So in this class, only after the closing, this let me mention one method to finish the data.
So let me create public.
Boy.
Which Kobe began begin to pitch does data.
This is my.
So.
OK.
As I told you, we need to mention this again, I need to mention the decision.
I'm going to create location.
Don't worry about it.
I will create it later.
Little Park, let me create one HGTV client you HGTV.
Client.
So remember, this is a Javadi.
And what I want to mention is you're OK.
So dot net job is to decline for you.
And let me create one client which is basically name as it was this you are supposed to.
Lyon gives equal to.
New.
And she learned.
So this is all about how well I'm going to do this.
OK?
I forgot to mention our client is not in this physically and.
I will explain this again.
OK.
What a thing is to to create a strategic plan for the sickly HTP.
Client daughter new.
I should be glad.
That's it, I need to engineer a strategic plan to receive the client request.
So let me create one builder team.
What is the thing is we disagree.
Did you request?
Did request oh, let me mention this as a request only so variable.
You can use anything here.
Extremely request equal to request.
With some builder class, which is basically issue to be.
Request not newbuild.
Or we can say, the new building on new media.
Not so mentioned in the note, as I told you over the days, you are a not so you are, I think I need
to mention yet you are Ireland's.
You are.
So your eye is basically nothing but integrated, you can see your eye create, and I'm going to mention
this latest data.
What are you hearing?
Plus, I mean, I need to mention one thing here is Bill, I need to build this, so build.
So I mentioned this, so we already created this, so I need to mention one thing here is or this is
basically to give you oral, I think this is what I need to mention me to.
You are I have your eyes embedded.
So I need to create one in Britain here.
And I mentioned this.
So forget about these things.
I'm going to create the ArrayList for that purpose to store the location.
I already created this.
I'm going to run this project after all the things I invoke.
Let me just do one thing.
Whenever there is a.
This thing.
Let me.
Buddhist part.
What I'm going to do is.
System.
Don't start.
Request so this can be sorry.
Or we cannot bring the request here.
If you want to do you then put in the request also, but before that we need to create a string framework
here because it's not a string first.
We need to make a string here.
So what I'm going to do is to be responsible and also response.
Then inside this response, I'm going to mention one.
It's a string framework string.
Use this thing only not a small thing, because we are going to handle the.
And limiters also to be responsible young engineer.
Computer science is equal to what I'm going to do is gland.
This client or send.
Now, I want to mention the GDP response.
So first is basically request.
So this is basically we can say we are working with client request, and this model in the spring framework
only is should you be.
For this purpose, what is the thing is, if do re responsibility?
Its GDP response.
Not body handlers.
Then again, not all.
Bring.
OK, so.
What I need to mention is here is basically.
A GDP response, not body handler's offspring thing, knots, things like things.
Let me do this again.
So, OK.
So it is telling me to.
OK, so our example is not close.
Are you exceptional?
That's.
Year.
I exception.
And interrupted exception, I need to engineer.
Because we are going to face that is exceptional.
So we are going to do this.
So let me do one thing.
Let me invoke.
This.
Directly, OK, so what the missing thing is, I'm specified this so this can be general data.
Sometimes we mentioned this request with this.
And what I can do, I can put into this to.
OK.
So in looking over this application, what I can do.
I can run this application.
So let's check it's raining or not, if there is an error, we are going to develop this and we're going
to check that part.
So currently sticking big, it's raining and Eugen, everything it's doing running my way and is also
distracting the part of that.
So it will take time to run each and everything.
Once this is done.
You can say this is the.
Thing which is removed in future, but our spring will be doing very well.
And I can see change this.
This started Google application.
Gillian is running low.
So this hour, basically the application is running, it is building, subletting, everything is running
in the spring, is working very late spring.
So this is basically warning in check.
And as I told you, I'm just printing this part only, so it will print the info part on this.
And.
So our response thing is very simple.
So I will remove this in later part.
Let me create one thing or let me add one dependency injection here.
So other dependency injection is nothing but one, oh.
What we can say is comms failure.
So let me copy it from them.
Let me go to the.
Do not open here, you can check on your only, so let me go to the project in here.
Let me go to the bombed out and so I need to mention one dependency, so I will add it here, which
is basically in constant CSP and which is basically the for the common thing here.
So you can check your.
Injection, so let me look this part.
So it is resolving all our dependencies, and if the dependency on digital download that, so this is
the basic thing of what we can say are taking each and everything.
So the dependency injection here.
So as you can see, our dependency injected very well, which is basically a budget outcomes.
So what is the basic thing I'm using here is while bringing the data, I don't want to mention it as
a comma separated, I need to mention it says, handling the request and development.
So I invoke that mark.
So later, I will explain how this is going to work.
So for things, I'm going to take this part also.
Let me add to three things more here, all because due to time constraint, I don't want to specify
how much more time in that you can use directly these things.
So let me mention that breakfast, and it's very useful by just basically feet, but nothing more to
this listening reader.
I'm going to use it later because.
And OK.
Let me import jail, what are your dog's bottom?
Style, then it's also.
Started to use one thing using Java, you can import all the libraries.
Let me mention here these importing.
So you can take I importing the libraries, well, these are the some system for libraries here.
And let me add one more thing is basically about a single with string reader, which is basically terrible.
It is nothing but checking this again and again.
So.
Again, what is the thing is basically OK or dental?
So all.
I'm going to pretend.
So it will create glass and each and everything you look at.
Let me do the Slater.
So it will import this, and this is we already done it, POM for.
And I mentioned England before in Europe, or you can check the documentation of commerce on the available
internet, but commerce isn't the thing, but it will take all those sites, though, as in this little
file or we can set you get off table, there are already hurdles.
In further part, I'm going to mention extremely busy on Zoom and we are going to depend that part and
we need to store some locations also in our system.
So I will tell you how we are going to do that.