Who in previous drills I told you how you are going to create this project, which is basically every
new project.
So this is a very title page and I will create your make.
Welcome, E!
So this is over.
My name.
What I can do is like this, OK, so these are basic name and.
I'm going to create two things here or between logging, and another thing is Artemis Logan, so first
grade Logan Logan is very simple.
As I told you, this is important level, which I will put your footing.
Nameless for the Lebanese to post commentaries for the postings, and I'm going to add something she
had been longing for.
So we are remaining with now, whom I will create will now, which is basically going to the navigation
page again.
So let me create one Web page, which is navigation home.
This very simple page.
I'm going to create.
Let me do this first, and I will add that my home page.
So this is my navigation homepage.
So once this is clear in this and it will go to this start, never, I mean, it's basically the first
page of this forum going to index, which again and like between EU level and global.
So I have to create logout admin part of here.
So let us see how we can create logo admin, so it should be in so late.
So let me mention that part also.
So let's.
Not.
As you can, as you if you know this.
This competition will seat again.
So now let me create lobotomy barcodes.
I'm going to show you this.
This shouldn't be this new novel doesn't mean you finish.
So this is my lobotomy.
I will do one thing I will be my new Simpsons movie star.
Then I'll get using.
Start here and.
Eugene, start here again.
So no need to do this.
No need to.
Nic, this production.
New York in the process request and everything is required.
So they do nothing but.
OK, so this in my class and I'm building libraries.
No, I'm importing when another library.
Which is basically.
Java, it's not so late.
Not a notations, basically, because annotation is basically there is overriding.
And nutrition not start, not OK.
So now I'm done with everything.
So.
Let me add one thing here and there it will be, so let.
And so in this bracket.
What I'm going to mention is you're so late about.
Name is logo.
So I'm done in this, no, let me create one protected award.
What I'm going to do is I'm just going to.
U.S.
Defaulting in.
Well, I don't want to waste time in this, I will explain this, but it is very easy for.
If you know this part, so it will do great, it's due to be the commission's response.
It was so without exception are exception.
That's it.
So let me do this.
OK, now I'm going to mention request.
Not.
Get session.
This decision not included.
So what will we do?
It will be invalidated that decision directly.
As you can see.
Well, it will be a good response.
Cindric United basically said that it.
It should we go in lakes, not.
So that's it for the logo part.
Let me read your comments.
Importing images.
Logo.
For.
And.
So now we are done with Lord Automated off our admin.
So now we required some more things like we created now admin and you can see a library and view library
and logo.
So we need to create some form methods once a year.
So this should be inside the solid part only.
So let me create your own phone.
Let me write this knowing why this is important, I'm mentioning the location of this sort.
Once they're done with this, I will explain what is the significance of this?
OK.
So for this purpose, and if you see here admin log in, you can see there are different bewildered
superlatives for the food papa.
So beautiful, but nothing but its ending of everything.
And then now home is basically the navigation home, which is similar to the next major thing you need
to required is also navigation admin for admin part, and it is, again, if you will pardon me, as
you can see, collapsed and everything but you and additional information on the library in port.
Now we are definitely looking for so I'm mentioning admin logging as defaulting here.
If you want to add some more admin here, you can end using ElSaffar.
Also, if you want to use, you can you switch gears also maintenance here, but I'm considering only
one part here.
Then in this rotation and for the next part.
So let me understand, I mean, look, this is what we know and.
Just knowing you created a lobotomy part.
So.
And then with this now let us see inside, but that part, we knew the admin admin library in log information.
Let me copy this part because I'm going to create a let.
Or you cannot see the dialog box because it's another window recording.
But the thing is very similar.
You need to choose solid, you need to mention the class name.
This is basically the copied name that part.
Then add information to deployment descriptor, which is basically X-Men.
You have to check that mark and click the finish.
Once this is done, I'm going to clear this because.
We already going through this, so let me use this part.
So let me put on packages, basically, I get so late because we are accepting that solid, but then.
Let me use this part again.
So, OK, OK, and forward to add so little, so then.
Not.
OK, now let me explain what is this?
So if I create a low level region from which I'd love to be informed, basically it should go to the
desired level library inform not.
OK.
Understand.
So very simple.
It is just for wording part.
So let me create one extremely patient for this admin log in from.
If not, it will go to the navigation admin panel, and we're doing that part again for new instrumentation.
I will use this and finish creating new initiative for this purpose.
So let me use some defaulting third year mission in Michigan and be logging informed.
And that's it.
So what is a librarian?
It should be the name, email address, password and mobile, so that's it.
Be required here.
Let me say this and let me say if you are not suing, you can see there is a black market and so you're
so adamant log in form.
I will again, I will optimize the inputs.
Because.
Optimizing imports is very important to.
If you want to describe all things, then it's no longer required, but.
I'm optimizing the inputs, and I'm curious.
Bolting.
So now when we're done, we try to log in form.
So this is done, but as you can see, this is admin, log enforcement, et cetera.
As you can see, there is one level librarian.
So we need to create some add librarian method also to invoke that and would be in the database because
we are going to use your database connection also.
So in their part, I'm going to tell you how we can going to do.
Always give full name for that purpose, as you can see.
You can copy this from here because it's in a solid package.
So copy this part and you can hear again.
The admissions for longer than let me run this project means they will kill women and build.
So how could we know it will take time to clean and build everything?
As you can see, all in the libraries, we added some files.
So let me add another outfielder also, because we have another job.
John, let me add Alex Johnson.
So now it's added, and let me run this hourglass fisherman.
So it will take time and it will be deployed on your day itself, on your web browser, to the glass
fishbowl.
Sometimes it gives the error that bill is, then there should be a in Java or something that you have
to rectify that error first and then you have to deploy that part.
So this is just we are doing with printing and we are fetching the data.
But now what we are going to do.
We are going to put that data into the database.
But before that, we need to create one user in the database or a different user.
If you want to use default user, you can use.
But I'm going to create another user for this.
As you can see this no viability viability.
Well, as you can see, your module has not been deployed.
OK.
Let us see what is different and why it is doing so, as you can see in Lebanon in.
We created everything, but there is something missing always.
Oh, let me check, wait a minute, family's created admin log in for me, it's created.
All things are created, then what is the missing part here is basically we haven't deployed every part
like you can see that, I mean, and if you live in.
So this is not done yet.
So we need to create this method also.
So in the next part, I'm going to tell how we are going to create this part.
You leave it in and everything.
So first, create one user different user for this part.
I'm going with default user, but if you want, you can create another user for database and you have
bigs you group.
Some grid is there because you need to execute that part or aren't going to store that part inside their
database.
So or in further videos, we are going to create each and every part here, and I'm going to show how
we can execute this because we haven't mentioned some part here.
Lake view LeBron is not clear.
So in next part, I'm going to create new LeBron logos and I thought we already created.
So we will have it in method will be created in there and we are going with that, but.