Hello, everyone.
So in this series of main Java projects, we are going to make a new project again and going to end
this snake was really a game we your list of making Java projects.
We have already covered many projects.
Now we are going to make this project also.
So let's begin making that project in our favorite tidy visual studio code by creating a new Java project.
So.
Clicking on the file python and clicking on Create a project inset enough, I liken.
So after clicking on this button, a pop up asked for an option that what are their doors we are going
to use while making this browser?
So we have no use of these libraries, so we will click on this no fatal option and select this after
which it asks for a pack that we want to store our project.
So suppose I want to store that project inside my next door.
So selecting that project location and then.
It asks for the name of the project.
So my choice of name says that I should name leaked as Snake Australia trade the snake as we are going
to feed the snake in this game.
So I've been putting that name for this project.
We have to hit enter so that we will enter in the frame where we have a new Java project.
So after hitting enter.
OK, so I have already a project name like this, so I will try something under like the Snake of India.
Yes.
So the folder will be named as the Snake Australia.
So we are here inside a new Java project with some inmate folders inside.
If we have the starting window right, we have our dart.
We have Golden Dawn based extension folder and we have a live feed folder.
So that assigns the folder is going to be the core of this project inside the folder only.
We are going to bring the files required in this project.
The classes will be consistent inside this SIRC folder only.
There are three folder already has Dark Java file, which contains that app plus veterans whenever there
is an exception in the application, this file is for the handling that exception if the project is
not able to run or there is any runtime error in the project.
So we have already listed the fact this error handling exception handling in the previous videos.
Also in the previous video, we have given how to install this application and how to run the execution
of the compilers that JDK and everything.
You can check those video if you already have no visual studio code and get in your system and then
come here to make this new Java project, which we have created right now.
OK.
So we have successfully created the frame inside which the project is going to be made in this compiler.
Now we have to import the requirements of this project like I have already told you that we required
images of Apple, which is going to be the object.
And for this name, we have to import images of dogs we had and rendered our icons show you.
Yes.
So we have a green dot, a red dot and this app.
So we have to import these three images first to begin making this project.
So before going to start the programming, let me import the item.
So here we have an apple that's in default.
That file are not being defined and had not been defined.
So this is inside this icons folder, and I am going to drag this inside my assets folder.
So here we have Icon Folder, which contains a green door.
I can zoom in.
Yes.
So it is an apple.
Yes, we have the green dot.
Which is going to be the body and the tail of destiny.
And the head of the snake, other dog.
So we have successfully imported the requirement for this project.
Now we have to start making the project by creating glasses.
So in order to create the flames, we have to create a class called snake, not Java as a new file inside
this folder.
And this is going to give us the snake love.
Yes.
So here it is.
Similarly, for the board, this is that board which will consider the doorframe.
So to make the more we have to create, the more Java file.
Inside this R C folder as well, that is not the fact that we are going to clear the folders, so it's
only necessary for that.
We have our icon, we have our app, the Java file, we have world, not Java and Snake Gabriella.
All the classes are inside this exact same folder, only now switching to the prototype, which we already
made for the project.
We will check the points which we have covered, like we have created the new Java project.
We have added the images to that project and now we have to start creating the flame.
So to start creating the flame, so the snake glass is going to be in the main file, which will be
responsible for running this snake game.
We have created a Boulder Java class also, so we have two classes.
Of course, we can make it in a single class also, but the code will become complex and it would be
difficult for you to handle.
That's what function is doing was so to make that things distributed.
I created two different classes.
So to begin with the coding part, let's create constructor called Snake and inside, which we are going
to add the functionalities what the game is containing.
Now, just after creating that snake object, I am going to call this object inside a public static
main function, public static void main.
And the argument goes as string.
All right.
So yes.
The object is created.
The function is created.
The object is going to be called inside this.
So we have created it and now.
And embraces and inside the flame, no part part of the prototype was to create a frame.
So using that new keyboard, I am going to call the snake object, which we have just created in the
line number three.
Yes.
So no, visibility is by default.
NULL, all false.
So we have to set it to true.
Don't see the frame on our screens.
So we have set the visibility of the frame astral.
So it is showing in that.
So let's just check what the error is showing lying.
So we have said certain access specified as public, we have to change it to private.
So there it is.
Coming to.
So that it is still there.
We have to remain the class axis specified as family.
Let us check for the other way that all this is, said the VISIBLEMENT said visibility.
Some typos on such a hard.
So we have said the system is going to grow.
Now let us import that.
We are setting the frame to travel so fast we have to import that frame.
So that frame is inside the Java Swing Library.
So it is important as Java starts going north.
It is like all of the components are imported, so we are giving it.
So perfect.
Now that class has to forward inside the frame.
So I will extend this class.
As defining as the difference is that component of the Java similarity inside which we are going to
create that application.
So we have extended this to frame important Java swing library and.
And perfect.
So we have created a flame.
We have set it's visibility.
Now switch to the more dark Java class, showing that more glass.
Similarly, we have time for the swing package as it is needed everywhere.
So important the swing.
And after that, one more package is Nakatomi important, which is AWP.
As string is built on the top of the WD Java.
Unattainable WD is also needed with same importance for this project.
So Java?
No, no, no, no.
And similarly, that's true as we have to use most of the packages components of this package.
So yes, we have created the world class.
We will extend it to Japan.
Now you may be wondering that we are extending the.
Snake, as do you frame, and we are extending this, as do penance.
Sure, there is a panel inside which the frame is to be consistent.
We can't put a frame head on here and the both places, which is not practically possible.
The program will give an error.
So we have created a panel inside which we are giving the.
So the board is a panel extension.
Now we will create a board object or construct whatever you wish to see.
And in the similar way, setting the dimensions of the frame.
So said prayer for the size we have to sacrifice from the frame.
Like if!
Will, if there's new.
It's like mesh size should be seen as a new dimension.
And removing this unwanted lines from the all new dimension.
And suppose we want to give the high bandwidth down the frames.
Three hundred and ten on this.
So we have given the size us 200 and 300 for both done better.
This is unmonitored, so we have set the frame size up.
Three hundred and two hundred now switching to the snake glass and calling the board, they're so far
calling the border, we have to add a border object inside the snake object.
So that board object as new are not known simply newborn, newborn and the rockets and clothing.
So let's try to run this and see what happens.
So the snake glasses ominously outgoing to run the Java program soirées the frame is perfectly clear.
You can see it on your screen.
The frame is created.
Now we have to open this in the full size window, like in the middle of the.
Page, so adding.
One more line in the cold, which one responsible for doing so.
So we have gone back and now they will try to run this and waiting.
So perfect.
We have a full frame, which we have theater of size three hundred and three hundred on running Java
for the snake glass, after which we have successfully created this.
Now we have to add the snake and the apple object enmeshed inside this room, which we will be covering
in the next five.