Hello, everyone.
So I hope that you all have went through the introduction and the working of the project by then.
And in this fine, we are going to start up for this section of the game in our idea by creating a new
project from scratch.
So after visiting the introduction and working part, you all have given a rough idea about what actually
we are going to make in this project.
What are the functionalities we are going to attach in the program?
What are the like frame designs we are going to put up in the hold?
So I hope everything is now on like roughly clear thing.
So now we will the like put up things in an organized way so that drafting into an organized thing?
So let us start making this project from.
Visual Studio Code Welcome page.
So this is the welcome page of Visual Studio for an hour, like the installing this idea and installing
do they get parts has been already covered previously.
So before starting this project, make sure that you all have already installed this compiler.
We use studio code for writing the four of them and also the latest version of duplicate.
So make sure that all the Java functions, like the Java programming, can be done without any errors.
So I'm hoping that all of you have already installed both of them.
So I am going to start this project by creating a new project, by selecting a location and then starting
the code creation.
OK, so look at this file icon on welcome page.
We call this explorer and on clicking on this explorer, we will open up our options tab.
So let me increase the font size for better view.
So I hope that that everything is now clearly visible to the viewers.
Now on this Explorer tab, we are going to select this Create Java project option.
Here's this blue, but then we are going to click.
So on clicking this, we will be open upside input like text field, and we have to select from these
options that the water, the toolkits we are going to use in our project.
There are several toolkits like MAVEN, Springboard Works, Micro Profile and so many other tools in
Java for making Java projects.
But in this project, there is no requirement of any other toolkit, so we will be choosing not based
all options from the lake.
This option taps so on clicking no tool option.
Work with source code directly without any windows.
So we are going to write the source code directly.
Like I already told you, we are going to write the code from scratch on this, each of the functionalities
and making my thoughts objects on everything like glasses on everything from that.
So on selecting this non-menthol options, we will open up the final selection of the project to select
the project location and the final user of your system will open.
And inside this file user, you will have to select the latter.
What is the format of the folder?
You'll want to keep your project in.
So make sure that you select the project location ready carefully.
So after that, if you restore like, reopening, it did not get like missed up order like you forgot
where the location also to make things like the less complex.
Make sure that you select the project mitigation by me.
So I am choosing backstop for creating the folder of the project that we are going to meet today.
So I'm clicking next up and then selecting the Project Location Input tab will again.
I've got like up in and ask for any important Java project.
To me, it is asking for and you have to choose earnings for your project.
And that name could be anything of your choice.
So suppose like I am naming this game as not like you can name it, anything I am naming it does not
cross this, and I don't keep things simple.
I am not adding any and or any like above the punctuation things.
I am simply keeping the folder name and not crosses.
And on hitting enter, we will land up a new project like folder.
They automatically open.
So I am looking into and you will see what happens.
So I click then bam and this new window open.
So closing this meathead in our project window.
And there are stories in many files and folders inside this Nazem process project.
So now understand that we have scored all folders like in red folders, which are already like in big
folders whenever we create a dial up.
Jack in the studio could also live and see order in many folders of new Java projects, and the most
important folder here, which is already a patty, is supported.
Every important file of this code, like all the functional part of this code, is going to be stored
inside this SIRC folder only.
So there is no important folder of folders other than this is actually folder.
This is actually folder that is already creating.
And our job of file and inside this Abdul-Jalil file that are like already upperclassman and that last
name is app and this thing is going to execute when that is any of the exceptions authorized in the
application, which we are going to make.
So suppose that there are some bugs in the applications and the like.
Could the compiler want you to like the compiler rule?
How the compiler will let you know that there are some exceptions in your code LEGO and debugging your
code?
And then again, try to run me.
So this is a special feature that we have in Java.
Like, we have our exception and towing function, which with two exception whenever there is a runtime
in yet from them.
So now after covering this then Java file present in the Southeast folder, now we are going to pay
our actual file, which is going to be required to Lycoming, which is actually responsible for this
testing and running off the application and let Rachel's name for the file.
Like, I like the name of the file similar to the name of the folder, which I have chose, and the
file name is going to be knots and crosses, so there will not be any predominance of punctuation.
So I named the file as noughts crosses dark java and on hitting and we will land up to that window off
like that file.
So we have created a class of public not called noughts crosses.
And inside this, we are going to write that actual program, which is required for the functioning
of this application.
So in the end, in the initial steps for this project, we have to declare some of the variables like
the inside class.
We have objects we do not have idea, but we call them objects and objects that we are dual entities,
which we already know.
So inside this class, we are going to initialize some of the objects required file making this project.
So in the beginning, we are bothered about like creating the frame inside which the consistent of this
project are going to be placed so private different.
Private Jeffrey Amanda Alexis named the famous simply frame.
So this is the object of the frame, which we are going to like, make.
And firstly, we have to import some of the liabilities inside, which claim is consistent so far too
important for frame.
We are going to import Java X swing and inside swing.
We are going to like, call dear friend.
So let us write first this and then inside the G-string, we are going to import Jeffrey.
Yes.
So we have important the frame inside our applications, and you can see that there are latex animal
after which we are also going to like initialize other variables in quite so private text field is the
next object due to extreme.
Yes.
Heritage.
And that text field is going to be responsible for counting the squared off x like we have to place
accent.
Oh, and the second text field is going to be responsible for counting the score for oh, so replacing
it with her.
And afterwards, we have to like initialize to integer object for counting the scores of like extend.
So private then.
Private and an account, and we will initialize that gown, those Zino in beckoning as initially there
are no scores with any of the players.
So zero.
And similarly for like we have to change the variable, we can't put same name for two objects.
And in the similar way for oh, so we have successfully created integer objects for storing the scores.
Like initially, the scores are known.
It will be updated in order.
You will write.
We will like play the game and we have a separate function for updating that score, also after which
we have to like initialize the string, which will be responsible for starting the game.
So initially, the string is going to be.
So private string and the string is initially of the game.
So at the start of the game, we will call start again and we will set it up like we have already discussed
about it.
That's by default, the staff that is going to take the Symbol X for playing his last chance.
And we have to close.
This is growing inside double corpse.
And here we are, after which we have like nine locks taken.
But we did for each of the chances to be played.
So we have to like declare a night.
We have nine blocks for each other, so we have to declare it nine integer objects for storing the chances
of players so private.
Then suppose we have block one in the Magne and initially, like all the vault blocks, I say so then.
And after which we have to copy.
Nine times.
And then will change.
The one two, three, four, 10.
So changing this one to two.
So you may be wondering that's why the initialize these be one to be nine Madiba's 210 light, then
I can go to the grid layout so we can set anything less than 10.
We cannot set anything between one to nine.
Otherwise, the values between the blocks will overlap over one another and it will become difficult
to handle each of the blocks individually.
So we are setting value.
10.
Initially, we can take any value greater than nine.
It does not make any difference, but yes, but not take any integer between one two nine.
Now, similarly, there is that integer I like.
This is going to be the isolate for moving between the blocks.
We will see later soirées.