Hello, everyone.
So I hope you all have went through the introduction part of the noted down job application that we
are going to build today.
So after getting through that introduction, I hope that you have gained an insight of what we are actually
going to make in this project.
Our text editor or something that we call it.
So to begin this project, we have to create a Java phone, sorry, a Java project.
And then.
Start the project going, so let's get started.
We have opened the welcome page of Visual Studio code and then trying to write our code.
So.
On clicking this explorer icon.
We get the option of creating job uprising, so clicking on this icon, we will get an option of creating
our project.
You will click on this.
Then we will select No.
Remember, we have no need of Springwood Quarks or micro in this program project so vividly.
No, because you also have to select this in your system.
So, yes, now we have to select a park for our project.
Suppose I want to create my noted down in my next up folder, so I will cool that next door and select
the project liquidation as Dexter.
Now clicking we get the text fee asking are asking for input a job project name?
So think about a name that you want your project to be named as an input in this district.
So I want to name my project as noted down.
A folder, not a noun, will be created if I hit and then so me on projects carefully and then press
enter.
So after hitting enter.
So we navigate to this folder, not down head with some inbuilt folders inside it, so you can see that
this loaded down folder contains this dirt, this dirt with a school name, which is for libraries and
A.R.T. folder.
So that fancy folder is the main fun of.
Any job up?
So if we open this expand, this is folder it already is created in.
So these are the inbuilt folders which are created after hitting the Create project option and opening
this Abdul-Jabbar file.
We get this thing on our screens.
So this Java is basically a class of them.
This class is named as app inside this class.
We have.
I mean, my.
Which contains which is specified as public, so any class can access this throughout this project.
And inside this, we have a strange argument first.
So what this function returns us doing, of course.
So when this function is called, when an exception is thrown, this part of the project is outputting
hello.
So what is the exception?
You may be wondering are exception is that type of error which arises and the runtime in any program?
So suppose we are running this program and there is some metal.
So this exception went through this.
This part in the console that whatever you want to read that supposedly want to write it, does it begin
writing anything?
By default, it isn't written as Hanover.
So, yes, if the program is any exception.
This is called as an error.
So if they run this far or whenever this party's goal.
Yes.
So it displays that are so exception handling is one of the perverse mechanism to handle the runtime
data so that the normal flow of application can be mundane.
It is very difficult to find the box on your own.
It with the help of the compiler, we can do that on baseline and on which part of the code we are getting
data and it becomes easy for us to debug this and run that code again to get our successful output on
the program.
What we want to run, it does so after this.
We are going to create a note in Notepad loan application.
So we will create the new file.
In this as the folder itself and name it does not.
But not Java.
So this is the name of the file.
I am going to create a notepad on Java and this file will go to goingto display the main window of the
application that we discussed in the working part of the code.
So after hitting enter, a notepad class is already created.
So yes, we want a class name does not pass.
Now we want to frame inside with the notepad application is going to be consistent.
So.
We have to import the libraries for creating the functions.
Yes.
Let us import the Java Swing Library, which is going to give us components like free panels and so
on.
We have many other packages inside the swing.
API Soyez importing.
Java X Swing.
Yes.
So this asterisk here, they note that we are going to import all the classes and components of this
swing package.
And apparently it today as we haven't views anything from it.
Once they will use it, it will automatically change its color.
Now, inside the notepad class, we are going to extend it 10 to you to different.
Yes.
So this difference is a component inside Java Singularity.
So you can see it in the suggestions.
So yes, we have imported.
Swing Library and use a different component from it now, is this not one class?
We are going to create a constructor.
Or we can say that we're going to invoke a method called not bank inside this.
Now.
Suppose that we want to give a title to the official, calling it the sect title.
And think about a title like, yes, for me, that title goes up, not down.
We have sat tight there for our programs.
Program, sorry.
And yes, I missed Brace after this, after creating any constructor, you have to enclose everything
inside braces.
After setting the title, we are going to set bound like there is a heightened risk for this thing.
But we have to decide how much we're right and how much law we want it to be.
So I am setting bound.
Yes.
I think tank.
I think so, yes.
And I suppose you can create any things you want.
Now for him to be.
Extending, yes, so.
I have created Bounce.
Now I am going to.
Senator, default close operationally on exiting programs, close the window is going to close automatically.
So setting default clause operation, I have said before close operations and.
The should be closed on invoking this matter.
Exist on clauses, so the suggestions are life.
So that said, before the operation is going to close the frame when we did the program.
Now, let us try to run this and see what it is going to give.
But before running the program for us live, we have to create a function which really made us possible
for running this spyglass.
So creating a public class.
Call it does mean and not said it will be a string.
Yes.
No.
So I think this.
New CNN-ORC Bank Plus.
Setting the visibility of this glasses through.
We have to call set visible.
Yes, set visible.
And it takes automatically a Boolean argument.
So we want to see the application, so we're setting this visibility below.
Now let's try and run this class and see what are what we are going to see.
So perfect.
We have created a frame.
Yes.
So these are the dimensions for this frame.
The name in the title.
And then we click on the close.
It will automatically close and none will say so perfect.
We have created the right frame of this program, a mainstream which we inside which we are going to
add all the components to be performed for editing, writing in saving our text document.
Now, in the next part, we will learn how to earn nav bar items such as fine and help.
And what these buttons will consist of.
So see you in the next five.