So now we are going to be available for our first order on the steps of development is understanding
what is looking to see it.
So this project is, we can see deployed in blue box.
First, we are going to create on console or console team here, which is unsought application for Java
to understand the different algorithms and how the would have to later on.
We will discuss the solid part which our application we're going to see, which is providing encryption
and decryption interfaces.
So was this really relevant, which is you are alluding to the previous projects to customize that back
in the preferences?
I certainly welcome page or.
So hit new project here.
Well, you mean the new project window for, you know, there will be no lag, there is some lag, well,
deploying this for me.
The statement.
OK.
So for me, new project is started.
It will do one thing I do dear previously my mentor.
We don't want many.
Really glad you had a Java project.
So let it be loading, it is taking decades for me.
Saw Jews go abroad, you.
You're sitting in my new 16., didn't one to virgin it next.
Oh, don't do this it next.
Oh, these are some of the things most mentioned in.
Encryption, key electromagnetic encryption, encryption.
See this.
And you finish so it will take time to get a building for me.
So if you want to change different things related to cryptography, you may check on internet.
There is a lot of information available for different algorithms, but most common algorithms I already
know new and I already shared the previous information about cryptography, how it's important for different
purposes.
So wait for sometime.
Do these ideas based things need to be created?
The source told anybody thing for me, and we need for something to hide.
What happens?
So he's looking for me now.
First, I'm not going to or directly, I'm going to created for Steve.
My name is forward.
Oh, hold the keys generated.
So let us see who actually key generation part votes.
OK.
How is actually eating smoking here and what is the basic thing, so I'm going to explain here.
So let us do that by trying to create that part.
So let me mention one thing here, which is I'm going to create one class here.
So for some time to response the idea, it will automatically detect your bias and everything.
This.
So in the ICRC folder.
More to the ICRC team here.
We'll start to see you and choose your new glass.
So for me, I'm sitting to the semantic as my last name.
There should be one complete cluster mentioned as a symmetrical.
And he didn't do it, he one class for you, for me to make me miss so much.
It will take time to create your own glass, and it would appease.
So once you go to this, you can check your semantic glasses created, and now let me minimize this
because this is no longer.
OK, so this is my semantic glass, which is going to have some glass, which is going to create an
evil.
So for me, I'm for this really only or this tutorial.
What I'm going to create, I'm going glass the idea.
You mentioned to me.
Submitted to kill.
Oh, then it's been mentioned on screen, I'm using it good, so.
Yes, let me mention well before that, it shouldn't be final, so let me mention public static final.
So I mean.
Hopefully, not only for me, so I'm enjoying this, it's fine, a little one can taste this.
Yes.
So I want to stick it to that, but then I'm going to create one function.
To create one secret look.
I'm going to create one solution to store the secret.
The saying, why are you there?
It is as final arguing you shouldn't be given OK function to create some security by ammunition is final
because yes, my algorithm we mention algorithm for.
Encryption.
For encryption.
This is my final algorithm,
which is a advance encryption to make a deal with them.
I would use them.
But let me mention one.
Function public spending.
Secret.
He.
Police, state security.
Secret key.
All there is one before things.
Three, eight, three eight.
He is 80, yes.
So from here and us, so ultimately, so why I used your Orlando crypto job security is going to you.
Oh no.
Richard Cruise.
Exceptional because there is exception, it should throw some exception.
Then.
I'm going to create new instances of insecure random glass.
In new instances, when you see object instances for new classes, you basically see good random classes.
And you mentioned Glass on that maybe not erode.
We will understand why been this?
So.
Good, random, I'm going to mention good, random as secure, random.
We want done.
Secured random.
Is equal to new.
Securing them so this is my object for good random team, which is going to be the random class for
me by since the string to each other.
OK, now what I regret string to 300.
Since June, I need to pass this gene in.
So passing screen is very easy key generator.
There is one default function generator.
He can be done if he wins again.
He generated physical new key generator.
And I need to mention the algorithm.
So what is the matter with?
He was j used only.
But, you know, I need to mention here instances why I need instances.
So for the East spoke for this key generator, which are good them I'm going to use.
I need to ensure they get instances.
So.
No, that is for me to do.
Let me.
And this again.
You you generator.
Dick.
In this.
So there might be.
OK, I need to go.
Don't go into space.
I will.
The role of new because I'm not creating any instances I'm mentioning directly instances yes or no,
no, not one way to specify a new thing here.
Then I need to mention the initialize the key generator.
Initial rise, Ye Jin.
Initially.
I mentioned here with 256 256 bit that we will be initially.
So that's a data breach, which is going to convert 256 bit risk.
It's going to randomly get 256 bit sticky.
Then what I'm going to do is, oh, you generation initiative, so it's very easy to generate a and
you need to 56 and we're going to do this.
This is my disease.
No.
Not with this one guy I need to mention, which are going, you know, securing them and intervention
securing them.
So what will be happening 256 bit random randomly?
It's not independently.
Then I need to mention security.
Security.
Vic Bridges instance, security as my key part for which, but police won't let me mention a small key,
right, with which key generator will keep the generator gripped the nation off key, which is basically
generating.
So it will generate key foreign.
No return for.
So, no, you should listen.
So this is a metaphor for creating the key generation part and everything.
So in the next part, I'm going to create and I'm going to summarize this because this is not completed,
but it's just instances of its algorithm which isn't going to create class to create key with symmetric.
So it will randomize things like it's going to work.
Welcome.
Kathy?