In previous team, I already told you we create an email application and we are most interested in the
dark part.
So what we have done here is we created one in next door, Justine.
If you want to check how it's looking or anything, what you can do, you can just go here.
You can check your other options and.
You can check for that purpose where Web servers or.
Is configured if Web servers are not configured.
Oh yeah, I would check for the web server configuration for that purpose.
So currently, no service is running for me.
So if you want to check, you can go to the settings and you have.
Check for the silver.
This is for by Spitzer, who begin.
Was.
So you can check for that here, I was sure you can check for.
News, So these use our GSP anything but the.
So this campaign, which is committed to send one e-mail application with some people saying, I'm writing
something here, so remember this will be good just from this minute planned.
So these are my glass.
We're also near term going to work.
So this is my glass.
I already preferred or I already told you about this.
So in this class, what I'm going to do, I'm going to create one method to handle, request and response
to everything.
So what is known is once this is constructed is closed, I'm going to create one method and then request.
Request.
And just response.
OK, so what is the request for response and so any class warfare initiative is certainly I need to
get two mentors.
If you do both stand to work, which are very popular, but in such case.
There is an order requiring new post motor vehicles and not for wearing anything or doing any complex
application or selling which only do it.
So what are going to dictate?
You can use us also, but remember who I am protecting?
Well, look, this is a matter of budget and safety you do get what I'm going to do is etched deep.
Answer and choose for legal response on everything, so it should be a response.
And.
OK.
Then what I'm going to initiate.
So let me do one thing here is GDP, so it's not responsible to be solely responsible.
If we were to add to be.
It's a solid response.
So a little response is both an extradition request on some.
So you think what you just so late?
Increased.
What I can do is also because it's no longer required Johnny Galecki and we look.
Yes.
But.
No, I need to handle this better and need also to let me do one thing, let me minimize this so I can
display this one.
If you know, there is one request in this budget, so you can refer any name here, as I told you,
I'm with already, which is very common in the dispatcher.
So it's a request not.
Request, dispatcher, so it's basically going to fetch the student body, so which street parties,
when crews index.
So please don't speak.
Well, now we're done with this.
So what is going to do it is going to fetch all the data as a stream format from next door.
Basically, when, say, the location of my index dog day spent providing.
So remember, always handle any exceptions, no more exceptions.
You might find the reason for this solid exception.
So let extortion, you have a solid exception.
Plus, if I'm not providing input and output, I always.
So that's it, I'm going to let you know when we learned some things in, you may not get any exception
here on Meet.
You may not get any input by the user.
If I'm not providing any input output, then this will not proceed.
So for that purpose, I'm putting this exception.
I'm the exception to bring that part, then R&amp;D forward.
Response request, response
response.
I'm going to handle this request in response, so you just don't need to do anything.
So.
Right.
What's being made it is OK, first time you get to exist and then having a good response.
So I made an error here.
We just don't want you to know this is bad, because remember in the article forward first to request
the response, there is no first response from the first is request on this sort of brutal force.
Is on always.
Newcrest, any so far, so do the solid work you remember just getting part of the weekend fetching
data.
If I want to put any message, I also need everyone to post metal.
Remember my posting any message, I need one.
Most important here.
So.
I will put your great metaphor.
So let me put one thing here is May to bring.
So let me message to.
Page, so this is.
Fortunately.
Similarly protected void.
Who post?
The funeral is due to be sold to sponsor.
Request, so let me do one thing here.
Let me pocket this point because it's as it is.
No need to change in the group was trying to get rid of the sin and expose this again.
I extortion and everything.
So why it's doing exceptionally well relevant while developing any application, you now may find that
part.
So what is going to ask?
Sure, it will ask what is going to fetch it is going to which it is going to fetch some data.
So we did not string email list.
So if you don't request, don't get me get parameter.
If you're not doing this, get very interesting.
It's going to fetch.
Stringer's image is going to feature.
So let me copy these things again.
Let me tell you what I'm going to do is so news for them.
This then and this is just to sentiment which receive us.
But even then, subject for these photos and what your subject subject is basically anything what your
title of your mind and body so you can put anything here.
I'm cooking as a musician, musician and just change also music.
So which are these drinks in the subjects?
And if you don't know?
Let me show you.
Well, putting this, I use the name here.
This is e-mail.
Fish e-mail, subject and message.
So I created a connection here and I know featuring this guitar as my everything.
So let me do one thing.
I can create an operation team here, so let me tell you why I'm putting operation because white and
green and accepting that in an e-mail application, once you put that part request, don't get barometer.
And it's operation.
So I'm mentioning Operation New Single On Me, initial operation this operation, so I need to create
this upheaval and everything, what's going on?
So these are done, but email.
We go, which is basically the same thing we're not equals, which is basically going to equal signal
case, it is going to, you know, the cases will be.
Basically, these open implications here don't have that much on their part.
Now I'm going to say some messaging team here, then I'm putting some things here.
So let me just copy these things and I will tell you, what is the significance of this and what you?
You can copy an instance in a cable just so you.
I haven't created this part sending me.
So what is going to do it will.
I'm going to create an e-mail message last year, which is going to handle safe set subject, saved
message suit message, stay clear, which is extremely, extremely misleading, will be mentioned here.
So all the things is consist in this e-mail message part, which e-mail you did.
And it's going to send that message.
So it's related to all these.
Quite.
But I want to mention this part, so let me do one thing.
Let me handle this first.
Did you basically request a request not to sit and review the first extreme Cindy's message?
And what I'm going to mention is the oldest meeting.
Has been sent.
Successfully so once this is sent out to do a redo, it will bring this that issue Milpark, or we can
suggest people, so I'm going to do this part later, but I just copied this and I already created this
part.
I will tell you what is the significance of this letter?
It is the main function to send any e-mail here.
So this is done in each loop now.
Let me handle decreased this budget request, it ought to be a lead is going to request not get requests
dispatched to get requests dispatched to deal with endangered jobs.
Just that location, which is a single location.
I'm going to Griffith and already not.
Forward.
Request slash.
This box.
So, no, we are done with this mail.
So medical and handling is very simple.
It will handle some it will be asked for and the data handling that despite it will do.
It will handle that.
But this e-mail message is going to work with male flag.
So considering if I told you earlier, Oh, my sympathy is going to work every day later, but what?
This class is just great.
It's just that they act as a reaching the data from their JS people because we are moving in just people.
We as a user, we know that, that we are putting in that meeting, but we don't know how the vaccine
works, actually.
So that's making parts for this milk gland going to face data in order to realise I'm going to tell
you how I'm going to create.
I'm explaining the same and also how it's going to work each and everything.
Plus, I'm using your Gmail as my seem to be again, telling you if you're familiar with there is simply
this there are a lot of services haven't even begun to freeze and give you services also looks so you
can use that part also.
But I'm going to hope you understand this.
Thank you.