We already started our project, which is based on Jarablus system, which I am the name is Connect
the Globe because I'm keeping the people throughout the software.
Or we can.
So where are you planning to be, Angela jealously?
So if you have seen we already created this in our space, we created indexed on this page.
And I already quoted some part, I will tell you the significance of this part.
So this is the index page, which is basically first loading beach or landing with the page you can
see knowing what if these things?
I will tell you later, but this is very important.
I'm referring my page language a Jawa, not a demon, so I'm embedding it, meaning the Java coding
HTML.
You can see Jews.
So the beautiful thing of Jews being ignored is these are all the JavaScript where I refer to some see
as this place.
So if you have seen these things.
OK, let me show you these are the GSP to create.
But if I'm going to downward a little bit and I will tell you where I'm using in.
So all these things are basically just be just be language.
Or are we going to lose language?
OK, now you are saying this not logging message, editing out print, it's basically not estimate it's.
So I'm embedding inside these these other things very important sitting in the green, so the Green
Party's jealous, so I'm using you to GSP, know why I'm using GSP instead of using it and you say it's
very useful you can use this in the stimulus long, but thing is very printing this message.
You can see this.
I just want to bring non blogging message or something like that in this.
What I have to do?
Oh, I have to create one steam and then I have to submit for the silver lining back in the general.
Now I can create one just just fine.
And in that only I can use Java.
I need reloading.
So that's a beautiful thing because I don't want to create any stimulant that makes so little time.
It is.
I will tell you what is the gist?
Yeah.
Then I created an admin page at Ninja SP, which is pretty similar, which is pretty similar.
But the one thing is here is.
Just ignore this, I just I didn't see nothing but just the same things, if you know the job or the
stimulus is just writing this, but because I do, I'm going to add some imaginary part.
I even just this platform again.
And these are some images I'm downloaded from the internet and.
Here you can put some things, then all the things you can put here.
So important thing here is his form.
Well, then what is the form?
Basically anti-logging?
I've been logging procedures in the direction.
It will ask for username and password, name as username and password you logging everything you need
is very important, and I'm including who directed him and who at that super and which is the designer
who directed him and basically nothing but which mean some links, images, then something like that.
So we all already created I just added admin to speak with this.
If you want to create another team you like just on your phone, you can activate Google minimalistic.
Look, I'm just adding all the text here.
I'm just copying that part only so you can add that part.
So let let's see what you the GSP be basically.
So I would.
So let let me go to this whole post.
If I told you that, so what is this?
It's so pure.
You can add extremely insane that where its requests are, what I'm just posting each in related with
this.
But what if I can use only if I can put them job only on the network instead of being on the server
instead of giving load on the server?
Because Server is also searching that file for that particular part.
But instead of that, I can put Java in the network.
Player, which is basically network, is also having some storage capacity.
We can say where we can transfer copies if you so I can embedded that pipe in the forward network,
including each and every team, then so important parts.
I'm going to tell you if you know, the Solarte team bought on Berkshire estimates, this is just for
the frontend Java servlet program for banking or logic.
We can see and Vivek's email to control flow of webapp each and every one instead of this great piece
of Java.
So they just basically Java language inside a single page, so you don't need to worry about them,
not email me if I use any law and order.
No need to worry about that is, to me, will take care of itself.
We know that syntax, or we can say scripting syntax for that was to link between Java and streaming.
Do you then cannot use drinking for dirty money, sending me money that you need to create dollar,
single dollar for you, for the debt?
Like, please notify everything.
So that's another thing.
But I don't just for fetching power, just for this playing part.
I again, you just feel so juiced for technologies used to create web application, just like cellular
technology.
It can be part of extension of so little because it provides more functionality than solely like expression,
language just in general, scripting languages, everything.
Transcript language also provides.
So Jaspreet Page contains statement explicit GSP text, as I told you before that.
But then GSP pages are easier to maintain because of soldiers because we are designing development.
If you know, like let me show you.
These terminologies.
On that is more padding here, but nobody's asking you, is this part of you?
So it's very big file, as you can see.
So as you can see in this part, you can see this are all the teams are basically designed and these
all the things are a basic part of our development.
So GSP is easier to maintain what we can say, easier to specify the gap between designing and development.
If I'm using a steel mill and late.
And what is the difference?
I have to here to one another fight which isn't going to slow down the silver and which just going to
load.
So it takes more time and everything.
Maintenance is very difficult.
In that case, it provides additional features, with some expressing in languages custom tags.
You can create some custom tags in scissors or JavaScript.
You can use that directly in jiffy.
So that's a very good thing.
A lot of things happen.
But what's the advantages?
Basically, I'm going to tell you it's an extension.
So if you know, just like we have so many mutations, like four legged forward material, each and
everything, you have to remember everything, syntax, each and everything.
But here there is no such case.
You can provide as many as four cases.
Everything and extension are solid because random extension, you can use some implicit objects you
tags because sometimes you can create expression language you can create.
You can create other methods in just be.
Also, this link to lets you have to remember you use this index.
What this will do is be embedded in just that triangular arrows with precision.
And you have to indicate this.
Who do you recall that estimate, hearing some buildings that easy to maintain, as I told you, it's
very easy to maintain.
We meet a lot of business logic with presentation, logic and solid like logic.
You basically do look at this video and you have to make Meeks look like for the simple part, each
and everything else could outdoor and you didn't.
Oh, then fast development, no need to complain.
I will tell you what is the 10 year old solid if you create a new zone, if you are really it down in
your butt induced B, consider, you know, the one goal induced field you can say, you know, no one
and which is related to your got a -- thing after you created industry for you.
And after developing all that violently blowing on the silver, I'm not playing under this law, but
I'm getting one on of wood after three weeks.
You are as a developer.
You have some mistakes in that you need to add a one more GSP.
You can add them just spin that slower part.
Or we can say the plumbing part just added, you don't need to redeploy.
No need to change that dot com part or your part.
It just added it just acrobatically really blurred.
So no need to re compile it once it is really oh, what are we going?
Say there is no interest in that DSP.
You can really blow it again and again as many as I want because I going into clearly plug in JVM or
Java support.
Similarly, if GOP bridges is modified, we don't need to compile redeploy.
So let girls need to updated RE compiled some names autobahns for reaching their database.
If we are militarys, the black teams also swing them so it's more on if we change the look and feel
the application and everything.
We are needed to the internet so that it means we need to stop this all, but we need to redeploy.
And then again, small but Indexer would like.
So instead of this, what are we going to do?
We're going to just add to just being said that, I mean, oh, we can perform such actions.
So let us in the IED.
What I created already, so do the Adam and Eve person I put along in this.
So let me along in procedures.
So this is very simple for you.
More than putting the ad may not have been my password.
You can choose any differently because I'm saying this only I don't want to specify.
Oh.
Thing here, and this is importing this apart and all the things into this plane.
So this is all about power.
I'm creating this, but let me tell you the basic thing here is, Oh, if we have seen this far, oh
already, oh, I'm listening to a status DSP.
So I will tell you later, what is the significance of this is that knows everything, but always remember
one thing while developing this, you don't need to recompile it again.
As these are the GSP files you don't need to compiled.
So what you are going to do is just here, just add that file in your project in GSP.
As I told you earlier, how we can add these files in your GSP.
Similarly, you need to add that file in, just be just be complete and you are going to develop your
files and each anybody can hear.
So this is all about how we are going with this.
So in further videos more, I'm going to tell you, I'm going to create some files here and I'm going
to build it throughout my project with some difficulties I'm mentioning here.
Some place you need to create here, but.
All these women will create all faiths, don't miss any food profile or anything.
So this is the age status and I'm using a school.
I will tell you what is the significance of this glam, putting the school file in each and everything?
Logo dispute I'm going to create.
I'm putting everything here, so I will tell you what is the significance of this each and everything
in later part.
So this is how we can create.
Well, so let us create one mortgages we already created.
It's just to see what you can see in the file.
It's not very useful for because there is no logic inside this.
But let me show you what is the file.
So specify the file name is in here.
You can finish.
So it will take time to produce before it, once it is loaded.
Oh, you're going to see this file.
It will be all of this.
With win lose faith, I'm hoping this as it is because.
I want to stress and we going to go.
So let me tell you what I'm going to do this year.
So my plan is very simple.
You say she's very simple.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to create one.
I'm going to use one HGTV protocol here, which is basically nothing but some.
Well, what are you going to package your some templates here, which I to use?
So it's nothing we're just creating the objectivity thing and creating some, I'm going to edit some
locations.
So if you want to add more locations, you can add.
But I just started only two or three locations.
You know?
These are the locations I ordered and I found on internet easily.
These are some random locations I did, and I just want to put this.
So if you want to, you can hear more using or creating objects.
So these are the probability and these are the only JavaScript things so that suitable period or DSP
which I created, you can be it in this part, if you want, you can develop this far parties.
Very easy.
But I'm adding some functions here, as you can see here.
So this is how you can develop this part.
Function functions and learning all these things are related to script JavaScript, so if you want to
add Java, you have to mention that syntax, but I just started reading JavaScript parts far differently.
So we can create this part.
I hope you understand.
In the first part, I'm going to explain the mean logic of this girl Baqir here with their database
connection.
And this is it about this problem.