Hello, everyone.
So I hope that you all have went through that introduction five and the working off the application,
but black David and have gained much idea about what actually this project is about and what are the
functionalities we are going to attach by making this project?
What are the classes and what's inside the classes?
Although like methods, we are going to add in order to make this project properly functional.
So this is like the internal initialization of the programming section.
We are going to make a new project in our favorite tidy visual studio code.
And then after we are going to like and classes and functions in order to make this system functional.
So this is the welcome page of our individual studio hall and inside this welcome piece.
We are going to create a new project on clicking this explore.
That option will appear and we have selected our project from that sidebar option.
And inside this, we have to like choose the type of based tools we are going to attach in our project.
So this is a basic project to you.
We are going to use core Java in the programming section of this project.
So we will not be attaching any external tools otherwise.
We have several tools in Georgia, such as MAVEN Springboard Quarks, Mike Low-Profile, and these are
like, very important to those in making most of the project.
So in this project, we are going to work with the source code directly without any of those.
So we will be selecting Norbert, those now our friend that files user of their system will open and
ask you for that.
The what is the location of the project that you want to keep of the folder which will be created,
which will be containing all the files regarding this project.
So Jews are like a correct location for your project in order to like.
If you want to find that project in future, then you can find it without any mess easily.
So I am choosing next up as my project location and on helping the select project location.
But then we will enter this input field, which will be asking for the Java project to name.
So I choose like a good project demand, but which is going to be the name of the folder containing
that project.
So like, choose your name wisely, which defines your project.
That's what actually this project is doing, so that if in future you like going through all of your
projects just by listening to the names like reading the name of the project, you can like remember
everything that what is happening inside the project, so do not choose any fancy or anonymous thing
as a name of it.
Just simply name your project.
Read more Actually, like files are doing inside of the project, so I am going to name this project
in management system.
So it team management system is going to be the name of my project.
You can choose any name for your project according to your choice, but make sure that it defines the
meaning of the project pretty well.
And there should be no anonymous kind of names for the folder.
So it then management system is my choice of name for this project on heading and.
We will enter the window of the project, which we are going to me.
This is the folder it power management system.
There are some sub folders inside this, which I like already present in baseline of folders on creating
this project.
So we have created this project project targeting this explorer option from the sidebar and then creating
a job up to now selecting a location and naming the project.
We enter this project like interface in our compiler, so this darndest and not be chords of.
All of these projects are at the mercy of this gun pilot.
We are having no use of these two folders in our project.
These are just like inbuilt folders of the compilers which have no use, no use for us right now.
So yes, they start this standard bar Bardot.
We have called folders can be ignored right now.
Now, after this, that ASIC folder, which is going to be the main folder of our project, this ASIC
folder is going to like contain all the mean files on the folders, which are going to be involved containing
the classes and functionalities of our data management system.
So basically, we can understand this as this ASIC folder is the body of this project.
And inside this body, we are going to have our different body parts which are going to like, handle
this complete system.
So inside this, I see folders that is already present file and this file is containing a class called
app.
So the name of the file is after Java, and it is going to be a class app inside this class that we
are having our function.
I mean, function, which are containing string as argument.
And this will run whenever this application with or other in diameter.
So we are like handling the exceptions with the help of this class.
And whenever there will be an exception, this will print hello so we can like let's signify that are
yes, there is some runtime error.
So we have to like debug things and try running the project again in order to avoid any kind of exception.
So yes, this is going to be like the the structure of the project.
Once you create a new job project in the magnet in your compiler.
So now what?
Actually, we have to do, firstly, we have to like we have discussed in the prototype section that
we have to create the mean class, which is going to be responsible for testing and running off of them.
So the main class is going to be the class, of course.
So I am going to name this class as if the dark java.
So the file is created and we are inside the file.
We have a public class atrium created already, and this class is going to like, as we say, responsible
for testing and running of the application.
So yes, now inside this class, we will be creating a main function of, of course, as we have to
create a mean function, though like I stand on the program.
So public start date.
Void main and again, string arguments are going to be parsed inside this function a square bracket
and access box.
So the arguments are strengthened.
This little exception.
I use exception, and this exception will be thrown whenever there will be like any kind of exception.
While running of this project.
So inside this, we are going to create option menu.
So we have discussed already in the prototype section that we are going to like integrate every options
inside the options menu plans.
And that option menu class will be responsible for handling everything about Nokia, like the input
and the like functions attached to every choices.
So option menu and this new All My Card is created inside the main class now calling the introduction.
And the introduction will be called as a tone or a construct, as we can say that all we will be creating
this inside the other classes.
So I've shown my new yes, dark main menu will be like reflecting as soon as they execute the program.
So we will be creating this option menu later in this project, just in the main class.
We are making things clear that the what is going to happen when I read on the project.
So yes, the introduction of class or the function we have created is going to be like containing six
out.
So six out is the sharp good for system, dark out the plain talon, which is going to like print anything
we are now are about what we know.
We can see that.
So let us capitalize.
Everything will come for a better life.
You are so welcome to the IT Dam project.
And yes, so welcome to the Ethereum project.
Our estimation mine goes well with it.
And.
So we are done with the main class.
As far as I can see that, oh yes, you can see that there.
We have called this your exhibition type of exception handler.
So automatically get this job i dati or notyou exception back, which is important to our data class
and Ghatak to this import does so in case there is any kind of Input-Output exception, as we are like
inputting our values from our keyboard.
And according to that, the compiler is outputting like regarding function to that specific choice.
So everything is going to be handled with the help of input output function.
So any kind of exception would be handled with the help of Iowa exception packet of the Java Library.
So yes, this is going to be our mean class.
This will be like learning at the time of testing and running of the project.
So let us fast through some like really working things to the project.
So the second concern was to create an account class.
So icon, not Java, is going to be the name of the second class we are creating inside this account
that Java.
So we are having our account glass and everything about the like, we have mentioned it to her that
this account glass is going to handle this type of account.
The customer ratification process and operations regarding the balance of the nation will be mentioned
inside the account, plus only the exception handling for the invalid choices will be also handled inside
this account, plus soirées everything Mahender.
So our first step should be like declaring some global variables inside this account class.
So we will move forward with the help of this private access.
Specify it indeed, therefore customer number and for a pin number.
So initially we were being asked for our customer number and a pin number.
And both of them are going to be integers.
So I will be copying this and again for a pin number.
Yes.
Changing this customer's open and things are going to be working the same.
The third and the fourth to endanger, like double global variables, will be checking balance and savings
balance.
So private double.
And checking balance, so checking balance and saving balance in the similarly.
This issue should be in small.
And initially, the checking balance value will be set to zero, as initially we have no balance in
our account.
Once the user deposits the money, then only the balance will be updated, whether it be the savings
balance or the cheque balance.
So here we are, done with the declaration of all the global variables.
Now the next concern is to introduce the scanner, which is going to scan the choices imported by the
user and then our next scans and will be to get the answers to all the values of which we have declared.
And like the variables, customer number, pin number and they have declared everything as private in
the beginning.
So in order to access these variables are objects we can see by any other classes.
Then you have to use get them set, start in Java so that it can be accessed by any class without any
exception.
So yes, we will be seeing that in the next five.