Hello, everyone.
So I hope that you all have went through the introduction, but and the working of the applications
by pretty well.
And now you all must may wondering and the power of to the coding section of the application and must
be excited about start the programming part.
So let's begin this by opening the welcome page of our IEEE Visual Studio code, in which we will be
creating this application.
And once opening the welcome page, you will be seeing like interface like this on your screens, where
you will be provided some options like file, edit and so on.
So on the welcome page, you start to make the application.
We have to click on this File Explorer icon, and once you will select this explorer icon, some options
will appear on your screen.
Let me maximize this in order to make it more clear.
So we are having options like open folders, long repository and future projects.
So we are going to create a new job up in L.A. from scratch, so we will select this plan and our project
working from this this explorer option in the welcome page.
Once we will select create a project option, then we will be provided with some options.
And these are basically the toolkits which are used as a support to make any application in Java.
There are two gifts like MAVEN Springboard Plus Micro Profile and so on.
So in this, we are not going to use any soft Java support any tool kit, except like we are going to
make this application from scratch.
So we do not want to embed any of these supports in our applications.
So leaving these and making no tools, and we are going to work with source code directly without any
details, so we are not going to use them no tools in this application.
So clicking on normal tools and interface will open up files that are off your next stop will open,
basically.
And inside this, we have to select the location of the folder of the project we are going to make.
So I am choosing backstop as my project location.
You can choose any location of your choice.
But keep in mind that you have to remember that you have to choose their location.
So and later, if you wish to like open the application, it would be better if you like remember the
location to make things more time soon.
So I am choosing desktop as my project location, and I input the text in the past asking for input
as our project.
So we have to input our project the name of our choice, which is going to be the title of the folder,
which will be created inside which the main folders and files of the application will be consistent
so you can choose any name for the project.
I am going to name it as phone ordering system, so my choice of names suggest that I should name this
application as this one.
If I want to give you all that, we should the name of that application, our projects according to
the functioning of that.
So that data makes us clear in future that what actually this project was made for.
Like, suppose if I named this application as a whatever any of the X-Y-Z on any other like fancy name,
but that would not help me in any way in future.
So it was an infusion.
I have to sign that whether I have made the food ordering system application in my boss and I would
like, I am not remembering that I have created this.
So this will be like very complex inserting like a b c x y z or anything, any fancy name and so on.
Things becomes complex on naming applications, you know, fancy or anything like anonymous things,
so we shouldn't name our app.
Occasion in such a way that then becomes easier for us to find the gold like what is the significance
of this application?
So name your project projects wisely.
Choose appropriate name for your applications in order to make things more like it.
This was basically a tape I wanted to give you all of the but otherwise it's upon you.
If you remember things, then you can name any names.
So, yes, I have selected the name for my project food ordering system, and now I even hit enter to.
Land into our projects, folder soirées we have and turned our projects folder, and there are some
inbuilt folders in this project, so we have selected the key project option from the Explorer tab and
inside this project called US Food Ordering System, we have our darndest and not in the squad folders
and these folders are written myself.
I'm going to compile.
This has nothing to do with our project.
We are not going to use these two folders in our project in any views so that ignore these do we are
going to use this site see folder as a whole body of our project?
So suppose that is a body.
So inside the body may have body parts.
So this SIAC folder is the body which is going to contain the parts of our project and these parts,
I say I mean that files and folders, which will be consistent inside this ASIC folder and will be totally
responsible for testing and running of the application.
OK, so now switching to the prototype, which we made in our to so like understand the functionalities
and workings of this application, the first thing was to create a new project in which we have done
already.
Now in the next part, we will be creating a main class of this project.
Inside this are simple line.
As I said, this is the main body of our application.
So creating the main class, calling it label dart the job.
So we have to create finds and miles creating files.
We have to keep in mind that these file names should end with dark java.
So in order to make it as our program files.
So we have to enlarge our as a necessity while making files inside the folder on any object inside any
other folder.
So the main glass is called as labelled our java on head thing, and then we will be landing in the
label that is our logo file.
And we will be.
Yes.
So there is already a class main called App Dot Java, and this after Java then run once there will
be any exception in our app.
So this app Java will run in case of any runtime set arising in our application.
So basically, it has no functional use in our application.
It is just an inbuilt file inside this default and contains no functionality of our application.
So yes, we have created a label that Java file.
Now inside this, we've been declaring a class which will be called as a label.
So we have labelled jealous in a class name is going to be labeled.
This is a public class.
And inside it, we will be like declaring some of the variables or we can qualify as objects as there
is a class.
So in third class, we have objects, and inside this class we are like declaring the objects as public
static.
Final long.
So these are the optics which are going to be used in our application.
OK, so these are the objects required in this project in order to make the form complete for ordering
the food items, and these objects are from the single library.
So you have to import in order to make things working.
So we are importing everything one by one importing data.
I am already like this first this that we are going to like.
Use this Minion NWT frameworks extensively, so we are doing that now.
So we have imported all the objects here from Java Swing and Java Swing is the main circuit which is
responsible for making the frame of the application.
So inside this class, we are going to initialize the constructor called as labels as well.
So this public label constructor is going to contain the layout of the lake, how the interface will
look.
So a sad thing now, Tim NULL, as this is going to be in default state.
So we have set the layout now.
We are going to set the size of the frame and the size is going to be suppose.
The said size is going to be 600 by 400 are the height and weight of the application, and we have to
import something in order to make paint like we have not demonstrated the metric.
So we will see it sometime later in this class as well.
Firstly, let us set everything in order to make the frame ideal, like the water frame is going to
look as so location delayed if you.
Relative to.
None.
This is also going to be nuts and after this.
We are going to.
Said some more things.
OK, so before setting the size and layout of the frame.
Firstly, we should discuss the water, the objects we are going to use while making this frame on application,
we can say anyways, so we are the initializing along the water type for Virgin.
So we have a serial number for every menu item.
Similarly, we have like four levels.
We can see it here.
So we have labels for size, for how many glasses we want to order.
And similarly, for the report and beverage, we have ordered that dialog box will have also contains
labels.
So if you like, memorize it, you will get to know.
So this label is for all the labels inside the application.
Similarly, this combo box method, that type of string is responsible for this size, like the combo
box is basically that are what we call it.
It is not like options which you are pairing her as the Mali medium large.
You can see her small, medium large, and these are possible with the help of a combo box or the sizes
that are three sizes in whole.
Also, we have radio buttons for all the items in the menu.
We have already discussed in the introduction five that these radio buttons.
One two three four.
According to our choices, that how many radio buttons we are going to use in eastern Libya are like
declaring for radio buttons for juice, water and coffee.
Similarly, for Bathurst, we have buttons and order, so Button Group is to be declared before and
then after we are run, initializing the martins with the help of Britain and with the Northern.
Also for the state laws, we are declaring a next free.
But how many glasses of the specific item from the menu we want to order an amount of.
So this is that antigen which is going to like, contain the amount of this fight.
Next, you so this is going to take integer outputs input.
So we are going to save it does amount to with the help of this.
So we have declared all the objects associated with this application.
Now in the next five, we will be looking at adding some more stymie and force with separate beverages
as coffee bean, water use and add ons attached to it will be declared in size.
Those glasses only so everything will be attached inside the glasses, and we have to add functionalities
of each menu item within their glasses only.
So see you in the next five MC, all the other classes.