Well, our project is basically we are going to create a chat application.
So we already created three classes server client chat message server for the server establishment,
90 for the user side and chat messages for the handling on legitimate use.
So I immediately glasses or you can see three job offer this year.
So first, I'm building this.
Which is basically sort of what if I.
So as I told you in previous sessions, I did this and I created a constructor.
Am creating or start?
And each and everything.
Always remember these start and some run out.
Both are related to the.
Basically related to the what we consider trading concepts.
So is what I'm going to do is I'm going to build a function to stop a server.
I'm going to create a function to stop serving, and it's protected.
Protected void stop.
My pleasure only.
Then, you know, there is one information keep going is equal to wholesome telling here.
And creating a trap because all settlements should be and then you it.
Introduce a new dimension local post.
All.
And.
Wanting to lose.
Match exception.
He.
Kim wrote a book detailing.
So we handle this exhibition, and I created to stop this, then I need to create.
So do you remember why I created a project and because I'm going to use in saying this only I'm not
invoking injuring the client or I can use this as protected also.
So.
The specified is protected.
This May.
Even consume and consume or do we consume a function private?
Would.
Display.
Dream.
I'm bringing a message here.
But and you bang, so basically saying time is equal to is death dot format.
And so this what I'm going to do is I'm going to specify this new.
Did.
As it is.
Plus.
This this.
Even even with this special edition.
So we are a great addition and wouldn't lose anything, but just not.
Not println.
What I do, I'm going to bring it in.
So now I am going to create a synchronized shooting.
Or you can say.
Who brought the cost?
Message.
Two on.
Of claims, this private, synchronized world wide shouldn't be synchronized, I will tell you.
Bullion.
Broadcast.
Because I'm going to handle it in a trade.
So it should be synchronized on this show, I created synchronized stream.
Already created, imagine for him creating your message.
Now, I understand this very important and timestamp.
Bring.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to copy this because I'm going to use this again.
For broadcasting the message.
That's it.
And.
What I'm going to do is.
I'm going to check in private or not check, because I'm going to create a constraint which can be like
you can send message private.
There is see to see claim, to learn to basically.
So what I'm going to do is for such purpose, I'm going to split the message.
I will tell you what is the significance of this, and I will split this message in this.
Know what I'm going to do is.
If character is this what is you do, this is basically edited if you put something like.
And John, are you going to say its it's John?
For the region, then space message.
Private message.
So I'm going to do this, so it will help me.
Make that and limit is three way.
I'm raising the limit is trees, as you can see, one two three four.
So that it should not be exceeded.
So I'm using this and.
Now, let me use some.
OK, so I will use your.
OK, I will tell you, what is this, all things?
So if private mission sink mentioned username money using this, so it will go to that particular point.
And we knew winning was our order to find dimension and basically I'm kicking in reverse to check your
username.
Well, look.
And I will tell you what to look.
Get username in each and every year because I haven't created any client, so I will create that and
I will tell you, what is this basically?
So this is all about this.
But what if messages and not from this?
Let me do one thing here.
If the message is not from what I'm going to do is I'm going to listen to.
I already created this, but I will tell you.
So.
OK.
We're doing it, OK, so all about how we can do this.
Vitamin.
So if this is true, I'm going to mention this.
What if?
If I'm printing else something else, basically?
It should be given some more.
Things so what I'm going to do is if messages broadcast message, it should be printing something now.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to use this part.
You basically inspire you if it is not what I wanted you to be broadcast, so it will be directly put
out to the client and it will go to the right and I will tell you what it is.
You didn't send the client on me, so I will tell you what is the significance of this?
So this is all about how we can create this.
Now I'm going to create one logo dimetrodon.
So you're.
You create one lovely thing.
So let me go with the local thing one, so.
Well, this is the end of private and everything, OK, now.
OK.
So let me explain all these things.
So we already created this mentality, if you know that what is the starting news, what the starting
of the server?
Sort of starting.
Then this is the constructor, basically, as I told you.
Then this is all about sort of starting why?
Because I'm using some before libraries here and we'll keep going.
No, I'm doing this and printing stops and each any looting.
And then I created protected way to stop this server.
Because while I'm doing this, keep going, it's false, it will stop this event.
Now this is displayed console message and to broadcast message all, I'm going with this new format
and if and everything, if the message is private, I'm splitting this.
What it will do it, will you check something and each and everything year first, then what you do,
we will do measures should be, you know, blessed with basically that length and it will time plus
measure.
It will print William from musical defaults because I'm stopping that part and I'm reversing out I can,
looping the part in reverse to check that gland granted and using it username.
And I'm sending to that particular username only from its phone, deliver the message and basically
break the loop.
If fund is not equal to be basically generally not user fund, it should be written false or involved
is basically nothing but error messages, a broadcast message not with any underage audience.
It is going to know in this.
And what are it will do?
We will look in reverse order to remove the client also because it is disconnected if it's disconnected.
It should be removed from the client.
So I'm removing to the client and Glenn traditional thing at least, which is to pull the blankets on
each and everything.
Then I created one little augmentative that string disconnected on each and everything.
And similarly, I can use this remove that as you can see this remove it is basically system defaulting.
And we can see for eel, which is basically at, we can put removing it and had broadcast demonstration.
It is not available.
That is basically going to this.
Room model, you can see this is all about how we can do this.
After this, what is the remaining thing is?
All I need to create a server and to run a chat application on the server side.
And you to mention some things.
What I'm going to do is I'm creating your and basically public static void main.
Then what I'm going to do is here, I need to mention some.
He's one of the things I'm going to mention is word no.
Then switch gears for Argument Linton each and everything, so I will mention him or no?
Is equal to 5000, I mentioned in photos, and you can check your port number, then switch gears and
each and everything I'm going to mention.
Here.
So let me use this first.
So what is doing this?
It is going to pass that, in turn, this is the exception in really no doubt whatsoever, but nobody
in our phone dear basically will, but it gets zero.
Is basically is that usage our server because it is not using and creates sort of what object to start
this ability to start that object is server is basically this.
So we have we are done with this part, but we are remaining something here, which is basically no
OK, which is this part again?
OK, probably started, and this is part and this part did not work at all.
And did it instead presume it should be?
OK.
So we created this part and now what is remaining thinks we need to create one blanket then, which
is basically we need to create one plus for that purpose.
And we already did this.
But now the client reading or letting said remaining here, which is basically very important and we
are going to create this and now we can stop this, basically, which is basically public class and
each and everything as you can see our client through this machine.
Now I'm going to create one client $3 for you.
OK, if I'm reviewing this.
As you can see, nothing is.
This thing it is all about, and we know it is, which is basically not undeclared, declared already.
No, I'm going to declare that part.
So this is how you can do this part or you can do this part basically.
This is basically said we're saying I'm creating when at least in four unique graded format or no keep
going format, I'm using your local.
Also, no need to mention each and everything else you're going to see.
I'm using local only.
You can change the board.
No to this.
So what I did this is I'm created vision to start this over, basically, because all these things are
mentioned here only.
So once you do started, all things are embedded in this only.
So what I'm going to do now is I will do I will create one planter class with some metals like good
use of the name, great message, then all the things like stopping each and everything user name on
something new to engine.
So I will go with that part and in the later part, I will tell you it's very cold as ice as you can
see.
I already done our own design, but it will help me to run all the processes on the server side, and
the client program will be very easy in this part.
So in the next part, we are going to see some plan things also in chat message things also including
I'm going to create $3 here.
And before that, I will explain the trading partners.