If you carefully go to this, my first tutorial, I told you how we created Mary Gland, so Mary Clark
is just going to the data.
And if you are, this is a very important part for locating the data.
It's very small code, as you can see, and I'm using the most to get the method.
As you can see, these are the overrating methods and you can check here in the in full annotations,
so you can check here.
So this is related to mail client and why I created two methods here.
Do is just going to create a connection and getting the data.
It's my independent Syrian and the post is to handle everything and request and response.
So now what I'm going to do, I'm going to tell you what is the same to be Baqir so you can see this.
So it's basically symbolic, meaning transfer protocols in the world of internet.
If you have seen there are a lot of many protocols for chatting, then then normal web surfing.
So if you are looking on, you are looking for advantage tips.
So these are also protocol explained who we are providing information on the network.
So these are related to the networking protocols.
But let me go deep into this little bit.
So what is the protocol here?
Just like a standard?
If you have seen there are a lot of applications only available on the internet like nowadays, we can
call to an internet also, which is basically we are used through internet protocol rules and there
is voice also.
But for that purpose, you cannot use one single stream for that.
So to maintain, do what we can see the logic behind this, then maintain the ethics of internet enabled,
getting rid of all sort of media.
So first of all, it's nothing more than a set of rules than a set of layers that are here that defines
everything automated and all the protocols.
So I'm not going to go into the telling part of this and when our context also with project context.
So every email application available on the internet, you just simply so seem to be so what's available
on the internet also may simply be sort of what is basically just for me, simple of one.
So these are sort of moves which is providing some deep function over the internet.
So Jimmy, we are going we can use for that purpose.
We challenged some submitted reports and they seem to be addressed.
Similarly, you can use any other is simply booting three services also available.
You can use that.
So it's a program used to sending a message from one computer user visiting to another artist.
So if you know the email address are specified, you can go do that part also.
But remember why so many e-mail?
It's not like girls who need 20 minutes of useful and other service.
You can send email from Gmail service to Yahoo Mail also, or you can do for Outlook email to give me
a lot so you can send from anywhere.
Similarly, for that purpose, we need one email or some TV.
So it provides email exchange between users from similar or different computers, which also supports.
So sometimes again, you can send your own mail, so there's nothing more complicated in that part.
So you can send single message, you can send text the latest video graphics it I'm considering when
you text only because we are going to hear definition for video, voice and graphics.
Also, we need to handle that file using everything, so it's moving to more complex part for that purpose.
So instead of this, I'm mostly focused on text because we can get streams easy in Java.
It can also message on the outside of the internet.
So if not, continue here to internet as well land or local area.
And it could be instead of putting on nobody, then you can check other people also.
So it is just short multimedia user, a user to be able to use mailing systems.
So use it.
A user mailing system empty is just a mail blank.
It will go to the internet.
These mail gateway.
It will use and deliver another system.
So how this some TV works actually delivered?
So this is all the things it needs, or we do in the rectangular part out of this interview.
So you can see.
So it simply works on the host and automatically host is basically had this anything, it's going to
work.
So what is our application is going to work here is very simple.
It just gives your web view over what is going to publish our view about a job program and what is going
to do is it is going to.
Would that just be just also it really asks for that extension, so let me do one thing, you can put
this as this also this is also correct.
You're.
It is going to go through this and it is going to do as you.
So now let me tell you this, what is this so you cannot see like this onslaught?
It is going to sort of look at the experience.
This job problem is going to be solved, which is going to find the sendmail to given or you can use.
Authentication fails also required their username and password to gain in the S&amp;P and using IT service.
So this isn't about it, simply behoove, you are going to perform here.
So if you understood this latest move with our e-mail application part.
So we already created this sign integrated e-mail message.
So let me copy this to.
Let me go, please.
You know, music and what I mean is that email or mail package and we to create new glass.
So you can see your new getting grade window.
I already opened this part, let me paste this in an invitation.
Plus, it entered the default class will create for you, so you can.
So we created this, but we haven't mentioned anything yet.
So as you can?
OK.
As soon as you create this, it is announced for you, but we have a greater say to these things out
here.
So let me go with this.
So more time it is here.
But I would say I needed some packages.
Also, I needed, so I needed more things here.
So.
Let me add one here.
One by one, look at this private screening group.
It's my first requirement to message.
And let me be wanting to supplement and let me one too small because hear the case so.
Then I have what I need, it is for my address, also
from Qantas.
So I'm going to mention your former list, but.
Oh, Link, for handling any purpose, I need this from you.
I'm going to put this with you on.
So why I mentioned earlier, if I'm not mentioning it, will assume it's not ready for you.
So there may be some error cases or anything you're going to do, then address, mix, address, you
can add here, Oh, I'm going to add it so.
So you see, and we had this.
So let them do it for us.
I'm not.
Focusing on this point because the carbon copy in the U.S., let me complete control is just for the
opening of Berlin.
I mean, you can lose that childhood.
So all these four string because these are just all important things for message and everything here,
even for these purpose.
I need all the consider, which is basically.
Subject.
And message again, it's private string subject is important.
And similarly for.
Message.
So now we are done with this.
So but now we need to check whether the five messages estimate if you are putting a statement or text,
if you're using HDMI 2.0 to will be, as you know.
So I need to do this.
So let me put up here.
To me, slash each DML will hey.
So for that purpose, I need to specify who treated this year.
So let me just copy these things, but I don't want to focus on this.
OK, so we are to do this, but we are remaining with some.
So let me to tell you, I'm I'm using strategies because these are the statistics here, even if given
in Michigan.
So these are very important to see it.
So let me add a methods here.
It is basically steam strength, so it's it magic in that it's.
So.
You can take me there at least.
OK, now they're are.
So let me tell you how all the things that I did hear all the noise and they get confused here.
So let me tell you who I do some things.
These two are unable to console.
Let me just.
And what they need, so.
Well, I don't want to focus on getting sick when it looks, what are you going to do in India, Julia
Priest or concert or your shortcut key on your keyboard?
For me, it's all in, so you will get general operating.
You're going to get through text.
Press control and choose for these things.
And it does case.
And therefore, these days, I'll put in all these these things to render.
You got all the things, you know, what are you going to do?
You're going to change this according to your papers.
And what is your going to use change you?
So these are the gates you see from interviews you can.
So you can change it, according to your part.
It's not compulsory, but if you want to change, you can change it.
You're.
So we had mentioned this, but we are remaining with said message I.
Said message and everything good message to both of them.
OK, e-mail utilities, meaning liquid a liquid is included in that thing in later part.
So let us go to this or she is going to be here basically evil message.
So if you look at this FAQ, this is sex objects and this is going to work here.
But what is going to work?
So you're like, get get used for getting that, who is putting in this to similarly get from this and
from who Buddhist this to see to get sick, sexy similarly.
So these are some important I'm quoting here and what?
I don't want to hear this again and again, so I would will take care of me and I put that back for
me instead of typing it again and again.
So now we are done with this.
But so.
This is the E.M. is it's all what is going on behind it is her new email message is going to handle
our data as this is made, planned mainland is going to face data.
Email message is going to handle the headline.
It's going to create some lawmakers who handle it later as our email application is going to use here
so I can pay for the name as meal service.
Or let me check here.
What is it?
My name is this female utility, so email utilities going to mercury sending service for my application.
So for a lot of videos, what I'm going to create, I'm going to create email.
So once email utility, then we can perform email action.
How do we can say we can send the information after that?
But I'm going to handle some e-mails.
So handling emails like phishing emails is quite a tough job in Java because sometimes there may be
media files or anything.
So for that purpose, we need to file handling everything with her, but sending messages very easy.
And it's a very helpful way of saying because for the faking the data, it's very easy or an easy job,
but via sending data.
Maybe Hank, she can get us or anything.
So we will check that and we are going.
We will create one email class which is going to have some send email function.
So just to handle on what to do, and that's it.
We are going to perform here.
Thank you.
Hope you understand this.