Now, so that we have covered everything up to the download button and the text, see whether you are
al is going to be like Princeton and then on clicking the add download button event is going to be performed
that the download is to be started after that thing now in the next part.
We are going to set up their download stable.
OK, so this table is going to be set up with the help of this part of the goal.
And this part is going to create a new table model with the help of the datable component of string
library as well.
And this table is going to like select like action list that is attached to that table also.
And whenever we are going to, like, select any event from the table, then our event is going to be
changed.
Like, suppose our download is started and like this.
So like this, suppose this is going to be after like this to the law and this is like continuously
changing.
So the action is to be listened continuously and then downloaded.
The progress bar is increasing and everything is like in motion all the time.
Not in this, but in this part, everything is in motion.
So the table is set to event.
Values are getting change.
So the argument is don't list selection event.
So we have like this action performing at the time, so that function is going to be considered for
this.
And similarly, for all of them now after this, like, we can select only one at a time to play, pause,
resume or to perform any other actions we can order like a pause do often those at the same time.
So we are going to use this single selection method of the list selection model for doing so.
So, yeah, so only one rule is to be selected at the time.
Now we are done with the the selection part of the table introduction.
But now the progress render.
So the progress bar is increasing continuously from zero to 100.
And this renderer is also saying so that zero and hundreds are going to be the starting and ending five
of the progression in the next bunch.
We have like a certain string painted through like by default, the if that rule is selected.
So the progress render is by default set to blow back down.
You can see it here that it is showing a blue background thing.
And so if the download is here, then it is that background.
Now, if it is completed 200 percent that complete the block, this progress render that is converted
to blue background highlight.
After this, we are setting a high standard for the table and the provenance, but also so that the
progress world do not exceed the table column.
So in order to do so, we are using preferred size in order to like, fix that progress bar within the
column, not to like, exceed outside of a column.
So this is doing that now we have to set up their download plan.
So what actually, the download final is?
This complete thing is the download panel, and this download panel is going to be like, contain a
title.
So that title is containing the word downloads.
And inside this, we are setting our layout and the size further download the label hence.
You can see this bold download is updating with the help of this.
So, yes, we have certain that tighter border and border layout center.
So this is going to be the like layout and position of the text according to the table size.
So it is in the middle of the above line and the below line we have above and below border for this
text now, but panel.
So this buttons panel is also a very important part in this.
We have this button panel.
Once a specific door is selected, then only the button panel is going to be highlighted and also the
player is disabled in the beginning.
Once we have like selected arrow and.
And certainly then only we can clearly or otherwise, if that are not done, then we can simply clear
it.
But if they're downloading is a progress status, so we cannot clearly directly, we have to first cancel
the download, then only we can clearly.
OK, so looking up to this new law bottom column, this contains four buttons for it, as you can see
and clear.
So what actions are attached to those boxes?
So we have used like all the components of the celebrity.
So in this, we are also we're going to do so.
So this pause button is going to call action for us.
We are going to create functions for every button in the action event thing we are going to create later.
So action last night is going to be attached to our last download manager.
Firstly, let us like understand what is happening inside this panel.
So initially, we are like setting everything inside up and then only we are going down actions.
So yes, this is for the pause button.
It is going to create actions of one function with event as an argument and action is going to be boss.
Similarly for Zoom and for cancer care.
So everything is going to be written inside the G button component as all four of them are like pins
and nothing else.
So I guess after looking at the addition of these buttons to the panel now after this, we are like
setting this clear button to disable it in the beginning by this one.
So by default, this certain number, each side of the argument is Boolean.
We have set this clear button as follows and buttons panel, and we have added in the clear button to
the panel.
Now, similarly, we have added all the buttons to the panel and this is for like and fairness to the
display.
So we have four buttons, so we are adding all the four buttons to the theme after this for the exhibit
program, we have created this action exhibit above here.
We have done it in the first part, I think.
Yes.
So this is for the closing window event.
We are going to perform in order to escape the application window.
So yes, we have created this exhibitor program function, which is going to call like system exhibit
and it is going to say its donuts null in order to escape from that application.
Also, we have added all the panels to the display now after this.
We have covered this exit program program by now to add new down.
What is this?
So this is the addition of a unique role.
One snake based on what else in the text field and hit that download button.
So this part is going to be responsible for adding unique roles for every download.
Like in order to attach it to the table, we are like making.
So this table so far this fine every row is going to be added for a specific download.
You are then modifying the order.
So this modified you are is a component of that string library as that which verifies that whether this,
you are told, is like a valid one or not.
So by default, that this is said like not the null.
So we have to like based your order in order to add it to the download button.
So after this on clicking the add download button and new download is going to be either that or like
this.
So we have pasted the order now.
It is not equal to null, then only we can click this and download and then this is added to the arrow
and the download starts.
So our text field, said Texel.
So this text field is reacting to this action and in order to like, make things like, yes, this action
on is a we have added this are the banner.
So the banner now after this, we are attaching like the action is null for that, our panel, which
we are doing here.
So initially, the text field is empty.
Once it pays to know you are there, then it is going to start their download and to the frame also.
So is the suppose.
If you analyse north of Ireland, then what is going to happen?
So it is going to display that invalid, invalid download.
You are.
So suppose that you miss think in the best like pasted are wrong.
You are in and then this ah, download button.
Then this is going to like, show out there that you have pasted it wrong.
You are to try pasting another one and then start laying down the new download process.
So yes, you should import their download you very carefully.
In order to make us successful, download.
So this is the new download, but now for the verification of for the other, like we have covered in
the introduction part that wants to be base like input.
Are you are and ED was displayed.
So that is going to reject her that whether the link is not broken or that link is like error free,
then only the download is too restrictive.
So it is going to check whether the link is starting with as TTP and then all that text like in fibrates
inside I you are is in lowercase.
And also we can like start things with SDP on a stick of this.
What are the protocols?
Valid protocols?
Just this s.
The notes are secured and this without us is simply hypertext transfer protocol.
So yes, we are like a modified to the you are at least very valid are not now.
Format of the URL is going to be checked and using and try and get the exception.
Handling return you are in is not null.
Then ratified you are in is to be added with the new you are in.
And the argument also say so.
But as if like there is any exception, they all is not valid, then things is going to be like stop
and it is going to really turn on.
So make sure that you are in specify the phone so like you are and should contain a file like you can
paste any lame, which is not containing anything.
So we have to like check that whether this link has a file attached to it or not.
So yes, this is going to check whether the user is verified in all of these are not like modifying
the download other format of the UI and specifies the file whether they want to specify the file or
not.
And then after all this, we are going to return the verified you on.
So this is the total process of modifying the unknown, whether it is valid or not.
Now after this, if suppose everything is modified, either download has started successfully now.
After this supposedly select specific you are it specific is selected in order to perform any part.
So this part is for that.
We have to like check the back over there.
The selection is that to be made is not a null, then only we can perform.
That got us so if not glaring.
So this if statement signifies that we have to add a clearing like suppose this download is not cleared,
it is already present, then only we can add like receive notifications from it, like whether it is
downloading that that is, then error or the download has completed.
So these are the specific notifications we are supposed to receive now.
Pause or assume cancel on clear functionality.
That added, here we have created a POS function similarly for the resume and for cancer, and clearly
so these three are like working in a similar way.
But the difference that I had in the clear button in the by default, the cladding was set two floors
above.
We have discussed it.
So for clearing, we have to set the Boolean clearing object total rule.
Then we have to like enable that clear button.
Once that guns are like.
Once the download is selected and it is cancelled, then only this buttons becomes enabled.
And yes, so we are going to like certain clear that's the specific selection.
A specific selected rule is only going to be cleared, not all the rules.
So yes, we can clear one brew at a time, not multiple roles at.
So once they're selected, row is cleared.
Then again, the clearing boolean object is set to force and everything is like back to normal.
Selected download is again sectional now, in order to clear something else, we have to again select
and one.
Then this null will set to like a specific item and then we can perform all the actions pause, resume,
play around, cancel everything.