So in previous scenes, I created one JPA with model, so I will tell you, in short, how we are going
to perform better in the advantages of hybrid.
Let me explain.
First, you see the open source and lightweight.
Anyone can perform different actions over hibernation by a range of hibernate glasses, and everything's
already created with the different databases because each database provides different kind of utilities.
So for that purpose, for each database, different hibernation already created, then fast performance.
Its performance is fast because it's force level katchi is it enabled by default.
So if you know the coaching level, get GS basically storing the local some data inside the variables.
So it's not always switching from the proper database.
It's sometimes switching from the Kashi files on the database.
Independent query because HQ will hibernate, query language use object oriented with a general physical,
which I already created that hibernate and each by which grid language.
Basically, it's not a school, it's a hybrid integrating language.
So it's some kind of object oriented language.
So I created one objects and I can use it later, but also so that's about how we are going to perform
here.
So let us see it.
What are the things we are going to create and everything?
So if you close, look, I created one routines, two classes, one is in play service, Interface says,
putting that in the least part and putting and creating some.
You can catch it here.
I'm creating here to get you.
Then in the employee, I created one GPA to perform the database actions and everything.
Now, in the service part only, I'm going to create one class.
So if you know how we can create class, then it's very easy.
And.
Let me mention that class name is emblazoned with and B, because it's important, so I mentioned those
in place and we say this then.
In this employment.
Employs service, so let me use this implementation part.
So you're just going to use that part.
Now let us know how it's going to work and everything.
So.
Let me mention some annotations and everything here, oh, so.
And Bob Jordan, don't you to stand up to the important and involved, what did you don't bring framework
on then?
I needed different things here, but OK, which means I needed means music means.
And I tree inside this factory
and patients.
Not start.
OK, so this is very important for.
As soon as we are developing it, are doing to clean planes and played some libraries for diesel.
I'm not going to work here then.
Let me mention this as a service.
So, OK, it would automatically deploy any service, so it is the service service is basically for
the deploying and up and then or toward an intervention afterwards, basically for generating that part
of the wildly.
And in the wired part, I need to create one repository.
Private employer repository taking.
But before the day, the employer depository let us create one repository last year, so keep it as
this and let us create one more package inside this mansion as the repository.
Because we haven't created any repository, so let me create one package.
Repository and inside this repository, I'm going to create one another plus employ repository, so
it will help me to create one employee repository here.
So just basically JPA, we're going to provide me some extending part.
So while developing this, you can closely this very easy part in creating a new repository, so you
minimize this and.
OK, so let's see.
And in this, what I'm going to mention is
the repository, so it will default.
If you use this, then I need to extend it to some more part of your repository.
So exchange GP.
Repository, as you can see, is in my repository and to three things I need to mention here, it is
basically all.
Its name.
Let me mention the name as employee, no decision of employee.
Long.
And OK.
But again.
So if you use the meaning here, OK?
There is a good.
Let me import one thing, you know.
I mean, with me so.
Well, the team.
OK, OK.
So I need to implement methods on these things.
So, OK, that's it.
In inflatable therapy, so I will create that method scene controller part, which is basically the
controlling part in later.
So let me mention one controller here.
Also, because I haven't created one controlling part which is going to handle the mapping part and
everything later.
So I will create that part in later.
But.
Let us assume we need to implement teams you.
In the morning.
And.
Okay.
So I'm implementing this and.
I'm accessing everything you.
You said 80 percent.
Yes.
So let us in this part.
She's basically employee service.
And they can create one of the waiting.
Altering the.
So it will import Douglas.
So it will automatically implement this, but I don't going to implement every part here in services,
so I'm going to create my own methods here.
Basically.
For that purpose.
Let me use that team.
OK.
So what I'm going to do is I'm accessing my own methods here.
So I advice in import class.
Then mentally mentalism.
Then Beijing will impose.
Then.
And what we do here, three things here.
Which is basically the repository, all.
OK, because I mentioned as a class or accessing as class or union to create interface.
So that's the problem I created to mention as it interface to.
Remove these things and then.
OK.
No.
And.
You need to be reviewed again and again, because sometimes it gives the data.
And what is irrelevant here we should be.
OK.
Well.
Why employs me?
OK, I need to import the glass just anything for the class, and I need to learn from museums or.
So that's when I've done this or it'll get removed.
And.
Class is not working, so let me mention what I created, just I just debug it.
One of the things I mentioned is already it's so related to speeding, so otherwise it is just I created
an employee repository as an interface to create a repository, as you can see a repository to store
the cashier for you so you can see inside this employee.
What I'm going to do, I'm going to create one two three methods.
So first is or going to create and implement the private repository.
Then in this, it's overwriting this list employee and it's getting it from the employee.
So this at least part.
I mentioned the Gate SEAL Gate employed, delete anything there, so I'm not creating different methods
here.
First is overriding this overriding is to find all methods to get all employees safe, all in place
to save all these employees and this employee, as is my object.
Then in the override part, I created an employee with two overriding methods and.
It's a very simple thing I created in the get employed by Ali with this employee as method, a bit different
things.
And now in the overriding pain, these things, I'm accessing this sort of material.
And so it is very easy in spring, you can actually see the matter in the spring.
It's already implemented this and you can use this part as a pages.
So now we are set with this, but we haven't created any mapping part.
So.
For mapping purposes, you need to create or do three things.
First is mapping, mapping, using just basic water mapping of what if this became the front end?
So I need to create one controller part.
So in the later part, I'm going to create one controller.
So it's very easy just to package and you need to mention controller you.
So I am going to create one package here, I created one package.
I'm going to use it.
And in the Resources tab, I'm going to mention the template basically in this new millennium, written
in little part to create the printing.
So hope you understand.
Thank you.