In previous material, I told you, we need to create one database and we need to create some methods
to improve that data in the database.
So on screen, you can see this is our database team.
So I'm using user, another user with this is my password.
Anything, you can change this.
OK, it's on your device.
Let me close this.
So these are day school goodies, and we are going to create three tables here, which is basically
the first e-book.
Second is e-library and for four library limited.
I'm putting the constraint here.
Always e-book.
We gave it the name primary call number.
And what is basically call number for that purpose, which is basically it should be a primary key.
I am enabling that call number should be unique.
So name can be common.
Publishers can be a common quantity, can become an issue of numbers until we can meet common but column,
but it should meet unique similarly ID of Élaborer and should be unique.
I'm mentioning that email can be same because it's universally thing.
Want part of that and you should book which is call number, which should be not unless you don't really
not know the student name also.
I'm mentioning that and the dancer doesn't mention all the things.
So these are all about how you can create that villain database.
So let's see how we are going to create this.
So I already told you you need to create a new library in form and why it's going to be needed because
in the long run, I haven't mention all the things here.
So it brings me error also.
And like library in four months or missing there, so I created our library and for monsoon.
And Library in form, as you can see here in this part and in the images, there are images and all
the things that are mentioned.
So let us inside the view library.
We need to create a library and be.
But before that, there do we need to mention some or part also.
Did part, I'm going to tell you.
Because we need to mention their database, so I'm creating BP, which is basically a database DB with
our Java, including the finish.
So I'm creating your when?
What you can see.
No, simple.
I'm reading.
I'm just creating a package.
And let me mention, the package is over the simple.
As simple as that, I created him, so this is my soul, and this is all the things I mentioned.
So let me also.
Stream.
User is equal to.
Deb, as I told you.
And another user is doing.
Password is equal to.
And one good thing, so this is my username and password.
If you don't, how you be your default password.
But in my case, I'm using another user name.
And one, two, three.
As I mentioned in the notepad also, I'm creating this, I already created this part and I created a
good collection of and and Anthony Kiedis.
So I will put your database.
Connection method.
So now we're done with this in the.
We created this now India, we need to create law library.
India is basically a library and all we can say library in part adding and creating.
So let me create one, so let with the same name in India.
So I'm adding the information and I'm building this part, but I'm not deleting the package because
I need to mention it again and again.
I don't want to do that.
Well, as you can close this part, I mean, well, it's no longer required.
So let us create labor in the but.
So.
As you can imagine, you can delete this for the first.
And.
So now we're done with this book in the library, and we we need to mention that part also like importing
the this part.
So let me form this first, and we haven't mentioned this library and been first, so we need to mention
that part also.
So, no, I'm done with this.
So let me explain this, what is this?
So it contains all mentions here.
I mean, building libraries for first time, I'm adding some class, so it will be for sale in the library
and be without taking the name from this and insert into the library.
As you know, the name, email, password, movie, everything.
Then find a mate of 11 in Sydney and all the things mobile where I so.
Nothing but and mentioning your status and everything.
Oh, then this is again used for putting in a really stupid.
All the things you buy it.
You can view by ideals.
You can delete, then you can authenticate, authenticate or no authentication because.
I'm creating here and it is basically select email and password.
So for the email, we need to mention this, but before that in, we need to create liability and been
also.
So let me go with this and it's only been I'm going to create new solid.
Librarian been.
And then with this.
So.
Let me delete this part, because it's no longer required, I told you.
And let me.
I already created this part, Liberian bin, so let me use that part.
So let me tell you what it is, basically it is taking this, it is putting in another part laboratory
and been similarly in the laboratory and been basically constructed all those things and it is creating
when we're building them on some data illicitly get name, shift name.
If you know what is doing this, it is thus fitting the data and it's putting into this.
So as you can see, being slavery and then everything is done, but what is remaining is basically you.
So while this view is showing the area, as you can see.
Instead, this view is this, and now you can see these results.
So you need to see everything.
And we are done with all dimensions here.
Basically, you, LeBron and everything, but before we need to deploy some another solid fossil.
So let me explain what this deal is doing here is basically what are the purpose proposing this?
But what is inside this building is basically just taking that data and it's putting in another variable.
So why this is required?
If you are going to do this, you will understand it takes too much time to process some parts as this
is, I'm doing in some part it takes.
As for the library and method only, I created that much part.
So it is.
It should be like some different things your own.
So.
So if you are, well, managing your school bag, considering you are managing your school or college,
make you put in our database that will automatically you to your timetable, you choose your timetable
or you took your timetable.
You seem to be ready to do this.
Then you are putting the first known book on your book or anything.
Similarly, what I am doing here, I'm creating three packages you it for the controlling part, bill
is basically for logging and all the methods it considering, but it also contains one b b, which is
basically the connection and b meaning basically what is the been creating being is for creating all
the constructors.
These are the constructors basically.
And from the Superdome, I I'm mentioning the super.
And if you know the super keyword and this keywords, so I'm mentioning this a to do this early and
because it's private, so it gives me some security purpose inside the database.
Otherwise, anyone can check that part and anyone can use that right.
So and all these methods get it.
What it is?
Get ideas for Glenn, which stands for so sole purpose.
Great name again for the plan for positioning image for the server purpose, getting all the things
that are similar.
So why I'm creating two different methods here again and again.
Similarly, I'm going to create four admin part of.
Creating these methods also is very helpful.
Again, this is public.
If it's a public, but all the variables are private, so no one can change this public and all the
things here.
So excuse me, 100 percent abstraction you can see here and I'm opening up again and again using this
keyword keyword.
So this very simple thing I can do if you I don't know if you don't want to create such methods, if
you don't want to create but ideal condition that you can create this and it's very easy if you don't
want to create, you are not to mention instead of you, LeBron, you said, and this is very tremendous
because you, LeBron, you can create only to view LeBron thing only.
So as you can see, this will be nice and everything you can create.
So.
The very simple reason being, Bill is basically this is so it will create one metal as a toll booth
and everything.
So as you can see these 11 being and we knew it would lead.
So this is a very simple thing I can do with this.
If they change to the beans, as we can see, this will be the edit.
So for the library and been very helpful for me.
And if you know this part, it is the once for loop or follow each loop you can see.
As for Lebanon Bean and if you notice Liberian Bean.
And so it's all the things here, but like LeBron Deal, as you can see, at least if you want to invoke
or use that as inside of Java, you have to go with two methods for normal for loop or normal way loop.
But you can use for each loop in any library, at least any advance on secondary data to make any strings.
Least at least said all things hashing.
Hash it, you then use for each loop.
So for each library in this Part B, is that what we can instantly liable for this list, this list,
what it will do, it will get into and print everything inserted.
I will remember and I'm mentioning here that bulletin here, and I need to engineer a library in form
on so a little library in form.
So we need to mention what is a librarian from here also, and it should be in select.
So I need to mention again here.
So let's not.
Because it's so late only and delayed labor unions again, so late, but let me when duty will copy
this because naming is very important.
Otherwise, it will give some error again and again.
So if you want to delete it, will this part?
So always you have to mention this.
And you can say I mentioned all the things here.
And now we are done with this.
If you want to add here.
You can and this part.
So now we are done with it in.
Let me tell you one more in like bill part, which is basically booby.
So I'm going to create it later, but I'm going to use this part because it is very helpful to me.
First thing, it's very helpful for me.
Second thing.
I'm mentioning all the beings here, so.
Currently, it is no longer required for us because we haven't created such matters for that purpose.
But.
Filling in in advance is very helpful.
While deploying all the parts.
So let me help you.
Well, I already created this good.
I'm just explaining you said this little movie.
Similarly, I'm going to create one issue moving, or you can say, issue moving part or the issue in
that.
With some this method in a school.
So I'm just mentioning this because I don't want to focus on it later part because it's just being part
or you can see me through the part.
So now we are done with this, so I would have been parties done, as I told you, we give you directly
means your library an issue, and so now we are done with that connection, but also so in the next
weeks, I'm going to create some gaming and I'm going to add some or more will be part of that purpose
and so that we are now focusing on the solid part later.
So in the next two days, I'm going to tell you how we can create the solid part and everything.
So in this shooter I just created beginning, if you will, we are going to use it later, that purpose.
But I already created this.
So nothing but all the student IDs always create some tables idea before deploying all the produce because
we are going to use this also inside the library you need to add or technology TV celebrity.
Otherwise, it will show me the error again, as I told you.
So let me add that Oracle Library also here, which is basically what I call database GBC Dialer.
So as you can see, these added incentives.
So now our duty vehicles are connected and everything is done, so Pennington dibs on everything, you
know.
So in the next two days, I'm going to create some looks inside the admin part and you back, we are
done with the part and we need to create some Alonso.
So let us see how we can create that instrument in the next parts.