So in previous scenes saw I created two simple logic things, you're basically if you win, win a game
and if you lose your game, I believe that if you are an aborted please post was that part.
And now after this, I need to mention basically keystroke things.
Yeah, which is very simple, which is I'm going to create some key events.
Let me mention as public or public worried again, because I'm not returning anything.
Let me mention as key press events, which is a key press.
With.
Key event.
OK, unique evening.
So in previous cases.
We're doing it divides United.
OK, now the reason one is just floating.
OK.
So in previous things, as you can see, I created the one thing which is basically public void pink,
meaning that part the graphics for us.
Now I need to mention key, even for the main mechanism of battle moving playable unanimity so it will
hold all the.
Key mechanisms here.
First condition, if.
You're not guilty.
You can check here, get equal to each, give me some key equals, which is basically right to left
or something like that.
Oh, I saw these things and again, event I need to mention here he.
Even.
And you lost, you're going to take here every key location key, so know what I need to mention is
basically giving you not one to three I need to mention.
We care about all these law abiding people and you can check your everything.
No.
I will take this because it will be one for each event.
Not, Vicki.
And once I am giving this right, you've been here, right?
So it is not right parenthesis or anything, if I press right, it should be moving to the right.
So what I need to mention is just basically moving that burden on a player if this is done.
No, I need to mention concern to that panel and it not moving to the highest part.
So again, it's coordinates greater than not is equal to.
Six hundred, if it's greater than equal to 600.
What didn't should mention as Blur X, which is basically X coordinate.
So there's six of them, which is basically not going away from that.
And.
As I'm mentioning, right, it should be going to the right counsel.
I need to mention mood lighting here.
So just let's move our.
So I will later create that mood, right, anybody thinks so what is the mood, right?
I will create it later.
So this will be the user defining returns, which is I'm going to create it later by.
Similarly, I need to mention all the things for left, so I will competition, let me paste and now
I'm going to change a few parts, which is basically here if you assume that we can left only.
Now at the end, it's Blair eggs, and it should not be greater than or equal, it should be strictly
less than 10.
So why not go to that part so it should be banned?
You feel less than or equal to Tent City 210 again and move left, not move right, move left.
It should be moved to the left, so I will.
This is again you different method, which I will create later.
Now another thing I need to mention is very basic thing.
If you are closely looking this part and everything, OK, now enter into thing is basic, so let me
again copy this, which is.
Do you think if a user presses enter?
Enter, which just basically simple selection you can get yourself into.
If.
Play which players you can kick your that's a bullying culture.
And as a starting point instead of do now, I need to mention that at tarting I mentioned as follows
Now I'm making it through.
And no one.
Would that users and into a.
For that purpose, if users and those in Turkey just.
Authorities in Turkey, I need to mention ball position.
Then I'm mentioning of right at random positions or and.
I'm limited to one position.
Why again, I'm putting its random position 350.
So for the toughness of the game and starting only in one direction, it should be moved downwards,
not upwards.
So its direction should be minus one.
It should not be going downward.
So.
And bowl valediction I'm mentioning is minus two.
Now.
Blair, as you can assume, Blair should be aired and to student a score and the score should be zero
always total because you can choose as much you want.
I'm mentioning S21 only, so 21 will be higher score and it will create on the map so that we I'm going
to generate later.
But.
To avoid any enemies I'm mentioning earlier, despite gender and I guess three soon enough.
So I will create that letter, and I will tell you, what is this and this will do?
But now?
Only these things are not enough.
I need to mention one thing here is the deep end.
So I will tell you, what is the reprinting here?
Oh, OK.
Let me show you what it is dipping is basically creating a rectangle or creating plate in Java, NWT
again.
So it's just like the creation of that void again, deep and this is my, yeah, this is my this look.
And OK, this is my ball position.
It's.
So now all I need to mention ratings, move liftings, action, perform things because action event,
which is basically the bouncing part and some more things like collisions and everything I need to mention.
So.
The game plays only dumb job encoding, otherwise we are creating you, and everything is very easy.
So now what I'm going to do is I'm going to the moon left and these things.
But before that, I need to mention public void.
Gives me a 30 year.
And let me tell you why I'm creating it earlier, because if.
He went.
E again, if I created this earlier.
There may be chances.
Our players will not move that part is not.
Let me mention again, I don't see it in one important thing.
Even.
E!
So I'm mentioning these methods earlier.
And this note, I'm going to create public.
Void.
You are right.
I already moved on.
Well, let me move in this moment, please, equal to two, because it's single game only.
True.
And politics.
Position always goes to.
Is it 20 by 2020 positions, it will be?
Similarly, I need to mention four of my.
But with little difference, as I'm adding here, I'm again putting this left.
As I'm adding in the right position, which is basically plus, but for the left condition, I need
to mention minus.
So, no, these things are done now.
What I need to mention, which is basically actions by starting in doing all these things, I need to
mention which is again another matter.
Public void.
Action performed.
Action evening.
So, which is basically dependent on action, not on pressing.
They were the first time I mentioned already it should be start at the starting position start.
After this, if Blair is going to play, so if play, which is always false, the starting.
But it will create a new rectangle forming so new.
So action performed is basically creating a mean layout of your energy, you so.
I already created inside parts of that, that ball and everything, but what about the net templates?
I need to create one template, so I'm going to include that in everything rectangle.
With bold position.
It's.
Omar Ball position.
Why now?
I guess don't debate to induce enough friction for me.
With some intersecting methods, again, it's a very complex thing.
The six.
With another new rectangle.
So it's just like overlaying on two rectangles with.
Player X, because there should be a player also at the start.
Otherwise, it will be no use of Game 30.
And I guess it isn't OK, how it is mentioned and everything is mentioned.
And is, you know, not.
In general for this launch.
Very, very much so.
So I'm no gender rectangle.
No, I need to mention one by direction.
Is equal to minus of worldwide addiction.
She's basically very similar, like it should be Clinton and the starting point and one direction.
Just starting, it should be minus two.
And if I need to create another key because I need to create random things here, so I will create different,
different parts.
I'm going with three parts here, so and see if I'm going to create here another method and see which
is another condition I need to mention.
Similar things I need to I'm going to create a bit more positioning, small position, why and everything
here.
So let me do one thing.
Let me copy this part.
But I don't want to use such things.
Let me mention, so what are the different things series or Player X?
As I'm mentioning, it's 550.
It should be five.
They didn't know it.
But let me do one thing.
It's basically here that we mentioned, I totally.
With 40, this is enough and.
That's how it is.
So I created with this image lifting, or let me do one thing here.
Let me go with first 20 Park.
Twenty 550 and 30, ritualistically you deal with but part.
Of anything.
And.
In this, again, the similar thing.
But I will change a little bit here.
His bold direction is going to become bold.
Its direction.
Let's once or.
It will move a little bit, but no, I again copying this.
And this time is something new, which is basically.
With 30.
You should be what should be it only?
I'm not going to change the height of you to basically paddle.
Ball position, and this time it's the one single condition only.
So this is basically over in logic.
No, I need to mention the collision with a football song.
Collision with the ball, I need to mention then, oh, let me check for I've created already, it's
not actually random, basically.
Also.
In this section, you won't even need to book, so I will create one thing here, which is basically
our ball collision in an expert in that thing.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to create one method which is going to collide on that ball or collide
on that platform.
It will bounce, so I will create such thing in next momentum.
Hope you can understand.
Thank you.