So we are really creating disinfectant.
The key generator part, which is generating a semantic game of.
Cipher takes using a yes algorithm.
So we don't regard this because Java security in this package will take care of this easily, so we
don't belong here.
And as I told you, already developing this corn, I told you will always create another key difference
here.
So you required this Milosevic's Java execs combined.
Or you can use by example, you may find this on internet.
This is Java you have to download.
It's another dependency.
If you are using marijuana, you have to use dependency injection behavior and not using heroin.
So I need to.
Mentioned this directly.
So let us see, we already created this.
So no one will get full throated for this, so we closed out outpost and sold it for more than two billion
small.
I'm going to get you one at so let can give the name is Abdul Jalil Java class at.
So what am I are creating this semantic game is for representation, but for the Gila family at and
to proceed with this then modern dimensions.
Atheists are included first.
So, again, that's simple but enforced.
I used your public static.
No, I'm going to use private here and private.
I need to mention or I don't want to change this algorithm later.
So no one is going to change this.
This is the two time dimension of this.
Using Block.
Safe would say, for blocking technique, CBS technique, commonly known as CBS, to ensure that predicts
that it won't change steady.
Fine, then.
Green, oh, I'm giving.
Site for an eight this cycle.
No, kidding.
Yes, atheists slash each other with CBS board log of seven.
OK.
All CBS Remember there is another Cameron B key scheme.
So you remember this for 30 oh, package for you.
Also, package it is for you.
Planning and willing to use it.
So these are all about who his name.
I'm going to create one static scanner, private static scanner.
Scandal and listening in for the message, but.
So long we've done with this.
No.
I hate to mention mental.
Here's what I'm going to do, I need you to stay.
OK, well, because as I told you, in previous order against a tutorial or previous video, we created
that part already.
So similarly, one equals we required one strategy here.
Step two All security secrets.
Step two So let me create one secret.
Method to create security.
So again, it's simple, as we already created this, it shouldn't be public only standing.
Secret give great secret, you always keep on going to the secret key.
Create yet atheists, because it's easy, so it shouldn't be easy.
You know, we learned this.
So it shows you've got to be so alone in securing something that wants to get random java for randomizing
and everything securing them.
Let me be honest, man.
And it means you.
It's a good thing, so that's for.
Bring the mines.
And, Jim, I need to randomize again when I hear putting new messages.
First, I will tell you what kind of message key should be different if I could next message by for
anybody.
He should really always.
Then you generate revenue, abuse you generate, but that's not me.
You don't let me squander this, but can you generate a.
He generated.
Don't get instance gives instant wisdom.
I need to mention them a you know, it's.
So, right.
An exception to the rule search algorithm.
So anything exceptional to you then cumulatively gives you generator the generator, I need to initialize
it, not because I haven't created, I need to initialize degenerated in it basically issue 256 similarly
to slash securing the moment to boost.
So could let me OK, don't I need to create security here of security?
This is my security.
Jail under greater scrutiny.
Equally, he didn't to.
And not disputed game that he delivered oxygen rated, not generic, which is default better and which
is going to really look.
So let me tell you, what is all these things?
We already created here.
So.
Let me mention this again, you're who?
Or the confusion, confusion part, so it's going to.
Now I need to create one the third part.
So let me you, what is this matter who you need?
We don't.
And create Victor, which.
And even so, when you look to pass a message, bye bye, bye, so for this purpose, I'm standing.
Bite me, bite.
What you did not only despite, I mean, create mission.
So I'm going to mention is create an issue.
So this is my name known in Michigan.
You can read initialization reports I'm mentioning as the solar radiation.
This is my name.
And I'm giving you some criticism.
I used encryption.
I need to encrypt something.
And this is just what he's proposing, what I'm going to do, right?
Not long remember, I need to create initialization.
This initial question you get.
Perpetrators.
There's.
Let me use Camel case.
So there may be no it is using gambling, it's not like we is equal to me, if you will, by mentioning
60 by 60 Minutes, it seems expensive.
It will let you 256, then I need even see good random.
Now, remember why I need random cause, I need to again create secure random thing here.
Randomizing every part I need to create, every king around them is not only the Egypt park, but also.
Achieving the under two percent randomizing.
Secure, random, not mixed by mixed, but.
And what I need to mention is the Victor party, which is exactly.
Initially, we saw.
That our new dimension and what it should, if do today, we should have done.
That it should be well, it should return this far to.
And.
We will do this later.
What we going to is good start.
And let me optimize the imports because.
It's very useful to optimize imports from just about optimising imports to avoid.
Maudlin delays, so I created this now I need to create which functions is going to make plain text
the key with the initialization and its return, and another way to convert plain text will say four
days.
So we need to create that part also.
So.
Meantime, who?
A plain text.
And when he converted to.
Ciphertext.
OK, so I need to get details also.
So public static static, but again by.
And military engineers who eat this encryption.
They need to get this encryption.
And said this encryption warning.
Bringing the string.
Glenn IGST wants to.
Secret key and regression secret keeps secret.
And need to engineer it.
Now it is the long, metaphysical.
We really created by.
Small, small talk, but.
So let me tell you one thing here.
Let me put these two, says Mark, as my Oh.
Kings, and let me tell you why I'm here as it's happened, because all teams are determined.
Initiate.
Oh.
With her and Rooney as like this, including this, because there are many things you wish you would
do to me that exceptionalism.
To that, we require all risk.
Well, these are the plaintiffs secret key and initial victories, their attributes.
And now we are going to create one site for next and everything you.
So let me mention so for you so far.
Safer is building.
So full.
The great instance can get dangerous.
Atheists.
So it is that it is so full.
It is so fluid.
I'll go get them.
So.
It is all we currently.
That's name is a you see it.
Well, our decided is that OK, so this a CBSA for the block algorithm eat cake.
I would say put on with them.
Well, what I'm going to do this first, I forbid I'm required some I.V. parameters, pics of that part
and everything, so we will do that back later.
So consider I created two vectors with might, which is initial vector for initializing the randomizing
the part.
And so again, these take plaintext and keep going and the donkey can work with the ciphertext.
So hope you understand in the next part, we are going to complete this.