Well, now or in the previous thing I told you, we created one line there, which is extend straight,
I mistake that in both parties.
We close that sort of glass of only, you know, these glass doors are planted inside only that sort
of glass.
Otherwise, it will not run for that purpose.
I'm going to using inside only that sort of glass.
Now we are created already this concept that we are remaining with some methods, which is basically
that get input each and every thing, as I told you earlier.
So first, create the one input on, or we can say we can create the one method, which is great user
name or getting the user name.
Inside our.
Client.
So let me create one public way.
Get.
User.
Name.
Which is basically.
Returning.
Username.
So.
Why it should be strong, let me tell you, it is returning as a string, so it's a mystery.
OK.
It's not returning void or anything.
No, I need to set the username similar method oblique.
Now it's what it should be, said username.
Again, this.
Oh, so let me check first.
If I use this third username anywhere.
Not.
So said username is the first time parts so no need to require.
I told you because.
This is very well what we can say, sometimes it is very good.
Sometimes you mistake us the some part or, you know, writing or you can say uppercase, lowercase
or always remember you should.
We will soon be using the same username to the username.
So done so this formal setting, the username and all letters.
So what I'm creating here, I need to create infinite loop.
Late in the night and late night.
New to read and forward a message.
And so what it's actually going to do, it is storing as a object inside of their client, really,
we can see and ought to begin to add a glass at least and what it will be do.
It will print that in broadcast to be.
So I knew the void method, public void.
Run run is basically for the running that.
Ted, as you can see here, we go to the one symbolically, what is this thing is exuding the third
glass classroom then, and you can step out of your trunk in the overriding control of this.
Never change that, but I've been telling you that before laboratories.
You know, Andy.
Novel.
So what I'm going to do is, Will, then, you know, keep going, I already.
Bullion keep going is equal to.
Well, they keep going.
I need to mention the reading back.
So read.
Stunning.
OK, so what I'm going to do, I'm going to read that story.
So are the things we required here is very similar.
I need to try block or I will tell you what is going to do is you did object to this news chat message
and chat messages to another class in this class and it will go to that issue.
And each and every.
So as I mentioned this earlier this morning, what is remaining glass, not phone team here?
So I'm mentioning what we can say will specify the cage block for expression, different classes not
only accepting different because these are very important partner.
If you are mentioning exhibition, it will bring all the exceptions.
But for our client user interface purposes, I'm using this.
Then.
I'm going to get the message, I should get that message from that part.
What I'm going to do is I'm mentioning this part of the show, so I will tell you where I'm going to
create this good message in the chat messaging each and every day.
So what I need to do is I need to get a different action based on the type of data messages, as I told
you, or if that username part is different and each and everything I can create.
Switch gears here.
So I will explain this, which is first you.
After this and we mentioned this, OK, now, what are these things after this disturbing and said,
I'm going to switch the tape, which is basically in the chat message chat room, which is a message
which some broadcast will?
What do you think the user name and the message?
And what is the confirmation if the confirmation is blocked?
No such use that exist.
So what is this part, actually, as I told you?
Why I'm asking if I I'll check for that ad, but it's symbolic to the region.
It will go to that private message board for such purposes.
What I'm going to do, I'm creating here that broadcast part here.
You can see I can say that, but if I'm printing logo from the user, it will be disconnect for the
who isn't metal.
It will print all user name since that date part.
So this is all about things how we can create.
So I need to create or.
If you're out of the loop or disconnected, I need to remove that idea and accept the things I need
to mention here.
Then it will be asking for all the.
OK.
So this is how we can create this part.
So.
Let me do two or three things here, first, as I created here within matter.