So in previous part, what we have done is we already created one in New Jersey, which is for the in
part like this government fly and we are importing some failures.
So we are importing this page and what is page import is basically I am just accessing this melodic
land lampooning me because the packages mean here, as you can see this bombed out exactly which is
my property.
A daily record.
Is this basic needs?
If you know this, this is just basically the injection dependency dependency injection I use you.
So I use this as a dependency part.
So late, I'm putting this, you can see I'm accessing this may look like you and I already wrote a
program for this, so my client is nothing, but it's accessing data on GCP police and.
This is going to indexing, so it will take them indexing.
So more then let me tell you, was in previously with some short recap.
So what I have done here is it's very easy.
I have a here.
So.
These are the teams.
It may look like I'm creating here, albeit string, which is saying basically then souvlaki what I
used as a constructor here.
You mentioned this is the constructor of this, so you can minimize this as it is the only platform
that actions sometimes indexing will take you a little bit of more time.
But what are you going to do?
You can just load this from, you know, independence is a big part of that indexing.
So.
The building parachutes went to see this subdivision.
As you can see with the cloud.
So we created this message and everything, and it's going to dispatch and I'm using it two methods.
When is due post and one is doing it?
So this is it about how we perform in Maitland, so news just for accessing the daytime, everything,
then what is the mood in some individuals employed?
This can do one thing you.
If we were to open this and and.
What I'm going to do is you can just reload this because sometimes it takes more time indexing so you
can hide the process.
So it will take time.
But I know I can potentially beat my furthermore indexing part time.
I don't want to stop for this on this, but what I'm going to do, I'm going to create the one more
thing is email you.
So let me copy this.
OK, I got this, but no, let me go to the main line for.
What I'm going to do now is this gleaming new gel like glass.
Based on this e-mail utility being the.
So that's it.
It's created for this part, so it will take time to indexing and doing everything here.
Sometimes it takes more time than this.
We are not sorry about that, but we will check it later.
Let us start with coding part.
So I already created this, but we are remaining with some final strings, which is basically a special
socket factory.
We are going to factory is just basically for factory resetting and doing everything.
So if we go to the bottom.
I mean, over the mean.
But I read.
Let me mention one thing here is
this, too.
I will tell you, what is the significance of this?
So essentially, it's just handling this, so I'm mentioning this, but I will tell you later how it's
going to work.
It's not actually I'm as a comedian and I'm commenting.
This part is, I will tell you later.
You just it's a silly factory invention.
So that's not required at all.
But sometimes you just use more references for that.
Let me get one.
Private.
Steady.
Oh, I needed properties.
No, these props you can rent out, you can add anything so.
Sometimes it takes time like you can check your bag around us taking more time due to network issues
and more things.
But you can go to war with this new.
Properties.
So, you know, the job on properties, then what I'm going to perform here is I'm going to create one
static part.
So if you know, are instead putting all mean or or we can say between the Israelis commenting, it
will be like complete study or.
It, that would be a stream.
Instead of doing this matter, what I going to do, I can just mention a starting block.
So it will execute for me, steady.
I can create a standing block in Java.
Similarly, I created this.
So now what I'm going to do, I'm going to mention some properties of my assembly protocols.
These are good.
First is mentioning the host, which is basically me, not a simply the host.
So what is the host for me?
Let me put here.
It's MTV, which is G-mail, Moltisanti TV, Jimin Lodgement dot com.
So this is my sympathy for what you mean.
Then what is the pool probs?
Not good.
Tourism imports.
Next thing is, I want to mention the poor information, do you remember it's always so mentioned indirectly
monitoring China's extreme.
And I need to mention the authentication part, so why we need authentication, we need authentication
always.
We don't want to stop it.
They seem to be more.
Well, let me put Mike off, it is on this report, the you.
I am performing this through Baqir.
Then we are remaining with star BP, and all we can say is start fearless, start this.
So what are these things?
So let me mention here these are no proper fees of SMP server, so I'm mentioning all the proper people
who seem to be sort of like may not seem to be posted online.
Do you mean dot com?
All these fires to an authentication is so lame you need authentication or places you how do you e-mail
account and, you know, password?
We are mention here.
So I want to mention that authentication is always true in this case.
While sending e-mail is authentication is always true.
So you can say this and it will.
You mean the authentication on this.
But what I needed before is, I need to mention here.
One thing may not seem if it is simply not stop, be a closer we saw of we can see the.
Anybody else is a very common thing in what you can say, you need a new program if you're taking it
through this.
It's basically transport layer security and we have to enable it always this way using GM India.
So now we are done with this.
So let me check in.
Nixon is operating in the Nixon.
So sometimes it may take time according to your network connection at the moment.
So even though this, could it be done from this project that it will take, butI mean, and sometimes
it takes more time also.
So keep it as it is and move forward with your price.
So what?
We have done it.
Let me tell you again, I'm mentioning the WHO says this all has this authentication and the transport
list is going to be I won't be anyone mentioned as a trooper.
So that said, I had done it.
So no, what I want to mention is I want to mention here one sand mail message or saying the mail team.
So for that purpose?
We've seen me.
So I went public spending.
Right.
If you know why I'm mentioning it's not running anything.
So what is the reading, if you know the basics?
If you're from Italy is returning something re-allocating or getting this help getting some memory.
It should be here.
It's not doing anything.
Send is my method.
I want to mention one parameter is email message, which is my email.
Message.
The so another barometer I mentioned.
So these are the main parameters, not.
Anything you mention.
So, you know, you strike out instead of using triage.
What I can do, I need to.
Mention string saying that to me.
So.
Or you're going to lose.
Notice your e-mail, I mean, something like this because I I'm going to.
I will tell you about your e-mail.
Andrew, do you mind if you call this?
Second is that is password, because for the authentication purposes, I'm authenticating this and always
do well on which parameters I'm going to take your email address, which is basically username and password
for login in any as individual, whereas you want specific username and password for you.
So similarly, I'm mentioning this single email.
Plus, so I guess you're.
You mean, so this is not my e-mail password, and it's not on my email also.
I will tell you later what I'm going to put here, so I'm mentioning as you.
Tim Incursion.
Farah, Lucas, OK.
So these are the authentication parameters, which is basically saying the email, which is this the
username and password is for the password basis.
So I will tell you what I want to do.
You know, let us consider this a very routine I'm going to do here.
It's a security.
No, not at all.
Because when using your ID, it's public void.
Anyone can take this as a security service.
So I will tell you later what I'm going to do here, I'm going to use string handling and everything
I'm going to do here.
But I will tell you later for simplicity and keeping ladies in for a little part, I will change it
to more complex thing.
But.
Let me make a connection with Servlet Foster.
OK, so I need to create one session here session.
So once this is in next news, don't know, libraries will automatically be added here and everything
will be done session.
Not yet.
Default instances.
This default in systems, which is basically a very common thing I'm going to do here is.
Props.
I don't want to mention props, properties.
And.
His proves.
We don't take me to your office because.
France, which is basically properties then new, the new Jaguar XE not mean, which is overwhelmingly
male, not OK.
Or to Google.
So this is my instances where what is going to do in accessing these properties.
As you can see, this property will be accessed because this is the state.
These are the properties of same degree.
So it will come this team, which is basically my name.
Mr Object ought to be going to class its object, and it will ask me who this makes me a him to get
done.
No, these are decisions I need to mention to do things here, which is password protected thing and
everything and information.
So in the further part, I will tell you how we can create a connection with the server.
Plus how we are going to handle this thing because now it's currently very unsecure method.
And let me tell you why this is unsecure, because this is public and I'm directly putting my password
in, so if anyone having some injecting in our political analysts server injection, they can follow
this directly.
So instead of this, what you can do is, I will tell you later.
There are many a lot of options you can do, but for this condition, I'm going to use some more other
simple options if you are testing purpose.
You can do this and other things I'm going to mention here.
But I will tell you in later regarding, you know, if somebody before any help you understand.
Thank you.