So when I go read some part of you, if you closely look, I created different things.
First, I created one employee service as an interface, which is passing the list with quite some data
that employees to employees and some fingerprint reader.
It's just for page sorting files and everything is going to create sorting the fields and everything.
I created a page employee as my another list.
In this, I created one model thing, which is purely based on DARPA, which is going to create columns
and everything.
Toward things like creating this, obviously is basically this is the interface, and to implement implementing
the class, I created one service.
I mentioned one service.
It's very easy to do.
I mentioned some of the wired things and I'm putting in the list and I'm going to create that.
I'm creating auto generated.
So that just object oriented thing I created with some existing parts.
This is very important.
I'm well descending in the descending order.
I'm creating that quilt.
I created one repository to store the cashier files, and I'm using this.
So if you close and look, I already created one controller part in the controller, I'm going to mention
one class name as the employee controller to control the employee files.
So.
Let me mention employee controller.
So this is the main team which is going to handle the backend and featuring the data it's going to create,
it's going to excuse the editing part.
So now it's let me mention the controller in the spring framework that is defaulting, which is basically
the controller again on the way.
It's very important to not create a manual connection, always.
We can mention the team then, but I would.
I need to mention service to employees.
So this I need to be here.
I'm going to mention employee service.
Two employees, so you saw it will access that employee service director.
Now I need to display.
I need what I need to do, display a list of employees that what are you going to sue Ford it all for
data or part of a statement by learning to display all the things?
So for that was I need to create one mapping paintings so it's easy to get my.
Because it might be.
So wide screen, the error is because create an additional human being and a memory.
Or I haven't added the great mapping dependency, so you need to access that dependency.
Let me show you it's very easy, and if your dependency is not added to here and out of my own dependency
in this, it will search for the tapping and click here and.
That you need to perform.
So wait for some time.
It will.
And my independency for you, which is basically the get mapping.
As you can see, it's resolving my dependency part.
Ignoring this, I'm going to create for my.
Is basically the destroying.
View home page, which is basically home page view.
As the name suggests.
Model.
Molly, I'm OK.
So it's me asking you to order dental to get that nothing bar.
So what we can do is just start to optimize the imports.
So that's it.
I need to mention here.
This is basically my meter, which is going to perform this new morality.
So default page is one basically page.
One.
So in this, I need to mention that you done.
And.
Basically, I need to mention that Beijing didn't think.
One, which is basically my one first name as my defaulting.
It should be all synchronized or you can say, Oh, ski park and we're going to in the morning.
No, you didn't ask me what is is so.
It's asking me to create the condition.
But the thing is, I already created creating.
Somewhere.
Let me check with OK.
I need to mention this one.
And the thing is.
I need to implement and do something.
So let us take wide the error because.
Newt, we will check it later.
The main, I think, is Memorial, So.
Let me explore.
Let me move on to.
It's accessing everything, but it's not accessing these unbelievably friendly things, right?
It's obviously not cheap, is it any?
OK, we will find find that little park.
So maybe there is one error with.
Mapping part of the energy.
So we will check it later.
So we created one mapping for the basic mapping, so it's not really complicated editing, I guess.
So it's just creating a mapping and it's creating one mapping part.
So what is creating is basically it's creating different things.
So let me do one thing.
Let me.
Divide this young woman, if Alexis is just.
Let me mention this as this and.
I guess this employee controller is basically the.
No, it's not that far.
It's not guilty for it on this.
OK, OK.
In the later part, we need to create one better than defaulting, so.
No need to.
What do you what do you see?
So in a similar way, I'm going to create different, different mapping system.
So let me show you what I'm going to do.
So as you can see, I created this part.
Already and is do.
Important job one, don't you do not start informed everything, OK?
No, no, we created this.
So let me tell you what I'm going to do, what I'm doing here, so I'm just mentioning you one paid
for one.
Our food first name with the ask you directly.
This model show new employer form two showing the new employee form that this employee with the model,
then same employee.
So these are my opinion bootstrapping methods like that you're doing so if you want to check, you can
put your own insert also to check whether you can or to.
While dependency, you can add and you can check everything in the generation generation part.
But let me tell you, this is for the ID purposes, then delete employee again, listing then pages
for the paging part and all letters those.
So in the later part, I'm going to create one extremely pages.
And after that, I'm going to show you how you can set up fluster database and that you can implement
that database in your application.
Hope we understand.
Thank you.
This is just a controller part which is accessing the controllers.
If you go to Old Insert.
Also, you can take your device dependencies with different, different dependencies, staff, scheduler
and everything.
Or you can check so you can directly create him live.
Also here instead of executing again and again, so you can it.
So this is just a great mapping and shoot mapping methods and creating post mapping.
And can you do so for the delete employee and everything?
So you were looking this you can check here.
It's very easy.
You can perform.
Hope you understand.
Thank you.