So after the successful creation of the teacher and the student class, we are heading over to the school
section.
So the school is the main body which is managing the funds in a way of giving the salary to their teachers
and receiving the fees from the students.
So the main system here is the school for which we are creating this project for the management of soirées
in the school.
Similar way of teaching the students.
We will create a class.
School and inside the class, we will see some variables so private.
Feature.
Peter?
We know that the school comprises of teachers and students, so it is the beginning.
Collective bargaining for this class by initializing the students and teachers, soirées the students
and teachers now.
School consists of teachers and students, but what is the actual purpose of this project like we are
here to manage the funds?
So how the funds are consistent of in the funds we have our total money on, our total fund is earned
by the school and thus will have to spend it in various ways of giving this salary to certain teachers
and say something as a profit.
So, yes, we have to care about people sort of that thing also.
So creating a private a static class for the total money, we will learn about stepping in something
total money on.
Yes.
So the total money earned by the school and in the similar way.
Total money spent.
So I will copied this part and pasted her.
Total money spent, so yes, we have successfully created the members of this school class as teachers,
students.
The total money on and the total money spent.
Now, you must be wondering, that is student and teacher class, we initialize the ID engine, which
was unique for every teacher and student.
Each teacher has a unique name and each student has a unique name, similar with that IDs.
What does a school contain?
A single teacher?
A single student?
Is it possible?
Like, think about this on yourself.
The answer is no, that a school can never be built with single teacher or student.
It will not exist in that.
So you must be wondering that how to add multiple teachers and students in this class new school.
So I am giving you a second and think about what comes in your mind, how to gain multiple data with
this teacher variable.
So a method may arise in your mind of declaring this as an addict.
Right.
So.
Trying it in this way.
Yes, so we went to Canada and they're in this way.
But think about it.
So if we take their teacher and students as an ally.
We know the concept of adding it has a limited number of sites like we have the initial line the size
of that in the beginning and it is immutable, we cannot change the size of another.
So suppose if I didn't want to leave the school or join, our teacher wants to join the school later.
So is it possible to do so with errors?
The answer is no, as it is are immutable, evicted size.
Initially, we could not alter networks, so we have to think in a broad database to create a data type
which is resizable and x, or delete data as off teachers and store names very conveniently without
any restrictions.
So removing this.
I am going to tell you about a very beautiful day that I call Adam.
Yes.
Java has this date day at least, which is pretty sizable and has many features in it, which makes
it useful in many movies.
So I am going to show you this in this demo.
Dark Java Fi Soirées Head I have already created this demo done Java file.
Yes, so in this.
I have created a demo glass and inside this public static void main string.
So here is a main function inside which the analyst is called.
So list in danger number is equal to you, at least this is the way to declare an analyst in Java had
it after writing this like, I even show you writing this again.
If I write, list her.
It is showing that it is from the Utilizzati.
And when I write this list, this import library automatically comes here.
So after this?
I have created a list called Numbers, which contains outdated type of integer.
So this is our demo function, and I am going to run some integers in the alleys and show you how it
works.
So let me remove this first and start adding it one by one.
So in the list, call the numbers.
I am going to add integer.
Add an integer.
Five Yes.
So yes and.
And another integer called.
Mistakenly typed in numbers, it is no.
Yes, so no more than 15 and.
This is the method to add numbers to the list.
It those numbers.
Yes, so you may copy it multiple number of times.
And this is the beauty of Harold, is that it is.
It is sizable, and it will never say no.
You keep adding no.
The rest of your life and it will never stop.
I am full.
There is nothing like a limitation in analyst, so after adding numbers to the list, I am going to
run this.
So on running this function, I am getting that test five, fifteen five, fifty fifty five, then seventy
six.
After adding some more numbers.
I can keep doing this multiple number of times.
Any number I can add like.
Yes.
And running it again.
So perfect, keep adding numbers to that list, and it will keep displaying it in the terminal.
It will keep giving you the output and never see that downfall.
So this feature off of Java is very useful for our project as we need this kind of data type only for
managing our teachers and students.
So in our student dance, our fight and teacher devil fight, we are going to use the A-list feature
in the school function to call the teachers and students multiple number of times, and we can add features
again, again and again and adding students again and again and again.
So let's start begin adding this here as an add on.
Now let us write this teacher inside Alice.
As we discussed in that demo, far soirées A-listers created a feature.
Similarly for the student.
We are creating an Arab list for the teachers and the students.
So here you can see that the job you didn't list back, it is importing itself.
And as far as I know, this list, as soon as this list is declared, the packages imported itself.
No women, no further.
So after creating this school class, we have created our school object or a constructor as we see that.
So the school object contains the parameters as an analyst for teacher and student.
So we have used this key word for adding features to this object.
And students.
The total money on and total money spent is not inside this construct then, so there is no need to
add this giver.
So yes, we have created this object school, so romantic that objects school.
Is created.
Now moving further.
So the total money earned is zero in the beginning, and the total money spent is as low now as similar
as the teacher and the student.
We have said that teachers and students to the school function school class.
So we are adding teachers to the class and.
Yes, so setting and getting teachers and students are must to.
There is no restrictions with teachers and students than they are.
They cannot be altered.
So yes, we have said anger.
So this publicness teacher returns their teacher.
Let me comment this out through dance the teachers in the school class.
Yes.
Sorry.
Does the teacher in the school?
Similarly, this said.
This is a sad matter.
And is this a heard of said I have used as teacher for a better understanding of the goal.
So this one of the teachers in the school?
Yes.
So you can see that we have a certain gentleman turned up for that.
And similarly for the students and despite returns, no students in the school class and this part of
the students in the school class.
Now, for their total money on Park in this school, we have said the.
This yes, we have said this matter for total money.
So this returns the total money earned by the school, total money and so far, yes.
So total money earned is return to this function.
And if we need to update, we are using the segmenter and in the business of that, we have always done
up the total money.
So this update?
The total money earned.
Yes.
So this update, the total money owed by the school, and in this, we have summed up it as a total
money on.
This is does somebody in so total money on is a sum of total money earned plus money in the beginning?
Yes, we have lost money on it as a barometer.
So total money initially is zero, so we can write it as.
In a comment, I will show you with me.
Yes.
So this is something in the beginning of this something as zero is equal to zero plus.
Money on support student submitted our fees like for anti-terrorism, so that total money on will store
of value of twenty thousand.
Yes.