In previous videos on today, as I told you, I have created one studio method for connection to the
database in search to run this one.
Then all records get all records.
Using array is another method.
Then I'm using the little automated also get pseudonym method also.
So these are some common things I used.
We did and record also.
So this is to run be you.
Similarly, we created a deal, which is the release, actually, because I'm just preaching from the
database and putting because everything has a poor role to use all the to be you and ultimatums.
Similarly, we have to create matters for Christians and insurgents.
So why do we need to create these methods?
So if you pre-defined some versions, these are not very useful because you need to again and again
use a database queries.
No database part.
So if you want to use interface, you need to create one also.
So I created commission, be my turn.
Then this instruction in question, whether I'm using you so this what it will, we do, it will face
data or I'm not providing you're fetching data because I need to create another file also.
So in further part, I will told how you can create images before here and we are going to create JS
to file in webpages, but also so this will execute this and update that we took action.
So I will show you which queries you want to do because we need to just create tables here.
No need to create all things or interpret that.
We need to create our own or we want we need to execute only viable sixth in sector database, only
to create a database to question you for the get the records of the questions and then delete record
to question the question and update to update that question partner.
So you can update question table using it or like you can put the new question, or you can change that
position, you can change your option and there is one another for additional question because you need
to see that original version also.
So this is all around the question, Neal, which is a very simple matter and which is very helpful
or no.
One special deal, which is really symbolic.
The logic is simple as we are willing to do any deal, we need to get to run them similarly for the
good questions and everything.
And using this, if you know the solid part, you can easily create that part, I will explain.
Step by step, you two for the insert question, I'm using Boolean mentor.
So I I'm using Bulleit.
So once it is done, it will show that Boolean part only if true, then I can use that logic and I'm
switching the exception for the ArrayList.
I'm using a as designation and select from the question list.
It will print all the released.
So this is the backend part.
I will connect this back in to the printing tool, showing some beautiful loop manner inside our just
before or web page.
Again, I don't want to create some Mill and Java fighting for that.
I will embedded the Java code, inserted HDMI and so I am using GSP here, so it will be very helpful
while creating GSP, you will see how we are going with this pipe.
So once released is done, for the record, same simply deleted from question to question you.
So the next item will be from that good question, and what is your quote, good question, Christians.
Where is the Christian part?
So Christian is basically Oracle, which we created only order already good Christian and all the things
to do.
You are so Christian and it will delete that part and.
Let's see.
We are doing our part.
I'm handling the exception, and the exception is very important part.
We always handled that then with the original question, new question.
And with all the options and answers, you have to update that record and then the new record.
So this is all about how we can create a question mark.
Why don't you to the question be?
Similarly, what I'm going to do, I'm going to do, I'm going to create instruction deal to insert
instructions, and some are all getting all records, delete records and update records.
So as we are creating for us to learn deal, I'm going with same logic, same methods here.
So get connection insert connection, which contains internet connection with the instruction.
Then what is this instruction?
I ask you where I'm getting this instruction, and if we do this, we all use the instructions I told
you in for Barbato, in previous part, how we already created this.
You can use your daughter stardom and call for a school and all these things, but I'm feeling which
libraries I'm using only connection prepared statement and said I'm using here, not always for your
time using.
So this will insert all the values inside the database, then at least and get all the codes it will
of getting all the codes from this.
So remember, this is a very important distinction.
Then similarly for deleting instruction, tableware, instruction, and this also the reason seems simple.
But all I'm doing, doing just database and all things are simple and similar to one type.
You have created student's deal, all things that are similar.
Well, this is all about how we can create all this, so all we know when we are done, we are done
with or is going to be part because we already know that an alternate model.
So not only are we finished here only, but we need to create some control in part with content, law,
old instruction, certain method also.
Also, we need to create one and other things in GSP because we just we are just doing this back and
we need to create different channels.
So we will see in this really only how we can go with that.
So let us see how we can create instruments that we use, control instruction in part.
So instruction insert.
Let me close this part.
So what will this method do?
Well, it will insert all that matter into all things and which is basically a very simple method for
the state and everything I'm using this to.
I need the need to use this method of instruction because if you are inserting the instruction, you
need to create some java for you.
We are already created with the instruction insert or instruction Dubuc, which is using simple audio
as you can see this part, but we need to push some message that database is updated or we can say the
instruction is inserted for that purpose.
I'm using this controller is basically you can see what level Java Silverlight, which displays only
messages to the user then DBS for or creating some methods, which is helpful to create some database,
then updating that evolve method, updating the apartment or inserting some database inside that.
So it will the second let itself glasses, or you can see second level important classes.
Remember, we use that model is very important because I am creating all the methods with the instructions
and everything.
So it will if instructions are inserted into that part, it will print message instruction added and
it will add instruction GSP, which I'm going to create an instruction GSP method, which is for it
to be in part only.
It will put in that instruction in the idea, if not instruction is not order that on that same page.
So this is very simple, and this is only for the one pushing, or we can say only for the showing that
message on the database.
Similarly, we need to create some amateurs in previous part, or we can see we can create the one only
one button.
And once users log out, it'll go to that first part.
But for some user-friendly website, it shows a message what it shows.
It shows your logo successfully, or if you enter, it should welcome your name.
Similarly, for that purpose, I'm going to create another methods.
So these are very simple methods, logout student and I'm inside your door package only.
I'm using this.
Let me change to the star part only because.
I'm facing specifying all the libraries, which I'm using, because you can use or you can use directly
methods like you can always write first code and then you can import libraries because it will take
care of the importing all the libraries so it will import step by step.
So you need to optimize this to not start because it takes like it contains all bytes libraries.
No need to specify specific libraries here.
So I'm overriding this to this only like these methods and these matters.
So as I told you.
So what it has to do that I knew was to post it for the posting was do it is just for showing some information.
So it is always useful to them to do what takes too much time.
Even GHB is taking too much time for loading for that purpose.
We need to optimize everything.
But if I'm using just if it does matter, it will take too much time.
And there I am, using very small, small things like low successfully, and I'm just going to show
this by opposition invalided.
But I'm just put this once I click the log button and to show this part on which we're logging on GSP
page.
So for that, do get method.
It will take less time and it is very effective.
So I'm sitting here only.
Printing my statement.
So this is for the printing message on then logo timing.
Again, this is a very simple method for the logo and log in, but it was similarly for students.
I have created only logo student.
Similarly, you have to create for the log, so you are again going to use these methods on de novo
students and everything.
So I am using this because for user-friendly website, you need to.
Involved this, or you can say you need to create this part.
Similarly, we need to create question in certain part of Europe.
So let us see how we can create one Christian insert part of Christian entertainment material.
So for that purpose, inside the controller, you need to create another method, which is basically.
Cushion insert metal.
It.
Your solid.
Questioning.
These are very important step daughter of a victim and create a new file.
And I'm deleting this all part.
So let us see how we can do that, but let me use.
Some matters here.
So what I'm doing, I'm importing these matters only.
Because these things remain same here.
All the what I can do is I can.
Take it from.
Logo student, because it is already optimized, but.
OK.
So I mean, pulling all the leverage first in what I'm doing, I'm importing.
Import duty is not the.
Not.
Christians.
Then what I'm doing is I'm importing more intensely here because that we export more than.
Not Christians, do you convince that part?
Then you need to create an.
At the rate we so late, Mr.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to just pitching this.
And.
I will explain you, OK.
We need to see how we can create this.
OK, so we completed this part only because this is a very simple method, I'm going to you.
So no need to put this again and again because you see the Virginia, which is basically defaulting
since I already created in this part, knitting.
OK, so question insert, what do you need to do?
It will take part from this to get method and.
Option one option given uncertain only, so this will setting dances and you, Christian ideals successfully,
it should print, Christian added.
But if not earlier in June, that question is not with the same dispute.
So we need to create order.
We need to focus on GSP only.
So now we are done with discretion insert or so we are remaining with some another method, which is
basically student insert.
So again, it is very similar thing.
So I will explain yet only once this is done, we need to proceed with GSP files only.
So let me create another solid.
You're.
I'm acting in the way protection, and I'm deleting this part and what I'm going to do is.
I'm going to switch.
Similar libraries in Europe, because these things are always similar.
Then.
Instead of using that question, import, I'm going to use student input, but.
So.
That's it.
So we are already done with the.
Similarly, you need to create some lending support your.
So these are all defaulting, all already created, so we need to focus on this.
Once this is done, you name password and username, or it will print to the answer to that database.
So we need to see how we can create GSP.
So now we are done with all our solid parts.
We control comptroller is done.
Also, I told you in the previous We are done with this and we are done with the model part.
So now in for the videos, I'm going to tell you how we can create GSP, but only because we are already
done with this.
So step by step, I will tell you how we can create.
So I will explain the code because writing a code is very huge because typing each and every segment,
so it's very huge part.
So I will explain the code.