Hello, everyone.
So in this part, we are going to add functions for adding the songs, finding the songs and then adding
the songs to the playlist.
So let's begin.
OK, so we have to take this class, the function and the constructor.
Now we are going to create a public song, public song.
Find some.
Class 3A function, yes, and inside which we are going to add string string type then, so that title
of the song is going to be the argument inside the find song class.
After creating the class, now, we are going to end all fall.
Firstly, we have to create.
Of attention and things like before the finding of the song in order to find the song is present or
not.
Firstly, we have to add the song to the playlist or the library as we have named it.
So that song is going to be a Boolean type function, and the arguments are going to mean that I love
this song and the duration the song contains two tormenter like the song class, contains two networks,
the title and the duration.
So that is what we are going to call and say this.
So we have created the function for adding the song.
And now we are going to.
Check if the song is present or not.
So in saying this, if if statement we are going to call the find a song, which we have created had
a title of this song as we are going to find the song with the help of its title.
And if the title is present, then this is going to return true.
By default, it is set to null.
So if the song title is pressing inside the list of the songs, man, we are going to add some songs.
To the list, like if this song title is not a prison bailout, then only we are going to earn the songs
to the list and this is absolutely fine.
What is the need to a song which is already present?
So, yes, we have successfully added enough songs with its title and its duration.
Now in saying that if statement we are going to like, exist out.
This is the shortcut for printing, something we have to write as well, yes.
And the suggestions are going to suggest that we have to select the 6lb option and this will complete
the state run automatic light system dark powder print.
So what if statement is going to print fake whatever song is not present in the list?
So we have to add this song to the list, right?
So we are going to write this.
The title of the song, like calling the title of the animal and then successfully added to the list
like this title is successfully added to the list.
I suppose the title is anything like naming the song is ABC Plus successfully added to the list, so
as a whole, it is going to print.
ABC successfully added to the list, and this is going to return true as the eighth tape of this function
is rolling.
This function is returning Boolean Boolean argument.
So yes, we are done with this, but now we are going to complete the Find Song section also and then
start off the song like suppose if the song is already present, then what may have to?
Output like more, this function is going to get done, so if the song is already present, then we
have to sizzle song of it to name song it name.
Plus.
Plus, it's used for adding a variable and a variable, here is the title of the song written they are
wishing to add in the list already exists.
In the list.
What list?
The library, which may have created.
So if that song is already present, then this is is responsible for returning that the song is already
present in the list.
Do not bother to add the song again, so the add song part is completed.
Now we are switching to the Find Song.
Inside the find song function, we are going to check that the song is present in the list are not like
the day-to-day reality using to store their songs.
Is that a list which is recyclable and nothing else?
So this recyclable at it.
So we have to try to throw this out in this show in order to check whether the song is present in the
list or not.
So far, I think we have to use the loo so that we can move one by one in the songs and check if this
is present like we have to match the string that this data is already present or not.
And we are going to do this with the help of an enhanced form.
So inside the Find Songs section, we are going to declare the enhanced for piano and inside the far
loop.
We are going to check that check.
Check the song.
Check this song like we will need the checked song functionality.
Let me first complete that, find the song section and then we will.
Get tighter.
We have already declared in the song that Java class, get tighter and after this get tighter.
If it equals the title not in good thing, then it will draw an exception like this is already present.
Please do not bother to learn this again.
And after this chicken.
Song Chick, so this is going to be the if inside the four.
First complete of forty four.
So check.
Song Chang, the song.
Yes.
The suggestions.
Song cheering the song is the mountain is like a colon.
This design held for a loop which is going to stick to the barrels and asking that if this song is present
in the list, are not.
Inside the hall, we are.
I think his statement, which is going to.
Return that if this song is already present, then you're just checking the checking that with the help
of it, a string matching my show equals data.
If this is true, then this fine song is going.
This fine song function is going to return.
No, no.
So, yes, we are done with the public song find some function, which has the argument that the song
title.
So if they wish to find a song inside the Nest, we have to call for love and check that the song is
already present on now so that we have successfully added functionalities to an song and find find songs
from the list.
Now, the other next model should be to add and songs to the playlist like we have a list of songs,
list of albums, list of artists.
Now our main concern is to add songs to Playlist Rachel as the main goal of making this project.
Like, we are bothered about making a playlist of our favourite songs, so let us initialize our function
for adding songs to Dublin's name, this says and to playlist using cameras case.
And no function for ironing songs to playlist is created now, arguments when we like, so goes the
track.
No track, no is going to be like one two three four.
And it is going to be an integer.
Of course, also the playlist is going to be in the link, the list, the power structure.
So we will come to the linked list like what name list is shortly in some time?
First, let me call on human and the function, and I hope you are done.
So we have created the function of which is going to return Boolean tonight, like a true or false.
So public Boolean act of is in track number and we are good to go.
I think the English song playlist.
Yes.
So I can say this in this similar way may have done this for finding songs again, for adding the songs
to the playlist.
Firstly, we have to iterate through the list and check that whether the song is already present in
the plane is diagnosed.
So in order to check so we have to like, firstly, call off or lose an enhanced follow.
And this is going to check again using that check the song thing like we have used to moving in the
song section and then going to check back when the song is present in the playlist are known.
So Song Cheng, the song calling this dark songs is used for iterating through the song list.
Now how we are going to create a playlist like we have and our list of songs, which contains supposed
five to six songs from makes me want to add the three songs to our playlist, so we will iterate through
the list and check that whether the Tengiz Brothers song is present in the list or not.
And we are going to make that playlist as a lengthy list.
So you may be wondering why me into a single playlist as a link list?
So I listed the special data structure data tie, which is going to contain a pointer to from the previous
element and from the next element.
So basically enclosed is like two or three type of data structure, which has nodes and the roots are
connected to the first thing like previous elements.
And the second thing, the next element.
So yes, we are going to create a playlist as a link list as the members of the playlist are connected.
Now, current song is connected to the previous track, and the current song is connected to the next
track as well.
So yes, it is going to be done in this way only.
So we have covered the link list now we are going to check this with a similar way.
We have added like a similar way.
We have checked it in the Find Song section, so we've checked song title equals equals.
Under title, so the government and the.
Equals is going to be that tight, the.
So he is here we are.
So the we have checked everything inside this statement and then this song is present and I give this
song is not present in the playlist.
So we are going to add that to the playlist in English, which is playlist.
And this is our to this mental life playlist and more than check this song.
Yes.
So it is going to be done like this.
And we have added to the playlist.
And this function is going to return a Boolean expression, which is going to be true like this is true.
We have successfully added songs to the flames.