Hello, everyone.
So we have successfully created a file, but then as with options attached with it as new open sea energy.
So we are done with this file.
Now we're going to jump to this edit button.
So creating functions for this and this button as new menu item.
Similarly.
I read on it for the file section.
So, Jim, menu item will be like for edit me and do a cut of copy paste.
And I think we can select on.
So yes, the you can't.
No new menu item will be closed.
Yes, I think it does a menu item could.
We can certain this.
Method to the Edmonton.
And we can use this fact again, space between you and Jim menu item, so similarly for coffee.
Base and select all decks.
So coffee.
Based.
Select all.
And replacing it heralds.
I'll be.
Based and select all.
As we say.
So, yes, now successfully importing these menu items for Java Swing Library.
Now we have to add constructors to it.
So adding this did not and.
For the one so and in to cut.
And.
Similarly for BP, stem cell still.
He's.
It's four times.
And then this place.
Non-human cells, copy paste.
And door.
So select we are so we have glitter actions for the edit button now we will try to run this Soyuz running
this not burn gloves, run Java and waiting for the program to run.
Checking for that.
So, yes, we have successfully added cut copy paste and select all options for the Note 10.
So when we are inputting text, we can coordinate copy paste and select all the text.
Now the filing also has options and it also have options.
Now we are going to learn about the space in the health section.
So for that, we have to create a about class.
In our.
So.
We have successfully created the world class now, Java Swing Library.
Similarly, as the Note 10+ import Java X naught swing.
Import.
Hmm.
So that struck her the note that we are importing all the components from the liability now writing
the code for About Constructor section.
So creating a constructor called about.
Opening braces.
And we have said bounds for the flame side of the notepad window.
So similarly, we have to set bounds for the about section as well.
Let us first set the title for this about session suspect title.
As.
About noted down application, so in the handling of this about families along the way.
No, no.
No application.
So it's fine now.
We are going to set that tighter.
We have certified and now we are going to set about.
So it's showing some aerosols.
I think if we were to extend this class as Jeff Green, we are going to create a frame, then only we
title Atlantic bones.
So, yes, extend.
Friends now, their star vanished, so set bombs on.
What do you think the bone scan will do?
The rectangle feels so.
Something smaller than the notepad window for me.
Hundred hundred.
500 or something like 400.
Just fine.
So the bouncer said, now let's try to run this by creating a main function public static void main
main function is creating fostering string arguments and then try to run this.
They know all about us page.
We have to set the visibility to go first, then only we can run this new involved.
Martin mentioned is involved to the constructor that we created.
I'm setting the vision related to.
Through.
Remoteness not.
Yes.
So the about frame is created in a of ways.
Let us try to run this.
So perfect.
We have about Grindle about their known application with this size.
Now we will try to input something inside this and try to check this after writing the call.
So closing this and trying to.
You're writing how your source said the foreclosure operations said
so on closing on clicking the close button.
We know about the.
Setting this to frame this forum close.
Jeff?
This falls on close, so this when this falls.
On close.
So, yes.
We have to settle down as normal.
Now live similarly, and I can do the above thing, no, and then not by far.
So copying this part from her image, I can class and.
Treating this like, OK, so when we're done this, we really get a similar window.
As not but on the African is an issue.
So we have nanoparticle in the title bar and on minimizing in their task what?
So after ending the item, we are going to add some text inside the about talked.
So for the text part, inside the window, we have this dilemma.
And inside the jail and then we have an edge band which contains some stairs, as noted down the watered
down version.
All right.
Another noted down is a.
It is basically no idea what what this app is doing.
So we have used well.
So you are really using this button as deliver takes only input as a stammer dance and does not support
backlash, and so we are using this as demonstrated from the beginning to the end.
You can see the.
So let's try to.
So I'm running this about when do we get the polls as this, the things that are done inside the testimony
that are displayed here in them about this window.
No.
In the Note 10 home page, we are supposed to edit, write and save text so that it's possible only
when we are going to take input inside the notepad window.
So let us figure it out to function so that we can write text inside the notepad window.