Hello, everyone.
So as far as I can see that that we have successfully created the flame and inside of it, we have called
two function known images and initiated the.
So after these do function, now we have to create a new function called Public Void Locator Plus.
So we have to locate the apple and we have to set some positions for that apple.
So that are the coordinates of the Apple are dedicated for this project.
So initializing this function and inside this function, we are going to initialize an integer variable
which is going to be in.
A random mathematical expression and images called using math to talk to random.
So we have called the random function outside which we have to give this straight and call random positions.
So we have to set a random position for the app.
It is not fixed in every start.
Like, if we start again again and then go and then start the position of the Apple changes every time.
So this is created for the Axworthy new and similar name.
They have to create this for the Y coordinate.
So Apple X is R and their large size.
So the dart size are multiplied by their dot size.
So we have this in our suggestion and we have to create a similar thing for the Y coordinate also.
So Apple has a specific X coordinate on a specific Y coordinate.
So we have successfully created the position of the Apple method to help this locate Apple variable.
So we haven't done and we have to not to declare this again, it is already declared.
So I guess that it is gone.
So let me give a quick idea about what this metadata random is doing.
So common thing is down to explain the random function calls are numbered between zero and one, any
random number between zero and one.
It could be like 0.1 0.2, 0.5 0.6.
So the number is going to be between zero and one.
So suppose the number that is called randomly zero point six.
So we have to set it like 0.6 into the DOT says.
Let us take it to 20.
So next, guarding it is going to be zero point six and don't do anything and which will end it as.
Well, and then that 12 minute past here in this and again in 220 is going to be 09:48 is going to be
120, so 120 is inside the frame of the game.
We have three hundred in the X8 and 300 you, I will say.
So they have to set this random function in this manner that this needs.
If goes outside the three hundred one e that in white or X, the game is over.
So we have successfully created the locate upper.
Now let us call this looking at the ball inside the is in the game.
So calling this look apple.
The void function is to recall her.
We have called it now ventilating the it up function.
Now we have to check that will check that the Apple is eaten by the snake or not.
And if the snake is though apple, we have to increase the size and if not, then we have to do nothing.
So similarly, creating a void function for checking that Apple public void checkup would.
Similarly, using camel case for the function name.
And yes.
So we have created a check up on function inside which we are going to call a conditional operator if.
If not coordinated of exit zero and nine, which is equal to Apple Apotex Coordinate, then.
Bollocks.
And similarly for the Vivan.
So if the Y coordinate is.
Same may have to go up in this.
The whole but inside the bracket and attaching it with her and operator.
Replacing the ActionScript why?
So if the X and Y coordinate are same as the Snake's X and Y continue, then we have to increase the
size of the snake.
And if that coordinates becomes same, we have to increase that, not by one.
This new note?
Let me comment this out.
Like this, they note.
After this, I am going to dance is going to be not plus one notch size isn't fazed by one, like initially
the Darksiders three and I'll spare the snakes, eat the apple.
The dark side increases by one after which we have to call again to locate Apple, like if they're not
saints, is increased by one.
We have again gone the apple, so the Apple appears again after checking that police eaten my destiny.
So we have successfully created the Apple section like we have created a look at that point and check
whether the apple is eaten by the snake or not.
Now we have to set a timer.
Like if the snake is starting to move, so if the snake started moving, so if the snake hits the wall,
then the game is over.
So there is a fixed in time like the snake is not moving for the rest of our lives.
There is a time of like four seconds, five seconds or something like that.
So we have to set a timer until when if they do not perform any keyboard actions, then the game will
be automatically more like the snake will hand down.
And the game will over over.
So the time is like this the timer we have call new timer and insiders.
We have fast operator like 140 milliseconds of time you can set any time you wish.
I'm calling this operator and then calling this timer when the game starts.
We have to declare that timer inside the bone glass and for implementing that timer, we have to implement
the action.
Listen to this more glass and this action listener is under that NWT event.
So we have covered that timer thing.
Now the next thing, we are going to cover Oak Ridge, so that bone is showing some IRA that Diebold
must implement that in an abstract and mental action listener.
So we have to inherit this matter so far, which we have to call override function, like if you on
the basis of our abstract method cannot be called without the override function.
So often this.
If Endgame, we have to check up.
So we will get it in game function first.
Like, I am randomly handing this.
We will see this.
So I hope not, and yes.
So the border that is removed, we have added an abstract class for this matter, and now we will move
forward.
So after covering all the apple and the timer writing, now we will switch to drawing the graphics inside
the frame.
So creating a function called public wide draw graphics G.
So importing this as on human graphics and if condition says Endgame, like if Endgame is true, if
we do not write anything, just a variable incentive, then that says that if.
Now in is showing it.
So let me first import this, even the Boolean variable private Boolean Indian, so endgame had an alternative
if the game is on.
So if the game is on is true, then we are going to run the graphics if in-game.
This denotes that if individual points are this, if I am going to add some conditions that we, if
the endgame is true, we have to draw that image and insert the argument section.
We are going to set it as a full.
So.
And in the X-ray, we are going to read it as a black stand up alone Apple X Apple II.
And in the observer side, we are going to earn this, that this Cuba.
Yes.
So if Endgame is true, then this is going to be the case.
And if this is going to be the case, then we have to wait up for low for the North.
So the graphic will be like the follow up says that if the snake French their are, then increase the
size of the snake legs, move the snake forward and make it to reach the North Shore, make it to their
dog and eat it.
So that in zero g dry range hen we have to go ahead and attaching with the hand, we have the wrong
dog.
So if the hen then is a dog, if there is little we have learn the hen, I know it is going to be simply
the dog.
So this is how the graphics are going to be and I give the snake finds the dog the size will increase
or otherwise the head will remain the same.
We have to do this by using that toolkit function, by getting the default toolkit.
And this toolkit is the Damasio inevitably so thanking you for giving such amazing toolkit.
So this is going to be the graphics of the game if the game is true, like in-game is true.
If this is true in all, we can say that if one.
So if one, then this is going to be happen.
And if zero like it false, then the game is going to be over.
So we have to create a function for game over.
Also now, in order to create the game over function, we have to recall that what are the conditions
that makes the game to be opened?
So the game could be over if the snake hits the obstacles and obstacles?
Are that force out of the wall, like on the flame and the snake fixes itself.
So there are these possibilities which which will make the game to be overrun.
So inside this game over function, we are going to learn that things and then see what happens.
So let me show you that's what this game over function is responsible for, like vision, though it
is being responsible for.
So that game over is responsible for this thing like this window will open.
If that's the function which we are making now will be gone.
So that is a game over 410 in the middle of the frame and everything is black outside.
So let's try to write inside this.
Like firstly, we have to write a string message which is going to display a frame like a game over
text.
Game over.
So the frame is going to this play game over.
Everything is slow.
So, yes, the game over.
No, so that we have created the mission, which is going to be this play in the game over a window.
Now let us move forward.