So in previous part, what I created a trade which is using runnable interface and mentioning, I mentioned
you're in the keep going part.
I created each and everything with the right message.
I'm going to write that message and that message for the level, a possible reason for the WHO is an
agent, et cetera.
Everything.
So I need to mention a close method also to close everything.
So.
Notice anything but this part, and I mean, the latest version of.
As you can see.
All this is done, basically.
Now, all I need to create one right message part, also you're.
Wait a minute.
It is run by basically.
OK.
Well, we saw the close, this is for to keep going.
This is for Darren.
So keep going.
Should be ended first.
As I told you.
So let me do one thing.
Keep going is in the first.
Well, you can see this switch cases in the first.
Then after keep going.
Well, then.
Let me do one thing here.
This is for all with Jake, your lubes, because I'm just using this part.
Keep going.
It ended.
And after that, keep going is ended.
I need to close that training, but also.
This is not at all the question one.
OK, so I created Alderley Keep going and each and everything and now news trading partner and this
is basically my glass part.
So what?
I'm creating new and created all things, and I'm in that part it will that closing part.
It will be directly through that user out of that sort of part.
So this is done, no work or required thing easier.
We need to create the right message material.
So losing my retirement in return, which is basically writing that Bob, and so bullion with connected
interconnected, that writing message error in the sending message and.
So this is all about server part.
Now we are required, some, as I told you, is in log log in getting messages and everything inside
a giant message to let me go with the chatting message chat messages.
Very simple.
He.
Let me import one thing.
In both Java and thought I ordered started because it was very important, but now what is required
things is this class is defines the different types of messages that will be what we can to exchange
between clients and so on.
So let me mention.
No specified this class will.
But a form.
For.
Different types of.
Messages.
OK, then second thing is when talking from Java Land to Java server, this lot easier to pass objects.
No need to count bytes.
Then wait, then lime and foods by each frame and saying what you can do.
You can create and parse that full object inside the frame.
So.
Is easier to bust wall.
Object.
Instead.
Of white stream.
Frame of BCB is really.
So I am mentioning here is I'm creating I already created it.
So I'm going with this, so different types of messages.
As I told you so these are the different ways in message, which is already in text message and local.
So let me let me suggest here.
So let me tell you, what is this basically status for a cuisine message and logo degenerating?
Well, if you change the Green Line, you can see the addiction, the buttons.
And so these are all private things you cannot change this year.
So let me create one constructor here.
And Procter.
Genetically chat message.
And so that message, what I'm going to mention here is apron strings message and I.
Bring.
Message.
So I already created this.
Then this tape to this tape with, you know, who you can assign to that part.
Then this dark message.
Is to message.
So these are all the things you can do know, what is required this year is get time and all the things
you need to create your book in your type.
This is basically mental.
Return.
I.
OK.
No more these remaining two more remaining injuries yet the message.
Get the message.
Written message.
So, David, how are you going to do now, you can see?
There is no it is there are some warnings here, but there are no errors inside our server class.
As I already created this part.
Let me ask you this part and save this part.
So no one ever thought we can run that server if you want, you can check also.
Let me do something here.
Let me run this over.
But on server mean, so it will run that part.
As you can see, it is building.
And it is raining and dust each and everything, so it will take time to compile each and every part
here.
But it's building now.
Our server program is running.
So in Iran program, you can say at this time that things stem.
Mr. Robot is waiting for the client and on board this.
So I will explain what is the burden each and everything, so our server program is low, you can see.
And this time also the program is like.
Well, you know, for their part, I'm going to tell you how we can do this stuff, our client and client
Java.
Again, it will be very simple, but it will take time for each and every part.
So I already created this part or let me use that part.
Most timely review.
So I will explain this blindness.
OK, so what is the message here is it will ask for me, the different parts here mostly declined or
notify us as input for its input.
Its output for that purpose socket is for the socket private string server plus user name and load.
Get user name for the user name citizen and for the site name.
I'm invoking this part for setting username, each and everything.
And as you can see, start bizmeter for that purpose.
To create that socket and put in that stock socket using some sort of work creates a trade to loosen
up server and your username will be saying there are no exceptions for the purposes.
Don't these are letting send a message for the sending message, discontent for the disconnecting from
the initiated exception, each and everything similar like this?
Now this is very important, but I'm stating the port number is 1500, although you can say one five
eight zero zero.
Why I'm using this port only because what is on that boat?
If you want to change this port, you can change, then change the number four digit number with zero,
two, nine and new digits.
You can change that.
Again, this is localhost sinews and then default is anonymous.
If you want to input, you can input that and you then scan it and directly put that in this.
Argument as a true luxury.
The debt limit is greater than three Garlock land use an important Amazon address.
And each and everything.
But if word is invalid, it will.
Similarly, it will do that.
Hello, welcome to chatroom instructions.
It will bring first instruction or even spaced this username.
Your message you make is that you can fit within for all the instructions here.
And I create the log in and load them into it.
Then again, I need to create failure and this is basically that no, what you can see this from this
part and each and everything I.
So let me turn this over.
So first, you need to run the server, and if you want to check more clients, as you can see, I can
run only one client here.
But if you want to run more clients, you need to use one plugin inside, which is basically my didn't
I tell you how we are going to do that stuff also?
Well, let me run your.
My client also you can use control issues often also, but I'm using the following year, so now I will
put names John.
So welcome to chatroom each and everything it will, my local news connection is accepted, and now
you can say who is in, you can mention that name.
So you can say at this time, John, I joined the chatroom.
So this is how are going to create this.
So if you want to learn what lines or you want to take, basically, as I told you, I ran this only
I ran this only at one instance, Glenn.
What I'm going to do, I want to run more claimed.
So what I'm going to do?
Go to edit configuration.
After edit configuration, you can see there is a one dialog box.
I think I'm unable to see here, but you can see a new box here first in that new box.
What you are going to do, you are going to create new configuration.
You need to install one ideal plug in to this ID, which is basically multi multi multiple plug in.
You need to mention the name of the plug in tools configuration to run.
You can see there are two things you run server and client run blind.
You can use that part.
So in that way, you can create your own or tinker.
Basically on these are some similar things.
For all you can say, adding the plug in each and everything, so you need to mention that which is
you are adding here, so I'm adding the client to it and then so what I'm going to do and adding another
client.
So as you can see, there are two clients I'm running currently.
Another name is Sam.
So as you can see, some have joined the room.
Let me add one more client here.
Is this in more detail than.
Lion, the.
And it will run the Oketch.
So these are another blank, you can see there are big lines drawn, Sam.
I don't want to diminish Johnson.
And this.
ABC, OK.
So in a server party, you say, John is then stem and then ABC adjoin.
So I want to broadcast some if I want to get queasy.
So.
What is the exception is writing in general, everything it's been.
It's basically not serialized, but you shouldn't put this on me.
So now.
There isn't anything news of this or exception.
You can print.
OK.
Establish the kind was awarded for no host machine, so now why?
Because.
Exception is and John has lived.
So as I told you, you need to mention each and everything.
Well, let me just stop this process was.
John, let me run that, John, again, topping it even.
So.
Let me run stop all the things.
Let me run server first.
Then let me run a line first.
He's basically John.
Let me run, stop and rewritten.
Then first.
Then let me run.
This again.
Which is basically ABC.
So let me check first easing.
OK.
Oh.
But then.
So now we're done with each and everything.
So.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to run the server first.
Then I'm going to mention the client here.
Then I'm going to run your line one here.
I'm going to run line three year.
First name is John.
Second name is.
This didn't want to go.
Her name is ABC.
So as you can see, Simon, each and every one is joining this room.
This is the John Howard.
So if I would, who is in?
It should be printed and everything, so similarly, you can create more threads for each and every
part.
So let me go with some more parts here also.
So we created this back in the next few days.
I'm going to tell you how we can create Java swing part each and everything.
So hope you understand this part.
If you want to check more parts here or you can go, let me.
Jake, first year, OK?
So let me run this again server by.
So I will tell you all the functions, you're lost.
No, because I heard mention that in earlier.
Then my line should be running.
Then my client one should be running.
Then my client should be running.
So as you can see, I can create more claims here.
It's a beautiful thing for what we can say Java and multithreading.
ABC.
So you can say all the things that are doing here.
If I want to broadcast message, hello.
I'm except getting the exception of my radio station because the river is closed, the connection for
that purpose.
OK, so similarly going to do this stuff and you can proceed with this part.
So this is all about how we can create this park.
In the next video, I'm going to mention the server part, plane part and jack message each and every
here.
So this is it where we can create all these jobs in the for the I'm going to tell you what, this part
also lets some Java swing and you are part of the client groups.
So hope you understand this, but.