In previous things, I created the gameplay and we are done with the gameplay metal.
Now I'm going to create one another thing which is basically my gender too, so I'm going to create
another class right click on inside of the source folder.
Go to New.
You can check your loading menu, go to Java class and mention as name Map Generator.
My generator, so it will give me when new public class, my junior.
So I'm using it only.
And I mean, when you don't, you don't you can minimize this.
And now in general, the first thing I need to create to demand.
So for two, the very similar thing I'm going to grill here as we are coordinating two, very.
As map and creating as it to the Eddie.
Posting first public in Britain, I need to mention big word.
Then public.
And.
Brick, right?
So if you closely this or this is a similar thing.
I'm quoting here.
Brick.
So these things will be resolved when I clear the map and everything.
Now I need to create one constructor of yours so you can use your old insert to go with your constructor.
But let me create it as it is my generator default package.
Well, you can check in row or row purpose and column for column this, which is going to put in that
part only, which is.
Matt?
Is equal to new.
Increase in.
Room.
Gone.
So it will put in that, but.
But in again, that iReport just basically generating some values for map and putting in the map lint.
Matt Lind.
I + +.
And one more look.
For.
And G is equal to zero.
Gays and lesbians linked again, but not the complete zealot looking, which is basically the starting
position of now.
Lint.
Duplass Plus.
Matt?
I met Jim.
She should be one.
So I need to mention this.
After this, oh, and to mention mentioned brick wall, so brick will be quite well written, create
with written brick liquid.
540 divided by a column.
Which really directly depends on this and 150 divided by.
So it will take directly.
So, I mean, not to mention everything again and again.
Now.
Public void.
Which is basically shooting this part or directly dividing the similar order as so it will be reinvigorated,
the world order number of caller breaks that my.
You me draw.
Graphics are 2D graphics, 2D.
Yes, so once I call this you to hear AWG things, it's called.
No, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create one or not want look for look.
With the entire.
Zero.
Other than implementing it is Madeleine to me.
At length.
I believe that Maryland.
So.
And what I'm going to do is I'm just going to copy this point because.
And very.
Well.
So, OK, so these things are done.
Let me mention this if we can get so.
If map is I come up, gee.
Might not my.
Everything is greater than zero, which is the ideal condition.
Oh, gee, not set clear.
I'm going to it see you.
It's you, and I don't.
Wait, wait.
OK.
It's just OK, color that light, which is relatively light colored, it's going to say to the bricks
white.
And you, Dodd.
Be that rectangle.
Ignore this era is giving me some kind of hit it off.
So we will resolve it later, but it needs to create that with brick built.
You, you wait.
Yes, liquidity is what Brickwood plus 80.
With I start, it should be mentioned with brick height, the height, let's 50.
With which liquids and bleach type?
As many, many things, so we go off field rectangle, Oregon suit creating whole the rectangle as my
main part.
Now these things are done.
No, this.
And to do so, I'm going to create that mental separate.
Big.
Game.
It is basically going to separate the bacon game, so it will create another rectangle from it.
So basically can still run without it also.
So in this world testing purposes, we can stick, but.
Very important, whether that strong, I need to mention stroke.
New.
Basic stroke.
Java EWTN three, I'm going to mention as three.
With which stroke is basically no state killer method.
Sue, and you are not.
Black Angus, I.
Black first is Rachel did not know when I need to mention broad rectangular yet.
The rectangular window similar to this.
I think they would do it similar again.
We take down everything, everything is single.
No.
I created this, but I need to sit, but it really also for public.
Why?
Sit.
He.
Well, you.
In.
Tell you which is basically I'm going to mention how much you need to mention the raw flesh and column.
And now in this column, I'm going to create a map.
Rule.
Column.
Music will be held, so it will create different things for me, and I guess.
We're doing it.
I close the class, and that's not a problem.
OK, now it's, you know, now if you would do these things.
You can check.
And starting me for the resolving any purpose, and now you can check that there will be no errors in
our gameplay because I created a map generator function.
So this will create a map and this will create the functions, know what things are remaining.
I call this, but I won't six minutes and not creating an M.A. So for that purpose, I'm going to create
one main battalion.
Before that.
OK, it's clear on and close.
So what I'm going to do is this is my gender definition, isn't game plays, function is done.
Now I need to mention your mean function to call this my gender and gameplay functions in a minute or
two, I'm giving as mean only.
In this mean.
Obviously, to run any mean, Michael, you need.
All public static void may be going to ESPN to be extremely public, one minute should be print.
Jeffrey?
Geoffrey, I'm calling as an object your new Geoffrey.
My commitment or job, if it's something you can do you.
Gameplay.
So it's my default class gameplay with gameplay, I'm going to create your gameplay.
Well, what I'm going to do is we're game, OK?
Campbell, guess I'm going to use your game play with new obviously gameplay default package.
No, I need to mention boundaries of my object object.
With six bombs.
With two rectangular, which is basically my rectangular inverting by high dimension.
This will be the.
Well, tonight, X-ray Typekit.
Now I need to mention object title for this title.
So title name engineers.
Break.
Out.
Ball.
Game, which is my title game.
Are now said to be sizeable, which is basically disguising the part and don't want to do that when
mentioning is false.
If you are going to retire, it will default.
It will be create deformities in mapping functions, which is basically creating this.
So I'm mentioning, as this says, it should be avoided and certainly visible, which is basically creating
a visible and it should be true.
Well, Renee, it should be, too.
Now I need to mention your running function.
So for this object, not state.
Default.
Close operation, which is basically closing operation.
Jeffrey?
Jeff Green with.
Except on clothes is basically going to exist, so if I close, it should be closed object.
Which I am going to add basically gameplay.
And again.
It visible.
And it should be, too.
No, I created this mean, so game, please, I'm going to create your map generator is going to generate
a map and main method is going to load it.
So let us run this.
So you can check here it's running for me.
So it's giving me the running condition.
So it will take time to build and do everything but hope our code is correct, otherwise we will debug
it in a short way and we will check what sort of errors are, what are the errors in this?
But I guess it is perfectly fine.
Surpassing everything.
The beautiful thing of Java X-Wing is you should not be mentioning you or Java fix things, which is
basically WBBM options or anything it will load directly in your console only, which is very similar
to the No.
You can check here.
It's maddening and you can check your mind.
Coley started on this in my ballgame, so as you can see, I mentioned resizable.
So as we're going to check here.
My these teams are remaining, but my ball is not moving, so let us debug it.
I guess we mean error in our fault, so we will take it, but you can check your mind these things are
working and this is not going to do this part and this is demeaning to this part, so you can check
here.
It's not moving like upward trend downward, not just moving from here to there.
If I close this, it's going to me finish good with this.
So now it's looking.
But.
We made some errors in poor look.
So first we will debug it.
OK.
I found one error in this, which is very common error.
I started this fall appear to be my for.
And before I know.
But before that, I'm closing it in earlier, which is basically and moving it upwards.
With this for some practicalities for newbies going out of this.
So it's not going to move at all.
It's obviously.
So do one thing here is just move this below this map to this end, and now let us run it again.
Negotiating, whether it's working or not.
So we look at this, and if I press this now, you can take my ball is moving and it's going to bounce
and these results, so you can you and mine?
These things are also happening.
While recording this, you can tell there is some lag due to some system configuration or otherwise.
It's moving very fine.
And you can check here it's giving me this.
And you can check if it goes down, it is going to know if I press into again.
It will create meet another man, another new.
On which most to the right part, you entered on this late.
This is going live because I mentioned this.
So if it suits this position at this part, so it will go to right now moving to the right.
Now you can check in this.
So it's looking very fine.
Work all is working very successfully.
So now it's moving in that we only.
And our goal is working to know which very critical condition to in that game, and as you can see,
my sport is pretty violent.
You can press intrusion into this uniform.
I hope you understand that suit for the breakout ball game.
So know what you can do in this is as a creating from scratch.
That explanation light pollution.
What you can do.
You can create some illustrations here and you can add it directly.
As I'm creating here a single player game, you can create your multiplayer games on so you can create
animation.
You can add a sound also in this game.
Hope you understand.
Thank you.
So this is a very basic game and created to learn how the AWB things works here and what is the basic
mechanism of AWB?
Hope you understand.
Thank you.