OK, so in the previous five, three have created objects for size and mountainside, which is going
to be displayed here that there are five medium glasses of water with the added so as a whole, this
text is displayed in the form of a string.
But this five isn't the judge, and the prize may have said which will be displayed later.
Like this, which you should pay?
Twelve point five.
So this is double, but still this is also displayed as a string.
So we have to simply override this all the database and set the override and set all the data types
no strings.
So this is done with the help of public string.
The string method is a feature of Java, which we use to convert all their text dislike, whether it's
been by a float or string anything.
Just simply all of the data types are converted to string and displayed as a whole.
Basically, this does all the items as string format, so string format and inside this, the format
is going to be called an argument.
So what is the format we should use modulus to set the the database, let's suppose, for ten days for
an integer or as soon as is for double and glass.
So glass as I suppose, there are more than one glasses, so we are adding glasses to make things.
OK, so class is the answer for the characters, the and these foreign teachers.
Glasses off.
And this format is completed now in the human section.
We will be using the objects with the help of this keyboard as a private global variable accessed with
the help of this only.
So arguments are going to be they start getting around and separating them.
Also, this not a second thing, is size.
So get sites as strange for me.
So now that we have converted all the string in the for all the text in the form of string above it,
be double or integer, we have converted everything.
This is for the like amount which is in the integer format and the size which is in the form of string.
So percentages for this get amount and.
On this good science is covered in the format, but with the help of and test access, specify.
OK, so we have completed this beverage dark, the Java class.
Now our next concern is going to be to cater for more classes associated with all the menu items.
So the first item I am going to add inside this folder is going to be Coffee Dark Java, which will
be containing all the add ons and like the the text pairing and the dialog box associated with like
suppose if we click coffee in that button and then press add button.
So before adding that coffee to the darken, the dialog box was opening so that all the dialog box that
I don't think will be covered inside this coffee glass only.
OK, so suppose inside this coffee glass, we are learning more like an object and quality as me, so
that add on to the coffee was milk.
We have discussed it in the introduction, but only now inside the coffee glass.
We will be creating a constructor containing coffee object.
So yes, and the arguments inside this construct that is going to be the size, like how many glasses
of coffee we want to order?
What is the amount?
Like how much prize is attached, so integer amount and also only Bill.
The label.
Is responsible for.
The label, which was added with every menu item, so we have imported all that, as you mentioned,
said this constructor.
So this glass is an extension to the beverage glass, so extend beverage.
Now inside this.
OK, so we have to override first, then only the error will be gone, so overnight and public.
Public string, those string.
So this string is going to.
Convert all the other data types to a string format.
Oh, yes.
Now, after this, we will be adding now in the next bag inside the coffee constructor, we are using
this super keyboard for this size and amount of the like coffee to be order and setting up if conditions
inside this if statement, it is going to ask us for whether we want to add milk to our coffee or not.
So sure, confirmed dialog box will le.
And inside this unlabelled will be seen and the messages it is going to make ask for is what you.
Like milk, like Thor and milk.
OK, so yes, this is going to be asked.
And after this also the male option, brain will appear asking for a yes or no to this day option been.
Dr.
Yes, no option.
It is going to last or so, yes, yes, no option is covered.
And after this, there should be an early statement also.
So if the user selects yes, then mate should be said to draw.
We have declared this as a global variable, hence our Boolean milk was declared above.
And if this happens, then we can make it certain true.
Otherwise, inside that is Melchizedek so false.
After this, we are going to discuss the prize.
Think that what is going to win a prize of them is so like the coffee with milk and coffee without the
minute.
So suppose if the user asked us small or medium or a large coffee, so the prizes should be different
in each case.
So setting the prizes in that manner?
So suppose the user selects for size equal small.
So if their size is small, the prize should be three point five units.
As if the sign this medium, then the prize is going to be five.
You can set it to five point zero.
So as we have double detected for the prize, also if there is no medium and small, so of course it
is going to be lost.
So we have said as prize to six point five, you can also Typekit as is if size equals launch price,
but that is not going to go.
Simply, if it is not medium and smart, it is definitely large.
So these three are the prizes set for each of the sizes, and there is a unique prize for each size.
Now, if user wants to add minutes, so is milk.
So this is going to contain arguments as true and false.
So suppose this Boolean milk is true, then prize is going to be multiplied with one point five.
So suppose if we have ordered medium sized coffee and milk to it, then five is going to be multiplied
with one point five.
So five and a one point five is going to be like, OK, so seven point five calculations are made and
according to that only and the prize is six.
So I suppose you have ordered a medium coffee with a single glass of medium coffee.
OK, so that's private sector's seven point five units.
Now we are done with this inside this override option.
We are using if milk is true, then we have to display the label they both enable.
According to that, this report labels suppose five million glasses of coffee with milk added is going
to be displayed in this report label and that is done with the help of this or what I would drink function.
And this is returning super toasting the super.
We have all the tests and this it is possible for that to me.
So this is converting the amount and the size of the coffee five door string format and then displaying
that.
So if Americans are going to display that specific text with less coffee with milk, and if that is
more, then it is simply going to be done at five medium glasses of coffee or whatever we selected in
that manner only.
So these things are done for the coffee glass and we have completed love coffee glass functionality.
Now our next concern is going to be that the more that and the juice less so we will be creating three
more classes in order to complete this application.
Are the Dark Java Water, Dark Java and you start Java and then will add similar dialogue.
Most functionalities are dedicated to that.
Also, add ons will be attached in that manner only, so we will see that in next part.
They'll then tried this on your own and write the code and find it in your ideas.