So we already created everything.
Well, let me explain what I created in the newspaper, so I added some form here in this British unit,
which is some extremely pages, as you can see, which is quantity and everything, and then a library
information.
So I created with mobile number and everything.
These are nothing.
I didn't go to jail for that.
Esteem and purpose and everything I've created.
So this is all about how we already created this.
So let me explain what I'm going to do is I'm going to just bring you the deployment in this fire.
But let me explain what is room in Coral Gables and everything is done.
So this is a log in from.
Which is basically so let's then leveraging library and logging, I'm creating so.
You didn't say this of late, if you want to do you have to mention this again?
Then there's all the email address and password method I'm going to lose.
Oh, so this is basically navigation at the Ministerial Page Navigation Home page, then written book
form to form and written book everything.
So your budget each and every part here.
Otherwise, you will get sometimes error your way, log in and everything.
But.
So let me close this issue in a bit, and I will explain this.
So I with it in my traditional thing, but I'm going to add some librarian methods here.
Hope you already created everything, intelligence and integrity, Java, you mentioned everything here.
So let me do one thing is it is I'm going to mention.
User.
And it makes them mention the boxwood of this.
As a password, anybody can get.
So.
Look, I don't want to deploy it again because I already deployed.
So this is done in we.
Let me explain what is this?
This is the part which is a condition of a school.
Always remember to mention Julie Bishop.
Drivers don't see it.
So this ad part here, I'm going to add the part and what this is, this is done, Mukesh.
So this in the library and so we can see this for the library in part only then after this ad, from
when creating an e-book from it is just amazing.
But I written in HD email with the job up to the request, dispatcher and book form and everything here.
So there's nothing but just printing the statements, it's demon codes here.
Then in this part is also very important here, so it's adding the librarian inside this.
And this very simple and more lenient with some extremist pages.
Oh, well, then this is a libertarian form.
As I told you before today, your paycheck, each and everything you're written would not actual content
written book, but you need to mention various written books.
So let's again, then you have to mention fully specify the name.
Then you have to check this also.
Everything, so I look for me again so late, so we have to mention this again, so late.
So you mentioned this, then you also need to mention the foolish whisper names.
Otherwise it will do the internet ears again and again.
So our already created this part.
But remember, you have to be in this stricken navigation home page, also don't don't click that button,
otherwise it will start in the running part.
So now we are done with this part.
Some extremely on Zoom.
The navigation admin page.
I already mentioned everything here.
Then in admin, log in or library and log in of also mentioned the solid part here.
Then this is no longer just for convergence, let's.
And we should also mention, so let's again hear.
Then in the admin log in from the book also, I need to mention.
So let's start because it's really important here.
I library and also so let's not.
So.
And, OK, now we are done with everything.
Always you, the fully specified name and these admin login form or to inform, as I told you inside
the Java, then you can include some things because we already created this part.
This this is done basically.
Let's go to the lead.
I created one delete your delete library and materials like did because we need to mention this part
again, delete library and you exclude deleting the library in a library and basically deleting that
library in part.
And all things I haven't done, you should book is very important.
I value traditional form and it should be an introductory year for the form, literature and everything
that is clean and this first.
So you can directly use these methods, all you can create your own methods also, you're with a different
name.
So if you're in the marching output as a tool, you go to windows and that put your.
And hope you can see, you know, mine will be successful.
Let me run this last few server so it will take time to run on the glass, which will be successful.
Well, let me one groom was.
My thing is going to the only.
Then.
I will add that.
Part.
You can see this is my team and let me go you the aluminum, as I know this is aluminum 1-2-3 on your
noggin.
I'm going to add library and basically, as you mentioned, John.
John?
And the IT University in +40 gave one to three mobile number I'm mentioning names will be four or five
zero one.
Maybelline added Successful if I click view, LeBron is not doing anything, you this, so we created
everything here as a librarian and everything.
So this is all about how we can create our methods and everything.
Hope you understand this.
Always remember to specify some default names and everything.
Oh, and don't need to mention each and every time your or everything inside law library in the field.
So you can see some methods I already created like Siri and everything, so always give some meaningful
names to these teams.
And I already created this part again.
Why is it showing me?
Sometimes, because if you've seen my level in winter, there are four things name I.D. also yet.
So let me add one more thing you can see ID and I'm what I'm going to do is I'm going to mention that
IDs always some default thing you can see.
So entirely is equal to one, I'm mentioning IDs all with one.
And because I haven't mentioned that part post inside this idea.
So let us move this.
Let me make question mark here.
OK.
So because there are few, for instance, are this one two three four five in the library in Madrid,
also one two three four five.
So sometimes you can give it to me.
Yeah.
Second, this is the third.
This is old and this is it.
Then what is the first part is?
Yes, don't sit.
String.
One woman did basically I.
So you can do this also, or you can take your methods also like I'm using get name, get your name
on things not so you can use these onshore or otherwise you can mention directly like.
One here.
You can really play these things.
And again, you can check so.
Always remember have to keep that part specific.
Like, if you created two or more things and said this part.
Always, you have to mention.
Those similar things.
And you have to create some similar things on site.
John Howard University.
One, two three.
And J, one, two, three.
One reason they nicknamed you.
You name.
Submit.
Now you can see why these things are adding, because I haven't mentioned it.
So you can create, edit and everything, but I don't want to change this.
I'm mentioning that you can create a loop and you can do everything.
So I know this is my email for the Liberian purpose.
If I go to design, I'm despite.
And you one to three logging.
Now you can see I'm going to the login page and you can hear everything you just got a little part.
If I go to the ATM book, I can add the book if I click The View Book, I can click The View book.
Let me add one book is called Number One Name Is.
Wings.
It is a big.
Publisher is mentioning anything up or don't change that and remember quality and quantity I'm mentioning
to so bookseller successfully, you can see this will be an issue you should book if I created Calombaris
one student elitism mentioning S1 01 student name is.
James Student Mobile in lining up three four five zero one two.
If you look because you'll successfully viewed this, you look, you can see this is you.
If you want to return, call number one, it's number one zero one written book.
So sometimes it gives the error because it's one zero one is not inside this because you can see it's
one zero one.
Is this and you'll do it in that book.
Always so this is all about you can create elaborate methods, and this is all about how we can create
each and every part.
If I create log in, you can see username and password is.
Not correct.
If I go to the home and if I put this, you can see the very know informal part and you can create item
informing you.
January is also I won't mention each and every year, but you can create such methods and you can create
a library in part.
Also, you're as a creator.
You're.
If I go to this and I believe you can do this, I can delete this part on so you can see now it's deleted.
Then no, I'm going to this logo.
You can do that part also.
So this is all about how you can create the logging method.
Always remember to use some specific names as I made some mistake while giving died.
So you can do that part also.
And you what are you going to do?
You can create one loop here and you can do it before.
Like, I just want to use that loop again and again.
Using for loop, you can put after one, you can put the two second third fourth leg that you can create.
So these are all about how we can create elaborate motor.
So we created all this old partner waiting.
Now we are human.
We did everything.
Oh, then we created and we created so and we deployed on the glass receptor.
So this is all about our project.
Thank you.
Hope you understand this project.
You can build your own on things like e-library hospital microphone.
So.
So this is all about and this very simple project, I told you, oh, you can put a little more extend
to some garden methods.
Also here you can create QR codes.
Also, you're using some steamy parts.
You can change the UI on this also.