In previous part, I told you how I created each an extra controller.
But let me.
Well, with some more advanced in your.
So let me.
Do one thing you.
So, as you know, these are looking back, I will do it or I will.
I'm going with that part, but they're just check whether our application is running or not.
First, because I'm curious about that, whether it's running or not.
So.
Family.
I already created that method.
I'm listing home.
Which is going to determine.
Know.
What is the home?
So home is I'm going to create incentive template.
So home is nothing but the team.
I am going to create so this is all about I'm going to duplicate, so what I did is I just created this
part and now what I'm going to do, I'm going to deploy it on the web.
So if you have seen this on my crontab and I'm going to mention that you are enforced.
And before that, remember what I'm going to do, I'm going to check applications.
These are not very important.
Statement checking application applications, very important was whether it's running or not.
For that purpose, I'm going to use this so.
Let me check whether it is running or not.
So.
Inside that template, go to template part.
Click right click you can click new file, you can use this directly, even under extreme.
I think what you do you create when an extreme environment for me.
And this is it.
Let me mention it, one slash.
It's one.
Hello.
Would.
So this is it.
Let me run my application.
So this is currently running, but what are you going to do?
You can go to your local state.
And you can check that part, so once it starts running, but.
Thank you so much for what application is running now.
Well, let me move to my.
No closed.
And let me turn this.
So this is really extreme there, because it's fluid and sleep mapping is showing here and why they're
still in the home control.
I mentioned this explicit mapping.
So what are you going to do?
Might label it, are you going to do on what you can take?
On.
New fall back or not.
It would fall making you can do one thing, you can check your bombed out, examine whether it's working
or not.
So.
If it's working.
Let me do one thing, because.
I haven't mentioned this earlier.
This is.
Let me tell you why it is showing deliberately because I haven't mentioned this controller kidnapping
part.
So this is very important because it's not mapping at all.
So let me run this again, and now you should understand why it is showing me the error because this
is the home.
Yeah, I mention world to this.
But what is the kidnapping mapping method?
It should be mandated.
So let me run it again.
Localhost.
And let me go to the microphone down now you can see the Helloworld is not painting, so basic thing
is that I mentioned this local news, Jennings that's OK.
But inside the elite body, get my be controller is very important and basic the injection part of our
database.
So let me remove this.
Now you should understand or you can understand what local history is running.
Let me go with this.
Our full review started.
University of the Wired.
Then they'll get mapping method.
Then this list, which contains all these things, which contains all the things.
Well, currently, most of this part.
So no application is no running.
But the thing is, we haven't mentioned any further part yet.
No, we are remaining with some things here, which is basically in, first of all, let me create one
in total reported cases here.
So in.
Totally.
Reporter.
Is equal to what I'm going to do.
I'm going to put inside the.
All stats basically on stats don't.
Now what I'm going to do, I can stream this part.
Stream this part inside the location, part steam board.
Map and where I'm using this map to.
So basically, I'm going to map to end.
And basically that.
We begins to that's sort of the thing that they used.
STAT only stat.
This is the mapping.
And let me just do this.
It is going to print me on everything here.
OK, thanks.
OK, so it will mean this current live here and the turnover thing, so I need to return the listing
also later.
The home park but no, I'm going with this only.
Similarly, I'm going to create this.
STEM.
And total new cases, no, I need to create more alert.
And attribute, if you know, the spring party, you need to add the attributes here first.
So adding that tribute is basically location stats.
Location.
That's.
All.
On stretch.
Let me check with the.
OK.
Like it's going to.
You mentioned this part on.
Mentioned is my own.
Similarly.
I need to mention this.
And by law, no, not at.
Tribute, OK, so and the things I'm going to have done.
Well.
So what is going it is going to create is.
You know this home.
It is going to.
We'll put that in the home part.
I'm going to that to the home park, so coronavirus data service, it is going to face the data from
a very early December you are in.
Then location starts is going to get the all data.
Basically, these all the data from.
This and it's basically modeling.
So it is going to take my everything here first.
So this is all about how I'm going to create, but.
The thing is.
Very important here, as I created this moral part or what it specifies, since that good search is
going to use it.
But this is going to say that it each and everything.
So let me use the part first to basically Helloworld.
And if you want to use, you can use directly the template part or if you want to change your template,
you can change your template also.
So you can use any bootstrap program or anything.
But as I told you, I'm going to this directly on the web.
I will tell you what is the basic thing you saw?
These are the tables, I'm going to use this and it's a total reported cases to open a new case is going
to users which span each earning.
So.
All this is all about how I mentioned this, so it contains some controlling jump apart with this is
the controller for the running, with the location statistics.
And these are all the things.
So let me mention this for sure.
These are some p.m. If I'm going to use, they shoot with the container and.
Let me change this earlier, I mentioned this as a COVID 19 for.
This new cases reported since previous day with total cases in the table and these changes since last
day, each and everything you can get sick country, each and everything state in the country and start
started all from the other data country.
And I'm going to use the pool.
If you know some useful thing, you can use this.
If not, you can zero here.
And so just a tabular format, the home controller, I'm mentioning the home controlling part.
And you can check here and see if it's working or not going to check it from here.
Controller is just controlling everything here and go it alone.
Let me run this again and it is going to first build the project that it will run throughout this project.
If there is an error, you can check your case before you first, whether it's running or not.
So currently.
My data is running low spinning and work is running low.
Don't get Tom Sawyer original running.
Let me reload this.
So sometimes there may be some errors in data.
Although sometimes there is all.
There is not an error in data, so.
Why sometimes you showing me the error because the room is empty, so let me go to the Graham application.
So as you can see, this is my final way it's looking, so.
In different states like not New South Wales, in Australia, total cases reported and changes since
last day zero.
But sometimes in this country.
So these are my new total cases reported.
We visited these.
These are the these things.
So this is all I'm getting.
I'm that I'm getting from this.
You are in Oregon City.
I change you to tell you what I have to get done in budgeting.
Then I created to response to get response.
And I created a cleansing to send that request.
Then using for each loop, I'm going to invoke this.
Then of hail doing this all the stops.
What I'm doing here, I'm creating here location sets with more than.
While developing this or there is one tricky state you can see, I need to mention, at least at least
you can use it.
I'm mentioning, at least here.
Then I created one for each loop to in throughout this process.
And it's going to bring me down, if you want to do one thing, you can change this star.
Who this one?
So what will happen?
Let me show you.
You can run this again.
It will started running.
So it will bring this.
And it will started turning in each and every one second, so it will be updated each and every one
second so it can be done this again, you can check your reading again.
Total cases, new cases in the state, country and each and everything, so some having not in states
like Brazil, it's not showing any state because it's the whole country.
So these are the cases and all the things in.
So if you have seen the present data there, you can check it's not very useful because there are no
what we can see such differences in case we fail.
So what I'm doing, I created one web application to check each and everything.
So now it's very useful to check.
Is there any thing inside this?
But unfortunately in that data, there is no Indian method or we can say not India.
If you all want to check for India, you can check.
And you can use similar logic here.
This you'll need to change the you worry and you're good to go with this fight.
So this is all about how we created everything.
Let me go to the contacts list, so this is our application, and I told you so this is the state and
this is all is taking from the U.S. and not printing anything you do taking from the URL.
This is the Australia, the kisses and the kisses.
So why would bring need a zero?
Because it is not updated.
If you want to check any updating thing, you can do so in the ID.
You just need to require to create three things coronavirus data service to create service in spring
application location search to create modeling home controller to control in each and every part one
that estimate no home control.
It is just controlling the park, as in the cellular data, are accessible for the mappings.
We removed this example in the spring and we created one controller to print this morning here, as
you can see, and I'm printing this return home.
If I change it in return home, you can check that changes in that part.
Also, as you can see, I created this code on all my this I can mention as a COVID 19.
Cases.
Let me.
Sue, this if I.
Notice you going to check here, also committed against drop in.
So it will be the parallel running.
So this is all the world I created.
You can check here this is running.
So this is very useful in.
Why are you creating such applications, which is basically realtime applications?
It mingled with the chrome type again.
And let me read on this again.
Look closely.
Now you can see things, so it is not displaying this.
If you want to check, you can check it.
And another thing.
So that we're told we created over oh, application, hope you understand you can extend it to further
more like in the mail for the other purpose.
What are you going to do?
You even mentioned some search methods also.
I just the simple up here, but you can check that part also here.
Now you can move further with some useful things like go with Ben.
That's also if hospital beds, you can check for that purpose, you can create log in log odometer for
that also.
So these are the simple application I created, but you can extend it.
Furthermore, now, while developing this, there are two simple steps Never change this coronavirus
data.
These are the default things.
No need to change because it will apply this.
Then create default on what we can see some specified names, packages to display all the things.
So this is it about how we created our data visualization application using spring.
So this is it all about COVID 19 replication?
Hope you understand.
Thank you.