But if you're saying, I don't, you know, we are already creating and testing here and actually basically
all the synchronized Java, you know, a stupid seven feet.
And we already done with this.
So more hijacks and everything is mentioned.
Let me tell you what is the jobs he widows.
The nation, which was in Java database function, really busy stand for January to boost connectivity.
It's a Java API to connect the database, execute to create the database, form the update, execute
update.
Everything related to database began performing the Java.
So it is about dollar for dollar.
AC Java Standard Edition GBC API uses GBC drivers to connect with database.
All different drivers we are using currently driver because we are performing Oracle database.
So let us see with this database what we can use.
We can use libc API to exist and loaded us stored in any dictionary database by the help of GBC API.
We can say delete the data from the database.
So it's basically API nearly API driver so that don't login if you see your name going to show you how
we can develop the spot.
So after doing that part needed to log in, I need to get back for Houston.
For that purpose, I created everything related to the register because you basically quite similar
to this with endless blank and everything won't mention her.
With the location, everything anywhere to getting this over everything at the mansion.
So next hour, I'm going to go at this, but this is it.
I am going to create my friend.
So new registered.
But this I need to get registered process for this process.
I'm going to create one try block.
I want to specify these names.
Now I created this new database.
If you want to create babies manually, you have to enter in there on a scale that commands.
And it was manually, but I'm providing this only.
So if you want to create this database, what you're going to do will be the service file.
Just going on this database, create a new connection and you can check for the Oracle, Okay, or Oracle
Tin, you can choose and you can create connections.
If their driver is missing, you have to do that.
New drivers earlier this year, there are different things.
You can add it here, but we are going to.
High school is already deployed.
You can check for that purpose.
But Oracle's newly deployed.
If you want to respond to this proposal goes there may be some errors or some very.
Doing this.
So let's it about all these services part.
But in the projects only we need to create a registry process to create a registration card, then they
will look this on that part and we are going to create one just before doing this.
So Jim, I'm going to store it using this string username parameter to that, I'm going to specify this.
Then in this news, you just don't fall for it in part, as you can see, it is one of which is just
for fair and good, but I'm going to look this one in this and anyone wanting it is basically using
this GBC want and look, I'm going to fetch some data like this.
Select these IDs and everything I'm going to select and I want to create.
So in this part, I'm going to list this as a connection that's really simple, and we do.
Oh, let me show you how you can.
Create a coalition.
Well, first, let me tell you this connection, which already created.
OK, so it isn't all illegal.
OK, so let me add one more here, so it is not building because it's currently under review, so it's
not really going to cost.
And let me leave.
So, OK, now you can not see anything you.
Do your database.
Create a new coalition known you can you can just more quickly.
So this is what I call out is Oracle team.
Now you can see this is then.
I already read that the.
You can check for these changes to your system name.
Mine is for system only if we want to change.
You can change passwords for creating nation.
Then this connection you can see connection is like connection is there is a connection between.
This saw no need to change anything.
If we want to remember password next.
Then select ski mask is over 60 immunity people next.
System on default scheme, so you can see things soon on our database connection is finished within
this, so we don't need to create anything.
If you are deploying in the summer like look, you need to mention the contradiction in basically properties
actually in.
Therefore you need to mention post-victory dependency, which is related to that by virtue.
This is all the things how we can deploy or on this part.
So it is good to get this device, which is quite similar to this, which is select image from I.D.
And I'm going to put this and I'm going to try and put in that.
But also, let's see who I can do like.
This is again, just a few nights ago, if you want to put your for you, get create for that purpose.
So.
Oh, again, to the applause for applauding part.
And each and every team upload image part I already created here so that see here.
And if we want to use, you're going to use this, do you upload and everything I mentioned already
here?
So no logic web pages, so you to blue cleaning.
So what needs to be done?
You can't help but can see.
But.
OK.
Forcefully unregister, so I just read this blog and really successfully close this.
Know what I'm going to do.
I'm going to run this project.
So it will take time.
And my bill is successful.
So.
We would do this, OK, now you can see my diploma and be successful if I could care and mean as my
anger, but I can go to the beach.
So.
I hate to go to the beach, sometimes you say time to scroll down through the park, but as you can
see, this is loading, but it's working really fine that it's moved.
Then this long embrace process.
And I'm going to specify this, so if you want to check, you can check your work log in process.
So this is the log in process.
It is going to use a year long process and it is going to deploy everything here.
Then currently, I don't have anything there, so it's not changing anything, but if I go to the admin
page again.
You can check if I'm using new user.
So log in as admin, I put here and mean.
I mean.
And when logging began to go to.
So here is who I'm going to create this part, so this is my admin page.
So Chrome supports because I was glad to be there to me is the beautiful thing again.
Well, this is all the things, that is the things I can take for these days to disclose your device,
your area post report, you can check here.
So let's see how I'm going to develop this more.
So post report is this you are going to post the report with your about anything you can do when you
get in force field report.
Pending your trade, you can perform.
So I'm considering only here one country and two if you want to add or you can add more.
Drop them in, if I log on, it will be logged from my page.
Currently, my system is performing very heavy load applications, so there may be some things in that.
And if I enter a new user letter here, it will show me the new user.
You can add the new files.
Also, as you can see, this is all the things I can do.
Then there is one discussed put on, so you can do your article.
Also, you can add your your area.
So you just like all we've for the globe, you can use your.
So that said about how are we going to develop this project if you want to add some more different things
here, you can add.
Oh, it's your wish to add more things, but you can see, please log in first, you can do here, hear
the new status, you have to use status and everything.
So that's it.
We are going to perform this, so I hope you understand this part in further.
Oh, so this is the full deployment of the software.
If you want to extend it more like you want to deploy on servers or you are going to do, Heroku is
one of the seamless platforms for this.
So let me show you this.
It'll.
So he always went on the cloud application platform.
Well, you can perform.
So this is not safe.
You can perform.
It supports many languages using this go by the time you need to, you go out.
So it supports which is a basically job.
So what you're going to do, you have to sign them disclosed.
But let me go to the one thing here.
All.
It is basically documentation, for part.
So in the documentation part, you can choose documentation for Java.
And in Java, what are you going to do?
You're going to deploy.
Java, absolutely.
So you can see it being a swimming pool for Java, applications can do everything here.
But remember, you need to install, you know who.
Oh, so you and my entry, as I mentioned numerically, you have installed that and you need to add
some standard equipment.
Everything is available on this platform.
Once this is done, you're going to get, you know, who have said anything closely with that part.
So this is it how we are going to perform.
So I deployed it on the software, which is basically local laws, but if you want, you can develop
on your local platform.
But it's new library.
So we created a global application using Java.
Hope you understand.
Thank you.