So by far in this project, we have covered the download manager Glass and the misgendered glass.
Our next concern is to cover the light good table more than glass.
So firstly, we have to create our download table model glass.
In order to add, like good structures to the table, how actually the table model is going to be look
inside the frame.
So if the glass is created or download the model now inside this glass may be light.
Or firstly, we have to import some of the packages in order to use the.
Components of those specific packages, are you?
This is the first component we are going to use after this.
The second package?
OK, so it is import.
And the second package we are going to use is Java Swing.
So import Java X-Wing and.
After this, we are going to import job X-Wing.
So it is going to be similar, so we will copy this and just add them stable to it.
Yes.
So awesome job X-Wing, stable, not astronaut.
So all the components are going to be important.
That's why we have added, I stick to all three of the packages.
Now we will be extending this download, they will more than last.
So struck, they wouldn't want this component of the frame.
So abstract table model.
And had this.
So inside this download table, more than Class B will be like adding O string, adding for the names
of the columns, we have already discussed that we have a table supposedly like we had agreed for.
You are the size of listing the past speed part and then Spain and after which elapsed time and then
running them and the last for this status.
So we will be like creating a string at a direct start date.
Final spring.
And square races, so.
Like initialize, so column names is going to be the name for this story and the consistency of this
that is going to be you are in.
The second one is going to be OK, so we have all of them the size in and we broke this speed.
Average speed and both of their times is remaining time.
And the status, so it is like this after this, we have to like asset classes for each column in order
to set specific one for each class.
Like, suppose that you are all is going to contain a string form and input.
The size is going to contain like integer inputs and be not integers.
The size could be in this in this, so we will be using like a float data type for storing the size.
And similarly, for progress and speed, we are using the like.
So similarly, the flow database.
Similarly, for a further time on the meaning than on this date doesn't go going to be a string, which
is really be showing downloading completed past error and all of them.
So yes, after this, we are going to contain classes for each of them.
Private static final class.
And in a similar way, it is linked to be an editor and the name is going to be the column glasses.
Column glasses.
It is not slow.
They will be copping it from here.
And.
So I guess this is again going to be.
So we can simply set all of them toasting in order to like, avoid any kind of inconvenience, Sting
takes all of the inputs that need to be a numerical value or not.
So we're going to be using strings as at last.
Everything is going to be displayed in the form of string.
So we are going to copy and paste for all of them one, two, three, four, five, six, seven and
eight.
And we have.
So we will cooperate seven more times and.
And we have done before by six and seven.
So, yes, this is done.
We have created a string class for all the columns in the format of fire.
And after this we are going to like create a buzz list on download.
We are adding rules.
So what is going to be the next time to add new artists to the frame?
We will be using at least we have already discussed what they listed in the previous CDs.
Also, I am quickly summarizing and that list is due to start with me using Java.
It is basically a type of edit, but it is desirable.
We can input any number of for like a de facto decided list.
There is no fixed size.
We can increase the size according to the need.
It is going to be like an infinite size it, so that makes it more useful.
We can use this analyst for a starting like a team, which is not fixed to specify what we can see specifically.
So calling this analyst does download and the name is going to redownload a list.
So a download list is going to be the name of the object and a new analyst.
Downloads will be created.
So inside this, we are using now, not again.
And this is going to add their downloads to this ad and this.
Yes.
So head of the.
We have created the two areas for all the columns in the table more than we have created are the list
for their downloads.
Now our next step will be creating a new download for the table.
So a new download function we are going to create now after creating this item list for all they want
is to be stored inside this sadness.
Now we are adding new downloads to the table, which is going to be like visible in the window.
So we are creating this add download function, which is taking download out of human, and this is
going to add that specific download to the list after which they have to like, set to account for all
that cause.
I like this file tomorrow insertion notification is decreasing their role count whenever a new download
you are is added to the program and after which we are like getting an download for specific a specified
role.
So yes, so this is their table model.
Suppose our task is downloading and it is then.
So what happens after this is completed?
It will be showing hundred percent heard of.
You will be seeing a completed in that status thing, so that specific role will be downloaded now.
No actions need to be performed otherwise of clearing it, and that specific role is like finished action.
Now the next part is to remove that down removal from the list.
So suppose if we want to remove that are specific at all.
So we have to first select the download and then only we can remove the download.
So how to get that download?
So once the download is completed, I suppose if the download is taking place so we can firstly get
a download by selecting their specific role and then we can perform actions like removing that specific
role from the list.
So this is doing that only so forgetting getting a specified rule and removing the download from the
list.
That rule will be removed and the rule can't will be changed at all, minus one.
So suppose initially we had potatoes, we have cleared that third row.
Then the raw count is going to be three minus one, which is two at the end of awards level.
Like we have covered, though, getting and removing specified at all the deleting part we have seen
now get stable columns count.
So we have like a column saying we have eight columns.
We have already discussed it.
So for getting the column count, we are using this column gown function, which is going to return
the length of the column.
Similarly, for the names we are using this string get column name function, which is taking column,
ask them both and going to return that specific index of the column names.
Plus, suppose if we are talking about the status, then this index of this column names will be written
similarly for count.
So are we like increasing the number of hurdles once we are adding a new download to the list?
So this is going to like return the size of the rule, which is present in the table more than at present.
Now are forgetting all the things four columns now, like discussing what actually happening inside
each of the columns to check what is going to like.
We are using this switch case for this column.
We have total eight cases from zero to seven for all the indexes of the column after which we are using
this rule.
So for a specific rule, we have to get all these eight columns like in a unique way.
So what?
You are going to return?
So the case zero is going to return the for that specific role.
Suppose you are talking about this first rule.
So if they select the first rule, we are talking about the first rule, then we will be returned to
the other side's progress.
Read everything of this rule.
So they switch case is doing so.
It is going to return all of the values for the column, things like whether it be the size that prerogative
surrenders.
And there are.
All of them, we have slowed for their download.
We are going to return to Spain.
We are going to return that time and similar leader status.
But whether it is completed or not.
So all of this is coming from the download manager.
Plus we have already talked about this status on time.
Now our next concern is to notify the user that what is actually happening with that specific role?
So, yes, update is called whenever a download notifies its observers of any changes.
So we have done this in the previous part.
Also, we have used this observer observe it will function as an argument for that update.
We have used it in the progress of Android, I think.
Oh, OK.
So it was in the.
Let us check the download manager.
Yes, so we have called this update whenever there is like change any update, then this update function
is going to be gone in all of the functions.
Similarly, we are doing this for the download stable model also.
And this is going to like return the index of that specific column whenever the index is.
Suppose that is the second row and the fifth column.
So we will be concerned about this.
It's been around two three four.
Yes, we will be concerned about the average speed up there of that specific you are to which we are
talking about.
So by far, we have completed this download.
Stable function is now.
Yes, the download table model class is completed now.
The last part is going to cover everything which is left.
We are going to conclude everything about this code execution in the next review and it is going to
cover about the speed design.
Like you can see that everything there, which is showing a rectangle line, will be varnished after
the creation of that download class.
So it will be covering the status, time, speed and the size functionalities, and we will be looking
up to it in the next part.
So see you in the next.