So I already ordered some part, and now I'm going to show you how we can perform this.
So these are already done in previous regional.
I forgot to mention.
You need to install the music app, which is a Windows pick application, which is available on the
internet.
You need to install that, but otherwise it will not run.
Then what I'm going to tell you, I created this, it wouldn't, you know, if.
Which device I want to because I want to give that information.
Then I need to create one snapshot paling.
So what is this and I'm starting to?
It's created one FYI, I will not be get to perform an ad for you, so it will add to my listening board
and everything in this fight file.
But so then I'm going to capture that part later in further and further to the rules.
I'm going to tell you how to capture that part.
So this is just handling and capturing the linebackers like I need to handle that package, so for that
purpose.
Oh, I'm going to handle these packets.
So let me check whether this outdoor pick up or when I sticks.
So as you can see in some package that these are not in these, but yeah, some packets are added.
So you can create different, different things, but I think the files and everything but.
No, you have to check whether it is listening to these people or not, so my ideas is not currently
listening to the people.
But if you can somehow implement this, you can create these are set to free from lilies and DCB bigots
on board for this.
If you create this HDTV, you will get people.
So I will run this and I tell you how it's going to work, but.
Is currently loading, and we find out all the networking devices available on my site, on my system.
So it will take some time to know everything, so it's loaded and.
This is going to provide the things for me, so as you can see, these are the minor devices.
So I will tell you what is the exception for me is certainly.
Syntax error.
What is this index in it?
And you can download this source.
Said Phil, that this OK.
Why?
I haven't mentioned the issue.
I should mention that D.C. people always time.
So hope you understand this fire, so not always do you have to listen to the people.
So I created this part and I could probably really got back into material.
Then I created the Max package to bring that box and package to this new package dropped and everything,
but my little package capturing and everything.
So my device is not currently connected to the network to some issues and networking issues are not
connected to the network.
So you may not find their are packets captured, but you have to check everything.
So hope you understand this, but oh, this is it for this project.
If you want to implement this part on your site, you can create when you are using string and you can
implement this part.
Hope you are listening?
Thank you.