So in the previous five, we have successfully created enough functionalities for adding some, finding
the songs and adding the song to the playlist with the help of track numbers.
We have certain playlists as our data structure calling list, an important link list from the YOU delivery
as well.
So removing that extra part from the import now we have imported both had a list and link list from
that job.
You do package.
Now, so that we have successfully created that playing this function.
Let the facts see that what is happening?
So we have created an integer called index, which is going to store track number of minus one in the
beginning and inside the if when we are checking that if the index is greater than zero and this is
called and operator and it is a logical operator, if you know the Java basics, you must have heard
about logical operators.
So if the index is greater than zero and index is less than the song says, like suppose, initially
we have a size of song says.
We know that we are using it in analyst, so that list is desirable.
But there should be some size in the beginning.
I suppose the list is containing five songs.
So this is going to check that if the correct number is greater than zero and the track number is less,
then like the index of the track is less than song size.
And this if statement is going to be a function even only when this both parties too.
Like if this is false and this is true, then it is going to return false and the loop will exit this
statement.
And even if this is true and this is false, then again, the same thing is going to happen.
So this issue will only be entered if both parts are through one and one on one leg through and through
is only going to return true.
And then only this is going to check Playlist Dorton.
So if both of that things are true, then only the song is going to be added in the playlist and this
function is going to return.
Otherwise, if any of these two is false, then the function will exhibit this if statement, like before
entering this segment, will directly put into this system that are not playing.
This album does not have the song with track number and calling this object track number with the help
of plus symbol and the function will return false.
Of course.
So after checking like adding those songs to the playlist with the help of track numbers now in the
next bag, we are going to add songs to the playlist with the help of its title.
So initializing the function in this similarly public Boolean as the playlist.
We already have that function called as stop playing this, but this time the argument is going to be.
Are tighter strings tighter?
And let me go with this same thing for the playlist part.
As only the first argument is going to differ now, if we are going to add songs with the help of title,
we have to.
And it with checking if the title is same, then only we've been born there.
And the song.
So the playlist, if that item is not seen, so check the song, and if the song is doesn't this not
songs is used to call the song matter from the above declaration inside the far loop.
We are going to leave statement, check the song Don't get title to get the title.
We have declared this title in the song class in the song Java.
And after getting that title, we are going to check that if this title equals the current title or
not, so equals and enter.
And the argument of equals is going to be the title of this song.
Yes, fair enough.
Now inside the statement, if the song title equals title.
Then playlist should be added.
The witness from.
Playlist, Naughton.
Check the song name we have checked before this song, and it can be added to the playlist.
It is not pleasant already in the list and after which this Boolean function is going to return through.
So return to is going to be the.
Output for this function.
Yes.
So are here with this.
Now if there is if statement, then to counter this if statement we have tonight a statement like what
will happen if this if is not accessed, this is not performed.
So we have the out the same thing we have.
Like this song like track number, no, was the above argument.
So in this part, we are going to see a subtitle.
Plus, there is no such song in that there's.
No such song in the album.
Yes.
So we are here would not add to playlist matters.
So we have completed both topline, this functions one way to not track no argument, and there is no
title argument.
So track number as the argument and Typekit argument are going to be that though part of the add to
playlist function.
So as far as I can see that we have successfully completed the song class by adding songs with title
and duration.
And yes, the song part is completed by adding the title and then duration.
Also, the Album Pass is completed by adding.
Methods like functionalities for finding those songs like me have to list the songs.
I hope you have gone through the introduction section, so we have to find the songs and the songs,
list the songs and then move the songs.
So yes, we have completed everything inside the album, plus also.
Let us summarize this album, Glass and then switch to the next breath.
We have found song and song our playlist two times, and this is going to output that.
Rather, this song is present in the playlist on on.
Now switching to the auto type section, we have created Project.
We have written the song Glass.
We have created the album Glass.
Now we are going to create the mean blast, which is going to run the project like this main glass is
responsible for.
Testing and running.
Of the project.
Of the register music player playlist.
Whatever we say on this.
So now we are going to create them in class.
Inside this RC folder, of course, so mean dark Java.
Is going to be the name for the middle class.
And here we are inside our main glass.
Now we will start writing.
The quiet is inside the main glass, so let's initialize this main glass with initializing.
Static void, main function and the arguments are going to be string args.
Yes, it is going to be this way and the function is created for the main glass.
Now inside this, we are going to create a like we have to play songs.
So firstly, we have to earn songs to the album.
So we have created the album Glass already, so adding artists songs to the album.
So I suppose the first album is like the album and this album is new, so we have to add the new keyboard
and an album.
Inside the album, suppose that we wish to add some name for the album, so the name is going to be
like you can see that in situations it is asking for a string name string artist and add a list of those
songs.
So inside this album object for this function, we are going to earn a name artist and I'll add a list,
of course.
So suppose the name for this album is album one.
And now I this is there's going to be inside the double gold, so album one.
And this is.
Like, this second one is the lightest.
And the this is going to be.
Nurses are calling.
You have to select this thing from the side dishes only.
I missed the suggestion, so I am writing it manually.
So new album name is album one.
And for the artist section, I have the check.
In the head.
So the song First Day Peaches Memory, so is the artist version of me.
Maroon five.
Yes.
So Maroon five is like this or I sang these amazing songs.
I'm going to end in my playlist.
So the album is created now inside the album, we have to have our list for the title of the song and
the original The Song, as that a list of songs consists in the song and the song consists of title
and annihilation.
Now we have created this album and songs to the album.
We are calling this album.
Object and and song.
Yes, that these are song we have written in the album, plus I have talked about it, that this sad
song is going to end the song to the list only if the song is not already present in the list.
Incase if the song is already present in the list, it will still an exception saying that stop, this
song is already present and the Boolean function will return.
Like this sad song was a Boolean function and it is going to return false.
Next stop!
You can dance song to the list.
So our song I am selecting this.
I'm supposed the title of this song is.
Like the first song is supposed stay.
And our duration, let's suppose it is four point five minutes.
It is a double daytime soap.
Yes.
No.
Ending this and copying this to me more times than we can complete as many times as we want.
Number of songs can be in finite.
And we are using analyst, and it allows us to run multiple data now for the third song I have to check.
Yes, it's memories, memories.
And the duration for this is supposed to be point five.
And for this purpose, 5.2.
So we have added three songs successfully.
Let's add one more song or better lyric.
So we have created the first album now in the similarly, we have to create one more album so that the
song has some variations, so it is showing some matter.
Let's try to see what it is.
So the syntax error tokens are misplaced.
Okay, so you.