In previous sessions we have already seen be created for Page for participants, I know and admin page
also.
So all the participants sign up for.
We created this page for log in and sign up.
So this is the page for signup page, and we have already seen how we are going to store these to their
database.
So this is for sign up, but what is for login page?
So it should validate each and every person according to that.
So what I'm going to create, I'm going to create one another page listing will page participant login
page for the log in proposal participants.
In this, we are going to pass on your username and password.
So what will happen?
Users or participants will add this inside this page username and password they're given on by signing
up.
So these will use the app to validate password and configuring your.
To validate each and every person's or participants, including this, so this is about the this is
very simple.
I'm using former method we have already seen fundamentally in admin page or admin scenario also.
So as I told you, we already created this.
I'm closing this now.
So what will happen once it's log in is done?
It should proceed to the next page.
So let us see how we can create the EPA Java.
So let's sort this out in building to source package, right click the new and also look while adding
it.
I'm going telling you how to take it to the web.
Not accessible file.
So that's solid.
So this is our vapor page, I can see.
So do you think you're taking all the inputs?
Are you using libraries?
All the.
And this is all about the VPN extent you know about this, but it should throw this lovely description
and everything.
And this is also important for teams inside.
Writing this on it.
So what is it doing?
This fetching the data.
From achievement from this, the pitching narrator from the extremely warm.
This is via username and password.
This is your username and password.
So what if logging deal not validate?
So what I'm going to do, I'm going to create another simple Java program to invoke this.
These things, so we can say job of and I'm going to use this as these are the public things, we can
easily use this without using any object or something because these are in the same package before the
so no need to specify object and then go for them.
So and be and then be basically the username and password.
I'm passing this and this will proceed to participants, even the human.
Simple.
If no, stay on that page using our do not include, I'm going to tell what is in glutamate or also
in for other videos or examples.
And this is olive oil to stay on the same page as for username and password are incorrect.
I will put there and.
And next year about this and closing the connection, oh, Duclos, oh, so this is all about things
like what?
Well, it it.
But now we are going to create a logging deal, or I can say, log in this to validate the password.
So this is very important method.
I'm going to use this.
So just create another method due to time constraint.
I'm Moon base planning this.
I already created this method, so I will tell and I will explain this part.
So inside this source package, you have to right then create devils on it and in the logging deal and.
So let us see how we can create a decent return here.
Our need is just Java School, no need to invoke anything, then it should be Boolean because I'm going
to pass Boolean value as a status or we can say true or false.
If it's true, it will pass.
If it's false, it will show the error.
It is very simple, as we can see, so I created one major public static boolean, I lead it as you
validate Boolean return string username.
Now remember what is this user name?
As I told you, this is very important in this.
It should not be any different things.
Why I am using these specific names here.
So if you know that while creating table in the CMB, I will bring this select.
Toilets are fun pillows and doodles you can see over this, you are username like this password is like
this and like this, so I'm just storing the name, I'm not using the name, I'm going to use username.
So this and these are very important.
Hence I'm using.
Similar things inside this username and password.
Or as often as I can see the arguments, parameters.
So these very same building I'm going to use.
So these are the parameters, and to pass the username and password, you first create Boolean variable,
I'm setting two statistics equal to false positive should be false.
It's not always true.
So I'm watching these polls, then I want to access the database.
So for accessing the database, I'm using this class floated out name Oracle Jollibee's.
You travel to do that very simple thing to invoke the class in this.
So I am asking for the connection.
I a manager in this and I'm passing with your user name, database and password of the database and
that particular user.
You can create another string for this and you can directly put that things on.
So yet, but I'm just passing directly because the program is very short.
Then I'm considered a prepared statement.
So in the previous cases, it's like, Oh, OK, store bid to buy.
So the participants you can see, we get an we are creating the statement and the statements, and we
are executing the query.
But in this, what I'm going to do, I already create a prepared statement.
What is the difference between this and this?
So we can see the instant statement, which is not to execute something to execute that query, or we
can say we can invoke it.
Very advanced things inside this as this store be what it is doing is just executing that query and
it's just forwarding.
But in this, I want to create everything and each and every statement.
So what is doing it to create a prepared statement, piece this statement.
So let's start from below in details where username is this question mark?
So what is the thing between question mark location to specifies the line number for, we can say,
one two three sequential numbers here.
So I don't know what is the sequential number of these.
It can be 2000 also, as their bootloader position of the user names appears again, like inside the
CMD.
As you can see, this is the first name I know this is first and second.
But while putting all the names, all the usual names, the user name can be this third and this can
be become for password.
So for that purpose, I'm putting question marks there because I don't know the specific position of
that.
So username and password in selecting so be is not seeing one slash username and for two or four, the
password.
So it's not like that one for username, two for password.
If the user name comes out third position, the password becomes a default position.
So Java program will take care of that.
Then the reserve set audience is equal to be it not execute query to execute this if you decided to
provide the further or go to for that one.
Then third position, then Jake or no position and then even no collusion or username and password and
closing the connection.
I'm accepting this exception, and I'm still retaining the status as the Boolean.
I have to return something, so I'm ending the status.
This is all about logging the odd login credentials or logging information.
So inside this really validating it should validate our username and password.
So this is all about how we can create participants log in scenario using sign them.
So let us see.
Oh, I will build this project first.
To check whether there are some errors or not, if there are errors, we have to debug sometimes.
So as you can see, our database review process is started.
And lastly, Server is learning.
So this will boot up your every program inside this late and it will through your output to your default
browser and it will show you automatically.
So every time while you are running this first time after opening this, it has to build and clean build
and then it will execute so you can see all the frameworks are distributing and visiting and visited
references, then it will show everything virtual server and everything, so it will take time to load
everything.
So now you can see over these pages and now.
And this is all about.
We created the event, so let us see how we can go to the participants log in page.
So we already know how we can create sign up.
Now we have moved up our differential.
So this is about the participants log in.
So let us go to see him there and we know that our username is J one zero one and password is one two
three four.
Let us see if we put this what this happening.
J one, zero, one zero and one two.
One, two, three four.
So as you can see, I already created the folder page for this, so I will do that for their page,
which is basically participants, page participants, page for event registration and everything.
I already created that page.
But inside it, while you're playing, oh, you can see we created participants.
You were in the Middle East.
Even if you are not created this page, it will throw the 03:46 for error, basically.
But for the time constraint, I already created everything page inside this.
So in saying this, I created participants event page.
So this is all about the participant event and everything.
So what inside this we created?
We want participants to sign up.
Participants log in, validating the participants and log in.
So what will happen?
Exactly.
So in the program, it will fetch that username.
Is this password for this?
Is this?
So while validating this, it will check both for that username password should be seen like that,
like ways that it will execute everything inside this.
So as you can see, we are using Bobo's method.
So there are two methods inside this do both and do it.
Let's see what is the difference between them.
So this is all about good enforcement.
So in case of an unlimited amount, data can be sent to the hidden web.
Inside the post, we can send a large amount of data like you can create in Yemen to eschew mail tags
and anything inside what's inside it.
You have to execute at least two or three on.
You can proceed with further.
So that request is not secure because it is exposed on your.
But as you can see, I want to store inside the courtroom, as you can see.
It is not saying anything your participants log in or anything, but while you are using the gate method,
it will show everything like your username and password.
So this is a very insecure method.
So this is very important who by most method is very secure.
But while using some simple things like I want to base the data, just want to face data from database,
and I want to show you, I want to declare everything.
You can use get me to get a request can be bookmarked.
But what are you?
Bookmark amateur means you can invoke it again and again, but post method you cannot be move it again
and again.
Only one time you can use it.
Request ID. Potentially number 10 means if second request will be ignored when the first request is
delivered late, you cannot ask for too many engagement.
Built in signpost method you can ask for too many post same postal methods.
That request is more efficient and use more than post.
Like inside our world of getting everything.
I want to create the one secure scenario, so I use post material not to get a method.
As you can see in this ad, I use mostly post meter for logging also or store password and also everything,
I used your post meter because for the logging and everything, I need to create one security environment.
If you do get a metal, what will happen exactly inside chrome, as you can see or for the log in,
it will pass Blake username and password.
Is this for that purpose?
As we know, we are creating some things.
Oh yeah.
You can also go with some encrypted password emitters, audit everything, but it's very complicated
programming or the simple programming.
What are you going to do?
You can click just to do both methods to secure security involvement because it's not showing your username
and password and sending you are in.
So this is all about the things you do push.
So what you do post on do get used to it the request.
So we want to create a request.
So we use the poster to get content input he gives us for this.
You know, I will tell you how we can use do get method, so get requests more efficient.
As you can see, text ball much less time than you post her new boss method because too much time to
invoke it and then everything in the Java program.
So this is all about the boost method other than to do post-military.
We have too many things get parameters inside this for thirty nine years.
I will tell you how we're going to create servlet request interface.
So in this case, we created everything related to do it and do it.