So by far, we have covering the contents inside the frame like we have been clear things, the contents
of the frame by initializing the frame, our furniture settings panel inside of me like attaching to
it, we have set the background color to the panel.
Like initially, we have to see if we can take a look like this is de panel van.
This is the first panel.
Now this is the second where it is.
So we have three panels.
This is third panel and above it we have the second panel.
So in total, we have three panels below and up, like buttons attached to all of the all three of them
and all that.
See, four buttons are functional like we have actually.
It's not attached to that button and some event is going to be performed after clicking on that specific
button.
So now let's take a look at the window of running the program and check whether everything is working
fine now or there are any exceptions.
So let's take a look at the function.
So getting to this tried on in Java and waiting for the program to execute.
So yes, we have our theme.
We can maximize it, minimize it.
As I already told you, that the frame is like the size of it so we can decide this and it will adjust
accordingly.
So yes, so we have three panels.
We already talked about it like the three panels have been attached and then this is and one.
This is between two and this is the entry.
And if they click like by default, that equals signal.
His keyword was responsible for starting the game with the X character initially.
So if I click here, I am getting X symbol with red color and the font size, then I'll find a way and
a specific font style, which means that in that program.
So the first to Martin is working perfectly fine now, taking a look at the second one.
So after the excess chance, the chance transfers automatically to or in the next button.
And similarly, for the third, then that chance is transferred to X.
So our tell all three panels are theater, three buttons are created, an action, listeners are attached
to those.
But then this negatively.
But what is going to happen after the click of the button?
So like one by one, we have covered all the panels and the voters are looking at that.
We have already set the font style that font, the bold light weight of the font and everything.
So in total, we have like 15 buttons in the or like frame, so we have to set total 15 banners and
number 10 attached to them.
And then actually it's not attached to that, but this respectively.
Now that after completing that three panel, successfully getting into the fourth panel configuration
and this is responsible for creating like a new panel and we have some dimensions to the panel, some
colors on that panel is added to the frame, of course, for the functioning and panel for the layout
is two zero zero initially jailable and the fourth panel is not actually doing so.
The panel is responsible for like handling a label which is going to contain the score of the player.
So we have two panels for the score.
This is like the name of the player on this list for that school application.
So in this, we are covering the name part like the running this year will be get a clear idea about
what I am actually talking about.
So waiting for the execution soirées this panel is created.
This is a panel created right now and this player is containing a text called Player X.
And this is going to be this thing and this is going to be in our raw and handling the score off.
Lyrics, so we are done with this.
Now we will close this and try to, like add this similar thing for flair also.
After which we will look at the score of Nation Bloc also for vote of the players.
OK, so you may be wondering that why I said this is the panel.
So x count six columns like this is going to count the score of the player next and I am setting it
2.10 to like column in the row.
As we have nine britnell columns.
It is Zone four, the chances to be played by both the players.
So this is going to be placed like this here after the nine blocks so that this a player playing like
Ronaldo will not get affected by the score.
This is a separate thing like this nine and this six separate thing.
They are outside the window.
They are not going to be changed by the players anyway after this, like similarly adding, we have
successfully added banners now.
After this, we are going to are like taking into consideration that how the chances of the players
are shifting after each player played chants.
So far this we will be going to initialize up, then calling it Delbarton forward and New Martin for
that, of course.
Initially, the button is going to contain empty string, and inside this, we are going to like an
actual listeners so that bartend floor is going to consist action last night and we are going to add
actually similar to now, but then we are going to choose it from this side of cost and new action list
that is going to be placed.
So our action is not.
Listener.
Yes.
So we have our listener for the weekend, for and after which we are going to like create the function,
initialize the function of calls.
Now this is something.
We have placed this at the wrong place, I think.
Yes.
So there was a bracket.
Missing, we have to place this here now again, creating the same, but that.
And this is this is not our channel is not an issue that be in for.
And what actually it is doing.
So this public wanted action performed function, which contains action events at zero as the argument
and the action attached to the event, like me are calling the button savvy event and what event is
going to be performed on taking that again.
So the game is set to start in the initial stage.
By default, the game is going to start now without like escaping or closing when we will that close,
but then the game will be closed after that only.
So inside this if statement we have initially, like already set the first player eggs and the button
color is said yes, so before it is said to one initially.
So suppose that the first chances played that the fourth or like, let me show you yes.
So this is the fourth column for the button, be whatever we call it.
So when X is going to play, it stands head.
So we are setting off color to the font and we are implementing the I like.
The next spread is going to play that chance after that that only so before it is going to be placed
hat and I've of it, the chance is going to be played had not this place is implemented.
So we have already set conditions for return one we to be dancing.
Now we are done with 10 four and I is incremental.
So we have total after nine nine like guys from one to nine and already we are like implementing four.
I do four.
Now if as like suppose if zero is playing that, John said before supposedto is playing John chances.
Before we saw that color that will be reflected through the text is blue and before will reflect zero
like before will be starting zero at this place.
Like simulate this similar to this.
Yes.
And choose player winning game is gone after this like more than the minimum look like the chances to
be played.
To make a specific man.
So minimum four chances are we replaceable explained this chance.
OK?
And so you play resistance in the second chance and after which?
Expedition's now the next chance is transferred to zero.
So we have already covered like four blocks of specific specific.
Now the fifth, the chance is going to be like our decider.
If no x has already placed in the column and only one is left for X to make it, then so we are going
to flatten winning game after this only.
And I suppose the X comes in and then the game will be over, X will win and the purple will appear.
That X means congratulations.
So now, in the similar way of everything for me, I have set conditions for Derby Day and five and
the panel is also up being like, Suppose we have a panel of 15 buttons, so one two three four five
six seven eight.
So what actually within six is so from the panel it is not like five six seven eight.
Like if panel is considering the lack of great layout of nine one nine one was covered in the frame
off panel and the panel asked that each one is going to be considered as per the six to be PM six.
So yes, we have within six and after we have initialize the panel ID.
So we are like setting boundaries and then we are setting buttons.
So initially we have three panels.
I i the program and showed it to you.
So we had three panels and three weapons.
Now we started incrementing that.
We made the button store 15 and the panel is still 15 or so, and each panel has about 10 attached to
it.
And that building is performing some specific tasks.
So we are like checking these nine families first.
Oppose the what are the actual takings of the games taking that if a player in the build up these this
side of it in the initial stages, if any player, even then only we are going to have the loss for
us.
So initially, we are going to like listen to the action of these nine blogs and these six are like,
Oh, we have our complete panel, but only six and nine, but those are going to win listen for making
up narrative.
So there are differences.
So we have our listeners attached to all the nine buttons.
Yes, we have a black line border alert and everything, but every panel and between all the actions
are, listen, we have got alerts for the X and no for the O's, and we are choosing the player every
time, like every time.
Action is in a sense, every time we are choosing a player.
So simple action is listen for the player that we are choosing the player at all.
And similarly, wait, the action is listen for we are choosing the Player X and this July there is
a function we have needed above here.
Oh, OK.
So it was created very early stage.
I think so.
Already it was Oh, let me find it for you all so that we can take a look.
OK, so head.
It was so like, we are choosing a player.
Initially, it was set to X, so by default, and if there's a chance, then zero is transferred to
the next round and as X is transferred to the next.
So we are calling this choose player again and again and after which we are calling this reni function
again and again.
So the winning function was taking into account a consideration what this near-death experience I noticed
earlier or once we discussed earlier.
So again and again, we are calling these two functions only inside of the action list of the weapons.
Now we will try to like run the program and see what the actual frame layout till now after completing
this part of the code.