So in previous two years old, we dated different soldiers and the member and his name climbed, which
is my soul, it was certainly.
These male clients client, instead of accessing to the well, not examine, which is basically controlling
fail.
What I created, I did an audition for creating the mappings.
So this might be intimidating.
So if you don't know what is the mapping thing, it is just not executing and just adding this year.
So.
This will aggravate the back and in next location.
This is my next door to Espinal.
It was not this or this, and it is the e-mail message I created in the password text, I'm going to
add my password later.
And in this, what we clearly already created is just.
However, what we can say.
You mean you build it and so on.
Now what?
And Lou, I'm going to add here my email and I'm going to add my passport of my e-mail in this letter.
So let me do one thing I did CC address the address and everything here.
So what is the remaining thing is I just started this email list to lend, but it's we need to create
one address to feel because I created CC, cc, everything.
So I need to create one for New Year.
So creating the for loop is very easy.
If you know this, what I am going to do is a very common thing.
I'm just going to travel through this list using I need ink.
I is equal to zero emission is with me.
Even I is less than you.
Me, it is.
You have that email is few ideas.
Dark blend.
Blend in.
What I need is I would accidentally and Warren to earlier this.
When this is done, addresses do feel the needed address to feel.
Rich Marlin, I commend.
Which water does I need to earn new, which is going to create one new object in you?
OK?
What's more, he's OK.
OK.
New and internet ideas, free internet address.
And we and you in.
You may.
Ideas which let.
So do you create middle on what you can see travels through that, and it will be assigned as a distributed
food again and again, so I don't require to travel one by one retailer to medically export things.
Similarly, I need to great address to fill.
So let me do one thing here who I had in I need to these this seeking and I created no similar thing
I need to perform, which is basically the listings or one thing you're going do.
Or I might even try edge because I need to handle the exceptions.
But if you want don't want to use tricks, you can use your tools here, so you can check out that part
also.
But I'm using projects you try to look for in an exception similar I'm going to perform for in I is
equal to zero.
I usually employed easement, basically.
Because it will travel through this again, and I need to check that email, it is now it's in the ladies.
Because is sissy field not a common field, then actress Sissy, I need to perform comedy in this scene.
And I feel it is a quality new internet.
Later this I need to engineer again, similar to my home internet address.
Oh, then this field again, which is basically.
Or email IDs, CC, so this isn't really.
You don't.
No, no, no, no.
Not because I need to travel to this song.
Let me mention.
Who?
Guess this.
CC argues this is going to chip in what is remaining tenure and going to air this week, so.
It will do one thing.
Let me directly copy, which already created a record because I don't want to focus more because it's
commenting thing again and again, I'm going to tell us after this what I needed is the most important
thing is.
If this field, which is addressed, land basically.
And disciplined.
Is greater than zero, which is basically perfect condition, I need to mention it.
Message dog sick distribution response.
So I'm going to ask the receiver in.
Dude, basically message my get free message.
No.
Babe, I need to find the tape.
Not.
CC, it will add Typekit CC.
Because I mean, there's another former Mexican.
So that's it, and you can enjoy.
Similar for me, he was.
OK.
Addressed to or written news for tourists, not musicians, or increase unemployment.
Now I have to create for me because I've created for CC first.
Now I need two engines for a DCC will lend greater than zero.
And who do you see your message toxic again?
Similar things I need to mention.
Message messages and getting word that you may feel it or they don't seem to see.
And this is not addressed, this should be addressed.
Well.
Do you think?
And this suffering similarly for Mississippi.
So let me just move on to let me copy this part because I need to change some variables and not everything
you.
We.
She
is.
NBCC.
So.
Wait a minute, something is different.
And.
So whites asking me for.
Let me check it again.
It is the error of two, there should not be an error.
No, it's been because I haven't decided this.
So now we're done.
So I need to mention contentment with everything.
So these are my campaign team sets of delegates, object subject and content and.
Let me take that.
For using Switch case, whether it's based on a statement or plaintiffs, so if it's giving a message
as you know that it's cumulative, we can see what it will go with the it's different.
If not, it will take for that purpose.
So.
This is my last question, which is going to transport my main function and sing me, which is very,
very easy function.
Transport, Joe, I mean, not send a message message.
So it will directly handle my message, so that's it with me.
The 14 year old kid so.
Let me optimise my inputs.
So now you can check here.
We are done with this part and now what I'm going to do, I'm going to add my password and e-mail here.
So.
But in doing this.
So here I'm going to get my e-mail.
So let me do one thing with me and my password.
Then let me add my e-mails.
So these are my received e-mail.
I'm launching my IEEE team because of safety, because I don't want to expose my cell I.D. and everything
here.
And if you want to check out a Google free password field, I recommend you don't you just need password
or take this.
Just try to give fully-fledged location of your password, so there may be some things that are not
day.
Sometimes there may be error by locating such files.
So my suggestion is you fully place name who that the password field is popular, then you can go to
base that will.
So my feelings and everything is airing, and this is the thing that I'm going to resume my e-mail.
Another e-mail.
So.
Before proceeding with any project, let me tell you one thing here, you always remember all these
bombed out equipment and everything we already created like try to go along.
There are no one sitting in Gmail, which is basically very common, sitting alone or less secure apps.
So our App Security Security's very little allow it.
If you want to do this full fledged, you need to upload these files on Google Cloud, then you need
to find the SHA256 uniquely registered everything.
So that's configurable.
And instead of this, you can allow that temporary mail for that purpose.
Like allow the low, secure apps for your email.
So it is very helpful.
You don't want to.
I need to configuration you.
I'm going to need confirmation if you don't want to do lists.
It's not at all required on this, but let me check my configuration.
OK.
This is the configuration I clicked and it ran.
So it takes time to run some names because first thing, it's building my own data at first.
This is the first time it's going to open.
So this is the distancing part in the next tutorial and tell you how we can perform the receiver part.
So now you can check it's currently running and reading everything.
So it will take time to do this.
Once this is done, you can check it for the service.
Book was so great.
Currently, my service is not started because my project is building so.
Forcing cruise project to rebuild, basically, so it takes time because we have too many modules surveyed
for doing this, all the stops, so.
It will take time sometimes.
Don't try to interpret this process because, oh, these are not a very heavy application, but we are
there some normal things.
And so then after Dallas closed stores, there may be errors as bomb rotting smell.
I mean, now you can build a successful.
And you can choose the services not started it, but it will start.
So it started building output, but.
Willis completed the first thing, but now it's no need to run the service, also, it may it.
So wait for me in all three segments.
No, my you can check my phone, Curtis, no.
So that it will take time to deny everything and it will, you know, direct output of my team.
So wait for the New York.
It will take time to learn everything so currently trending.
And.
If it will take for three seconds, Mr.
Well, as you can see, it's not any.
So you said what is connected, but the fact is now deploying on my team.
So our artifact is vast and exploding, so it will take time to trace again stood on everything you
saw.
It's configuring everything.
As Hourglass Server doesn't have such forward to do, so now you can check my email application is not
working.
I need to put this mail messages best and email bodies just miss.
Is based.
Mail from Java application.
So once they keep saying, oh, it should be better, posted an article by you all because the thing
is it's not allowed sometimes.
So in the four day thing, what I'm going to do, I'm going to review this and what is showing the error,
I will tell you, is not going to do so.
We will rectify this error in the letter.
Thank you for this.
And for the part, I'm going to explain everything and how I perform this.
I will hope you understand.
Thank you.