Hello, everyone.
So let us quickly summarize what we have learned by far, do this, not a dumb application.
So from the beginning, we have created a notepad class.
We have created menu items as finally health and enzyme PHI.
We have, I didn't know, open Steve damage options inside the edit menu bar option.
We have added cut copy paste selector and inside the help menu, but we have added the about section
of this noted down application.
Also, we have added a text area which is the soul of this text editor noted down.
So then we have also set a title for the main body of the frame, which we have today.
We have added the file open different option to the constructor so that it becomes working.
We have added similarly the added options to the structure, and then we have created a scroll bar for
the text data.
So we have created a text area and it is very necessary that it should be scrolling like we can't type
a single line in the code and wait for it to complete this project.
We have to make a proper functioning text editor.
This is the goal of making this application that we can write in finite number of lines in our text
file editor, save it, print or read whatever we want to do with it.
So I asked.
Now, everybody in the Northeast has a action attached to it.
Like, if we click in the new file, we have to open a new window in the northwest.
When we click on the open file action listener button, we have to open a file from our computer like
previously saved file, already present existing file in our computer.
And if we click on the save button, then we then the computer next.
Whenever we want to save scene, it should open similarly for an exit card and copy.
So now.
Yes.
So the Action Perform event is called here as a function, and it has a radius conditional operators
if inside event is.
So for the new option we have created, if conditional law, which says that by default, this app opens
up a new window is open by default, which is initially set to narrow the text inside the text area
is set to null.
Similarly, the at once we have to click only one button so that if we click on the new button, then
this option is going to be performed if clicking on.
So let me just add options to it like we have.
Save Martin inside the file menu bar, we have brilliant action.
We have an exit button, which helps us stoke escape through the application.
We have our edit option, such as cut copy paste, as if we are writing something.
The main news is of copying and pasting like suppose we have to paste some data from another resource.
Then we have to use this paste option.
So suppose if the application does not contain a paste option, is it be fruitful?
No, not at all.
A paste option is very important.
So adding it to the queue dialectal, suppose we have to write this text like suppose you are composing
an email or something like that?
So we have we want to write it in the notepad, in the offline one.
So we wrote the content and want to select all at once with a single button or with a mouse, with a
single click.
So this select all option contains that feature and about return, which gives us our intro about this.
Now let us check what is left.
We have an open new save button, exit card, copy paste selector, and I think we have covered all
of them.
Yes, new open save print tags.
We have a total of 10 things which need to be action lists.
And so one two three four five six seven eight nine 10.
So yes, we are done.
So let's remove this extra one.
Yes.
So customize this save button.
Like what action to be performed when it does seem?
Button we have already decided is that what is going to happen when you click the new button?
Now an action should be attached with the save button as well.
So if we write some text in the notepad, we want to save it.
So calling the default user component from that swing library of job the weekend, we are going to do
the same thing.
So do file user naming the method as file user and a new keyboard with a different user.
Yes.
So how do we add this function is invoked here?
Different user.
Now we have two steps select that in which format we want to save our text like we have previous extensions
attached to files.
You must have seen them in some of them.
We have that PDF in some of them.
We have got MP three, not MP for like four videos.
We have an extension of the time before, so it is already decided in the program that what action is
to be see what action, what extension is to be added to this side.
So in the text, we declare that this text really is going to be saved as the dot the extension.
So in initializing this as file name extension for it to.
We are going to add a filter that filters that to the extreme.
Tax extension.
Text filter.
And I knew you weren't saying that by extension further.
And in putting a string and saying this, my turn as only text files, only text files.
Yes.
And in bracket, I'm going to add the dark extension like this.
So I think this is done and.
60 as history also.
Now closing, the statement has.
Now, if we want to save anything, we have to open the file to the menu from our system.
So how to open that file, choose an option like let me show you what I want to see.
So I'm running the program.
We have our notepad window.
Let us try to type some random text and suppose we want those saved.
So on clicking on the save button.
There should be a file to get off of this backstop, our system should be open so that we can choose
that we want to save this file like in which folder?
What will be the.
Well, this will be saved.
So let's adamantine for that.
So this is going to be fine, chooser.
Dart said, accept all figures.
That acceptable file will try to use.
Yes, this is the matter.
And then say, we are going to end up Boolean argument as follows.
Sure.
This is said to be false as the only one that the ex defines.
So again, find chosen and choose bill.
Fine center.
And inside this, we can only allow this text further.
Like, we cannot make it as in Vietnam before on anything else, we just simply want a text from the
inside the.
So yes, no, that action is initialized us into action.
And while chooser.
Tuned show save low.
And it is no.
So now let us try to run this on running this not and our Java clicking on the run Java and waiting
for the program to execute.
Yes.
So let's try to type something.
Hello, wine.
I am a Java developer.
Yes.
The text is ready.
Now, suppose you want the same.
So initially there are no action performed by clicking the button.
But now you can see that the action is attached to the button.
So I'm clicking on saved words and actions should perform.
So yes, button on opening this and clicking the same button.
This is open file choose option from your system and you can save it.
Hello, the see there is a text filter, which of it only takes twice.
We added only text filters, so it showing that somehow load on the X2 and sequencing so they should
be saved in your system.
Let us check for it.
See?
Inside documents searching for it.
Shouldn't be a lot of Java.
So there are no fires.
There are some more modifications needed to be made in this actual listener, so action and content.
If else conditional, which says, OK, so I've been this lion get exception handlers.
Now we can see our fine, I'm going to see the results.
So I'm running this.
And aren't some random attacks like hello, everyone.
And try to save it by clicking on the same model.
Suppose I want to save it in the next door.
And name it as hello.
Only a text file folders as we have attended.
Now, let us see that it is saved in the next dump or not.
So when we open again, the next stop.
Yes.
So, yes, hello.
Not be successfully saved.
So the save option is completely functional.
Now for in a similar way like this, try to make this print option also functional.
So for the print case, that is a simple logic, which opens up any window.
Data not linked to call this and.
And not try and catch exception.
Makes think things from the not been ready.
So inside the catch, we have to call it for being the exception.
So bring that exception.
The that exception, it's so.
X.
So they're trying to get blocks out of corn now inside this longer.
Is to get get longer and then say we have been protests.