So in previous videos and tutorials, I told you how we can create some days before year and we are
done with a so laid back, so we are now focused on with just be.
So let me close this in a minute.
So we created an admin panel just before admin panel student list just before the student list instruction
list for their instruction purposes and question list.
But the question is what is there to see how we can create an update to the NTSB because we mentioned
the objects weren't so need to grade average student?
So.
Let me create one job of the student here.
You finish.
So he and his son and.
Remember when you are writing Java, for instance, are this you need to specify?
This takes.
So let me create an update to the news with a list their student.
Then.
Let me show you sort of these language Java Studio, because it contains that object student.
I'm using least your own some.
So let me print your title is a bit.
Done.
I'm using bootstrap method in this.
Again, this is you said I'd be.
All of them things.
Then, student, you am using this method, I'm invoking that ArrayList, then this all student.
It will fetch if requests don't get better, the username for that particular user is if their user
name, which is basically sort of that specific user, if that is correct.
What it will be do.
It will go to the end of the extruder.
No, no.
What is that object to?
The note we already created a bit shouldn't just be so widely required.
So if I want to change the username, if I want to change the name, if I want to change the password,
there should be another file to process that.
You can include in the same just before.
But for some simpler purpose, or we can see what the user friendliness and managing purpose.
I'm going to use this.
Again, get user name for this object student.
You already created and this for their religious children, so these very simple Jewish people, as
I told you, you need to create only this part.
And if that or look, it's that, which means if that meant just to that part, only you can easily
use this X will be the specific that name only.
No need to change that because the student is not available symbol.
So let us see how we can create objects to Duncan the to here.
So let me copy this.
I'm going to create another here.
So as you can see, we have some more JCP faces than.
Our park.
So this will contain basic logic of updating part soon.
Let me.
Use this part of good student.
And this is.
Instead of this and what I'm going to put this.
The thing?
To Ben.
In this, so it will use this degree, not because I want to update in that part, only with student,
the new model will inform this only and released anyway.
But what it will do will new user rating, new password, new name with original ID, U80 and everything.
If this is done like student, these jobs, we are already created to enlist.
It will send that to that part.
It's not, and it will go into that error in the database.
And then so this is all about how we can create a black student, nobody.
So this is just a logic, not very important.
Or you can say you can easily using the average student only, but I just created another part.
So this is very important because this contains the logic of changing username and password and name.
Which originally means.
So this is the new tablets front, so let us see how we can create some delete student potentially here.
Let me create GSP failure again.
Dillard's student.
This part, because this can some default poor while you are creating is.
So we don't want to be in the year to that, we need to create logic for indigenous students.
So let me clear the student part here.
Delivered to student.
People just need to remove that part.
So what we are doing is it's just deleting that part.
With the student list and delete record, delete records already mentioned in a database, and we are
going to delete that record soon.
Let me change the title.
You're also.
Delete student.
Now we are done with that, the student part.
So we just created a good student and student update student, then a good student.
Nowadays, you can directly use these quotes because I already created this part.
So remember what I mentioned the student days with the new student with username.
This if the user name is this, I'm going to delete records and it will send me to this.
If not, it should print it under.
So that it about how we can create delete student.
So now we are done with student lists.
Let us see how we can create instruction listing all that we need to create instruction, update instruction
and all listings.
Operating instruction.
Pages of GSP failure aren't going to create.
Ability instruction.
So in further videos, I'm going to show you how we can create prononcer agreements, so I don't I have
very little time limit here due to time constraints.
I'm just doing this.
So let us see how we can get rid of this construction material.
So as we created of that student part, we need to create a Buddhist instruction methodology.
So again, I mean, we're doing all these things, you mean, but I'm inputting pages, all pages.
Let me enjoy this.
A did.
Instructions.
With this number, because it's no good product instruction operation, the operation in the city,
basically for the public part, will get the parameters for that purpose.
If that part is equal, it will go to that park or otherwise, it will go to the toilet part.
We'll update instruction and deliver instruction.
Remember, I need to create an instructional method also because it contains the logic of that object
instruction to me earlier as a creator for.
Student.
So result will contain all the desert information for that student purpose.
OK, so update instructional.
Let me say this first and let me show this what's going on.
So as you know, I've added instructions to Ernst Non-confidence this.
I will just copy this because I want to insert title European.
I'm reading.
Options.
OK.
Lexi, similarly, we created this, I need to hear this part again, because if original then modified,
if this instruction list, it will send me to direct you do that, but it's not true.
I mean, so this isn't basic logic for that of instruction.
No, what we require.
So we are done with this.
So now we are needed.
The lead instruction part also let me create another, I believe, the instruction.
Just justified on religious people union.
This.
New GSP.
OK.
Remember the names here, if you are mentioning some of their names, it will not look.
No.
Listen, Dylan, this.
Again.
Do your instruction.
So let me deal to deliver the instruction, but also your.
Again, simple logic.
Or delayed instruction?
Instruction night, that instruction get parameter, which basically means instruction, if that delete
record.
So there is the delete record I'm using is.
Delete instruction.
So this from the TV and.
Instruction.
So I'm deleting I'm what I am using digital economy to insert the instruction to you.
So now you can understand why I'm using the so, but if I'm not using different packages, it will take
too much time for the creation of the solid.
So creating this alert is a task for the developer, as you can see, because they need to create and
I need to mention everything and serve that purpose.
So once I created this internet model, it contains instruction to delete record, so I'm using that
method in that part.
So as you can see inside the model instruction to open this digital economy.
So now we are done with the instruction part.
So our remaining part is no the question list.
So let's see if we can use that question list again, because it also contains some Christian or Christian
list object question.
It's a new GSP.
Similar things I'm using, I'm using similar logic, but variables are different just because it contains
all different.
And it's it is using the database.
So let me create and I already it.
Let's see how we can correct.
This winter.
OK, so.
Update, Christian.
So now this is done only.
OK, now this is done.
But the question now is remaining, which contains logic and this very similar thing like.
These only and let me put theories of that question.
And it will create this GSP and square this part also.
Miller.
Delete that part because it contains some default code.
Go to this part.
So I am not deploying it again and again, because at the end of this program or everything, I'm going
to deploy the single thing on I am going to deploy.
No single party will be sold.
Let me use this one.
OK, so similar thing.
I'm using his.
I'm getting.
Christians.
OK, so.
This will import everything.
I mean, importing only Christians, do you, because these are only required, no need to important
before anything.
Option, the option B options, the Option B I'm importing is the answer, then if you are changing
something.
Or questions?
It will relate to this part in the state of Missouri has acknowledged it in the database.
It's not exhibition is open.
You can put that part.
So this is all about how we can create in B and everything in, for part, I'm going to create some
articles, questions and everything.
So I will just go through that and I will declare our project on the sort.