So we already created one command lemak for this, so now we're going to create one solid F or web application
platform using this symmetric key encryption anti-corruption.
So considering I'm using encryption pardon decryption part, the same interface for my purpose for the
project proposed to display, it's working.
But what you can do?
You can create two different programs for such things, and you can display that.
So let me show you how we're going to work on this is it'll be inside a button inside.
You can choose this Aurelien choose endangered for web development, but preferably for web development.
If you want to simplify this, you will be thinking instead of using in danger.
So he'd enter.
The new project will be Java, the application or I'm giving them as.
Encryption.
Oh, my name for this kid next to their server, I'm using Glasby Server Java eight even context for
you.
And then the next belongs to basically anything if you want to specify Marvin's application, which
bring go with this, otherwise never do anything.
Yeah.
So it will create logic for us default, which of course.
So wait for something it will look.
So, OK, so now we then will cover encryption.
So this is indeed not criminal, and it's in my individual testimony, and you may find all these things
here.
Source packages, these things and all the things to manifest.
So let me just because.
Also discarded in the Web, we never required delayed in big stories to me because I'm wounded GSP,
we're just jealous.
So litigious.
So know what I look.
I'm going to create here one filter.
So what is a filter in the default package, you can create new packages also.
No, I like it.
So let me mention one Java package as
any sort of game.
OK.
In this encrypted, I'm going to create a new order.
What is a dirty Indonesian?
I'm going to create a filter here.
Next name address in group printer.
I'm going to mention those in group filter.
Then you turn the nest egg smell.
Oh, and I need to you the.
Enter at least one you are editing, so I need to enter this, so to that request.
Thank you.
Everything is mentioned below.
All three so and influential African-Americans.
Okay, so I need to mention this next.
So in the encrypted I created, one filter filter is limiting, but you can sing all the tunes that
already mentioned here.
Saw this package and delete these 20 lines.
Because it always comes with some important things that we.
Also, just like so latest showing me the error.
Let me tell you why it's showing the error.
First, let me add Library Johto, which is Java X.
And if you haven't been installed, my suggestion is already download Java Celebrity.
So I already added Java exceed my heart, so.
Wait a minute.
I did it all wrong, you.
John Ford, famed for La Jolla, exciting to.
And you do you fix excuse for delay affects you, so it will take you out of this part, guys.
And what I'm going to create here is to remove these points.
I need to remove some part.
And let me tell you, I am doing this later.
Let it be known about this material because this is no longer required.
The right good part and everything they mention.
It's not always working.
Released in the inner cities.
This is the filter, basically.
And let me do one thing.
The not of more concern.
They're to remove all the things you're currently and.
Let me add
my things here first, so I created different things, so let me implement my own things here.
And it.
Package name.
In.
And let me implement some in to you.
Then let me I used your other team, so let me mention these things also.
So this is just lurking here.
Then law filings need to change.
So change it accordingly.
I will tell you what this is doing and everything.
So this is just a filter.
We threw that in for.
With all the message.
And everything.
So when we're done with this, Peter King, but we required a one page order, you can say GST.
Let me mention this peace index.
Looking to finish because in these jobs, very important you.
Check whether your files are ready.
We've not examined.
So.
There is no way Botox, family or creators, so we need to create this framework and also.
In later part, we did our reporter noting.
If you hit the properties.
You learn the idea on the property, so let me add in next page for you.
So this is so late, I'm adding with my.
And.
But.
In.
Encryption like encryption.
So we created this.
Now let me tell you what, we are missing.
We created one filter thing, but.
If you check.
Let me check with the.
There is an option.
OK, so I made one mistake.
You're.
Basically, it's very hubristic, actually.
I haven't heard it in the broad experience.
Didn't create one thing to do with encryption.
Senator.
Next and information, click next.
OK, so now it will added that part in my.
You get me copying that clock again.
I need to refactor this file, also the rename.
What I then it is encrypted, incorrect feeding.
Because I read in the paper economy.
And that's a very huge mistake.
Later, he picked.
Slide showing me the era.
OK, OK.
So it will take time to effect the list.
It's not raining here, but truly, it's OK.
And we've not examined you mentioned the freedoms earlier.
If you want to check our filter, is it working or not?
Press cleaning to windows and us?
You can check here, but let me tell you what is the encryption filter is working here.
So this is just like a backing bar with filtration, but like I'm adding what I'm going to do.
I'm going to create the one database in the jar off label, creating log file in Java file only restore
all this encryption keys.
OK.
So as you can see, believe success will define the new.
He OK when you have already been auctioned off suit.
I don't believe.
Specifying that location also.
Starting my police service will take time for something, but it will work, so in the next part, boredom
and booze show you.
I already created this in the next part of what I'm going to create.
I'm going to create one see our friend in part for this purpose to create one response, response and
everything.
And I'm again going to use.
And remember, I am using filter instead of creating the servlet.
So Luke can easily anyone can check that part by the filter team.
No one can change easily.
So it's currently running and starting.
New York, the silver.
OK, it's looking.
Move back, I presume you.
So for the first time deployment, it will take time.
After that, it will really give you the starting circle.
So.
It mean running.
And while it's running a what is this thing?
So instead of using directly these things.
So let what I can do.
I can create one filter pipe and filter is just like food information.
So there is one mesh in filters.
As you can see, there are different log methods also stored in one file, which which.
We brought in, as you can see.
So that's my painting I created.
But that simple thing and.
So currently, different frameworks are deploying their own work.
And it's in place of employment.
So remember, you have to always add, I made the mistake, and when when that bogged in that we similar.
So what I work on this, as you can see, not really wrong, but you need to create another way broadcast
on your own.
So.
That's very.
Not a good thing to go home again and again.
So currently, it's still working to be successful and working.
No, wait a minute in this room.
OK, you you don't kick over encryption as was working in and do application, so we in this part know
the further part.
What I'm read, I'm going to create one similarly between index and everything part in later.
Hope you understand.
Thank you.