So till now, we have covered everything about glass account glass and inside the option, many of us,
we have covered the noggin by then that's using that type of account, like this type of account the
user wants to make the transactions in.
You know, our next concern is to create a function or like separate functions for both, thus saving
account and or checking account.
So the options displayed by what that accounts should be covered within, they are different like separate
function.
So this public void gift saving is going to be the function for savings account, and the argument we
are going to pass is the account.
So that type of account is going to be the argument for this gift saving function.
Now, in saying this in a similar way, we will be using a Boolean data time for end.
Initially, it will be set to false.
So if we are in the workingman, we are inside the saving account, so north is equal to end.
So when we are inside a savings account and we have not entered this process.
So what will happen using a trading block?
And so we have two systems that are not trained in all the five choices which are to be made in order
to.
Yes.
Make any specific task, whether it be New Balance, withdraw deposit funds or transfer funds to the
checking schemes.
So I think the choice is using sits out for.
For the first function, the type one, so that type one is for New Balance.
So type one, New Balance.
So this is the first choice inside the savings account and other choices that have been made in this.
Similarly.
OK, so inside the gate saving function, we have, like said, did all that type like the choices to
be made inside the savings account, whether it be New Balance, withdraw funds, deposit and transfer
funds.
And these are the list of choices inside that savings accounts.
Now we are like using switch cases for any of the options.
If they use their children, then what is going to happen?
So if the user chooses to view their balance, then it is going to like our full savings account balance
and like the variable is used for their savings balance.
So we have already created budget savings balance thing inside the account class.
So it is going to like access that balance from that class inside this option menu.
Plus now second case is to like it to draw saving money.
And the third one is forget saving deposit and the fourth one is the tax planning.
So we have created all of them inside the account.
Plus, whether it be the savings transfer calculation, whether it be the saving with the drawing board
or less saving deposit in the transfer input is going to be the same in both of a checking account or
other savings account.
So yes, this is going to be displayed whenever the users calls for saving need to draw our saving deposit
options after this upper transfer input for savings.
And if they to be here, then that process is going to be end and you are going to be like, exit this
problem.
And back to the main menu like we have already encountered inside the barking farm.
So this is all about the saving class.
Now our next concern is to create a similar class like this naming class for the chickens glass.
So yes, we are going to that and make that class also.
So for the checking account type, it is going to display the similar choices as the savings account
are, all the five choices are going to be similar.
Other differences will arrive just in the switch cases.
So if like it is going to display the balance, then the balance will be displayed for the checking
balance.
It is going to call the gift checking balance matter inside the account.
Plus, we have created this, so this is going to display the net checking balance function and it will
be just done.
So yes, similarly for the.
A way to draw, like checking with the drawing board and checking deposited input.
So all of them are going to be accessed from that account.
Plus, as we have used the luggage method also for that transfer input.
So if they want to transfer the input from the check ins accountable savings account, then there is
our dedicated function inside the account on Java for transferring money.
We have, yes, in the last part of that conclave, we have covered the transfer inputting, which is
covering both the chickens and the savings account.
So yes, this is going to like our food choices accordingly, whether it be the chickens and the things
we have like covering right now, the chickens are gone, then this is going to happen.
OK, so we are done with the border guard, checking function and get saving function.
So yes, navigating through this life savings account, these options.
So suppose if you were to leave New Balance, then this will be yes, the switch case will be executed.
And similarly, for all the options, the get method is like activated on that specific function will
be performed.
Now what's left like, we have to create account for the new user.
We haven't created our function right now.
Like till now, we have not created a new function for creating an account.
So our next concern is to create a function for creating a new account.
So yes, this public void created account is going to create a new account for our like are not already
existing customer and we have like customer number, which is initially set to zero.
And inside, the tribal user is asked to enter the customer number and like that.
And then like, get that entry by the customer and map it to that specific pin number.
So every customer number will be mapped to his or her pin number and which is going to be unique like
no other user can use that customer number again for making a new account.
So this is responsible for handling that and also that customer number could be in danger.
No other data will be allowed for no.
OK, so this customer number is already registered will be displayed if the user inputs are already
existing customer, which we have already discussed about the customer number should be unique for every
user now.
OK, so if the user enters anything except integers, then it is going to be a mismatch exception and
they were invalid.
Choice text will be displayed on the screen now for the pin number.
In the similar way things will be checked, but our pin number could be more like the same for multiple
users.
Yes, the customer number needs to be unique for every user, so we are not checking things like this.
Customer number is already registered.
A pin can be like similar for more than one user.
So after the and throwing off focused on my number and pin number, your account will be successfully
registered to the system and now you can like use the benefits inside the ID management system.
Now, after this, we are checking the main menu.
So the main menu is about.
Inside this, this is the main menu.
So after the successful logging, what is going to be displayed?
Checking account savings account.
And so whenever a user enters this project, then load things will be displayed type one for logging
in and Typekit or creating a new account.
So inside the main menu, we are using triangles block for logging and creating accounts.
So suppose if a user like log ins, he or she is already existing users to diatom system, then get
log in will be gone from the account, not hourglass.
We have already created the logging function inside this.
And similarly for creating an icon, we have just created it.
So Create Account is going to simply navigate the user to create account.
And after this create accounts, everything will be transferred in the similar way for the logging method
we have created inside the account last.
So this is the main menu.
Afterwards, yes, we have exceptions not checking if the user interface set wrong choices.
We have only two options type one and type two.
So anything apart from it will be like regarded as invalid and after the end, like suppose user enters.
OK, so if the user enters exit, in the end, we have.
Yes.
So icon, we do not want to access any of the gun.
We simply want to exit the project.
So if we type three, then this system is going to print.
Thank you for using this idiom, and the menu input is going to be close and system will be easy.
So this is all about the options menu glass.
We have covered so far, so we have options for everything from this stack to begin.
We have covered everything the logging net savings account, the checking account and everything with
that new balance and draw deposit and transfer and then existing it.
So till now, we have covered all that three glassell accounts, plus the main glass and options menu
glass.
Now let us try to like run this project and see that what actually happened?
Everything is working correctly or not.
And if there will be any bugs, then you will be debugging them.
Then again, trying to remedy.
So, yes, this is responsible for testing and.
So we are running the.
Mean glass and inside this, we are going to suppose create a new account customer number.
PIN number and then redirected to log in.
OK, so I think we have entered the wrong.
So yes, let's check that section.
OK, the wrong customer number.
So exception is working correctly now entering the right.
Pain and customer, no.
Now let us try to enter inside the checking account and deposit some money, so suppose we want to deposit
10000, then their balances changed.
Now let us try to transfer some funds to the savings account.
Suppose we want to transfer 2000, then the current checking account balance is updated to eight thousand.
And so let us try to, as we've done in the savings account, and check the balance.
So perhaps savings account balances two thousand checking account balances is eight thousand.
The transferring is working correctly.
The New Balance feature is working correctly and navigating between the type of account is also working
correctly.
So until now, we have covered everything about this active management system.
I hope that you all have gained much idea about what this project is trying to explain to us.
What are the concepts behind it?
And I encourage you all to make this project on your own and learn these concepts at events.
And I hope that after the successful completion of this project, you all must be aware about all the
concepts of Java classes and objects and everything about the data structure we have used, like Input-Output
exception, hash maps and the scanner in Java, like we are using the scanner in the most minting inside
this project.
So yes, the mapping, the scan and everything you will be aware about.
So I am completing this project on a good note and will tank you all for joining this session.
So, yes, try this on your own.
And thank you.