We already created some GSP files as adamant updates to the end of litigation and everything, but we
need to create some more space for everything to make student content, some display displays as adequate
and we try to question GSP.
So let us see how we can create that.
But.
So this part of this article shouldn't just be here.
OK, so let's see student list first, which contain.
And student speed, I will call police for naming purposes only if New Jersey.
And I'm mentioning the GSP failure.
It I'm.
Defaulting, I already told you about.
There are some default things, so let me remove this part and let me remove this part of.
In one line.
So it contents first at a student this.
So let me create at a student, just be here.
So this is very important.
This is you're going to see ads student because it contains all things related, adding the student.
Using GSP.
OK, so what would convince you to see?
So I'm using the Java as my language.
Let me turn this and.
Two groups.
OK, so this continues, and I understood in detail with by Luis Fonsi, formation is basically all
U.S. college student concert.
So as you can see in the OAS controller, I created a studio instrumental.
So it is different in order to determine support, but you can see this is the front end of that concert.
If that message to like 220 is inserted or something that is not inserted, I'm printing this message
here to this gate parameter and using so I already told you, I already mentioned the messages.
Your message to any student at any message to any student is not it.
So I'm printing this.
Oh, good trade not added, one added for this is the frontier, for the similar thing, I'm going to
create an instruction later.
Or instruction, just be.
Again, similar thing.
You just been so as you can see, we can't we are using just be more than this.
Java, but it's Java only because we are writing Java files in three days.
But you can see it's demand, so we are using a steel mill embedded with Java to add instruction.
Again, the start of an instruction.
And this.
Shows.
With instruction in third.
GSP.
And this adding just instruction with text.
And an instruction in.
Which is open to the instruction list only if submitted purely for that purpose, instruction instruction
and in order to do that or again, I need to create an instruction disposal.
So these all things are similar.
Let me go with this at Christian Christian speak.
Deciding the question.
Well, we are done with adding part, adding Jewish people, so some things are determining which contents
basically exempt GSP, the desert Jewish people already playing in the desert and some day days before
that.
So let me create one exam just before examination fronted.
You speak.
It's him.
Much.
OK.
It is the.
We are done with our project now.
So let us deploy this for the different purposes and deployed end tried already, so let me redeploy
it again.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to play here, Clinton will host.
We close this part, so before this, you should always check all the libraries are like ordinarily
do see 14 for the database connection.
Sometimes I also made a mistake because I never added some displays, so it will throw the nil point
reception area.
So now over will be successful.
No running over.
So as.
You can see.
Well, Glasby server is now deployed with this on things in milliseconds, so it doesn't go to the Chrome
browser.
And you can see this part is done already.
No.
First, let's go to the logging part.
And if I am using Root or something here, it will bring me the error basically invalid username and
password.
So for this, I know the password is admin, so there's no other admin panel.
Let me add one student aid or object.
You can go to the back panel and then check on it.
Let me add a student here first.
Let me add my name as John Ujiri's Jr. one zero one Asked what it is and mentioning simple.
One two three four.
The student leader let me go to the home.
You can either object an instruction or you can see there is no instruction manual.
Let me add one instruction.
Always be ethical.
All right.
Then I want to add one more.
Answer.
On Christians.
That is the moment, if I were to add a student again, you can see this is done.
You can go to a black student or you can delete that student also.
And remember, this is starting from zero.
So you can implement it already where you are pushing that on the code or you can see you can always
be taken, answer all questions you can.
And little student.
Let me add a question here, first question is.
Java is.
Dot dot, dot dot.
A higher level language.
I can add some simple question.
Just be means.
Look mirrored Java, so pages just two options, basically Java server pages, but one option.
Jake Query.
Jake Assuages.
The ocean is.
None correct option.
We know if it was done.
Why the issue in question is not, are you OK?
So as you can see, we have to mention something here.
Always.
OK.
So let me add this book.
If you go to this and the nation is successful, you've done.
You can see.
There are too many values inside a school excursion, so I'm getting a skewed exception.
Let's check that.
First.
What is the explanation that I'm getting here is?
Christians, the.
Do you?
Scripture exemption at 31 and.
OK.
Let me.
Remove this because.
And am going to stick.
Deploying the again.
None.
So now we are done with this part.
So.
Hmm.
Let me check first.
Right.
She's doing what she thought doing that would be.
OK.
So it is showing me you are providing some more values less than this because.
So and what we have in question, people is only.
Six questions, OK.
So.
We are adding some more extra things.
Rations and food options with the correct option, because.
We.
So let me do this for you and what is 48?
Let me run this again.
So you may find some errors here on some.
Now you can see Christian in Israel.
If you go to the homepage and you can add an application can see on television and we go back to the
canon.
And you can create a model seamlessly on a four day one zero one one two three four a password for the
student.
I'm going to go page again.
And then it will be easy.
So once you exit and going to student page, you know?
He's basically student in admitted.
Nobody was already in jail, one zero one password is one two three four.
Let me know in this, so if your student instruction, Jesse.
He's in London.
OK, we are remaining with student instruction, guys.
Let me create this is as fast as possible.
Student instruction, yes, we are remaining with one dispatcher told Do Student gives me instruction
to use speak because it should show the force through student instruction to use.
Looking Chick.
It's done.
And broke those.
OK, I will click finish.
I told you, like there are some errors when deploying this.
Remember, you have to check each and every team before deploying.
So as I told you, I'm remaining with this.
Let's just clear this.
So this is very simple GSP.
And just check again, one, two, three, four million.
Oh, it is not really.
OK.
As I just screamed, let me be deployed again, our server.
So sometimes it takes time to deploy it, all things will go fast in this.
So let me go to the student blogging page.
Given one.
One, two, three, four villages and logging.
Student instructions.
OK, the thing is that I made some errors.
Let me remove this first.
Yes.
What?
I made some errors is a file name is this let me copy this because I won't include this findings service.
Then.
Let me do this.
Just.
Mitch?
The you this despite.
So as I told you, you have to always remember weird, all finds you mention.
And let me really apply myself in.
I mean, look this.
We learn.
Now you can see welcome, John, always vertical our instructions.
If I could start based here.
You can or you can see your options on and before, you know, if I put Java solid business.
Some.
Questions is wrong answers.
John, you the result is pending.
So this is all about how we created our Aegis and Student-Run.
So this is very simple.
If I go to again.
And if I'm going to one, two, three four.
Start inside, I'm going to break and starting this security again, if I put these security is going
to be this and wrong answer.
This correct answer is zero and spending the holidays.
So this is a very simple thing.
You can add a more and more questions here, but I certainly.