So now we are fully developed with our code.
So I will explain what I'm going to do.
So consider these all the libraries I'm going to use.
But instead of these, I created one class, which is an immense public class server.
So by creating any application, client and server part are very important.
So what is for getting all the part of your client in our chat system?
So client is going to attach with server and through the server, we are going to send the message.
That's the basic thing we are going to see here.
So first, I'm creating your vector using this syntax.
So I will tell you what is the function here?
So Vector is going to hold the instance of all the classes with the handlers.
So I'm creating your static vectors, which client handler?
You can schedule the object, which is reasonable.
I will tell you, you can take your two classes, know this and extends to object, and I'm giving the
names sockets.
So Socrates is just like electrical sockets.
Client is going to attach judicial and mentioning azure sockets, and I want to run any method in order
for the running purposes we need method, which is main method to running the list over which is going
to total input output exception that took common exception.
We can find in silver until then.
Server socket is I'm creating your socket, which server socket.
So you may ask me, like, what is this server socket?
So it is basically J1 dot net package.
We can use zero, which is the default package in Java, and you can use your server socket.
Then I'm giving you that I'm going to little increment it later because I need to name the plans ideas
as when we incrementing.
So I'm currently giving as a zero.
Then it will print, build common ground or console that it's waiting for connection.
Our server is waiting for client connection.
No current plan count is depends on socket size.
If while two is basically being in the of role for not opening police officer, there is always true.
So Server will always exert life on the network.
So I'm considering network as not the internet, it's a network I'm considering.
It's a loop of networks.
I'm what is always louder then.
For that purpose, I'm giving the way to then.
What is the significance between this system, dot dot print and what is this thing?
So basically current Glenn Count, I'm giving as a shock.
It's not safe.
So as it says our vector, which is released here, I'm using it as a list year so we can use this as
the defining look lenses, then socket connection.
I'm creating connection as object and which is going to accept the clients.
Then client IDs is going to plus one, which is basically I'm adding the client IDs your.
Then print writer, I'm using your print reader output to get output as the output stream, connection
output stream with then input stream, I'm going to create your which is buffer reader because lines
need to input and output both things.
So I need to mention that then this is Glenn Handler is going to hold some defaults, which basically
Line NIM connection is basically able to accept connection output, base for output stream and inputs
for input stream.
Then Add is basically I'm going to add the client and you may ask What is this?
The client look, and I created your trade and I'm starting the trip.
So why I'm so we're currently I'm deploying on local, so I'm going to specific lengths on my own.
I'm not going to disclose it later, like I'm not going to know I'm going to choose only my own clients
as my for this deployment.
But working on current systems of MultiJet systems, you can assume that new client wants to get connection
to the server at the same time.
Like, if you call someone, you may get busy, but while you check system, you should not get that
busy calls in the server part.
So for that purpose, we need to create trade.
So each client connection will be handling by a thread.
So there is basically a small part of the process.
I told you earlier, and I'm going to start here.
So this is just part of connection, but I need to print it out as a client handler, methods and everything.
So this is just for close streams and everything I created, but or for that purpose is what I'm going
to create.
I'm going to create a public run method to create one re-enable interface.
So again, we try and catch block.
I'm going to accept the exceptions.
But in the wild, true, I'm accepting the message with two this--you method and the is basically input
dot ruling, which is basically input, cinematic and plant and let again the connection.
And I'm mentioning as this is my construct of Alkaline Handler.
And this is for the animal interface is going to class, it's going to use here.
And for that purpose, I created this.
This is done with the server part.
So remember why you're giving the server?
This is your server.
I'm mentioning as 2020 as my server.
No.
Let us see what is the client here.
So forget about all these things and let us see what I'm going to do.
So in Bakersfield, I'm going to use our text chat window and we're going to mention I mentioned your
two friends if when and if if we need to just put in the name.
And if Cruz's full message connection and everything I'm going to specify, then I'm creating your first
set up with DreamHost as argument.
Then if Lenny's new frame, which server host and I'm going to assign it, so no, I created your GITEX
studio text field with the button and everything I explained to you, and I'm just giving a recap for
this.
Then I created to get a bottom panel and everything.
Oh, and bottom penalties for the bottom purpose.
I'm giving the bottom panel button on there for accepting the connections and everything.
Now let us see how we can run this.
So running is very easy as part yet.
So first is, I'm going to bring my server so.
For any purpose you need to run for server, then you can run lines.
So I'm not currently running my server.
So we'll wait for some time, it will be and it will deployments over.
Again, sort of what he's always like.
So it will accept connection at any time, like I'm not giving any or this time they took time to sort
of work, so it will not at all stop for anything and so it will always accept the claims.
So it's building, sometimes it may take time to build everything.
So it will take the resources and it will take everything depends on your system speed.
Without any like line mentors whatsoever, mentors who can not run any direct mentors like.
Well, so what needs to deploy force on your system or you can take on your local host?
So normally successful, my will be successful and you can take surveys waiting for connection and current
plan can be zero.
That's usual.
I haven't created any client, you know, listening to my client.
And let me run blind.
And so if you're going to care, I'm going to run my client, which is client start running.
I will tell you, what is this post later?
But if I am currently running on my local horse, so there is no errors I'm not getting because it's
a direct part.
So now you can check.
Currently, my lease is running and this is my.
A blank check system, so I'm mentioning as a B C as my name, and I'm submitting it so it will open
me on the next things.
So this is my client one, and if I pressed high here, so ABC will be I know why it is mismatch, I
will tell you and what I'm getting your error.
It will run on your local host.
No problem.
But the thing is, I'm mentioning as my defaulting, so you can check here if I run again, it will
be another clamshell.
Currently, it's giving me the error because of this post, because I mentioned the host 60 kb in Europe.
And what is this?
I will tell you.
But the thing is, my client is not running on local host.
It is running on some another interface.
And this is my server, which is running on student client is not connected, actually.
So that's the error in my program.
So how I'm going to use that because creating on a local machine, it's not a very useful case for multi-threaded
system connection between establishing between two systems or you're between two friends chatting with
two friends is the full approach of this.
So let me stop all the processes here currently.
So it is getting stopped and you can check your link.
Let me stop this also do just about anything.
And no one stopped.
So what is this, I will tell you?
So in judokas of service, you can check your in Europe is a free service, which is useful to form
through your network or for your local news on the internet.
So it's a local like exposing your local host on the internet, but it's a security and it's not like
any cyber security bubble.
It is very secure and directing, and you can connect to services and you can establish the connections
from anyone.
So I downloaded it for my system, which is basically for windows.
I'm downloading it.
You can unzip and you can use different things, or you can sign up also to your ideas and log in with
your attorneys and you can pass your token on tool.
So let me move in this and let me show you how the in Europe is going to work.
So this is the new document.
Once you open so you can check your different, different boards are giving your examples already given
FTP, then TCP also given.
So my protocol is TCP PCB, which is I'm going to use your PCB traffic to handle TCP traffic.
And what is my port?
It's basically 2020, my server port readiness.
So let me mention this command.
Indie-Rock PCB 2020.
So sometimes what I think I forgot is basically all.
I haven't mentioned that or two or three things, so let me open in Europe again.
So it will accept.
My team looking when it again, because I haven't mentioned the inaugural not easy BCB.
And 20, 20.
So.
OK, so I'm getting the error as in Europe and a local port is not available for.
Let me open it again and.
Let me check it again.
In judo.
DCB going deep.
Twenty.
OK.
No, my story is low, you can check here my server is low.
So this is the web interface.
You can check it later.
But what we required, we require this line.
So this is my TCP IP protocol, then this is my host.
I will I this is my host and this is my code.
So now what I'm going to do is I'm just going to copy this part.
You can copy my control here.
You can copy this, go to your ID.
You need to make changes to client only.
Let me put it down this, so I will use it later.
Copy paste.
So I will use it later.
Let me comment on this.
So it not useful.
OK, so what we need to declare, we need to paste this six to this six, so it will start all of it.
So I already mentioned you six only.
So I need to check this portable and let me copy this.
And you need to mention about that, about the port, as I told you, you need to change the port about.
So let me check, where is that all?
OK, so in the void, connect to server, oh, I need to change the board, which I got, which is.
Basically, this food, you can dig your baby interface and you going check for that purpose also.
But for me, it's going to work.
Oh, and now we are done.
Now we are done.
And now what I'm going to do is, as I told you, I need to run my server first.
When my server is running one 2020 port with the local host, what it will be doing in Utah and Utah
will love that localhost 2020 server request to that client part, which is basically to this.
To this, it will pull up, and no, my client is not connected to this.
So basically, server is running on my machine, but or it is connected to my machine, to my machine
is act as a server part, but the client is not on my server.
So let me do one thing here and the client part.
Let me run this and let me show you how I.
I'm going to use it.
So this is my client I'm going to use.
You and which is I'm going to using currently running currently click so it will take time to build
once it is fully built, it will render and and it will deploy me one window, as you can see here.
So this is my window and let me mention his name ABC here and let me submit it.
So now you can get connected to this IP, which is basically.
This port, this IP a.m. connected connection.
And let me mention as high.
Now, you cannot see your any messages like there is no error.
This is my blog.
But if I go to RentPath and if I go to Server Park, you can check my gland when it's connected.
So I want to connect another client on my son's team.
Only you can check with your friends so you can connect between two friends.
But I need to do blood on my machine.
For that instance, I need to read the configuration.
Yeah, if you want to check, you need to install one plugin in Algeria, which is my patron plugin.
So go to plus icon in order and debug configuration.
Then or go to download and check for my PSN as I'm doing here, my Deran letting them give the name
as.
Client one.
This is my client.
Let me add one thing, Ron Plank, which is my method, or don't give anything after launch and click
apply.
And he took so in this.
Now you can take this is my main methods, but this is my material.
So what we do is we do it will create and unedited instances for a client, and it will call that.
So you can.
The basic purpose of these things, I can use another window.
So currently in this, you can check this is my ABC.
And this is my another window, which is I'm going giving the name x y z.
And I'm entering this.
Now, what do you think?
If I am put in here by, you can check your exposure to the police printing, printing by if I'm printing
here high X, Y and Z, you can check I'm getting high x z another.
So this is my x y z and this is my ABC window.
And in the server listing, you can check the client code.
So.
So what is basically giving, not giving?
They need you, but please, because it's command line interface, just but for the clients, I created
one.