So in previous scene, we found one error and error is related to Java e-vapor application.
So my suggestion is, ah, this dependency in Java API that you'd known there is no other errors and
these very similar things are created a new ticking.
So let me move on to it and close these things because we are already seeing these things.
So what I changed now I changed to treating.
Should I need one involves just feet to create one in now.
What do you mean I'm using?
I'm new venues for treating.
Also here.
So I told you, creating the embossing is complicated because you need to handle with the file extension
and everything.
So creating in walks is legal team using Java.
Other than this, you can use sort of these verbal javascript is very useful, but it always not very
common thing.
So I created this.
It's very similar, I added.
Some would say file using case file, and I need this for these four words.
I need my listing, which is me limiting, and I'm passing the file name for my email and everything
I'm doing here.
And bullfighter, I'm acting is just music I imagine is missing in an increased use element mining and
the password learning protocol is outdated, don't you?
I read the horse to Centipede is deceased and I'm going to his to my urine.
Now, I don't want to specify the more detailed thing here.
I just go with some booty old images, not new ones in my inbox.
But oh, let me show you how we can forcefully do this in these.
And previously I bought either.
And that error is regarding to so now I rectified that error.
And let me show you this email you deleted also.
I changed a little bit, which is basically thing and email client also.
Or I have one link I never mentioned, but this thing which is basically overloading team where I'm
loading the overload with GDP so late.
So no need to choose anything yet.
Just this because I didn't my independency.
So you do in boxing.
So you need to do this thing, whether these are upended or overrated or not.
If not, you have to write it again.
Manually select one error I rectified.
I changed.
Email utility.
You did not really deeply.
And it delivered some variables.
I changed.
Oh, then let me do one thing here.
Look, you start to optimize imports like optimizing imports is a good thing to do because I don't want
to spend that much time this year.
And it's OK now I can remove all these things directly.
It's no longer required.
So I created this.
Now it's time to test it.
So testing is very easy.
We'll do any configuration for you and.
One required thing is, Jake, you're you're a Tomcat server who told him to call my bootloader and
also not use, so I'm using this.
And similar to what I'm going to this, so it will take time to build and performing the actions while
building, you can keep these.
So let me show you what it's doing, all these things and it's sexism going on, compiling everything.
So new ideas to do these things while regularly developing this app, you need to add some application
things and maybe independency.
Also, you can add to your database on.
So now you can take this, and I don't get sort of what is an old building successful, as you can see,
will be successful in 13 seconds completed and the service is running.
So you can add, oh, you have to add some dependencies here in 1.6million to perform every actions
that PostgreSQL he took.
You have also providing the was this girl dependency, and you can perform these applications directly
using this.
So.
Let me show this is my e-mail application, if you know this.
And.
Let me show you all these things.
So.
So this is my e-mail, basically, and we are going to review this and this is my email application,
so let me send this is my main test.
Let me put this in my best.
Application mean.
So you can add as many as we want, you can use that things are small and to send here, so it will
take time to perform actions.
While performing actions, you can take all the actions in your dorm, get local or server their log
where you can find that it's connecting or not.
So let me show you one thing.
You can check your roots adding and doing deals and everything it's doing cloakroom.
So.
You can check my emails sent successfully.
Let me reload this.
So it's lowering them, and you can check on my email I received.
So this is my another e-mail I use for the temporary connection and everything.
You can use any other thing and can work as many people.
So let me put this.
And so this might establish and now it's working.
So let me show you how I created that.
Another thing?
Even then, the spirituality you with this, OK?
So this in my inbox and everything I read and you can check mail has been saved successfully.
You can change the look of results.
So let me go to the box.
So Inbox is not very performed.
I created I just created as a prototype here for you to time constraints.
So I added some things here.
So this is my old tenacity, not new thing.
I'm facing this very old thing.
I was eating all the e-mails and editing and not telling everything here.
So lengthways this, you can create your own inbox.
You can hear different things like contacts you can search through.
I created this also using the steam so you can click on this.
So this is a tool you can perform.
And as I told you, I had assumed that me, but you can check your losing connection.
They seem to be sober where I am accessing what I'm doing.
You can check everything and you can check what you're passing and everything information from you.
Hope you understand.
Oh, thank you.
And or you can go to more extended to most professional thing because this is not just isolated from
what you can do now.
You can extend it more and you can build your own API team as you can create API values mostly used
for APIs.
You can create your own API microservices for this in the Nordics in May, which is basically properties,
properties, Immelt's.
You can perform these actions directly.
So let me show you on the Nordics and then we were living on location.
This is my home of experiment or
this is my bond of excitement.
Oh, so what are you going to do instead of adding your own email artifact?
It is different.
So.
OK, now this is done.
Now we are going to go with this point or symbol.
So you need to action do three things here.
While developing on the server, you need to add a Lynnfield wound up your API.
These things again and again, plus all you need to create one more thing to add database because this
is limited to only one user.
But when they were looking for company out of industry, you need to find data from the database console.
So that's very easy.
You can use the exclusive means directly there.
So next, sift and hope you understand.
Thank you.