So in further cases, I don't see how we can create event and everything.
So no, I will go with those some fast methods I'm going to tell you.
So for them, these all in, we're completely in for the admin part or the version of events and everything
inside this, I'm going to deploy all things or as I told you, so first, we need to create the registration
of our participants.
First entry, I'm going to create one instrument registered instrument, so as I don't do that in the
partnership participants even.
There is one view event.
So let us deal with the View event or I don't want to go to the extreme, but I want to display everything
inside the job only.
I'm going to create every form the starting instrument tagged with the ending of the body.
I want to create and display the instrument based through the job, only for that purpose.
I'm going to create one so that we went to one instrument.
Oh, it's funny, you one Java.
For that purpose, I created this.
So after this, I told you, I already told you how we can going with this.
So for these members, we can go in with this part for outdoor learning everything.
And with the morning.
So you can create in one single plus and then can all these and send one statement.
But for the simplicity, I'm considering different, different segments.
It will not change your image, you or anything it will do, mincing then with the Oracle database and
setting this all the connections and everything, then create statements.
I'm getting the statement for part of moving the data from the event database.
I'm going to use statements.
Let's start from event, which is basically event details.
So for that event, it is.
It will.
Jake, every event details you're details reading, so I'm going to show in tabular form.
So using the CIUSSS, I need to improve this on so you can improve your courses, things you ought to
do.
But for the simplicity, I'm going to use your table simply so this simple, able, able bodied with
one with the little and everything I'm specifying here.
So no need to worry about this is one and how we can proceed with this.
It will take care of older, more ratings than these that some titan see no event name.
Even name then coordinator and coordinator contact.
And I mean, remove this part of the show because.
It will take more space, coordinated contact fees when you did so you can add more fields like this
picture and everything, you can add image part on to there.
You have to upload the image of something.
You can use different parts like that.
You can create some cookies to store passwords and everything data.
So there are more things you can search and put into this.
But I'm going to be sitting inside this.
So.
As these are done, what is while are so new executing.
So I want to display each and everything inside this event table or event database to what I'm going
to do is I'm going to create a report next as this lobby's endless.
This will not end at all or we don't need until we reach the end part like this is the end of this year.
This is the last known of this database.
It will in the pilot.
So for these, what is going to your desk?
It's going to fetch in them what is in here even numbered?
But how would my extreme string in them or the significance of enemies?
The Enum is the similar character name, or we can see similar to that variable, which I used for the
store.
You ain't no inside.
Database, so always remember, these names are very significant, always remember what you do on that
school, run the school command line to create a database.
It's very important.
Then I'm going to do this and I'm going to be inside the Rose Garden.
I'm going to insert dirt roads.
Well, then connection commit.
I'm committing this connection and closing this connection and being all the times which I invoked already
the table and everything I decided to do for the event.
Or you even for a part similiar part, I'm going to show on the participant part also.
You can create another meter or you can hide something like you can hide some coordinator.
No, no or anything.
But I want to show everything, do not publicly.
What are the participants?
So these are done, but for the participants, I'm going to show the two things.
What are the participants of what?
I'm going to show two things.
One is you were in securities registration for the registration and you mean what I'm going to do is
I'm going to create another one form for you to action register so that you study to basically the loss
of learning to register their all things like, you know, even no even name, card number, expiry
date, CV, etc., etc. So you can include this also.
Otherwise, you can put the View event as another.
You can create one another address to show the event.
In the next part of the part, you can create one event register button there and clicking it will proceed
for the registration page on.
So I'm creating one simple scenario fill the form.
Because I'm using the CSIS and everything here, it will take time to check everything, every part.
So for this, I'm going to go through with an even name the no enter interguard expiry dates.
And once this is actually posted for the payment gateway.
So I'm proceeding with this.
So this is all about how we can create that, it is just an estimate of what it is, but we need to
create one registers the disturb civilians.
So go to the register that this so before that, you need to create.
So let's go to this source packages right click on new and so it.
Again, I'm telling you to click that, but also to add it to them.
They got not examined flight.
So go to that register, go up.
And I already created it at each and every call because it takes time to run and go to the court about
why you are writing in the first time.
It will take time.
But if you use to this part, this is very easy, but I'm telling.
So I am preaching from where I'm going to email bomb on this.
So these are again, I'm going to use the post meter.
But with all that, you should remember what I'm going to use the areas in view event I'm using get.
So why I'm using the word method is.
I'm not I'm this lineage publicly.
Second thing, I don't want to waste time full of users on this to show that we went is so do through
this very fast.
They do post if I'm using do post, I'm not posting anything.
I'm just sleeping this and I'm displaying.
So do get method for reaching the request.
It's very efficient.
So I am using this tool inside this registered or Java.
As I told you, this is print writer I'm facing from dual form, from that card number and everything.
So inside this, my sequence is different.
Not, no.
Don't worry about your sequence.
Your form sequence is different and the sequence is different.
Nothing will happen.
So for my purpose for storing inside the database, I'm using this sequence was card number.
Then event date didn't query then cardholder name, ID, name and your name.
I'm going to stay tuned to the card database, so you'll notice the listing or let me, well, some
part of what you're.
I'm pretending that connection with data database.
So you know how we can connect to this, our database system similarly like that you can show it to
the database or connect to the database.
Then again, I'm printing or inserting this into the database until basic values all the values inside
the card.
So always remember you have to create that similar or those inside the table of card like these.
If you see an extra connection or commit connection that goes to inside the registration, you always
see the which should be in the password will make Dot Dot Dot CVB.
Then you can also use that if equivalent is not more than three, then there is the error.
If card number is not exist on its value, you can check or you can check for the expiry date for that.
You can create such.
But once it's done, you can go with this payment.
So supplementation, you doing lose nothing but showing the information in your payment is done or something
or proceeding to the payment gateway, etcetera, etcetera.
You won't do that or proceeding or printing some.
Our transaction history page or transaction or anything you can do, so this is all about the list of
each.
So as I told you, you need to clear the one payment for payment is likely not very simple.
I will bring you this welcome to payment for Audible.
You can use similar things didn't like.
Beaming beach, cetera things here, are you going to add when it is going to back, be anything you've
entered into your reading, just this.
Once it is done, you need or you created everything to insert this transaction details.
So I told you this is all about the.
These are the for the participants.
And but you can create one another method like which the participants should look like, which you inside
distilled, which you and I don't.
Traditionally, you can do that.
Also using their databases, you can create some foreign key, public key or private keys, also not
in elevators, also inside their database.
I'm not considering very higher level database here, so I'm proceeding with the Simple Database Europe.
So for the admin part of the admin, then we will left with one another method, which is transaction
details for the transaction details what I'm going to show, I'm going to show one meter.
You need each transaction history for the issue.
So in this part, I'm going to create one issue inside the job.
Only two transaction history will look like this, so it will ask me for everything we'll get, whether
I'm going to use because I'm just fetching this from the database.
Then I'm going to use similar data database, select start from card transaction details.
And there were no even named the name of on that then payment date, etcetera, except I'm going to
display.
So this is all about this now, let's see how we can deploy on the part.
But before that, let us see what is the difference between these include and forward a method.
So, so let requests these tragedies on different things because this budget provides the interface,
with the facility dispatching the request to another resources location and will let just be extra.
There are two methods for forwarding the request from the late one.
Other sources include content to include the content of the resources.
So how it's look like forward methods If requests you so ladies, then it should forward to the solely
to other.
For the response response.
Again, another response is generated and response and to the back to the browser or user.
I can see inside the inaugural method what is doing requests, then to do so let it include those only
two.
And again, this led to the oh so we to one only so let one create creates another response.
We just find no response and it's showing to the incubator.
So it's very simple, as you can see inside our pre already created with log in so we can use this sort
of username and password does not exist, or you can use a welcome username, anything you can use.
So let us see how we can deploy this part over this.
Well, I project on them, so I'm going to run this first.
So we are using your local server if you want to publish this globally.
There are different things you can use.
You can use Babel Sting, which provides Java Sea panel you can use, then Heroku app is also available
on Web Europe, who use this Postgres virtual.
Inside this, you have to create one phone or text email, which is properties similar, which is available
on internet, and you can see that.
But for the chicken bubble, I'm going to use your last resort only with the one host.
So let us see how we can proceed with our project, and we are already done with our all things I told
you in starting this project.
You can enhance it more with using some different techniques also.
So let us see how we can proceed with this.
So this is our main page, as I told you, we'll do the early logging I told you, then I'm printing
this username, I told you we already moved this part.
So we were given details.
Then I told you we went so far to this.
You can you with this floating.
So we already checked this far.
Let us see how we can add another event here.
Event number is to help in this event, namely what it actually effect, same this.
Anything you can name coordinator name by renting this as a real.
This only coordinator, no, you can print anything.
No need to worry about that before registration and printing 250.
It'll be like this when you offer you in.
Due.
You can do in building general.
In law, anything you can think, I'm just giving the example I'm renting like, well, late 2020 when
I'm.
I'm printing here, or you can use 2020 your of your choice.
I'm clean, I'm clean submitting.
So now you can see you added.
So let us see how over a year in desert area.
So go to The View Yuengling, as you can see our view and this is added to this park.
Event details.
So let us see how we can proceed with our participants agents, the participant of events, one suit
participant log we already have seen we can create sign a page with the log in page, then go to the
this given Zululand already created the user, then submit.
Now we can see our view events, so these are two events we already have seen.
So let's see how we can register for it.
So enter even name, I'm reading this virtual effects, even number two, then enter card number, I'm
printing anything nine eight seven six four one.
Well, I'm pretty excited it is on 09.
2020 CBB, you can print anything your CBB cardholder names, some printing.
John will see two women, so nothing new you can proceed to the payment will tell or anything you're
going to do.
I'm just printing premium payments, don't go to Backpage, so I'm creating a simple thing you can proceed
with some like I'm willing to proceed with PayPal only, so you can put it in the PayPal page or of
some third party payment portals also.
So this is all of this.
So let's see how we can see in the admin part of this transaction history.
We go to admin, log in again.
I'm printing.
I'm going with username.
Your submit.
Transaction details.
So I want to transition details, so as you can see, even nobody to even name is this name is this
and payment.
So for these done, this is done, so you can create a one filter option to filter that even names according
to the payment data.
Also, you can do so exaggerated or you can do these things or you can add some payment date earlier.
So this is all about how we can proceed with our project.
So we are done with our project now.
You can move it further, some are the ones see things inside this.
So or our well event registration portal is done for the admin part and participant part is on.
Thank for this.
So thank you for attending this.
And we already have been all the parts here.
Thank you.