Now, so that we have created on our menu items, classes except for water.
So in this part, we are going to create a separate class for the water item in the menu and the name
is going to be turned out Java.
So on thing and then even land up to this file containing a public class water.
Similarly, as previous classes, we are going to declare a Boolean class call ice so private boolean
ice.
And after this, we are going to an.
So I could be better.
It sounds like a war.
After this, we are going to create a constructor called Water.
Public class.
The water and this water object is going to contain an immense string size as the previous classes.
That is no more different ends and a label being OK.
So this object is created and inside this object in the similar way, we will be adding a supersymmetric
containing this size and the amount to be displayed in the label.
After this, they will be yes, attaching if statement and this if statement is containing us option
paint.
A dialog box will appear and the label will be the.
Like main argument and the message is going to be would be all.
Likewise.
So this will ask this question to the customer.
Would you like guys?
And a question mark after this I also have in Caprica and this is going to ask you.
Yes, no.
So again, option been asking for a yes or no option.
So yes, no option.
And it is going to return null in the beginning.
Said Thank you for this.
If statement is going to set, I don't know it.
Also suppose if this if statement is true, then that statement should segue to the I store false.
So as I is going to be false.
OK, so we are done with adding that I start now.
Our next concern should regarding the price be so double price and if size is small, so in the price.
But we have set up price like if the size equals small, then the price for what there is going to be
one point zero.
If the size equals medium, then price is going to be two point zero.
And as if we haven't chose small and medium, then definitely the size is going to be a lot and the
price for the large water is 3.0.
Now what if ice is added to water?
So the cost associated with ice is the cost of the they're like the respective sizes will be multiplied
with one point two five and what will it be updated with the help of this price method?
So suppose if the ice is Ivan, then the price is going to be one one five for a small glass of water
and supply for like ice is not adding, then the price is going to remain same as one.
So we have completed this water less now.
One more thing to be added inside.
This is going to be the override method, which we have a need for that.
Pretty interesting.
So I am going to copy you from the D class and we'll paste it here in order to save some time.
So water with ties.
Is going to be this plane.
And similarly, here, water simply is going to be displayed.
If I not sugared in water glass and we are done with this also.
So all the classes I've successfully ran are tasked with every menu item in the radio, but this water,
the juice and coffee, all are done a beverage glasses used to set the size, amount and price of all
the items respectively.
Now, heading back to our neighbors, our classmates use them in class and we will be adding events
inside this in order to make things functional.
So now attaching actions to all the buttons like make all the things functional inside, though our
ordering form.
We are adding a string side here, which is going to like SAG the size of the selected item.
We have three options in this size small, medium and large, and you get source equal.
So if they click button and if we have selected use R.P. or coffee or water, so things are going to
be added inside the car.
And if this statement is getting a drink and if there is a like any kind of exception, then this block
is going to be get executed.
Then during the execution of this if statement, if a button is clicked on any of these item is not
selected, then we have to try.
I like this calling the beverage glass.
If juice is selected, then accessing the amount of side of use.
Similarly, for if water is selected, then we have to assess the size and amount of that.
Similarly, for the coffee tea now, the next day, glass is going to set the external and our beverage
to the garden.
This labor report is going to add this flavor.
This thing is added.
We have already covered it in the above section.
I can show soirées we have covered it had only inside this labeled report, and this labor report is
going to display that this specific beverages that are so different.
Similarly, for the bar in group, we have setting the bar to do so.
Initially, the order button was disabled.
Do you can see that this thing was responsible for disabling the but then in the beginning, and once
any of the action is on and neon the tank is added to the cart, then the bartender will be enabled
and the certain antibodies will be, said Total.
Now, after this, if there is a try block, then that should be to block in order to start next section.
Now, think about that what exceptions could be by placing any order?
So are there exceptions going to mean that the amount we have entered is not an integer?
Then this gas block will be responsible for getting that data and showing the exception that the enter
an integer, as I suppose that in the like this place type, how many glasses you want that you haven't
done on any non integer thing.
So an exceptional number and the text will be displayed doesn't get any bigger than them.
Similarly, what could be the that exception that would arise that could be chosen beverage dependent
on the Moon?
So suppose that the old bar like place tried to place order without setting the beverage type and size
so that we last fall chose a beverage dependent on the Moon.
So you have to choose apostate and on five lesser not to try to click this add button before selecting
these two.
This is set so small by default, so you just have to choose from this and this.
Until then, we can't click this add button.
So this sketch exception block is responsible for that only so we have covert actions attached to all
of them now.
Let us try to check what is left now so that we have common actions like that of this size.
These radio button and this input text will now.
Our next concern should be that the what actions should be a list.
Then when the an order by then killed so.
On that, but then got that try and catch exception block was mentioned above.
Now suppose it's vaguely down there, but then then what should we now put?
So on saying this?
Things can be made clear that if you don't get souls like that event that is before them is equal to
that bit then or that this means that suppose it's Britain or order like, but then that is being clicked,
then our report should be like this played out.
Initially, that important is fact or none and zero.
But if things are getting ordered, then this far not being responsible for combining all the items
added in the court.
Suppose that we have added beverages one two three four.
Suppose they have ordered four things in a row so that the pings are to be combined at the end and displayed
as a whole sum.
So this is, you know, like sum, the total amount will be paid.
I suppose this is initialized as we know.
And then this is going to be extended till the total number of items till we are there and the report
is going to be displayed the total number of items in the form of the string.
We can see that 10, supposing have are no more than one piece.
And then the dialog box will show that five million glasses of water, three million glasses of three
are ordered.
So yes, that is going to be responsible for that.
Also, the beer is going to win a total prize of all the beverages we have ordered as a whole.
So this is going to add the like total.
So I am going to lend it out and the total amount to be paid.
This statement is responsible for adding the total amount to be paid by the customer.
This total prize is initialized as the double date that died.
Similarly, we have declared the prize.
So the prize is double.
The total prize is also the validity of that image.
The report is going to display that total prize of beverage is So what is this report?
This is that you should pay twelve point five, so you should debate or dialogue.
Box will appear showing the report that this this is that report you should pay and the amount of event
in dollars or any of the currency you would like to add to your application.
It's up on you.
So initially, the labelled report said text is null and the written order is being disabled in the
beginning after the completion.
So after this report is generated, then everything is going to be set as default as it was in the beginning.
So after this dialog box of padding, everything will be know as in the beginning.
So I hope after the completion of this programming section, you all have gained a lot of conceptual
idea about what is being applied inside this project.
Everything we have used, we have extensively used the Swingin NWT Library in order to embed our life
the items to our frame.
So now let's try it on in-app negation and check that whether all the functionalities that we have,
our test is working fine or not.
So this is the application window open.
So suppose we are trying to order something medium or a glass of tea, four glasses of B we are ordering
adding to the cart.
Would you like to add sugars?
So clicking yes.
So for me, the glasses off B with sugar added energy port is generated now after this on clicking on
our day.
But then our dialog box, there's this plain form reading glasses off.
David Sugar is costing $20 and on heating.
OK?
Our dialog box again appears showing that what is the total amount to be paid by the customer?
So you should pay $20 and on who they aren't, OK?
Again, they will be landing back to our like previous window, which was initially open.
So again, let us try to our order two things that are also adding four add ice.
Then again, a glass of coffee, a large glass of coffee, adding it to God.
And yes, we want to attach milk to the coffee.
One large glass of coffee with milk is our.
Now on who they are for glasses, for large classes offered to retirees costing $15 and one large glass
of coffee with milk nine point seventy five dollars is added to the card on anything OK.
A total of twenty four point seventy five dollars is generated as the total bill for the customer on
heating up.
Get back to our homepage so they'll know everything is working correctly.
Find the application is running pretty well.
I hope you all have been through the program section like the very concentrate give me and gained every
concept we have used inside this application.
Now I tried running this.
Try making calls on your own and try running the application on your own so that you will learn everything
more accurately.
So yes, we have completed this project and everything is working perfectly fine.
And then I want to thank you all for joining this session.
Thank you very much.