Hello.
I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting the module, Know Your A B C's in the course,
Leadership and Communication Skills for Software Engineers.
Okay, let's get started with this very insightful quote.
This is a great quote.
"No one really wants to read a document; they just want to know what it says.
" I think that's a great quote and that's a great
challenge to us as communicators.
Let's face it.
People are busy.
They don't want to take the time to read,
yet you will still have to write things even if some of your
audience either won't read it or will barely read it.
Guess what?
It is your job and your responsibility to write in
such a way that your audience, you know,
your customers, your team members, your management and stakeholders,
actually do read it.
It is not an easy thing, but this module will give you the tools,
techniques and skills to help you on your way.
Okay, now let's see what I'll be covering in this module.
This module focuses on writing communication skills in the
context of your new role as team leader.
Okay, first why write?
Why get good at writing at all?
We will discuss that good writing leads to credibility which
is required for success as a team leader.
Next, I'm going to cover Michael's 5 C's.
This is my checklist and your prescription on your road to better writing.
The core of this module will cover five of the most important areas
that you need to grow and improve your writing skills.
The first,
presentations and how you can effectively deliver the message
you need to and get the results that you want.
Meetings and how you can create effective agendas and
get the expected outcomes you need.
Status reports and why it is important to communicate progress,
plans, and issues regularly and consistently.
Emails.
You've heard of structured programming and we will
talk about structured emailing.
Lastly, interviews.
You will learn how to prepare and select your new hires for your team.
As a quick reminder, the next module,
Let's Talk will address the verbal communication
skills in these and other areas. Okay, let's get started.