Are you ready to put down some of your technical skills and tools and
delegate that work to other and manage and lead your team?
Moving from technical duties to leadership activities can be
scary and as I've said in the overview module,
it was definitely scary for me.
Early in my career,
even the notion of delegation alone was foreign to me and
it took me a while to get through it.
This section will further help you face your fears and help you take that leap.
Your journey ahead of you is to move from software engineer to leader.
As a software engineer, you are an individual.
Your success was all about growing yourself,
but as a leader, success will now be about growing others.
I suggest to you to constantly and regularly think about how to grow your team.
I would put a reminder on your calendar for once a quarter,
say,
to review the activities you have underway to grow the
skills and qualities of your team, and what new ideas you have yet to implement.
Now part of growing your team is for you to let go.
Let go of those tasks you used to perform as a software engineer.
Maybe not all of them, but maybe quite a few of them and how do you let go?
Through delegation.
Now let's take a look at how best to implement delegation in your team.
If you master the art of delegation, you will also be building trust big time,
because they will say to themselves, you trust me to do this?
This instills trust back to you and a deeper sense of responsibility
and motivation with the person you just delegated to.
Okay, determine the tasks or work to delegate.
Look at your entire workload.
Determine which tasks you might delegate,
place a team member's name or two next to each task,
call a meeting, discuss your plans, consider their feedback,
and then delegate the tasks you identified.
If you don't delegate enough, you will not have time to lead.
Provide clear instructions.
The key to successful delegation is being absolutely clear
about what you're expecting for the output,
for the finished product.
How much direction you provide to get from point A to point B will depend
on the level of expertise of the person doing the task,
but in all cases,
you need to be absolutely clear about what your expectations and goals are.
Next, empower your team.
Delegating provides an opportunity for employees,
team members, to develop their own skills,
knowledge and abilities.
By allowing your workers to make their own decisions,
you'll ultimately have employees who can work independently
and deliver even more value to you and to the other team
members and to your company.
Avoid the need to micro manage.
That's always very tempting as you're moving from a software
engineering role to a leadership role.
Step away and give them room that it will be done.
Your door is always open and encourage them to ask
questions to you that they may have.
Remember, by delegating, you are also displaying trust.
Keep the task broader, more high level.
Allow members of the team plenty of room to develop their own
task or subtask which will work toward the general goal of
the project or the assignment.
Spend more time overseeing functions and tasks rather than creating them.
Your new role will be to oversee the tasks you are delegating,
review progress, review the status,
keep clear of any roadblocks for the team members,
and reiterate the expected outcomes.
Also, what I like to call as delegate up or out,
rather than say down, in this case.
Some bigger issues will not be delegated to the team.
You may in fact work them or in some cases, sit with your boss and delegate up.
Have your boss handle some tasks.
Like, for example,
you may need some help with funding your project and you know
your boss has a great relationship with the CFO.
Now delegating out means you may want to bring in outside resources,
contractors, or maybe consultants to help you get things done.
Okay, here's a tip.
Of course, in order to empower others, you need to delegate, but not dump.
Effective delegation is not about dumping the dirty work off
your desk or asking someone to jump in and fix something that
you let fall through the cracks.
These tactics will ultimately lead to a breakdown in employee satisfaction. Alright, let's do a little leadership sanity check.