Hello.
I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting the summary module in the course,
Leadership and Communication Skills for Software Engineers.
Okay, now let's recap this course.
In the module, The Interconnection of Leadership and Communication,
I shared with you a very illustrative quote: "Communication
is where leadership lives and breathes.
" It is really a very poetic way to represent the
interconnection of leadership and communication.
This module covered the fundamentals of why leadership and communication
skills are so critical to your professional growth,
to your employer, and to your customers.
We also dug deeper into the linkage between leadership and
communication and that you cannot have one without the other.
And lastly, we emphasized the importance of improving both of these skills,
leadership and communication, to improve your career opportunities,
your personal growth, your ability to mentor,
and grow your team.
In the module, Lead and They Will Follow,
I shared with you another illustrative quote: "Leadership is
the art of getting someone else to do something you want done
because he or she wants to do it.
" This is a more practical quote,
giving you insight that your success is all about growing others.
So what does leadership mean to you now?
So you have learned that it is not just leading people to a common goal,
which is great, but more importantly it's how you are leading them.
Do they feel like they have accomplished something and do they feel empowered?
And if so, you have done a good job well.
Connect, change, motivate.
We discussed first what you thought leadership meant and then we reviewed
two quotes and analyzed the words and discovered that the key action words
or phrases boiled down to connecting with people,
being change agents, and inspiring long-lasting motivation.
So that's a real great cheat sheet for you.
Follow the leader.
It's not a game anymore.
We discussed several key attributes of a leader.
Trust, compassion, stability,
and hope were essential elements to encourage your team to follow you.
Some leadership qualities.
In addition to the qualities we've just mentioned,
you will need credibility, negotiating skills,
planning and management skills, and strong communication skills,
and I called it a leap of faith because we discussed that your
transition from software engineer to leadership roles required you to
realize that your success is all about growing others and one method
of doing this is through delegation.
Because through delegation you are instilling trust and giving your team
a greater sense of responsibility and empowerment.
These are more complex, long-lasting motivation factors.
We wanted to align to the business.
That is,
as a leader you will need to understand the broader
business goals and determine how your work and projects
will align to those business goals.
And you want to identify who are your customers and how they would benefit.
This is your first step in setting the direction for
your team as a new team leader.
We talked about aligning daily work tasks,
so for each project,
you want a list of features and tasks required to fulfill
the project and with each of those, include priority and estimated hours.
Now this is performed at a reasonably high level of granularity and
this would allow your team to feel more empowered and give them room to
be creative as they drill into those tasks.
Lastly, motivating your team.
By allowing them and enabling them to learn new things,
to exercise their creativity, to have a voice in what they do,
and to be recognized for their hard work and that they
will build something that truly matters.
In the module, Know Your ABC's,
I proposed to you that you need to have a set of
rock-solid skills in the following five areas.
Presentations.
Because you'll be standing up in front of your peers or
customers or management and they will be listening,
watching, measuring, gauging, and critiquing you from the second you stand up.
So plan and prepare and you will be successful.
Meetings.
No agenda?
Hey, no meeting!
When you prepare your agenda,
have your expected outcome in mind and don't forget to take good
notes and deliver followup emails quickly.
Status reports.
They're going to help you communicate your progress,
plans, and issues regularly and consistently.
Keep them short and simple and be specific.
Write and send status reports regularly.
Next, emails.
Like structured programming,
follow my simple guidelines for structured emailing
to produce professional emails.
And lastly, interviews.
By following the simple interview selection process,
you will better find the best and the brightest to join your team.
In the module, Let's Talk,
I proposed to you that you need another set of rock-solid
skills in the following five areas.
Presentations.
You need to follow four key steps.
Plan, prepare, practice,
and present and in this module we focused on
practice and present and believe me, practice makes perfect.
Meetings.
And here I gave you another four key steps.
Plan, prepare, lead, and follow up,
and in this module we focused on lead and follow up.
A key outcome of any meeting is the commitments and
that's not a 1960s band from Britain.
It is who will do the something, what is that worker task, and when is it due?
Next, stand-ups.
So assemble your team and one by one, talk about progress, plans, and problems.
Walk-arounds.
I know you have a busy day,
but make your walk-arounds part of your daily routine and you
will be amazed about how much you learn about your team and how
your team feels more inclusive.
Lastly, interviews.
Get your candidates freely talking.
Ask open-ended questions and don't just focus on aptitude, but also motivation and attitude.