Productive business emails.
How your emails can avoid your company's spam folder.
In this section, we will discuss how to write productive,
that is useful, business emails.
These are your lifeblood as a new team leader.
Okay, let's get started.
Here's a great quote to start this section off.
I really love it.
"Here's how to write a good email: Write your email,
delete most of it, and then send.
" I think that is right on.
To me, people just write too much and it's unstructured,
hard to figure out the purpose.
I can't tell if it's important to me, the reader,
or whether I need to take any action.
So it's very important that we write really good, productive business emails. So this section will help us do just that.