Here are the benefits of stand-ups and why I love to use them.
To get real-time feedback on project activities, it's great.
Everyone gets together, it's informal, what's going on.
Also, to avoid issues or problems early.
It's a very, very good method for early problem detection.
To get a pulse of the team.
So while they're talking about their projects,
you're getting a feel for how they feel.
What's going on with them and you get a good pulse,
a good feeling of, is everyone good, is everyone happy,
are there issues?
Other dynamics other than the projects themselves.
It also can create synergy and team work and what I call magic.
Next, to start the day well.
Everyone is kind of welcomed, included, what's going on,
maybe even some excitement to the day and how we're going
to accomplish these important tasks.
Also, to support improvement.
Different ideas may come up which improve not only the project itself,
but the processes that you use to actually write software.
Next, to reinforce focus on the right things.
Maybe the day before you got a phone call from a customer
and it's going to change priorities,
or you found out something from somebody else that's going to
change the way you're going to do things.
So you can make quick, reactive,
and planned changes in the team's activities; I really like that.
And lastly of course, to reinforce the sense of a team.
In other words, you're all there together,
you're all focused together on the work activities,
and it really does build teamwork.
I like that a lot.
Stand-ups greatly improve team communications.
So here's a tip.
People feel more comfortable with each other,
people share information, work gets done,
and problems are corrected early.
I really like stand-ups.
Now let's see how I like to structure a stand-up.
Here's how I like to structure my stand-ups.
I like to follow my status report guidelines.
In other words, from that template we had progress, plans, and problems.
So first, a person is going to talk about what they did since we last met,
reporting their progress.
Next,
they're going to talk about what work they're going to
do today; that reports their plans.
And lastly, issues and problems.
So I'd like them to talk about the issues and obstacles they've
encountered and how they're going to maybe solve those.
Now while those discussions are going on, magic can happen.
Someone could say, oh,
I have a problem with the stored procedure; I can't seem to figure it out.
Someone else might say,
well I actually changed that yesterday and I changed the parameter.
Oh, well great, let's talk after the meeting.
So all sorts of little things can be discovered that
might take days or weeks to be uncovered,
maybe way downstream in the testing process.
I just really enjoy them.
Okay, so now you have a feel for the general process,
let's actually see a real example in practice in the next slide.
Here is a working example of stand-up.
I might begin with, okay, Lauren why don't you start.
I worked on the filter criteria user control on the accounts receivable screen,
Lauren says.
How did that go?
Fine, but I had a problem with the stored procedure GetAccounts.
Oh, I changed that yesterday (oops) and I will fix it for you, says Danielle.
Thanks Danielle.
Anything else Lauren?
What's on your plate?
That would be plans.
No, I'm good; I'll be moving on to the invoice screen.
Thank you, Lauren.
Then I just keep going around the room.
Now a person might just start off with a problem,
that's fine, as long as we cover plans, progress,
and problems, they don't have to be in the exact order of those three,
I typically like that but it doesn't have to be.
If someone has a problem,
I might want to hear that first and then you just go around the room.
It's informal,
but you're trying to make sure you understand what was done yesterday,
what they're thinking of doing today,
and are there any barriers for them to succeed in
what they're going to do today?
That's real important.
As a leader, you want to remove the barriers.
They could be technical, it could be something wrong with their office,
who knows?
So it's good to get that pulse of the team.
Alright, now let's look at the logistics of a stand-up.
Here are some logistics and guidelines on how to run and manage stand-ups.
The first is frequency; how often should you have them?
Well, it's a simple answer, as needed and what makes sense.
Now in our scenario and in your new leadership role, I would do one each day.
It can be a welcoming and nurturing activity.
People can feel more connected and supported,
especially if they get stuck on an issue or have questions.
Remember, people tend not to reach out for help,
but instead want to solve their own problems,
especially engineers.
That is noble,
but not always the most productive way to do things and the
stand-ups will bring out more communication.
Now on larger teams and I've had quite large teams,
I might have stand-ups per project, maybe two or three per week,
per project.
So it depends.
I might have a stand-up of just my project managers or just my senior managers.
So there are different slices of the organization that
you may wish to have stand-ups across.
Alright, duration.
Relatively quickly of course.
If necessary after the stand-up,
people can break off and drill into deeper sub teams.
You want it to be, you know, 5, 10, 15 minutes.
Typically 10 or 15 is about normal and location.
You know, you want to find a place where others are not disturbed.
I like to avoid conference rooms if possible because they're
full of chairs and people will sit down.
So there's a white board somewhere or a corner of an office,
sofa area, those are great little areas for stand-ups.
So if there is an white board area where people can
easily stand and do a stand-up, that's great,
a little bit out of the way, you don't want to disturb other people.
And who goes first?
Now, I think it should be a bit random.
Maybe it's round robin by last name or whatever you like to do,
but don't always start with the same person every
time and just kind of mix it up.
In fact, if there are five people in a row,
maybe do the first person,
then the third and then the fifth so people aren't really sure who you're
going to call on next and that's always kind of fun,
too. Alright, now let's move on to the next session on walk-arounds.