Email is the communication tool of choice for most of us today,
but here are a few problems I see in the business world.
Email is easy to use and has easy access from PCs,
tablets, and phones, just from everywhere.
Emails are great because you don't have to be available at the
time as your conversation partner is to communicate and it
allows us to keep projects moving when our coworkers are
unavailable or out of the office, but that's one of the downsides,
too.
It's just so easy to use, in the appropriate way.
Also, there is another problem.
Most of us are just drowning in emails.
The average person using email for business receives and sends probably
over 100 per day and I don't doubt it; my inbox is loaded.
I get almost 200 per day and the more projects I have going on,
the more full it gets and on top of all that,
emails are all too easily misunderstood or misinterpreted.
A recent study by Send Mail found that 64% of people have
sent or received an email that caused unintended anger or
confusion and we have all done it.
I'll bet you it's closer to 100.
Because of the volume of emails we send and receive and
because emails are often misinterpreted,
it is so important to write emails clearly and concisely; that is,
following my 5 C's, of course, and also,
my simple approach in this section that I will send with you.
Now let's see some concrete, succinct examples.
Okay, let's get down to business.
Write BUSINESS emails.
At work we are not writing an email to your buddy or your family.
In your new role,
a leader needs to write business-oriented and professional emails.
That is now part of your job description and of course,
follow the 5 C's to the letter.
As we mentioned, people are drowning in emails.
Hence, we need to have ours stand out from the crowd.
You want them to be easily understood and noticeable so that your
customer or manager will click on them in their inbox.
And of course, you want them easily understood.
How you ask?
Well, follow my approach in this section.
By writing clearly,
you'll become known as someone who knows what he or she wants
and who gets things done and both of these are good for you
and your team's career prospects.
So, what does it take to write clear, concise, and professional emails? Let's dive into a very detailed example and see just how.