So, why are you here?
You might be here because your story is somewhat like my story.
Or you may be here because you do know that companies are looking
for people with strong communication skills,
regardless of a leadership or non-leadership role.
Or maybe it could be one of the other following reasons right here.
Are you afraid of leadership or management responsibilities?
Are you perplexed or unsure on just how to develop your new team?
Have you been asked to be a leader and not a doer?
Are you a software engineering expert yet feel like a fish out
of water when it comes to leading a team?
Maybe.
Now let's check out the next slide on a few more
potential reasons why you might be here.
Here are a few more reasons why you might be taking this course.
Is creating and presenting a PowerPoint presentation somewhat daunting?
Is leading a meeting and getting people to accept
assignments somewhat impossible?
Do you need help augmenting or transitioning your technical
skills with leadership and communication skills?
Or maybe you've been asked to be a project manager on a new project.
If any or all of these relate to you and your position in your career presently, stay tuned, sit down, and hang on; we're going to have a great time.