If you don't think about what you need in a new employee ahead of time,
you will have a much harder time knowing when you find him or her,
so here is a simple, basic process to get you started.
Follow company HR standards and policy.
Always follow company policy and standards.
So the process and approach I am recommending,
must be used in context and are in conjunction with your company standards.
Alright, so in general, here are the following steps.
Step 1.
Document your requirements and then post them online and social media.
I'm going to go into each of these in detail in the following slides.
Step 2.
Phone call interview.
Step 3.
An in-person interview.
Step 4.
Possibly a follow-on in-person interview.
Step 5.
The selection process.
You know, getting down to one person.
Step 6, of course is the HR paperwork.
Now the focus of this section are steps 2,
3, 4,
and 5 because those are the ones where your verbal and
interpersonal skills are critical and the most important.
Okay,
for completeness we will still cover each step but
drill deeper into steps 2 through 5.
Document your requirements.
Just like when you build software, you need to know the requirements.
So, why are you hiring?
Did someone leave the group?
Did management approve another person?
Is the workload overwhelming?
As a backdrop to the hiring process, first understand why and document it.
Next, document the business requirements required by this person.
Let's put the technical aspects aside just for a moment.
We want to understand and identify the business requirements.
For example,
competition to your company is driving the need to expand their
internet e-commerce presence and in particular,
multi-tendered point of sale transactions.
Maybe you need to find someone that may have that
experience in the business domain.
Next, document the technical requirements for this person.
Now identify what I call the alphabet soup of requirements such as.
NET, C#, SQL, Bootstrap, etc.
Those are the tools, platforms, operating systems,
project management skills, etc.
You may also need to identify process oriented skills like code promotion
using software configuration and build release tools.
This skill is sometimes known as DevOps.
Communication and leadership requirements.
Well, you know I wouldn't leave this one out.
Based on all the discussions we have had so far,
you could list the attributes you would like.
In fact,
you could use the other modules to determine your checklist
of characteristics of communication and leadership you need
for the new person in the group, so that will make it easier for you.
Next is team input.
I think it is best for you as the leader to make the
first pass and gather the business, technical,
communication, and leadership requirements and then get your team together,
present the requirements, and get their inputs,
feedback, and validation.
To be sure that you have all the requirements collected and documented,
I recommend this approach.
Next, document.
Write up the requirements that you will use throughout the interviewing process.
Also, HR may need these as well.
Now post or advertise your new job opening using any
number of websites like LinkedIn or Indeed.
com or what your HR department may recommend.
Okay, now that we have our requirements,
we move to the next step, the phone interview.
Step 2.
The phone interview.
The job posting is starting to yield results and you're getting responses.
You may get a ton.
Read each one and use your judgment which ones you want to call.
Again,
the goal of the phone interview is this: Do they meet your
threshold of requirements for an in-person interview?
In other words,
what are the minimum things you need to know in either end the call and say,
thanks, or to move them to the next step,
the in-person interview.
Have a list of deal-breaker questions.
Don't waste your time or the time of the respondent with
random questions or playing chitchat.
Get right down to it.
So now for the interview and taking notes.
So start calling, begin with pleasantries and be upbeat in your demeanor.
Begin with, may I ask you a few questions,
and then move on with your deal-breaker questions.
If enough are answered to your liking,
they will become a candidate for an in-person interview.
If not, well, they're out.
Now you'll want to review the results with your team.
Always be inclusive with your team, share your findings,
and that you now have a list of say, five candidates for in-person interviews.
You want to review your results with your team.
Always be inclusive be with your team and share your findings.
Now you're down to say, five candidates for in-person interviews.
Lastly, keep all documentation and notes.
You never know.
In today's corporate and litigious world,
you may need your notes so please keep them.
Now that we have our phone interviews complete or most of them,
and we have our short list of in-person interview candidates, we move on to the next step, which is the in-person interview.