This module focused on the verbal communications and the interpersonal
aspect of verbal communication such as body language,
class, style, finesse, personality, humor and other attributes.
And we continued with our theme of the software engineer in
his or her new role as the leader and the added
responsibility to lead and build a new team.
Okay, let's review our topics.
First, effective communication tips.
We learned that not only what you say is important,
but how you say it is even more important.
The delivery.
How you say things is critical.
Then we covered the 5 C's.
Again clear, that is to be transparent and easily comprehended.
Be concise.
Use as few words as possible to give the necessary information.
Be courteous.
Always be polite in a way that shows consideration of others.
Be consistent.
That is able to maintain a particular standard or repeat a
particular activity or artifact with minimal variation.
Next we covered presentations and you need to follow four key steps.
Plan, prepare, practice, and present,
and this module focused on the practice and present; those are the
verbal aspects of those four steps and believe me,
practice makes perfect.
Next, meetings and we needed to follow four additional steps for meetings.
Plan, prepare, lead,
and follow up and in this module we focused on lead and follow up.
A key outcome of any meeting is the commitments and
that's not a 1960s band from Britain, either.
It is who will do something, what that worker task is, and when it is due.
Next was stand-ups.
Assemble your team and one by one, talk about progress, plans, and problems.
Next was walk-arounds.
I know you have a busy day,
but make your walk-arounds part of your daily routine and you'll be amazed at
how you will learn and how your team feels more inclusive.
Interviews.
Get your candidates freely talking, ask open-ended questions,
and don't just focus on aptitude, but also on motivation and attitude. Okay, in the next module we will summarize the entire course.