Hi, and welcome to the creating a test framework for DynamoDB module from the
Developing .NET Core Applications with DynamoDB on AWS.
My name is Daniel, and I'll be taking you through this module.
In this module, we'll be creating an integration test framework
using an in‑memory test server.
This will allow us to spin up an in‑memory instance of our
application and make requests to our application.
We will set up and ensure Docker is running on our computer so we can use
a DynamoDB Docker image that will allow us to spin up a local instance of
DynamoDB to test our application against.
We will then create a set of tests that will test the movie rank application that we have just built.