We'll start off by taking a walk through our MovieRank application,
looking at what code we have removed relating to the Object
Persistence model that we created in the last module.
We are removing this code ready so we can add the
document model equivalent code.
We'll be adding the code to get all items from our database,
the ability to get a specific movie using only the
first letter or word of a movie name,
we will get what movies a user has ranked based on the movie name,
we will add the ability to allow all users to rank movies,
we will also allow them to update an already-ranked movie,
so they are able to update the ranking,
we want the ability to get an overall movie ranking,
taking in all user's rankings and then providing us with the average of those rankings.