Let's add the DynamoDB low-level code needed to get all items from our database.
We are starting off in the Controller class.
The reason I'm starting off each time in the Controller class is
to show the pipeline that is followed when a request from a user
is received into our application.
No changes are needed inside our Controller class,
so we can head over to our MovieRankService class.
Inside our MovieRankService class,
we call off to the GetAllItemsMethod inside our MovieRankRepository.
We'll be adding the method inside our Repository class shortly.
First,
let's create the code needed inside our Mapper class to map the response that
we get back from DynamoDB inside our MovieResponseContract.
Inside our Mapper class,
we will create a method with the return type of IEnumerableMovieResponse,
and name our method ToMovieContract.
The type that we get back from DynamoDB is a scan response,
so we need to add this type to the method's parameters,
and name the parameter Response.
We need to add the Amazon.DynamoDb .Model using statement.
We now need to iterate over each item from our scan response.
We will say response.Items, and we'll use links .Select method,
and call off to a separate method named ToMovieContract.
If we create our second method, ToMovieContract,
we want to return a type of MovieResponse,
and we'll pass in the parameter's Dictionary of type string and AttributeValue.
The AttributeValue is a type class from the DynamoDB SDK.
This is where each value is stored once it's been returned back
to us from within the scan response class.
Inside our method, we'll return a new MovieResponse,
and we'll map our items similar to the way that we
mapped our document model's items.
We'll say MovieName equals item, open square brackets, MovieName.
Each of these items represent a property inside our MovieRank table.
When using the low-level model, we also need to specify what type our item is.
In our case, MovieName is of type string, so we'll say .S to specify that.
We'll map the Description, and for Actors we want to use the type .SS,
that specifies to DynamoDB that this will be a list of strings.
For Ranking,
we'll Convert the ranking item that we get back from DynamoDB into an Int,
and Ranking is of type number, so we'll add the .N.
TimeRanked we have stored as a string,
and we'll add our public method to our interface,
along with the DynamoDB model using statement.
Heading over to our MovieRankRepository class,
we want to create a constant that stores our TableName.
We want to dependency inject our DynamoDB client,
so we'll add a field at the top of our class named _dynamoDbClient,
and create a constructor and inject our IAmazonDynamoDB client.
The first method in this class will have a return type of Task ScanResponse,
and be named GetAllItems.
We'll add the Amazon.DynamoDb model using statement,
and inside our method we'll be using the ScanAsync method to
call off to DynamoDB to get all our items back.
But first we need to create a new scan request.
We'll say new ScanRequest, and pass in the TableName.
Using our _dynamoDbClient, we'll use the ScanAsync method,
and pass in our scan request. We'll add this method to our interface, along with the using statement.