There is a key feature that the low-level model offers that the
Object Persistence and document model don't,
and that is the ability to create, update,
and delete tables.
Let's have a look at how we can create and delete tables.
We'll start off by creating a new Controller class inside our
Controller folder named SetupController.
Inside our Controller,
we want to call off to methods that will exist in the SetupService class.
We don't yet have this class or any methods inside it,
but we'll be creating those shortly.
We'll create a field at the top of our class with the type
IsetupService and name our field SetupService.
Inside our constructor, we want to dependency inject our ISetupService.
Let's create our ISetupService interface and setup
Service class in our Services folder.
Make sure that the ISetupService interface is set to public.
We need to make sure that we bind our ISetupService to our SetupService class,
and we'll register our ISetupService inside our Startup class,
and bind it to our SetupService class.
Back in our SetupService Controller,
we will add the MovieRank.Services using statement.
Our first method in our Controller class,
we will look at how we can create a DynamoDB table.
We will have two attributes,
the HttpPost and the Route of createTable/ squiggly brackets,
dynamoDbTableName.
We will also set a controller-wide Route setup at the top of our class.
Our method will have a return type of Task IActionResult
and a method name of CreateDynamoDbTable,
and we'll pass in a string parameter.
Inside our method,
we will call off to our newly-created Setup Service to a
method called CreateDynamoDbTable, and pass in our dynamoDbTableName parameter.
Once our table has been created successfully, we will return a status of OK.
Inside our SetupService class,
we want to call off to our MovieRankRepository class,
so we'll set our IMovieRankRepository field at the top of our class,
we want to make sure we have we have the appropriate using statements added,
and we'll dependency inject our IMovieRankRepository
inside our class's constructor.
Inside our SetupService Class, we create a method named CreateDynamoDbTable,
and pass in the string dynamoDbTableName parameter.
Our method will call off to our MovieRankRepository class
to emit the name CrateDynamoDbTable.
We will also pass through our dynamoDbTableName.
We add this method to our interface and head over to
our MovieRankRepository class.
Here we'll create a method at the bottom of our class, CreateDynamoDbTable.
We will add a parameter to our method of type string tableName.
When creating a table, we need to build up a CreateTableRequest.
We will say new CreateTableRequest, and set the TableName.
We add the AttributeDefinitions,
these are the properties that we want to set on our
table during the creation of the table.
Remember, when creating tables, we only need to set the partition and sort key.
The other properties will be added when adding items to our database.
We will set the AttributeName as Id and the AttributeType as N for number.
We add the KeySchema that will set our partition key,
which is sometimes referred to as the hash key.
We new up a KeySchema element List, then new up a single KeySchemaElement.
Inside our KeySchemaElement, we will set our AttributeName to Id,
and the key type as HASH.
This will set our partition key on our table.
We need to set the read and WriteCapacity,
we do this by setting the provisioned throughput property.
We will set Read and WriteCapacity to 1.
We make a call off using our dynamoDbClient to
DynamoDB's CreateTableAsync method,
and pass in the request that we have just built.
We'll add this method to our interface, and we now have the ability to create a table.