Our final endpoint,
we will get the overall ranking for a movie based on all user's rankings.
Inside our Controller class, like with the other methods,
we don't need to touch any of this code.
So we can head straight to the MovieRankService class.
Inside the method GetMovieRank, we'll call off to get a specific movie.
We will be returned the movie and all user's rankings for this movie.
We want to add some C# code here to get an average of all
the user's rankings for that movie.
We will then use the Math.Round method and use the response that
we got back from DynamoDB in our previous call.
We'll say .Select r, lambda, r, open square brackets,
Ranking.AsInt, and we'll also add the .Average.
This will take all user's rankings and give us back an average rating.
We will then return a new MovieRankResponse and map the MovieName to
the movieName the user gave us in the request,
and map OverallRanking to the overallMovieRanking that
we worked out in the previous step.
Inside our MovieRankingRepository class,
we want to create a method with a return type of Task IEnumberable
Document with a method name of GetMovieRank,
and add in the movieName parameter.
We will create a new query filter and say MovieName,
this is the property in our MovieRank DynamoDB table.
We'll say QueryOperator.Equal to the movieName that we
passed in as our method's parameters.
We will create a query operation config,
as remember, this endpoint is using our secondary index,
so we need to set our IndexName to be our secondary index name,
MovieName-Index,
and well set our query Filter that we set above
inside our query operation config.
Now we'll use our DynamoDB Query method,
and pass in our config, and add the GetRemainingAsync method,
allowing us to get all results back from DynamoDB. We'll add this method to our IMovieRankRepository interface.