Inside our SetupController class, we want to add the ability to delete our table.
If we add the HttpDelete attribute and a Route of deleteTable,
squiggly brackets, dynamoDbTableName,
we'll create a method with a task IActionResult return
type and a method name of DeleteTable.
We'll pass in the dynamoDbTableName inside our methods parameters,
then we'll call off to our SetupService class,
to emit the name DeleteDynamoDbTable, and pass in the dynamoDbTableName.
Once the table has been deleted successfully, we can return a status of OK.
Inside our SetupService class, we will add a method named DeleteDynamoDbTable,
and add our string dynamoDbTableName parameter,
then call off to our MovieRankRepository class to
emit the name DeleteDynamoDbTable, and add our dynamoDbTableName.
As usual,
we add this method to our interface and head over to
our MovieRankRepository class.
Inside our MovieRankRepository class,
we create a method named DeleteDynamoDbTable,
with a string TableName parameter.
Inside our method, we want to create a DeleteTableRequest.
The only thing that we need to set in this request is our TableName.
Using our DynamoDbClient, we use the DeleteTableAsync method,
and pass in our DeleteTableRequest. We'll add this method to our interface.