For our next test,
we will test our update movie endpoint. Our method name will
be UpdateMovieReturnsUpdatedMovieRankValue.
We will create three constants to set a userId, movieName, and a ranking.
We will call our AddMovieRankData method to add our dummy data.
We want to new up our MovieUpdateRequest and set the movie name to our
movie name we have added and also the updated ranking.
We want to serialize our object and create a StringContent. We then
want to call our updateMovie endpoint and pass in our updated
ranking. In order to check that the value has been updated, we want
to use our getMovie endpoint and pass in the movie name that we
used to add our movie.
We will deserialize our response and we'll assert that the ranking that we get
back is the ranking we have passed in to our updateMovie endpoint. Again, we'll run all of our tests and they're all passing.