In this module, we looked at and spoke about the DynamoDB low-level model.
We implemented inside our application the following endpoints.
The get all items from our database endpoint,
we can now get a specific movie using only the first
letter or first word of the movie name.
We added the ability to get what movies a user has
ranked based on the movie name.
We allow our users to rank movies,
we also allow them to update an already ranked movie,
so they are able to update their ranking.
We can get an overall movie ranking, taking in all user's rankings,
and then providing us with the average of those rankings.
This is the first time that we were able to add the ability
to create and delete DynamoDB tables.
In our next module, we will create an integration test framework, including tests to test our application.