It's really important that we have tests that run against our code
to make sure that everything is working as expected. In this module,
we used a local instance of DynamoDB.
This allowed us to test our endpoints against the local
instance of DynamoDB without the need to connect to and use
our AWS instance of our DynamoDB table.
This saves us costs, time, and removes the risk of
accidentally changing our production data.
We created the classes needed to spin up an in‑memory instance of
our application to run our tests against. We then created some
tests that allowed us to test each of our endpoints that we created in our movie rank application.