Let's have a look at some of the core components of DynamoDB,
so we understand DynamoDB's terminology and how it's all pieced together.
DynamoDB stores data in tables similar to other databases.
A table stores a collection of data.
Each item is then composed of one or many attributes,
in our case we have UserId, MovieName, Description,
Actors, RankedDateTime, and Ranking.
Each table can contain 0 or many items.
Items are similar to rows in a SQL database.
In our case, we have one item, UserId 1 and MovieName,
The Secret at Purple Hill.
The partition key, which is sometimes referred to as the hash key is mandatory.
In our case here, we could set the UserId as our partition key.
All items that have the same partition key are
stored together behind the scenes.
The sort key can be used in conjunction with the partition key.
In our case, we are setting MovieName as the sort key.
We could set any of our other attributes as the sort or partition key.
When creating the sort key,
this allows us to query data that is related to the partition key.
We can use such filters as begins with, between, greater than, etc.
Each table that is created must have a primary key.
The primary key is set by either having a partition key by itself,
and in this case we have set the UserId as the primary key.
Or we can create a primary key using a combination of
the partition key and sort key.
When using the partition and sort key, this is called a composite primary key.
If you're only using the partition key as the primary key,
then this must be unique.
If you are using a combination of the partition and
sort key as your primary key,
then both of these values must make up a unique value.
To efficiently find your data in DynamoDB,
sometimes you need to query data using an attribute that is
not your primary or composite primary key.
DynamoDB offers a way to achieve this by offering secondary indexes.
You are able to create a secondary index with either a different sort key based
on the partition key that you set when creating your table,
or you can create a different partition and optional sort key.
There are two types of secondary indexes that we can create.
A local secondary index is where you use the partition key that
you have specified when creating your table.
You can then choose any of the other attributes in
your table to be the sort key.
A global second index is where you specify a different partition key and
optional sort key from the attributes in your table.
You are able to create up to five global secondary indexes and
up to five local secondary indexes per table.
You should be careful when creating the secondary indexes.
They come at a cost,
so don't create secondary indexes on attributes that you don't query often.
They will contribute to increased storage and input/output costs that
will not improve your application's performance.
There is one last concept that I think is important to understand and that
is eventually consistent and strongly consistent reads.
AWS is available in many different regions around the world.
We spoke about regions earlier.
We'll be creating our DynamoDB table in the region Oregon.
Inside of each region is what is called availability zones.
These are distinct locations that help isolate us from failures.
If one availability zone went down,
we can still access our services and data from the other availability zones.
When we write data to DynamoDB, it is copied across multiple availability zones.
If we were to write data to DynamoDB, then immediately read the data,
there is the potential to get the response back that doesn't
reflect the recently-completed write operation.
The response might include some stale data.
If we were to repeat the call shortly after,
you should get the latest results back.
This is called eventual consistency.
Normally this copy happens pretty fast,
so you don't need to worry about eventual consistency; however,
if you have an application writing and another reading the data,
and you must get the latest data back,
then there are options that we can set to ensure strong consistency when reading the data back from DynamoDB.