We've seen some of the basic Entity annotations so far in the previous modules,
so let's describe in more detail what they mean exactly.
An entity declares the object as an entity and how
the database should be aware of it.
Basically, it declares to JPA, hey, pay attention to me.
I want you to know who I am.
The Table annotation describes more specific details about the database,
for example,
the name or the schema or how we want to access that by uppercase or lowercase,
things like that nature.
The Id is the identifier attribute for a very simple primary key type.
You can do an Id class for a compound primary key,
but it's kind of out of the scope of what we're trying to cover in this module.
Then there's GeneratedValue.
A GeneratedValue is used in conjunction with Id.
And there are four options for us to choose for GeneratedValue.
There is IDENTITY,
and IDENTITY is used to specify an identity column in the database.
These can be a little problematic because the ID isn't available to return
back to the user until after the transaction has committed.
It can also be a little slower as they cannot preallocate IDs for inserts.
The auto‑incrementing field in MySQL is an example of an identity
column. Although they can be a little problematic as far as some of
the features that you're looking for,
they are simpler to use as far as just wiring your bean up and saying
go. Let's just persist something now. The next option is AUTO, and
AUTO defaults to IDENTITY if available.
If there's auto‑incrementing fields on the database vendor,
it will automatically choose that one.
But it will fall over to whatever is available if that's
not available in that implementation.
Databases like Oracle don't have auto‑incrementing fields.
You have to use a sequence,
and so it's not going to default because that's not an option for Oracle.
Speaking of sequence,
one of the GeneratedValue choices is SEQUENCE, and SEQUENCE
works with a sequence if that database supports it. Now
MySQL doesn't support sequences, so this wouldn't be a valid option for that.
But Oracle and Db2 or some of the other database vendors that are
out there have sequences, and you just plug in the sequence using
@SEQUENCE generator tag annotation, and that will tie to the
underlying implementation.
The most portable of the options is TABLE. TABLE will work
with all implementations of the database.
It's a little bit simple, but it works anywhere.
It just uses an identity table and column to ensure uniqueness, and you also have to tie this in using the TABLE generator annotation.