I've closed all the files we had open and shut down our server from the
previous demo so we're starting with a clean IDE.
Let's open up src/main/java and go down into our model package and
open up User. User is a pretty basic class right now,
we're going to continue to add stuff to it throughout the rest of this course.
We can begin by going above the class markings and say @Entity
and choose the javax.persistence entity. And you'll notice
that we already have a red error, and if you hover over it,
it will tell you that it doesn't have a primary key designated in it.
So, let's go down to above the rest of the member variables and say @Id, and
choose the javax.persistence annotation and @GeneratedValue.
And we need to give it a field that it can tie to, so we want
to create a member variable of private Long,
and we'll just name it id.
We can go down below the rest of the variables and right‑click and say Generate,
Getter and Setter,
select id, and save this. And we've got everything set up
for this class to now tie to a user table,
but we haven't created that table yet. Let's talk about how we do that.