The next piece that we want to update is to open up our
RegistrationServiceImpl, and we're going to do almost the same thing.
And, I am making a really deep example or a harder example out of this to prove
a point, and that's why we're going to use Spring Data JPA.
The actual Spring Data portion is what we've been dealing with,
but the JPA combined with Spring Data we haven't delved into yet.
But this example is going to help illustrate that and show
you why we want to upgrade these things.
We're going to do the same thing here.
We're going to wrap this course with an if statement.
Say if(registration.getId() ==null,
then let's go ahead and add that course to it and save that,
if not, we're going to just skip that.
We don't need to add that default attendee course to the
registration on an update, we're only going to do that as
part of the creation portion of this.
So, illustrating where we're putting our business logic at inside the
ServiceImpl, we have overridden our save method,
and there is a tiny bit of business logic in there that's
going to get replaced with Spring Data JPA. Let's save this now though and we'll move on to the UI portion.