So I mentioned it in the previous slide, but to get Docker,
you literally just go to docker.com,
choose Products, and select Docker Desktop. From here,
it'll bring you to a page where you can choose to download for
the specific operating system that you're on.
I am on a Mac, so I'll download the one for Mac,
which I've actually already done, and just run through the install on it.
Nothing special there.
I do create an account and sign into that account on Docker just because it'll
allow me to store and select images and do some other things.
Really nothing promotional that comes out of it.
But that's all you've got to do to get Docker installed on your machine so that we can start using the containers that we want to.