We've used the conference/registrations URL already to retrieve
all of the listed registrations in our system.
Let's go ahead and call that again using a simple GET,
and you'll see it returns a course and the associated
registration with those courses from our query here.
Now that we know we have a course with an Id of 1 and the name of Bob,
I want to do a POST on a new URL.
That's the one we just created.
So I'm going to switch this to POST and go to registration/update.
I'm going to put in a name value pair down here,
and the first one's going to be id and the value is
going to be 1. And the key is the name,
and it can be to whatever you want to change it to.
I had Bob in here, maybe I'll change it back to Bryan.
Let's click Send.
And it says that it went through clear to our database.
Let's go back to our previous example here,
which using Postman I already have it stored over here, I
can click on this and call registrations again, and you'll
see it switched it to Bryan.
So all we had to do there was type in a new POST and go to
registration/update, and you can actually put everything on the URL there.
I didn't put it in the body, I just did it as request parameters.
You can do it a bunch of different ways, but this works for this basic example,
but it shows that we're updating rather than creating a new one each time.
And that's the example I wanted to illustrate with this.
Now we're going to talk about using Spring Data JPA to clean up
a lot of this boilerplate code that we've been copying and pasting throughout our application.