Let's begin by opening up our Docker Desktop.
And if you're running Docker natively,
you can just open up the admin app for that as well.
But looking to see that your database is,
in fact, running. And you can see that mine is running here on port 3306,
and I just pulled up the log files. And sure enough,
it is started up and is running.
One common mistake I'll see from a lot of people is when they have
pulled a new version down from GitHub or they've restarted their
server for whatever reason, an update on their laptop or whatever,
it will stop their database,
and they can't figure out what's going on when they go to run their
database with that create script. So make sure it's running.
It looks like ours is up and everything is ready to go from that end.
Now let's switch over and look at the MySQL admin to see that those tables are currently there.