So we have all these pieces we've started putting together,
but how do we use them all in one application?
We've gone through and overridden IDs and column names,
tables, got all these things set up.
How do we actually start combining them all with Spring?
We've looked at both halves, Spring and JPA.
Well, let's put them all together in our application now.
I'm going to start with the PersistenceContext.
And this annotation is used to inject our EntityManager,
which is how we persist things through Hibernate to our database.
It gets our EntityManager for us.
The next thing we need is our service tier.
Now I'll be honest.
You can do all of this without creating your service tier.
But architecturally, this is how it's intended to be used.
And this is where we put our business logic at.
It also happens to be where we start our transactions from as well.
And then next we have our Repository annotation or our repository tier.
This is a one‑to‑one mapping of our model objects to our database.
Trust me,
this is a lot to learn or bite off all at once, but it will
all make sense as we start cobbling the pieces together in
this next couple of demos.
Lastly, we need transactional,
and that is the beginning of our transaction. And that
should start at our service tier.
Although if we're just doing an update against one table,
it is implied that it's in a transaction because it's just one commit.
It's when it spans multiple tables that you need to
start and stop a transaction. Let's begin by creating our service tier now.