The previous release of this course required us to
import five different jars into it.
Since we're now using Spring Boot,
we can just include the spring‑boot‑starter‑data‑jpa jar that's listed here.
A couple of things to note though, we don't have a version on this code.
So if you've used Maven before or it's maybe not so
common for you to recognize it, there is not a version element inside of here.
And that's because we inherited from the parent version inside of our pom.xml.
Secondly, the Hibernate jars, you'll notice, aren't being imported here anymore.
So we just have the data‑jpa starter jar.
Well,
it pulls all of the other libraries we need in through transitive dependencies.
If that's foreign to you, don't worry about it.
But if you want to dig deeper,
I suggest going and watching my Maven Fundamentals course here, on
Pluralsight, and it will explain that greater detail to you.
Let's add the spring‑boot‑starter‑data‑jpa dependency to our pom.xml inside of our application now.