Let's update our UserRepository to now be a JpaRepository.
To do so,
we just open up the interface and say that it extends JpaRepository, and
it's used to service the User class, and its id is a Long. From here, we
can actually delete this method because it's going to inherit methods
from the JpaRepository interface.
The other thing that we can do is go in our
UserRepositoryImpl, right‑click, and delete it.
Click OK.
And our application already knows that this is a JpaRepository
because we have extended that interface.
But I am going to give it the annotation of @Repository up here, and this
is how you also would override the name if you want to give it some other
registered bean name. This will work for us.
We can save this. If you open up your UserServiceImpl, you can see that we don't
have any compile errors because that method save is already implemented for us
in the JpaRepository interface that we extended.
That's it.
We have no other functionality here.
We will add functionality to one once to show you how to customize this. But the default CRUD implementations are already here for us.