Picking up where we left off in our IDE,
let's open up our pom.xml. And we can give ourselves a little
bit of space just somewhere between spring‑boot‑starter web
and spring‑boot‑starter‑tomcat.
And let's add a dependency inside of here. And the groupId is
going to be org.springframework.boot, and the artifactId is going
to be spring‑boot‑starter‑data‑jpa.
And when we save this,
it's going to go ahead and download those dependencies in the background.
I've already done it once before on my machine, so it did it quite fast.
It was already cached.
It may take it a minute or so for yours to download them. And a couple of
things to note about this. Again, as I mentioned in the slides,
there is no version here,
and that's because it grabs this version from our
spring‑boot‑starter parent version up above. So doing
dependency management inside of our POM file,
it grabs all of those based off of the version of the parent that we're using.
If you want to verify that the libraries were, in fact, downloaded, you
can expand the External Libraries section and see inside of here that
we've got org.hibernate‑core. And we've got 5.4.12.Final for the
version of the parent that I'm using.
You've also got the various JPA libraries,
the Spring Data libraries inside of here.
So everything looks like it got downloaded correctly for what
we're trying to include inside of our application. Now let's continue configuring the rest of the database connection.