So in this module, we covered setter injection and constructor
injection, we looked at code to see that it was all in basic POJOs under
the hood, and we looked at doing both methods using XML configuration,
as well as auto wiring using annotations.
And lastly, we covered briefly the topic of context files, and it still
has to be initiated or started through a context file, except now we're
doing everything using Java configuration,
that's kind of a historical approach.
In the next module, we're going to walk through getting all of this
configured and into our application so you can see these principles we've talked about and now put them to use.