Let's do the same thing we just did to our user object,
UserController, UserService, and UserRepository to our registration.
We'll go through and annotate our registration model,
inject resources into our RegistrationController,
create our registration service and repository,
and be able to use those for that web interface.
We start out by going to our Registration and annotate that as
an Entity and then add our Table annotation.
We can give this a name = REGISTRATION.
We'll want to add an ID in here.
We'll say @Id and @GeneratedValue.
We can do a private Long id.
Once we go below our name,
we can right‑click on that and say Generate and
select Getter and Setter for our ID.
Click OK.
We'll save this.
Now we can go ahead and start creating our service and repository.
So let's go out to our service package and right‑click on it and say New,
Java Class.
We'll call this RegistrationServiceImpl.
Inside of here, just for the sake of showing the example,
I call this method public Registration addRegistration
because it is the business logic tier.
It's not just about saving.
There may be some business logic wrapped around adding the registration.
We'll pass into that the registration.
And for now, we will just return that registration instance.
We're going to swap that functionality out,
but we want to annotate this class as a service.
And we know we're going to end up wrapping this in a transaction
because we're going to save this to the database.
So we'll say @Transactional.
And then we can right‑click in here and say Refactor, Extract Interface.
I'll call this the RegistrationService and select that addRegistration
method so that it gets extracted into that interface.
We'll choose Refactor,
and it's going to ask us to double‑check if there's anything we want to change.
Everything looks fine.
Going to our RegistrationController,
we can now auto wire in our RegistrationController the RegistrationService,
and I'll save that.
Going down to our addRegistration method, we can add an else on our method here.
If there's no errors, we'll go ahead and persist to the database.
So we'll say registrationService.addRegistration,
and we'll pass in our registration and save that.
And now we got to go out and add our registration repository.
We'll say New, Class after we've right‑clicked on our repository package.
And this will be the RegistrationRepositoryImpl.
And very similar to what we did in our UserRepositoryImpl,
we are going to auto wire in our PersistenceContext or inject it.
So we'll say our PersistenceContext.
We'll do private, it actually is auto wiring behind the scenes,
EntityManager, and our method inside of here will be public Registration.
We will call this one save because at this point we are saving the registration.
There shouldn't be any business logic that's inside of here,
just persistence logic.
So we'll say Registration registration,
and we'll do EntityManager.persist and pass in our
registration object and save that, and we can return that instance as well.
We're not modifying anything on it,
but that's a good habit to get into is to return that object
in case you have updated anything in there.
We want to annotate our class as a Repository.
And everything inside of here is set now.
We'll do the same thing as we did before.
We'll right‑click, Refactor, extract our interface.
Call it the RegistrationRepository.
We'll choose to have that method included in that interface.
Hit Refactor.
Everything is fine there.
Going back to our RegistrationService,
we can now auto wire in our RegistrationRepository.
And we'll choose the interface and go down to our return statement,
and we will say registrationRepository.save and pass
in our registration and save that.
We're now ready to fire up our server,
and it will go out and create those tables for us,
and we can go run our web application as we do that.
After starting up our server,
we can go ahead and pull up localhost:8080/conference, click Add
Registration, and put whatever name you want inside of here.
I'll do Bryan and say Add Registration.
And the page is set to refresh back to itself.
If I go over to our MySQL Workbench,
I can go ahead and type in select * from REGISTRATION,
put my cursor over it, and select to run the SQL underneath my keyboard cursor.
And we'll see that it has, in fact, put my registration in there.
I ran it once or twice.
You may have done so as well.
So you see I've got Bryan 1 and Bryan 2 in there.
That's just the names that I passed in there.
So now we've got both our app wired up.
We've got the web services wired up for Postman to go into.
We have registration and users wired up.
We can actually go through and now start looking at some of the more complex
annotations of pulling back the various JPA entities based off of things like join types and more concrete examples like that.