And Spring is continuing to make life even easier for you as a developer.
In the previous version of this course,
we needed to create an EntityManagerFactory.
It would have looked very similar to this code above.
But now Spring defaults to Hibernate as its EntityManagerFactory so you
can omit creating one. Like the persistence.xml, I want to mention it in
case you're looking at legacy examples,
as well as to point out the declarative nature of this older code where Spring
simply now just encourages convention over configuration.
If you need to create an EntityManagerFactory, you can.
But if the common defaults work for you, you can just simply begin coding.
I also want to point out look at how we had to create the EntityManagerFactory
and then begin our transactions, actually persist our code,
then remember to commit it, close it, and close the factory. Very
error‑prone things that are more indicative of a library rather than
a framework where Spring, as a framework, it takes care of all of this for us behind the scenes.