Switching back over to Postman, if we run our getter on the
registrations URL again, you can see that it still works
correctly, returns that one course that we expected to be in there
tied to that one registration object.
If we go to our request for the registrations reports that used the
named query and the projection and click Send on that,
you can see that we get the projection model back of just the name,
courseName, and courseDescription without the id, but
this was also using that named query.
We can verify that our post is working correctly as well by going back
in here, and we can change that back over to Bob or whatever you want
to and click Send. If we switch back over to our registrations and get
those again, it's updated. So all of that functionality is working now
how we expected it to. Looking back at our IDE, our UserRepository is
empty.
All of the basic CRUD functions and the basic searching functions are
available to us by just extending this interface.
Same thing with our RegistrationRepository.
That logic surrounding whether the ID was there or not and how to
do those things, even the use of the named query, we named our
method the name of the named query.
We just had to specify the domain.
You remember, if we look at our registration,
we had to say registration., which just said registration needs
this domain assigned to this named query.
We have cleaned up all of that code,
eliminated two classes, and condensed it all in one,
still using injection to auto wire it and deployed our entire app
without having to do anything more than add one line to one interface inside of our repository tier.