Inside of our IDE,
let's go below the spring‑boot‑starter‑data‑jpa dependency that we
just added and add another dependency inside of here.
The groupId is going to be mysql, and the artifactId is the
mysql‑connector‑java. Again, no version because it's going to inherit
that from the Spring Boot parent starter jar,
even though this is on MySQL jar, because it's using dependency management.
So when we save this,
it'll automatically download the correct version of that library
for the package that we have inside of our app.
And now we have all of those dependencies inside of here and can begin configuring our data source and the other resources.