So we're just about finished with our JPA context,
and the last thing we need to add is the data source to it so that we
can fix that yellow squiggly we had on our EntityManagerFactory as
far as injecting that resource into it.
We're going to configure just a straight‑up data source.
No connection pooling, nothing, no JNDI lookups right now
just so we don't have any more moving pieces to try and
keep this as simple as possible.
I would change this before I went to production so that I didn't have a
hardcoded username and password stored in my file.
And we're probably going to show that as a bonus
module at the end of this course.
It doesn't do anything for showing you how to use JPA specifically,
but just how to better develop software using Spring.
So for our data source,
we're going to use a DriverManagerDataSource that
comes out of the spring.jdbc.jar.
For our class name,
we're going to use com.mysql.jdbc.Driver, and that comes out of the My
SQL jar that we loaded through Maven. Our URL is
jdbc:mysql://localhost:3306. Those are just all the defaults.
And if you remember,
we created our schema and named it Fitness Tracker. And then our
username and password is just root and password.
Those are the defaults we set up.
If you chose something different,
obviously you'll want to substitute those in for the ones I've created here. Now we'll go ahead and set that up and get the rest of our application tied in.