When using an annotation like OneToMany or one of the other join types,
we can choose at what time we want to fetch that data.
There are two types of fetch.
There is a lazy, which queries the database when that property is called.
So when I call getCourses on the registration object,
it's going to then go out and populate that collection.
It will wait until we actually call that getter to query the database.
And then there is eager. Eager queries the database when
that object was originally created,
and this is one of those that does vary by implementation.
Hibernate does limit you to only having two eagerly fetched
collections on an object. Usually not a big deal,
but it is different between implementations.
So let's look at what this means for our registration object that we just
created. The OneToMany annotation we had mapped by registration had a cascade
type all. If we tack on fetch = fetchType.lazy,
which is the default, it will wait until we call getCourses on our
registration object before it queries the database.
Up until now, we haven't had an example to read from the database,
so we don't have any code out there yet that will demonstrate this. We're going to change that now.