Up until now, everything we have been doing has just been simple inserts.
We need to do a read in order to demonstrate the
various fetch types. We will use JPQL,
which is the Java persistence query language, to work with the data.
I believe that JPQL syntax is the hardest part for
people to learn because it's not SQL.
So when dealing with JPA and the different persistence APIs, Hibernate
and that, the hardest part seems to be understanding that I'm working
with objects and not working with SQL.
People often know what they want to do in SQL and are still trying to figure out
how to do that in JPQL. So JPQL is centered around objects,
and this is an example of a query using JPQL.
That same query written in SQL would look like a select *
from Registration. So it looks very similar. Except since
we're dealing with the object,
we say Select r, and you can use whatever variable name you want there.
But it is selecting from the object. Registration is referring to
the Java object, and it's spelled accordingly.
If you don't have that uppercase R lowercase
e‑g‑i‑s‑t‑r‑a‑t‑i‑o‑n, it will look for a differently named
object. So it has to be tied to the objects were trying to query on. Let's add this to our application now.