It's not often that we want to go through like our report and display
every filled and every element to the end user.
In fact,
some people will subscribe to the notion of never showing
an ID to the end user for them to see.
There's a really great way using a technique called projection
that we can select the fields that we want to and build an
object based off of that request.
We can do complex joins and things like that.
So we're going to actually do two things here in one
example to show you how this works.
Projection is a great way to present objects to the UI. We have an object
that represents exactly what we want to show to the UI.
Objects are added using JPQL syntax.
So we go through and build our query using JPQL, and I'll show you how that
works and what that looks like here in just a second.
And then projection objects can be JPA entities,
but they don't have to be a JPA entity.
This is the other reason I like this,
and I'll talk through that design issue here with you in a second.
You can do this using a constructor for the projection.
So what happens is your JPQL ends up looking like this code up above
here. You have a Select new, and I've created an object that we don't
even have here yet called RegistrationReport.
That takes three parameters in it, three arguments. We've got
name, the course name, and the description.
You can also look and see that we're selecting from
registration and course where the id equal to the r
.registration id in the course object.
So I've joined these two together and done that query. Got the information back.
This is actually a lot more efficient query than what we were doing
before where we had a collection of registrations and then a collection
of course objects that we were going down into.
If I had three or four or five registrations,
it was going to run through that query five, six, or seven times.
And they actually call that an N + 1 select problem. Using projection,
I can go get what I need in one query and one join in the database.
It's a lot more efficient database operation, and it's only showing the fields I want to to the UI.