To convert our object over to using a named query,
let's start by creating a couple of static final strings
inside of our registration object.
So at the top of the class, but below the class designation,
we'll say public static final String,
and we'll call this first one REGISTRATION_REPORT and
set that equal to registrationReport.
And the name of this actually doesn't matter, but it does have to be unique.
You can't use registrationReport for another named query.
It's tied to this specific one.
And then the second string you want to do is the
actual JPQL that we're going to create.
So we'll say public static final String,
and we'll call this one REGISTRATION_REPORT_JPQL.
We'll set that equal to a string.
We're going to go grab that right now.
So let's grab that code from our RegistrationRepositoryImpl
and scroll to the bottom, and we're going to cut this JPQL
out of here. So we'll grab that.
I'm going to switch back to my registration object quick so I don't
lose that out of my buffer and paste that in here and get rid of
that jpql string. And just so it's more readable, I'm going to bring
this down to the next line.
So we've got our string inside of here and moved that out of
our object that was in our repository.
We're going to fix that here in a second because it's broken right now.
But first,
let's create our named query. So we'll add an annotation up at the
top here that's NamedQueries, the plural version.
And we want to add a curly brace inside of there because we do
an array of these. We'll then have @NamedQuery. And inside the
NamedQuery, there's two parameters.
There's name, and the name is going to be
Registration.REGISTRATION_REPORT. And the query is going
to be Registration.REGISTRATION_REPORT_JPQL.
We can save that.
So we've got our named query created inside of here.
We have the NamedQueries array.
If you have more than one,
you just comma‑separate these and do another @NamedQuery annotation.
We have our name,
which is REGISTRATION_REPORT and then the actual JPQL inside of here.
Now switching back over to our repository,
we go inside of here and just create a named query and change the name
equal to Registration.REGISTRATION_REPORT and save that. Bring it down to
another line so you guys can see it better.
That's what we had to do to switch this over to a named query.
It is compiled.
It's checked and validated at the time of us creating our object so we
can actually find errors earlier than if we just try and run it and
have it fail. Let's fire up our server.
And once this starts up, I'll switch over to Postman.
And now I can just rerun the same query that we had
before for registration reports,
and it switched over to a named query. Really easy to do.
At first glance, it may not seem like it's buying you a whole bunch,
except all of these can now be passed around through static
names rather than us making them up on the fly.
And it keeps everything contained in our domain object. That's beneficial for
one reason that I'm going to show you here. Inside our domain object, I can
see the fields that we're doing our query on.
So looking at this,
I know that I have registration.name, I have registration courses, and
I can walk through and tie that to the actual fields inside the
object. So it takes a little getting used to.
As I mentioned at the beginning of this,
JPQL is working with objects, not working with SQL. And so you have to think of this in terms of the object graph.