Let's take a second to walk through the steps of
downloading our scaffold application.
First,
you can download the app and slides right here on the course
web page under the Exercise files heading.
It's definitely a good option.
I have also hosted the application up on GitHub just to make it
so that I can update the files that are in there and that you
can get the most recent version.
Don't worry though if you've never used Git or GitHub,
you actually don't need to have Git installed for this class, and you don't
really need to have any prior working knowledge of Git either. We'll do a demo now of how to get that and get our environment set up.