Controllers, as we've mentioned,
handle our incoming request and building the response.
I can't emphasize strongly enough that business logic
should not be handled in the controller.
This is also where our request and our response object should stop as well.
We shouldn't hand those off to separate tiers.
It should grab information from the request and the response
and hand it over to the business logic.
This works with our service and repository tier for
business logic and data gathering,
and it's also annotated with the @Controller annotation.
There are some convenience classes that you can extend,
but you either have to wire them up or annotate them with controllers
still. It should also be noted that this also handles exceptions and
routes views accordingly based off of whether or not we had an exception or we've gotten the correct information.