Let's talk about the problem that JPA and Hibernate
solve and why we want to use them.
Whenever I'm interviewing Java developers, I always ask them why
should I use Hibernate or why should I use JPA?
And a lot of times they don't understand what the
problem is that we're trying to solve.
Let's take a second to talk about what that problem is.
One of these things is that developers don't always make good DBAs.
A developer doesn't always understand some of the reasonings behind why we
have foreign key constraints the way that we do or how to best represent what
they're trying to do in a relational database.
Relational databases are two dimensional where
object‑oriented languages are three dimensional.
Also,
the data model doesn't always line up with that object model because of that
two‑dimensional versus three‑dimensional representation.
I'm talking about it from the object‑oriented side.
What if we have an existing database that we're trying to map to?
Getting these two to line up isn't always easy.
Another problem is configuration. Although
configuration is a lot better with JPA, it can still be better,
and that's where Spring steps in.
Things like transactions, testing,
data source injection and configuration, these are all things that
we're going to solve with both Spring and JPA inside of our sample
application that we're going to be writing.
The main point I want to talk about for a minute though is business focus.
The business doesn't care if I'm using Spring or JPA.
They care that I'm focusing on solving their problems.
Let's look at some sample code to show you exactly what I'm talking about.
This method that you have in front of you is an old‑school JDBC query,
and yes, you'll notice it's really wordy.
In fact, I had to shrink it down just to fit it all on this screen.
I've got to get a connection, I've got to get a prepared statement,
I've got my result set, I'm getting all the stuff,
populating it, binding it, looping through it,
everything going on,
and then finally I've got this catch statement at the bottom where over half
of my code is making sure that I've closed the result sets,
and I've closed the statement,
and I've closed the connection, because if I don't do all of
that I'm going to end up having memory leaks and the database
will run out of connections.
Believe me,
if you've developed in Java code very long and you've done JDBC for very long,
at some point in your career you forgot that finally block
or one piece of that finally block and you've ran out of
connections on your database.
So really, what is the business focus here?
They care about two things,
that I got this query done and I shoved it in that object.
So there's 35 to 45 lines of code there that they don't care how we do it.
They just care that I'm grabbing the car based off the Id and
getting this object back and returning it.
It's all the application wants.
What does it mean to get a car by Id?
Well, just that,
it doesn't mean that I have a finally block and all
this other stuff that's going on.
Our focus is really just on using a tool rather than
getting the business what they need back,
and you can see it's very error prone.
If I forget one line in here,
the application will deploy and it will run, it'll just chew up
resources and finally run into and out of resource exception or out of
memory or heap space or perm gen or the number of database connections,
all problems that you can experience in a full‑scale application if
you're just using plain old JDBC. Let's talk about the solution though and how JPA fixes this.