Hello, and welcome.
I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting the module, gathering requirements for the
business unit, in the course, Best Practices For Effective
Requirements Gathering. Our backdrop for requirements gathering in
these last three modules is by business context.
In the previous module,
we covered how the business analyst would perform requirements
development for a product working within an Agile or Lean team
and working with the product owner.
In this module,
we will discuss requirements gathering in a broader context within
the business unit, or also known as program,
where you may have dozens of systems,
applications, and complexities that must be managed. And for what's
coming up in the next module, we will cover the requirements gathering
in the enterprise or portfolio context. As a reminder, these contexts
are not cut and dry and may not even be existent in most
organizations, but as I mentioned,
we need a form of categorization to frame our discussions.
Here are the topics of this module, the business unit in programs,
the power of program management, designing program requirements,
the BA's role at a program scale, levels of expressing user requirements,
the BA's role driving epics to backlogs, analyzing the
optimal workload composition, and analyzing the optimal
Agile team composition, and finally, point of view and module summary.
Okay, let's get after it.
Here is the module outcome, to enable you to improve your
requirements development skills for multiple products,
systems, and applications to meet a broader spectrum of business needs within a business unit or program.