What's a requirement?
A requirement is a description of what a system is supposed to
do. Now, can it get any easier than that?
Then why is it so challenging and take so much energy to
figure out which requirements are the right ones that will add
the most value? Because it is hard,
takes discipline, and you need a solid process and the right soft
skills for your success. Categories of requirements.
There is a world of requirements, and they come in all shapes and sizes,
and it would be impossible for me to list all the
different types of requirements.
So I narrowed it down to these categories for the sake
of this course. The first, strategic.
These are quite large, big picture,
long‑term and critical for the success of an enterprise.
An example, we need to integrate wearable devices into your product offerings.
Next, is epics. For me, several epics can fulfill a strategic initiative.
An example, create a mobile app that integrates with a
fitness watch of brand X. And lastly,
features. Again, as we move down this slide,
there is more granularity. An example, our mobile app can
connect and share data with fitness watch brand X.
I wanted to show you that a requirement can be quite broad and vague.
Yet as a strategic requirement down to a very
detailed description with a feature, the requirement spectrum is a big,
juicy grayscale.
Take a moment and reflect as to where you spend most of
your analysis time on this grayscale.
The three modules at the end of this course will focus on these
three categories or requirements context and how to handle each
to add value to the business.
The result of your requirements analysis has a significant and
far‑reaching impact on your organization such as making quality,
value‑based business decisions. Make versus buy.
Should we make something internal or buy it from the outside or
maybe both? System software development. Will what you provide
enable the software and system development teams to build in the
most effective way? Go/no‑go.
Should we even do this strategy, epic or feature? It is just as
important to say no if it will not add value or you need some more
analysis time. Estimates and schedules.
Yes, I know they sound boring,
but management needs to know, at least roughly, how much
it will cost and when will they get it?
Even in the Agile world,
management needs to have some idea. Budgets and capital allocations.
My same comment here, may sound boring,
but management needs to know. So you can see that the results
of your hard work is so important in providing the necessary
information the business needs.
I truly believe that how you gather, specify,
analyze, and recommend requirements can make or break a company, that
is garbage in, garbage out, right? Your software development teams are
ingesting your requirements to develop applications. Again, that is
why your role as an analyst is so important and critical to the
success of an organization.
And that is why you need to have a solid analysis framework, processes, and good soft skills, and this course will help you get there.