The uncertainty of business requirements.
Just what makes requirements so uncertain?
Let's find out.
Poor definition of requirements is one of the major causes of failed software.
Well, no surprise here.
What may cause this?
Lack of experienced analysts, not enough analyst resources,
inadequate interpersonal and interviewing skills,
the absence or half‑heartedness of adopting agile and lean processes
for requirements gathering and software development.
Any sound familiar to you?
Successful software development is often affected and in
fact hindered by the generally inadequate state of the
process of requirements analysis.
That is why I laid out the lean process and framework to
mitigate these issues in this course.
And by the artifacts that make up the requirements,
the documentation, mockups, workflows, data models,
and all the other items you need to clearly and
accurately capture the requirements.
Also,
the ability of the business analyst who provides the
interpretation of the business rules and requirements,
which are then further interpreted by the technical development team.
The operative word here is interpretation.
First, the analyst has to interpret the business,
and then the technical team has to interpret from the analyst.
Room for error.
Lastly, the fast‑paced business environments we live in today.
Business is moving so fast,
your requirements development process must be lean and agile to
address the fast‑paced business environment.
To me,
the insufficient process to gather requirements is a
major cause of failed software today.
The critical role of the BA.
The business analyst, that is,
the person doing the requirements gathering, must
address and understand three key areas.
There may be many kinds or roles of users.
The analyst must fully understand and appreciate the
users' needs and expectations,
which, again, are many and varied, based on the roles of the users or
customers. There are daily end users, there are the managers of those
users, there are business stakeholders,
the development team, and a host of others.
Also, how well is the problem domain understood?
Is it a complex sales order process?
Is it a multi‑system integration project?
It is a migration to a new ERP system? These all require
either a deep and rich knowledge base of the business domain
or the ability to figure it out.
Analysts must clearly understand the business or problem domain to
be successful, so working a few extra hours here and there to first
fully understand the business, well, that might really pay off.
Lastly, how rigorously,
accurately, and succinctly are the requirements
captured in the specification artifacts?
Many of the ones I've had to read our are marginal at best. And that is your
job too, that is, just how will you document everything. Too little provides
vagueness, and too much may just be a waste of time.
Also, don't do too much up front, since requirements get stale over time.
Try and capture quality requirements just when you need
them, also known as just‑in‑time requirements. That is an
agile and lean way of doing it.
I would like to suggest to you that for a new
software system or a major enhancement,
the requirements will not be completely known until
after the users have used it.
At first, I thought this was somewhat funny, and then I realized how true it is.
And why is that?
It is because getting to the ultimate system the users want
is an incremental and iterative process.
Always has been, always will be.
And that is why agile and lean approaches have been so successful. By
leveraging agile and lean approaches for requirements gathering itself, you
will be more successful in adding value to the business. Because of the
potential shortfalls that we have discussed,
the skills of the business analyst, documentation,
domain knowledge,
communication skills, and more, we can say the following truism.
Uncertainty is inherent and inevitable in software and systems development.
So what can you do about that?
Let's embrace and adapt uncertainty.
Don't fight it.
You will not get all the requirements right, so let's adapt to a new process
such as avoid taking big steps, certainly. Frequently stop,
inspect, and adapt. And have the shortest possible
feedback loop to your customer.
Sound familiar?
That's agile and scrum and Kanban and maybe some other methodologies
as well. As I've been saying, agile and lean reduces uncertainty. By
adopting agile and lean approaches,
tools, and techniques such as scrum and Kanban into your
requirements development process, you can minimize but not
eliminate the uncertainty of the requirements and greatly
improve the quality of the requirements.
A major tenet of this module is to use agile and lean
approaches to requirements gathering. You will be more
successful at adding value to the business.
Now here are two of my Pluralsight courses that tie
right into what we're talking about,
so you may want to check them out. Kanban for Agile/Scrum Practitioners
and also Developing Effective Agile Sprint Plans.
Both can be directly applied to the requirements process, as well as, if
you're a business analyst on an agile or Kanban team, this will greatly help you.