Before we drill down further and perform more decomposition into epics
and features regarding the business unit program requirements, let's
level set on some terms and definitions.
Here are several forms of expressing user requirements. User stories, to me,
the most popular and atomic unit if you write them well and follow the invest
guidelines we discussed in the last module. Features, just a note, many
organizations intermix the term user story with feature,
and I suppose that is fine. To me, a feature,
though,
is a higher level of abstraction than a user story. Epics, even
broader than features, and I equate epics to business unit or
program‑level requirements. And lastly, themes,
which I equate to company strategies and enterprise‑level requirements.
Features and stories will apply to a product or single team,
typically. Epics will apply to program or business units,
so a broader range of requirements. And lastly, themes or business
strategies apply at the top of the enterprise.
We will discuss themes and enterprise requirements in the next module,
Gathering Requirements for the Enterprise. Now our starting point for this
module are the epics since I'm equating those to business unit or
program‑level requirements. Now let's look at the four of these in more
detail. For expressing user stories, they are detailed,
succinct, and follow the invest guideline.
They are used by the product owner,
the business analysts, and the dev team members.
They are designed and sized to fit into an
iteration of an Agile or Lean activity.
And the form that is used is the user story format that I described in the
last module. For expressing features, they are short,
descriptive phrases and easily understandable by the business.
They are used by the product owner, business analysts, and the developer team.
Features take multiple iterations or releases to implement.
They are typically a bit larger in scope than a user story and can be
expressed with user stories or use cases, and again,
are broader in scope.
Now let's look at expressing epics.
They are broad, challenging,
impactful, and market‑driven descriptors. The
creators of epics are product owners, business analysts, and senior management.
They can affect multiple projects and teams,
and the time estimates to complete are in months or quarters.
The form they take are phrases, very high‑level use cases,
bullet lists,
business cases or project goals. Expressing themes, and
themes are strategic business goals.
They are large initiatives, consuming sizable
resources for competitive advantage.
The creators are CEOs, board of directors, and senior executives.
They may be measured in quarters or years to get things done,
and the form they take are vision statements and strategic business documents.
From theme to user story. Let's say we have a theme
that is created by a CEO of a company.
Several senior managers create three epics.
A product owner and her business analyst partner create three features,
and in turn, one of those features is further decomposed into five user stories.
You can see that from themes to user stories remove from a very high
level of abstraction to a very low level of abstraction.
Here are our four forms of expressing user requirements,
and I want to talk about the testability test. User
stories and features are testable, that is,
you can take a user story or feature and write test cases
to test it and prove that they work.
That is because they are highly decomposed and succinct.
On the other hand,
epics and themes are not testable. They are very high level and abstract.
This is just another way to view and think about
the ways to express requirements.
A requirement is something you want to do,
but there is no predetermined way to know whether it is a theme,
epic, feature or user story.
And don't let anyone tell you otherwise.
But there are norms,
and you need to decide how you want to use these in your
organization. Define them and provide artifacts to help your
team better understand and use them.
Having a common way of working and expressing requirements is critical.
I have certainly given you some good guidelines to begin with,
and you can annotate them as you see fit. You just want everyone to be on the same page.