Let's see how we can more efficiently gather requirements.
Here is a great quote that I truly believe in.
If you can't describe what you're doing as a process,
you don't know what you're doing by Mr. Deming.
So if I walked up to you and said,
please tell me how you go about requirements development,
What would you tell me?
Usually in about 5 minutes, I can tell whether you
know what you're doing or not.
When you are performing business analysis,
you need to have a process by which you follow.
That may include a framework, tools, standards,
artifacts, and best practices in order to quickly
implement your analysis assignments.
The bottom line for me, process is critical to
successful requirements gathering.
If you do each analysis activity randomly,
you will have random, unpredictable results.
Develop a basic process in how to do your requirements development.
This can improve productivity greatly.
For example, if you hire new people,
they can immediately begin using your material.
This material can be a repository of all your processes tools,
approaches, artifacts, and requirement examples.
This does not have to be detailed or voluminous, keep it all in a
wiki and continually update and improve it.
I am sure you and your team already have a ton of material to get
started. Create your own best practices and document them. A best
practice is a method or technique that has been generally accepted by
you and your team as better to any alternatives because it produces
results that are superior.
A best practice may be a process, tool,
template, or outline, or return on investment spreadsheet, you
name it. In this way, you can quickly grab something from your
repository, say in Confluence or SharePoint or a cloud drive, and
start working immediately.
So how much process or best practices is enough?
Well,
it depends. For each activity you embark on, you need
to look at your context, system,
business unit, or enterprise, you need to look at the stakeholders,
timeframe, urgency, budget, and many other factors.
This matrix of information should be in your process and
best practice repository to help guide you on how much
level of effort is appropriate.
Now we'll talk more about level of effort in a bit.
I have used the term lean several times earlier in this module,
and here is a more formal definition.
Lean can be defined as a set of techniques to identify
and eliminate waste from operations.
Keep this in mind when developing your processes and best practices.
Lean systems, or lean anything for that matter, focus on process improvement that eliminate waste and improve workflow.