So why not apply some of the basic practices of Lean and Agile
to the requirements development process?
So, adopt Lean. Adopt techniques that streamline your work,
that is, eliminate waste.
So ask yourself, are your processes streamlined?
Can you make some improvements?
Well, if so, make them.
Apply some features of Agile.
They will work great, not just in software development, certainly.
And here are a few that might give you the most bang for the buck.
First, standups are essential.
Maybe have daily standups with your team of analysts and another standup
weekly so you can report progress to your stakeholders.
Define a backlog and perform iteration planning and iterations.
Set up your backlog, that is,
what are the basic tasks I must do to accomplish my task or project?
Even if you are doing this alone, doesn't matter; define your backlog.
Now,
pull forward into an iteration of a week or two what items you
think you can accomplish and start working on them.
Working in an iterative fashion is lean and is smart.
Readjust at the end of each iteration,
and readjust your backlog based on the feedback you get
daily from your standups with your teammates and weekly
standups with your stakeholders.
Employ the appropriate LOE,
or level of effort, for documentation and artifacts per
activity or project you are working on.
You will leverage your artifact repository for your templates,
examples of past projects, tools, knowledge base,
etc.
You will draw upon your repository to employ and use just
the right amount of material and tools to minimize any
waste and maximize your output.
Now let me walk you through an example of setting up a simple
backlog and laying out your iterations.
Here is an example of creating your backlog for your analysis task.
Let's say your task is to determine if the purchase of
accessories in the vehicle order system is worthwhile.
That is the assignment you've been given by your manager.
Here is my backlog of all the tasks I need to get done.
I need to interview the sponsors, determine business drivers,
determine return on investment or any benefits,
determine existing systems effected,
maybe view a demo of the existing system or systems,
analyze the ordering workflow, understand just what accessories really means,
set up and conduct daily and weekly standups,
develop and deliver my findings in a presentation.
Now that we have itemized that, let's move on to the next step.
Let's define our iterations in the Agile analysis process.
Okay, here is our backlog from the previous slide,
and I have numbered each one for reference.
I decided that I would lay out three one‑week iterations as follows.
Here are the tasks that I or my team plan to do in iteration 1,
here are the tasks for iteration 2,
and here are the tasks I plan to work on for iteration 3.
Now, here is my analysis Agile process I will use to run my assignment.
So first, I'll conduct daily standups with the analysis team,
review backlog and iteration assignments,
make any changes as necessary, conduct weekly standups with sponsors,
provide incremental progress and findings to sponsors
and solicit feedback and guidance,
remember we always like really short feedback cycles,
adjust backlog and iterations based on the feedback.
I mean, how simple is this?
Let's leverage the basics of Agile and apply it to how
we conduct our analysis activities.
Now feel free to modify and improve this in any way that works for you.
The approach builds trust with your sponsors and team and
will provide artifacts that you can show and prove to others
that you have your act together.
I would recommend running your analysis activities as described.
It is even more important to follow an approach like this if you have a team.
Use a repository of backlog templates.
Here's what I mean by that.
In our example, I showed you a backlog.
Keep that backlog with its list of tasks around as a template
for future assignments of a similar nature.
Determine the type of analysis you've been assigned,
say a high‑level strategic, or multi‑system,
or single system.
Now, over time you will figure out your general types of analysis work.
Maybe you can categorize the backlog templates into three to six categories.
You don't want too many.
I think three templates, one for each business context, would be just fine.
Next, select your backlog template.
This has the list of tasks that are required for this analysis type,
premade and ready to go.
Before you start,
remove any items you know you won't need and add any that you think are missing.
When your analysis activity is complete,
update the backlog template as needed,
or maybe even create a new backlog template for a new analysis type.
Also when complete, update your analysis Agile process template, if required.
I have five process items on the previous slide. Maybe you need to add some.
Or you could take this to the next level and have an analysis Agile
process that is paired with each backlog template.
I like that even better.
Always remember, at the end of every activity you do,
you want to reflect upon and capture your lessons learned back
into your framework process of artifacts.
Pure analysis iterations, you know, like the ones we just discussed,
well, your outcome or deliverables could be recommendations,
options, reports, business cases, and the like.
You are following your own independent iteration schedule.
Another form of engagement could be where you are doing the
analysis iterations, and your outcome are backlog items to be
given to the Agile development team.
You have partnered with your product owner,
helping them articulate the business requirements,
and at the end of your two‑week sprints there are new backlog items.
They in turn are given to, and consumed by,
the Agile development team and worked in their next iteration.
You then start on your next iteration doing more
analysis and developing new backlog items.
I have used this approach a few times. Basically, it
is just‑in time backlog items.
This approach worked well when the project had to start immediately,
yet there really wasn't a backlog ready yet.
Hence, we broke the work up into two Agile teams,
one focused on analysis and delivering backlog items and one
team focused on developing the software.
In this case,
your iteration schedule was in sync with the development iteration schedule.
Next, you, the analyst, are part of the Agile development team itself.
Maybe you are taking fuzzier backlog items and refining them into user stories.
Here, there is only one iteration schedule,
and it's the schedule of the Agile development team.
In all of these, you want to be using analysis templates,
best practices tools, frameworks, etc. to optimize your work and reduce waste.