Apply the "Right" Level of Effort. And what I mean by that is be lean.
Lean is when you eliminate waste and optimize your work.
So you want to keep this in mind when developing your
analysis processes and best practices framework.
I have seen so many times when the philosophy is one size fits all.
So no matter what the task or activity assigned,
they use the same templates, tools or whatever.
Be creative and use the right level of effort for each analysis context type.
Apply the right level of effort for each context type.
So we have our analysis activities, Gather,
Specify,
Analyze & Recommend, and then we have our business context types
along the top, System or Product, Business Unit,
and sometimes we use the term program, Enterprise,
and sometimes we use the term strategic. At the intersection of
the analysis activity and the business context,
the analysts will apply their best practices in the
most optimal and efficient manner.
So in that intersection or cell, you will have listed your tools,
templates, presentations,
etc. that best support a lean approach to the requirements development process.
Maybe this is all in Confluence or SharePoint for easy access
and maintainability by your whole team.
Obviously,
you could extend this model any way you see fit.
Here is a simple framework example.
We have chosen the view the world by analysis activity versus business
context, and wherever they meet will reside all of the artifacts,
processes, templates,
etc. that we need. Now you can choose to view the world any way you want,
and it could map to and reflect how your company is organized and
operated. And you can see at the intersection of the Analysis Activity
and Business Context are things like backlog templates and Agile
analysis process documents and materials,
maybe stakeholder presentation materials,
system design template with workflows and state diagrams,
etc.
Let's see how we might extend this framework.
Here's a product or system example.
You can extend this model as you see fit. In this case, we will find
the top access to represent operational work based on ticket sizes. We
decompose ticket activity into three areas, from a ticket where the
estimated work is less than 24 hours, tickets between 24 and 40 hours,
and tickets over 40 hours, which, in fact, could even be projects.
These intersection cells are not dumping grounds
for a bunch of bloated documents.
They contain only what's needed, including process templates,
backlog templates, etc.
Always think lean, only what you need, not too much and not too little.
Maybe in another case,
we want to look at the vertical access of Analysis
Activities. And instead of Gather, Specify,
Analyze & Recommend, maybe there's other elements in there or
decompositions of those that are shown. Here is a short list of
potential candidate framework items, checklists,
templates, and samples, recommended tools to use, best practices,
artifacts from previous projects, training required, Agile iteration
templates and structure, continuously update and improve the
repository for the framework at all times.
I am sure you have tons of artifacts that could be used or reused
and improved so that you can quickly jump start any activity you
have and apply Lean to your own processes.
Can you imagine how helpful this can be for new hires or
new people transferring into your team? A common flexible framework is lean and supports an agile environment.