Why Agile & Lean Make Users Nervous. Whenever new ideas, processes
or approaches are introduced into a business,
it creates many challenges. Adapting easily to change
is not that natural for many of us,
especially when there are established business norms.
So what about the users?
Do you need your customers or users to buy into
Agile or Lean development approach?
It would be best if they all did,
but they may still want to know how much will it cost and when will you be done?
Do they really need to know about Agile? To optimize Agile benefits, all
stakeholders should be involved and follow Agile principles and adopt an
Agile methodology like Scrum or Kanban. But you may be fighting an uphill
battle since all requirements first and software second is still so
ingrained in many companies today.
So maybe begin with a few iterations 100% dedicated to requirements
gathering and iterate with more detail until you get a reasonable
rough estimate and schedule for the client.
That was the approach we took in my consulting company.
Let's face it,
would you hire a contractor to build you a house if he didn't tell you
how much it would cost and when would it be done?
I think not.
Customers,
users, and stakeholders absolutely need to be informed and educated about
Agile and Lean. Business people want to save time and money,
and Agile and Lean will save them time and money.
Remember those relationship and communication skills we talked about?
Well,
now you can put them to good use because you will need them to
convince your stakeholders a better way to go.
Here's some ideas on why users are uneasy and nervous when introducing
and using Agile and Lean into their organization.
Users want budget predictability.
Agile requires a huge leap of faith for customers who are used to
hard budgets and fixed bids, as many people are,
especially in the CFO or more financial roles.
Users want technology predictability. Users want everything, don't they?
How do you balance maintenance versus new features?
A traditional detailed requirements document might reveal issues that
would appear in an Agile project at a much later stage.
Traditional versus the appearance of disorganization and never‑ending.
Users worry that development teams will avoid providing estimates,
documentation, and plans,
and Agile and Lean give the appearance of never‑ending work.
It's just iteration by iteration by iteration.
That's why I always recommend having one or more iterations for
analysis artifacts to rough out estimates and plans.
This will help alleviate the fears of management.
Oh boy, yet another way to make software.
Some users are overwhelmed by a new methodology and how
collaborative and interactive Agile projects are.
Users will see this as an increase in workload for project involvement.
Remember, you need that product owner involved daily,
and if they're not involved in an Agile or Lean project,
it's less likely that it will succeed, only proving their fears.
Change is scary.
Adopt Agile/Lean over time and gradually incorporate it into
your analysis and development processes.
Be patient.
Also, it never hurts to have executive sponsorship. That's a must.
Agile and Lean approaches will have a good chance of taking hold if you
have executive sponsorship. Without executive sponsorship,
a grassroots effort may be a course of action. And if so,
have patience and look for small wins.
Don't leave your users or customers defend for themselves.
Educate and support your Agile/Lean users. Find ways to give
users some sense of predictability by demonstrating functional
deliveries at the end of every sprint or with Kanban daily. Earn
their trust incrementally.
This will take some time.
Give users enough information to make good decisions such as backlog burn down,
priorities of features, value to the business,
quality estimates, and the like.
Make sure you talk to all your stakeholders.
We spent some amount of time on stakeholder management in the previous modules.
Don't use developer buzzwords.
They'll never like those. Adopt Agile techniques gradually.
So think back to the relationships module.
You will need to use those skills and capabilities to
educate and support your users, stakeholders, and customers. This is important.