Now, for my point of view and module summary.
Where do you fit in or feel the most comfortable doing your job?
You likely have spent most of your business analysis career
in the areas of user stories and features,
and maybe even with epics.
In the next module, we'll go into the enterprise realm, that is themes.
As you move from left to right, I believe you need greater experience,
maturity,
interpersonal and communication skills to be more effective and successful.
So, let me ask again, where do you fit in and where do you want to go?
Here is my point of view, my thoughts and opinions.
Programs are not projects.
Many projects can be contained in a program.
Many companies do not use the notion of programs and
instead just call everything a project.
It's not what I would do,
but everything in this module still applies whether
we call it a program or a project.
For business units and program type work,
a higher level of business analysis skills are required.
Sometimes the role title may come by many names:
program manager or project manager, or just manager,
or senior business analyst.
Or, they may not even be defined in your organization at all, but should be.
You may have to be assertive and creative,
and simply take on the role and get the job done.
Here are the key points and summary of the business unit
or program level requirements module.
What makes programs different from single systems is we
are now covering large scale systems, applications,
products or suites of products, and then organizing Agile teams at scale.
Our goal throughout this module is to manage the
effective use of business unit resources,
whereas in the previous module,
your analysis is mostly focused on the product or system features,
now you are also focused on how best to implement
those features across a business unit.
That takes strong analysis and interpersonal skills.
We discussed the organizational construct of a program management
office that would lead or guide a large program.
We also noted that the same activity can be performed by a
senior business analyst or a project manager,
or some other title.
Not every company embraces the program concept.
We emphasized your important role to translate epics into more detailed and
refined notation in the form of features and user stories.
Next we then proposed a method to optimize the
workload of features and user stories,
and assign them to the backlogs of your Agile teams.
We looked at the backlog as having feature items or service items and how we
might want to factor those out across different teams,
where subteams will focus on the user stories and other on services,
and yet others will be hybrid teams.
So in some cases, you'll want a team to not only implement features,
but also include them in your backlog service items,
and, in fact, that might be more productive than otherwise.
All managers and executives want to know when they will be getting something.
Yes, I know,
the Agile approach just says you'll get it when you
get it after every iteration, but trust me,
executives don't care about Agile, they care about revenue or business,
so you will need a release roadmap,
and I provided you with approach for that as well.
That will provide a level of comfort and trust to the stakeholders. Up next, gathering requirements for the enterprise.