Consider the viewpoints of others.
Sometimes when we start our analysis activities,
we don't spend enough time or effort really trying to
understand the makeup of their user community.
Let's take a closer look.
So, who are the users?
And we use the term users quite broadly, don't we?
Users are people who will use the results of your analysis,
say, a new feature, or even an entirely new system.
Now customers.
This is a broader term, which includes users plus others,
like the management of the users who may benefit from the results
of the system, but not literally use the system.
Who are they?
Do we design the system for them too? Sponsors. Typically executive or
senior leaders that want to see the results of your analysis and how that
will benefit them and the business ‑ costs,
deployment, customer impacts, and things like that?
IT professionals.
These folks are responsible for the development and
support of the systems and applications.
You may need them to provide you with information to support your
analysis activities, as well as they may be the people who must implement
the results of your work. Subject matter experts,
sometimes known as SMEs,
are key resources that may be scattered throughout the
organization that you need to complete your work.
There may be other categories, certainly, but I likely got most of them.
Notice my icons on the left side of the slide are all representations of people.
I hope you like working with people.
I believe that the most successful analysts are
people‑oriented and relationship‑oriented.
I like people, hence, I enjoy the analyst role.
All of these "users" have different viewpoints, that is different wants and
desires that they need completed to fulfill their requirements.
In one sense,
I like to use the term stakeholder in a broad way for all of these
interested invested parties I've listed above.
Now let's drill into the stakeholder concept.
Multiple stakeholders ‑ single focus. In your job,
performing business analysis for a new project,
for example, you will encounter the following stakeholder types.
System stakeholders are users of the system or works with the
results of those who use the system, or possibly will be impacted by
the deployment and operation of the system.
Then there are the project stakeholders, whose interest in your project is
about the project's financials typically, such as cost, budget, and schedule.
These stakeholders may be the business leader and those who care about how the
results of your analysis may be implemented,
such as developers and other IT professionals, and still others who may
be involved in installing and maintaining the system.
You need to consider these communities for a complete
analysis of your task or project.
Their requirements and ultimate expected outcome may be different and competing.
Therefore, your role is to provide a single focus,
which may also be known as the product owner,
project manager, senior analyst, or simply, business analyst.
Your job will be to ensure that the requirements are
aligned across both of these communities,
as well as manage the myriad of expectations towards a singular outcome.
This could be challenging indeed. As a business analyst,
you will need to integrate diverse viewpoints by
performing the following additional roles.
To begin building your relationships,
you need to collaborate with all stakeholders and champion
their needs and desires, let them know you care, and will do
everything you can to gather, specify,
analyze, and recommend their needs to provide the highest value to the business.
This begins your journey to establish trust. As you work with them, you may
play the role of facilitator, working with each stakeholder to find common
ground so that the entire community can accept a combined outcome of your
work. And other times, stakeholders will look to you to lead, to make
decisions that are tough, and to pull all the viewpoints and requirements
together into a unified specification.
Please note, the larger the number of stakeholders, the greater your collaboration, facilitation, and leadership challenges will be.