Next are my final words and closing remarks for this course. Wherever
your career path may take you, always remember, the bottom line is
your ability to deliver business value.
Do not forget that. It is one of your biggest assets as a
professional. Thank you very much for taking my course.
It's been my pleasure.
I, like you,
have been challenged over the years on how best to
provide value to the business.
My mind is constantly focused on it. I hope and trust that this course
has been able to provide you with the essential tools,
methods,
approaches, and renewed confidence to help you be more
successful in requirements development.
Lastly,
I hope I see you again in one of my other courses, and I wish
you the best in your professional journey. Never stop learning!