The BA's role and responsibilities on an agile, lean team.
In my own experiences,
I typically have not seen BAs in general as regular members of agile teams.
The BA role seems to be played by the developers themselves,
and to a greater extent, the dev lead.
That's okay, but sadly and mistakenly,
the BA role has either been overlooked or
inadequately resourced on agile, lean teams.
This section will outline where the BA's role will give
you the biggest bang for the buck.
Here are the typical responsibilities of the business
analyst as an agile or lean team member.
As a member of an agile, lean team design,
a BA role should be considered for every team.
It may not be relevant for every team,
but the BA role should at least be considered.
Based on the nature of the makeup of the team,
the complexities of the user stories, and your available resources,
sharing a BA across multiple teams is an option,
certainly, just like a DBA or QA role may not be full time either.
So you usually have a full‑time core team and some other
members adding value as needed by the core team.
The BA as a part time member.
So in a perfect world,
the dev team is one single group of people performing
multiple iterations and getting more efficient,
that is, improving their velocity with every iteration.
A BA may be on several agile teams working part time on each.
I think this is a great value, helps manage limited budgets,
and adds value to the business.
But that is not how it usually is in the real world.
Resources vary and the business analyst skillsets vary,
therefore,
be flexible in how you allocate your business analyst
resources for an agile or lean team.
The BA needs to really focus on supporting the team to deliver
features and components to add value to the customer.
This helps increase the value of the BA to be on the team.
Quickly and efficiently focus on resolving any issues or
questions on features and user stories.
The software engineers will greatly appreciate your
effort, and further respect you.
If there are budget or resource issues, you want the software engineers to say,
hey, please don't take my business analyst away,
they remove requirements roadblocks and make my life easier.
The BA role may fluctuate over time as requirement needs will
vary during the lifecycle of a project.
The BA is interfacing with the product owner to track down and
resolve any questions on business rules,
requirements, user stories, and priorities.
Now let's talk a little more about the relationship
of the BA and the product owner.
In this example, we have the business analyst partnering with the product owner.
The product owner fulfills the product owner role completely,
and the business analyst augments the product owner's role when
they are too busy or away from the office,
such as providing additional business analysis for
improving the backlog items' quality.
Furthermore,
the business analyst works with the product owner and other key
business experts to clarify requirements and user stories.
Executives and senior managers will typically describe
requirements in large and fuzzy epics, and hence,
the BAs will perform more analysis to deliver more
granularity on the epics and the user stories.
This is essential for the success of the development team, certainly.
You can't program fuzzy requirements.
Also,
they can perform analysis to validate priorities as set by the product owner.
The product owner may make some quick priority swags,
and then you, the BA,
can further determine what priorities would be the best for the business.
Develop rough estimates for backlog items.
Estimates are key in helping product owners prioritize work.
It greatly helps in giving them a relative value for each.
And lastly,
represent the product owner in agile and lean
planning activities such as standups.
This keeps the project moving forward when the product owner is busy elsewhere.
In this situation,
the BA is either reporting to this business organization or
maybe is on loan from the IT department.
Now I will illustrate how I see the level of effort of a business analyst
interacting with the agile process flow with the product owner,
so ideas, concepts,
very chunky epics and lucid‑defined features and requirements in business terms.
The BA is helping the product owner convey and relate
this information to the dev team.
When designing the agile project,
the BA will be able to describe the idea or concept with some
detail at the epic level and in business terms.
When designing the agile releases,
the BA will be able to describe and explain user stories with
conciseness in business terms and help lay out the features or user
stories to be included in each release.
When designing the agile iteration,
the BA should be able to describe and explain user stories
with conciseness in business terms, and which users
stories can be in each iteration.
And with daily work, to be able to answer requirements,
questions or issues about the user stories.
Now, the brightness of the orange represents the level of
effort of the BA in this process flow, brighter on the left,
and less so as you move to the right.
On the left moving right,
it is likely that the BA will spend more time with the product
owner and in project and release planning,
and less in iteration and daily work planning.
On the left, we have more pure business and on the right more pure technology,
hence,
the BA is supporting and enhancing the translation of those
business requirements into technical implementations.
Since business people are great at business and technical
people are great at highly technical activities,
it allows an opportunity for the business analyst to bridge the gap between the business and the technologists.