Let's go through an example of identifying and classifying stakeholders.
It is very important before you run off and start gathering
requirements that you clearly know who you are doing it for and
with, so identify and classify your stakeholders.
Here is a scenario. You have a new analysis project and
here are the steps to do just that.
Step one, identify and get their contact information
and determine their stakeholder type.
This may change after you have interviewed and begun
building your relationships with them.
This is not in concrete, but a starting point for your activities.
Step two, determine their involvement.
In what way or role do you need them to cooperate with you, inform, consult,
partner, or decision maker like we talked about in the previous section,
and it could be more than one of these for each stakeholder as well.
Step three, determine the interaction you want with them.
Identify the forms of communication and interactions for each person.
Now let's look at a specific example.
Here is an example on how to prepare to work with your stakeholders.
Let's say you have a new analysis assignment and you've been given the
task to develop the requirements to add the ability of dealers to order
accessories when ordering a new motorcycle.
You are assigned to the IT department and have been given a few names.
Before you begin, you want to get your act together,
set up a simple grid to start the process.
We have the stakeholders names, the contact like senior VP of sales,
stakeholder type like system stakeholder, involvement like decision maker
and when you think the interaction would be like weekly, and the
interaction format like status report. Now,
as your work progresses, you may add people and add new
columns to keep track of other information that I haven't
thought of, so be creative.
This is a living document and change it any way you want to, but this will
give you a great overview of who your contacts are and how you have to work
and relate and build that relationships with.
There are tons of other interaction formats,
and here are a few, face‑to‑face meetings and workshops,
telephone and email, presentations, standups,
texts and instant messaging, video web conferencing,
wikis, and other requirement portals, and Teams, and
Slack, and other tools like that.
So which of these options will facilitate connecting
with your stakeholders? Maybe one, maybe all,
maybe a blend, and maybe each stakeholder would like a
different type of format that works best for them.
Please accommodate your stakeholders.
We now have a new artifact, so add it to your analysis framework.
Remember our analysis framework from the last module? This is now
a best practice for you and your team to use so you can name this
best practice stakeholder prep and add it to our framework for
future use and improvements.
This approach works for any business context. It'll be either system,
business unit, or enterprise.
In fact, the bigger the responsibility, the more stakeholders you will have,
and thus this makes this approach even more important.
Every time I create a new artifact in the progress of my
work that I deem important and reusable, I immediately add it to my framework.