Now let's look at how you can work with your product owner
to develop and create your user stories.
This is important to emphasize.
User stories are at the heart of agile requirements‑‑ from the product
owner's backlog through development and implementation.
The entire process rides upon high quality user stories.
As we discussed in the relationship module previously,
you've spent the time with your product owner to define your relationship.
Now you can get down to business and ask, let's have a look at your backlog.
You never know what's in it or what the format is.
Let's see what she has.
It is rarely in user story format, and that makes sense, really.
Product owners know their business and have not likely
learned how to write a user story.
And that is just fine.
And that is why you are there.
We will talk more about the user story format in a few slides.
Quite common, it's in a spreadsheet format.
This seems a pretty popular medium, which is just fine with me.
It may have some screenshots, text, workflows, and a collection of well, stuff.
Maybe it's a Word document, and again, with the same kind of content I
just mentioned, and maybe even a wiki, like confluence.
Or it may be a very detailed, structured,
traditional style requirements document.
I had one given to me in psuedocode style.
Yeah, really! Since it was almost impure code,
I couldn't figure a thing out, since I was much too close
to the trees to see the forest, so it took a while to
unwind that into user stories.
Sometimes content quality is simply just inadequate.
I look at this as a challenge and a great opportunity to
learn about the business and build a fun and rewarding
relationship with the product owner.
So be prepared for a myriad of formats and content quality to contend with.
Let's discuss the BA's challenges with normalizing
the backlog into user stories.
As you know,
a product owner is a person from the business who typically represents
their business community and represents their needs.
As you can imagine,
product owners come in all makes and models with various backgrounds,
from purely business to highly technical.
Therefore, the nature and quality of the backlog may widely vary,
and it may be very unclear.
The English language can have a lot of ambiguity.
Plus, the team is learning about the domain and its terminology,
so discussions may ensue, all good. And a backlog may have multiple styles.
Many times,
the product owner is gathering requirements from all the
other departments or organizations,
and hence, different people wrote different items
resulted in different writing styles.
It is the goal,
then, of yourself to refine those writing styles and try
to standardize and normalize them.
Backlog items can be very high level.
Sometimes the backlog item is at such a high level,
it will require additional refinement. Sometimes, like the example I
gave in a previous slide, it's at a very low level,
so this is the flipside.
Some items can be way too detailed to be in the backlog.
Maybe it's more like a task than a real requirement.
Also,
the product owner is still learning. The product owner may be learning not
only about their business domain, but also about backlogs,
agile,
lean, and other things, so please give them time and respect they
need to come up to speed. Priorities based on need.
Now, need is interesting and can be tricky.
Initially,
you might be presented with an item of high need, and you
believe it is just not that important.
For now, just sit tight.
Don't presume you know everything. Now, you might be right, but give it time.
Listen, seek to understand, and show empathy for the need.
Remember, they don't need the new system for fun.
They have a business to run, so it's up to you and your team to normalize,
if you will, the originally presented backlog into more actionable material.
That is what we will be doing in the next section.
Educate, collaborate, and define your relationship with the product owner.
So let's say you meet them for the first time. Before you get into the
backlog on user stories and all that stuff, first,
do the following.
Educate the product owner on the actual process.
Talk about its value, how the backlog works,
how iterations of user stories work, and that they are in control.
That is key.
They control the backlog and their priorities.
Of course,
there is collaboration and give and take in the agile process as well. Work
to collaborate and partner with your product owner. So describe how you will
help write user stories, how you will analyze their fuzzy ideas and needs,
and normalize them into user stories.
Maybe give some examples. In your initial discussions with the product owner,
you will define how you will work together.
That is, what will be the product owner's
responsibilities and what will be yours.
It is not clear cut, since every product owner is different
based on their background and knowledge.
Every relationship I have had with a product owner has been unique.
Come prepared with a simple PowerPoint presentation so that
you have a template on what to talk about.
It makes these discussions go smoother.
These topics include how you will educate them on agile or lean, and
how you will collaborate and define user stories.
Remember we talked about the secret to successfully gather
business requirements? That is building a solid
relationship with your product owner.
Always work to improve your relationship.
I can't tell you enough how important this is.
Your projects will go much smoother and be more successful.
As discussions proceed with normalizing user stories,
be sure to observe the level of understanding, the level of confidence,
and the quality of discussions with your product owner.
Watch the body language and be intent on assessing the degree of
understanding. If you see soft spots, jump in and clarify. The process to
normalize the user stories is a mechanism for you to learn even more
about the business domain and to further illuminate the product owner's understanding of the requirements.