We have talked about business themes,
and now let's turn our attention to architectural and technology themes.
So what about architectural and technology themes?
We have focused on business themes, which makes sense,
and most themes are likely to be business themes or business theme oriented.
But today, no business should ignore architectural and technology themes.
Technology is, or is becoming, the heart and soul of every business.
And in fact,
architectural themes are required for the success of business themes today.
So it really boils down to this, what architectural or technology do you need
in place so that your business themes will be successful?
It is likely that no business theme will succeed without some
architectural or technology enablers to support it.
Here are a few architecture and technology examples:
implement remote voice and video corporate wide,
and maybe the supports want to more business themes,
such as allow all employees to work from home. Enable data storage,
processing, and analytic solutions in the cloud, and this technology
theme supports remote storage for all employees,
enabling better data management, working remotely,
and security of corporate data.
Roll out all new laptops with the latest OS to all employees.
This theme supports, at a basic fundamental level,
all business themes. Migrate remaining on‑prem computing to the cloud.
The cost of operating on‑prem computing keeps going up and up.
And maybe by migrating to the cloud,
we will not only save operational costs, but provide an agile
and cost effective platform for our future.
Typically, architectural themes are large,
complex, and require major investments and management oversight
using portfolio management. Business themes,
as you know, drive business epics, and tech themes drive tech epics.
So all themes drive epics and are placed in the epic backlog.
Typically,
the technical business analysts will assist in the
development of technical epics.
Now the BA also has a role with architecture themes and epics.
They will help articulate the architectural and technology
themes to support the business themes.
Of course, timing is important.
If you don't have the technical infrastructure in place,
the business themes will not be fulfilled.
Help translate to architectural technology themes into
epics and ensure they are visible,
estimated, and planned just like business epics.
Help translate the architectural and technology epics into features and ensure
they are visible, estimated, resourced, and in a release. Help ensure technology
features are further translated, refined, and articulated into technical user
stories. And again, your involvement will be heavier in the beginning and will
lessen as you move down through to the user stories. You need to ensure tech and
business themes are in sync, technically and from a fiduciary responsibility, as
well.
The tech teams know their stuff, certainly,
but you need to be sure that the business epics will be implementable
via whatever technology or architecture is proposed by the technical
teams. You will convey, describe, translate those business
requirements to the technical teams so they fully understand what the
technology theme needs to do, and at the right time. Releases need to
be coordinated.
Also, you will gather timelines, estimates,
budgets,
etc. from the tech teams and work with portfolio
management to ensure the tech and business themes are in sync with the investment expectations.