Now let's go into more detail with Epic
Identification and Creating Epic Backlogs.
Translating themes to epics,
your main job would be to identify and describe epics from
the theme or themes you are assigned.
You will likely be on a team, well, I certainly hope so.
That is definitely a team activity to do.
You may be with stakeholders, subject‑matter experts,
product managers, analysts, IT experts, or others.
Remember, themes are high level and usually fuzzy and,
therefore, need a lot of refinement.
So you and your team will perform what I call normal requirements
gathering‑‑analyze and document requirements further,
validate and prioritize requirements further.
This activity, though, may not be suited for detail‑oriented analysts.
Epics are still very high level,
and you'll be working more with visionaries and not nuts and bolts stakeholders.
Suffice it to say, there'll be a lot of talking,
fact finding, business case development,
timelines, budgets, and all that going on.
Here are a few more activities you will be doing.
You will be using all your business analysis tools
that you are already familiar with.
Workshops.
I find I get the most out of stakeholders when you roll up your sleeves
and get on a white board and really brainstorm ideas.
I do find it a bit harder to do this activity remotely with video conferences,
but do what you can.
Workflow and data modeling.
For me, workflow means process, and everything has a process side to it.
And, of course, data.
Without data, we have nothing.
Business and technical architecture modeling.
I look at this as sketching out some high‑level building
blocks that may become part of the underlying platform
supporting one or more epics.
High‑level cost estimates.
Without estimates,
your stakeholders will have a tougher time prioritizing your epics.
Incremental reviews with stakeholders.
Hold as many stand‑ups and review meetings as possible.
Error on the side of more, not less.
Communications.
Always keep everyone up to date with regular status and presentations.
And you'll be roughing out implementation opportunities and options as well.
And business cases of course.
Just because you figured out a few epics does not mean it makes sense to
implement if there's not a sufficient business case to do so.
The outcome of doing these things at the epic
enterprise level is they will be high level,
less detailed, and may give some of you an unsettling sense since you,
if you're like me, like specificity over fuzz.
But I have learned over the years to like and appreciate things at a high level.
It's important to feel good and comfortable about high‑level,
fuzzy requirements because that's what executives usually like to give us.
Let's now prioritize our epics.
Now you have your compiled lists of epics.
How do you know which ones to do?
Just like any other backlog, you will need to rank or prioritize each one.
Every organization or department will be different,
so come up with your own criteria to support a common
process of prioritizing your epics.
Keep it simple, lean, and agile.
You do not want long, drawn‑out estimates or research but a quick way to decide.
So maybe look at value.
What is the potential value of doing this epic?
What is the level of effort?
What are the risks of doing or not doing this epic?
And what's the estimated ROI, or return on investment?
Now this is just a short starter list.
It will be up to you or the portfolio management team to come up with one
and only one criteria so that then you can ensure that all epic backlogs
have been prioritized fairly and equitably.
Now that we have our epics, let's keep it going to features and user stories.
A prioritized and approved epic is pulled off the backlog.
It is assigned to an epic owner.
Now that could be a program or project manager,
maybe a business unit manager or business analyst.
Their portfolio management office manages and tracks all epics,
as we discussed previously.
Now let's get from epic to feature and user story.
The BA supports and guides development of the features and user stories.
The BA may join the team or only act as an adviser.
Now we go from user story to software development.
The BA may join the agile dev team or maybe just be an adviser.
There are countless combinations that may work.
Different skills and varying resources will drive the types
of assignment a business analyst may get.
Now everyone is down to doing the real work,
so we made it from theme all the way down to code.
Let's do a visual recap.
Here are our sources and stakeholders for themes such as Board of Directors,
Executives, etc.
They drive our themes,
some business and some architectural and technology oriented.
Let's take Theme A.
That will drive a backlog of epics.
Now let's take Epic 2.
That will drive a backlog of features.
Now let's take Feature 4, and that will drive our list of user stories.
Hopefully,
all this can be generated automatically by some great cloud‑based tools,
like Jira and countless others. So check those out.