Here is my point of view and module summary.
There may be an organizational influence on the business analyst's role.
For example, the BA is organizationally with the product and the product owner,
so you are reporting into that organization.
Or the BA is organizationally in the information technology organization, okay?
Or in some companies,
the business analysts are organized under the finance
organization under the CFO and maybe also in a project
management office also known as the PMO.
All three work, and there's no right a wrong way.
Every company is different.
If you have an affinity to the business,
then you might prefer working in the product organization
and partnering with the product owner.
I have found that product owners need the most help
than any other role on the agile team.
And if you have an affinity to IT and technology,
then I would suggest you work within the IT or
technology part of the organization.
And lastly,
if you come from a business or MBA background, working closely
with the CFO or finance part of a company may be more rewarding
as well. Consider your professional passion when choosing your
next position in a company.
Here's my point of view, thoughts, and opinions.
Do you need a scrum master?
Personally,
I think agile scrum teams can learn the role of the scrum master easily.
Now,
if you are in a large company and have 50 agile teams, then
certainly having a few scrum masters ensuring all the teams are
following the scrum process makes sense.
Who makes the best product owner?
Certainly someone who really knows the business and can
devote the time and attention to your project.
Since that's not always the case,
you have a great opportunity to jump in and really
help the product owner be successful.
Can't find the right business analyst role in your company?
Well, go make that role. Be proactive.
Suggest to your management the role you think would add value to the business.
You will be surprised on how easy it is to chart your own
path in your company. But focus on how your recommendation
will add value. And good luck.
Now, you might want to check out my Pluralsight
course, The Technical Business Analyst,
where I go into great detail about the skills you need to be a very
successful business analyst in today's world. In this module,
we covered how the business analysts can contribute to requirements
development for a new product, and here are the key takeaways.
We discussed the composition of the agile product team and how the BA
is a member of that team, though the BA's membership on the agile lean
dev teams is underrepresented, in my opinion .Normalizing the product
backlog. We learned that the product backlog can have all sorts of
odds and ends in it,
and that the business analysts can normalize those odds and ends
into succinct user stories that can be understood by the product
owner and the technical developers.
There are some other benefits to normalizing the backlog as well.
Besides creating quality user stories,
the process itself to normalize the user stories is a mechanism for
you to learn even more about the business domain and to further
illuminate the product owner's understanding of the requirements.
For user stories to be effective,
they need to follow the user story template, the three parts being the role,
the goal, and the benefit. Use INVEST as a checklist or a
mechanism to develop better user stories,
resulting in better outcomes, thus yielding more value to the business.
No matter where you are organizationally in your company,
you will have the best success with your projects by partnering
closely with your product owner. Up next,
gather requirements for the business unit.
This is where we take a broader view of requirements gathering. I'll see you there.