Here's my point of view and module summary.
This module is titled Relationships, the Secret to Successful Requirements,
and I hope you think so and agree as well.
But the secret has yet another secret, trust.
Here are a few guidelines to think about to further build trust with
your business stakeholders and colleagues. As you begin each
engagement or encounter with your stakeholders,
have clear and consistent goals. Always know where you are going,
the big vision, the projects, and down to the daily tasks.
This will help your coworkers and your stakeholders have a better
understanding of what you are proposing or aiming for and what the
end game may look like and how the teams will know when they arrive
at a conclusion or solution.
And, as we mentioned before, be open and listen.
This builds trust and shows compassion.
Your business coworkers will come to believe that they are
understood and feel they are being listened to.
Not only is this respectful in all encounters,
but you will also actually get more honest input to do your job better.
Being open and honest builds trust.
Be decisive.
Wishy‑washy is an ineffectual quality in your position.
Would you want to see the CEO of your company in a very serious situation say,
gee, I don't know.
What should we do?
This does not mean that you have all the answers,
but it does mean if you don't know something,
you'll take the action to find out. You are not perfect, so admit mistakes.
This shows you are human.
And even if it was not you perse who made the mistake, take
one on the chin and show responsibility.
This will build trust as well. Respect the opinions of others.
Always listen.
It does not mean you have to agree, but you do have to listen.
Then, be decisive and make appropriate recommendations or
decisions and explain your reasons objectively.
Manage expectations.
This is a biggie.
Every single stakeholder interaction is an opportunity to manage expectations,
meetings, emails, phone calls, status reports,
presentations, the water cooler, and more.
Never pass up these opportunities to further connect with and
communicate with your business stakeholders and coworkers.
Now you can't be robotic or stiff or go through this
list like it's some sort of checklist.
You need to be sincere,
and it should come naturally because these qualities are who you are.
Here is my point of view.
Everything we talked about helps build strong relationships.
You absolutely need them to be the most you can be.
And it's all related, interpersonal skills,
a healthy connection with your stakeholders,
leadership skills, trust, communication skills, and collaboration.
They all fit together to support great relationships.
Here are the key points of this module.
The toughest part of requirements development is the
process which results in helping users discover that what
they need provides business value.
The secret to developing quality requirements is through influencing,
nurturing, and cultivating relationships with all of your colleagues.
We categorized our stakeholders where some need to be informed,
those that need to be consulted, and those that are more like partners.
And finally,
the decision makers. Thinking of them in this way provides a method to
better target how we want to relate and work with them.
We expanded on that to develop our stakeholder preparation document.
This captured their involvement and how we want to interact with them and,
of course, feel free to add any attributes that make sense.
There are activities that we can use to foster
collaboration and enhance our relationships such as
workshops, discussing potential solutions,
one‑on‑one meetings, team meetings, and standups,
to name a few.
It is a premise of this course that the business analyst is typically the
integration or touch point between IT and the business.
This is a big responsibility, requiring interpersonal and communication skills.
In fact,
interpersonal communication skills are the
underpinnings of a quality leader. And lastly,
always strive to build and sustain trust with your stakeholders and peers. Up next, The Evolution of Requirements Gathering.