(Music) Hi everyone.
My name is Tyler Griffiths, and welcome to my course,
Spring Retry: Getting Started.
If you love Spring, you'll love Spring Retry.
It's a great way to alleviate some of the pain points
associated with microservice environments,
and it's painless to implement in your existing application.
In this course,
we're going to add retry to an existing microservice application that's
probably very similar to applications you work on.
Some of the major topics that we will cover include adding
retry to Spring's venerable RestTemplate,
configuring custom retry policies such as backoff and max attempts,
fine tuning retry by specifying specific exceptions to retry,
and pain points that retry can help you avoid.
By the end of this course,
you will know the basics of Spring Retry and be ready to implement
Spring Retry in your existing microservice environment.
Before beginning the course,
you should be familiar with Java and have a basic
understanding of microservices and Spring Framework.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn Spring Retry,
with the Spring Retry: Getting Started course, at Pluralsight.