This is a beginner level course,
so we're going to keep the prerequisites to a minimum.
For our environment setup, we'll need to install JDK 8, IntelliJ IDEA, and Git.
I won't be demonstrating installing those items,
but I've included the download link for their respective installers.
In terms of knowledge,
I'm assuming you have some familiarity with Java or other
object-oriented language such as C# or C++.
If not, Java Fundamentals: The Java Language,
by Jim Wilson, would be a good place to start.
I'm also assuming you have some familiarity with Git,
specifically cloning a repository and checking out branches.
If not, don't worry,
I'll be demoing how to clone and check out the needed
branches for each of the modules.
Lastly,
since our sample application operates in the context
of a microservice environment,
it wouldn't hurt to know something about microservices.
Microservices: The Big Picture, by Antonio Goncalves,
is a good reference, though not required.
The SaaS Bass sample application consists of two self-contained microservices,
the Bass Tracker Service and the Lake Profile Service.
We'll talk more about these services shortly,
but suffice it to say for now that each service has its own repository
that you'll need to clone into a local directory.
I've created two public GitHub repositories for the two
microservices in the sample application.
You can access the Bass Tracker Service using this URL,
and the Lake Profile Service using this URL.
To clone the repositories, you can click on the Clone or download button,
which will display a URL.
I've organized these repositories by module using Git branches.
If we look at the branches for the bass-tracker-service,
we can see that I've prefixed the branch names with the module name,
followed by either initial, final or the pain point name we're simulating.
This makes it simple to check out a branch and push play to see what it does.
I'll highlight which branch to check out for each
service as we simulate pain points.
Assuming you have all the prerequisites installed for the environment,
let's clone the repositories and get our services set up to run in IntelliJ.
The first thing we need to do is clone the bass-tracker-service and
lake-profile-service repositories into a local directory.
There are many ways to clone a repository,
but for this demo we'll use IntelliJ's Check out from Version Control feature.
We will copy the URL we got from the Clone or download
button in GitHub and paste it in as the URL.
Now we click Clone.
It may ask if you want to open it.
We'll be importing the repository manually, so we won't open it at this time.
We'll do the same for the lake-profile-service.
After cloning both services into a local directory,
we're ready to import them into IntelliJ.
To do that, we'll use IntelliJ's Import Project feature.
Starting with the lake-profile-service, select Maven as the import model,
Next, leave all the defaults and click Next,
and Next.
Make sure JDK 1.8 is selected, and then Finish.
It will take a moment to index the module.
Once it's indexed, let's import the bass-tracker-service.
Select Maven as the import model, leave all defaults,
and make sure JDK 1.8 is selected, and Finish.
To start,
I'm going to show a high-level overview of how these services work together,
and then we'll dive into the gory details of how they are built.
Let's start with the lake-profile-service.
First, we need to make sure we're on the correct branch for the module,
so let's check out the correct branch.
Next, we'll create a run configuration for the lake-profile-service.
Make sure to select the class with the main method and leave
everything else at the preset defaults.
At this point,
we can run the lake-profile-service and verify that we see the web
service has started and is running on port 8080.
After lake-profile-service is up and running,
we can switch over to the bass-tracker-service.
We will check out the correct branch for the module,
then we'll create a run configuration for the bass-tracker-service.
All right, now we're ready to run the bass-tracker-service and see what happens.
Basically, the bass-tracker-service posts a request to the lake-profile-service,
and then it gets the lake profile it just created. We can see the returned Lake Profile object in the logs.