Now that we've implemented custom exceptions,
let's talk about socket exceptions.
We've been using a socket exception to indicate a generic server error.
But in reality, there are multiple types of server errors.
The two server errors that we're concerned with are
HTTP 500 errors and HTTP 503 errors.
An HTTP 503 error should be retried due to its temporary nature,
whereas typically an HTTP 500 error should not.
Let's get more specific about server errors and see if our retry
configuration does what it should for them.
To follow along with this demo,
for the Bass Tracker Service check out the
adding-custom-retry-exceptions-server-error branch.
For the Lake Profile Service,
also check out the adding-custom-retry-exceptions-server-error branch.
We have our lake-profile-service set up as usual,
but for this demo, instead of throwing a socket exception,
we're going to return an HTTP 500 code on the GET endpoint
and an HTTP 503 code on the POST endpoint.
With this setup, we should except that the createLakeProfile call should retry,
and the getLakeProfile call should not retry.
Let's switch over to the bass-tracker- service and run it.
We see that indeed the createLakeProfile call retried and the getLakeProfile call did not and returned an HTTP 500 error as expected.