We've seen how adding basic retry has helped SaaS Bass
with temporary socket exceptions.
Now, let's see what it can do for timeout exceptions.
In the SaaS Bass's case, timeout exceptions are caused by temporary I/O latency.
As a reminder,
we've configured the LakeProfileClient to throw a
timeout exception after 3 seconds.
Let's see if adding basic retry has alleviated this pain point for SaaS Bass.
To follow along with this demo, for the Bass Tracker Service,
check out the adding-retry-to-rest-template-timeout- exception branch.
For the Lake Profile Service,
also check out the adding-retry- to-rest-template-timeout-exception branch.
In the lake-profile-service,
we're simulating a socket timeout exception by sleeping for 4
seconds for the first two GET requests.
As a reminder,
we've set our socket re-timeout threshold in Bass Tracker Service to 3 seconds.
By sleeping for 4 seconds,
we will trigger a timeout exception to be thrown in LakeProfileClient.
You can imagine that this could be simulating a database or other microservice,
causing I/O latency for the Lake Profile Service.
Let's run the lake-profile-service,
and then switch over to the bass-tracker-service.
The bass-tracker-service remains unchanged from the
module branch for this simulation.
The CommandLineRunner will create the LakeProfile in a separate thread,
wait for 3 seconds, and then try to get the newly created profile.
Let's run it and see what happens.
As we would expect,
even basic Spring Retry has given SaaS Bass respectable safeguards against timeout exceptions.