Last, but not least,
let's simulate a resource race condition and see if adding basic Spring
Retry can alleviate this pain point for SaaS Bass.
As a reminder,
resource race conditions are a hazard introduced by the
asynchronous nature of microservice environments.
To follow along with this demo, for the Bass Tracker Service,
check out the adding-retry-to-rest-template-resource- race-condition branch.
For the Lake Profile Service,
also check out the adding-retry-to-rest-
template-resource-race-condition branch.
Starting with the lake-profile-service,
you can see that we haven't made any changes from the
module branch for this simulation, so let's go ahead and run it.
Switching over to the bass-tracker-service,
we've made one simple change,
and that is to bypass the sleep between creating and
getting the LakeProfile resource.
This simulates a truly asynchronous situation in which the resource is
being both created and requested at the same time.
Let's run the service and see what happens.
Oh no.
It seems we've found the pain point that can't be alleviated
with a basic Spring Retry implementation.
As you can see,
we get a 404 not found error because the resource can't be created fast
enough before Spring Retry stops attempting to get it.
This is because, by default,
Spring Retry does not wait or back off in between attempts.
Not to worry though,
in the next module we're going to add custom retry policies and,
spoiler alert, fix this pain point for SaaS Bass. Stay tuned.