Last, but not least, let's simulate a resource race condition.
As a reminder,
resource race conditions are a hazard introduced by the
asynchronous nature of microservice environments,
and are typically caused by developer error.
Even so,
SaaS Bass wants to guard against resource race conditions as much as possible.
We'll discuss how retry can alleviate this pain point for SaaS Bass.
To follow along with this demo,
for the Bass Tracker Service check out the
getting-started-with-spring-retry-resource- race-condition branch.
For the Lake Profile Service,
also check out the getting-started-with-spring-retry-
resource-race-condition branch.
Starting with the lake-profile-service,
you can see that we haven't made any changes from the
module branch for this simulation.
Switching over to the bass-tracker-service,
we've made one simple change,
and that is to bypass the sleep between creating and
getting the LakeProfile resource.
This simulates a truly asynchronous situation in which the resource is
being both created and requested at the same time.
Let's run the service and see what happens.
We get a 404 not found error because we've now essentially run both
the create and getLakeProfile calls in parallel.
So the LakeProfile resource can't be created fast
enough before we attempt to get it.
This is because, switching back to the lake-profile-service,
we have a simulated database latency of 2 seconds.
If we would have retried the getLakeProfile call for
slightly longer than 2 seconds,
the resource would be available and we wouldn't get a 404 error.
This scenario can be prevented by being more careful with parallelization, but adding retry adds an invaluable safeguard in the event of developer error.