Now that the core basics about nodejs and expressjs are set,
it's time that we work more on what the user sees because ultimately, we obviously want to build an application
which delivers some value to our users, right? Now
thus far we're always returning static html pages and typically this is not what you do in real applications
because you don't just have static html code
most of the time, instead it is pretty common that you have some data managed on your server,
later we will also do that in a database, that you have some data on your server which you want to
dynamically output in the html code you send back to your users.
An example would be a page with a list of products
where these products of course are coming from your database,
so from your server. Or for example, we already have a very simple form where people can submit a new
product title,
well right now we're not really doing anything with that, in a real application
you would obviously want to store that and then kind of return it in some other page where you have
that list of products I already mentioned.
So in this module, we will have a first look at how we can start managing data on a node express backend,
for now without a database,
no worries there will be a very extensive module about the databases in this course so you will learn
how to interact with a database too
but for now, let's just manage data like this and let's focus on something else here, on rendering dynamic,
for now dummy content in our views.
So these html pages which we're returning should now become more dynamic and actually contain some content
that is dynamically entered into them on the server, so that if we had additional data on the server,
we would send back a different html page with different content.
And for this, we'll use something called a templating engine and you will learn how such templating engines,
there is more than one alternative
and I will present some alternatives in this module,
you'll learn how they work and how you can use them.
So this is what's in this module
and with that, let's dive right into it and let's have a look at how we could manage that data before
we then have a look at how we could output it.