Welcome to this optional, that's important, optional module where I want to introduce you to the javascript
basics and this module is really just a quick refresher.
I do expect you to have some basic knowledge about how javascript works, what you use it for and it's
base syntax.
This module does not replace that,
you can't really use that module with zero
javascript knowledge or at least it will be very very challenging.
But if you only get some very basic knowledge or it's been quite some time since you worked with javascript,
then this module will be a great refresher.
Please skip this module if you already know javascript though because then this module is not for you,
so you don't have to be an expert to skip this, if you know javascript and you also know some of its
next-gen features like the rest and spread operator or object destructuring,
so a bunch of nice things that we can do in javascript, definitely skip this module and maybe come back
later if there is some feature you don't recognize or you're not sure what it's all about.
If you don't have that knowledge though, this module is for you and also have a look at the next lecture
where I provide links to helpful resources in case you're brand new to javascript because there are
some free resources that allow you to get started with javascript after which you can come back to this
module and the rest of the course where you will need that basic knowledge.