We worked a bit on the cart model, some things are still missing
for example we never display our cart and we also never really, we're not able to delete an item from
the cart but let's ignore that for the moment,
let's instead focus on editing a product.
We've got the edit product ejs file and in the end what I want to do in there is I want to render
the same form I have for add product,
the difference will be that I want to pre-populate that form with the values of the product I want
to edit.
Now if I'm using the same html code in the end, it would make sense to reuse the same template. If you
ever plan on using a different one, it doesn't but here it makes sense.
So what I will do is I'll take my add product.ejs code and move it into edit product because I find
this to be the more generic name and I'll delete the add product.ejs file,
so now we just have edit producte.ejs with all the html code in there that we need.
Now first of all, that means that I have to load that file in admin.js
when we load get add product, I no longer need the add product path here, I need edit product here only,
the part down there can stay add product because that is what we use for highlighting a certain navigation
item. By the way we can get rid of these additional information pieces.
So now this should still work, if I click on add product
I still see that form,
so that's looking good.
However for editing a product, I now also want to have a route and I want to use that same view, so
I'll copy that route
here and add it maybe below post add product to keep these two together
and here I will have get edit product as an action name and I also want to render edit product here.
The difference is that here I plan on passing in my product information
but the problem is of course how should I reach this controller action
and my idea is that since I already have my edit button here,
if I click that I don't want to call edit product like this,
I also want to add the ID of the product I want to edit.
So if I grab a real ID from my products.json file like this one,
then I would have that in the url
and if I load this, now I want to have the form pre-populated with the data for this product and if I
hit the save button, I of course don't want to create this product but simply edit the existing one. Now
this means that I need two things,
the ID I need to pass that and the information that I want to edit a product instead of create it.
Well if we go to our admin routes, we can add a new route
first of all, this edit product route here with the ID and you learned how that works actually, you
can add a new route here, get route
will be at slash and then here, the /admin is available for all routes in the admin.js file
anyways as you know, so it's just edit product
and then the ID and again this is a variable,
a dynamic path segment indicated with a colon. And then we can load the admin controller and there the get
edit product
action we just added.
So this is step number one
and actually, we now already can go to our admin.js controller
and here we obviously know that we want to edit a product.
So what we can do is we can pass an additional information field to our view editing and set this to true
maybe so that we can check this with an if condition to find out
for example if upon clicking that save button, we should try to add the product and send a request to
that route or try to edit it and send it to a different route.
But let's say we want to get an additional confirmation by ensuring that people have to pass us a so-called
query parameter in the url. A query parameter can be added to any url by adding a question mark and
then a key value pair separated by an equal sign, like edit equals true
and you can have multiple query parameters by separating and them with and percents,
so we could also have title equals new for example.
So this is possible
and this is so-called optional data,
the path here, the route which gets reached is determined by the part up to the question mark.
So you don't need to add any information about query parameters
you might get to your routes file, these paths are not affected but you can