So right now, our get products page is a bit broken because there we still use fetch all in a way that
well simply does not work, we don't have this callback approach anymore
so we have to remove that and instead we still want to render our view here in the end
but we can pretty much copy the code we have here on get index
and of course you could also therefore refactor this to use a shared function.
But there, I now also have my then block and catch block and I will simply replace the render function there
to not render the index page but the products page and use the rows as products. By the way,
you can of course get rid of that field data,
you don't need to extract that because we're not using it,
I just wanted to show you how you can extract the different elements of an array in the argument list
already.
With that if you save this, the products page will also work again.
Now that's all nice,
what about add product?
Let's tackle that next.