Now there's one thing which I also want to cover in this module and that are the http status codes, which
codes do we have and why do we use them?
Let me first of all start with what the codes are
therefore. The codes are simply extra information we pass to the browser which helps the browser understand
if an operation succeeded or not.
If you're writing an application with a lot of client side javascript or a mobile app and you will fetch
only data instead of complete html pages, something we'll do in the rest
module later, status codes also allow you to understand if an error happened, which kind of error because
you typically map certain kinds of errors to certain kinds of status codes.
For example you have 200 status codes,
most importantly 200 and 201,
these are always success status codes,
they indicate that the operation simply succeeded.
You have 300 status codes which simply indicates that a redirection happened.
You have 400 status codes which show you that something happened because an error was done by the client,
for example incorrect data was entered into a form,
well then we return this 422 error code
if you remember correctly and we have 500 status codes which indicate that a server side error occurred.
Now here are some examples, you can find a full, a link with a full list in the lecture after this one. For success
cases we have 200 and 201, the difference is that we use 201 typically when we created a resource on the server,
so in the database, it's not a must but it's a pattern you can use and you see often. 300 like 301
simply is a code that is used in combination with redirection to inform us
whether for example this resource moved permanently or just temporary thing, whatever. The 400 codes,
there we have 401 if we are not authenticated, 403 which you could translate with not authorized
so you might be authenticated but you were still not allowed to do that specific operation, 404 for a
page that's not found, 422 which we often use for invalid input and a couple of other error codes and for
500,
the most common one is 500 which indicates hey there was a server side error but you got also other codes
for timeout and so on, again in the next lecture you find a full list.
Now let's quickly scan through our code. If we have a look at our code,
let's start with the admin controller,
we rarely set a status code.
The default then always is 200 which is fine for this case but for creating a new product, it would be
better if we not just render 422 when validation fails
which is correct but that when we succeeded, we also return 201.
The thing just as if we succeeded, we redirect which will use a 300 code
but later when we dive into creating restful APIs which is a different kind of node app where
we don't return html but just data, there you will see the
201 code coming back, here it doesn't really make sense.
Now forget added product again, we're fine with 200 and we're fine with 200 here.
If we did fetch data and we do load the page and if we try to save or update a product, then we get our
validation error with 422
and if we succeed or in all cases here, we redirect which again will use 300 automatically.
So all these codes here are pretty fine, pretty decent,
one of the most important things, we're in good practice at least is that we do use 422 for validating.
Now we also have isAuth.js where I do redirect when we are trying to do something where I'm not logged
in.
Now again since I'm redirecting, I'm sending a 300 status code but of course we could add status 401 here
to kind of also make clear what the problem is
but it will be overwritten with a 300 code due to redirect,
so it does not make a lot of sense and that is fine here.
Later again when we have a restful API where we don't redirect because we don't route around on the
server, then we'll use that 400 code. And for that reason that we now most of the time redirect or directly
render a page,
we don't set that many status codes here,
we'll see them later again as I mentioned and we see some codes at least, also in error.js
where I set 404 and 500. And these status codes not mean that our app crashes,
that's important to understand,
instead if I do enter some invalid route here, I do get page not found
and if we open the chrome developer tools with the network tab and I reload, we see that here, this 404
code can be seen,
it's also marked as read because chrome is intelligent and detects that anything which is not a 200 or
300 code is an error but error does not mean that it crashes.
This still renders a valid page in the end, we just pass that extra information of
hey here's the page but you see that page because something went wrong
and chrome knows this too,
for example tell us in the developer tools and later when we create that restful API I referring to, we'll
also benefit from that because there we do have a more direct interaction with our requests because
we don't render new pages all the time
and then we can get useful information out of these status codes.
So that is http status codes and how they are related with errors,
your key takeaway is a status code does not mean that the request failed or that the app crashed.
We had some problem and now we're returning information with the problem to the client
and that is also a way of gracefully handling errors.