So to pre-populate this form with the product data, we need to fetch the product first,
so for in added mode here after not being redirected, then I want to get my product information. For this
I need the product model which I already have and I need the product ID, prod ID can be retrieved from
the incoming request because if you check the routes real quick, we have that dynamic segment here,
so by this name we can extract the Product ID.
So in admin.js, here I can set or I can access request params product ID and get that ID from the URL.
Therefore I can then use my product model and find this product by id and then here, I have my callback
where I receive the product that was retrieved and by the way of course, you should also try to add
a check to see if you have a product and redirect the user in case you don't but let's do it like this for
now.
So here I will now get my product and I will then render this page assuming that I always get a product and
pass my product on a product key and you can name this key whatever you want of course.
And we can for example add a check if we don't have a product, so if this is invalid, if it's undefined
then we could return a redirect for now which is not the best user experience,
most of the time you would want to show an error instead
but let's now, for now do it like this.
So we assume we always make it here and we get the product in the view now,
so let's move over to the edit product view. And here first of all let's work on that button.
Right now it's add product
but I want to change that button caption if we're in edit mode.
Now remember we're setting this editing property here so this is a variable available in the template.
So here I simply want to check if editing and then add a curly brace,
if this is true then I actually want to display the edit or maybe update product text here on the button
otherwise and for that, I'll close the first if block here and add an else block still in my ejs tags
of course.
So otherwise here if we're in this else block here, I want to show add product and thereafter I also have
to close my curly brace of that if statement. If I now reload this page, we see update product correctly
and by the way if I go to add product, I'll now get an error because editing is not defined.
So to fix this, I also have to make sure that in my controller, for showing the add product page, I set
editing to false of course. And now here reloading this page will work,
going back to the editing page will show us the update button.
Now that is one step, back to the template
I don't just want to show the caption here,
I also want to change the action. So here on the form, the route we're sending the request to should also
change of course.
Right now it's always add product but it should only be add product if we are not in editing mode.
So here indeed
I will also output something dynamic,
I will check if we're editing,
so I'll have the same logic as for the button
and if this is the case, I went to load /edit product let's say, otherwise I'll close that and have
my else block open up, so otherwise this is my ejs else block, I'll add add product into my url here
and I can inject these segments into the url
because this will just be converted to normal text in the end.
This is what ejs does or or what all templating engines do.
So also close that curly brace of the else block here and with that if I save this, we should make
sure that if we click that update button, we go to edit product.
Well let's go back and let's see if we can pre-populate this with product information.
Now keep in mind that in admin.js, I am retrieving the product, whoops not here but here in get edit
product and I pass the product information into my view.
So therefore in the view, we can of course use that
and we can set it on all our inputs, here on value,
I also want to check if I'm in editing mode and if I am, I want to display my product information, if
I'm not I don't want to do that.
So same logic as before,
I'll check if I'm editing, if I am then I will display product title here because this is the title input
otherwise I will not do anything and therefore I don't even need an else block,
I just do this if I am in editing mode
otherwise nothing will happen.
So if I now reload this, we indeed see product title and the issue here is that of course this is simply
output as text, to output the real value behind it,
we need that equals ejs tag here nested into our other ejs tags like this,
so this was now added, equals unclosing with a dollar sign greater than sign.
And this can be hard to read,
you simply have to divide it up in blocks, you've got if, then you've got the output and then you've got
the closing curly brace for and with that saved if you now reload, you'll see the real title behind
that. Now let's do the same for all the other values,
so I'll just copy that value here real quick, for the image url.
I obviously want to output image
url, for the price.
I want to output product price. For the description we get a text area,
so here I will not have value equals, I'll just output the value between the opening and closing text
area tags
and here I'll output the description. And with that all saved
if we reload, this is looking good
and now we can start editing our products.
Now I want to hook up that edit button so that we can really load the product and this newly added view.
So let's do that
and then also work on the functionality to store the updated information over the next lectures.