That's it for this module. We had a look at the different types of errors and how to handle them.
You can differentiate between a couple of different errors,
there are technical errors where you get this error object and where some place in your application
throws an error with the throw keyword and you can do that on your own or some package or express or node
itself does this
and you can handle these errors with try catch or with then and catch in a promise for example
and there are expected errors. These are errors which are not technically errors,
there is no error being thrown, at least not necessarily
but there you could be dealing with invalid user input and invalid email or some file access that should
work most of the time but might fail occasionally. Depending on how you treat that,
if you throw an error or not, you might still need try catch or then catch here as well but you could
also just use an if check to see does that e-mail address exist in the database,
so normally if check could do there. And if you want to throw an error or if you want to forward
an error in then or catch, you learned that you can use that global express error handling middleware
of which you can have multiple which are then executed step by step,
you can use that and express will automatically call it whenever you next an error or you throw an error
in synchronous code.
We also had a brief look at status codes and it is a good practice or it is definitely something you
should consider, that you set the right status codes on your responses so that you don't always return
200 codes but that you instead let the browser know about certain issues
and that will become more important later in the rest API section of this course when the browser gains more
power, when more UI logic is executed in the browser.
And you've got different types of status codes,
you can have success codes, the 2x codes, redirects,
client side errors and server side errors
and you should look at all these codes and see which code is best set for your scenario, your use case.
Important
as I mentioned, when you set a status code, this does not mean that the app crashed or that the response
is incomplete, it's simply an extra piece of information you pass to the browser.