So we added csrf token protection but it will only work if we are visiting our get index page.
Now we want to have such a token and by the way also, our authentication status on every page we render.
What we can do to get it onto every page is we can remove it from our render function here and instead
tell expressjs
and this is now totally unrelated from csrf thing, tell expressjs that we have some
data that should be included in every rendered view.
We'll do this in the app.js file and there after this middleware where we extract the user
but before all our routes, I'll add another middleware, a normal middleware with our normal middleware function
with the three arguments and in there, we can use a special feature provided by expressjs, we can access
a special field on the response, the locals field.
This allows us to set local variables that are passed into the views, local simply because well they
will only exist in the views which are rendered.
So there, we can add our isAuthenticated property which I removed from the render function where I access
request session is logged in
and I can also add my csrf token variable which I get from request csrf token from this function.
So now for every request that is executed, these two fields will be set for the views that are rendered
and then we have to call next so that we are able to continue. With this if we go back and we reload
this page, seems to work, seems to work
and now let's also try signing in where we also have a post request
and now this fails
and now do you know why? Well
because I do pass my token into all views but in the views, I still need to use it.
So for that, we have to repeat the code we added to the navigation,
we need that hidden input with that name and that value
and we have to add it into all our forms and that is something you just have to do.
So for example here in the Add to Cart post form, we need that hidden input with the csrf token and also
in admin edit product, we need somewhere in that form that hidden token input. The same for our auth routes
of course, when logging in we need that hidden input and the same for signing up,
this is required. In the products.ejs in the admin folder, there
we also have a form for deleting a product, we need the token in there too.
And in the shop in the cart, we also have a delete cart item button, we need the hidden input there as well
and also down there for the order now button, this also sends a post request and we need our hidden input
there, our csrf token. On index.ejs
we don't need it, in add to cart
I just added it so there we already have it, in the product list page, it's the same, it was added
to add to cart and on the product detail page,
I also only have add to cart. On the orders page here,
we also have no post form.
So now we should have this token everywhere where we need it
and if you save all that and you now go back to your let's say starting page and you visit the login page
and you do login,
this now works because we have that token, we also can add items to the cart,
we can also order them,
well there is an error which we'll fix in a second.
So for now let's not order them but let's delete them,
this works and generally this works.
Now let me fix this bug here which is not related to the csrf token in the next lecture real quick but this
hopefully and that is the main takeaway here, shows you how to use csrf protection and this is a
crucial thing which you have to add to any production ready application,
it's not optional
otherwise you'll have a huge security issue on your page.
You need to add this to ensure that your sessions don't get stolen.