So let's sum this module up
now.
First of all we had a brief refresher on how the web works and in general, it looks like this, client
so the browser sends a request to the server, the server does some magic, reaches out to a database, works
with files, sends back a response, can be
html, can be something different and sends it back to the client, the browser which then can display
that
and that is the entire flow we also saw in this module.
Now nodejs is the part that runs on the server
and regarding its lifecycle, there is one important concept and that is that so-called event loop.
Nodejs code runs in a non-blocking way which means we only register a bunch of callbacks and events
and nodejs will eventually trigger that code
once a certain task is done, so that the javascript threat is always free to handle new events, new incoming
requests and stuff like that. And node program can exit if there is no more work to do
but on a server, this well should at least never happen because create server registers an event listener
for an event which is never done,
if a new event is triggered, so if a new request is received, this does not mean that node unregisters the event
listener
instead we keep on listening for more requests and that is of course how a server should behave.
So it's this cycle that's important to understand and that we have this loop which always keeps on going,
keeps on waiting for new events and which does something when some event happens and then basically
dispatches some actions to the operating system you could say for example
and then again frees up the threat.
Now this also involves a lot of asynchronous code which we saw with all the callbacks. The javascript
code should be non-blocking,
so we have this callback and event driven approach where we are able to register some code to be executed
in the future instead of running right away and blocking the main threat because this has to be avoided
under all circumstances and nodejs is built around that concept of avoiding this issue.
We also saw how to work with requests and responses
the nodejs way. We saw that we have to parse the requests data which arrives in chunks and that we can use this
concept of streams and buffers which I explained and that we should avoid sending double responses
so that after res
end, you must not send another response and this can happen easily if you forget about that asynchronous nature
and that a line of code you write might not execute immediately.
So depending on where you write it, if it's in an event listener, it will not execute immediately.
That is what I mean
and that is what is important to keep in mind here. We also learn that nodejs is all about using it's
built in functionalities
and whilst there are some global variables or objects or functions we can use, this also means that we
should use its core modules. Core modules are things like the http, the fs or the path module,
there are more and you can learn all about them in the official nodejs docs of course, we'll also use
quite a lot of them throughout this course and these core modules give us a couple of different functionalities
that allow us to basically do whatever we ever could want to do on a server like create a new server
with the help of the http module. They're
imported via the require syntax
and we can only use them in the file into which we import them
and if we want to use them in two different files, we have to import them in both files separately.
Now that leads us to the node module system and this basically works with the help of this require
keyword which pulls some functionality from one of our files
if we start with slash or ./ or from a core or third party module, we haven't used any third party
modules thus far
but we'll also do that soon
and it basically pulls in whatever we export there and stores it in a new variable or constant as we
did it in this module.
And export is an important keyword here,
we do export with the help of module.exports or for multiple exports with the export shortcut
I showed you in the last lectures.
So this is what we learn in this module
and I know that this was a lot of theory or nitty gritty stuff about
nodejs. Doesn't look too easy and beautiful but it'll get way more beautiful from now on,
it is super important to never forget what nodejs is and does it for you though because many courses
right away start with expressjs which we'll also use starting soon
and therefore you never really learn what's happening under the hood which is sad because this is important
and makes you a better node developer.
But with that, let's move on.