So I added a message box in the last lecture, you can download the finished version of the entire project
attached,
I simply added css classes to my div which surrounds the message
and then I worked on these classes in the main css file,
I added user message and user message error and also added some user message entry to my desktop sys
classes. So you can add this manually from the attached code,
now one thing you'll notice is that even if you load the login page regularly, you'll see an empty box
here.
So even if no message is flashed, it looks like error message is not set to undefined and therefore let's
quickly go to auth and let's simply console log request flash error to see what's in there that's
causing this to not be undefined
basically. So if I reload this page, I see it's an empty array
and if I do enter something here, you see
it's an array of messages.
So in the end what do we want to do is we want to extract our message here is equal to request flash
error. Now if message length is now greater than zero, then I know I have a message in there,
so now I'll actually turn this into a variable by using let here and then I can set message equal to message the
first element because I want to retrieve that otherwise I'll set message equal to null and now down there,
we can use the message and pass that as an error message. If we now save that, don't have the box here, if I
do enter something invalid,
we do see the error message though
but if I go to the login page regularly without an error, I don't see it.
So this is now how we can use these flash messages and output them in a nice error box.
Now here's also a challenge for you,
find some other places in the login and sign up screen
where it would make sense to flash other messages onto the screen.
We'll do it together in the next lecture.