So I clicked add to cart in the last lecture and we're now failing to do this
and if we go back, we actually see an error that request session user add to cart
is not a function.
So we somehow fail to execute our Add to Cart function, so basically our functions that normally are
available on the user object
and why is that? The reason for that is that previously, in previous setups, we always store the user
in the request and this was a per request action anyways and we fetched that user for every request
in the middleware in app.js,
right,
so we fetch the user from the database and mongoose automatically gave us a full user object not just
the data in the database but the full user model with all the methods and we stored that user model
in the request, with the session
this works a bit different. With the session
we are not fetching this for every request
instead we store the user in our session upon logging in here.
Now what happens to the user there?
Well it gets stored to the database.
If we refresh there, we can see here is our user object
and this is now just the data.
Now for every new request, the session middleware does not go ahead and fetch the user with the help
of mongoose, it fetches the session data from mongodb,
that is correct but for that it uses the mongodb store and the mongodb store does not know
about our mongoose models.
So when it fetches the data from the session database, when it fetches this data, it only fetches the
data,
it does not fetch an object with all the methods provided by mongoose.
Now what can we do regarding that? Well
one thing we can do of course and now we're reverting back a bit, we can re-add that middleware which
we had earlier here after we initialized our session.
So here I have my general middleware which we used before to store our user in the request and we can
take our logic from our post login route where we fetch a user for a given ID, move that back into that
middleware,
so exactly what we had before,
instead of redirecting we'll call next so that the incoming requests can continue with the next middleware
but in here, we don't want to store anything in the session because the session is already something
which will be managed for us automatically and for the incoming requests, we register the middleware, the
middleware will then basically look for a session cookie, if it finds one it will look for a fitting
session in the database and load the data from there.
So by the time we reach this middleware, we'll have our session data loaded.
Now this means that now we just want to use that session data to load our real user, to create our mongoose
user model and how do we do that?
Well we don't need to reach out to the database again,
instead we can again set the user for this request only
and now here I want to create a user based on data stored in the session,
so data that persists across requests and I will create that user and store it in the request user which
will then only live for that request but it's fueled by data from the session and therefore it also survives
cross request
you could say and I simply need to do that because I need a mongoose model to work with, because the
data we store in the session storage in mongodb there, well we retrieve it as just plain data not
as a mongoose model with all the cool methods mongoose gives us and that is why we get this error
regarding add to cart not being found and so on.
So here I will initialize request user and actually I don't want to find a user by id like this,
I will find a user by reaching out to request session user id. This make sense I guess because that
is the data, the user is what I store in my session and I want to get the ID and then find that user
in the database with the help of the user model which is provided by mongoose of course
and then here, I get back a mongoose model user which I store in request user and this is exactly what
I need now to make sure that I have a mongoose model to work with so that all these cool mongoose
methods work again
and now we need to adjust admin.js and shop.js again and replace requests session user with request user
again because that is where I'm storing my mongoose model user.
So let's do that, in shop.js and in all the files where I do use requests session user,
I want to mark these all with command or control D and revert it back to request user because now we store
our mongoose model in that request only object again, do the same in admin.js.
So in, not for logged in because that's just true or false, we don't need to turn this into anything but
for all the places where I do use my request session user here,
all these places which should only be one here is now request user again.
Again this will not mean that it's now only existent for this request,
the mongoose model object is but it's fueled by data that's stored in the session and therefore data
that persists across requests. And now that we saved all of that,
let's go back and let's try adding this to a cart again
and now this works as before as long as I'm logged in, if I do log out we now get an error, that error is
now stemming from my app use function which is triggered for every request and this will simply fail
after logging out because request session user ID is not set there.
Well we can fix this in this app use function
app.js by checking for the existence of requests session user
and if we don't have one,
so if I don't have a user stored in my session, then I can just call next and I return next so that the
code thereafter, this one will not be executed,
this will only run if we do have a session user.
So now with that, we can safely reload the starting page, this works.
I can login again, I can add this to the cart,
I can also add this from the cart from the details page,
I can delete this and I can log out and this should all work.