So that's it for this module,
again we learned a lot and practiced a lot. You learned about dynamic routing and that you can pass dynamic
path segments by adding a colon to the express router path, the name after the colon is then the name
by which you can extract the data on request params. As a side note
you can have more than one dynamic segment per route,
this is absolutely possible.
You can also work with optional query parameters,
these are the parameters you append with a question mark at the end of your url and you can have multiple
ones separate with an ampersand and you can extract these values with request query and then the name
of your param.
Now you don't need to register or name these parameters in your route registry,
you totally don't add them there,
you can just start extracting them but since they're optional, you should also have a check in place
to see if that parameter was passed
in case you are depending on it. We also continued working on models and we added a cart model which only
holds static methods because we don't really create a cart that often, instead we just want to work with
the data storage behind it. You also saw that you can interact between models,
for example delete a cart item if a product is deleted
but as I also mentioned towards the end of this module, it's not that good if we only work with files
for data storage because accessing them is a bit slow to be honest
and in general, there are better options,
most importantly of course, databases.
So let's move on to how we can work with databases in a node express app in the next module.