So how does sending mails work?
Well we obviously get our node server with our code and we get our user and we want to send an email
to that user.
Now it's super important to understand and a common misconception that node and expressjs, these are
language or frameworks runtimes that we use for writing our server side logic but with nodejs,
you can't trivially create a mailing server. Handling mails
is totally different to handling incoming requests and responses,
it's a totally different technology, something totally different happens behind the scenes.
Therefore in reality, you will very likely never implement your own mail server because that is a very
complex task,
creating a mail server that is capable of handling thousands or one hundred thousands of e-mails
at the same time, sending them and so on, security, all that stuff is highly complex,
so in reality you typically use third party mail servers for that and that is exactly what we will
do in this module too
but I will show you how to interact with such a service to send that e-mail through that service.
And by the way all major web applications you might be interacting with including Udemy don't have
their own mail servers, they are using third party providers like AWS or whatever it is for sending
e-mails,
so that is exactly what we will do in this module too.