I'm back in the project and I actually changed the html code and the styles a little bit, you'll find
all css files and html files attached
and just make sure to move the html files into the views folder and the css files into the css folder in the
public folder.
I did this to
well change the styling a little bit and also add a little bit of additional markup which we'll use in
this module but no worries, I will walk you through all of that markup
and regarding the styling, it's just a little bit nicer to look at right now
and I also added some styling which we'll need in this module. So with that, I can of course visit the page
on localhost 3000
and this is how it looks like right now,
a little bit nicer than before in my opinion but of course you can always style this to your needs
but let's now focus on the data.
And right now, we don't really work with data in our app
right in
admin.js for example, we do get that data for a product here in a host route but we just log
that to the console,
we're not storing it,
we're not working with it and working with it is kind of hard right now because we have no database
where we could store it permanently
but one thing we can of course do is we can store it in javascript variables and see how that works
and if these are then shared across incoming requests from different users and that of course will hold
some important learnings because you often well don't want to share such data.
So let's see how that works before we then later in the course move towards a more permanent database
driven solution.
So let's say the incoming product title which we output here should be stored in a more permanent place
and in general, I actually want to also add some fields to the form then later so that we can add
more for a product than just the title but step by step.
So let's start storing that title which we get here
and just to bring that back to memory,
right now we got this field here
and if I submit this, well then I get this object with the key title and the value the user entered.
So how can we store this?
Well we could add a variable where we store it in and the first thing we could try is we could add a
variable here in admin.js, let's say we create a new constant here which I'll name products which is
an array and keep in mind even though it's constant, the array can receive new elements because the array
itself is still the same object,
we just add or remove elements to it but that doesn't affect the overall holding object.
So now I got my products here and I actually want to export my products,
so what I'll do down there is I will use a different syntax where I export
my routes and export a router here and exports products and export my products constant. This has one
important implication, since I changed the way I export my routes,
I have to go to the app.js file and with that in the app.js file where I import my admin routes here, well
actually this is the admin data and there, I want to access the routes object because there will be such
a routes object because I'm creating it here.
So admin data refers to all the exports you could say and there we now have routes and products and
therefore when I do import my routes, I have to import them like this, of course admin data is then also
something I have to change up here
in the import.
So now I got this adjusted and now I got my products exported too, products is an empty array.
Now in here, in router post let's take the products and push a new element into this array, a new object
let's say
and that object will have a title which is the title I'm getting, so request body and keep in mind that
also is an object with the title property
so I will extract the title with the dot notation,
I could of course just push the overall request body since that will be an object of the exact same
structure
but later I want to add more fields here and therefore, I will create a new object here, also to make
it a bit clearer to see what's happening here.
So now we're adding this to products, now in shop.js where we output all our products or where we want
to do that at some point, we therefore need to get access to the products and for this,
let's add an import up here, let's import admin data by requiring admin,
so this admin.js file where we do export its routes,
something we're not interested in in this file
but also this products array,
so now here let's console log admin data products so that should be the array.
Now save everything
and now let's simply see what we get.
If I reload this page, the shop page, I get an empty array which makes sense because initially, this
is an empty array,
we export it,
that makes sense.
So let's go to add product now and let's add a book here and it clicked add product,
we're back to the shop page and we see something interesting.
We see the array with the book inside of it and that console log statement, where is this actually coming
from? Well that is coming from the shop.js
file here, we can also make this clearer by adding shop.js here and logging the products, so logging two things
to make it clearer what is responsible for the output,
so shop.js is logging the empty array
and now let's try outputting that book here
and now we got shop.js with the array with the book in it.
Now this is interesting to see,
so we can export something, some object or array, a reference type therefore
and if we change that in the other file, it also gives us the update here.
So this is interesting,
this is one way of sharing data and to be honest we'll later use different ways because this has one
disadvantage. Here
if I reload shop, we still got that in there.
Now let me open up a totally different browser,
I'm in Firefox here and I also visited localhost 3000.
So this is a totally different browser and this is kind of like a brand new user,
it doesn't share any cookies with the other browser, nothing of that kind,
it used the same IP address but that doesn't matter here.
It's a brand new request as if it were made from a different machine and you will see, I still log
this,
so this is actually data which is inherent to our node server as it is running and therefore, it's shared
across all users.
Sometimes this is what you may want but very very rarely to be honest, actually you will probably never
implement this,
you always want to fetch data for a specific request and if that happens to be the same data you show
for all users that send this request,
this is fine but sharing this data across requests, across users is typically something you don't want
to do because if you now edit this with user A, user B will see the updated version
even though you might not want to show that.
Maybe it's added that normally it wouldn't have been saved to the database yet,
so you don't want to show that to the other users yet,
maybe it's some personal data.
So this is a pattern we can use for now here and it's fine for practicing what we want to practice here
but later we'll learn about a technique to share data in memory here, in the node app across different
requests but only for one and the same user and not across users because now we have shared data across
requests and across users
and we will later of course also learn how to use a database.
But for now let's stick to this approach,
let's use that for some dummy data sharing and let's see how we can get this data into our view now.