So what is authentication?
Well we obviously got our user using our application, interacting with our views and we get the server
and also the database with which our server works,
these are all things we worked with in this course already.
Now in our application, we might have different routes, different actions
a user can do,
we might be able to view all products, to create and manage products or to place orders,
now obviously we can do more things in our application but these are just some examples.
Now the idea behind authentication is that not all these actions are available to every user of our
application
and now here's one important thing, with user I don't mean logged in user, I mean simply a person visiting
our page, visiting localhost 3000
in our case here, later of course the domain under which we deployed it.
So I'm not talking about logged in users but really just people using our page and such anonymous users
who are not logged in should not be able to do all these things,
they certainly should be able to view all products just as you are able to view all products on Amazon.com
even if you're not logged in,
we want to allow this in our shop too.
But there are other things like for example here creating products, managing products and placing orders
which should only be available to logged in users and not to every visitor of our page because in
order to buy a product, you need to be logged in and in order to create a new product, you also need to
be logged in
because in our application, we of course connect a product to the logged in user, we match the two things
and this is what we need authentication for.
We need to be able to differentiate between anonymous users who are not logged in and logged in users
and we need to provide a flow, a view and the backend logic that allows people visiting our page to
sign up and then to sign in and then we can use sessions as I showed it to you in the last module to
store the information whether a user is signed in and well let him interact with the page across requests.
This is the idea behind authentication,
now how is it implemented?