So what are asynchronous requests?
Well we have our client and our server, so the browser and our node application and that's the setup
we had for this entire course,
this is the set up you have with any web or even mobile project that you build these days.
You have your backend, you have your frontend.
Now typically, you send a request from your client to the server and you get back a response
and as I mentioned, thus far in this course, the response always was a html page or a redirect to another
route that then returned a html page.
Now there is nothing wrong with that but there are tasks where you don't want to reload the page just
to for example delete an item and actually in modern web applications, the portion that happens behind the
scenes grows
since we can do a lot with javascript in the browser where we never need to fetch a new html page
but where we constantly change the existing page as this is faster than loading a new one
but that's something I'll cover in the restful API modules.
Now the idea behind asynchronous requests is that you do send the request but that request typically
contains just some data in a special format named json and that data is sent to the server, to a certain
url or a route
accepted by that server,
so that logic doesn't change. The server can do whatever it wants to do with that
and then we return a response and that response is also returned
behind the scenes,
so it's not a new html page that needs to be rendered,
it's instead again just some data in that json format typically.
And that is how client server can communicate through javascript,
so through client side javascript and the server side logic without reloading or rebuilding the page,
without exchanging a new html page. And that allows you to do some work behind the scenes without interrupting
the user flow, without reloading the page.
Now let's have a look at how that would work in this module.