We're coming closer to the end of this module, only the order part is missing and I want to include that
too because this will show you another way of creating relation. With the cart, we had like the middle
way,
the cart is an embedded document but the items on the cart then are a combination of references and
extra metadata.
Now for the orders, this will change.
So let's work on the orders now
and for that I'll go to my shop.js file where we post the order. Again I want to store orders on users,
so in the user model, we can add an add order method and this doesn't take any arguments because the cart
which will be passed as an order or as the data for the order is already registered on this user,
so all I need to do here is I need to add the orders to my user or the other way around.
You could also argue that you want to store the orders in a new collection because you might have thousands
of orders and you don't want to embed them all into user objects because these objects will then
get pretty quick,
carts don't get that big but an order history,
well often that can get very long so I will actually work with a new collection here.
I'll still create order here as a method on my user though, so I'll reach out to my database client and
then reach out to a new collection, orders. There
I want to insert one new order now and I'll return the entire thing and that one new order will be well the
cart
I currently have,
right,
that is essentially what I did before too when I added an order, I added my products in the order model,
we had no special fields for that,
we just had our products and then the quantity of every product
and that is still the same I want to add here.
So you could say I'll insert one and I'll insert my cart,
so this cart which refers to the users cart. I insert this as an order and then when this succeeds, I set
this cart equal to an object where items is an empty array,
so I basically empty my cart at this point.
Of course I don't just want to empty it here,
I also want to clear it in the database,
so we'll also copy that code for updating my user in the database and I will return that here in this
then block and there, I will simply search for that user and set the cart equal to an object where
items is an empty array.
So now I cleared both in the user object as well as in the database
but I also insert the cart into the orders collection before I clear it
and that of course is the important part. With that,
we already are adding the order. Now in shop.js,
in post order where the order gets placed, I can therefore remove all the code up here and simply say
add order, simply execute this method and then redirect
once this is done and in add order, I will store my cart as a new order and you could of course also
add some new fields like the total of value for example if you wanted to
and that is it for now,
so thereafter I redirect.
Now let's see if that works
by going to the shop.js file and re-adding that create order route and let's click order now here.
Now I have page not found because orders, the orders page the route wasn't added again but let's refresh
the entire page here
and my items in the cart certainly are gone but I don't see new orders in the shop database,
I don't see that collection here
but here it is after updating this once with the update arrow in the top left corner and in orders,
I have one order with indeed the items I had in my cart previously and the cart is now empty.
So let's now make sure in the next lecture that we can see our orders page again.