To add payment to our application, let's work on that
checkout.ejs file with which we never work thus far.
I want to go there before I actually place an order when I click on order now in my cart, so I'll go
to this page first.
For that, I'll copy the content of cart.ejs
add it in checkout.ejs to make sure that I have my default head.
I'll get rid of that stylesheet though, I don't need it here,
I want to include the navigation,
the main content will be totally different though,
I will keep my body however, so or my end here.
So with that, I have everything set up to have a basic checkout page,
now let's first of all make sure we reach that before we start adding stripe.
For that we need a new route of course in a shop.js file,
here we have our create order route and in the end what I need is a new route, a get route which we
can name checkout and there,
I want to be authenticated because we can only buy something if we are logged in let's say and
then I'll use my shop controller and there, get checkout which is an action I still have to create. And in
that get checkout page then, we'll have the possibility to create an order and so on.
So for now, let's just add this and let's work on our controller then, on our shop controller and there
I need a get checkout method.
So maybe here before post order because logically, it comes prior to that, I'll have get checkout with request
response and next and in there, I want to render my checkout page. So we can of course grab one of our
other render functions here,
render that, here I will render shop/checkout,
the path can be checkout, it doesn't really matter, we don't have a naviagtion
item we want to highlight, here we can checkout as a text
and of course we need some data for the checkout.
Now what do I want to return here?
Well in the end,
I will need the same data as I have in my cart, so I need my products here which I do have in the cart,
so I can actually copy that entire code from get cart
I guess and add this here and now just make sure we use shop
checkout, path checkout and here,
checkout but besides that I also need to calculate the total let's say. So total sum or whatever you
want to name it and that total sum of course can be retrieved from our product data
because in the cart or in the products here we have in the cart,
you have to keep in mind that products is in an array of products where we have the quantity and
then a product ID field with detail data about the products because we populate this product ID field
with the detailed product data. So therefore, the total sum can be generated by looping through all products,
so here I can do products forEach
and create a new variable, total which is zero initially
and then there, total is equal plus equal this shortcut to add something to the existing total, so total
plus the product and then there is a quantity field times the product product ID price and then it's
this total which I pass to my view.
So that's all the data I should need in checkout view.
So now back in my checkout.ejs file,
now I can indeed grab that unordered list for rendering a list of items
like this, I'll go through all my products.
I'll remove the delete button though, it's too late at this point let's say, we can of course always cancel
the checkout process if we want to though,
actually I'll delete this entire form therefore, this is my unordered list and below that, we can add
a div with a h2 tag of total
and then here I output total sum.
Now let's have a look at that and to have a look,
I need to make sure that on cart.ejs when you click order now, I don't submit this form here,
so I will actually comment this out,
we don't need that anymore
but instead I want to have a normal anchor tag here where I say order now where I simply point at
/checkout,
so this new route we added and I'll just give this a class of button to look a bit like a button. With
all that added,
let's go back to our page,
let's go to products here maybe, add this to the cart and click order now and this is now my,
well a page here.
Now it's not looking super beautiful I'd say,
I need to include that cart.css file again because since I'm reusing the rest of the code here and we could
create our own stylesheet but I want to keep this relatively short, since I'm using all that,
I of course also want to use the same styles.
So now if I reload this checkout page here, it's looking ok,
the total could be placed in the middle maybe, we can do that by giving this div a class of centered
which is a utility class I added earlier in the course and now we have this checkout page.
Again we can always work on the visuals but it's not so much about the visuals here.
So now we have this total and now I want to add stripe and for that, let's first of all set up an account
with them.