I'm back in Visual Studio Code, the IDE I'll use throughout this course and this is again a totally empty folder,
I only got my gitignore file in there because I will use version management here,
git
you don't need to use that at all, if it doesn't tell you anything you can just ignore that,
you don't need that gitignore file.
So I have an empty folder
and again I will now create a new file with command and or by pressing this icon here and this file
can have any name you want
but often you name it server.js or app.js
because it is the root file that makes up your nodejs application,
so the nodejs code you will execute on a computer in the cloud on a server in the end, so I'll name
it app.js here.
Now in this file, I want to create a server through nodejs and thus far in the first module, we only saw how
we can work with the file system,
so how can we now spin up such a server?
We again need to import some functionality because the way javascript works both for the browser and
nodejs,
there is a handful of functions and objects we can use globally without importing anything into the
file
but generally, most functionalities aren't available by default, to not pollute our global namespace
with all these reserved keywords and names basically
and also to make it very obvious in each file on which functionalities this file depends
and thus far, this file does not depend on anything.
Now there are a couple of core modules nodejs ships with and as you will learn throughout the course, you
can also install third party modules which do not ship with node but let's stick to the core modules
for now.
Here are a handful of them,
now not all core modules, just some
and as you can see there is fs which we already used thus far,
there also is path which helps us with constructing paths,
so paths to files on a file system that work on any operating system because Windows and Mac and Linux
use different path formats.
There is the OS package which helps us with operating system, relevant information and so on
and there are the two topmost packages, http and https
and as you might be able to guess, these two sound very helpful when it comes to creating a server and
working with http requests and http responses. And indeed, http helps us with launching a server or also
with other tasks like sending requests because a node app could also send a request to another server,
you can have multiple servers communicate with each other.
For example you could send a request to the Google Maps API to send some coordinates and get back
an address but that's just an example, let's keep it simple here and let's focus on the launch a server
aspect. Https would be helpful when we want to launch an ssl encoded server, so where all that data which
is transferred is encrypted
and as I mentioned earlier, this is something I'll come back to towards the end of the course.
Now with that. let's use that http module and to use it, we need to import it.
So we basically need to make sure that we can use features from that http module which nodejs ships
with but which still is not available globally by default,
we need to make sure that we can use these features in this file
and for this, we import that functionality.
We do this by creating a new constant
and you could create a var or use let too but since we'll have some value here which we will never
change, we can also just use a const to make this really clear that we will never touch this again,
we'll use it but we'll not overwrite it
and you can give this any name you want but typically, you keep the name of the module you're importing.
So I'll name this http
but again you could rename this to whatever you want.
Then you have an equal sign and now we need to assign a value
and now there's a special keyword, a special function
nodejs does expose globally,
so you can use it by default in any file you run via nodejs and that is the require keyword.
Now this is simply the way you import files in nodejs, require either takes a path to another file,
you can also import your own javascript files but we'll not do this for now,
we'll do this heavily throughout the course though
or if you don't have a path to one of your files, you can also import a core module, like http.
By the way, a path to one of your files always has to start with ./ or slash if it's an absolute
path, ./ would be a relative path,
so this would lead to the same folder and would now look for an http file.
By the way it automatically adds .js at the end,
you don't need to add that on your own but you can.
But this would now look for a local file named http,
if you omit ./ or slash at the beginning, it will not look for a local file,
so even if you had a file named http.js, it would not import this file,
let's get rid of it but instead it will always look for a global module named http and indeed, such a module
exists because nodejs ships with it.
So now we got this imported and now we can start using functionalities from that global module and
you can see that if you type http., this is how you access functions or so-called methods and properties
on objects in Javascript and as you can see, this http object which we import from the http module
has a bunch of fields and methods we can execute.
Most importantly, it has the create server method.
Now as the name suggests,
this is a crucial method when it comes to, well creating a server. And create server,
actually if we hover over it
we can see it, actually takes a so-called request listener as an argument. A request listener simply is
a function that will execute for every incoming request
so let's define such a function. For this I'll create a new function with the function keyword,
we can name it however you want,
rqListener or whatever you want, the name is totally up to you and this function has to receive two
arguments,
you can see that here if you hover over that. The request listener receives a request which is of type
incoming message and a response object,
so in short nodejs automatically gives us some object that represents the incoming request and allows
us to read data from that request and it gives us an object response which we can use to return a response
to whoever sent that request.
So now we have to accept these two arguments here and you can again name the arguments however you want,
you just have to keep in mind that the first one will contain data about the request and the second
one will help you send a response, so I'll name it req and res
and these are typical shortcuts you often see.
Now this is a function,
rqListener
and now we can pass this function reference so we don't execute it,
don't set these curly braces,
just pass the name to that function because this will simply tell create server
hey please look for this function with this name and execute it for every incoming request,
so this is now what we'll set up. This function will now run for every request that reaches our server
which will be started by calling create server or almost, one piece is missing,
I'll come back to that.
Now this is one way of doing it.
Now you don't have to explicitly create such a function though,
you can also use a so-called anonymous function.
So here, you can also type function req res, like this,
this is now a function without a name,
that is why it's called anonymous and it still achieves the same.
We pass that function to create server and therefore, node will execute this function whenever a request
reaches
our server. This is an event driven architecture
nodejs uses heavily.
You work a lot with such setups or such code snippets where you tell node if X happens, do Y,
so in this case if a request comes, please execute this function.
Now you can also use next-gen javascript syntax and use an arrow function where you omit the function
keyword and just have the two arguments followed by an equal sign and a greater sign
hence an arrow and then the function body. This is basically the equivalent to the function keyword approach.
Ok, so this is our create server callback function as it's called, it's called by nodejs whenever a request
reaches our server,
for now let's simply console log the request object to see what's inside.
Now if we execute this file, we can do this in the built-in terminal which is already navigated into
this project folder,
make sure you go into that project folder
if you are using the terminal outside of that IDE.
So once you are in a terminal, navigate it in that folder, you can run node and then app.js,
this will execute the app.js file and let's see what it does.
Hmm, nothing right?
We don't see console log and that makes sense because we didn't send a request to the server but we don't
even know where the server is,
how do we reach that server, which address does it have?
Well one important thing is missing,
this create server method actually returns a server.
So we have to store that in a new variable or constant and I'll use a constant because I'll never overwrite
it, I only create a server once.
So now the created server is stored here and now we can use that server and do something with it.
As you can see we get a bunch of methods we can call and one method is listen. Listen now actually starts
a process where nodejs will not immediately exit our script but where nodejs will instead keep this
running to listen,
that's why the method is named like this for incoming requests.
Now listen as you can see takes a couple of arguments, optional arguments,
the first one is the port on which you want to listen. Now in production you typically would not fill this
out and it would take the default of port 80
but here on local development, we want to use a different port and you can also define a hostname. Now by
default,
this will be the name of the machine this is running on,
so for our local machine, this is localhost by default.
So let's just pass a port, 3000 is a port you often use but you're relatively free to use any
port you want, the thousands port are typically pretty safe.
And now with that, if we re-execute this, you'll see one important thing. The cursor here in the terminal
doesn't go back in a new line because this process here is now still running,
it didn't finish, this file execution didn't finish because we now get an ongoing looping process where
this will keep on listening for requests
and this is obviously what you want, right?
You want to have a web server that keeps on listening for requests.
Now we can see that in action by opening a new browser window where we simply enter localhost 3000
and once you did that,
nothing happens because we haven't configured it to return any html page
but if you go back to your terminal, you'll see a lot of output there and that is this line, this is your
request being logged to the console.
Now let's analyze what happened here in detail and what's inside this request
over the next lectures but these few lines here already give you a fully functional or almost fully functional
web server
and this is how you create servers in nodejs and I know that this can be hard to wrap your head around
because it was for me when I started out with nodejs years ago, it was difficult to understand that
coming from a PHP background
you suddenly write your own server, that sounded like something super complex.
Well actually it's just these few lines
and from now on we'll just have to focus on doing something meaningful with the request and important, sending
back a response.
So time for detailed analysis in the next lectures.