So in this course, I will use sendgrid
you'll find it on sendgrid.com and I'll use it because they have a free entry tier which
stays free as long as you send less than 100 e-mails a day.
Now there are many alternatives, MailChimp, AWS, SCS and you can google for nodemailing and your favorite
mailing service to find tutorials on how to implement it,
now I will use this one because we can use it for free.
So let's click try for free and then we simply have to create an account there.
Now once you did sign up, you can quit that page here and go back to your node project and there we'll
now install a package. I'll install a package with npm install --save which is called node
mailer and to interact with sendgrid,
I'll also install another package in the same go, nodemailer-sendgrid-transport,
that is a package that will help us with integrating sendgrid and conveniently use that together with
nodemailer. Nodemailer is a package that as the name suggests, makes sending emails from inside
nodejs a breeze. With that all added,
we can move on to the next lecture and now start using nodemailer to send messages.
So let me start that server again and
let's continue in the next lecture.