So back at the project, let me quit the development server because now I need to install another package and I will
simply install these three templating engines so that we can work with them.
So let's install them with npm install --save because all three engines are part of our node
code and ship with the code we deploy on some computer in the end,
so let's install them as production dependencies and there we need to install EJS, that is the package
name and links to the websites of these packages with more documentation can also be found in the last
lecture of this module.
So EJS, then we also got pug and handlebars,
there is a handlebars package but that's actually the wrong one, we need
express-handlebars here because this has built-in integration with Express, EJS and pug already
have that built into their core packages
you could say.
So let's now hit enter and now these three packages will be downloaded.
Now what you can also see here by the way is that you can of course install multiple packages at once
by simply repeating or by adding all the names after npm install,
now the packages are installed and we'll not use them all at the same time but one after another so that
we can have a close look at how they work and let's start with the most exotic package, pug. To use that,
we have to go to the app.js file
and now we have to let expressjs know
and that is an express feature, not node by the way, another strong reason why we want to use express because
with node, standalone node, this will be harder,
you would have to do all that manually, here
we can just tell express hey we got a templating engine that is express conforming and that is the
case for all three we installed
so please use it to render dynamic templates.
We do that by going into the app.js
and after we created our express app here and stored it in the app constant, we can set a global
configuration value.
Now what is that? App set allows us to set any values globally on our express application
and this can actually also be keys or configuration items
express doesn't understand,
in that case it just ignores them
but we could actually read them from the app object with app get
and this would be another way of sharing data across our application but not really something I'm interested
in here.
What we can do is we can use a couple of reserved key names here,
so configuration items we can set that do lead to expressjs behaving differently
and you see a list of all these items here in this table.
Now most of them don't really matter for us here
but feel free to browse through that, interesting for us is the view engine and the views key.
View engine allows us to tell express hey for any dynamic templates we're trying to render and there
will be a special function for doing that,
please use this engine we're registering here and views allows us to tell express where to find these dynamic
views. So what we can do here is we can app set and set the view here,
view engine to a string, pug.
Now you can't enter anything here,
we use pug here because we installed the pug templating engine and this engine actually ships with built
in express support and auto registers itself with express
so to say.
So that is why this works,
it doesn't work for all engines but you'll find more in the links in the last lecture, here
it does work,
pug is supported out of the box and with that, we're already set to go.
We can set an additional configuration though, we can let express know where to find our views,
however the default setting here in this last column, the default setting for views already is our, basically
our main directory and then the views folder,
still I'll send it explicitly here to show you how this would work if you would store your views in
another folder which is not called views but maybe templates or whatever it is, that you have to set this configuration
item here, whoops
this one and here, I will set it too even though it wouldn't be needed because views is the default.
So now we're telling express that we want to compile dynamic templates with the pug engine and where
to find these templates.
The last step of course is that we add templates,
so let's go to views and let's add a shop.pug file here.
So we now have a templating file and now pug actually works different to normal html,
so I can't just copy over this whole html code.
The good thing is however in my IDE here if I type html in the shop.pug file and then
I use this html5 template,
I get a pug structure of this
and here we already see the minimal html syntax.
We get no normal html tags
but keep in mind that the pug templating engine will compile our code to normal html in the
end. So this here is basically the equivalent to this part here
you could say, except for the stylesheet imports.
If we wanted to add these, we can do that here too
and thankfully, the IDE helps me here,
if I type link and hit tab, I get a pug conform implementation of this.
So here I now can also add my links,
the paths of course to the css files
are the same as before.
So this is now how we installed pug and how we added it,
now let's quickly finish this file to look like this file before we then actually have a look at how
we can add dynamic content.
So let's replicate this link here and import the product.css file and now for the body,
here I got a header and I got this main area, so let's replicate this in pug quickly.
For this in the body, indentation matters in pug that's important,
you basically structure your nesting of html with indentation levels here,
so if head is nested in html then it's
indented
and if meta is nested in head, it's also indented.
If they're on the same level, they are siblings,
so this is how that works.
So if you want to add something into body and not next to it, we have to indent here and then I add my
header which has this main header class, so if I type again another useful feature of the IDE, of visual
studio code,
if I type dot and then the name like this and I hit tab, then this looks like it didn't do anything
but actually this is the representation of a div with this class,
now I want a header with this class so I just write header.
So this strange syntax will create a header element with
this css class and this is something you have to get used to and where I strongly recommend diving
into the official pug docs
if you want to stick to that, here by the way, I'll replace the title with my shop.
So let's not just add the header but also nav, unordered list and so on.
For this in the header I want to nest something, so let's add an indentation level and then unordered list dot
and the class
and now the same, whoops that was nav not unordered list
so that should be a nav item.
Now for the unordered list,
let's take that class,
let's go in there and
it should be nested in the nav.
So let's indent, unordered list dot
class name
and now we get the list items,
so here let's again pick the list item here
or the class on it, indent because it's nested in the unordered list, list item dot
and then the class.
And now last but not least, I have the anchor tag which also has the active class but which then also
should have some text content in it
and then also have a link.
So let's now go in there,
nest this anchor tag and the class, if you hit tab, you automatically, this is the attribute notation,
so in parentheses after the anchor tag or after any element but always without any whitespace in between,
this allows you to add attributes onto the HTML element,
so here this should go to just slash and now for the text content,
you could add this next to it,
so shop like this. This will basically place this text between the opening and closing anchor tag.
Now this is the setup I want to have here,
of course we have two list items,
we also got add product which leads to this link,
so I have to replicate this.
So next to the first list item, I add
another one, main header item and then I have my anchor tag,
this one without the active class, just with the link
and there, I'll say add product. With this if I run npm start, we wouldn't see anything
and I am aware of the fact that I didn't add the main content but let's ignore that for now. With this
however, we wouldn't render this template because we're not telling express to do so. We're telling express
that it should use this templating engine whenever we try to render a template
but we don't try to do that.
So in shop.js
where we do define what should be our response, we have to change the response because right now,
we're sending the html file,
now we want to do something else.
We can use response
and then there is a special render method,
this is provided by expressjs and it will use the default templating engine which is why we had
to define it here,
it will use that default templating engine and then return that template.
And now we defined that all the views are in the views folder,
we also don't have to construct a path to that folder
instead we can just say shop.
We also don't need shop.pug because we defined pug as the default templating engine
so it will look for .pug files. With this if we save and we reload the shop page, we see the header,
we don't see the main content because we didn't add this
but the rest is working just fine.
And if you inspect this or view the page source, you'll see this is normal html code,
so it's not our minimal version which the browser wouldn't be able to read anyways but it is the html
code pug generated for us based on that minimal version.
Now one thing we're not doing here is we're not outputting anything dynamic
but since that is the reason why we added templating engines, let's do that too in the next lecture.