So let's analyze this react application to find out which rest API endpoints we want to provide.
Now you don't need to know react for that,
no worries.
The app.js file is essentially our entry file where our react application starts or where it basically
starts rendering the first screens
and there we also have some logic on which we'll have to work on later.
For example for logging users in, we'll later have to insert a real url here that allows us to do that
and the same for signing up and so on.
Now in the pages folder, you'll find a feed folder and there the feed.js file is what's responsible
for this page with the new post button and so on.
There we also have a couple of routes,
for example here where we fetch the status of the currently logged in user
but then also additional routes for loading existing posts, here where I want to reach some url
that serves up some posts but also later down, hooks or methods where we can edit the user status,
where we can also add new posts or edit existing posts, we'll do this in the finish edit handler and
where we can delete posts, something we'll do in the delete post handler.
There you already see I have a couple of fetch methods set up but the url is always missing and that
is something we'll have to do of course,
we'll have to add our own url and make sure that this works or that we have the respective endpoints
for that. On the single post screen here,
we load a single post if we click on it and there indeed,
we also want to reach out to the backend and fetch data for that single post.
So in short, which endpoints will we need
and now I switch back to my rest API which we started building in the last course module,
you also find this snapshot attached to this video.
There I already got a route for getting all posts and for creating a new post,
that is great,
we will also need routes for getting a single post, for editing a single post, for deleting a single post
and we'll also need routes for logging a user in, signing users up, so creating new users, for viewing the
status of a user and for editing the status of a user.
These are the routes we will need
and with that, let's start working on that and let's implement them step by step.
We already got a route to get posts and to create a new post which does not sound like the worst start,
let's maybe continue with these so that we can start implementing the appropriate code in our react application
to get posts and to create posts.