I added nodemailer and now I want to use nodemailer to send an email. For that in my auth.js file
which is the only file where I will interact with it,
I will import nodemailer and store it in a constant at the top,
so require nodemailer like this and I will also import sendgridTransport,
you can name these constants the way you want as always and this will inport nodemailer sendgridTransport.
With that imported,
I can initialise a couple of things here. For nodemailer, we need to initialize a so-called transporter,
so that is essentially some setup telling nodemailer how your e-mails will be delivered
because as I mentioned, nodejs won't do this on its own,
you need some third party service for that.
So here I will use nodemailer and then call the create transport method. In create transport,
we can now pass sendgridTransport and execute this as a function because this function will then
return a configuration that nodemailer can use to use sendgrid.
Now to that sendgridTransport function, we pass an object where we pass an auth object and this in turn
holds an object where we have to pass in an API user and an API key field.
Now both are values you get from inside your sendgrid account,
so if you head back to your sendgrid account, you can click on settings here and then API keys and
there, create a new API key.
You want to give that a name and I'll name it node shop, the name is totally up to you
and I'll take full access and create this.
Now take that key and you actually only need that key,
tou could have used your username and password but I'll just use the API key.
So just that key which you copied here, of course use your own key not mine
and with that, you configured the transporter.
Now with the transporter configured, you can now use it to send an e-mail and I want to send an e-mail
after signing up let's say, so in post sign up once I'm done,
so here when I also redirect back to the login page, here I want to send my message
and I use the transporter for that
and then there is a send mail method we can execute. To that method,
you pass a javascript object where you configure the email you want to send,
for example the two fields, so to whom this should go,
well this should go to our e-mail address of course from, so which e-mail address will be displayed
and here I will have shop@nodecomplete.com
let's say, then a subject, sign up succeeded and then html content, so the content of your message.
Now you could have a complex html message,
I'll just add a h1 tag here,
you successfully signed up, like that.
So this is the message I want to send, now send mail then gives me a promise so I can use then and
catch or of course I simply return that and then I redirect in the next then block, so once the email
has been sent. However that is up to you, you could also redirect immediately and not wait for this to
be sent because you're not really relying on that being sent
and so this will send
and at the same time you redirect,
so whatever you want. What you should do though is if that is your plan, you might want to switch positions
here and still return that so that you can still catch any errors that are stemming from this
so that here we could still log any errors we might be getting or do something else with these errors
of course. With this set up added,
let's give it a try.
Let's head over and sign up
and now you should use a real e-mail address of course
otherwise it can't arrive,
click sign up here,
I am redirected
and now check your e-mail account
and in that e-mail account, you should have an e-mail from shop@nodecomplete.com with that message.
If you don't get it, verify you entered a correct e-mail and also feel free to verify your sendgrid
e-mail,
you should have gotten an e-mail from sendgrid when signing up verifying your e-mail address there.
But with that, this should work and you should be able to send e-mails like this.
Now dive into the official sendgrid docs and also in the nodemailer docs if you want to learn way more
about what you can do there,
also as I mentioned, google for nodemailer and your favorite e-mailing service if you want to use a
different one
but this is the general theme of how this works.