So here I got a very simple sign up form which is a pretty typical sign up form that though, you have
to enter an email,
you have to enter a password, confirm the password and click sign up.
Now in that sign up view, I changed my button label and there I also want to point at the sign up route
in the action now, /signup, send a post request to reach that sign up, the post sign up route here which
ultimately triggers the post sign up action.
Now in this action, we want to store a new user in the database,
now which steps does this include?
Well obviously we want to extract the information from the incoming request,
we want to read the email from the request body email field and make sure you check your view,
how these inputs are named because you retrieve the values on request body by these names,
so email, password and confirm password in my case, so request body email should work, here
I will have request body password to retrieve the password and then I will also retrieve my confirm
password here from confirm password,
so these are the three values that should reach this route.
Now typically what you would do first is we would validate the user input,
so for example we would check is this a valid email address and do password and confirm password match
and we will do this in this course too
but actually I will have a complete module where I dive into how to validate user input because you
can of course do a lot of cool things when it comes to that and therefore I dedicate a whole module
to that.
For now we'll ignore this and that means for now you of course don't have to enter a valid email and
you don't have to enter a valid password,
you don't have to confirm it either
but of course you should do all that to have a realistic testing environment, we'll add validation later.
We still need the values here, at least the first two because the next step is that we create a new user
or actually there is one step we want to do before we create a new user,
do you know which step it could be? Well we want to find out if a user with that e-mail already exists
because there should not be any duplicate e-mails in our database. For that
we actually can do two things, when using mongodb
you could create an index in the mongo database on your email field and give that index the unique property.
Now this is something you can do if you know how mongodb works,
if you get a little bit more experience with it which you can get with my mongodb course, there
I do show this scenario for example but this is only one option of achieving this.
An alternative is that you simply try to find a user with that e-mail,
so for that we'll use our user model which is of course a mongoose user model
and there we can find a user, we can find one user because we already know we don't want to create a user
with that e-mail
if we find only one user who already has that e-mail and we find that one user by passing a filter with these
curly braces and we'll look for the email field in our collection,
so in the documents in our collection and see if we find a user where the email field holds a value
equal to the email we're extracting here.
So right side of the colon is the email we're extracting,
left side is the field we're looking for in the database.
Now here we get back where we can call then to find out if this worked,
we also might get an error which I'll simply log here then and in then, I will get my user object, so my
user document you could say, you can name this however you want.
Now we know that if user doc exists,
so if this is not undefined, then we do have a user
and if we do have a user then I certainly don't want to create a new one with the same e-mail.
So if this exists, I will actually return a response and I will redirect back to /signup to inform
the user that this did not work, right now not much informing is going on as you can tell, we just redirect
without showing an error message,
this is also something which I'll show you how to better solve this,
how to show error messages to the user,
for now we'll just redirect back to the sign up page and we'll not create a new user.
If we make it past this check, we know that no user with that e-mail exists yet and therefore we can
create a new one
So what we can do here then is we can create a new user object with new user and we configure our new
user and there, we store the email,
the e-mail we're retrieving here and we'll store the password, like this for now.
One important thing, in the user model there, right now I have a name and an e-mail and no password.
So I will change the user model,
I don't really want to store a name,
you could do that but I'll not do it here
but instead I will store a password for the user which will be of type string and which will absolutely
be required like this,
so my user model changed slightly here.
Now with that change in the user model, if we go back to our post signup action, I can create a user
like this,
we can also add a cart here, the cart by default will be an object where items is equal to an empty array
like this
and this is now a valid new user which we can save in database by calling save as you learned
and then I can return this so that we can chain another then block here which will be called once
this save action completed,
so this function here will be executed
once saving is done. And here we can then redirect to let's say the starting page because here we then
know the user did sign up or to be precise,
let's redirect to the login page because after signing up, you need to login.
So this should now be an authentication flow that does check for the existence of a user and then create
a new user.
I'll quickly also go to my app.js file and at the very bottom here where I always create a new
user if we don't have one yet, I will get rid of that code because now we have a real user creation flow
so we don't need that dummy user anymore
and I will also head over to compass which I'll start to connect to my mongo database again and in the connected
database server if we have a look at the shop database, in users
we obviously have one user, the dummy user we used before,
now let's delete that user now,
we don't need it anymore.
And with all these changes and all these files saved, let's reload the sign up page and now let's try
creating a new user with a dummy e-mail, dummy password,
you don't really need to enter a confirm password because we're not checking this anyways
and click sign up.
Now this is looking good because I'm on the login page so I was redirected,
I also have no server error,
if I now reload my users collection in mongodb, in compass, I also see this is a user with the credentials
I add.
So we did add a new user but we have a huge problem with that user,
can you identify it?
We'll fix it in the next lecture.