We're almost done with the theory part,
now there are some core principles that are indeed defined in theory and that are important for you
to keep in mind where at least there are two core principles
I want you to keep in mind when building rest APIs. The first one is the uniform interface principle,
this simply defines that your API will have or should have clearly defined API endpoints, you remember
endpoints were the combination of http methods and paths with clearly defined request and response data
structures. Put in other words, your API should be predictable and if possible and if open to the public,
it should also be well documented.
So people should know which data does your API expect, which data does it give back, which endpoints do
I have
and the thing that happens when a request reaches to an endpoint should of course not change over time,
it should be predictable, it should be clearly defined.
The second important principle I want you to keep in mind is the stateless interactions principle
and this will be super important when we later talk about authentication. When building a rest API, the
server and the client are totally separated, they don't share a common history.
So no connection history is stored and no sessions will be used
therefore because every incoming request is treated as if no prior requests were sent.
The server has a look at every request on its own,
it does not store a session for the client,
it does not care about the client at all
actually, that is also a cool thing about resting APIs.
You can build a rest API,
open it up to the public like the Google Maps API is for example and you don't care about the individual
client,
you just say hey here are the endpoints I have,
here's the data you get back for each endpoint,
here's the data I expect from you for my endpoints and then I don't care about you,
I don't store a session with you.
We have a strong decoupling of the client and the server
even if they were to run on the same server because we're building our own API for our own frontend.
We still would decouple both so that they work independently and just exchange data.
This means that every time we set up a new endpoint, we have to make sure that it works independent from
prior requests
and a typical problem here is authentication where once we logged in, future requests should be treated
as logged in
and I will show you how to solve this in this course too of course.
Now other principles which are less important or which you don't need to learn by heart is the cachable principle
which means on your rest API, you could send back some headers that tell the client how long the response
is valid so that the client may cache the response. Client server separation is mentioned again, here
it's more thinking about the data storage, client and server are decoupled as I said and the client should
not worry about persistent data storage
therefore, the server will be responsible for this.
We may have a layered system which simply means as a client when we send a request to an API, we can't
rely on that server
we sent it to you immediately handling the request, the server might instead forward the request or distribute
it to another server,
Uultimately we only care about the data we get back which should of course follow the structure that
was defined by the API. Code on demand is a last optional principle
and this basically just means the rest
API could also for some endpoints transfer executable code to the client.
Now to be honest, in reality you don't see that too often, we're mostly talking about well normal data
we're using but still, these are the rest principles, the top two ones are the important ones which will
have great implications especially on authentication.