Now to work with SQL,
we need a SQL based database and I'll go for MySQL because you can install and use that for free,
at least in the basic version which does suffice for this course.
You can visit MySQL.com to download and install it
and there simply click on downloads
and scroll down,
we don't need the enterprise edition here
instead we'll go for the community edition which is the free one, click on downloads there too
and now what we will need is the MySQL community server and we'll also need the workbench.
Now you can also download a combined installer, especially here for Windows you should choose the MySQL
on Windows Installer in tools which allows you to set up everything in one go
but you can also click on MySQL community server here simply and this should give you a download
which allows you to install all these things in one go
anyways. So let's choose the MySQL community server here,
always dive into the installation instructions
in case you're facing any problems on your system and then if you scroll down, select your operating
system here, the one you plan on using,
so for Windows you can then also download this general installer which allows you to pick the programs
you need, for MacOS
we simply can go for this first download, the DMG archive and then once you click there you don't have
to log in,
you can simply choose
no thanks
just start my download to well start the download.
Now this can take a while because it's quite a big file,
on Windows you have the choice between downloading a web-based installer which is smaller but downloads
what you need to during the installation or a complete installer which downloads everything in advance.
Once your download is done, simply execute the downloaded file
so the windows installer
or this Mac DMG archive. Here I'm asked
to well continue through the installation wizard and I will do that,
agree to the license,
leave the default installation path, click on customize here though to choose what to install and make
sure that you do install
the MySQL server here.
If you're running this installer on Windows, you should have a different installer where you can choose
to install the MySQL server but then also in one go, install the
MySQL workbench,
so make sure you select both for installation and click install here
and now on both operating systems,
this should install it. Now
once installation is done, a configuration process should start automatically. There
you should make sure that during this configuration process, you do choose the legacy password encryption
which sounds insecure but which is perfectly fine and the newer version simply is not supported
by the node SQL package we're using yet.
So choose the legacy password encryption and choose next, you also have to choose a password for your root
user and you can also leave
start MySQL server once installation is complete
checked or check it if it is unchecked and click finish.
On Windows,
simply leave all the other settings as they are and click through them and by the end, it should be done and
it should then also start a MySQL server for you
with the setup you chose here in the configuration steps.
Now once installation is complete, on Windows if you also installed the MySQL workbench, you're done, on Mac
or Linux,
you're not done yet,
instead you should go back to your previous page where you chose MySQL community server and there also install
the MySQL workbench.
The workbench basically is a client, a visual client we can use to connect to our database to inspect
it and play around with it outside of our node application which simply makes debugging and developing
a bit easier.
So choose the MySQL workbench here and there you also can choose your operating system,
now again on Windows if you used that general installer, you already have it. Download that file here, again
you don't need to log in, just start to download and wait for the download to finish
so that you can again execute the, well executable
once it is done. Finish the installation process as instructed
by the installer and once you're done with that, you should be all good.
You can now test your setup by starting the MySQL workbench you just installed and then there, you
should already see your MySQL instance running.
If that is not the case,
have a look at the attached document where I describe some common issues or in general give you some
links on how to make this work and how to bring this up,
you just need to make sure that your MySQL server is running and during installation, you had a choice
to check that it should always start with your system, on Mac
you can also open your system preferences and there you should have the MySQL option where you can
also stop and start the server. To connect to the database,
simply click on that instance and now enter that root password you assigned during the installation.
This should now allow you to connect to your SQL server instance like this,
then once you enter the password you should be connected to your database system. And right now this is
what you have, basically an empty window and we won't work too much in that, we'll of course work with
our database from inside our node application
but this will allow us to conveniently look into our database from time to time and see what is stored
and one thing we can do already is we can go down to schemas here which can be translated with database
here
you could say and there, we can define a new schema, so a new database with which we'll work and I'll name it
node complete,
you can name this whatever you want and you can also leave the other settings here and then on the bottom
right and I know it's small here,
unfortunately you't zoom in,
you can click apply. Now
this will create a new database
you can say with which we can interact later, you can leave all the default settings and simply click
apply here and now you should see that node complete thing which has a couple of tables or none right
now but where you can then later connect to and store your data in the tables that will be created here.
So with that, we can continue and we can now move on with our code and start interacting with MySQL
from inside our node application.