Let's make sure we can create new posts so that this new post button does not only open the modal but
we can actually add a new post,
for now without the image upload. So let me go back to my rest API
and there we already have a create post route of course so we can continue working on that.
We expect the title and a content there
and for now this is the only data which I will really need to worry about because well as I just
said, we'll not worry about the image
for now. You can pick an image here but ultimately even though it's previewed here, it will not be uploaded.
But it does not matter,
we can implement this in a way that at least the title and the content is uploaded.
For this we already got our route in place, a post route to feed post and there, we then extract our title
and content and we,
well for now basically echo back that message.
Let's try that and
let's go to our frontend application so to the react code and in there,
let's simply go to the
feed.js file and there you should find a finish
edit handler function.
This is the function which is responsible for handling the case that we clicked on
except here once we entered a valid title and content,
by the way here I also got validation in place, frontend validation which is not the matter of course
because it's not related to node at all,
it's just a user experience thing that we use browser side javascript to validate the input right away,
you can learn more about that in my react course if you want.
Still worth noting that we have some validation in place here, not validation on the server though.
So if I now click accept, I want to reach my /feed/postroute, for that
here we have to edit this url.
This url here will actually be required later
when we start editing posts, for now we want to create a new one,
so here the url
will be http localhost 8080, so our backend url /feed/post,
this is the route we set up on the backend.
Here we send a fetch request to that url and we need to configure that request because it will
be a post request.
So the method here can be post
but actually I'll write this in a more flexible way too
because when we later edit this, we'll use a different method,
so here I will create a new variable method which I'll set to post which we then later could override
in here.
So here I'll not hardcode posts down there but instead use my method variable.
I will also need to add a body, the data which I want to set and that has to be json data so I will
use json stringify to convert a javascript object to json
and then I pass a javascript object here and this javascript object
in the end should hold the code which I want to, well send to my backend. In this object
for now, I simply want to set my title and that can be extracted from post data, an argument
I receive in this function, so post data will hold the data the user entered,
post data title and then here also the content to post data content,
so this is again what we add in the react application.
Last but not least to send this request in a way that the server understands it, we need to add some headers
here where we set the right content type,
so here I'll set content type to application json to inform the server that I do indeed send some json
data.
So with that, I'm targeting the right url and I'm sending json data and I'm sending a title and a
content and
this should be everything I need on the server.
So let's save this and it should reload automatically as long as you keep npm start running here and
therefore, well it reloaded the app here and let's create a new post, the title has to be at least five
characters long such so as the content, choose a file otherwise you're not allowed to submit this
even though the file is not getting uploaded right now and click
accept. Now you will run into an error here which is related to the frontend missing some crucial data
it needs to update everything correctly.
However let's go back one step and let's actually console log res data here, still in that finish
edit handler, just in the then block after fetching and save again.
The app will reload and you can enter something into that new post model again,
testing again and hit accept again and you'll get that same error
but before that error, you'll see a log which actually proves that on the rest API, everything worked correctly.
You get back that post created successfully message and the post with the data you entered.
The error is simply stemming from the fact that on the server, we're not doing everything we expect it to
do because we're not creating or we're not attaching a user, we're not creating a date and so on.
These are all things we can fix though by going back to our controller on the server and there when
we create a new post or when we echo back that post,
first of all it should have an _id not an ID,
it should also have a creator field which is again a javascript object with a name of your choice
and later this will not be dummy data anymore but real data,
so we add this creator and we should add a created add field and that created add field is simply a new date.
And now with that being echoed back, if we save that server side code and we reload the frontend application,
we can test this one more time, click accept and now we don't get an error
instead we see our post there.
So now we indeed do create our data on the server or at least we fake to do so
and we return that back to the client where we can now render it. Now editing will not work though
we can select it for editing at least, deleting will also not work and viewing will neither
but we got our basic flow set up.
Now since we're creating a new post here, what is missing on the server though,
at least two things are missing and what is missing?
Well validation, server side validation,
we only got client side validation but that can always be tricked because users can see your browser
side javascript code,
they could disable it,
they could basically find ways around that
so it's not a safe mechanism,
it's only meant to improve user experience.
So we need to validate on the server
and of course we want to store the data in a real database, so we should add mongodb or SQL solution
again
and that is what we'll do over the next lectures.