We added the isEmail validator.
Now there are way more built-in validators available from which you can choose and you'll find them
when you visit the express validator page because there if you check the official docs to which this
link points, you'll see that in the end it's a wrapper around the validator js validator,
so that's another package that was implicitly installed with express validator. And here on the docs
of validator js which is a different package which was installed,
you'll find all the built-in validators and what they do and how you might configure them if possible
and you see this is the one we're using, isEmail,
this is what I'm using here,
we could configure it to change different e-mail formats we want accept or not accept,
we can check for emptiness,
we can check whether something is a full domain or a full
url,
we got all kinds of things. We can check if a value is in a certain array of possible allowed values,
if we have a certain length will be important for the password
and so much more.
So you see there are a bunch of things we can check and definitely go through this list to learn more about
the built-in validators.
You can also add your own validator though and to demonstrate this real quick,
let's say we're not just using isEmail,
I also want to make sure it's a specific e-mail
I want to have. For that I can add custom here and now a validator is in the end a function like this, a
function that receives the value of the field we're checking, so the value in the email field and optionally,
an object from which we can extract things like the location to which this was sent, the path or the request
object in case we need to extract more from the request.
Now in this function, you want to throw an error when validation fails,
so here we could simply check if value equals and now let's say it should be test@test.com because
we don't want to allow that,
that's just some dummy logic here.
So if that is the case, then I'll throw an error by calling throw new error with a message of this email
address is forbidden, something like that.
Of course this is very arbitrary that I'm checking for exactly that e-mail address
but this is how you can generally write your own validators, in case the many built-in ones don't suffice
your requirements.
So now if I save this, we should see that if I reload that page and I enter test@test.com, I get
this email address is forbidden,
if I enter test2@test.com then I get invalid value though.
The reason for this invalid value here simply is that if we do succeed, we should return true,
so we throw an error if we fail,
we could return false to go with the default error message or we throw an error to have our own error
message or we return true if it succeeded
and now you will see that if I enter test2, this worked.
Now this will actually be stored a bit strange in the database now because I entered a new user with
invalid password, with an empty password but we didn't add any password validation yet.
The key takeaway is that you saw how you can add your own validator, returning true if it's fine,
returning false or throw an error if it's not and how you can use the many built-in ones
and of course that you can chain them after each other to add multiple validators to one and the same field.