We're now storing a product with all the data we need, now we should also display all that real data
and don't show any dummy data anymore.
So for that, let's go to our product-list.ejs file which is one of the views where we do display
all products and there, we already output the real product title but that's it.
The image source for example is something we should now also replace
and we can simply add our ejs expression in there and output image url and this will be
a string that should be a valid
url, so this should be displayable.
Now for the alternative text, we can also use the title again,
so I simply copied the ejs expression up there, for the price
let's say it's always dollars,
so I'll keep that dollar sign here as hardcoded text and then output product price and for the description
here,
I will of course also replace the dummy text with my description as it is saved in the product.
Now all old products will not fulfill this new structure,
so in the data folder in products.json, I will actually remove them all from that array here so that
it's an empty array again.
With that back in product list, this is looking good,
now in index.ejs, we have the same logic
so we can simply copy that and back in index.ejs simply replace it.
Now if I reload my app on shop and product, we got no products but if I add a new one, this is a test
product or simply a book. Let's search an image, I picked a url here and insert it here,
then let's add a price 19.99
and this is an awesome book,
sounds like a good title.
Now you can press add products and right now this does not support decimal numbers, to fix this,
we can change something in the add product view, there on the number input
we simply have to add a step attribute and set the step to 0.01,
this means you can have well two decimal places essentially and increment in this step size.
I'll save this but not reload,
for now I'll simply go with a number without decimal places to not lose my other data and hit add product
and indeed on the starting page, it's now showing this product with all the data I entered.
So now we improved that and we made a major step forward,
therefore on both these pages obviously we see it,
let's now of course also work on making sure that as an admin, we also see the products here
and we then not just see them but we can also edit or delete them.
That will be the next step.