So let's convert all these html files to pug templates now
and for this, I'll start with add product and create an add-product.pug file in the views folder.
Now again I will create a html5 skeleton with the help of emmet here by typing html, selecting
that
html5 template here and hitting tab,
so this already gives us a nice start.
Now I'll set the title to add product and now I want to convert this form to pug and of course the header
too. Now the header is something we already got in the shop so we can just copy that here,
move it over to add product in the body like this,
just make sure that you move the active class from the first anchor tag to the second one
because now this is the active route and of course I also want to add my main section with the form
now. I'll again reverse engineer it by copying the main html code, going in there and next to the header,
I want to add it.
Main is now just main, the form then is nested in that so let's indent it, the form has this class so
let's chain this and the form also has attributes
so let's add them here as a comma separated list in brackets.
Now we can indent the div here because that is of course nested in the form,
the div has this class and you learned that a div can also be omitted then so you can just have dot and the
class to render a div. And then in there we have the label, the label here has an attribute,
so let's add this and it has some text which is separated with a whitespace as you learned.
Now we also have an input here, input of type text so let's add these brackets
set here to render some attributes separated with commas and the id can actually be rendered separately
with a hashtag in front of it,
again using its css selector,
something you already solve for the class,
this also is the css selector for this class, pug uses these selectors,
so now you have #title.
Now let's remove the closing tag of the div and let's also add the button, it's indented because it's
part of the form so
let's make sure it's in the form,
let's give that the button class
don't forget this and let's add the attribute list to make this a submit button, like that and then a
whitespace to separate the add product text.
Let's remove the closing tags and that should be it.
Now let's also render some dynamic content here,
for example add product here, this title. I'll again
output this dynamically, page title for example,
now we have to make sure that we pass this key into this template and we do render this template in
admin.js. So here where I do send this file,
I don't send this file
instead I now render, I render my admin file here,
the admin excuse me not the admin, the add-product.pug file, this is automatically picked then and I pass in an
object which holds the key value pairs
I want to be able to access in the template and there, I got my page title key,
so that key
I'm trying to access here,
I got that and I will assign a title of add product, just like that. With that if we reload,
this is gone because the server restarted due to our server side changes.
Now if I click add product, this is the html code by the looks of it,
I forgot to add the imports,
yeah I need to of course also import my stylesheets, so let's copy the links from shop.pug and
add them here in the header.
Let's also check the add
product html file,
I also need to import the forms.css
file as you can see.
So let's duplicate this here,
this line and also add this import. Now no server restart is required because we just changed the template
and therefore nodemon doesn't restart
and now the reload, this looks much better
and let's give this a try,
it also still works.
So that's it,
now let's also work on the 404 page. For this
I'll add a 404.pug file here and I will again create a normal html5 skeleton,
I will say page not found here and I will already copy the, what do you need,
the main css file,
I will copy that import here from the add-product.pug file, this link, let's copy it over to the 404.pug
file so that we got that. And then in the 404.html file, I get the header and I got Page Not Found,
well we got the header already in add product so
let's copy the header here,
move that 404.pug into the body by indenting there and next to the header inside the body,
I'll add a h1 tag where I say page not found.
And with that we should have it,
now let's just make sure that this gets rendered and for that, we have to go to the app.js file
because that is where we have our catch all middleware and there instead of sending a file,
I will now also render the 404 file and as before, it will automatically look in the views folder
due to our setup and it will look for .pug files. So with that, if I now enter any random path which doesn't
exist, we indeed get page not found.
So this is now working and this is now using pug as a templating engine.
Now there are a couple of other nice things that pug can do that I want to show you.