So in the last lecture I showed you how you can set a cookie and some a bit too complex way of extracting
that cookie.
Now if you want to extract cookies by the way, there also are third party packages which can help you
with that
but our approach has another flaw.
Well obviously since I can access my cookies that easily
in the developer tools, I can easily change them, I can go here and manipulate the value,
for example if I set it to false and I reload,
I'm actually still logged in
because false is sent as text and text is always treated as true
but we can simply add a comparison here and see if that value is equal to true, so to the text true here
and now if I reload here, I'm not logged in anymore.
If I change it back to
true though and I do reload,
I am.
So the issue here is we can manipulate that from inside the browser and obviously you don't want to
allow the users of your website to login by simply manipulating some cookie value.
So whilst it is certainly interesting to store some data in the client side, especially things that are
related to tracking users, advertisements tracking and so on,
whilst this is interesting, sensitive data should not be stored in the browser because users can edit
them as you see, we can edit our logged in cookie. So whilst
cookies are generally a good thing for storing data across requests,
it might not be the best approach in all scenarios and that is exactly something where sessions can
help us with.
However before we dive into sessions, let me quickly explain you some other fields you can configure
about a cookie which will also highlight when a cookie does make sense to be used
before we then dive into the scenario where it's not the best tool.