You now learned how you can display product information by getting that information out of the url,
now we have a similar problem for adding a product to the cart.
We get that add to cart button but in the end when posting our data, we also want to know which product
to add to the cart.
However here, I will send a post request right,
add to cart sends a post request and this has one important implication,
we can pass data in the request body.
This was not possible for a get request but for post request you typically use the request body,
this is also what we use when adding a product. For adding a product,
we have a form and as I mentioned there when we added this the first time in the course, this automatically
gives us a request which puts all the input data and so on into its body
but this only works for posting data,
this is not available for getting data but for posting data, we therefore don't need to add anything
to the url because we can put the information in the post body. So therefore what we should do on product
detail in this form is we should simply pass some important information as part of the post request.
So I will add an input here and I will make it of type hidden so that it doesn't really get displayed on
the page but still is encoded in the request that is getting sent and I will give this a name of product
ID, the name is up to you though
and now we also need to store a value here and that value will be the value that is added to the request
for that product ID
and here I'll use ejs again to output product ID
because I still want to pass that ID to my backend so to say, to my node express app but I don't want
to use the url because I do use a post request so there's no need to use it.
You could do it though,
you can also add a dynamic segment for post requests,
that would work too
but there is no need to do it here.
So let's pass that data with that hidden input and let's now work on the backend on our shop.js file.
There we got get cart but get cart is not the route we're working on right now,
we'll use that to display the cart then
but for now I need a post request.
So let's add a new route which accepts a post request,
still to get to /cart,
that doesn't change but now we need a new controller function and we'll add one here,
maybe near get cart, maybe in front of it or after it
that's up to you,
exports post cart
and there I also will get my request response and next function as arguments. And in here
we will now have to retrieve the product ID from the incoming request and then also fetch that product
in our database,
so in our file and add it to our cart. We got no cart yet though
so this is also something we'll have to work on.
For now let's simply extract the data as a first step,
the prod ID by accessing request and now since it's part of the request body, we'll access request body here
and then product ID because product ID is the name I'm using
in my view here on the hidden input. So therefore here, I got this available,
I can console log this for the moment
and thereafter I can simply redirect,
maybe to just /cart here and this will then load the get route, so it will render the cart page. So
with that let's go back to the routes file and let's connect the newly created controller action with
the post route there,
so post cart should be connected here
and now if you save that and you go back to the details page
and for now only there
this button will work
and you click add to cart, I'm on the cart page and in the console we see that random ID which was
generated, that random number being logged.
So this is working,
now obviously we're not storing that in a cart right now
and before we work on that, let's actually go back to the product detail page and grab that entire form
here and make sure we also use that form in all the places where we also have add to cart buttons.
So let's add it on the product list.ejs file,
now important
there I also have product ID available,
so I also access a product field so this is working here and let's add it to index.ejs and there
I also have the product object available which is now important all the time of course because I'm
accessing product ID here and since this is exactly equal in all three views, we can also add an include add
to cart ejs and put that entire code into that include here and then simply well include that include.
So instead of having that code here in index.ejs, we can use the ejs tag with the minus to add include
and then we go to well up one level and then into includes and then add to cart and we use that
same code also in the product detail page here and also in the product list page.
So there I also want to replace this form with my include.
Now let's see if that still works, if I now go to products,
now we get this error because if you have an include in a for loop or in a loop in general as we have
it here, we're looping through all the products and then product is a local variable available in that loop
only, then in include, included in the loop
unfortunately doesn't get that variable by default but you can pass it to that include here and
you can do so by adding a second argument to the include function where you again pass an object and
simply add that variable again.
So here this product is what will be available in include and on the right side, you include or you
add the value you have available in this file, so product in the loop is now passed to product in the include.
This of course needs to be done for all our include, so also in the index.ejs file and not for the
one in the product detail though because there, it's not inside a loop,
so it's available globally and therefore works
and now if we reload here, this works, starting page works and the details page also still works and
we can go to the cart on all these pages.
This is looking good,
we're also outputting the ID here so this is working. Now as a next step, we'll have to work on that cart.