So we're executing a query here with execute on our pool, on the products table we just created and I
added then and catch. These are functions we can chain onto the result of the execute call,
so they will execute on whatever this gives us back and this whatever is some so-called promise.
Now a promise is a basic javascript object not specific to node,
it's also available in javascript in the browser which allows us to work with asynchronous code. Instead
of using callbacks which we could also use with the MySQL package, promises allow us to write more structured
code because instead of having a nested anonymous function here as a second argument, we simply have
a then block which will then get the anonymous function to execute.
Now the advantage is
we can also write it like this
and now we have very readable code
instead of having a nested code here and that nested code especially becomes a problem if we have more
and more asynchronous tasks depending on each other.
Now we also don't just have then, we also have catch and this also has a function which executes in case of
an error,
so for example if the database connection fails or something like this. We get the error object here
and this is just a modern javascript syntax where we get one argument and then we handle it here
and I can simply log it with the console so that we at least see what the error was.
Now we hopefully end up here and we probably get an argument here too,
let's name it result for now
and let's also log result here then
and now let's see what we get.
If I run npm start to bring up that server again, this immediately executes because it's part of the
app.js file
and if we have a look at this, we see this is the object we got back and in this object, we essentially also see the
data that was retrieved here. The
data we do get back has a format of an array with a nested array where the first nested array seems
to depict our data, the rows it fetched and the second array seems to hold some metadata about the table
we fetched it from.
So result basically is an array with two nested elements,
so we can also logout results 0 and result 1 here and if we now save this and therefore our server restarts,
we have almost the same output
but now it's not a nested array but here we have the first object we retrieved, the row we got
and then this ends here,
here is the closing square bracket and then here we get the second log,
so this is the result one with the metadata.
This is what we get back and this should allow us to work with our data.
Now obviously we don't just want to work with dummy data but let's now see how we can adjust our models
to interact with our database instead of local files.