We're now working on the cart and right now, we don't have a cart,
we got a product but not a cart,
let's now add a new model here, the cart.js file
because the cart is like a separate entity in our project you could say. Therefore I'll again export
a class here and I'll name that class cart,
so that is pretty similar to what I do in product, there I export the class product
but now it's class cart
and now we have to think about how we want to manage that cart.
Now obviously we want to have a cart that holds all the products that we added
and we also want to group products by id and increase their quantity in case we add a product more
than once.
So to do all of that, I will first of all create a constructor here which allows us to create a new cart.
Now when this cart is created, I'll add a products property here which should be an array
and there I imagine having some objects in there which do maybe hold information like the ID and important,
also the quantity of this product.
We can also add an information like total price which initially is zero let's say and this of course increase
with every product we add.
Now what we need on this cart though is a way to add and remove our products
obviously. Now the problem we have is the cart itself is not really an object we'll constantly recreate,
not for every new product that we add we want to have a new cart, instead there always will be
a cart in our application and we just want to manage the products in there. So the approach
I want to take will actually be a different one,
I don't really add a constructor instead I'll add a static method, add product like this.
Now this will take the ID of the product I want to add and the goal here will be to then fetch the
old or previous cart from our file for now, analyze that and see if we already have that product,
find existing product and then add new product or increase the quantity. That is what I plan to do,
so let's start with adding the logic for fetching a cart from a file.
For this I'll import the file system here
and also the path helper here,
whoops, path
to construct a good path. Now in product.js, we see how that path should be constructed so we can copy
that basically, go to products, to cart.js and then add it here.
Now the difference is that the file will now be named cart.json
and in there we'll store an object that represents our cart and then here, in this part here for adding
a product, I want to use the file system to read a file and that will be the file at this path so
my cart.json file and we have a callback where I either get an error or or the file content.
Now if we have an error,
we know that the file doesn't exist yet and therefore we got no cart yet.
So if we got an error then our cart will have to be created otherwise
we know that we, well get an existing cart.
So here I'll add a new cart
first of all which will have products that are an empty array and maybe that total quantity we were
talking about, the total price excuse me which is zero.
And therefore if we don't have an error, again that inverse logic, if we don't have an error
then we know we got an existing cart,
so in this case my cart should be equal to the parsed file content. We'll store it as json so I'll
parse that with that json helper.
So now at this point after the if statement, we know that we will have a cart and now we can analyze
it and add a product,
so let's analyze the cart and see if the product we're trying to add already exists.
So we'll search for the existing product by taking our cart products in there,
remember we'll have products in the cart which is an array
and by then finding an element in there.
So again we'll loop through all the products and have a look at each of them, each prod,
so in each product we'll have a look and we'll see if the product ID matches the ID of the product we try
to add.
Now if we got an existing product already, then we simply want to increase that quantity.
So let's say we assume that each product object that gets stored in there is not just a product object
having the data in our product model but also that it has an extra quantity field.
Now if we have an existing product, then I want to create a new product and for this I'll create a new variable,
updated product
and here in this if statement, so if we have an existing product, I'll use updated product
and now next generation javascript with the object spread operator,
I'll take all the properties of the existing product and add them to a new javascript object
and then on that updated product, I'll set the quantity equal to the old quantity plus one.
So I'll simply increment the quantity by one
and since I distributed all properties of existing product into updated product, the quantity will be
available there already because it was available in existing product.
Now if we have a new product, I'll set updated product equal to
and I should put that into an else block,
so if we have a new one, I will set updated product equal to
a new javascript object where I add information for that product and that will be my ID let's say.
So ID will be equal to the ID I'm getting as an argument and I'll set the quantity to one because
we added just one. Now the remaining thing is that I want to update the price of the cart.
Now we got the cart here with the total price and the total price will always rise by the price of
the product we added.
Now I don't have that information in here though,
so I expect to get it as an argument, product price and therefore here after this if else block, I can say cart
total price equals cart total price plus product price right because we want to, price because we
want increase that.
So now we got our product added,
we found it
and we also analyzed it and added a new product, increase the quantity,
now we just need to save the cart back to our file. And of course the cart should now also contain the
updated product, that's also important.
So we updated the price thus far,
let's now also update the products,
so the products on our cart should equal the old products
and here again I'll use a next gen javascript feature
by spreading the existing products of the cart,
so this will now be an array with all the old cart products
and now the question is what do I want to do?
Well if we are creating a product for the first time,
so if I'm in this else block, then I simply will add the updated product as a new additional product.
However if I got an existing product here, I don't want to add a new product
instead I want to replace the old one and to do that, I need to find out where in my old products this
existing product was located,
so which position it had. To do this I'll get the index instead of the product,
so here I'll have the existing product index and then I'll add my existing product which is simply cart
products at this existing product index,
so one extra step
but this now allows me to use that index to replace the item in our cart products here.
So there, I will set cart products equal to cart product,
so first of all copying the old array just as we're doing it down there
but then I'll not add updated products, instead
I will set cart products and overwrite existing product index, so at this position I will replace
the element with my updated product.
So now the updated product is either replaced or added to the cart products and the price is updated,
now we can save it back and for this, we can use the file system write file and write it to that path
and then of course also define what we want to put there
and I want to write my cart into the path,
obviously in a stringified
version, so as json
and then here I have a callback where I might get an error which I want to output so that I see if I
do have one and which one it is
if I got one and then I am done.
So this is now an add product method that hopefully does the trick,
let's simply try it out.
So for this, let's go to the shop controller
and in post cart, I want to add my product.
This of course means here first of all I need to get the product because I need its price too,
so I will use product find by ID for my product ID and then I have this callback where I get my product,
so here that is the product that is retrieved from the products database so to say, from the products
file
and once I have this, I can use the product information to update my cart.
So in here, I now want to use my cart model.
First of all, let's import it, cart by requiring it from the models folder and there from the cart
folder and with it being imported, let's go down to post cart and say cart add product and now cart
the model basically serves as a utility model you could say, we're not instantiating it
instead were using this static function and I'll use add product to pass in my prod ID and also my, here
product
that is what I'm retrieving from the product file, my product price because that is also information that
I need in there.
With that let's see if that works by going back to our app here and clicking add to cart,
now looks good because we're logging the error here and if we see null that means there was no error
and now we got cart.json and in there, I got products which is an array of products with an ID and the quantity
and the price is stored as a string which is a bit suboptimal here I have to say, so we'll have to
work on that
but besides that, this is looking good.
Now if I add another product or the same product again, then we see indeed the quantity was increased,
the price is misbehaving because it's stored as a string and therefore concatenated,
so we'll have to do something about that. In cart.js the price we're extracting, it's stored as a string
in our product model,
so what we have to do is here when we work on the price,
I have to add a plus in front of product price to convert that string to a number
and now if we quickly delete cart.json to start from scratch and I add my element to the cart again
and I do that again and we now look into cart.json,
now this is looking better.
So this is now working, this is our cart model added
but with that let's go back to our routing topic which we had in this module and let's see what query
parameters are and how they can help us with editing a product.