We're restricting the amount of products we can see
and that is one great step forward
but it still doesn't mean we can't send requests somehow by creating our own pages where we still
try to delete another product.
So we should also add protections in our post actions, like in post edit and post delete product, there
we want to check that the product I try to delete is really created by the user who is currently logged
in.
So in post edit product, there I might want to add a check
once I found the product that should be edited where I see if I'm allowed to edit that product.
So here in the then block where I have that product fetched from the database, there I will quickly
check if product user ID is not equal to request user ID because if it's not equal, then this means the
wrong user is trying to edit this.
So here I then want to return and simply redirect back to the starting page let's say because we try
to do something fishy here,
we don't want to continue,
so all the other code will now not run.
We would still go into that
then block though as you learned because the next then block is still executed even if I do redirect
here,
so to circumvent this, I'll add
then right after save here
so a nested then block so to say and now we have protection in place that ensures that we can start editing
products that don't belong to us. To quickly check this, I'll temporarily remove my filter so that I can
see all the products again and I will log in with the wrong account,
so with test2 and now what we should see is that when I edit this and add a couple of exclamation marks
and I click update, I'm redirected but the edit wasn't saved because I essentially ended up in my extra check
here and I was redirected back but without saving the changes because this code was never executed.
Now let's try the same for deleting before I re-add my filter here. For deleting
I also want to check if I'm really allowed to delete that product and we can easily implement this by
changing our deletion method here and use delete one
and there I want to delete the product where the ID is equal to the prod ID but also where the user
ID is equal to the request
user ID.
So both has to be true
now, the Product ID alone is not enough, the user id also has to match and therefore even if we have
a valid user id, it will not delete this product if the user ID does not match.
So if I save this and I go to admin products with the wrong account still and I click delete,
you see the product doesn't go anywhere,
still there.
Now let me add that filter in get products again so that we can't even see it
and now we have the best possible set up because now we can really only see it in that account where
we are able to interact with it.
So if I do login with that valid account, there I do see it and there I now also should be able
to edit it, though if I try that, it fails.
So let's explore what's wrong here in the next lecture.