In the last lectures we learned how to spin up that server and that we get a request object with information
about the incoming requests and the response object that we can use to send back a response,
let's now connect both, requests and response.
Instead of printing some request data to the console which of course doesn't do much for us,
let's instead start writing a very simple web server that does different things depending on which route
we enter,
so depending on which slash whatever part we enter here.
So let's say for slash nothing,
we want to load a page where the user can enter some data which we then store in a file on the server
once it is sent. We can do this by first of all parsing the url. I'm storing it in a new constant and I
do this by accessing request
url, remember that was something like slash, /test, whatever we entered.
I will then add an if statement and check if url is equal to just slash and only this will match,
by the way the triple equal sign means that this will only be true if url is both a string and has
that value.
So now here if that is the case, I want to return a response which holds some html that gives the user an
input form and a button that will send a new request in return and that will not be a get request
by the way.
So let's do this step by step, let's copy this code here and put it into this if statement
and here I will write a html document with a head, maybe a different title, enter message
and the body will now not hold a h1 tag but instead a form,
this is a default html element of course with an input of type text
let's say and a button and this will be super ugly because we have no styling but it's about the
functionality for now,
the button tag must be closed by the way. The button will be of type submit so that it submits the form
and that will be some default html behavior we're using here
where a button with type submit in a form element will send a new request and we'll configure that request
in a second.
Let's first give the button a caption, send
and now on that form element here, we add an action which is basically the url this request which will
be generated automatically should be sent to and I will use /message here and this will automatically
target the host
it's running on, so localhost in our case here, localhost 3000
to be precise
and then we define the method,
the http method that should be used and there we previously saw if we expand this, that we get a get request
which is the default if we enter a url,
well here we are not entering a url instead we want to send a so-called post request. There is a limited
set of http words you can use, get and post are the two most important ones. A get request is automatically
sent
when you click a link or enter a url, a post request has to be set up by you by creating such a form,
there also are some other ways by using javascript but we'll ignore them for now.
So in html we create such a form and we defined that the method should be post and this will send a
post request to /message and the cool thing about form is it will not just send such a request,
it will also look into the form, detect any inputs or related elements like selects
we might have
and if we give that input a name which we should, message, it will also automatically put that message
into the request it sends to our server.
So now here when we visit just localhost 3000 slash nothing, we will return a response where
we render this html code.
Now let's also put a return statement in front of res end. This is not required to return a response
but to return from this anonymous function and to not continue this code because we return prior to
it
and this will quit the function execution. And we must do this because I told you that after res end,
we must not call any other res writes or res set headers
but this what happens if we not return because then it would just continue execution with these lines.
I don't want that,
if we make it into the if statement,
we should also quit here,
we should exit out of this function. With this let's restart the server by quitting it with control c and
restarting it with node app.js
and let's reload this page on localhost 3000 slash nothing
and we see my input and the send button here.
Again not super pretty but it's working.
Now let's make sure that if we enter something and we hit send,
we see this, that we now not only see this but that something else happens.
By the way we do see this because now the url is /message and /message does not make
it into this if statement and therefore this code runs.
But we want to do something else
so let's do that in the next lectures.