Now that we are able to sign up and sign in,
we have to work on route protection.
We already have a setup where we only show the menu options we should be able to interact with
but even when I logout and therefore my session is gone, even when I do that, I can still manually
enter admin add product and reach that page and I could even try to create a product here,
I would fail then because there would be no user object on the backend where I tried to get the logged
in user
but this is not the user experience
we want to offer,
we don't even want to be able to load this page if we're not logged in
and for that, we need to protect our routes.
Now how do we protect routes?
Well to protect routes, we want to check where the user is authenticated before we render back
let's say the add product page.
So in admin in the admin controller, in get add product which loads that page, before we render that
page, I want to check if in the request session is logged in is set
and to be precise, I want to check if it's not set because if this is not true, the user is not logged
in
and if the user is not logged in, then I want to redirect
let's say to the login page like this.
So then since I return here, this code will not execute and I won't load the added product page.
So now let me try to reload this page,
keep in mind I'm not logged in and I'm on the login page.
So this works,
I am redirected here because session logged in is not set.
On the other hand if I do login now,
so if I do enter my valid credentials here and I try to access add product,
this does work because now I make it past this if check.
Now this is a code we could add to every route which we want to protect but adding it like this is a
bit cumbersome,
so let me show you a better way of protecting our routes or a more scalable way in the next lecture.