Our plugin is almost complete.
There are just a few more things that need to be done.
The next thing on our list is to make a widget this widget will display a recipe of the day.
If you open the static template you'll find a widget that displays the recipe of the day.
We'll be creating this.
We'll be using a few WordPress API to make this work.
The first API is the widgets API in the resource section of this lecture I provide a link to the widgets
API WordPress provides some really good examples on how to implement your own widget.
We will have to use some object oriented programming to create a widget.
Don't worry it's easy.
Inside the main plugin file.
Let's use the action hook called widgets in it this hook is called When widgets are initialized we will
be able to register our widget with this hook.
The function will want to call is our widgets in it.
We're going to define this function inside a file called widget stop BHP create this file inside the
includes folder and include it from the main plugin file.
This hook is called very early on so to make sure our file is included properly.
We have to pre pen the plugin directory to the inclusion we can accomplish this by using the dir name
function and passing in the plug and you are all constant.
Like so this file will now be loaded properly.
Next let's register the widget to register a widget we have to call the register widget function this
function has 1 required parameter and that's the name of the class that contains our widget.
I'm going to pass in our daily recipe widget
this class doesn't exist.
Let's create it now.
I'm going to create a folder called widgets inside the includes folder next create a file called daily
dash recipe dot P HP and create a class called our daily recipe widget.
Lastly include this file from the main plugin file
the code for loading the widget is finished.
Let's focus on creating the widget.
Now this class has to extend that WP Widget class this class will help integrate our widget with Wordpress
a system.
It will leave us to take care of the rest by displaying the widget and setting up the fields.
Go back to the widgets API documentation page you'll find a default usage section.
Let's copy the code inside the class and paste it into R's.
Let's go through this one by one.
The construct function is where we'll be setting up the widget.
There's only one thing we need to do and that is called the parent constructor method.
This method has three parameters.
The first parameter is an idea for the widget.
Set this to our daily recipe widget.
The second parameter is the title of the widget.
This will be displayed on the widgets admin page and will help users identify your widget.
Let's call this widget recipe of the day.
The last parameter is an array of additional options we can set.
For now we only want to set the description.
The description will be displayed on the widgets admin page.
The description should be short and concise.
Let's set this to displays a random recipe each day
WordPress will now officially recognize the widget.
The next method is called widget.
This method takes care of displaying the widget on the front end.
I'm going to skip this for now.
I promise we'll get back to it later.
Before I move on I'm going to move this method to the very bottom.
The reason I do this is because of my workflow.
I usually like to set up the widget method last.
Now the second method formerly the third is form WordPress.
We'll call this method to render reform that will allow the user to customize this widget your past
in a variable named instance.
This contains the form values of the current instance of the widget our widget won't be super complex.
We're only going to have one field and that's the title of the widget.
First let's create some default values since there's only a title will set the default title to recipe
of the day.
Next we're going to set the instance variable to the value returned by the function WP pass args This
is a utility function provided by WordPress.
This method will merge two arrays together and return the merged array.
If the instance already has a title then the default won't override that title.
Otherwise the title will be set from the default array.
This will guarantee that will have a title set.
Whether this is a new instance or not the widget would be considered a new instance if the user has
dragged and dropped the widget onto a sidebar for the first time the widget would be considered an old
instance.
If the widget is already on the sidebar let's begin displaying the fields.
I'm going to paste in this bit of code paused the video if you need to and copy what I have.
Let's go over what this code does.
We have a label element will set the four attribute for the value returned by the get field idea method.
This method will generate an idea for our field.
You simply pass in the name of the field.
We actually use this method twice the second time.
As for the I.D. attribute in the input field the next method is the get field name just like the get
field I.D. method.
This method will generate a name for our input.
You may be thinking why is this important.
Can't we just generate our own names and I.D. the WordPress widget form is submitted with Ajax.
WordPress takes care of submitting the data and updating the corresponding fields since WordPress is
handling the submission and updates but it's required to give these field special names rather than
us having to worry about those names we can use these methods to do it for us.
It's recommended to let WordPress take care of generating these attributes for you which is what these
functions do.
You'll also notice we don't create form tags because WordPress takes care of that too.
The last attribute we're seeing is the value we output the instances title we sanitize the value with
the EFC attribute function.
This function will make sure that the value can be inserted into an attribute without breaking the code.
To recap the 4 method is for displaying the form it's passed in an instance variable that contains information
about the same data for the current widget.
By default the instance is empty for new widgets since that's the case.
We create some default values and merge it with the instance.
That way we always have the minimum data we need.
Lastly we simply output the fields like so.
The third method we have is the update method.
This method is called when a user submits the form.
This allows us to filter the input in our own way.
This method is passed in two variables.
The first is the new submitted data and the second is the previous instance data.
I'm going to create a new variable called instance.
This will contain all our widget settings.
We only have one setting which is the title.
We'll set the title to the new instance sidle we're going to just sanitize the title by stripping any
tags from the input using the strip tags function.
Then you have to return this instance so that WordPress can then save our widget settings
before we finish.
Let's go back to the widget method and echo out a simple recipe of the day message.
We'll be changing this later.
Let's go to the widget admin page.
You should find the widget ready to use.
Add this widget to your sidebar and place it at the very top.
WordPress takes care of setting up the UI for us and displaying the form.
We can change the title and it will be updated properly.
Let's view our site you should see the widget being output it onto the sidebar.
The widget method is called to display the widget.
Now the question is how do we display a recipe of the day.
We have to take care of picking a random recipe and make it last for a day.
Then our widget should refresh the recipe of the day.
We can do this a number of ways like using the options API.
However there is an API meant for this kind of task which is called the transience API.
Before we use that we have to set up a cron job we'll tackle how to do most of these tasks in the next
lecture.