It's time to get started with Gutenberg at this point.
You should be comfortable with node react and web pack.
We'll be using these technologies to help us with Gutenberg development.
If you're not comfortable with these concepts then I recommend you check out the previous section.
Right now I'm looking at the Gutenberg editor everything here is extendable.
There are two main areas you'll usually want to extend the first area is the content itself.
The content is made up of something WordPress calls blocks.
It may not look like it but every section here is a block each block comes with its own settings.
I can even freely move them around if I wish.
WordPress provides a way to create your own blocks.
We'll take a look at how to do that.
In this section the other area you can extend is the sidebar the sidebar contains information such as
the category tags status etc. we'll be looking at how to extend this as well.
Every area is extendable but these are the two main areas you'll find yourself wanting to extend often.
Here is what we're going to do.
Earlier we created a recipe custom post type.
We're going to create a block that allows users to input information about a recipe.
This will include information such as ingredients cooking time utensils cooking experience and a meal
type.
The overall process for creating a block will look like the following.
First you have to prepare your environment.
This step is optional but this is how I prefer to do things and so I will teach you how to prepare your
environment.
This is basically setting up web packed react and Babel.
Next you have to load in those files Gutenberg comes with a few hooks for making sure your CFS files
are loaded then you have to register your block once again WordPress makes this process easy.
All you have to do is call a few functions and your set.
Once you've taken care of that you will need to create the settings for your block.
This includes stuff like the title icon and form fields.
Lastly you will need to tell Gutenberg how it should display your block now that we have an overview
of things.
Let's start with the first step that would be preparing the environment inside the recipe plugin directory.
Create a folder called blocks we will be placing all our code related to blogs and the Gutenberg editor
here.
You don't have to name your files or folders anything special you can name this whatever you want.
I also want to highlight that we're not placing this folder inside the includes or assets folder.
This directory will contain a mixture of JavaScript CSX and HP code Gutenberg is mostly written with
JavaScript.
This is why we're not placing an inside the includes directory as the code will be vastly different.
However a lot of the logic inside these files do affect how WordPress functions rather than the user
experience.
That is also why we're not placing this inside the assets folder.
This is how I prefer to structure my plugin if you prefer to do something else than that's completely
fine in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a zip file that contains some starter files download it and unzip the contents into the blocks
folder we just created.
This is basically the same setup we had in the previous section with some additional features.
Let's go through this one by one.
Open the package file.
We're going to start with the dependencies.
The first module is the Babel core module which will allow us to write the latest features of JavaScript.
Right after this we're loading the Babel plugins transform react J.S. X module.
That's quite a long name which can make it seem intimidating but he performs one simple task.
It allows you to rename a function the function it'll change is the react dot create element function.
Previously you learned that this function will create an HMO element as you can imagine.
It's a pretty common function to use no matter what you're building.
The problem with this is that react can change how this function works in the future.
WordPress prides itself in being backwards compatible.
If this function changes then all plugins will have to update as well.
While the most popular plugins will keep up the lesser use plugins will quickly become outdated.
To resolve this WordPress wraps the react dot create element function with its own function even if
the we act version changes.
WordPress will make the adjustments required internally for you since that's the case we want to be
able to tell people to use the WordPress version of this function.
This is what that plugin does.
You'll see how bad is configured in just a moment.
Then we have the Babel loader module for web pack right after this is the at WordPress slash Babel preset
default module.
This is a new module I'm introducing in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to this module as we discussed before Babel can be used with various presets.
These presets determine what features of JavaScript you can write.
It helps people convert your code into code that most browsers can understand.
Previously we used the Babel preset e and V module.
However we're going to need some additional features that aren't available under this module.
This will force us to install additional modules and go over them.
Luckily the WordPress development team created their own preset that has us covered.
Now we don't have to configure Babel as much.
Let's keep moving forward afterwords for loading in a module called Cross environment.
As you may know there are various operating systems with their own set of commands.
Windows is particularly known to be quite troublesome in this area.
The cross environment module will make sure that certain settings and commands will work across all
operating systems.
It's a great module for keeping things consistent.
Lastly we're loading in the web pack and web pack CLIA modules which we went over in the previous section.
These dependencies will start us off.
There's quite a few more modules I want to introduce but we'll look at those as the course progresses.
Something I want to highlight is that you don't have to be an expert on these modules.
All of these modules are configurable but a lot of the defaults work just fine.
If we were building a server then we might want to configure this further but we're just building blocks.
All that's important is that you have an overview of things.
All right.
Let's keep moving forward.
If you look inside the scripts property you'll find that the commands are slightly different.
First up is the cross dash e and V command.
This will ensure that the commands we execute are cross compatible with multiple operating systems.
This is related to the cross environment module we talked about earlier.
It's important that the cross dash in V command is entered first so that all the other commands and
options that follow after it will work.
Next we're setting the Babel environment variable to default.
This will just make sure the default settings are used in Babel afterwords.
We're calling the web part command and setting B watch option in the previous section.
We had to continuously run the commands.
Any time we updated a file that watch option will force web pack to continuously watch for changes.
This should save us some time.
That should do it for this file.
Let's move on to the Webb pack.
Dot config dot J.S. file at the very top.
We're loading the path and Webb pack modules then we immediately export an object that contains our
settings for Webb pack.
A lot of this is the same as before from the entry to the output properties.
There are three things different here.
First is the watch property.
This will force Webb pack to continuously watch the file for changes.
We're already doing this in our command.
So this is a bit redundant.
I just wanted to show you the two ways of going about this.
Its all preference.
Next we have the dev tool property Webb pack.
We'll take the time to generate source maps for our JavaScript files.
The purpose of a source map is to convert compressed and modified code back into its original state.
There's very little impact on performance but build times do increase.
There are various values you can use but I prefer to use the cheap eval Valve Source map.
This results in a very fast build time but the source map isn't that great.
That's perfectly fine since we won't be using a source map.
We want something fast and cheap.
The last change is in the rules for the Babel loader.
I'm adding a new property called exclude.
This will make sure Babel doesn't run any files in a particular directory.
In this case we don't want Babel to process any files inside the node underscore modules directory.
We didn't do this before because the previous examples were simple.
However things are going to get a little more complicated from here now.
And so I want to make sure of this directory doesn't get affected.
That'll do it for this file.
The last file I want to go over is the DOT Babel r c file.
Not much going on here.
I'm just using the WordPress default preset we installed earlier.
We don't have to worry about adding the react preset as the WordPress default preset already covers
that for us.
The second property we're using here is called plugins plugins work exactly as you think they allow
third party modules to extend Babel directly.
All we're doing here is telling Babel to use the transform react J.S. exe plugin.
We're also configuring the plugin by passing in an additional object.
We're setting the pragmatic property to WP elements dot create element that is word Press's version
of the react dot create element of function.
We're essentially telling Babel to use the WP version when transforming elements to JavaScript.
That's basically it.
Once again you don't have to be an expert on every module but it's good to have a general overview of
things.
The great thing about this is that it's reusable.
You can copy this from project to project and things will just work.
Now that we have things set up let's install and check if everything works inside your command line.
You may need to see these into this directory to run the installation.
I'm going to input C D.
WP dash content slash plugins slash recipe slash blocks then I'm going to run the commands npm install
to install the modules inside the dependencies object.
This may take a while for some of you.
So be patient.
Lastly let's run the commands NPM run Dev.
This should have Webb pack process to code.
You shouldn't be able to run any additional commands since web pack is continuously watching our files
for any changes inside the blocks directory.
There should be a new directory created called dist.
This will contain the bundle Dodge's file that should confirm everything is working as expected.
That does it for this lecture.
We've prepared our environment.
The next step is to begin in queuing and registering everything.
We'll do that in the next lecture.
I'll see you there.