IOS 6 comes with a new way of creating functions which are called Arrow functions.
I'm going to call my now.
Any code inside the index file.
I'm now going to create a function called Hello and all it will do is output a simple message.
Lastly I'm going to call this function.
This is a regular function.
I'm going to run the node app slash index command as expected.
This will just output the message.
Nothing really new so far.
Arrow functions are a new way to create functions.
The syntax can be a bit confusing at first but it's definitely more readable once you understand what's
going on to create an arrow function.
You need to do the following.
First you don't need to use the function keywords so you can safely remove that.
Next you'll have to remove the name of the function.
Then you need to add the following symbols after the parenthesis equals sign greater than assign.
This is what javascript calls a fat arrow.
Lastly you can remove these curly braces and move the message on the same line.
This is a very basic example of an arrow function.
It's a shorter way of writing a function right off the bat arrow functions are completely anonymous.
You can not just write an arrow function by itself.
You either have to assign it to a variable or pass it into another function that will use it.
If you were to add the name of the function before the parenthesis then you will receive an error.
Let's first learn how to assign it to a variable.
I'm going to create a variable called Hello the value of this variable will be assigned to the Arrow
function like so just like that the arrow function is now usable.
I can run the node command again and you'll see the message.
Just like before let's do a side by side comparison I'm going to add a comment above indicating that
this is an arrow function.
Then I'm going to create a normal function like the one we had before.
These two functions do the exact same thing and are completely identical as far as functionality goes.
The only noticeable difference is the way they're written.
Unlike arrow functions regular functions are usually multi line even if you only have one line of code.
Of course you can always move everything to be one line of code.
However the code becomes less readable.
The arrow function is much more readable and shorter show right.
I'm going to come on out the regular function let's keep working with the aero function aero functions
can also be multiplied to make a multi line function.
You can just add in the curly brackets the curly brackets are completely optional.
If you have one line of code required if you want to have multiple lines just like any other function
we can also have parameters.
I'm going to create a parameter called param one to have multiple parameters.
You can just add a comma to separate each parameter.
For now I only want one parameter.
I'm going to update the code where I called the hello function and pass in a message.
I want to use this parameter so over place this static message with the message we're passed in.
Lastly I'm going to run my command
the script should work as expected where the message is being output it onto the console.
This is pretty simple so far.
There are two things you should be aware of when using arrow functions.
The first thing is that the parentheses are optional.
If you only have one parameter in this example we only have one parameter and so we can just remove
the parentheses from this line of code.
This is completely valid and allowed.
However this option is only available if you have one parameter.
For example if an arrow function has zero parameters then you're required to have parentheses.
If you have one parameter then you have the option of using parentheses.
If you have two or more parameters then you're required to have parentheses.
I'm going to add my parentheses back in even though we only have one parameter.
This right here is preference throughout this course.
I will continue using parentheses even if my arrow functions only have one parameter.
The second thing you need to be aware of is that arrow functions do not have a scope right below this
bit of code.
I'm going to create an object called foo this object will have two properties prompt one will be set
to 10.
Prop 2 won't be a regular function that logs Prop 1.
There are two ways to reference Prop 1.
I can use the foo variable and then access its property or I can use the this keyword.
The this keyword is the most commonly used method.
I'm going to run my node command and I should see the number 10 output it lets try using arrow functions.
Now I'm going to remove the function keyword and add in the fat arrow.
Lastly I'm going to run the command again and see what we get.
Node will not throw an error but instead output undefined ARROW functions.
Don't really have a scope.
This means that the this keyword doesn't really exist.
What javascript will do is look up one level and see if that property exists.
If we want to output Prop 1 we would have to change the this keyword to food.
Then we can run the command and we should see the number of being output it again.
That's all there is to it.
Arrow functions are popular for two reasons.
The first reason is that it's easier to read and write than regular functions.
The second reason is that the scope becomes less of a problem.
This is because you know what to expect.
Even if you have nested functions since arrow functions have no scope it becomes easier to understand
where variables are coming from.
I know it may not seem like a big deal but it really does matter when we begin writing bigger applications
throughout this course we will use arrow functions a lot.