We're almost done right now.
I'm in the header file.
We still have some static sections inside the template.
First let's tackle the title.
WordPress provides two solutions for adding titles to your head.
The first solution is a bit outdated and that is by using the WP title function.
This function is to be deprecated but it is still available for backwards compatibility.
I do not suggest using it the recommended solution is to add theme support for it.
I'm going to delete the title tags from the head tag and then open the setup file.
I'm going to call the function at theme support and pass entitled hash tag just like that.
WordPress will always generate the title tag for you.
Any SEO plugins will also be able to make modifications if they wish.
Next up is the logo itself.
The logo can either be text or an image.
Currently we only have text.
We are also willing to accept images.
I'm going to call the function app theme support again and pass in custom dash logo WordPress comes
with a feature for users to upload their own logos.
We don't have to make a form or handle the upload.
You'll see how this works in just a moment.
Go back to the header template and look for the div tag with the idea of Logo.
Inside this tag add a conditional statement to check if the user has uploaded a logo.
You have to use the function has custom logo this function will return true if the user uploaded a logo.
Otherwise it'll return False if there is a logo.
Then we can call a function called the custom logo.
This function will output the image along with the link to the home page.
In some situations the user might not have a logo ready when they set up the theme whatever their reason
may be.
You should have a backup.
Let's add the else block and manually create a link.
I'm going to use the static version as a template.
I'm going to replace the link and echo out the value returned by the function home yourself.
I'm going to pass in a forward slash so we can specify that we only want the route you are out inside
the tanks.
I'm going to call the blog info function This function takes in a string which is what pieces of information
about the blog we want in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to more info about this function.
Here you'll find a list of values you can pass in the very first one.
Its name which returns the name of the site so let's pass that in this function will automatically output
the value if you ever want the value returned.
Then you just use the get blog info function.
Let's refresh the page and check if everything is working so far.
If you look at the title you'll notice it updates accordingly.
The logo is also showing our text to change the logo to an image.
You need to click this button called customize.
This will take you to the customized which is a way to edit your site while also viewing the changes
in real time under a site identity.
You will find the form for updating the logo.
I don't have a logo image so I will leave this alone.
The next two things I want to do is update the menu and fix this advertising spot.
Before you do that I want to talk about this customization in the past the WordPress customized was
really hard to work with and did not have as much features.
This made developers make their own settings and options page to change how the theme functions.
However in recent updates the Customize miser is starting to become the main way to modify a theme.
A lot of theme developers are opting to use the customize.
We will definitely be working with the Customize your suit for now let's focus on this secondary menu
on the top.
We've already created a menu before.
So try creating another one yourself.
If you aren't able to do it then let's try it together.
I'm not going to go over every detail so will fly by this quickly.
First in the setup function.
Use the registered nav menu function.
I'm going to reuse the previous code and replace these values with the words secondary like so with
the menu registered.
We can now display it.
I'm going to go into the admin dashboard and create a new menu and assign it to the secondary location
inside the header template.
I'm going to copy and paste the last menu into the other menu spot.
I'm going to replace these two values with the secondary menu and then set the depth to one since I
don't want drop downs for the secondary menu.
Refresh the page and you should now see the secondary menu being displayed.
So far everything is really coming together.
This ad spot has been broken for some time so let's fix that.
Previously we used the plug in WP subtitle to add subtitles to our posts.
We will be doing something similar to this and the resource section I provide a link to the WP quads
plugin.
This plugin handles advertisement for wordpress sites.
It's a really great plugin that is updated constantly.
The best part is that it's developer friendly we can create our own custom ad spots and have it managed
by this plugin.
This frees us from having to handle all the logic ourselves.
I want you to install and activate this plugin through the admin dashboard
after doing so.
Look inside the WP dash contents flash plugins folder.
This is where all your plugins are installed.
The quick dash adds sense dash reloaded plugin is the plugin we just installed open the includes slash
API dot HP file you'll notice in these comments the developer left notes on how to integrate this plugin
into your theme.
There are two steps you need to do.
The first step is to tell WP quads that you have a custom ad spot in your thing.
The second step would be to instruct it where to display the ad spot.
I'm going to register this ad spot in the setup function instead of the function's file.
The reason I'm doing this is because the setup function is called right after our theme has been loaded.
Therefore I know nothing has been officially processed unless it was put in the function file so it's
technically the same thing.
The only difference is that it's in separate files.
This makes our code look a whole lot cleaner.
I'm going to copy and paste the commented code into this function like so I'm only going to have one
spot.
You'll see that this code does two things.
First we use a conditional statement to check if the function quads register ad exists.
This way we know that the WP wants plugin is activated.
Then we call the function quads register ad which has two parameters.
The first is the idea of the location.
I'm going to call this Udemy header and for the description it will be Udemy header position with this
in place WP quads will now know we have an ad spot inside the admin dashboard.
You'll find the WP quads menu under the ad codes section.
I'm going to paste in an image tag
the image that I'm using is from a site called Place whole dot I.T..
I'll provide a link to this image.
This site allows you to modify the size of the image and create a temporary place holder.
This is really great for web development save the changes and then switch to the position tab.
You'll notice that our new position is showing up at the very bottom.
Activate this position and assign it to the first ad we created.
Make sure to save your changes our ad is ready.
And now all we have to do is display it inside the header template look for the div tag with the class
top dash advert.
Add a conditional statement that checks for the function quads at
then I'm going to call this function and pass in an array with the key location the name of the location
will be the location you pass into the quads register ad function this function will return the H.G.
mail we passed in previously.
So we have to echo it out that's it.
Let's check if our ad appears appropriately.
Just like that we now have ads on our site with custom locations.
This plugin is amazing and it takes care of managing ads.
This is the second plugin we've used in our theme.
It's extremely common for theme developers to bundle their themes with plugins.
This increases the value of your theme in a future lecture.
I will go over how you can bundle plugins with your theme properly.
The reason I'm not showing you now is because I don't want to have to constantly update multiple files
whenever we add a plugin.
I would rather knock it out all at once when our theme is nearly finished.
For now we will continue working on the header and eventually moved to the footer on the header.
We have these social icons for these icons.
We will be using the word press customized.
This will introduce us to how the it works and how to extend it.
I do want to give you a warning.
So far we've really just been calling functions and using Wordpress as templating system to handle a
lot of the logic for us WordPress will still help us with extending the customized R but we will be
writing a lot more code and be focusing more on the code rather than the visual aspect.
The customized can seem overwhelming but I promise you we will be using it constantly so you will get
used to it eventually.
I highly recommend you take a break before moving onto the next lecture.
See you there.