Let's get started with child themes.
If you heard of child themes but don't know what or how a child theme works then this lecture is important
for you.
A lot of developers avoid child things because WordPress doesn't really make it clear how to develop
or use child themes.
I don't want you to be one of those developers.
A child theme is extremely powerful and useful.
What makes it so useful is that you can modify an existing theme without having to worry about your
code becoming irrelevant or overwritten back in the old days.
If he wanted to modify a theme then you'd have to directly edit the files.
Then when an update was available you'd have to start all over again and keep track of all the edited
files and changes.
It was very annoying and time consuming when child themes were introduced.
The whole process became so much easier because your code was never overwritten and the theme was also
not modified.
Now that you understand what child themes are let's get started with creating one go to WordPress dot
org and go to the themes pages.
We're going to download a theme called M H magazine lite.
Then we're going to add this theme to our WordPress site by opening the themes folder and then dragging
the contents of the zip file into this folder like so
next.
I'm going to copy this folder and I'm going to paste it in again.
I'm going to reading this folder and use the same name except I'm going to append dash child so I know
that this is a child thing
WordPress doesn't require you to name a child theme anyway.
This is just how I prefer to do it and how I recommend you do it open the child theme and select every
folder and files except the functions style and screenshot files delete these files
I'm now going to open my editor and look for the trial theme.
Open the functions file and delete all this code.
I'm just going to leave an open page p tag for later.
We're going to do the same to the style dot CFS file except you should not delete the headers that come
with it.
From here we're going to make two changes.
The first change is the name of this theme.
I'm going to add a child theme to the name
once again.
This is not required but it makes it easier to tell which theme is the parent theme and which is the
child theme.
Next we have to define a new property called template the value of this property will be the name of
the parent themes folder name.
In our case it would be MH dash magazine dash like
this value is case sensitive.
Be sure to set this value correctly.
After that you're all done.
Let's go to the WordPress dashboard and navigate to appearance.
We now have two MH magazine light themes activate the child themed version and then try visiting your
site.
We don't get any errors not even in the console.
But the site isn't displaying correctly.
Why is that.
Well it's pretty simple.
Wordpress is loading these style dot CSO file because that's what the parent theme does.
WordPress will load the functions file from the parent theme and load the child themes function file.
Let's take a look at the parents function file
if you scroll down a bit the parent theme and accuse a file with the function get style sheet.
You are right.
This function will return the you are right to the current theme style dot c SS file even if we're using
the child theme.
This would be the child style dot CFS file and not the parents style that CFS file the parent style
dot CSA as contains all the main styles for the theme.
The question is how do we load both the parents styles and the child styles.
There are a couple solutions here but the developer friendly one is by using action hooks lets open
the child things function file and add the action hook WP and Q scripts.
I'm going to be using an anonymous function since we won't be doing much with this child thing.
I'm going to register the parent style to get the parent style that CSX we first have to use a function
called Get template direct REU or I
this function will get better rectory of the parent theme without the forward slash.
Since we're in the parent theme directory we can append the style dot CSX file name
next.
I'm going to register the child theme style dot CSX file by using the function get style sheet you are
right which will return the URL of the current theme style dot CSX file.
Lastly I'm going to include both files.
Refresh your site and you should now see that it's working properly.
Just to make sure I'm going to open the child's style dot CSX file and change the background color of
the body to yellow
refresh the page.
That's absolutely hideous but at least we know our styles are loading correctly.
If your changes aren't being loaded you can press control f 5 on Your keyboard to force a refresh with
a clear cache for this page.
That's pretty much it for child themes.
From here you can add anything you like.
If you were to create a file named for for dot P HP inside the child theme.
Then the child themes for all for template will load instead of the parent themes version.
It's that simple actually.
Let's try that really quick.
In the address bar of your browser type in some random characters and you'll see the parent themes for
all four template being loaded let's create our version by creating a forum for dot P HP file inside
the child theme and just add the text for all four
let's refresh this page and you will now see the child theme template being loaded instead of the parent's
version.
Wordpress is smart enough to know which template to use your child themes templates will be loaded over
the parent themes templates you're now free to overwrite anything from the parent theme.