We have a fully functional plugin.
The code is clean organized and secure for wordpress.
However there may be people out there who disagree for one reason or another they may have found another
plugin that's even better in such cases.
They will uninstall our plug in our plug and does a pretty good job of cleaning itself up when deactivated.
But what about for on installation.
This is a common problem among thousands of plugins available to you.
They spend so much time adding to your database and system during activation but rarely do any clean
up during an installation.
We don't want to be one of those developers.
We want to clean up after ourselves once we get the boot.
WordPress makes it easy for us.
There are two ways to clean up but one is better than the other.
The first way is to use a hook.
There is a special hook called when WordPress on installs a plugin.
However despite its availability WordPress highly recommends we don't use it.
Instead they recommend the second way which is to create a file named uninstalled P HP that handles
the cleanup.
Let's create that file now inside the recipe plugin folder any code placed here will run when a user
clicks uninstall for our plugin.
There is one precaution we must take before running any code and that is to check if this file was executed
by WordPress.
You can do this by simply checking if a constant named WP uninstall plugin is defined.
If it isn't then it will simply exit out of this script.
The only thing we want to do is delete any tables we created during activation.
We're going to use the w PDB object again.
We're going to call the query method and use the following query drop table if exists.
W PDB prefix recipe underscore ratings
before we test this plugin.
I want to back up the plugin open the plugins folder in your file explorer and let's zip up this folder
before doing anything else let's try testing this out now open Heidi Eskew will and check your database
for the recipe ratings table.
Then let's go to the plugins page and deactivate the plugin.
Click Delete and you will be asked if you're sure you want to delete this plugin and its data.
Select Yes and our plugin will disappear from WordPress
if I look at my folders then you'll see that the recipe folder is gone.
If I refresh the database then you'll find a recipe ratings table is also gone.
We've successfully cleaned up after ourselves before we end this lecture.
Let's add our plugin back by using the zip file we created earlier.
Make sure to activate it as well.
A question I get asked a lot is if we should also delete the content for the post type metadata and
taxonomy is the answer is it depends.
There are plugins out there that will delete unused data.
So I prefer to let those plugins handle it.
The reason we're not doing it ourselves is because there's a possibility that the data may still be
in use.
Keep in mind that our plugin makes certain content accessible and manageable through our own interface.
However there are other plugins that can also access our data using the WordPress API.
The recipe table we deleted was a custom table so it's highly unlikely a plugin will know how to work
with it let alone know its existence.
That table was outside the scope of WordPress as API.
Therefore we should clean it up.
Custom post type data and metadata are things within WordPress as scope.
So it's perfectly fine to leave that data there.
We can leave it to other plugins to clean that up if the user needs that at the end of the day.
It's up to you if you want to delete the custom post type data then that's perfectly fine.