We are now going to talk about react react is a javascript library that allows you to build complex
user interfaces.
It's mostly used to build single page applications which is something we'll cover later in this course.
Truthfully we ask is a massive library with various features.
It's something that deserves a course of its own.
I won't be able to cover every little thing.
I highly recommend checking out a course dedicated to react on you.
To me the purpose of these next few lectures is to give you a light introduction to this library.
Luckily you don't need to know every little feature to develop plugins for Gutenberg.
The team behind Gutenberg have already taken care of the heavy lifting just like everything else in
WordPress.
You just call a few functions and you're set.
You don't even need to know react to get started with Gutenberg development.
However I believe having an overview of things will make you a better developer.
Everything I show you here will be enough to make you comfortable with Gutenberg development.
Right now I'm on the official react site.
Everything you want to know about react can be found here right on the home page you'll find a link
to a tutorial I recommend checking out this tutorial once you finish this section in the resource section
of this lecture I provide a zip file with some starter files download it and unzip the contents.
Let's review the files.
First up is the Web pack dot config dot J.S. file.
This is pretty much the same thing we had before.
We will be working inside the app directory and the final results will be saved inside the disk directory.
Lastly I'm loading the Babel module.
Next let's open the package file.
Everything is the same except for three things inside B dependencies object.
I'm loading three modules called react react.
Dom Babel preset react the react module is the core of React itself react is split into multiple modules.
This way we're not forced to use everything at once.
This is basically the only required module.
If you ever use react the react da module is responsible for displaying your HDL and working with the
H2 e-mail document.
This used to be a part of the core but since reacts inception the library has grown to accommodate various
scenarios.
You can use react for creating mobile and desktop applications in these cases.
It may not be necessary to use the react Dom module for this course we will be interacting with the
HDMI document.
So will need this module.
The Babel preset react module will make sure any react related code also gets processed will need to
add this to the DOT Babel RC file.
Open this file and add the react preset.
You can also set Babel dash preset dash Eon V to Eon DVD.
This is the shorthand version of that module.
That's basically it.
We don't have to worry about configuring Westpac since Babel will take care of loading the modules required
for react.
We don't need to install any special modules for those libraries.
All right let's open the command line and run the commands npm install.
This will install the modules inside the package file.
Make sure your command line is pointed to your directory before running the command.
Hopefully.
Everything was installed successfully for you next.
Let's open the index dot HDMI file.
This file is pretty basic.
I'm loading a script file named bundle dot J.S. which currently doesn't exist.
That's perfectly fine.
We'll be adding it later.
Right now I want to focus on one thing for this example.
I want to display a list of people inside the body tag.
I'm going to create a div tag with the I.D. people then I'm going to create a list of people.
I'll do this quickly
so I have a couple of div tags with the class person.
Each person has a name and age.
It's pretty straightforward.
The problem with this is that we're constantly rewriting the same thing.
Right now we have two people but can you imagine how much code this would be with 50 or 100 people.
It would be disastrous.
Since the HDMI L is all the same we can use something react calls components
components are reusable HDMI elements.
That's an oversimplification but just keep going with me here.
If you were to look at any web page then you can break it down into components the header content sidebar
and footer can be broken down into components.
The advantages of using components are pretty clear.
You can reuse them which can make your code look a whole lot cleaner to get started.
Open the app directory you'll find a file called index dot J.S. currently attempting to create a component.
The first thing we need to do is import react we can name this import whatever we want.
But once again it's common practice to name and after the module name the module is available inside
the node underscore modules directory.
This is why we don't have to pass in a dot forward slash web pack and Node are more than capable of
finding the package for you.
We're going to create a function called person when it comes to components.
You must name your components with uppercase letters.
I'll explain why in just a moment but let's keep moving forward.
Inside this function I'm going to return some HDMI out I'll grab the H2 UML from the document.
Like so.
All right let's stop here for a moment.
You'll notice that I'm not surrounding the h t email with quotes.
This is what's called J.S. X..
J Yes X stands for JavaScript x amount.
It's a way to allow you to write H.G. AML in JavaScript files you have to surround your HDL UML with
a pair of parentheses though if you put your hcm email all on one line then the parentheses are optional.
Since we have multi line HCM L then it's required.
Another thing I want to note is that I've completely emptied out the did element since we'll be loading
this through react.
This function is pretty straightforward if it's called then it overturned the JSC X the J NSX isn't
ready though.
One of the drawbacks of using JSA X is that some attributes may not work as expected.
For example the class keyword can't be used in HCM l the class attribute is used to assign classes to
an element.
However in JavaScript the class keyword is used to create objects.
This is a conflicting problem to get around this react provides an alternative instead of class.
Change this to class name.
This will do what the class attribute does.
This doesn't apply to all attributes.
I'll be sure to let you know which attributes work differently throughout this course.
This is also why be upper case the functioning lower case letters indicate that the element is a regular
H2 email element while an uppercase letter indicates that the element is a component.
This is common practice among developers.
Moving on I now want to call this function so I can display the J.S. sex inside it.
To do that we'll need to import the react Dom module.
Remember the react Dom module will take care of working with the H2 email document.
So we'll need an order for this to work below the function.
I'm going to call the render function from the react Dom object this function will take care of displaying
your J.S. sex on the browser.
It requires two parameters.
The first parameter is the component that will display the J.S. sex.
You may be tempted to call this function like so but that's the incorrect way of using it.
This function wants to render an element so we'll have to pass in the component like an element.
I'm going to create a self closing tag with the person component as the element name.
The second parameter requires the name of the element on the page that will contain the rendered J.S.
X..
I'm going to use the div tag with the I.D. people.
I'll just use some old fashioned javascript to select this element that should do it.
Let's run the commands NPM start
after running this command.
Open your browser to view the page.
You should see the person being displayed without a problem check the console for any errors as well.
There shouldn't be any.
Just like that we've created our very first react application.
It wasn't too hard.
Let's review what we did inside the file.
The very first thing we did was import some modules.
Something you'll notice is that we didn't bother using the react module.
However that's entirely not true.
Even though it's not written anywhere it does get used in our code.
I'm going to paste in some code really quick inside the person of function.
I've commented out the ASX instead I'm using react to create the elements.
You don't have to do this.
Just watch.
I'll explain more in just a moment but let's see if this works inside the command line input the commands
NPM start then I'll refresh the page and I'll see the name output.
Once again it may seem like there are two ways to generate HDL but it's actually all the same thing.
J.S. sex is first and foremost javascript even though it looks like h t AML this code will be interpreted
as javascript Babel will convert this into the code below react has a function called Create element
as the name suggests.
This will create an element.
There are three required parameters.
The first is the name of the element I passed him the div tag.
Then you need to pass on the attributes if your element doesn't have any attributes then you can set
this to know.
And this example I'm setting the class name property to person.
Lastly you need to pass in the content.
I'm actually passing in another create element function.
You have to do this if you want to have nested elements.
This time I'm creating an H one tag with the text Jack.
Other than that the rest of our code is the same J.S. X as javascript.
It looks like h t l but it will eventually be converted to the code I have here.
You can already see the benefits of using JSA X it makes our code look readable and manageable.
This is why I am teaching you react when we start working with Gutenberg.
You have the option of using JSA X or these functions right now.
Our example is pretty simple but can you imagine the code we'd have to write for 10 elements.
Writing it like this is not wrong but you do make it harder for yourself.
I highly encourage you to use CSX when creating plugins for Gutenberg.
I'm going to comment this out and then uncommon.
My JSA ex moving on this function will only create the person element.
The next step is to render it on the page to do that.
We use the render function we pass this in as J.S. X and then we tell it where to display that element.
That's all there is to it.
I recommend you play around with this a little bit in the next lecture.
I'll go over a couple more things before we move onto Gutenberg development.