Throughout this course we've been bundling various plugins with our theme.
We even have a custom plugin developed forcing the user to manually download each plugin would be a
pain.
It would be nice if the user could download all the plugins at once.
We could just download it and then included with P. HP but this would be inefficient.
We would have to manually update each plugin every time one of them gets updated.
It would also bloat our plugin heavily.
Can you imagine having to manage your plugin along with 10 other plugins.
It would be disastrous.
The more efficient solution would be to notify the user of the required plugins and then help them install
those plugins with a simple UI that would take a lot of code to write.
Luckily there's a solution that helps with bundling plugins and making the process so much smoother.
That solution is called Ti GM plug in activation in the resource section.
I provide a link to this class.
This class handles a lot of the work for us and it does exactly what we need.
It will check the user's WordPress site and their plugins.
It'll check if the site contains the plugins needed.
If they don't have those plugins then it'll add a warning notice and instruct the user to install those
plugins.
It will also provide a UI for installing those plugins.
It's a very lightweight class it's just one file so you don't have to worry about your theme being bloated.
Let's get started.
First we need to download this file.
Go to the download section.
You're allowed to download this plugin without any modifications but there's this handy little generator
that takes care of modifying the plugin to suit our needs.
I'm going to set this to work with our theme and for the fields I'm going to input our theme settings
like so feel free to follow along.
After setting up this field click generate.
You should receive a zip file.
There are a lot of files inside this zip file but the only file we care about is the class.
Dash t GM dash plug in dash activation dot P HP file.
Let's open the Udemy theme folder and navigate to the includes folder.
Create a new folder called lives and drop this file into this folder
open your code editor and required this file from within the function's file.
We use the required ones function instead of the include function because this is what the developers
recommend so will heed their advice.
Keep in mind that this class can also be used in plugins.
This can possibly cause errors as we may get errors related to redefining an existing class.
Luckily we don't have to do anything because the developers have taken care of this for us.
If you were to open this class you'll find the classes wrapped inside this conditional statement.
This statement will check if this class has already been defined.
If it has then it won't be redefined.
Like you said before.
This is a great piece of code to use in your theme or plugin.
All right now we can begin using this class inside the zip file.
There is another file called example dot p p that provides a very detailed example on how to use this
class.
It's neatly compensated and all examples are clear after this course.
I highly recommend you take the time to look over this example file so that you can get the most out
of it.
The first step we need to take is to use an action hook called T GMP a register the function to call
is j you register required plugins
create a file inside the includes folder called register dash plugins dot P HP and define the function
here
include this file from the function's file
where first going to create an array called plugins.
This will be an array of plugins our theme requires each plugin we want to require will also be an array.
First we need to determine which plugins we want to come bundled with our theme.
Go to the plugins admin page.
We have some plugins here that are only for development purposes so we don't want to bundle those.
I'm going to deactivate some and we'll go over the ones we do want to bundle.
All right so I just deactivated some plugins.
Here are the plugins I want to come bundled with our theme add since integration WP quads buddy press
recipe regenerate thumbnails Woo commerce WordPress popular posts and WP subtitle.
Let's start with the WP quads plugin to add a plug into the array.
You just add another array.
The array must have certain keys so t GM knows which plug in to grab from the WordPress plugin repository.
The first key is the name of this plugin.
We can grab this from the plugin page which is Ad Sense plug in WP quads
the next key to set is the slug.
This wouldn't be the plugins unique to URL from the WordPress repository.
You can grab this from the euro of the plugin page.
You don't need the whole your alt Justice bit that says quick dash adds since dash reloaded.
Lastly we can set the required key.
We have two options here.
If we set this to true then this class will tell the user of this plugin is required for the theme to
work.
If false then WordPress will recommend this plugin instead.
It's up to you whether a plugin is required or recommended.
I'm going to set this to false I'm going to posit a video and do this for the other plugins except for
the custom recipe plugins as those require different settings.
All right.
So I added the plugins.
All I did was I went to each plugin repository page and grabbed the title and your URL from that page.
The last plugin we need to include is the custom plugin we developed this plugin is not available anywhere.
There are two solutions here.
We can upload our plug into the repository but that takes a long time and I just want this plugin to
be exclusive to this theme.
Luckily te GM is also willing to look for plugins in other locations like inside your own theme.
Here's what I want you to do zip up the recipe plugin and cut the zip file
next open the Udemy theme folder create a folder called a plugins and paste it inside here.
Now we just have to let te GM know about this plugin.
Add another array and set the name to recipe
the slug should be set to the name of the plugin folder which is recipe.
The next key is a must which is source.
This path can be a system path or an H GDP you are out.
I'm going to use the function get template directory and then append the path to the recipe plugins
zip file.
Lastly I'm going to set the required key to true.
Next we need to create an array called config.
This will contain the settings for the class.
There are a lot of settings we can set but the following are the only ones we care about I.D..
This is a unique idea.
Keep in mind that we can use this class multiple times.
We want to make sure that these plugins and settings are related to our theme only.
I'm going to set this to you to me.
Menu.
This is the menu slug that WordPress will use for displaying the UI.
The recommended path is to GMP a dash install dash plugins
parents slug this will be the page to use for displaying the UI.
Once again it's recommended we use the theme stop BHP file
capability who can install and activate the plugins we'll be using the edit theme options capability
has notices a boolean value which will determine whether or not the admin will be notified about the
required plugins.
We want to set this to true
dismissal whether or not the notice messages can be dismissed.
Set this to true as we don't want to annoy users with immovable notices
the very last step is to call a function called TGA NPA.
This function has two parameters which is the plugins to install and then the configuration settings.
That's it.
Let's go to the plugins page.
We should see nothing changed so far but let's deactivate buddy press for a moment.
You'll now see a notice telling us that the theme recommends buddy press as an activated plugin.
Let's click install plugins.
We now have this table of plugins to install along with additional information.
Activate buddy press again just like that.
We were able to install and activate a third party plugin with very little code and work.
Now we don't have to worry about keeping track of this plugin as WordPress will do it for us all thanks
to the Tea GMP class.