After we pasted in the code into the loop I started to notice that our code is becoming really nested.
Not only that I know for a fact that this part of the template is reusable in future lectures we'll
be reusing this part of the template multiple times.
Therefore I want this to be reusable.
Luckily WordPress provides a solution for this by providing something called template parts template
parts are reusable templates that we can add into any template we want by themselves.
They don't do anything.
A template parts are meant to be used inside another template in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to the function get template part.
This function will load a template part into your template.
It's similar to the get header and get footer functions.
The only difference is that you can give your template parts any name you want.
If we take a look at the parameters you'll see there's only to the first parameter is the slug for the
generic template and the second is for the specialized template.
What does WordPress mean by generic and specialized templates.
This function tends to confuse some developers.
So let me break down how it works.
This function will load a template but it performs a lot of checks before it loads the template you
specify.
Here is the simplest example of the function being used in order to load a template.
You need to specify the path relative to the theme folder.
In this case WordPress will load a template named content dot P. HP pretty simple so far.
Let's take a look at the second parameter being used now.
In this example we're passing in the phrase foo for the second parameter.
WordPress will load either one of two templates.
First it will combine both content and food together into the file name content dash food up HP.
If that template doesn't exist then it'll search for the content dot P. HP template and load that instead
you can think of this as a backup.
At this point you may be thinking why don't we just do this.
Why don't we just use the first parameter exclusively.
You may be tempted to do this for the most part.
This is completely valid.
However I don't recommend it.
The purpose of the second parameter is to give yourself a backup template just in case WordPress is
unable to find your first choice.
The only time you don't want to use the second parameter is when you know for a fact that you don't
need a backup template.
I'm gonna go back to my editor and I'm going to create a new folder called partials.
This is where we'll be storing all our template parts.
You can name this folder whenever you want partials is just a fancy word for parts of a template.
Sometimes referred to as template parts or views by other developers inside this folder.
I'm going to create another folder called Post.
This is where will store template parts related to posts.
Lastly I'm going to create a file named content dash excerpt up HP once again you can name this whatever
you want but it should accurately describe what's inside.
I'm going to cut and paste the HP email code into this template like so.
Now we have the excerpt in its own file.
All we need to do now is load it inside the loop right after the post function call the function get
template part.
The path you have to pass it must be relative to the theme folder.
This function basically does what the required function does.
You may be thinking why don't we just use the required function that well it's because this function
does a whole lot of checks for you and makes sure it'll grab the template relative to the current install
directory.
Keep in mind that you can use this function inside of template parts.
So trying to keep track of where you are in your folder structure can get tricky.
This function eases that by always pointing to the theme folder.
All you have to do is point the path relative to the current theme.
The great thing about this function is that you don't have to worry where you are in your template.
If you're inside a nested folder structure then the path you input here will always be the same.
This is because it'll append the path you pass in onto the directory of the current activated theme.
The path to our file is partials slash post slash content Dash.
Excerpt you do not need to add the extension as it's added for you already.
Let's check to see if this works and then we'll explore this function a bit more after refreshing the
page.
You should see the static blog post appearing a few times.
This is exactly what we wanted.
Now let's go back and examine the two parameters for this function.
I'm going to make a copy of this function and make one small change.
I'm going to move the word excerpt into the second parameter like so.
This is also a valid way to use this function.
Earlier I told you about General and specialized templates.
This function provides a way to display a default template in case a certain template is unavailable.
Let's examine the first function first.
I'm going to add a comment above the template that will be loaded when this function runs is the content
Dash.
Excerpt BHP template file.
However if WordPress doesn't find this file then nothing will be loaded for this second function.
WordPress behaves a bit differently.
WordPress will look for a template called content dash.
Excerpt up HP WordPress will combine the two paths together.
Separating them with a dash.
This is similar to what we did above.
However here's where things get different.
If WordPress doesn't find the template content dash excerpt copy HP and WordPress will look for a template
called content dot P HP.
So basically whatever is in the first parameter.
If WordPress doesn't find this template then nothing will be loaded.
This behavior is really great as it allows you to create a fallback or default template.
If we go back to the documentation you should now understand that WordPress describes the default or
fallback template as the generic template.
If you want to load a template for a particular situation then you can use the second parameter to your
advantage.
This is really great as you won't have to do the checks yourself.
It's taken care of for you behind the scenes.
A practical example would be loading a template for a specific month.
For example let's say I had a function called Get month that returns the current month and this imaginary
example.
I'll have a template for the month Dec.
I'll end up having a file named content dash Dec dot BHP.
This will be the only template for this month.
Any other month will not have a template.
Therefore I would just let all the other months fall back to just content up BHP.
That's just the basic example.
That's up to you how you want to use this.
Anyway I'm going to change this back to excerpt and comment it out.
I don't plan on having multiple templates for the content dash excerpt.
So this first line will do just fine in the next lecture.
We'll make the content generated dynamic.