We're almost finished.
Folks the last step to any plug in or theme is distributing it.
Let's start by talking about licensing admittedly WordPress has had a controversial history with licensing.
Back in 2009 people predicted that WordPress would die due to dual licensing or split licensing.
Wordpress is licensed under the GPL license.
It basically means that the software is free to use modify and distribute.
There is no secret encryption or files that you are not allowed to access.
It's all available to you.
This was considered great to many but there was one important question some had.
What about commercial themes and plugins.
Well technically all plugins and themes must all be distributed with the GPL license to this concerned.
Many developers because it meant that all their code would have to be made available for free.
However this is far from the truth.
You are still allowed to sell plugins and themes.
Your code must be available to modify but that doesn't mean you can't sell it.
It's perfectly fine to sell your plugins and themes.
You can also create a license system that provides buyers a way to receive updates and support.
If you're providing your plugin or theme for free then this topic shouldn't worry you so much.
You can simply go to WordPress dot org create an account and upload your plugin.
The rest is taken care of for you if you want to sell your plugin and or theme then you have two main
options available to you.
You can create your own site to attract buyers.
This would mean you wouldn't have to take care of everything from MCO to processing transactions and
creating a licensing system.
A lot of developers have taken this route and are successful to this day.
For others this can be a bit time consuming as it can take a long time and money to market your plugin.
Luckily there's another alternative.
There's a marketplace called Code Canyon MTM forest.
Both marketplaces are owned by a company called and vato.
Right now I'm on the Infowars looking at the top selling wordpress themes page.
The most popular theme here is called a veto.
This company is selling about 2000 copies a week at the price of sixty dollars.
Through theme for us they're able to generate a lot of revenue in Votto provides the licensing transaction
processing and the marketing of your plugin and or theme there's a rating system a form a lot of buyers
and the tools to help sell your code.
All you have to do is provide the goods.
Of course there is a variable fee of around 20 percent but it's well worth it.
I've personally sold on this platform and have made a decent amount of sales selling both themes and
plugins.
If you want to start receiving sales quickly then I highly recommend you consider selling on code.
Kenyan MTM forest.