One section we haven't gotten around to is this breaking news which is keeping track of popular posts
can be tedious and it's not exactly built into wordpress.
Luckily there is a plugin out there that will help us out with that.
I want you to go to the admin dashboard and add a new plug in the plug and I want to install is called
WordPress popular posts install and activate the one by Hector.
This plugin will automatically help us keep track of what posts are popular by views
under settings.
You'll find a menu item called WordPress popular posts here.
You can control what posts are popular and additional setting.
We don't need to make any changes at this moment right now.
None of the posts are popular.
I'm going to open the home page with in a new tab and view at least three posts.
I want you to do the same refresh the admin page after you've done so and you'll now see those three
posts being displayed as popular posts.
This is great so far.
There are now two things we need to do.
We need to display the popular posts and then we need to let the user control whether or not they want
to display it while we're at it.
We will also make the text breaking news changeable.
First let's display these posts inside the WordPress popular posts admin page.
I'm going to click on the parameters tab.
This plugin allows you to display the popular posts two ways.
One way is through a short code and the other is through a template tag.
I want to use the template tag.
You'll find a list of parameters we can set to modify the output we'll be using these shortly inside
the index template.
I want you to perform a conditional check around the popular post widget.
I want to check for two things I want to check out the page being displayed is not a single post and
is the home page.
Using the functions exclamation point is single and is home.
These two functions are at WordPress calls conditional tags conditional tags or a way to check what
kind of page is being displayed in the resource section.
I provide a link to learn more about conditional tags.
Here is what WordPress has to say about it.
Conditional tags can be used in your temple of files to alter the display of content depending on the
conditions that the current page matches.
They tell WordPress what code to display under specific conditions.
Conditional tags usually work with p p if else conditional statements.
The Code begins by checking to see if a statement is true or false.
If the statement is found to be true the first set of code is executed.
If it's false the first set of code is skipped and the second set of code after the else is executed
and set.
You can read up on this page to learn about the many conditional tags there are.
But for now the ones we're using will suffice.
Throughout this course we'll be using conditional tags to help us change the final result.
All right now that we know that this is indeed the home page we can begin displaying the breaking news
widget.
I'm also going to check if the WPP get most popular function exists
we can now call a function called WPP get most popular this function has a one parameter and that is
an array of settings we can set back on the admin side.
You'll find that the plug in WordPress popular post gives plenty of examples on how to use these settings.
There are only three that I want to use and those can be found at the very bottom.
These last three keys determine how the posts are output it.
The first key we should set is the WPP start.
This will be the H2 CML.
That will be output and at the very beginning we have the static version of widget here.
I'm going to copy everything from the beginning all the way up to the opening tag with the class of
slider dash wrap.
I'm going to paste this in as the value the next key I want to set is the WPP end.
This should have all the closing tags.
The only thing we have left are these three links.
We only need one.
So I'm just going to cut one and get rid of the rest.
The last key to set is the post H GMO.
This Key's value will be the H GM l we just cut.
Previously
now we have to replace the static parts of this H2 UML into something like the function we'll be able
to read and replace.
If you look at the documentation you'll find that the developer provide you with what values can be
inserted and replaced the only ones we're concerned with are the your bell and text underscore title
content tags.
We just replace the static content with these content tags.
Make sure to surround them with one pair of curly brackets so that the plugin will be able to replace
the
let's refresh the page and you'll see the three posts we previously viewed being displayed as popular
posts.
The last thing we need to do is to make an optional to display this widget or not inside the miscellaneous
customized her.
I'm going to create two new settings.
The first setting is called J.
You show header popular post widget which will have a default value a false.
I don't want this widget to be turned on by default.
The second setting will be j you popular post widget title which will have a default title of breaking
news.
The next step is to create a controller.
I'm going to assign these two controllers to the AM I A C section the first controller will be a checkbox
with an I.D. of J.
You show header popular posts widget input
the second controller will just be a text input field with an I.D. of J You popular post widget title
input
there's nothing new here.
After creating these two settings and its controllers it's time to update the theme to reflect those
changes back inside the conditional statement.
I'm going to add one more check.
This will be checking if the theme mod J you show header popular post widget is turned on
the last thing I'm going to do is change the breaking news static text into its theme mod J You popular
post widget title
save your changes and let's check out the customize.
The checkbox should be unchecked and so therefore the popular post widget should not be showing.
Try turning it on and then change the text to popular posts after confirming if everything worked on
the preview then save your changes and double check on the front it.
That's it for now.
You'll notice that I spent an awful lot of time talking about other plugins and how to integrate them.
I'm going to show you something in the resources section I provide a link to the theme for a site under
WordPress popular themes.
You'll notice a lot of themes are killing it and making massive amounts of sales.
I'm going to click on a Veda and you'll notice that this item highlights it's compatible with various
plugins and even comes bundled with some.
It's extremely common to bundle your themes with plugins that help it with certain tasks and functions.
Of course you'll be put in a situation where you'll have to make your own custom solution and we'll
definitely learn how to make plug ins soon.
For now don't worry bundling plug ins doesn't make you a bad developer just a more efficient one.