I want to improve the way the users are displayed and the information presented on the posts in this
lecture will explore how to create custom author fields and avatars.
Let's start with the custom fields first.
I'm going to edit my admin profile to include a biography.
I'll keep it simple and short.
Let's go to the front end now and view a single post.
If we take a look at the author box you'll notice that it displays the author bio.
Wouldn't it be nice if it could also include social media information like Twitter or Facebook.
That's totally possible and easy to do with Wordpress.
The first step is to add the fields on the admin side inside the function's file.
Add the action hook.
Show user profile the function I want to call is j u custom user profile fields
this hope will only run if a user is viewing their own profile in the admin dashboard.
However I want admins to be able to view these fields as well.
So we have to copy this line and change the action hook name to edit user profile which will run if
another user is viewing these fields.
We'll be calling the same function.
WordPress will be able to determine which one to run.
Depending on who is viewing the profile inside the includes folder create a folder named admin and create
a file named author dash fields dot P. HP to find the function inside this file and make sure to include
it from the function's file
this function will receive a user object that will have information about the current additive user
inside this function.
I'm going to paste in some H2 UML code.
This is just some email code to format the input field to match the other fields.
I use the HP email from the page and modified it to suit our needs.
It's nothing complex.
There are two things that need to be highlighted.
The name attribute should be unique so that we can use it to save the data later.
The other thing is the value.
All I'm doing is grabbing a user medically called J U Twitter which will save later.
This function is new to us but it's a function that uses the metadata API posts aren't the only things
that can have metadata attached to them.
Users can also have metadata the user meta functions work the same as the post meta functions.
Now that we are displaying our field it's time to save it inside the functions file.
I'm going to add a new action hook called personal options update the function I want to call it will
be named J.
You save extra profile fields just like last time.
This hook will only run for the user's own profile for other users such as admins in order for them
to modify this value properly.
We have to use a different hook the other hook is called edit user profile update.
I'm just going to copy the hook above and rename it back inside the author dash Fields file.
I'm going to define the function here as well to keep things simple.
This function will be passed in the user I.D. which we'll use later.
I'm going to check the current user capability and see if they have the capability and it user if this
returns false.
I'm going to return the function.
We only want users who have this capability to be able to edit profiles if they pass this check.
I'm going to call the function Update user meta and update the information properly passing the user
I.D. set the key to J You Twitter and pass in the post variable
now that the user meter is being updated properly.
We can begin to display it in the author box open the single template for the theme right at the section
where we grab the author I.D. I'm going to create a new variable named Twitter.
This variables value will be assigned to the value returned by the get the author Meadow function will
pass in the name of key which is J You Twitter and the author right.
Next let's move on to the author box which is placed under the post and check to see if the variable
isn't empty if it isn't empty.
We'll echo it out with this HCM El
positive video if you need to.
All right now that we have that all set up let's test the form refresh the page you should now see the
field inputs appear and your Twitter handle and then update the user
next go to a single post that this user has created.
You should now see the Twitter handle appear right inside the author box like I'm seeing.
That's how you would go about adding and saving fields.
All right.
The next thing I want to do is add in a custom avatar for default users by default.
We're using the mystery man avatar.
Go to the admin dashboard and navigate to settings discussion at the very bottom you can assign a different
avatar for new users.
However you don't have the ability to add in your own custom ones just like everything else you can
add custom avatars with hooks inside the function's file.
Add the filter hook called Avatar defaults and the function to call will be named J.
You new avatar
inside the includes folder create a file called Avatar dot p p and defined the function inside here.
Make sure to include it as well.
This function will be passed in an array of default avatars.
You can add in your own avatar to this array or remove already set ones.
I'm going to create a new variable named Avatar you URL which will be a you are well to an image.
I've uploaded online
this is an avatar of wacko.
I'll provide a link to this in the resource section of this lecture.
Next I'm going to add this to the array by setting the key to the URL and the value to a human readable
name.
I'm going to set this to default Udemy avatar.
Lastly I'm going to return the avatar array
just like that.
We have our very own custom avatar added to the list.
Refresh the page and you should see the avatar being loaded.
The admin can now set this avatar as the default avatar for new users.
I'm going to select this avatar and save my changes
if I go back to the single post.
You'll find the avatar being displayed.
That wraps it up for this lecture before I end it.
I want to talk about the HDMI markup we use for the forms rather than using our own markup.
We used WordPress markup however WordPress doesn't provide much documentation for it.
We're left to study the current markup and learn it through trial and error in the resource section
of this lecture.
I provide a link to a plugin called WordPress admin style.
This is a plug them that will show you the markup WordPress uses for reference.
I want you to install and activate this plugin
you'll find a menu item called admin style.
If you click on it you'll find this long page of the various WordPress stylings you can use.
This is a great plugin to have in hand when you're developing plugins or themes.