Comments deserve a lecture of their own.
We'll be taking a look at how to make a template for comments and how to submit a comment.
I'm still working inside the single template file.
Scroll down into you find a section called comments right before this.
We're going to call the function comments template
this function will look for a template file called Common Stock P HP and load it let's create that file
now.
I'm going to move the comments from the single template into the comments template
back inside the single template.
I'm going to wrap the comments template function with a conditional statement I want to check for two
things.
The first thing I want to check is to see if the comments are open using the comments open function.
The second thing I want to check is if there are already comments for this post using the get comments.
No function if there are already comments then will want to display those.
Even if the comments section is close let's go back to the comments template.
I'm going to set up a conditional statement and call the function post password required
this function will check to see if this post requires a password value before viewing it and if the
current visitor has not input it that password if this returns true then we shouldn't display anything
to the user.
In this case I'll just add a return statement like so you may be wondering will this really stop the
rest of the file from returning.
Wouldn't using the exit or die function be better.
Well keep in mind that we're calling this temple of file using the comments template function.
This function includes this file and so we can use the return statement to end this function early.
You'll also notice that I'm not even using the post password required function inside the single template.
In a way it would make sense to block the rest of the post from displaying but we don't have to do that
because WordPress already does that for us.
The only reason I'm using this function inside the comments template is because the comments template
can be used anywhere in our theme.
Comments are used everywhere in wordpress so we want to take into account of those situations as well.
Assuming everything is good so far we can begin displaying the comments and form.
I'm going to start with the form.
Scroll down to the section that says comment form.
I'm going to place this code directly inside the div tag with the I.D. of response.
There is a function variable that will help with generating the form which is the comment form function
this function has two parameters which are both completely optional in the resource section of this
lecture I provide a link to this function.
Let's look at the developer page for a second.
As you can see like most WordPress functions this function is heavily documented.
This function will generate a form where a user can submit a comment for a post.
You are allowed to create your own form but this function is plug all.
This is a new phrase we're learning here.
Anything in WordPress that it's plausible simply means that plugins are allowed to extend the functionality
of that bit of code.
Developers are allowed to add in their own fields or change the way it looks with plugins so it's always
best to use this function rather than creating a form manually.
There are a lot of options we can set here.
We won't be defining all parameters if we were to leave this function as is and do the page then you'll
notice that the form doesn't match the one in our template.
This can be fixed easily.
Inside the comment form function I want you to input and array this array can have a multitude of values
and keys but will only be setting a few which are mostly aesthetics.
The first key is the comment field.
Keep this.
Value will be the actual input field for the comment body from the template.
I'm going to cut and paste the HP AML for the comment body into this Key's value like so.
Next up is the rest of the fields.
The other fields are defined using the fields key this keys value will be an array of all the fields
available in the comments form.
There are three which are the author email and you are about all you really need to do is set each of
these keys values to the corresponding H UML in the static template.
I'm going to post this video and do this really quick.
All right.
I'm back.
And as you can see I cut and pasted the HDL into each corresponding key.
There are two things I want you to notice.
The first is that for each label I actually made the text translatable which is completely optional
but always good practice.
The second is that you should take careful notice of the name of each field.
It's important that you assign each of these fields these specific names.
This is because we won't be processing the comments WordPress already takes care of processing and saving
comments.
WordPress expects these names for each field.
We're almost done.
There are three more keys to set which are the class submit label submit and title will apply keys
the class submit keys value should be the C assessed classes the submit button uses in the HDMI document.
I'm going to simply cut and paste like so the labels submit will be a translatable string but says submit
comment
the title reply Key's value will be leave a span comment span but is also translatable.
That should do it.
If you haven't already delete the static comment form then refresh the page and you should see something
similar to what I see.
This may seem like a lot of work but WordPress handles a lot for us behind the scenes.
This function does a lot more than output a form.
Let me go over what goes on first WordPress checks to see if the user is logged in and can submit comments.
It will also check if comments are open for submission.
It will also take care of submitting the correct post information.
This comment belongs to try submitting a common if you like something I should also note is that the
form may be different if you are not logged in.
I want you to log out of WordPress and check before
as you can see WordPress displays these extra fields for logged out users.
I'm going to log back in and then go back to the comments
if you wanted to.
You could have just written this logic yourself but that's over complicating things.
Using this function is much more simpler cleaner and efficient.
If you wish to customize this form further then I highly recommend you read up on the documentation
to do so.
Now it's time to display the comments scroll all the way up to the comments list section inside the
ordered list tag.
I want you to delete all of the comments except one we will be using the single comment as a reference
then set up a for each loop.
WordPress puts all the post comments in a handy little variable called comments.
We're going to look through each element in this array and refer to it as comment.
You don't have to worry about tying us all together as WordPress does it for you.
It will automatically create the comments variable for you.
I'm going to cut and paste that single comment into this loop like so
just like the loop before all we have to do is simply replace the static content with template tags.
The first template tag for comments is the get Avatar function inside the div tag with the class comment
dash.
Author replace the image tag and echo out the get avatar.
Function this function in general gets the avatar of a user.
Usually we can leave this function like so however we're using it inside a loop that's inside of a loop.
This makes things confusing for this function.
So we have to pass in the comments object itself
WordPress we'll be able to scan this object for the ideas of the user to get the correct avatar.
The second parameter would be the size for this template the size 60 is perfect.
The third parameter is the default image you are out.
If the user doesn't have one I'm going to pass in an empty string.
This will tell WordPress to handle the default image you are out.
I'm also going to pass in an empty string for the fourth parameter the value for this must be the text
to display inside the old attribute.
I don't want to display anything in the alter text so I'll leave this empty.
The fifth parameter is an array of additional settings.
I'm going to pass that in and set the class keep the value of this should be.
The class is inside the image tag below
scrolling down.
You'll find a div tag with the class comment author.
I'm going to replace the static author's name with the function comment.
Author unlike the previous function comments specific functions will only grab its values from the current
comment in the loop.
This function will output the name of the author of this comment.
The next one is the comments date function which returns a formatted date when the comment was made.
Lastly we use the function comments text to return the text made by the user.
Nothing much too and honestly if we refresh the page then you'll see the comment we made previously
appear.
The very last thing we need to do is add comments patch nation.
You simply call the comments Padgett nation function right after the loop
this next step is completely optional.
I don't want to display this part of the template unless there are comments I'm going to wrap this bit
of code inside a conditional statement.
I'm going to use the have comments function to check to see if there are any comments.
I'm also going to display the number of comments inside this H 3 tag using the comments.
No function.
Make sure you remove the comments text as well.
That's it for the comments template.
You may be wondering but what about spam protection actually spam protection is something we can leave
to plugin developers.
There are dozens of plugins available to block spam and so we won't bother adding a built in system
ourselves.
It would be a bit overkill.
All comments are processed through a particular file.
If we look at the wordpress installation you'll see the WP dash comments dash post dot P HP file inside
the root directory.
This file will process all comments posted to it.
Feel free to check it out.
That's it for now.
In the next few lectures we'll finish up the single template.