The next step is to register and in cue the assets.
This will most likely be the last time you write code for a while.
Unlike the other WordPress API is Gutenberg is mostly written in Javascript custom blocks are also written
in Javascript.
There are some exceptions but we'll get to those later registering and queuing the files are still a
p p process.
Just like anything else we'll be using hooks inside the main plugin file create an action hook called
in queue block Ed assets
the name of the function will be are in queue block Ed assets this function doesn't exist so we'll need
to create that next create a file inside the blocks directory called and cued up HP.
Once again any files related to the Gutenberg editor will be placed here after creating the file defined
the function and include it from the main plugin file
the hook that we're using is specifically for the Gutenberg Ed the Q block Ed assets hook is triggered
when the Gutenberg it's initialized for any post type on the admin end.
This is perfect as this will make sure only files meant for the editor will be loaded inside the function
called the WP register a script function and set the name to our blocks bundle.
The second parameter will be the you are out will use the plugins you are El function for this.
The path should be slash blocks slash dist slash bundle dot J.S..
Keep in mind that we're loading the bundle file and not the files inside the after rectory.
The bundle file will contain the finished result of everything.
Next up is an array of dependencies.
Before we load this script we're going to need a few things.
The special thing about the Gutenberg editor is that it's modular the Gutenberg editor is split up into
various modules that are bundled together to make it function correctly.
We need to make sure that certain modules are loaded first before our scripts so that it can function
correctly.
The scripts we're about to require are all registered by WordPress.
The first one is WP dash ie 18 in this script will provide us functions that we can use to translate
our script.
Next is the WP dash element script.
This will provide us with the function for converting our J.S. X code into JavaScript functions in the
previous section.
We would use react but WordPress takes the time to wrap some of reacts functions.
I'll discuss this more in depth later.
For now just include it afterwards we'll need the WP dash blocks.
Script this script will allow us to register our block and interact with Gutenberg then we'll need the
WP dash component scripts Gutenberg comes with some components that we can reuse in our own script.
This script will allow us to access these features.
It's great because then we won't have to reinvent the wheel.
Up next is the WP dash Ed script.
This script comes with tools and functions related specifically for the editor.
These will help us create a more consistent user experience when building our blocks.
Lastly we'll need the WP dash API scripts.
This will allow us to interact with the WordPress rest api.
We haven't discussed the rest api in depth but we will soon.
Something I want to note is that you won't be using all of these scripts right from the start.
We'll gradually introduce each one as the course progresses.
I'm just including them now so that we can focus more on the javascript code and not have to switch
back and forth between files.
The last parameter I want to set is the version as you may know some browsers will cache our files.
We don't want this.
We always want the latest version.
I've already shown you how to do this in a previous lecture but I want to show an alternative solution.
I'm going to call the file M time function.
This function requires the path to the file.
I'll pass that in as well
the function I'm introducing here will get a files last modification time.
This function requires the full system path.
I'm using the plug in dirt path function which will return the full system path to a plug and file.
Then I'm spending the rest of the path to the file.
This is a really quick and easy way to get the latest version of a file.
All right let's in queue the file now right below this call the WP NQ script function and pass in the
name.
That should do it before we confirm everything works.
Open the index dot J S file inside the after rectory.
It should be empty.
I'm going to console Doc log a simple message then will need to compile this file inside the command
line.
You may have to see deep into the blocks directory.
Once you're there run the commands NPM run Dev.
You should receive a success message and web patch should now be watching the files for any changes.
Then go to the admin dashboard and try viewing the Gutenberg Ed.
This can be for any post type for the rest of the section.
I'll be focusing on the recipe post type.
The code should work for any post type though open the developer tools and view the console.
You should see the message appearing in the log.
That should confirm everything works
we've taken care of the first two steps which was prepare the environment and in cue the files.
The next step is to register our block.
We'll take a look at how to do that in the next lecture.
I'll see you there.