It's time to create a page for editing the plug options to perform this task.
We need to use a function called Ad menu page and the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to learn more about this function.
We have quite a few options for this function.
Scroll down to the user contributors section you'll see the user contributor note suggests that we should
use a hook called admin menu and then use this function from within that hook.
So let's do that inside the main plugin file.
Add this action and the function we want to call is our admin menus.
I want you to take note that we're not running this hook inside the admin and IT function in the resource
section of this lecture I provide a link to this hook.
If you read the notes WordPress will state the following.
This action mustn't be placed in an admin in an action function because the admin in an action is called
after admin menu.
It's always good practice to read the notes for any hook or function before using it for clarification
on usage.
Moving on inside the include slash admin folder.
Let's create a file called menus dot P. HP.
Lastly include this file
inside this file create the R admin menus function.
Now we can call the ad menu page function.
This function has quite a few parameters.
The first parameter is the title of this page.
This will appear on the top of the browser in tabs.
I'm going to pass in the text recipe options.
The second parameter is the name that will appear in the sidebar.
I'm going to keep this simple and pass in recipe options.
The third parameter is the capability.
We haven't talked about capabilities yet in the resource section.
I provided a link to the capabilities Codex page.
A capability is basically what a user can or cannot do by default.
WordPress provides 60 fault rolls which are super admin administrator editor author contributor and
subscriber.
Each of these roles have certain capabilities.
Let's scroll down to the capability versus roll tables section of this page.
As you can see a super ad man can do everything whereas a subscriber can only read posts and pages you
can think of roles as a way to group capabilities when you are checking if a user can perform a certain
action.
Then you'll want to check their capability.
It's important that you check their capabilities rather than checking their role.
There are plugins out there that allow you to create new roles and assign custom capabilities.
Those same plugins can also modify existing capabilities for roles so it's always important to check
a capability rather than a role.
This function would like to know who can view this page by passing into a capability.
Currently I only want super admin and administrators to view this page.
If we look at the table we can use any of these capabilities that only a super admin or administrator
can do.
I'm going to use the capability.
Edit dim options you don't have to use this specific capability you can use any of the other ones just
as long as they apply to both super admins and administrators.
The fourth parameter is the menu slug.
This is basically the U.R.L..
I'll show you what this looks like in just a moment.
This should be a unique you are out.
Do you know what we do when you want something to be unique in WordPress.
We prefix it with our underscore.
I'm going to pass an R plugin arts the 5th parameter is the name of the function that will be calls.
We're going to call this function r plug in on this page this function doesn't exist so let's create
that now inside the admin folder create a file called Options dash page dot P HP
next.
Include this file from the main plugin file
Lastly let's define the function
whatever you output from this function will be output it onto the page.
We can if we want to use WordPress as stylings and classes style this page.
However we won't.
Instead we'll be using Bootstrap.
First things first let's try outputting something onto our page.
There is one special class that we will use and that's called the wrap class
this class is created by WordPress.
This is just one of the very few classes that WordPress provides that we can use.
This class will take care of placing our page to the right of the menu and make it responsive.
Let's output a simple message
now go to your WordPress admin dashboard and you'll notice our menu pop up.
Click on it you'll see the message output it and position correctly.
One less thing earlier I told you about the slug inside the URL bar.
You'll see the slug we passed in in order to access this page.
All we have to do is use the page query and use the value R plugin ops that should bring us to this
page.
That's how our slug works now that the page is being displayed let's start creating the forms and adding
some styles we'll be using Bootstrap styling for this.
It's not required but I prefer it to begin.
We'll need to load the bootstrap CSX.
WordPress has a specific hook for loading styles and scripts on the ataman side inside the ad men in
it.
Function add the action hook called admin and queue scripts
the function will want to call is r admin and queue WordPress has quite a few hooks for in queuing files
in different locations.
We have one for the front end one for the admin and N2 for Gutenberg.
Anyway let's create a file inside the admin folder called and queued up HP and define the function there.
Before we in queue any files I want to make sure we only load bootstrap in our custom page.
It's irresponsible to load bootstrap for every admin page will want to make sure the files only get
loaded for the admin options page we created.
Luckily that's easy to do.
Using the page query we saw earlier inside a conditional statement.
I'm going to check if that query argument is not set and its value is not our plugin ops.
If either of these conditions return true then we'll want to return nothing.
This will mean that the page the user is currently on is not our plugins page and so we shouldn't do
anything else.
If the user makes it this far then we'll in queue the bootstrap style sheet.
We don't need the j as the CSO style is inside the assets slash C Ss slash bootstrap dot CSX that is
relative.
The recipe plugin file
let's refresh the admin page if we get no errors in our console related to the files we queued.
Then we're good to go.
It's time to create a form inside the options page.
I'm going to paste in some markup this form has nothing unique to WordPress.
This is all bootstrap markup to make it look pretty.
You can find this markup inside these slash assets slash extras slash options dash page dot t t file
let's go over what's going on.
As you can see I have created a form input for the two options we created earlier in the activation
function.
I've also made all text translatable using the underscore e function.
One important thing I want you to know is the name attribute for each input as you can see.
I prefix everything with our underscore this is to prevent any collisions with any other data WordPress
sends out when we submit this form.
So how do we get the form to submit correctly.
Well it's pretty simple in the form tag.
I'm going to set the method to post the action will be sent to add Min dash post stop BHP.
This is very important.
Whenever you create forms this is the you are well you should submit your info to to be more specific
forms on the admin side of WordPress.
Actually you can find this file inside the WP dash admin folder open this file if you take a look at
this comment you'll notice it says intended for form submission handling themes and plugins it's safe
to assume that we can send our data to this file.
There are a couple of things we need to do before this form is fully functional.
We face two problems.
We're not the only ones who will be posting data to the ad men dash post dot PHC file.
We need to make WordPress aware that we're the ones submitting the form and execute the appropriate
functions.
The second problem is X SS injections.
This form can be easily recreated and submitted without our permission.
The answer to both these problems are simple and taken care of by WordPress.
First create an input field that should be hidden.
Its name should be action
WordPress.
We'll search for this field and check its value.
The value of this field will determine what function will be used to save this data.
I'm going to set the value attribute to our save options you'll see what this does in a moment.
Next we need to make our form secure from X SS attacks.
WordPress recommends we create a field with a unique key that is generated when we visit this page.
We can then validate this key during submission.
We already know how to handle something like this.
We can use the WP nonce field function like before.
Call this function and pass in our options verify.
I'm not going to deal with the other parameters because we're out putting this all to the screen rather
than returning it.
So I'm not so concerned with the other values.
Let's refresh the admin page.
You should see this field being generated by WordPress after confirming this.
We can now submit and update our settings.