In some situations you may want to add in your own custom buttons to the toolbar.
That's completely possible.
WordPress even provides some components for making that process easier to get started.
Download the zip file in the resource section of this lecture.
Unzip the contents inside the app directory.
You should be provided with a folder called Night mode block.
We're going to be building a block where a user can enable night mode night mode is a term used to describe
UI that switches the contrast from light to dark.
This reduces eye strain.
Will make a button that will allow the user to toggle this feature.
There are several files here but it's nothing you haven't seen before.
Let's start with the index file.
I'm importing the icon for the block and an icon for the button.
Let's check that out for a minute.
I'm viewing the icon in Illustrator.
If you don't have illustrator that's perfectly fine.
I've already taken the time to export it as an SPG file and export it.
You can find the icon inside the icon dot J.S. file.
All I'm doing here is exporting the SPG code as the default value switching back to the index file.
I'm importing a SAS file if you look inside the SAS file you'll find that I'm just applying a dark background
colour and a light font color.
Take note that this will only apply if the class night mode is applied to the element.
All right let's go back to the index file.
Everything else is the same.
We're grabbing some components and registering the block.
I'm leaving out the keywords property again to save room.
Feel free to add it in if you like the edit function will display some basic content.
We're not going to bother adding input fields or changeable content everything will be static besides
the toolbar right above the content.
I'm loading the block controls component it's currently empty but we'll be adding our custom toolbar
soon enough.
The same function contains the same HDMI all as above that should be it.
Now that we have an overview of things let's get started to create a custom toolbar.
We're going to need a couple of components.
These components are optional but they handle a lot for us such as formatting positioning and design.
All of these components will come from the WP components object so d structure that will need the toolbar
button and tooltip components.
All talk about what these components do in just a moment.
Next we're going to set up some attributes we only need one which will determine if the content should
have night mode enabled create an attribute called Night mode the type will be boolean and the default
will be false.
We're not setting a source or selectors instance will be a simple value that makes it perfect for storing
it inside the comments with the attributes set let's begin creating the toolbar inside the block controls
component.
I'm going to load in the toolbar component the toolbar component will take care of adding a separator
between the other toolbars that might be loaded in it will properly position your button within the
block controls component.
Next we're going to load in the tooltip component this component will display a tooltip if the user
hovers over the content placed inside of it.
We don't have to worry about the events or positioning as that's handled for us.
The only attribute we need to set is the text attribute.
Set this to night mode and make it translatable inside of the tooltip component.
Add the button component.
The order does matter here.
If the button component is placed inside the toolbar component then the stylings for the button component
will be adjusted.
The adjustment will make things look consistent with the other buttons on the toolbar.
All right we're going to apply a few things to this button.
First we have to apply a couple of classes.
However we run into one problem we act currently doesn't support multiple classes for a component.
If you scroll up you'll see I'm loading a module called class names.
This is a third party module that we installed.
Long ago I promised a very long time ago to explain what this is for and now I finally can.
This module will take care of allowing multiple classes for a component.
It's very easy to use on the button.
I'm going to apply the class name attribute the value for this will be class names function.
This will accept in the list of class names you'd like to apply.
I'm going to add classes which are components dash icon dash button and components dash toolbar underscore
underscore control.
We're going to apply one more class which is is Dash active.
However this will be inside an object if we want to have dynamic classes then we have to format it like
this.
The name will be the class to add and the value can either be true or false.
If it's true then the class will be added.
If false it won't be added.
Set this to prompts Don.
Attributes Dot.
Knight mode by default Knight mode will be false.
So this class shouldn't be applying the is active class will let the user visually know the button is
enabled.
I was able to find these classes by looking at the other components and toolbars.
WordPress creates it's not documented so it's always good practice to dive into the code itself to better
understand how things work.
Next we want to change that night mode attribute.
If this button is clicked we basically want to flip the current value the button component has an event
called on click this will be set to an arrow function just like before.
We'll call the set attributes function and set that night mode attribute to its opposite value like
so.
Next we'll end the button icon variable as the content inside
the width and height should be 20 pixels.
I've already applied that to the SPG icon itself.
Now that the button is functioning we just have to apply this to the content itself below.
I'm going to call the class names function instead of setting the class statically all at the content
Dash.
Example class and make the night class dynamic.
The night class will take care of adding the dark background and white text.
This is what we named it in our SAS files.
This will be set to prompt.
Don attributes dot Knight mode.
I'm going to copy this code and pasted over to the save function since it's the exact same thing the
block is now finished.
The last step is to import it inside the app dot index dot J.S. file import the night mode block module
C.D. into the blocks directory and run the NPM run Dev command.
You shouldn't receive any error so far.
Go ahead and create a recipe post.
If you were to search for the night mode block then you shouldn't be able to find it with the warp who
icon and the block to the editor.
All you should see is a simple message.
If you were to select it then you should see the toolbar appear with our custom button an icon you can
click it and it should toggle night mode.
If you hover your mouse over the button then you should see the tooltip as well.
This is great.
We now have our own custom toolbar.
Turn on night mode and then save the post try viewing it on the front end.
The block should have the stylings applied to it.
If you did everything right.
There's not much to this honestly you're just loading in a few components and using them to help build
your Custom Toolbar before I end this lecture.
I do want to note one thing.
Tool tips are optional.
If you wanted to you could remove this like so this is perfectly fine.
However I prefer to add it because it can provide more context to the user.
Just in case they don't understand what your buttons do.
I'll add it back in that does it for now.
We'll continue exploring more components in the next lecture.