In this lecture we'll be exploring what modules are and how to use them.
Right now I'm on the J query Web site.
You know what J query is.
You've used it before and it's fairly easy to use in order to use J.
Query on your site you have to create some script tags and pass in the path to the J query file.
The browser will automatically load this file for you and then you can use J query anywhere on your
site.
The process is pretty straightforward.
Unfortunately this process only applies to the browser for node.
You can't use script tags to include external javascript code.
The process is slightly different and requires a little bit of work in the resource section of this
lecture.
I provide a link to the common J.S. site common J.
Yes it's a javascript module loader as it states here.
In other words it's a way for you to load javascript code from external files.
You'll hear the word modules a lot throughout this course.
A module is just a fancy word for a javascript file that you include into your code.
I'm oversimplifying it but that's basically what it is.
Common J yes is a library that allows you to load javascript code with more javascript code you can
think of it like loading a page you file with the include or require functions.
This means you don't have to use H2 UML to load your files.
You can download this library and then load it in your browser to get started.
We won't be doing this.
This is because node already uses the common J.S. format already.
Let's take a deeper look on the sidebar you'll find the link used with note here.
You'll find information on how to use common.
Yes with node on this page.
The developer tells you that node isn't using the common G S loader specifically instead node is using
its own implementation of Common J.S. with the same format and consent.
The node module loader is very similar to the common J.S. module loader but you need to understand that
they aren't 100 percent the same.
With that being said let's take a look at how to use the module loader.
Open the index dot J.S. file we created earlier.
I'm going to Coleman out the code we had previously.
As I stated earlier node already prepares the module loader library for you so you don't have to do
anything to set it up.
You can get started with using modules right away.
There are usually three kinds of modules you'll be dealing with.
There are modules you create modules that node creates and modules that other users create.
Let's get started with creating our own modules.
I'm going to create a file named functions dot J S inside this file.
I'm going to create a symbol function named my func and all it will do is output a helo world message.
All right.
Now I have two files which aren't connected to node.
Both of these files are considered modules.
You heard that correctly all JavaScript files are considered modules.
As far as note is concerned the main module is what's called the entry point the entry point file is
the very first file that should be executed by node the index file will be the entry file so we'll have
to load the functions module into this file to do that.
We have to first create a variable.
I'm going to name my variable f u n c we will set this value to the value returned by the function required
this function has one parameter which is the name of the module you'd like to load.
I'm going to pass in the name of the file which is functions you do not need to append the DOT JSA extension
as node will always assume you want to load a javascript file.
However we do have to prepare as a dot forward slash.
This will tell no J.S. that the module is located in the same directory as the file.
Keep in mind that the variable name can be named anything you want.
In most examples and tutorials most developers tend to name their variables after the name of the module
in lowercase letters.
This single line of code will load a module and we can reference the module using this variable.
The question is what exactly gets loaded and how is it loaded.
This line of code won't technically work yet.
We have to now export our module before we can use it.
Exporting a module simply means that you're telling node what parts of your code can be used outside
of the file.
Let's explore how that works inside the functions file.
I'm going to use an object called module this object is defined for you by node.
This object contains properties related to the current module.
It's being used in in our case.
This would be the functions file every single file is provided a module object with properties specific
to that file.
As I stated earlier every single file is considered a module.
As far as node is concerned this module object has a property called exports which you can assign any
value you want the value of this property determines what values other models can access from this module.
I'm going to set this to my func which is the function above now I can use the function inside the index
file.
I'm going to call it.
I'll go over what's going on in just a moment but first let's check if this works.
I'm going to run the node index command again as you can see the message was output it without any error.
Let me recap what's going on here.
The very first thing we do is create a variable named f u n c creating a variable is required if you
want to use a module as this variable will act as a way to reference the code inside the module to load
a module.
You have to use the function required.
This function will load the module you pass in.
In our case this would be the functions file inside the functions file.
We have a variable named my func that is assigned to a function.
This function will output a message onto the console node will load this module into the index file.
However it will not load the variables functions or objects from this file.
Instead it'll look inside the module with DOT exports property and just return the data inside that
property.
So in order to pass in our data we have to assign our data to this property.
Once the module is loaded we can then just use the data from the module dot exports property freely
in our case.
This would be the function that outputs a message.
Lastly we just call the function and the message will be output it onto the console.
Let me prove this further.
I'm going to define a variable named foo inside the functions file and assign its value to five then
I'm going to go back to my index file and try to log this variable
if I were to run my command again.
I'll get this error stating that the variable foo is undefined even though this variable is defined
inside the function's file and I'm loading the module this variable is not made available globally to
every file that uses it in order to use this variable.
We have to assign the module dot exports property to this variable.
Let's say I wanted to pass in multiple values to do this.
We can simply create an object and then assign the data like so
since we're returning an object we have to update the index file to access those properties change func
to func dot my func and to access the foo property we have to call it as func doubtful let's run the
command one more time and we should see the message being output it along with the value of food.
All right.
So that's how you load code from one file into another.
I want to dig deeper though.
Here's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to comin up the food variable from being logged inside the index file then I'm going to clear
up my console.
I'm going to console to log the module object in both files
then I'm going to update my function to output a long list of equal signs so we can see the difference
between these two outputs after doing this.
I want you to run the command node index and the output you'll see two objects being output it as you
can see node takes care of setting the values for both these modules each object will have a property
named file name which will let you know which module object belongs to which file both modules have
an exports property.
If you take a look at the functions module then you'll notice the export property is filled with both
the function and the Foo variable.
These are the values that the index dot J.S. file will get when loading this module the index module
has no exports so the exports for that file will be an empty object.
Another thing I want you to notice is the parents property the parents property will tell you if the
module is being loaded from another module as you can see the functions module has the index module
as its parent the index module has no parents because it is the entry point file.
However the index module will have the children property which will tell you what modules this module
is loading something you should keep in mind is that children modules can and are allowed to load more
modules.
This creates a module tree structure for the most part you never have to worry about these properties
as node takes care of filling them out for you.
It's uncommon and not recommended that you modify any of these properties except for the exports property.
All right.
Now that we understand the basics of modules let's explore some modules that node provides.
And third party modules in the next lecture.