The home page features a list of posts submitted.
However I want to expand on this.
I also want to display recipe posts as well.
There are two solutions to accomplish this.
The first solution would be to create our own query ignoring the main query.
However that's a lot of work to do and we don't want to completely ignore the main query as other plugins
may want to modify how it works.
Luckily we can modify the main query to suit our needs.
This is the best solution and it's easy inside the function's file at an action hook called pre get
posts.
The function I want to call will be named J You modify a home page.
Query inside the includes folder create a file named home dash query dot P HP and define the function
inside this file.
Lastly include this file
this hook will be called when the main query is created but it will not be executed at this point since
it's not being executed.
We have the opportunity to modify it as we please.
This function will be passed in an object called query.
Whenever we work with the WP query class we always created a new instance.
However at this point we already have an instance to modify a query after it's created.
We have to use a method called set but we'll get to that in just a moment.
Something that you need to keep in mind is that this hook will always give you the main query for every
page not just the home page.
Since this is the case we have to use a conditional statement to check for two things.
We have to check if this query is for the home page using the is home method
then we need to use the is main query method to check if this is the main query if both return true.
Then we'll modify query.
I'm now going to call the set method and set the post type parameter to an array that contains the name
of the post types.
I'd like to retrieve I want to get the post and recipe post types
in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to the WP query classic and you'll find more information about these methods and properties
that I'm using.
All right now that we've modified the main query let's check out the home page.
If you refresh the page you should have both recipes and posts appearing.
That's all there is to it.
Before I am this lecture I want to talk about a function called query posts which you can find in the
resource section of this lecture.
There is a function that you can use to modify the main query but I highly recommend you don't use it
if you take a look.
You'll find this note from WordPress that says.
Note This function will completely override the main query and isn't intended for use by plugins or
themes.
It's overly simplistic approach to modifying the main query can be problematic and should be avoided
wherever possible.
In most cases there are better more performance options for modifying the main query such as via the
pre get posts action within WP query.
This must not be used within the WordPress loop.
Try your best not to use this function.
There are a lot of things and plugins out there that use this but it's just bad practice to do so.