Let's start working on submitting the recipe.
Let's give the recipe form an idea of recipe dash form above this form.
Let's add a status div with the idea of recipe dash status
we'll use this div to display a message to the user whether or not the recipe was submitted successfully
open the main dot J S file.
This is the same file that should contain the ratings submission.
Let's listen for the form submission using the on method.
We'll be given an event object.
We're going to call the prevent default method so that the form isn't submitted.
We want to use ajax force admitting the form we're going to hide the form during submission.
This will make sure the user doesn't submit the form twice.
Next we're going to select the Stannis div and add some AGM l add a simple weighting message.
I'm going to wrap this around some bootstrap markup to make it look good.
Just like last time.
Create an object that will contain the form values to grab the values you simply select the input fields
by their ideas and use the Val method to get the value.
For the action we'll set this to our submit user recipe.
Grabbing the content from the editor is pretty simple when we included the editor WordPress.
Also loaded the tiny MCP object we can grab the content by using this object and grabbing the current
active editor and call the get content method which will return on sanitize each GM El.
Lastly we submit this data using J queries post method.
Remember that the recipe object is available to us and we can reuse it to provide the Ajax you URL inside.
The response function will be doing either one of two things we're going to check the data object for
a status property and check if its value is equal to 2 if it is then we know that the form submission
was a success.
Otherwise an error occurred.
I'm going to update the status HCM l appropriately.
If the submission was a failure I'm going to show the form again.
Let's handle the form submission now inside the main plugin file.
Let's add the action hook WP Ajax we have to append our action to this hook like so the function we
want to call will be the same name as the action.
I'm also going to make this hook available for guests as I'm going to allow for get submissions to inside
the process folder create the file called submit dash user dash recipe dot BHP and define the function
here.
We'll need to include this file from the main plugin as well.
Create a variable named output this will be an array that will contain the status set the status to
1 I'm going to perform a very simple check on the title input.
I want to know if it's empty.
If it is I'm going to send back the output with the WP send Jason function.
This will also kill the scripts
after this.
I'm going to paste in some code pause the video if you need to.
All I'm doing here is sanitizing the input.
I'm also creating the metadata we create the recipe data array just like last time.
I've set the rating and rating count to zero something you'll notice is that for the title I'm using
these sanitized text field function but I'm not applying this to the content itself.
We can't use this function for sanitizing the content.
Instead I'm using a function called WP KSC as Post and the resource section I provide a link to a function
called WP KSC s.
Let's take a look at this function in more detail.
There are a few libraries out there in P P that help with sanitizing HCM l WordPress provides its own
solution which is the preferred method for sanitizing each team out.
The WP KSC s function is a pretty flexible function as it allows us to define what H2 email Tang's attributes
and protocols are allowed.
It would be pretty time consuming to have to re-enter what h email is allowed every time we use this
function.
If we scroll down there's a link to the WP KSC EZ post function.
This function does the exact same thing as the WP K S E S function but instead uses the same filter
for posts.
This saves us some time since our recipe post is basically just a post it makes sense to just use this
shorter function if you prefer to define your own set of HCM email and attributes than I suggest using
the WP K S S function.
All our data is now sanitized and ready to be inserted into the database inserting a post is actually
really easy.
We don't even have to use the global w PDB object to perform this task.
WordPress provides a handy function called WP insert post I'll provide a link to this function inside
the resources section.
This function will insert a post for us and even take care of sanitization just in case we forgot to
do it ourselves.
There's only one parameter which is an array of arguments.
There are numerous things we can set but we won't be using all of them.
The only required arguments are the content and the title.
If we skip anything WordPress will fill in the rest by default.
This function will end up returning the idea of the post created which we will need for adding the post
metadata creating a variable named post I.D. and its value will be the value returned by the WP insert
post function pass in an array.
We're going to define the following arguments post content will be set to the content variable post
name and post title we'll both be set to the title.
The difference between these two is the name will be used for the slug and the title is used for the
human readable title post status will be set too pending by default.
This is set to draft we'll consider the post complete but we don't want to publish the recipe either
pending we'll let administrators know that the Post needs to be reviewed before being published post
type.
We'll be set to recipes since that is our post type that's it.
Feel free to read over the Codex and set the rest of the arguments if you would like to customize this
further.
Next let's call the update post a function to set the recipe data metadata
our function is almost finished.
All we need to do now is update the status in the output array to 2 and then output it using the WP
send Jason function refresh the recipe form page and try submitting the form with no input.
You should get an error now and try filling in all the fields and we should see a success message.
You should also have your console open to check for any errors.
If you've received no errors and received a success message then there's one last thing we need to check.
Go to the recipe admin page and see if the Post has been added after confirming that it's available.
Let's view the contents in the editor as you can see everything was inputted correctly.
This is exactly what we wanted.
We now have a forum where users can submit their own recipes.
What I like about this is that even though we're not using the Gutenberg Ed on the front end this will
still work.
The content has been converted into a blog called The classic blog.
This makes Gutenberg backwards compatible.