Let's begin exploring some of the built in modules from node.
Right now I'm on the official no documentation page here.
You'll find information about using Node to its fullest on the sidebar.
You'll find a list of modules that come with node by default.
I want you to click on utilities the utilities module is a pretty simple one.
It provides you with methods that can help you with string manipulation and so much more.
If you scroll down you'll see a basic example.
You'll notice that node recommends you use const instead of VaR.
This is a brand new javascript feature that I don't expect you to know in the next couple of lectures.
We'll definitely explore some of the new features available in JavaScript.
For now we're going to keep things simple.
We are going to continue using var instead of const.
Don't worry you won't experience any problems by using var instead of cost.
All right.
Let's use this module.
I'm going to comment out the code inside the index file create a variable named you till and require
the module you till.
This is the same code on the documentation as you can see it's recommended you name your variable after
the module name.
You are allowed to change the variable name to whatever you want but I don't recommend it doing it like
this.
Just makes your code easier to read and manage.
One thing you'll notice is that I'm just requiring the module without having to specify a path node
modules are global modules.
There are usually two kinds of modules ordeals that exist inside your directory and modules that exist
globally node will search for modules in three locations.
A will search for the module inside your directory then it'll search for the module in a directory called
Node underscore modules.
Lastly it'll search for the module in the global modules directory global modules can be used anywhere
on your system.
You can use global modules inside your documents desktop and even your windows folder.
The you till module is a global module so we do not need to worry about inputting a full path node is
smart enough to find this module for you.
Let's use this module.
It can be used the same way we used our own custom module in the previous lecture.
This module returns an object with properties and methods that can help us with formatting I'm going
to log a message and inside this log I'm going to use the you'd still object and call the method format.
This is a method that will take in a string and replace certain parts of a string with other values.
I'm going to input the following Hello percent sign s exclamation point.
The percent sign S is a placeholder.
You shouldn't be familiar with this concept.
It works similar to this string replace p p function.
The percent s can be replaced with any value you want.
The second parameter to this method is the word world.
I'm going to run this now using the node index command just like that we should see the message.
Hello world.
It's a very simple function and it's provided to you by note.
All you have to do is include the utilities module.
You can go to the documentation and click on this.
You still dot format link to learn more about this method.
You can do a lot with this method and there are plenty of examples on how to use it.
This is just one of the modules provided to you by note.
There are dozens of them available and you're free to check them out for the most part.
We won't be using these modules ourselves as we don't really need them.
However the library we do plan on using we'll use these modules along with third party modules.
Let's explore how to use third party modules.
Now in the resource section of this lecture I provide a link to a site called NPM NPM is short for node
package manager.
This is the official site for node modules.
Here you'll find modules where users can upload their own modules and make it available for others to
use and download.
Let's search for a module called H API.
This is a module that provides a framework for building websites and single page apps.
It's one of my favorite frameworks along with admonish J.S. for building Web sites using Node installing
a module is pretty easy on the right sidebar you'll see NPM provides this command that you can input
to install it.
Let's use this command now type in npm install H API the NPM command is created for you by node when
you installed it actually let's use the NPM command by itself and see what we get.
As you can see we get a list of sub commands you can use with this command and some additional information
about this command.
Commands are allowed to have sub commands.
The reason for this is is because it makes it easier to manage so many commands.
The NPM command is a way for you to communicate with the NPM site.
One of the sub commands you can use is the install command which will download any module you want from
the NPM site.
The module I want to install is called a GPI so we pass him the NPM install H API command run this command.
This may take a while for some of you.
You'll see that node output in some messages about the installation for the most part you don't have
to worry about this.
You may see some errors but we can safely ignore those for now.
Once the installation is a success you'll find that node creates this folder called Node underscore
modules by default.
All modules that are created by a third party vendor will be stored inside this folder.
You can open this folder and you'll find another folder called HP.
Just like that we've installed another module so you may be wondering why use the NPM command instead
of just downloading the module ourselves.
Well the NPM does a lot behind the scenes that takes care of setting all this up for you.
At first glance it's not really visible until you start using modules that are more complex than HP.
Let me show you what I mean in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to a framework called Express Express is a framework that makes it easy to create Web
sites and single page apps just like happy.
It is currently the most popular framework available used by many developers around the world.
It's considered an industry standard.
If you take a closer look you'll find this command that installs Express.
You'll also see that there's this additional text dash dash save.
We won't be using this.
I promise in a future lecture we will go over what this does.
But for now I'm going to keep things simple inside the command line.
I want you to input the commands npm install Express.
This will install express for you.
It may take a while
after installing express.
I want you to take a look at the node underscore modules folder again right away.
You'll notice a whole lot of other modules were installed besides Express.
But why.
Well let's open the Express folder for a moment inside this folder.
You'll find a file called package dot Jason.
We haven't gone over what this file is yet but we can ignore a lot of it.
This is just a file that contains settings related to a module.
I want you to scroll down until you find a property called dependencies.
This property allows the developer to specify if the module requires other modules to work just like
in our previous examples.
We required certain modules to make our code work the way we wanted it to.
This same concept can also apply to other third party modules as you can see.
EXPRESS relies on other modules in order for it to work.
Node will look at this and begin installing all these modules next to each module name is the version
it should download.
Let's go down the rabbit hole and see how far we can go.
The very first module express requires is the accept module.
Let's look for this folder and sure enough we find this folder inside the node underscore modules folder.
Open this folder and open the package Dot.
Jason File once again I want you to scroll down to beat dependencies list and you'll see this module
requires a set of more modules.
Let's keep going.
One of the models required is the mime dash types module.
I want you to open this module and view its package.
Jason File you'll end up seeing more dependencies.
This will go on and on until every module required has been installed with the correct version.
You can already imagine the amount of work that has to be done just to make one module work.
It's always best to just use this command as NPM will take care of managing all of this for you.
Now that we have express and happy installed we can use it just like any other module inside the index
file create a variable named Happy and require the happy module.
You can now use the happy module however you like.
It's that simple.
I won't be going over how to use this module at it's not required to learn it.
I just wanted to show you how to install third party modules.
I'm going to delete the node underscore modules folder as we don't need to use any of this code for
our project that does it for modules.
There's a lot more we can talk about but we don't need to go that far.
We don't need to create our own servers or worry about processing data.
We have p p Apache and WordPress to do that for us.
The reason we had to learn node is that so we can use some of the tools that will help us with creating
dude Berg blocks in the next lecture.
We'll explore one of these tools which is called Web pack.