Depending on the complexity of your site you may want to pop in a way for users to register and log
in by default.
WordPress comes with its own log in and registration forms but they're very simple and not appealing
at all.
That's all right.
WordPress can't account for every user situation out there.
Luckily this problem is solved by using third party plugins.
There are dozens and dozens of membership plugins out there originally for this lecture.
I was planning on recommending one and then installing it then I would walk you through on how to set
it up but there were two problems I encountered.
The first problem was that the plugins were extremely bloated.
Now don't get me wrong the plugins were already using have some bloat but they're not so bloated that
they drastically slowed down the site because of features we're not using.
However the membership plugins that were usable have thousands of lines of code that we weren't going
to use such as payment processing custom fields and so much more.
The second problem was finding plugins that were super simple but they weren't exactly developer friendly.
These plugins had their own you guys and it was too much trouble to make the UI match the theme on our
site.
A lot of them were outdated as well.
So rather than using a third party plugin I thought this would be a great opportunity to show you how
to do it yourself.
Before we get started I want to take the time to let you know that membership plugins are extremely
beneficial for any theme.
If you plan on selling your theme then including a feature to packed membership plugin wouldn't be so
bad.
I recommend it.
However for the theme we're creating.
We only need something super simple.
All right let's get started.
Some of the steps we'll be taking won't be anything we haven't done before.
We'll be using a short code to display the form and an ajax request to process the information we'll
be working inside the recipe plugin rather than a custom one just to save some time inside the main
plugin file.
Call the ad short code function the name of the short code will be recipe off form the function to call
is our recipe off form short code create a file inside the includes slash short code directories called
off dash formed up HP.
Define the function here and include it from the main plugin file
next.
Create a file named off dash form dash template dot P HP
this file will contain all the H2 UML for the form inside the Udemy theme folder we have a template
called off dot h t email I'm going to open this up inside my browser here's what that page looks like
we're basically going to try and recreate this page.
If I were to open this template inside the editor and scroll down you'll eventually find the H2 UML
for the form.
To be specific the HP email should be inside the Section tag with the idea of content.
You'll find div tags with the classes call 1 3rd and call to 3rd copy both these elements and their
contents and paste them into the auth form template like so after doing so let's go back to the short
code function.
Just like before we'll be creating a variable.
I'm going to call it form H GM L and its value will be the value returned by the file.
Get contents function with the template in the first parameter and true as the second.
Then I'll just return the HCM out let's test this out now.
I'm going to create a brand new page with a title.
My account the content will be the short code recipe auth form the template will also need to be set
to full width.
Once you've made those changes save the page and then view it
you should more or less have what I have on my screen.
We can now begin authenticating the user the very first thing we should do is make sure the form is
secure for submission.
There are various ways you can go about this but WordPress provides a solution called nonsense in the
resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link for more information about this topic.
Let's take a look at what WordPress has to say about ns a nonce is a number used once to help protect
you or else in forms from certain types of misuse malicious or otherwise.
WordPress NS aren't numbers but are a hash made up of numbers and letters nor are they used only once
but have a limited lifetime after which they expire.
During that time period the same nonce will be generated for a given user in a given context.
The nonce for that action will remain the same for that user until that nonce lifecycle has completed
WordPress is security tokens are called non says despite the above noted differences from two Ns because
they serve much the same purpose as nonsense do they help protect against several types of attacks including
CSR F but do not protect against replay attacks because they aren't checked for one time use nonsense
should never be relied on for authentication or authorization access control protect your functions
using current user can always assume Nazis can be compromised so as WordPress states this helps you
create a layer of security by using a token for verifying the form submission but it's not completely
foolproof.
The rest of this documentation goes over how to use Nazis.
I suggest reading it fully after this lecture.
So here's what we'll want to do.
I want to load a nonce inside the template.
The process will be simple we'll just generate the nonce and then load it in the template using placeholders
inside the template file at the very top.
I'm going to add a place holder called nonce underscore field underscore P H then inside the short code
function.
I'm going to perform a simple string replace call like we've always have
for the replacement.
We'll be calling a function called WP nonce field.
This will take care of generating a nonce value while also creating an input field containing this value
in the resource section.
I provide a link to this function.
There are four parameters which are all optional.
The first one is always recommended though the action name is a way to reference this field.
You should set one as you'll need to verify it later on you'll see how this works in just a moment.
For now I'm going to set it to recipe off the next parameter is name for the input field.
By default it's underscored w peanuts.
I'm going to set this to the default.
The third parameter is whether to include a refer a refer is the euro but the request was submitted
on.
It's always good practice to make sure the form was submitted on this page and not through some other
site.
I'm going to set this as true the fourth parameter determines whether this field should be output ID
or returned.
Set this to false which will return the field rather than output it lets verify that the fields are
being generated and output it by refreshing the page and checking the HDMI out
using the developer tools you'll find two hidden input fields appear right before our forms.
Traditionally you'll want these fields to appear inside the forum but we won't concern ourselves with
that since we'll be using J query and Ajax to submit the form open the main dot J.S. file this is the
same file that contains the rating code.
We'll be working inside this file for all our javascript needs.
Once again I'll be using the on method for listening to a form submission and preventing the default
behavior.
We have this div tag with an I.D. of registered dash status.
I'm going to modify its age team all contents and let the user know their account is being created.
Then I'll just hide the form to prevent resubmission
next.
I'm going to create the form object like before the action will be recipe create accounts the other
5 values will just be the forms input fields the last property I want to create will be called underscored
WP knots.
It's important you name it.
This as WordPress will be expecting this field when verifying the knots.
The value will be grabbed from the hidden input field.
The idea of the input field should be underscored WP notes.
The last thing I want to do is make a J query post request.
It's the exact same way as we did it before.
Except I'm going to be using promises the always method behaves similar to the previous way we did it.
It will accept a function where the response is passed into it.
Just like last time we'll check the status property and display an appropriate message to the end user.
If the registration was a success we'll just let the user know they can register.
Otherwise we'll tell them it was a failure and display the form again.
Nothing new here.
Pretty simple stuff.
All right so that basically sets up the front end in the next lecture.
We'll process the data and create a new user.