In this lecture we're going to tackle two things.
First we're going to make the options we created in this section work as intended.
The second task is to use the media uploader to set the featured image for a recipe.
The first option we have is whether it's required for users to log in to rate a recipe in the rate recipe
function.
I'm going to grab the R ops option
then I'm going to check for two things.
I'm going to check if the user is not logged in using the is user log in function and then I'm going
to compare the rating long required Option 2 to
if both statements return true.
Then we will want to kill the script because the user is indeed required to log in to rate a recipe.
I'll have to move the output variable above so that this will work.
Next I'm going to update the short code function.
If the user is not logged in and we require the user to be logged in to create a recipe then we'll display
a message to them.
Once again grab the ah opt option and make the same conditional statement.
Check again
make sure to update the conditional to use the recipe submission log and required instead.
If both statements return true I'm going to output the message.
You must be logged in to submit a recipe
let's test this out really quick log out and then visit the submit recipe page.
Previously I saved my option to require users to log in to submit a recipe.
Therefore I should see this message telling me I need to be logged in.
Now I want you to log in and try seeing if you can view the form again.
If you can then that's great.
Now that we've made the two options work let's move on to the next problem.
I want users to be able to upload an image and set a featured image.
There are two ways we can go about accomplishing this.
We can create an upload button and then process that upload or we can just use the uploader WordPress
provides for us already.
Try creating a new recipe on the sidebar.
We have the option of setting a featured image.
Click the button.
This model will pop up displaying all the images you previously uploaded.
You even have the option of uploading a new one.
This is what's called the media uploader.
We can use this in our plugins and themes.
Let's learn how to do so.
First we need to include the files that will take care of styling and managing the model inside the
front and cue file.
We're going to use a special function called WP and Q media.
This will in Q all files related to the media uploader.
Now we can use the media uploader in our page open the recipe create or short code template right before
the submit button.
I'm going to paste in some HDMI out nothing too special about this team out l pause the video if you
need to have what I have.
Here's what's going on in the HCM l.
First we have this label with a link we will make it so that if the user clicks this link then the media
uploader will pop up.
Then we have an image tag which will allow the user to preview their selection.
The most important tag is the hidden input field.
This will be sent to the process function and it's what WordPress needs in order to know what image
the user selected.
All you need to send is the idea of the image.
Let's make this part of the form functional open the main dot J.S. file.
This is the same file with the log in and authentication J.S. code right above the submit code will
add the code to make the media upload a work.
Create a variable named featured frame this variable we assign to the value returned by the WP dot media
method this method was loaded by WordPress when you include the required files to learn more about this
method.
I provide a link in the resource section of this lecture.
Here you'll find a long example on how to use this.
You can click this link for more information about the WP object.
Here you'll find information about the javascript utilities WordPress has to offer.
Let's go back to our file.
This method will return a media object which you can use later to open the media uploader.
This method has one parameter which is an object of properties you can set.
The first is the title.
I'm going to set this to select or upload media.
The second property is the button property.
This property expects another object of properties which you can set inside this object.
I'm going to set the tax property to use this media the last property I want to set is the multiple
property which will be set to false.
This will make it so that users can only select one image instead of multiple images.
We only have one feature to image so we will only want one selected image.
This code will initialize the media uploader but it will not display it.
We only want the media uploader to display if the user clicks on the upload link.
To do this we'll listen for a click using the J.
Query on method the idea of the button is recipe Dash.
I am G dash upload dash BBM
as usual.
We will prevent the normal behavior from happening to open the media uploader.
You simply need to call the open method.
This method only becomes available after you initialize the media uploader which is what we did above
the very last thing we want to do is update the preview an input field when the user selects an image.
The featured frame object provides a few events.
One of these events is these select event that will be triggered when a user selects an image.
We'll use the on method and listen for this event
inside the function.
We're going to create a variable called attachment.
This variables value will be set to an object returned by a chain of methods.
Hopefully you'll be able to follow along because we have to use a number of methods to accomplish this.
So first up is the featured frame object.
We're going to get the current state of the media uploader by calling the state method.
Then we have to use the getting method to retrieve a value from the current state.
The value we want to get is the selection property.
This will return the currently selected item in the media uploader.
Then we're going to call it the first method which will return the first item in the array returned
even though we have multiple set to false.
The media uploader will still return an array of selected objects.
Finally the value return will be a stream.
Therefore we need to convert it into an object.
We'll use the method to Jason to accomplish this.
That was a lot but hopefully you get the gist of it.
The attachment will now be an object with properties about the image selected.
We only care about two properties.
I'm going to set the source attribute of the recipe dash AMG dash preview tag to the attachment.
Your real property.
This is the full eight CTP you are well to the full sized image
next I want to set the value of the ah input image I.D. input to the attachment ideas property.
This is the idea in the database and it's the idea that we'll need to assign the image to this post
the very last step is to send it when the form is submitted.
I'm going to create a new property called attachment ideas and said its value to the input field like
so
our JavaScript file is now complete.
The next step is to process it through p p open the submit dash user dash recipe dot P HP file.
This is the file we made to process new recipes on the front end right before we kill the script.
Create a new conditional statement that will check if the attachment ideas post he is set and if it
is an empty
then we need to include the WP dash admin slash includes slash image stop BHP file processing images
is not done on every request so it's unnecessary for wordpress to automatically load this file since
that is the case we need to load it ourselves by loading this file we now have access to a function
called set post thumbnail this function will assign the image to the post all it requires is the post
I.D. and then the attachment idea itself I'm going to wrap the idea of the attachment with the ABS into
function just for good security measure
this would be a good time to talk about data validation we've been using many functions to sanitize
our data but we haven't explored all of them yet in the resources section of this lecture I provide
a link to the data validation Codex page this page contains a list of all the functions provided by
WordPress that you can use to sanitize data feel free to book market as it's quite useful to have would
you want to sanitize data that's about it let's test this out and see if it works I want you to create
a new recipe and fill in all these fields
when you select an image you should be able to see the preview right under the label.
Submit your recipe and you should see a success message
just to confirm if everything worked.
Let's go to the advent dashboard and view the list of recipe posts you should be able to see our brand
new recipe created along with the featured image assigned to it.