The next template we're going to work on is the dates template the dates template is used to display
posts.
If a user is viewing an archive for a particular date year month or date the order that's used here
is date dot P. hp then archive dot P. HP and lastly indexed P HP WordPress provides functionality for
checking if a post is from a certain year month or day but doesn't utilize that in their template system.
This actually gives us more trouble than it does help.
It would be great if we could create templates for certain timeframes but that's just not possible with
Wordpress.
Instead you will have to perform those checks in our templates.
You'll see why this is a problem.
In just a moment if you haven't already drag and drop the archives of widget onto your sidebar.
This will provide some links to view our posts for particular dates.
It will help us a lot later in this lecture.
Once you have that setup let's create the dates dot P HP.
Temple of file the date template is an archive template so we can just use the category template as
a base when it comes to date templates.
We can't use the archive description function as you can't assign descriptions for dates in these cases
we'll have to create our own custom descriptions or just remove it entirely.
It's up to you and what works best for your theme or design.
I'm going to use something called a conditional tag.
Conditional tags are just a fancy phrase for functions that perform checks for you.
They're similar to template tags except they're meant to be used inside conditional statements.
We'll be exploring more conditional tags later in this course but let's keep it simple for now.
I'm going to update this description and add in some code.
All right I'm back and add in this series of conditional statements.
It's nothing really complex inside these conditional statements.
I'm using a conditional tag each of these functions will check if the date being displayed is for a
particular year month or day depending on the date that's being displayed an appropriate message will
be output it with that all set.
Let's check out an archive on the sidebar.
You should have this archive widget that displays dates.
Click on any of these and you should now see our template working once again.
WordPress was able to read the URL and determine what kind of posts to grab from the database.
It also took care of generating the title.
The only thing we did was taking care of generating the description.
Now let's look at the problems that arise with this template.
If you look at the URL you should see the date it's formatted as a year month and then the date.
If I wanted to see post on a specific date then I could pass in a day like so the only requirement for
displaying a date archive is the year so I can remove the month and day Like so.
Something you should know about the date archive is that it will only display if there's at least one
post for the date range.
For example if I want to change the year to 2020 and refresh the page then you should see no posts the
date template doesn't even get loaded.
Instead we get the 4 0 4 template even though it isn't documented inside the template hierarchy.
WordPress will fall back to the 4 or 4 template if there are no posts for a date range.
This is a problem because what if we wanted to display a message telling the user there are no posts
for a date.
We can't do that.
We can't even use conditional tags as they will return false.
Luckily the date template isn't a commonly used template.
I actually don't find myself creating it or even using it that often despite the quirks it gives off.
They aren't that dangerous or bad.
So you can get away with not creating this template.
It's definitely a case by case scenario though.