Now that we have Webb pack installed let's begin configuring it.
It's pretty simple.
You need to create a file named Webb pack dock config dock J.S. when we run Webb PAC Webb pack will
look for this file and use it.
This file will contain the settings for Webb pack and you can modify how it behaves through it.
I'm going to create a variable named config which will be set to an empty object.
Then I'm going to export it.
There are two properties required if we don't define anything then Westpac will throw an error.
The first property is entry.
I'm going to set this to dot slash app slash index dot J.S. This folder and file doesn't exist.
So will create those two now
inside the index file.
I'm going to log a message it's important to note that you can name this file whatever you want.
All right let's go back to the Web pack config file.
The next property we have to set is the output property which contains the settings to where the final
file will be saved.
This will be an object and there are two properties we have to set which are the path and file name
properties the file name property can be set to whatever you want.
If you view the documentation or read any tutorials.
Most developers name this bundle.
J.S. will follow this naming convention the path property is a bit tricky.
This will be the name of the directory where the bundle dot J.S. file will be saved.
However you must input a full system path.
You can't just put a relative path as you'll receive an error.
Luckily node provides some functions for helping us generate a full system path.
We don't have to guess and input some random directory.
I'm going to create a new variable at the top called path and set its value to the module path.
The path module is a default node module that helps you with generating path senior system.
This module will return an object with a couple of methods we can use.
I'm going to use this object and call the resolve method.
This method will return a string of an absolute directory.
The great thing about this module is that it's cross compatible.
This code will work on any operating system such as Windows OSX and Linux.
This method has an unlimited number of parameters.
You just pass in the name of the directories you'd like to have.
I'm going to pass in the constant underscore underscored journey this is a constant.
Created by node for you automatically it contains the path to the current file it's being used.
I'm going to then pass in dist.
This can be named whatever you want.
This will return a path to our current directory and point to a folder called dist which is short for
distribution in a lot of tutorials and examples.
You'll find that most developers will name at this some developers will also name it build which is
perfectly fine.
It's all preference in the end web path.
We'll look at this and create a file named bundle dot J.S. that contains all our javascript code and
save it in our current directory.
Inside a folder named dist.
This is the minimum requirements for configuring web pack.
There are more settings we can set but we'll get to those later.
In order for this to work we need to install another module.
The Web pack module is what takes care of processing everything in order for web pack to process everything
we need to write the code for it.
We've only configured it.
Fortunately there is a tool that takes care of that for us in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to the official web Pax CLIA node allows you to create your own custom commands and
there are modules that take advantage of that feature web pack being one of them.
With this tool we can allow Web pack to take care of making it process the code itself back inside the
command line input the commands NPM ie web pack dash CLIA dash dash save dash Dev I'm introducing a
new sub command here called I which is short for installing there's no difference between the two.
The AI is just the shorthand version run this command.
It may take a while to install.
So be patient the last step is to have NPM run the commands open the package dot Jason File Under the
scripts property.
We can have NPM run the commands for us rather than typing it ourselves.
Create a new property called start you can name this whatever you want but I recommend keeping it short
and concise.
The value for this will be the command you want to run.
I'm going to input the following web pack dash dash config web pack dot config dot J.S. the web pack
command was provided to us when we installed web packs see a lie module this command requires us to
set the option config this option will tell web pack what file contains our configuration settings then
you simply pass in the file name in our case this would be web pack dot config dot yes that's all we
need to do now we can run this commands inside the command line input NPM run start.
This will tell NPM to run the command inside the scripts properly called start after running this command
you'll see a couple of stuff being output it you'll be provided with the amount of time it took to run
this command it's fairly fast for me it took under a second.
You'll also be provided with the name of the file that contains all your code and the files that are
saved inside this file we only have one file and that's the index dot J.S. file.
One thing I want you to notice is the size of both files.
The index file is only a few bytes.
However the bundle dot J.S. file is way larger than the index file.
The jump in size is massive.
So why is this.
Well let's check out the bundle dot J.S. file for more answers after running this command web pack should
create a directory called disks with the bundle dot genius file saved inside.
Let's open this file.
It's safe to do so.
Web pack generates a lot of code.
There's a lot going on here.
It can be very intimidating but it's nothing you have to worry about.
Web pack is just making sure the code works without a problem.
In future lectures will definitely benefit from this optimization.
If you scroll around you'll eventually find the message that we logged in our file.
At first glance this seems excessive just for one line of code and you're completely right.
If you're using web pack for small projects then you really don't need it.
When pack is for larger projects like single page apps.
I promise we'll use Web pack in a larger project but for now we'll keep it to this simple example.
Let's check if this works.
The file that web pack generates is meant to be used on the front end.
I'm going to create a file called index dot H2 UML and inside this HD email file.
I'm just going to load the bundle dot J.S. file then I'm going to simply open up the index dot HCM l
file.
This is just a simple HDMI file so we don't need any servers or back and logic to help us open up the
console and you'll see the message.
How low being output it the real power of web pack comes into play when we start using multiple modules
before I am this lecture.
Let's go back to the terminal.
If you were to look at the message output it you'll see that web pack tells us we should set the mode.
Let's add this to the config file and set it to development.
There are two possible values for this which are production and development.
I believe it's obvious which setting you should use.
Since we're on our local machines then this should be set to development.
Once you upload your code to a life server be sure to set this to production.
Westpac uses this to optimize the code depending on where the code will be used.
The development mode will output more messages to help you debug your script.
Now that we've set that let's move on to the next lecture.