Throughout this course we've been using action hooks.
There is another type of hook called filter hooks filter hooks are similar to action hooks except for
one thing they are passive value and you're expected to return a value in most cases.
It's a modified version of the past in value.
We're going to be using our first filter hook.
So get ready Let's view the recipe posts on the front end.
You may receive this forum for error.
Initially you may think this is strange and it is.
We did everything right.
So why are we getting a forum for here.
Well WordPress is not aware that we have updated the permanent structure.
What I mean by this is that when you create a post type you will receive a special yourself format for
your post type.
In our case it would be recipe followed by the slug over the post.
Take a look at the URL bar to see this new format.
There are two ways we can fix this.
There is the manual way which is updating the perma link structure.
And then there is the developer way by flushing the rewrite rules.
I will be doing this the first week because it'll be a lot faster to do so I will definitely show you
how to flush rules through BHP but that deserves a lecture of its own for now updating the structure
will suffice.
Go to the admin dashboard and under settings perma links just update the settings once you don't need
to make any changes.
Now you can go to the recipe posts and everything should display just fine as you can see the post is
displaying just like any other post.
The only thing missing is the recipe data.
Go back to the main plugin file so we can begin this process.
There are a couple ways we can go about this.
The recommended way is by using a filter hook filter hooks can be used by using the add filter function
this function works exactly the same as the add action function for our post.
I want to add the recipe data right above the content so I want to use a hook called the content this
hook is triggered when the content of a post or page is being displayed.
The name of the function I want to run is called Our filter recipe content let's create a file inside
the process folder called filter dash content dot p p and define the function here.
Make sure to include it from the plugin file
unlike action hooks filter hooks will always pass and something for you to filter the content hook we
passed in the contents of the post.
We'll call this argument content inside the function.
You should always return the content.
Let's see what happens if you don't return anything.
Refresh the post and you'll see the content disappears.
Let's return the content from the post if you go back to the page then you should see the content reappear.
This function will apply to all post types.
We need to make sure this only applies to recipes.
We also need to check if this is a single post and not an excerpt.
We're going to check both cases by using one function called is singular this function will check if
this is a single post.
We can also pass this function a post type the post type we want to check is for recipe.
If this function returns false then we'll just return the content
otherwise we'll continue on with filtering the post.
Let's create the H team L that will be used to display the recipe data create a file inside the process
folder called recipe dash template dot P HP inside the assets slash extra folder you'll find a file
named recipe dash template dot P HP.
Copy and paste everything here to our HP template this is just a regular HMO.
We have an unordered list.
There is one thing you'll notice though we have all these capitalized words such as rates underscore
ie 1 8 N.
These are placeholders.
You don't have to name them like this but I like to make them all caps so that they're easier to identify.
We're going to grab this file and its contents and replace the place holders with our data.
First things first let's grab the template from within the filter function.
I'm going to create a variable named recipe on HCM out.
I will assign it to the value returned by the function file get contents the file I want to get is the
template recipe dash template dot P HP.
I'm also going to set the second parameter to true.
This will make the function work just like the include function to check if this is working.
I'm going to return the recipe HCM El variable and concatenate the content let's refresh the page and
you should now see the template right before the content.
Now all we have to do is replace these place holders with the recipe data.
First we have to grab the metadata just like last time.
We can use the get post meta function however first we need the post I.D..
Luckily for us WordPress will create a variable name to post this variable is a global variable.
Now we have access to all this posts properties.
Let's create the recipe data variable and grab the metadata like so from here we can use a function
called S T TR replace we're basically going to use this function to replace the tax with a new template.
The first parameter is the name of the string you want to replace.
In this case we want to replace the rating placeholder with the text rating.
Make sure that the string is translation ready.
The third parameter is a string that will be searched which is the recipe a male variable.
It's as simple as that.
You should now have something similar to what I have.
Let's refresh the page and you'll now see our data.
This is the power of filter hooks.
They're similar to action hooks except you will receive data to filter and be expected to return that
filter data.
We kept it simple by just translating the text.
We'll be adding the rating itself soon enough.
Before I end this lecture I want to talk about what this I 18 in phrase you see here means.
I 18 it simply means internationalisation.
The name comes from the first and last letters of internationalization with 18 being the number of letters
between these two letters.
To reiterate what's going on all I'm doing is grabbing the recipe data and the HCM El template.
The H2 email template is pretty basic.
It just contains place holders for our data.
This makes it so that it's always dynamic and fresh.
Then we just replace the place holders with the data using the function as TR replace.
Then we just return the template with the modified data right before the content.