In this lecture we're going to finish up our short code by making the log form work inside the main
dot J.S. file.
I'm going to copy and paste the previous javascript code we used for the register form.
I'm going to change a lot of this code from the field to the status messages so that they reflect the
log into form instead the action will be recipe user log in.
Make sure to update the status messages and selections.
Nothing crazy here.
It's what we did previously create a new Ajax action hook with no privileges.
I'm going to copy and paste the action I used in the form object like so
create a file inside the process folder called log and BHP and define the function inside here.
Make sure to include it from the main plugin file
inside this function.
I'm going to ground the first two lines from the Create Account file and paste it in here I'm creating
an output variable grabbing and verifying the nonce and then checking to see if the user name and password
was submitted.
I'm going to remove the email and password confirmation from this check.
Really nothing new so far.
I'm going to create a new variable named a user that will contain the value returned by the function
WP sign on this function will authenticate users for you.
This is the function I recommend you use when you're authenticating users who have already logged in
before this function has two parameters.
The first is an array of the log in credentials a will use to verify and authenticate the current user.
There are three fields we can set the user log in except the user name.
I'm going to sanitize this while I'm at it
the next key is user password which accepts the password.
Lastly the remember key allows you to specify whether the user should be remembered on this device.
I'm going to set this to true.
This will sign the user in just to make sure we're going to create another conditional statement checking
if this function and returns an error object using the is WP error function.
If it is an error object then we'll just kill the script.
Otherwise we'll update the status to 2 and kill the script once more.
That will take care of everything.
If you haven't already log out and then try logging in after confirming that everything works.
There's one last thing we want to do.
We're almost finished.
I promise.
If you were to go to the admin dashboard and navigate to settings general you'll find a setting called
anyone can register.
This setting controls word presses registration form even if this is ticked off plugins can still create
accounts with code.
We're going to use this setting to our advantage.
I want to hide the form.
If registration is disabled we'll start by creating a place holder inside the template.
Find the div tag that contains the whole registration form and add show Reg form will replace this place
holder with a style attribute inside the shortcut function.
Add another string replacement function
for the replace function.
We're going to use a ternary operator.
We'll be performing a check using a function called Get option.
We haven't discussed the options API but this function will grab the options from the options table
using Heidi yes Q Well you can open the WP options table WordPress stores all of its settings here.
It also stores transients and plug in options.
One of the options is users can register.
This is the option that is updated when you tick the checkbox on the admin settings page.
If the value is 0 then that means the registration is closed.
If it's 1 then that means registration is open.
We can pass this into the get option function and it will tell us whether or not registration is open.
If this check returns false we'll have the registration form with a simple display CSA style
otherwise it'll be empty and display as is.
Save your work update the settings to disable registration and try viewing the form.
It should not display the very last thing you want to do is hide these forms.
If the user is logged in right now I'm logged in and it should not be displaying inside the short code.
Function.
Create a conditional statement at the very top.
Call the function is user logged in.
If this returns true we'll just return an empty string
refresh the page and you should see nothing appear that's it.
We're finally finished.
It was a lot to go through but well worth it.