It's time to learn about web packed loaders and Babel.
It is completely possible to use the latest tools on libraries without note in web pack.
There is a problem with this.
The first is that you'll end up writing more code than usual to accomplish a lot of the things you'd
like to do.
In truth we're already writing a lot of code just to accomplish these tasks.
However this is just for setting things up.
Once you have everything set up you don't have to worry about viewing this code for quite a while.
On the other hands if you are trying to do these things without these tools you'll find that you'll
constantly have to update multiple files.
This becomes very hard to manage.
It's just not worth it in the end.
I highly encourage you to keep pushing through on learning these tools as they will speed up development.
We're almost close to finishing up the basics before we can learn how to integrate all of this with
Wordpress.
The next tool we need to learn is Babel.
Babel takes javascript to the next level in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to the official Babel site.
What Babel will do is allow you to write JavaScript that is not implemented in both browsers and note
it will then convert that code into code that the browser or no can understand.
This may seem strange because web packets seem to do something similar to this.
That's true but web pack doesn't cover every single feature will need web pack just covers the basics
by using Babel.
We are rest assured that we cover everything.
It's important to note that Babel and Westpac are two completely different tools you can use Babel without
web pack and vice versa.
However these two worked very well together and using them both is very easy in order to use Babel.
We have to load three different modules Babel is a very modular tool meaning that the code is split
up into different modules so you can pick what you want to use and leave the rest behind.
Usually you'll end up using a minimum of three Babel modules.
The first module is the Babel dash core.
This is the heart of Babel.
This module has the core functionality in order to make everything Babel related work.
This module will take care of reading your code and then transforming it into code that the browser
can understand.
The second module is the Babel dash loader module.
This module makes it easy to connect web pack and Babel together.
It handles a lot of the work for you.
All you have to do is load and then configure it inside the config file and everything else will be
connected.
The last module will vary depending on what you want.
Basically the Babel dash core module is just a way for you to read and pass javascript code.
However it doesn't handle what should and shouldn't be converted iOS 6 isn't the latest version of JavaScript.
There's also iOS 7 and iOS 8 the latest versions are barely supported in browsers or note iOS 6.
It's considered to be the next standard in web development.
With that being said if you wish you can use iOS 7 or iOS 8.
However for this course we will only be using iOS 6 code.
There are various modules with their own set of rules for converting code.
If you were to go to the Babel site under docks you'll find a link to the official plugins you can use.
There are two types of plugins experimental and official.
We won't bother with using experimental plugins as we don't need to go that far under the Official set.
You'll find a list of modules to use.
So which one do we use.
Well it really depends on what you want to use.
However for most cases the Babel dash preset dash in the module is the recommended one.
It's usually reviewed by the team of Babel and is considered the most stable and usable module out of
them all.
Let's get started with all these modules.
I'm going to enter the following commands npm install dash dash save dash Dev Babel dash core Babel
dash loader Babel dash preset dash EMV.
This may take a while.
Pause the video if you need to wait.
You may get a couple of warnings and that's perfectly fine.
A good way to confirm if a module was installed is by looking at the package dot Jason File node will
usually add your modules to the dependencies list.
If the module was installed successfully it's a good indicator of determining if your modules are good
to go.
All right.
We can now use Babel as a loader.
What exactly are loaders web hack.
Has a feature called loaders loaders or a way to extend the way web pack functions.
It's the same idea for using Wordpress hooks you are allowing to load in certain code that will modify
the final result in some fashion.
The Babel dash loader module we installed earlier makes it easy to integrate Babel with web pack.
All we have to do is update our config file to use this module inside the config file.
Create a new property called module since we're using a third party module we need to set this property.
This property allows you to modify how third party modules are used with Westpac.
Keep in mind that Babel is technically a module so if we want to load the Babel module we have to set
up this property.
Westpac will take care of loading it for you.
All we have to specify is what modules should be loaded with Westpac.
The value of this property will be an object which will contain even more properties about how modules
work with Westpac.
The only property I want to set is the rules property.
This will be an array of modules we want to use with Westpac to load a module.
You have to create an object like so each object in this array will represent a module.
We only have one module which is the Babel dash loader.
We installed three modules but the Babel loader module is the module that allows us to connect Babel
with Westpac to specify a module you need to set the use property to Babel dash loader.
This will tell Westpac to look for a module called Babel dash loader the Babel dash loader will take
care of the rest with connecting the other two modules together there is one last thing I want to do
before we're finished with configuring Westpac I want to set a property called Test Westpac is not just
for JavaScript Westpac will also apply to images and style sheets since we're using Babel Babel will
be applied to images and style sheets.
However Babel does not process or work with images and style sheets will get errors on top of that web
Westpac can also be applied to other extensions and file types if it's configured to do so.
We only want be able to work on JavaScript files to make sure Babel will only work with JavaScript files
then we'll have to set this property the value of this property will be a regular expression the regular
expression will be forward slash backslash dot J.S. percent forward slash if you're unfamiliar with
regular expressions then I highly recommend you take the time to study them regular expressions are
kind of beyond the scope of this course as they're complicated to explain all this will do is make web
park use Babel for JavaScript files only.
All right that's it.
There was one last thing we need to do before everything will work.
We need to create a file named dot Babel R seat.
It's very important that you name it this there is no file extension.
It's just dot Babel.
Ah see inside this file you can configure how Babel works.
You have to create an object and the property you want to set is the presets property.
You simply pass in an array of modules that contain rules on how to modify the output of javascript
to put it simply you pass in the Babel dash preset dash e and V module Babel will look at this array
and will load the modules inside this array the Babel dash preset dash in V is a module that will look
at your code and tell people how it should convert that code into something that browsers can understand.
It's important that you make one distinction between these two files.
The web page config files allows you to control how Web pack works.
The module property allows you to make the bridge between Westpac and a third party module.
However it does not completely control that module Babel needs its own configuration file so you can
specify exactly how it'll work.
All right that's it.
Let's test things out.
I'm going to run the NPM run start command you should receive no errors.
Let's view the H team I'll file again and see if we still see the message being output.
We can also view the bundle dot J.S. file and you'll find it's exactly the same as before.
The reason for this is because we aren't using any advanced features of JavaScript yet.
This will lead us into the next lecture.
We're going to begin using some of the new features that JavaScript has to offer.
Also you in the next lecture.