A lot of languages in the world are written from left to right.
English French and German are just some examples of languages that are read and written from left to
right.
There are languages out there that read left to right or RTL like Arabic.
In these cases having your theme support these languages can increase your reach in sales.
Unfortunately there is a problem which is most of our content by default is L2 ja meaning left to right
actually developing a theme or plug in for RTL sites requires that you set up a wordpress RTL installation.
This would take too much time.
Luckily there is a plugin that someone developed that will help us test our site with RTL content.
Go to the admin dashboard and navigate to plugins add new search for the plugin called RTL tester install
and activated
this plugin will add a new menu item on a now bar that will let you switch from L2 ya to RTL switch
your site to RTL.
You'll notice things don't really change.
That's because we need to prepare the CSX that will move things from right to left.
This isn't a CSX course so I won't be going over how the CSX works.
Be aware that to make a site RTL you have to add CSX code that makes it appear RTL I've already created
the CSX files that changed things to load these files.
We have to register and cue them open the includes slash front slash and cued up HP file to save some
time.
I'm just going to paste the register styles functions
all these styles will make the necessary CSF changes required to make the site and content Artie already.
However I don't want to include these files right away.
I want to check to see if the site is an RTL mode inside a conditional statement.
Call the function is RTL if this function returns true then that means the site is an RTL mode.
If it is an RTL mode then I'm going to queue all the styles we just registered like so
now that we're loading the RC l styles.
Let's test it out.
Go ahead and refresh the page.
The content should now be reading from right to left.
Switch back to L2 ja to test if the site returns to normal after confirming the changes you should be
finished adding RTL support is as easy as including the C Ss files needed to make a site RTL you don't
have to use any special P2P functions or change the core.