In this demonstration, you will learn how to connect to an Azure Repo.
An Azure Repo is a Git repository that is hosted in Azure DevOps.
Let's switch to Visual Studio.
As you can see, we work now as user Thomas.
Now let's go to the Connect page of Team Explorer by clicking here
on this little plug to manage the connections.
Here you can manage your local Git repositories.
Up here you see also a Hosted Service Providers section.
You can click here on Connect to connect to an Azure Repo, so let's do this.
When you click on Connect, this dialog opens up to connect to a project.
As you can see, it shows the hosted repositories for my Microsoft account.
You can see here that I am part of the two organizations,
thomasclaudiushuber and wiredbraincoffee.
Here is the WiredBrainCoffee.ShopInfoTool repository.
Let's select this.
Visual Studio detects that we have this repository already under this path,
so it just shows here a Connect button to connect to the Azure Repo.
But if I would change that path, let's add a tool here,
you can see this button changes to Clone.
Now it would clone the repository to this path and it would also connect to it.
But let me remove these two again, and let's click here on the Connect button.
Now you can see that we are connected to the
WiredBrainCoffee.ShopInfoTool repository from Azure DevOps.
Let's go again to the Connect page of Team Explorer.
You can see here in bold the WiredBrainCoffee.ShopInfoTool from Azure
DevOps and here the local Git repository that is used.
Now let's go back to the Home page.
On the Home page,
you'll find a few new sections that come from the Azure DevOps service.
You can manage now in addition from Team Explorer Work Items,
Builds, and Pull Requests.
As you might remember from the previous module,
Thomas worked on this feature/coffeeShopCommands branch
that you see down here in the status bar.
Now the user Thomas wants to send a pull request to Julia,
so let's click here on Pull Requests to go to the new Pull Requests page.
You can see here in this section the pull requests
that were requested by Thomas,
and you can see here the pull requests that are assigned to Thomas.
At the top, you have here this action to create a new pull request,
so let's click on it.
Now you see my browser opens up,
and we are here on the page in Azure DevOps to create a new pull request to
match the feature/coffeeShopCommands branch into master.
But now let me close the browser.
Instead of navigating to the browser when you click on
this New Pull Request action here,
you can also create a new pull request directly in Visual Studio.
To do this, you need to install the Pull Requests for Visual Studio extension. Let's do this in the next clip.