In this demonstration, you will learn how to browse the history of a file.
Let's switch to Visual Studio.
Here I've opened the WiredBrainCoffee.ShopInfoTool solution.
Now let's take a look at the history of the Program.cs file.
So let's right-click it here in the Solution Explorer and let's
select View History from the context menu.
Now you can see here the history view of the Program.cs file.
This view shows you all the commits where the Program.cs file was changed.
You can right-click a commit and you can select here Open to open this
specific version of the Program.cs file in a new tab.
You can also select here View Commit Details to open
the commit details in Team Explorer.
So here you can see, for example,
that as part of this commit where we introduced the command handlers,
the Program.cs file was changed.
In this history view,
you can also right-click a commit and you can compare the
Program.cs file with the previous version.
So let's do this.
Let's click here on Compare with Previous.
Now you see here the diff of the Program.cs file,
on the left-side the previous version,
and on the right-side the version of the current commit.
So you see here we have introduced the command handlers.
Now let's go back to the history view.
Instead of comparing a commit with the previous version,
you can also select two commits by pressing down the Ctrl key.
Now you can right-click and you can select here Compare to
compare the two versions of the Program.cs file.
So let's click here on Compare, and now you see a diff.
Let's drill down, and you see on the left side we had just the help command,
and on the right side other command handlers.
Let's go back to the history view.
Let's right-click again the two commits.
Instead of selecting Compare,
which brings you directly to the diff of the Program.cs file,
you can also select here Compare Commits.
This opens up the Compare Commits page in Team Explorer.
Now you see here that we compare these two commits,
and down here you see all the changes.
So here in the Changes, you can just double-click the Program.cs file,
and then you are again in the diff view that we just saw where the
help command is replaced with these command handlers.
Now, let me close this diff view again.
Another great way to browse the history of a file is by doing a Git blame.
You can right-click any commit here and you can select here Blame,
or you can also go to the Solution Explorer,
right-click the Program.cs file,
and select here Blame to annotate the latest Program.cs file version.
Let's do this.
Let's select here Blame.
Now you can see the latest Program.cs file version.
The tab header even contains the commit ID of this version.
On the left side,
you see all the commits that made it into this version of the Program.cs file.
You can click here on the left side on a commit ID to open
up the commit details in Team Explorer.
So let's say, for example,
you want to know where this line with the using directive for the
WiredBrainCoffee.DataAccess namespace was added or changed.
Let's click here on the commit ID.
Now the Commit Details open up in Team Explorer,
and you can see this was the commit Implement help command.
Now we can look at the changes.
Let's double-click the CS project file and you can see in this file
a reference to the DataAccess project was added.
Let's go back to Team Explorer and let's double-click the Program.cs file.
Here you can see that a using for the
WiredBrainCoffee.DataAccess namespace was added.
In this commit,
we have implemented the help command for the WiredBrainCoffee.ShopInfoTool.
Now let's close this diff again.
In this annotated view,
you can also right-click a commit on the left side and you can
select from the context menu Annotate This Version to open up
this specific version in a separate tab.
So let's select here Annotate This Version for this 4b70 commit.
Now you can see a separate tab opens up that shows the
Program.cs file for this 4b70 commit.
Now you can see this version of the file,
and on the left side,
you see all the commits that made it into this version of the Program.cs file.
So let's right-click here, for example,
on the commit where we created the namespace and the Program class.
Let's select here Annotate This Version to take a look at this version.
Now you can see here is just a single commit in this annotated version.
This was actually the commit where we added the initial Program.cs file.
Let's double check this.
Let's click on the commit ID, and now you can see the commit details.
In this commit, we added the solution, the CS project file,
and the Program.cs file.
Now let's go back to the Solution Explorer.
Let's look at another CS file where we have multiple users.
Let's right-click the CoffeeShop.cs file and let's select here Blame.
Now you can see in this file that Julia has created a commit
here for the PaperCupsInStock property.
There is another commit from Thomas for the rest.
So when you click on this commit ID,
you can see with this commit the CoffeeShop.cs file was added.
Now let's click on the commit ID from Julia.
You can see this is the commit Add PaperCupsInStock property.
Here Julia changed the CoffeeShop.cs file and the
CoffeeShopDataProvider.cs file.
So now let's double-click on the CoffeeShop.cs file,
and now you can see that Julia actually added the
PaperCupsInStock property with this commit.
All right,
now you saw how to view the history of a file and how to do a
Git blame to annotate the file with a commit.
In the next clip,
you will learn how to use CodeLens to view the history of your code directly in the code editor.