In this demonstration, you will learn how to review and comment a pull request.
Let's switch to Visual Studio.
As you can see, we work now as Julia.
Let's go to Extensions, Extensions and Updates,
and you can see here that we have installed the Pull
Requests for Visual Studio extension, so let's close this dialog.
Let's click on the plug to manage our connections,
and let's connect here to the Azure Repo and Azure DevOps.
Now we have here Julia's Microsoft account,
and you can see she is part of the wiredbraincoffee organization.
Let's select here the WiredBrainCoffee.ShopInfoTool repository.
You can see it takes already the local path Julia\
WiredBrainCoffee.ShopInfoTool that we have already,
so we just need to connect to the Azure Repo.
Let's click the Connect button.
Now we are connected, and you can see here the Pull Requests page,
so let's click on it.
Here Julia can now see that Thomas assigned her the
Handle coffee shop commands pull request.
Let's double-click this pull request to take a look at the details.
The title says Handle coffee shop commands.
Thomas Claudius Huber wants to merge the
feature/coffeeShopCommands branch into master.
Now you can click here on Open to take a look at the changes.
Here you see the changed files from Thomas,
so let's click on the Program.cs file and now the comparison view opens up.
On the left side, you can see the Program.cs file from the master branch,
and on the right side, the Program.cs of this pull request.
So here, Julia can see that Thomas has added the command handlers.
Now let's turn off the comparison view so that we look just
at Thomas's file from the pull request.
Julia actually thinks that this code with the command handlers is really nice.
So what she can do now,
she can just right-click here and you can see she can add
a comment or she can also add a like.
Let's click here on Add a Like,
and now you see this code line here has a thumbs up.
Now let's go again to Team Explorer,
and let's take also a look at the CoffeeShopCommandHandler that Thomas added.
Let's scroll down,
and here you can see how the Location and the Beans in stock of
the foundCoffeeShops are written to the console.
But in addition to the location of the Beans in stock,
this code should also write the paper cups in stock to
the console that Julia has added.
So let's right-click here, and let's add a comment,
Hey, and let's reference here Thomas, Hey Thomas,
you should include the paper cups in stock.
And let's click the Comment button.
Now you see that active comment here.
Now let's go back to the Team Explorer, and let's select here the action.
Let's approve with suggestions, and let's exit this pull request.
Great! So now we have reviewed the pull request, and now Thomas can send an update.