So far you learned in this module how to create a local Git
repository with my user account and how to push it to a
remote repository in Azure DevOps.
In this clip, we won't use my user account anymore.
Instead, we will continue as Julia Developer.
You will see now how she clones the Git repository from
Azure DevOps locally to her machine.
So, in this demonstration, you'll learn how to clone a Git repository.
Let's switch to Visual Studio.
Here you can see the start window of Visual Studio 2019.
Now let's click here on Clone or check out code to
clone the repository from Azure DevOps.
In this window,
you just need to paste the repository URL and you need to specify a local path.
As you can see, there is also a special section for Azure DevOps.
When you click on this, a dialog opens up.
You can specify here your Microsoft account.
As you can see, we are logged in as Julia Developer.
Then you can see here the organizations to which this account was added.
Julia is part of the Wired Brain Coffee organization.
So here she could select the WiredBrainCoffee.ShopInfoTool
repository and she could clone it locally to this path by
clicking the Clone button.
But let's cancel and let's use here the approach with the
repository URL that works with any Git service.
So let's open up Azure DevOps to copy the repository URL.
As you can see,
we are logged in here as Julia Developer and she is part
of the Wired Brain Coffee organization.
Now let's hover the Tools project and let's click here
on the icon for the Azure repos.
This brings us directly to the page with the repository.
So now you can click here on Clone and you can just copy the repository URL.
Let's go back to Visual Studio.
Here in the start window, let's just paste that URL,
and you can see the local path is now Julia\ WiredBrainCoffee.ShopInfoTool.
This looks good to me.
So let's click now the Clone button to close the repository.
The Connect page of Team Explorer is shown,
and you can see it is cloning the repository.
Now the repository was cloned and we are switched to the Solution Explorer.
Here you can see the folder view of the cloned solution.
You can click on this little icon to switch to the solution view.
So let's click it.
Now you can see the WiredBrainCoffee.ShopInfoTool solution is opened.
You can go to Team Explorer, you click on Home,
let's go to the Branches, let's right-click master,
and let's view the history.
Here Julia can see the two commits Thomas has made.
Let's click on Manage Connections here to go to the Connections page.
Here you can see now this local repository.
If you want to clone another repository, you can open up the start window again.
To do this, you just go to the File menu, and here you see Start Window.
So you can click on it,
and then you can again click here on Clone or check out code.
As you know, this brings you to this view.
Let's close it again and let's go again to the File menu.
There is also a menu point, Clone or checkout code,
that opens up directly this view where you can paste in a Git repository URL.
Instead of using this window,
you can also clone a Git repository directly in Team Explorer.
Just go to the Connections page and here you see Clone.
So when you click this, you can also enter here a Git repository URL.
Let's use this approach now.
So let's go to my browser.
You can see I have opened here github.com /dotnet/wpf.
Let's click here on Clone or download and let's copy the repository URL.
Let's go back to Visual Studio.
Let's paste the URL here and let's clone the repository to julia\wpf.
Now you can see the repository here,
you can just double-click it to open this repository in Team Explorer.
So when I hover here you can see we have opened this WPF repository.
Here you can see the solutions from that repository.
You can double-click a solution to open it.
But let's go back to the Connections page and let's open up again
the WiredBrainCoffee.ShopInfoTool repository.
Let's double-click the solution to open this solution.
Now let's go again to the Connections page.
Now you see here we have two repositories.
When you right-click a repository that is not opened in Team Explorer,
you have here the option to remove it from this view.
Instead of using the context menu, you can also just press the Delete key.
This just removes the repository from this view.
It doesn't delete the repository from your machine.
If you have existing local Git repositories that don't show up here,
you can add them by clicking here on Add.
Then you just specify the path to that repository.
So I could click here on the three dots to select a path to a repository.
Or you can also enter a parent folder and Visual Studio
scans all the sub-folders for repositories.
So let's just keep here D:\Julia and let's click Add,
and you can see Visual Studio finds again the WPF
repository that is in the WPF sub-folder.
But now,
let me remove this repository from this view as we want to focus on
the WiredBrainCoffee.ShopInfoTool repository.
Alright,
now you saw how to clone a repository directly from
the start window of Visual Studio, and also by using Team Explorer. Let's wrap up now what you have learned in this module.