You can update a feature branch with the latest changes
from master by using a merge or a rebase.
If you are familiar with the differences between a merge and a rebase,
you can skip this clip.
But if you can't remember exactly what a rebase is,
or if you have never used a rebase, this clip is for you.
Let's go.
At the beginning of this module,
the master branch pointed to the commit from user Thomas in
which he merged Julia's help message.
Then we continued with the user Thomas and we created a feature branch.
On that feature branch, we created a commit to handle the coffee shop commands.
Then we continued with the user Julia.
Julia created another feature branch and she created the commit to add
the PaperCupsInStock property to the coffee shops.
As Julia was done with that feature,
she merged her feature branch into the master branch,
which means that the master branch points now to that merge commit.
As the commits of the paperCupsInStock feature are part of the master branch,
she deleted her feature branch.
After that, we continued with the user Thomas,
and we crated another commit on his feature branch where
we introduced the command handlers.
Now Thomas is done with his feature too,
and he thinks it's ready for being merged back to master.
Let's assume now that Thomas asked Julia to review his feature branch.
Of course,
Julia would expect that her changes from the master branch are
also in that feature branch because Thomas said his branch is
ready for being merged back to master.
That's why you should update the feature branch so
that Julia can test your feature, including the latest changes from master.
Another reason for updating your feature branch with the
latest changes from master is that you can solve all the
conflicts in your feature branch.
When the feature branch will be merged back to master,
the merge won't have any conflicts as the feature branch
includes already the latest changes from master.
If you send out a pull request,
you'll definitely want to ensure that your feature branch is up to
date so that it can be merged smoothly to master.
To update a feature branch,
you can merge the master branch into the feature branch,
or you can rebase the feature branch onto the master branch.
Let's look first at the merge.
With the merge, you merge the master branch into the feature branch,
and the feature branch will point to that merge commit.
This means you have to create an additional commit in the feature
branch to bring in the changes from the master branch.
Now let's go even one step further.
Let me show you what the structure looks like when you
merge your feature branch into master.
Then the master branch points to that merge commit.
Then you can see the history is now a bit hard to read because we have
that additional merge commit in the feature branch.
If you want to have a cleaner, more linear history,
you should do a rebase instead of a merge to update your feature
branch with the latest changes from the master branch.
So let's go back.
Let's reset master to its previous state,
and let's reset the feature branch to its previous
state before that merge commit.
In a rebase,
you replay the commits from the feature branch onto
the branch on which you rebase.
In this case, we rebase the feature branch onto the master branch.
When you start rebasing the feature branch onto the master branch,
the feature branch is first set to the latest commit of the master branch.
Next,
the handle coffee shop commands commit is replayed on top of it
and the feature branch points to that commit.
If you have conflicts,
you have to solve them now and then you have to continue with the rebase.
If you don't have conflicts,
the rebase continues automatically with the next commit.
So next,
the introduce command handlers commit is replayed and the
feature branch points now to that commit.
Note that the two commits that were replayed as part of
the rebase will have new commit IDs.
Now the rebase is done, and as you can see,
the two orange commits from Julia are now part of the feature branch.
The history has a nice linear structure and no merge
commit was necessary to update the feature branch with the
commits from the master branch.
Now to bring back the commits from the feature branch to the master branch,
you could do a fast forward merge that just points the master
branch to the latest commit of the feature branch.
This is nice, but when you delete the feature branch,
it looks like you made the two commits directly on master.
So let's go back.
Instead of a fast forward merge,
you can also create an explicit merge commit to merge the
feature branch into the master branch.
And then the master branch points to that merge commit.
Now you can delete the feature branch and the merge commit on the master
branch makes it clear that you create it with two commits to implement the
coffee shop commands on a separate branch.
I like this approach with an explicit merge commit,
and this is actually what happens by default in Azure
DevOps when you merge the feature branch into the master
branch by completing a pull request.
You will see this in the next module, but here, let's go back one step.
In the next clip,
you will learn how to use Visual Studio to update a feature
branch with a merge and with a rebase. The rebase will lead to the structure that you see on this slide.