In this demonstration, you will learn how to approve and complete a pull request.
Let's switch to Visual Studio.
As you can see, we work now as Julia.
Julia is still connected to the repository
WiredBrainCoffee.ShopInfoTool in Azure DevOps.
Let's click now here on Pull Requests.
Team Explorer tells you here that if you don't see
all the pull requests in this list,
you can navigate here to Projects and My Teams,
and then select here your team project.
We have selected here the Tools project from Azure DevOps that
contains the WiredBrainCoffee.ShopInfoTool repository.
And we can see the pull request that we want to approve,
this Handle coffee shop commands pull request.
Let's double-click this pull request, and let's select here Open.
Now let's go to the Team Explorer,
and here Julia can see now that Thomas has pushed an update.
Of course, Julia doesn't look just randomly into this pull request.
Azure DevOps has sent her an email after Thomas has pushed the update.
So now she can look at this update in Visual Studio.
Let's take a look here at the CoffeeShopCommandHandler.cs file.
Let's turn off the comparison view.
Now let's scroll down.
Here you see an answer from Thomas to Julia's comment.
Julia wrote, Hey Thomas, you should include the paper cups in stock,
and Thomas answered, Hi Julia, that's a great idea.
I will add it in an update.
You can also see that this conversation is part of Update 1,
and you can click here to switch to Update 1.
We selected in Team Explorer to view Update 2.
Here this second comment belongs to the current update tool as
it doesn't have this switch to update header.
Here Thomas wrote, hi Julia, here are the paper cups in stock.
The comment was added to this line that writes the
PaperCupsInStock to the console,
and this statement is actually what Thomas has pushed with Update 2.
What you can also see here in the comments is that
Thomas is the author of the pull request.
What you can do in addition, you can set here the status of a comment.
So you could mark, for example, a comment as resolved.
But let's keep the comments active for now.
We will mark them as resolved in Azure DevOps.
So now let's go back to Team Explorer, and let's click here on Approve.
Before we approved with suggestions,
now let's just click on Approve to approve this pull request.
Then let's click here on Exit.
Let's go back to the Pull Requests page where we see this pull request.
The version of the Pull Requests for Visual Studio extension that I use
here does not have an option to complete a pull request.
To complete the pull request, you need to go to Azure DevOps.
So let's right-click here the pull request, and let's select Open in Browser.
Now you can see we are here on the Handle coffee shop commands pull request.
Let me collapse the navigation.
You can see here the pull request was created by Thomas,
and he wants to merge the feature/coffeeShopCommands branch into master.
Julia, the reviewer, approved this pull request.
When I scroll down, you can also see the comments here.
Here you can see the PaperCupsInStock Console.WriteLine that Thomas has added.
You can also see the comment, Hi Julia Developer,
here are the paper cups in stock.
Then when I scroll down further,
you can see here the one commit that Thomas has pushed to
create an update tool of this pull request.
Let's scroll down a bit more,
and here you can see the comments that were made before Update 2.
Now let's scroll up again.
We approved the pull request already,
so let's click now the Complete button to complete it.
Note that you could add policies so that a pull request requires,
for example, at least two approvals so that you can complete it.
In this case, we don't have such a policy,
so Julia can actually now complete this pull request.
So let's click the Complete button.
And let's click in this dialog Complete merge.
Now you can see that Julia Developer completed the pull request,
but we haven't marked all the comments as resolved.
So let's select here the filter, and let's select here Active comments.
Let's scroll down, and yes, Thomas has implemented the paper cups in stock.
Let's click on Resolve, and let's also resolve that second comment.
Now we don't have any active comments anymore,
and the pull request is already completed.
Let's switch back now to Visual Studio.
Here in Visual Studio, let's click now Refresh on this Pull Requests page.
And now you can see the completed pull request is not displayed here anymore.
Let's go to the Synchronization page now.
As you can see, we are on the branch master, and let's click now Fetch.
Now you can see here the incoming commits,
Handle coffee shop commands and Introduce command handlers,
then the Write paper cups in stock to console commit that
Thomas did to update the pull request, and finally,
the Merge commit to merge the pull request back to the master branch.
Now let's click on Pull to pull these commits into Julia's local master branch.
Let's run the application, and let's try it.
Let's type help, let's type in munich,
and we can see 56 kg of beans in stock and 427 paper cups in stock.
So we have successfully merged the pull request to handle the
coffee shop commands into the master branch. Now let's wrap up what you have learned in this module.