In this demonstration,
you will learn how to do a merge and a rebase in Visual Studio,
so let's switch to Visual Studio.
As you can see,
we work again as user Thomas and we are here on the
feature/coffeeShopCommands branch.
Now let's bring back the latest changes from master into that branch.
So let's go to the Branches page of Team Explorer.
Here you can merge or rebase.
Let's first click on Merge so that you can see this.
Here you can select now that you want to merge from the
master branch into the feature branch.
You can test this very easily by unchecking this
Commit changes after merging checkbox.
Now let's click the Merge button.
You can see Merge in Progress.
Let's go to the Changes page of Team Explorer.
Here you can see the Staged Changes of this merge commit.
Let's double-click the CoffeeShop.cs file,
and here you can see that a PaperCupsInStock property
was added on the master branch.
Let's go again to Team Explorer,
and let's also double-click on the CoffeeShopDataProvider.cs file.
Here you can see that the new PaperCupsInStock
property is also filled with data.
Now let's close this again, and let's go back to Team Explorer.
Now to do this merge, you would enter here a commit message,
Merge latest changes from master.
And then you commit and you have actually the merge commit.
But instead of doing this,
let's click here Abort to undo all the changes from the merge.
And let's remove that message here.
Now let's go back to the Branches page.
Instead of doing a merge here, let's click, this time, on Rebase.
Now you can rebase here the current branch
feature/coffeeShopCommands onto another branch.
We want to rebase our feature branch onto master.
Let's click now on Rebase, and you can see here, it will replay all the commits.
Now the rebase was done.
Let's go to the Changes page.
We don't have any changes.
Visual Studio automatically replayed the commits, and there were no conflicts.
If we would have had conflicts,
we would have seen a message like when we get conflicts with a merge.
In a rebase, you solve the conflicts in the same way like in a merge.
So now let's click here on the branch again to go back to the Branches page.
Now let's right-click on this coffeeShopCommands branch,
and let's take a look at the history.
You can see now, it looks like our two commits,
Handle coffee shop commands and Introduce command handlers happened after
Julia has implemented her PaperCupsInStock feature,
but in fact, we did these two commits before,
but now these are new commits with new commit IDs.
The rebase just took this current commit from the master branch and it
replayed our two commits from the feature branch on top of it.
This leads to a very clean structure here in our branch.
And we don't have the merge commit.
Now let's go to the Synchronization page to push our
changes to the remote repository.
So let's go to Team Explorer and let's select here Sync.
You can see, we are on our feature/coffeeShopCommands branch.
We have four outgoing commits,
the two commits from Julia and our two commits to handle the coffee
shop commands and to introduce the command handlers.
Then there are two incoming commits,
Handle coffee shop commands and Introduce command handlers.
This might be a bit confusing, but what happened?
We have pushed these two commits already to the remote repository,
and now we repeated them as part of a rebase so they got
new commit IDs in our local repository.
So they are different commits than the two commits that
you see here from the remote repository.
Let's double-click, for example,
this Introduce command handlers commit from the remote repository.
Here you can see the commit ID 5098, and so on.
Now let's go back,
and let's double-click the Introduce command handlers
commit from our local repository.
Here you can see the commit ID 1f25, and so on.
So it's a different commit.
Now what you want to do in this case, if you have already pushed commit,
you want to overwrite the commits in the remote repository
with the commits that you have locally.
And to do this, you need to do a force push.
So let's just click here on Push, and let's see what happens.
As you can see in the Output window, we got an error.
Updates were rejected because the tip of your current
branch is behind its remote counterpart.
What you can do now is a force push,
but you have to explicitly turn this on in the settings.
So let's go to the Settings, let's click here on Global Settings,
and let's check here this option Enable push-force.
And let's click on Update.
Now let's go back to the Synchronization page.
Now you can force to push these four commits to the remote
repository and to overwrite these two commits.
But if you do such a force push,
you should inform other developers that might work on that branch.
Because imagine they could have these two commits already locally,
and they build up on these two commits,
and now you just overwrite them with your local commits.
This can lead to ugly side effects on their sides.
But in this case,
Thomas is the only developer on that feature/coffeeShopCommands branch,
so it's fine to force push these four commits to the remote
repository and to overwrite these two commits.
Let's do this now and let's click here on Push.
Now you can see the same message that we just saw in the Output window.
This branch is behind its remote counterpart.
Visual Studio says it cannot be pushed without forcing the operation.
Would you like to overwrite the remote commits?
Yes, actually, we want to overwrite these two commits with these four commits.
So let's do the force push.
Let's click here on Yes.
Now the changes were successfully pushed to the remote
feature/coffeeShopCommands branch.
Now let's just go back to the Settings page.
Let's go to the Global Settings,
and let's uncheck this Enable push-force setting again.
All right, so now we pushed, actually,
this structure to our remote feature/coffeeShopCommands branch.
It includes the commits from Julia, and she can review this branch,
and she can merge it then to master,
but if we want that Julia matches that branch to master,
we can send her out a pull request.
You will learn how to do this in the next module. Now let's wrap up what you have learned in this module.