Great, so, we understood what NodeJS is.
It's the language running on the server.
Now, Angular 2, as you probably are aware,
is its counterpart running in the browser.
The job of Angular 2, therefore,
is to create a great user experience
because as it runs in the browser, it's able
to provide very reactive user experience.
We don't need to send a request and wait for a response.
Everything happens instantly.
So, when we have our client-server setup,
then Angular 2 is responsible for the client part.
Here it is also written in JavaScript in the end.
Though, we will use TypeScript, which kind
of is the official language used for Angular 2 applications.
TypeScript is just a superset to JavaScript,
which means it adds some additional syntax.
It makes the JavaScript syntax a bit nicer.
It adds some extra checks and some extra features,
but in the end we will have a bold process
which compiles our Angular 2 TypeScript code
to plain, to vanilla JavaScript code
because that is what runs in the browser in the end.
So, our Angular 2 app, therefore, allows us
to run on a single page and it updates parts
of the page which need updating.
We're creating a single-page application,
therefore, it updates the DOMs, so to re-render parts
of the page that need to be updated as a chess set.
It also handles our routing.
We won't use NodeJS.
We won't use our server for the routing.
Instead, we want to route in our front-end application,
again, to load things faster.
So, we will set up some server-side routes too,
as you will see, but only for Angular 2
to reach out to them in the back end.
But we'll come back to this.
And, in the end, it provides
with all of that a very reactive user experience,
which is why it's so great.