Time to get started.
Throughout this course, we will be build an overarching
project, and in this video,
I will show you how to set up this project,
how to start with the seed project I'm supplying.
Again side note, you will find the whole course module
where I explain how to build this seed project,
and with that, let's first understand what we need
to successfully create our Angular 2
and Node.js application.
Well, first of all, we obviously need Node,
because this will run on the server.
This runs our server.
This is our server-side code.
So we need to instal Node.js on our computer
to successfully test on our local environment.
We will also need the seed project
which you can find attached to this lecture,
so feel free to download it now.
Thereafter, in the extracted file in this folder,
we need to run a command to instal the dependencies.
We've got both server-side dependencies like Express.js
and client-side dependencies like Angular 2.
So that's the theory.
Let's see all these steps in action.
Let's start by downloading Node.js.
The place to go is nodejs.org, and here make sure
to pick the latest version, 6.7 at the point of time
I record this video.
Don't take the lower one.
This will not work correctly, so make sure to download
this latest version, and after downloading it,
simply walk through the installer
and instal it on your machine.
It's really straightforward.
If for some reason, you're downloading the version
for the wrong operating system here,
normally it should autodetect the system,
make sure to go to Downloads
and pick the exact version you need.
After doing this and running for installer,
Node.js is set up your machine and with that you're prepared
to write Node.js code.
We not only need Node.js code,
we also need our whole project, our front-end code.
For that, download the seed project attached
to this video and then extract it.
I already did this here.
I will walk you through all these folders and files
in the next video.
For now, let's start it
and let's see something on the screen.
On the right, I opened up a terminal,
or command line on Windows,
and make sure to navigate into this seed-project folder
or to whatever you renamed it in there.
Now in this folder, you need to run npm instal.
Npm stands for Node Package Manager,
and this is a command line tool which was installed
with Node.js together.
This allows us to manage the dependencies of our package
here and we conveniently don't have to download them
one by one from several webpages, therefore,
that's all done automatically for us.
So run this command, and this will take a couple of seconds
because we've got quite a lot of different dependencies
to fetch here.
And be aware that warnings like this one here
are totally fine.
I'll see you once it is finished.
With that installation finished, you may see some warnings
here, but as long as no error occurred,
that means it will work, everything is fine.
This created this new node_modules folder on the left
which holds the dependencies.
Now in order to see something,
let's run npm and then run build.
This runs one of the scripts I set up in this seed project
and this script will run the build process
taking all our Angular 2 code, compiling it
from TypeScript to JavaScript, and bundling it together.
Again I will come back to the folder structure
we're using in the next video.
So hit Enter, and this might now take a couple of seconds,
and thereafter it will keep running.
And this is important, keep this process running
because it will watch your files for changes
and automatically rerun and recompile
whenever you do change one of your TypeScript files.
This is great because it means you don't have
to continuously rerun this process.
It's not all though.
Open up a new window in the terminal,
and navigate in the same folder, in the seed-project folder,
and there run npm start.
This will start the server-side code.
Npm run build was responsible for the front-end code
and watching for changes.
Npm start now runs our Node.js server,
the little server I already set up in the seed project.
So hit Enter and this will start the server.
And with that back in the browser, you may now visit
localhost:3000 and you should see Hello World here
which means it works.
This is Angular 2 what you're seeing here.
In the next module, we will start working on Node.js
though, but we'll come back to Angular 2
and also change this app soon.