In the last video, we created
our C project and we started it.
We now see "Hello World!"
Let's now understand where this "Hello World!"
comes from and which files and
folders we have in this C project.
For that, I opened up the project in WebStorm,
which is the IDE I'm using throughout the course.
You're of course free to use any IDE
or editor of your choice, for example,
Atom, Sublime, Visual Studio Code,
whatever you prefer for your Node.js
and/or Angular 2 development.
So, this is the folder structure.
What you're not seeing here is the
node modules folder, because my IDE hides it,
since we shouldn't work in that folder,
it keeps all the dependencies which are managed for us.
So we shouldn't change anything there,
which is why my IDE doesn't show it.
All the other files and folders
are the same, you should see them.
Now, what do we have here?
We've got the assets folder, which has an app folder,
and this holds our Angular 2 app.
If you're aware how an Angular 2 app works,
you might already recognise all these files inside there.
I will explain how to work with them
in the Angular 2 module in this course.
The short version right now is,
we build our Angular 2 app with components,
and right now we've got one component,
the app component here.
In the app component here, we basically
set up which HTML code should get rendered
whenever we load this component.
And here is happens to be stored in
app.component.html, which is this file,
where we have this "Hello World!" we were seeing.
Therefore, if we change this to "Changed it!"
and hit Ctrl+S, this will automatically hit our
or rerun our compile process, since it is watching.
Hence, if we reload here, we see "Changed it!"
So this is how we change our app here,
but I will come back to the Angular 2 part
in the Angular 2 module.
The important thing to keep in mind right now is
that in the assets app folder,
we've got our frontend application,
the Angular 2 application.
All the other folders here are service side folders.
The bin folder here holds our Node.js server.
And I'll go through how our request
travels through our application
in the next module, in the Node.js module.
Generally, here, we set up the server,
because with Node.js, it's not like with PHP
that we write some code and then have
a server like Apache running our code,
but instead we create the server itself with Node.js.
And this is done in this www file here,
where we basically set up to which port
you want to listen and then start the server.
The public folder holds in the JavaScript folder
our bundled Angular 2 application,
because in the assets folder, we created,
but we didn't serve it from the server,
we need to load it here initially.
And there, it lives in this bundle.js,
which is created automatically, so don't change
anything in this JavaScript app folder here.
The stylesheets folder holds the style.css,
which basically has some basic styling
we'll use throughout the course.
In the routes folder here, this is the app.js file.
This is the only route I have
registered on the server thus far.
And this is the main route when we
visit just local host/nothing.
Here we will render 'index' and render
refers to this index.hbs view.
.hbs is a file extension, because here
we're using Handlebars as a templating engine,
which basically means it allows us to output,
or it allows us to use templates on the server
if we want to build our HTML code on the server,
which we won't do in the course,
so it doesn't really matter.
But this is where the file extension comes from.
This is the index.hbs file, which gets
rendered by this res.render function.
So, it's the one and only file which gets sent
from the server to the client, and therefore,
we should expect this file to hold our Angular 2 app,
or to start our Angular 2 app.
This is exactly what it does.
Here, we've gotta import through
Bootstrap to get some basic styling,
and then we got our own style.css import.
But then we got this my-app thing here,
which clearly is not a default HTML element.
Indeed, it is the component we build with Angular 2.
And thereafter we get this script import at the bottom,
which will import our bundle, which includes
our own code, the Angular 2 framework, the dependencies,
the polyfills Angular 2 needs, and so on.
So this bundle.js holds our whole Angular 2 app,
and therefore starts this app as well,
and leads to what we actually see on the page,
which is not "Loading..."
but "Changed it!" in this case.
Well, in all the other files here, app.js is important.
This is the main file starting
our express jsf on the server.
Each request reaching our server
is funnelled through this file here,
where a couple of methods are applied to the request,
some data is extracted, some headers are set.
And very importantly, then, it's
dispatched to the right route.
This app is here, where we forward the request
reaching local host/anything to appRoutes,
which actually is reference to
the app.js file under routes folder.
Again, I will come back to this detailed
request flow in the next module.
All the other files here, these are just config
files for the C project, for the build process.
And I will come to them in detail in the
Build Your Own C Project module,
if you're interested in that.
Typically, you don't need to change anything here.
The most important file to mention is
the package.json file, which manages all the production
and development dependencies of our project.
Quite a lot, as you can see, but as you can see,
Angular 2 alone has this structure where
the code is split over multiple files,
so this is why this is very long.
And yet, this is managed automatically by NPM,
this package manager in the node module folder.
Up here, you see the scripts.
We already used start and build to,
for one, with build, start our frontend
asset compilation and create this bundle.
And with start, to start our node sever,
living in the bin folder in the www file.
This is the general setup of this folder
structure we're using throughout the course.
Again, have a look at the detailed
Build Your Own Project module to learn more about that.
With that, I'd say let's jump into the
next course module and dive a little bit
deeper into the server side world with Node.js.