I explained how to set up
routes, for example, and get the post route.
Now there's more than just get and post,
especially when creating an Angular
to a Node.js application, we're not
limited to the get and post routes,
the browser typically is able to send
through a form or through a link.
We can use more HTTP words and methods
which better describe the nature of our request.
So we of course got the get request
whenever we wanna get a resource,
and this is how you should use it.
Use this type of request if you want to get a resource.
You will see all these methods
or the usage of these methods
throughout the course, of course.
Post should be chosen if you want to
send some data to the server to store there.
So if you want to create a resource on the server.
Patch would be a request you use
if you want to change an existing
resource on the server, whereas put would be
a request method you use if you want to
replace an existing resource on the server,
so entirely replace it.
A delete request is typically sent
if you want to delete a resource,
and there are a couple of other requests.
The requests I listed here are the
most important ones and the ones
you will use most often.
In this course you will learn how to both
send different types of requests from Angular 2,
it's really easy, and how to handle them.
Well, handling them on Node.js is,
as you already saw it, use the express router
and then for each of these methods,
you've got an appropriate method in Node.js.
So we use router get for a get request,
router post for a post request.
I guess you can figure out what we would use
for a patch request.
These are the HTTP requests we typically will use,
and again you will see the usage throughout this course.