Before you can really do well on LinkedIn,
you need to have a clear idea of what service you provide
and the type of clients that would benefit most from that service.
To use myself as an example,
I'm a front-end web developer who specializes in Shopify theme development.
The audience I serve are mostly busy agency owners who need
a reliable and efficient freelancer to whom they can
outsource their Shopify front-end web development work to.
See how I know exactly what I do and who I serve.
This is the kind of clarity required to be able to reach out to companies
directly and also it's going to help with
marketing your services and getting referrals as well.
On LinkedIn, it's very important to be seen as a specialist.
Not only is it easier to position yourself as an expert when you have a singular focus,
it also adds legitimacy to any outreach you do to connect with and attract new clients.
Later in this class, we will look at
just how simple outreach on LinkedIn can be when you have
a clear idea of the service you provide and the exact audience you serve.
But for now, I want to talk about how you can
actually go about finding your niche and for that,
I'm going to share my own story of how I landed on
my current niche of doing a Shopify theme development for agencies.