Now that you're clear on the service you provide and the
targeted audience to which you think would benefit most from your service,
we need to update your profile to align with your target audience.
I call this creating a targeted profile.
The idea here is not to max out your profile with tons of portfolio items,
experience, and education, instead,
we want to create a profile which will position us as
the ideal person to provide our specialized service to our targeted audience.
In this part of the video,
I want to take you through a few examples of targeted profiles on LinkedIn.
Let's start with my own profile here,
and by no means am I saying that I have the perfect profile on LinkedIn,
probably far from it,
not a copywriter by trade,
so I'm sure I could word some things on his profile better.
But the main thing I feel like I'm doing well at is having a clear headline,
and my headline is targeted;
it tells the person looking at my profile what I do and the exact clients I serve.
If a digital agency were to look at this profile,
they would see them listed and they would see that this is what I help with.
If they want more clarification,
they can go down here and learn a bit more about me.
I think the main thing with your LinkedIn profile that you want to get
right is your profile photo and your headline here,
everything else should be aligned with what you do and who you provide that service to,
as I keep harping on in this class about,
but that's really the core principle that's going to follow us through this whole class.
Obviously, the profile photo looks pretty good,
it's a professional photo that I did pay a photographer to do,
but you don't necessarily have to have
a professional photographer take a headshot of you,
you just want to make sure that the lighting is good,
you're smiling, you look approachable but professional,
and that you're centered well in the photo.
I'm sure there's a lot of information you can learn online about taking a good photo,
I'm not going to spend too long on that,
but use your common sense here,
you want a photo that presents you as a professional.
Up here, you can see the space for the cover image,
and I have this cool image of me presenting on stage.
This is a good one to show some authority,
but it's not particularly relevant to what I'm providing services about now.
I actually did a speech on how I got started on YouTube, but of course,
the person looking at this profile doesn't necessarily know that,
so I think it's a nice touch or maybe adds a bit of authority to my profile.
Of course, there's other areas of your profile that you'll want to do well at.
Your bio obviously, you just want to make sure that it's
communicating exactly what you do and who you serve,
and possibly, the story of how you came upon that,
or going into more detail about what you do for clients.
Definitely, I could probably do better than this,
but it's ticking all the boxes I feel for now and
it makes sense as to how I got into Shopify theme development.
Here you can see I've featured some of the content I've created,
and this content has done quite well on YouTube and Skillshare,
so I made sure to note that here,
it's one of the top Skillshare classes on
Shopify theme development definitely in the last year or so that anyone has created.
Also on YouTube, I've created a bunch of
Shopify theme development content that ranks pretty well.
This is authority building if you have any good content,
maybe it's an article on your website,
even so, that when people click on it,
they go to your website,
if you have anything that feature here, definitely do so.
Obviously, you're going to want to list your experience here.
I wouldn't get too caught up on listing tons and tons of experience,
just anything that's relevant.
It doesn't have to be a lot of entries as we'll soon see in a different example,
but just make sure anything that's relevant like, for instance,
this job where I first got into Shopify theme development,
definitely relevant, definitely want to include it,
so anything that's particularly relevant,
I could even get rid of this one here,
but again, don't try and fill up.
I used to have a lot more experience listed here,
I should probably even remove this one because it's irrelevant to what I do now,
I used to have all sorts of internships in accounting and finance in here,
just remove them if they're not relevant to the service that you're providing.
Also here you got an opportunity to list education,
depending on what your service is,
you might require education.
I'm sure if you were providing legal services, for instance,
you would want to list your law degree obviously, but any certifications,
trainings you've done that are relevant to what you do,
I think with the exception of a university degree,
you'll probably want to remove anything that's irrelevant.
Again, here I can probably remove some
of my school experience here and my study abroad experience,
I'll probably clean that up in future.
I need to follow my own advice here and cut out some of this profile but again,
I don't think it's hurting me too much and if we go down here,
you can see skills and endorsements.
If you can get endorsements for the service you provide,
great, definitely not going to hurt your profile either.
If you can get recommendations for what you do,
that is probably more powerful than having some
on click and say that you have skills in a particular area.
Down here, accomplishments, interests, yeah,
not very important, the rest of the stuff down the bottom of the profile.
You want make sure that you're optimizing from top to bottom.
The main thing you want to get right on your profile is the first impression where
you're communicating what it is you do and who you serve,
anything else is just authority building,
so everything that I put here in terms of experience or featured content,
it's just adding authority to this core message,
but the core message is important,
you want to know who you serve and what you do for them so that when
the person who's in your target market or target audience looks at your profile,
they know that you are the ideal person to help them with their needs.
Let's look at some other profiles quickly and then we'll move on to the next lesson.
I want to show you a friend of mine who does content removal,
I was recently on his podcast.
What I like about his profile is he's using the cover photo here for
a banner and he is clearly communicating what he does and the benefits of what he does.
He does content removal,
so it's clear what he does here.
Brands is a little bit broad,
but I think content removal is so niche that he doesn't really have to
go and niche any further because what he does is already quite niche.
I guess I would improve the head-shot by not having shadow on one side of the face,
but it's definitely a clear shot,
well-aligned with a smile,
he looks approachable, so not a bad top part here.
Here you can see in his bio,
he's got some sales points here
and some testimonials that might be something you would want to do as well.
As you can see here,
not much listed in experience,
education, and licenses, and certifications,
so only the things that are relevant,
and in this case,
he started his content removal business seven years ago,
and he has only that experience listed on his profile.
You might have all this experience from an unrelated field,
you can simply remove it,
you don't necessarily need it on your profile.
Skills and endorsements, he could do better at that but I
see here he's had three recommendations received,
so that's pretty good,
that's probably above average.
But yeah, the main thing is this part up here,
it's clear what he does and who he serves.
Another person, final example,
I'll leave you guys on, my friend Kathleen.
She does international tax advisory.
She probably doesn't need to put this in her title,
but it's clear who she helps,
digital nomads, global startups,
and what she does for them is deal with international tax and corporate issues.
Definitely, I think there's a lot she can improve with this profile in terms of having
a cover photo here and maybe fleshing out her bio a little bit.
Yeah, she's got some good experience from a local university here,
but the main thing I want to get across about her profile is that
she's clear on who she serves and what she does for them.
She could probably be a bit more clearer on
how she helps with international tax and corporate issues,
but I'm sure what she does is quite broad within that and I'm
sure international tax is quite a niche subject within itself.
You want to use your own knowledge of your industry to figure out how niche you are.
In my own example,
if I was just a web developer helping people build websites,
I know for sure that that is just too broad,
so knowing what I know about my industry,
I know I've niched down to the right level or to a good level.
You need to use your own discretion here and figure out whether you're niched enough,
it's going to be different from industry to industry,
but I hope these examples have shared what I'm talking
about when I say a targeted profile.
Again, I've got some stuff to improve of my own profile,
probably need to cut out a few things that are
irrelevant to the service I currently provide,
so I've got a bit of work to do myself,
but the core principle,
as always, is communicating what you do and who you provide that service to