Now that you've set up a target profile,
you might get the occasional view from a prospective client or recruiter,
as you're now more optimized to show up when
these people are actually searching for someone like you.
However, in order to increase the reach of your profile,
therefore increasing the chances that it's found by the right people,
you'll want to promote your profile through inbound and/or outbound marketing.
On LinkedIn, the main ways we can do these are by, one,
creating content, two, engaging with other people's posts on the news feed,
three, making sure to connect online with new people we might meet in real life,
and, four, outreaching to new connections through LinkedIn itself.
Let's discuss the main ways you can market yourself on LinkedIn in the next few videos.