In this lesson, let's talk about outreach.
At this stage, we should know exactly what service we
provide and to whom we provide it to.
We've set up a targeted profile that clearly communicates
this message and maybe we've created some content as well.
Given that you now know exactly who you serve,
you can reach out to these clients directly.
Now there's a few ways you can do this,
and it's going to depend on what your service is,
if you're selling high ticket consulting services, for instance,
you're going to take a different approach to say me,
who's offering web development support to agencies.
Having never sold high ticket consulting via LinkedIn before I'm
going to divert to industry expert Natasha Vilaseca here.
Natasha's E triple C method starts by;
One, engaging with the prospects content.
Two, sending a connection requests with a personalized note.
Three, starting a conversation with
the prospects when they accept your connection request,
explaining to them what it is you do and
see if your services would be a good fit for them.
Then getting a prospect on the call to discuss further if it
seems a good match or if not asking for a referral.
Finally, once you get the client on the phone,
running them through your sales script and closing the deal.
This is an example of an approach you might
take for selling a consulting package or any kind of
logic to deal with a prospective client needs to make a significant upfront commitment.
For me, I take a much simpler approach instead of going
through a process of warming up the client by engaging with their content,
waiting until day aware of me before making a connection,
I often just reach out to them directly with a simple message like this.
In the bonus lesson, I'll show you how
this one message landed me over 200 hours of freelance work.
But for now I want to stress a few key elements of this outreach message.
Number 1, this message is not at all salesy,
that's not to say you shouldn't ever be salesy,
but in this case there's really no need to be.
Notice how I'm simply putting it out there in
this message and then I'm not pushing for the sale.
Number 2, it's clear why I'm messaging this person specifically.
If the prospective client reads the message and
doesn't see how this message is relevant to them,
then you're going to look like a spammer.
Instead, notice how I make the connection
between what I do and what they do by referring to
the fact that the agency has
a Shopify Plus partner agency having done the exact same service for a different company,
I'm confident that my service is going to be
highly relevant to what they do in their business.
Now, I'm not saying that my message is
perfect and that we should all copy it word for word.
But I do want to stress that you definitely don't want to spam people on LinkedIn.
If you ignore my advice here and just start direct messaging prospects at random,
this can actually hurt your reputation and reflects badly on your profile.
So please always be targeted with your approach,
don't be pushy and makes sure to message only those prospects who are
clearly an ideal fit for the service you provide, agreed?
All right. Now that we've established some principles for outreach on LinkedIn,
let's look at the mechanics of messaging on LinkedIn.
Now, messaging on LinkedIn is a little bit of a weird thing as well.
There's a few things that can happen when you click message and the message button is in
a different place depending on how connected you
are with the person's profile you're looking at.
For instance, if I go to my friend Kathleen profile here,
she's a first connection and if I click "Message" is just going
to open up the chat box directly and I can send her a message,
there's no issues there.
But say for instance,
I looked at somebody who's outside my network,
maybe their second connection here,
the button for message is not going to be there.
Instead there's gonna be a button for connect and then I
can move over here to more and click "Message."
Notice that when I click ''Message'' though,
I'm taken over to sales Navigator,
where I have 60 credits for which to contact somebody.
On LinkedIn, they don't just let you message anyone and everyone,
you often will have to use up credits or jump through some hoops.
In my case, I had to sign up to Sales Navigator in order to message some people.
Sales Navigator is a subscription per month,
I think for me it's a $100 Australian a month,
so that's in my currency, not very cheap.
But the idea of this sales navigated tool is it helps you to
generate sales using LinkedIn's extensive database of connections.
From a business perspective,
it makes sense a $100 a month,
but for a lot of you guys out there,
I know that's probably going to be a bit too expensive.
I'm sure that there's some people on LinkedIn that you can message,
it's not everyone I hit the ''Message'' button
for on LinkedIn that force me to use Sales Navigator.
Not sure if I could find some other examples here of other people that I can click on,
for instance, if I click on this girl here,
she's a third connection.
If I click ''Message''.
Yeah, it's just going to take me to sales Navigator.
Sales Navigator good tool in order to be able to message anyone,
you can also create lead lists and manage your sales process.
A lot of sales people and I think recruiters use Sales Navigator,
I'm using it to contact people that are outside my network.
But I think one hack you can use to get around sales Navigator is to
try and connect with them first and then once you've connected with them,
you can probably messaged them without Sales Navigator,
so that's one thing you might do,
you might want to click here to connect.
Just make sure if you're trying to connect with them,
that you send them a personalized message,
if you don't know them,
telling them why you want to connect with them.
I get so many people try and connect with me,
but they don't write a note with it and so I just see
a random person that I've never seen before trying to connect with me,
it's not clear what they want.
I definitely recommend if you can send them a connection request with a message,
if you're going to connect with them first.
That's pretty much the way you message people on LinkedIn,
you find that profile,
you click even the message button here, or click more,
and then find it in this menu here,
then if you want to connect with them,
you can do that as well.
In my approach, which you'll see a little bit later,
I just skipped the How connection request altogether and just contact them directly.
But I do have Sales Navigator,
so that is a consideration there,
but that's about it guys,
that's how you message somebody on LinkedIn.
Now that you've sent your message, what's next?
Well, it's quite simple,
we just wait for a response.
In the bonus lesson, I'll share some of
the actual responses that I've gotten to my outreach messages.
But in general, one of three things will happen.
One, you won't receive any response,
that's fine, don't worry about it,
as long as your strategy is working on at least some prospects,
you don't need every prospect to respond.
Number 2, you'll receive a response that acknowledges your message and essentially says,
We'll get back to you if we need your help or if they have any specific questions,
they might ask you that here as well.
Then, of course, the ideal scenario,
number 3, the prospect might need your service right away,
in which case you move the conversation forward,
getting them on a phone call or moving the conversation over to email.
Either way, as long as your message is neither pushy or irrelevant,
then you should be fine to repeat this process with
as many prospects as you find within your target audience.
All right, that's it for this section of the class.
In the next bonus video,
I'll be sharing actual examples of how creating content and
doing outreach on LinkedIn has helped me to promote my service,
extend my network, and attract new leads.
I'll see you on the next video.