Hi.
This is Craig Golightly,
and welcome to Pushing a Docker Image to the Oracle
Cloud Infrastructure Registry.
We're going to review the sample application that is
provided with this course so you understand how to build a
Docker image of the sample app,
which will help you quickly see the process from start to finish.
We'll create a repository in your Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Registry,
OCIR, and push the Docker image to that repository.
This will set up everything for the next module where you will
deploy the image to your Kubernetes cluster.
Let's download the run the sample app so that you can see what to expect.
We'll build the Docker image with the app using the provided Docker file,
then run a container locally so you can see what it does before
you deploy it to your Kubernetes cluster.
The demo.zip file contains everything you'll need to create a
Docker image for the sample application.
The demo application is a Spring Boot app.
It's been packaged as a fat jar, which contains an embedded application server.
This simplifies the Docker image setup as our main focus is
how to deploy to the Kubernetes cluster.
You'll find two versions of the application.
This will allow you to see a change to the app and how
that can be updated in your cluster.
The demo.yaml will be used for the deployment,
and the Docker file will be used when we create the Docker image.
You can build the Docker images and deploy to your
Kubernetes cluster without building anything,
but I've included the source and pom file if you'd like
to modify it and rebuild it yourself.
To build the application, you can simply run mvn clean install.
Based on the pom, this will build the project and produce the fat jar.
You'll notice a new target directory.
This is where the jar file is placed by the build.
As you can see, this is a very simple rest service.
Version 1 of the application returns Hello from application and a counter.
This is purely for demo purposes to see how the requests are
handled by different instances of the application running on
different pods in Kubernetes.
Version 2 of the application says Goodbye from application,
plus the same counter.
To change the name of the jar file, simply change the value for version.
Let's start up the application so you can see what it does.
Navigate to the deploy directory, then run the version that you would like.
I'll run version 1.0 first.
The command is java -jar and the name of the jar.
With the application running, we can check port 8080 on localhost.
Here is the message from the application.
If I refresh, you can see the counter incrementing.
We'll stop version 1.0, then start version 2.0.
When I refresh,
we see that a different message is sent for this version of the application.
This will help us see when we make a change to the
application and redeploy it to the Kubernetes cluster that
the new image is indeed what is deployed.
Now that you see what the application does,
let's take a look at the Docker file.
This will simply use an open jdk as the base,
copy the jar for the demo app, and name it app.jar,
then start it up.
Let's build an image using the Docker file.
Right now I have no images on my local machine.
I'll run a Docker build.
Now we can see the image that was just built.
Note the image id, as you'll need this later.
Let's run this Docker image in a container.
We'll map port 8080, then give the image id of what we just built.
The application is up.
I'm running this on a cloud machine so I'll hit the URL, and here we can see the message from the application.