Let's walk through how to handle some common changes.
First, we'll change the number of pods in the deployment.
Next, we'll update the app and push a new Docker image to the repository.
Finally, we'll deploy that new image to the running Kubernetes cluster.
Let's edit the deployment and change the number of pods from three to six.
Under deployment spec, change the replicas from three to six,
then save and exit the file.
Now there are six pods running.
Notice the difference in age.
Three of them have just started while the other three
have been running for a while longer.
If we hit the cluster again, you can see several ones,
twos, and threes starting to appear.
These are requests that are being handled by the new pods.
The elevens, twelves, thirteens are the requests running on the older pods.
Let's say there was a change to the application.
Here we will simply change the message that is printed from Hello to Goodbye.
This change has already been built into the demo.2 .0 .jar so we can
go right to making a new Docker image with that.
Change the Docker file to copy demo- 2.0 .jar instead of demo.1 .0 .jar.
Next, build a new Docker image based on that modified Docker file.
Notice the new image id for the Docker image that was just created.
Now let's tag this with 2.0 so that we know it contains
the 2.0 version of the application.
Be sure to copy the image id so that you tag the correct image.
Here I will tag the new image with a different tag, 2.0.
Now we can push the new image up to the OCIR repository.
If we take a look at the registry on the web console,
we can see the 2.0 image has been pushed.
Now we'll change the deployment to specify that we
want the 2.0 version of the image, not the 1.0 version.
Under the spec for containers, change it from 1.0 to 2.0, save, and exit.
When we hit the application, we can see the change from Hello to Goodbye.
Notice also that the numbers restarted,
because this is a new instance of the application.
When you're done with your cluster,
there's a couple of things to clean up to avoid any ongoing charges.
When you delete the cluster,
the node pool will also go away so you won't be charged for those machines.
You can check the status of your nodes under Compute Instances
and see the different states: Terminating,
Terminated, or Running.
Once the cluster is deleted,
you'll also need to delete the VCN that was created with that cluster.
Go to Networking, Virtual Cloud Networks,
then select the VCN that was associated with the cluster that you deleted.
Click Terminate, then Terminate All.
The last item to clean up would be the repository in your registry.
Congratulations!
You can now deploy an image from your OCIR repository to your OKE cluster.
You can change the number of pods that are running in your app,
and you can update your app that is running in Kubernetes
by deploying a new image of your app. I hope you have found this valuable, and thank you for watching!