[Autogenerated] let me log in back to sage maker console
and see a live demo off automated, hyper parameter tuning.
Before we start the tuning process,
let's quickly review what we accomplished so far.
We started with downloading the data,
split the data into training on validation data sets and
uploaded them to their corresponding S3 buckets.
We created a sage maker estimator object on set hyper parameters,
and ran a training job that we saw in the previous
module on calculated the training error.
Before we start the tuning process, let's configure the tuning job.
Let's understand what a parameter ranges on how to define one.
A tuning job finds the best possible hyper parameter value by searching over
the range off hyper parameters values that you define.
There are three different ways you can define the hyper parameter ranges.
First one is categorical parameter range.
You define the different categories off hyper parameter values that you want.
The touring job to sell it next is continuous parameter range.
You specify the minimum on maximum value up.
The hyper parameter range on the tuning job will select a value
between this strange during the tuning process.
Next one is integral parameter range.
You specify the minimum on maxim hyper parameter range value as well,
but the values need to be an integer.
There are four different scaling options that the tuning job
uses while searching the range off values.
First one is auto scaling, as the name indicates.
Sage maker hyper parameter tuning two says the best scale for
the hyper parameter tuning next is linear.
The tuning job selects the value in a linear fashion,
starting from the lowest to the highest implementing in smaller intervals.
Next is log rhythmic scaling.
This killing works only for positive values.
Use logarithmic scaling when you're searching.
Arrange that spans.
A several order off magnitude on the last one is reverse blog Adamik.
This is supported only in continuous parameter range.
Only are not an integer parameter range.
It works only for ranges that are between zero and one,
and you need to choose this scaling when you're searching for a
range that is highly sensitive to small changes.
Let's switch our attention back to our example.
We're defining three continuous parameter range for E T Alfa
on minimum child way on one IntelliJ parameter range for max
depth under resource limits,
we set the maximum number of training jobs to 10 on maximum
concurrent training jobs to to this is the maximum number of
jobs that can be run simultaneously.
We're going to use Beijing search strategy in our example,
and our objective is to maximize the error you symmetric.
Let me run this code on the prints statement at the end
confirms that the cell has run successfully.
Our next step is to configure the training job and it
takes the following attributes.
First one is algorithm specification where you specify
the training image on the input more.
Next one is input data conflict where you specify the input on validation.
S3 bucket name on the content type in the output data conflict.
You need to specify the output path off your S3 bucket
under resource conflict mentioned.
The instance Count and type on the volume size.
Next section is static hyper parameters where you mentioned the values off
hyper parameters that has static values and finally,
the stopping condition where you specify the maximum
duration for each training job.
Another attribute that is occasionally used that you don't see
here is warm start conflict as we saw before.
One starting is the process where the tuning process used The results from
one are more previous tuning jobs as a starting point.
Let me run this job on we can.
See, the statement is printed successfully.
Let's start the hyper parameter tuning by passing both the tuning job
conflict on the training job definition to create hyper parameter tuning
job method on the first parameter off this app, a call is the name off the tuning job.