[Autogenerated] before we move forward and split the data for training purposes.
Let's look at some off the data splitting strategies.
This by no means is an exhaustive list.
Let's consider a business case where we would like to
understand how the new feature that we launched last year
is being received by the customer.
So in this case,
we're focused on the reviews from last year to derive meaningful information.
So for cases like these, we will use a time based splitting.
And timestamp is an important attributes on the data needs to
be sorted by time before splitting the data.
Consider the case where the data we have is very limited.
So if we split the data in a 80 20 or 70 30 ratio
for training and testing purposes, they might end up war fitting the model.
In orderto address these scenarios we use careful cross
validation splitting in careful splitting.
The entire dataset is split in to case subsets and K minus
one subset is used for training purpose on the last dataset
is used for testing purposes on.
Then the score is evaluated.
The next round at different subset is taken from the case subsets.
I'm testing this perform and this can be continued
until we test against all the subsets.
And finally,
the average of the score is calculated on the final score
is derived randomly splitting the data.
Consider the case where you don't need to maintain the order off your data.
In cases like this,
this is a very good strategy to consider in order to have a good
distribution of data between training and test data is also
recommended to shuffle the data well before splitting.
It is pseudo random number is used to randomly split the data and
this is a strategy will be using in our exercise.
I'm going to use the number I split method on split the data in the
70 30 ratio for training on validation purpose.
We're using random splitting strategy as mentioned before the output
shows the total number off rows on the columns,
both for training on validation data.
One of the data requirements off training a CSV data using XSLT bustan garden.
Is it the target variable must be present as the first column on the
CSV file must not have a header record for inference.
The algorithm assumes that CSS3 input does not have the label column.
We're dropping the last two columns that indicates if the
customer signed up to a term deposit or not.
And Perl fixing the dataset with a target column and header is removed as well.
This modified data is written to train dot CSV on
validation that CSV files respectively.
Next,
I'm going to use Border three API to upload these two files to two
separate folders trained at CSV under train folder and validation
that CSV under validation folder.
Let me run this cell and make sure that the files are successfully uploaded.
I'm going to log in back to edible is concerned on validate
If these files are uploaded successfully,
let me go to Amazon S3 dashboard.
That is a bucket by the name Globomantics that we created at the beginning
of our excise click on sage maker Demo Xcode Boost Diem.
You can see there are two folders Train on validation.
Do not worry about the output folder.
At this point, we will talk about it in the subsequent models,
click on train and you can see the CSV file that you just uploaded.
Select the file and you can also see the object you are Click on
permissions This list all the users that have access to this object
go back and click on Validation folder.
You can see validation that CSV file is being
uploaded under this folder as well.
In this module,
we started the training process by pulling the X G boost
algorithm image from the container registry.
Then we don't know that the data and prepared it
before passing to the training process.
Then you saw different data splitting strategies to split the input data for
the training and eventually uploaded them to the S3 buckets.
In the next subsequent models,
you will see how to use sage maker estimator object to train the model,
evaluate the metrics, logging to CloudWatch console on,
monitor the progress Before we wrap up this course,
you will also see how to use sage maker automated tuning
process to tune the hyper parameters on find the best training job recommended by the sage maker