[Autogenerated] now that we got good understanding on performance metrics,
let's turn our attention to sage maker notebook instance and
continue from where we left off from the last model.
We already downloaded our data,
split them and uploaded them to are S3 bucket in this module.
Let's start the actual training process.
If you have been falling along the different algorithms
that we shared in the first two modules,
this court should not look new to you.
Let's quickly go over and understand this court better.
We start with creating a sage maker session and error passing
the container object on the role object.
We're limiting the number of instances to one and error going
to train on M four extra large instance.
If we have a larger dataset, you can consider increasing the number of instances.
And if you remember from Model one,
that X G boosts training runs was only on CPU based instances only.
He created S3 Bucket to hold the output and assign it in the output path and
include the sagemaker position that we created before.
Let's look at the hyper parameters in detail.
The first value maximum depth indicates the maximum depth
off a tree higher the number complex, the model will be,
and it increases the chances off.
War fitting E.
T.
A.
Is a step size shrinkage value.
Instead of getting the weights directly at the end off each boosting,
this value actually shrinks.
The feature weights.
This value is I'll to prevent or fitting.
Next is gamma larger the value of gamma,
the more conservative the algorithm will be men.
Child weight is a minimum number of instances.
Wait needed in each node sub sample tells the ratio off
data that is used to grow the trees,
which in turn helps in preventing or fitting a silent value
of zero will print a running messages on one indicates the
algorithm will run in silent.
More Objective-C space face the learning task on the
corresponding learning Objective-C.
In our case, we indicated binary logistic,
which refers to a largest dict progression for a binary classification.
Enum round, which is a required hyper parameter,
represents a number off rounds to run the training process.
Now it is humanly impossible to get a complete understanding off all
the hyper parameters for all the built in algorithms.
And you don't need to know all these hyper parameter
values for your certification.
However, as you start the training process,
the best strategy is to select the UN garden.
First on, then you can dive deep and steady.
The hyper parameter is later, as you can see,
the court complaints off syntax error.
When I try to run, I'm going to move the parameter list in line with the object.
Looks like it is running now,
and it printed both the statements now that we created the
estimator object on set the hyper parameters.
It's called the Fit Method on past the training dataset.
To start the training process,
let me switch back to sage maker console Choose training job.
Under the training section,
there is a job at the top that is currently in in progress.
Status.
Click that it shows a creation time Last modified time on
the AM role under algorithm section,
you can see the instance count on instant Stipe value that
we passed in the estimator object being reflected here
under input data configuration,
it shows the data source under its you are IT under metrics.
It lists all the metrics that are output by this algorithm.
The hyper parameter section shows all the hyper parameters that we
said to the Xcode boost object under monitor,
there is an option to view all garden metrics and instantiate tricks.
Click on view algorithm metrics.
It takes you to CloudWatch since the training job started just now,
that is nothing to be displayed here.
I just switched back to the notebook.
You can see the instances are still getting launched under status,
Click on View History and I can see the same status being shown here as well.
Let me switch back to notebook instance,
and instances are currently getting prepared for the training process.
Once the input data is downloaded, all the 28,831 draws are being loaded.
Now the training process is started.
Under is currently under progress.
The training error during the first run is 0.100968 and as a
number of training integration increases,
you can see the error goes down on the run.
Number 96 has the lowest training error,
and after that the training error is starting to go
up from the 97th run onwards.
However, the training continues to run until it finishes 100 runs,
which is the number on hyper parameter that we initially say It took
totally 67 seconds to complete the training process.
Let me switch back to Sage Maker.
Console on the status is now completed.
Let me click on history and I can see the different
stages of the training process.
Though it took only 67 seconds only to train the data, you can see the instance.
Preparation took close to 13 minutes.
Let me click on view instantiate tricks.
Let me select CPU utilization memory utilization on disk utilization.
You can see that dots in the graph showing their corresponding values.
Let me go back and select the algorithm metrics.
Select the training error metric and you can see another point in the
graph that corresponds to the training at our value.
Let me log in back to S3 console and check if the output is stored properly.
Click on Globomantics bucket.
Choose sage maker Demo Xcode webOS Diem.
Now select the output folder.
The output off every training run is stood under its corresponding training job.
Me,
I'm going to select the sage maker Xcode boost algorithm
click on output again and can see the gzip output file has
been uploaded to this S3 bucket.
This is the same output path that we specified
while configuring a similar object.
Now that you have seen how to train a model in the next model,
you will learn about hyper parameter tuning and see a demo on automated hyper parameter tuning offered by sage maker.