Hello this is Carol from for example dot com.
And welcome to the third first tutorial on algorithmic training for beginners.
In this tutorial we're going to recap on the fourth section of our course which is called putting it
all together.
So in front of us here you can see the website where I post all these courses.
It is called w w w dot for X-posts dot com.
And now currently we're in the courses section.
So if we scroll down here to the section before putting it all together this is these are the tutorials
that we're going to quickly run through now so expert advisors are great for here we discussed the differences
between expert advisors and scripts and so we understood that expert advisers have this module which
is called on Tich which gets executed with every new tick which comes into the terminal and in that
way they were different scripts.
Then we talked about rule based decisions and algorithmic trading and we found out that there are quite
a lot of different types of rule based decisions but in this course we only looked at three main ones
which are price based decisions on time based decisions and indicator based decisions.
Next internal number 23.
We talked about strategy ideas and understood that for a new trading strategy whether it's a manual
trading strategy or training strategy for an algorithmic trading system there has to be an idea at its
core.
And given that we came up with an idea for our trading strategy which was to trade the British pound
dollar somewhere around 8:00 9:00 or 10:00 in the morning when the European session opens and in order
to capture retracement movements next we talked to we put that trading strategy idea into a trading
system and create a blueprint for that trading system.
So this was a very important tutorial because here we did a lot of ground work for our forex robot and
which simplified which significantly simplified the coding process process going from there internal
number 25 we coded the time conditions and we made sure that the algorithmic trading system opens orders
at a certain hour of the day which was 9:00 in the morning.
And also very important we created a using flags.
We created a module which checks that the system is only executing its algorithm on the very first take
of the hour when it's supposed to work.
And that helped us avoid duplication of trades.
Next we coded the green section meaning submission of orders to the market.
And finally in Toronto the 27 we coated the red section which was closing any existing orders before
opening new ones into tural 28.
We tested all forex robot and optimized it and this allowed us to get an array of really good parameters
out of which were all profitable out of them.
We chose the first set of parameters in the fourth set of parameters and we took them go further down
further on and talk course to see if we can improve them.
And we tried improving them in the next tutorial tutorial 29 where we attempted adding a moving average
filter and C and in order to cut trades and basically tell our trading algorithmic trading system when
it can trade and one cannot trade.
And finally in turn number 30 we evaluated effectiveness of the filter with default parameters and we
saw that with the default parameter the filter is not effective and it's making our system work worse
than it was.
But then we optimized the filter for a given set of parameters and we saw that by optimizing the filter
we can actually improve performance of the system.
And that that was the end of this section and I just wanted to say that it's been a very intense part
of the course and we created a whole trading strategy from scratch and we saw the this from start to
finish so all the way from a trading strategy idea we went through the coding part of the creation of
training strategy and we even tested out for ex-drug but we optimized it.
We improved it with a filter and then we optimize the filter as well.
So quite quite a big part of the course and hopefully you've had lots of takeaways which you can go
and apply to your own systems from here.
And I just wanted to show you while we are on the site that how you can get to the source code so if
you want the source code for a certain tutorial you just have to click on it and that will take you
to the page of this Tauriel where there's a quick short text summary of what we talked about.
Then there's the video which you can watch in full screen more dried on the website.
And finally the source code is underneath the video and you can always just copy paste it into your
own Mitta editor or you can look at it as you watch the video just to follow what's happening and see
the whole big picture.
And also it's very useful to have on your screen if you want to compare your code to what was quoted
in the tutorial.
So hopefully this is useful and you'll be able to access the source code if you ever need it.
And while you're on for example dotcom I would like to encourage you to subscribe to the first book
newsletter which you can do on any page of the website and the top right corner.
Enter your email address and your first name and then just click SUBSCRIBE.
And in that way you'll be able to be updated on any free tutorials that I post or any new courses that
I come up with.
I hope to see you on the next tutorial where we will just summarize the whole course and maybe I'll
give some tips on what next steps you would take from here to further improve your algorithmic trading
skills.
And until the next tutorial happy coding.