Blow this is Carol from four explode dot com and this is the third tutorial in our series of em kill
for tutorials for complete beginners.
Last time we talked about variables and types of variables and today we're going to move one step forward
and we will talk about how we can actually use these variables in operations how we can add them subtract
them divide them and so on.
So as you can see here I've already started a news group called the 3 which is you can also see on the
left the navigator.
We will start by creating a variable of type integer and it.
And we will assign a value of 10.
So this is how we did it last time and today I'm going to show you a new technique which will allow
you to save a little bit of space.
So this part of this first line is called.
But in the declaration of a parable the second part is called the initialization of a variable and kill
for actually allows you to combine the two into one line and to do that in order to do this we need
to take this equals 10 part and put it into the first line.
And that way we don't need the second line anymore.
And what this does is it first creates a variable of type a type of int and calls it a and then it assigns
a value of 10.
So now let's create another one.
There will be a value 5 and and another animal which we'll call C but we won't give it any value so
we'll just create variables.
Now what we want to do is we want to give one at a plus b and put the result into C and it's quite intuitive
how to do that and we see equals A plus B.
And at this stage this is an expression and we need to put a semicolon and turn it into a statement.
We will be using expressions like like like this.
We'll be using expressions like this.
Further on in kill for and use used for various reasons but we can just leave it here right now by itself
before a semicolon.
Because if you try to compile I get an error.
And we need to turn it into a statement and I will put a semicolon on and try compiling again as you
can see no errors or warnings.
And just like last time let's check if the program is working correctly by outputting C on our screen
the value of c on telescreen using an alert statement that's compiled that go to the terminal.
There's meditator for now will look into the scripts folder store all three.
We can either drag and drop or just double click and there we go.
So the result of IPOs be done five is 15.
OK that's that's good.
Now we'll go back to our code and for a change.
Now let's look at Double variables.
And so these are variables that can have a decimal point and say we'll call the first one bar one.
And if you get a value of two point five and double to your value of four for example and we want to
see the result of the division on one of these by the other.
So we can actually write initialized the result variable right here using bar 1 and bar 2.
And the really saved bar one divided by far too to semicolon again and then we'll add not a lurch here
resolved so let's see what that will do us.
We compile that and go to the terminal 3.
There we go.
So first alert give this teen and the second letter it gives us a point six to five which is perfect.
Now we going back to the code.
And the next step that we're going to look at it is working with string variables.
And I think that this is an important aspect of kill for because we'll be working with strings quite
a lot and mostly just to output messages for testing purposes and notification purposes.
Let's have a look at how we can use strings in a similar fashion.
So let's create a string called greeting and the value of this string has to be text and in order to
specify text we need to put two quotation marks around it a pair of quotation marks around and the text
in the sketch will be hello and a semicolon string they will call a variable or cause space.
It will put it on text which just cans one one simple spaced symbol and the last string that we want
to use say name will hold.
Will give it the value of both.
So just as we as it was with integers this is the variable and this is the value of doubles this is
the variable and this is value here.
With Strings This is the variable.
This is the value and the value is text and therefore it's in quotation marks.
Now let's see how we can add these three strings together.
We will create a string and call it message.
We won't give it any idea at this stage and he will say yes the polls reclean Plus faith plus the name.
And let's see if we can put this last
message.
All right let's compile that no errors or warnings.
Let's go to the terminal Tauriel three and here we can see Hello space ball.
That's right.
And now it's go back to the code and to finish up.
Let's do something a bit more complicated.
Let's try combining a string variable with our results.
Oh double variables or integer variables to get some sort of message.
So I'll just comment these out.
While we don't need them and instead of message being greeting Plus space placename
we will give the message the following values message equals
value.
All a is call on space and then here will say plus a semicolon and they will go with each compile.
So here we get a warning this is not an era.
It's got a yellow sign me.
It's a warning meaning that a is being converted to a string it's actually an integer but it's being
converted to a string and it's just letting us know that this is happening.
There's no problems with that here.
So just we've compiled that we'll go to the terminal and see what all three gives us a go value of eight
is 10.
All right.
So if we want to get rid of this era we have to convert a to a string ourselves and that is done in
the following way we have to type in a string and put brackets around.
We compile the error disappears and we go back to the terminal.
Same result.
It's not really necessary to do this just for peace of mind if you don't want the message the warning
to come up but otherwise if you find the warning us just a by itself is also good.
So that's basically how you can perform simple operations on variables.
And I hope you enjoyed this tutorial.
More information and tutorials are available on for export on and until next time.
But decoding.