Hello this is Carol from frigs example dot com.
And welcome to The Twenty-Seventh tutorial on ODC rhythmic training for beginners and this tutorial
we're going to continue programming our very first algorithmic trading system in the last tutorial we
got to a stage where we had already implemented all the time checks and actually created the module
that is responsible for sending orders and both buy and sell.
So here in front of you you can see the results of testing our system with the strategy tests over a
couple of days.
And as you can see all of the orders are being opened at 9:00 which is correct.
And we see both buy and sell orders but what you can also see is that sometimes there are to buy orders
at the same time or to sell orders at the same time.
So and that is something that's not prescribed by a training strategy.
Let's quickly jump back to the Paul point.
And so this is the change strategy.
This is a high level overview.
We've done the blue part when we checked the time condition and we've done the green part.
Most of the green parks have for the filters but we haven't done the red part yet.
So go into the detailed.
We have completed this completed this green part except for the Amay filters but we haven't done the
red part which is actually responsible for checking if there are any orders existing orders.
And then first closing them and then only proceeding for further to the green part where the more orders
are opened.
So today we're going to focus on this rarebit and we're going to see if any orders are opened and then
closed them first before we allow algorithm to open more.
So we will not see these situations at the end of this tutorial.
So let's go to kill four and this is our code which we will be building upon if we go back to the diagram
we can see that the bread bit comes into play right after we have changed the flag to false.
And so we will be coding over here software and deflect falls.
We will be adding a bit.
So the first part of the red bit is we need to select to order using or to select So we're going to
type that in.
We do have the ticket number already.
So it is going to is that we had we saved it over here and we're going to select by ticket as we did
in the associated tutorial.
Then we're going to need to check if the selection was successful.
For that we need a boolean variable result and we're going to assign a result the return value of order
select and then we're going to check if result is true.
If result is true if result is not true then we need not do you think and we don't even need an else
in this case because because all of the red segments of all this red segment leads into this one diamond
or all of them go this way we don't have to put an else because we can if this is not correct and we
just don't execute this bid and we let the program play out and continue working further down the code.
So we don't need an else in this case.
So if the result is true what do we do we need to check if the order close time is zero.
And if you recall from a couple of tutorials back when we talked about or to select men I mentioned
that checking the order close time is the key to finding out if an order has been closed or not kill
for.
And so if an order Clow if an orders close time is not zero then the order has been closed and we go
this way.
That means that the trader for terminal has assigned a time a close time to that order and that means
it's already closed and we don't need to do this part.
However if the order close time is actually equal to zero then we do need to close the order because
it's still open.
So we're going to go back to the code and here we're going to implement another check and the check
will be first of course we have to.
That's right.
We've already selected the order and now we're going to check we're going to check if order closed time
is equal to zero.
So if we're to close time is not equal to zero we don't need an else because we will.
That means that this part will not be executed on the program we'll just continue naturally through
to the green bit where it will send the buy and sell orders if conditions are met.
However if we're close time is equal to zero that means the order has not been closed yet and we want
to close it.
And the way we do that is we use the order close function and the ticket.
We have the ticket number lots.
So how many slots do we want to close.
Well we want to close the same amount of loss that we opened we want to close or complete and we see
here that we used the last variable to open any order.
So we're going to use the service to close that as well.
The price for a buy order it would be the bid price and for sell order it would be the ask price.
However we also know that the order is a sneaky way of finding the price really quickly by using the
order close price function and we discussed this in the tutorial about water select and force the fish
we're going to use 10.
So that's how we close our order are we going to need to implement a failsafe check which is described
here and we've done this so many times already so we just should be pretty straightforward.
Now we're going to add a new boolean variable which is result to rest two and recoiling trips to because
we already have a variable and we don't want to repeat the names of variables.
So risk 2 is equal to or to close the return value.
And then if razz two equals falls then we want to tell the trader that something is wrong and we had
we encountered an error closing order number and then we'll give him the order number at the end of
the alert.
So there we go that that should do it.
If we look back we've we have done that that that that and that we've done all of the red bit and it
was pretty pretty straightforward because we had that diagram compile no errors or warnings was to go
back to the terminal.
So we will stop this from executing.
And I'm just going to compile that again just in case.
And now we're going to execute it again but this time we should not see these scenarios.
We should always see one order at maximum.
So we're going to start play I'm going to change the properties not to show the grid but to show that
light period separators as you can see one order has already been opened.
It's a buy order and see how this plays out.
I might just switch to the line graphs it's easier to understand.
So now another order should be open because we're nearing 9:00 and as you can see the previous order
was closed then and the order was opened which is good.
And the new order is actually already closed because it reaches take profit.
So now we're going to we're going into a new day.
Let's see what happens here.
OK.
Now that order has been opened it's a sell order and now we're moving on to the end of the day that
order still hasn't been closed and we're nearing 9:00 so let's see what happens as you can see the order
was closed then and your order was opened and now the order has closed as well.
So what what we've done here is we have successfully implemented the red block which makes sure make
sure that there is only one order at any given point in time.
Let's just out of interest of course our training strategy is not completely implemented yet but because
we still have to work on this part with the MF filter but let's see what happens if we let this test
go through to the end and see what results we will get.
So as you can see there was a lot of orders.
It's been the test ran from January 2014 until mid July 2014 and there have been buy and sell orders.
And I'll just zoom in maybe a little bit and every single time the strategy has closed orders.
If you had to be open.
So that set the result was to have a look at the results so if we go into Graaff sort we can see.
So first when there's a bit of a drawdown but then it went substantially went up and then it just held
at that level so not not a bad result from $10000 that went up to somewhere around 11 and a half thousand
dollars and half a year which is pretty good.
However please bear in mind that our strategy is not completely implemented yet and we still have to
add moving averages checks and that's that's when that's when we'll be finished.
However in the next tutorial we will talk a bit more in detail about testing our strategy and in particular
we'll have.
And a short overview of how to use the strategy tester and how to quickly understand what the optimal
parameters may be and we'll be talking about that and off to that tutorial.
We will finalize our strategy by adding the moving average indicators and it we'll see how that can
actually improve the results.
So there we go.
We're nearly nearly there.
I hope you're enjoying the process.
And until next I'm happy coding.