Hello this is Carol from for example dot com.
And welcome to the 20:8 tutorial on algorithmic trading for beginners.
And in this tutorial we're going to be testing our very own algorithmic trading system.
So as you can see in front of you on your screen here we have already started testing our system a little
bit in the previous tutorial.
And these are the results that we've got so far.
So from January to July the system was tested from January to July 2000 14 and there is as you can see
there's lots and lots of trades based simply put there's a one trade per day because it just opens an
order at 9 o'clock every day at this stage.
And this is the result that we got there was like over 127 trades and from 10000 It went up to 11000
$435.
So that's that's a very good result.
There's lots of elements to this testing those results graph report Journal settings and so on.
So that's what we're going to be discussing today how to use this strategy tester but we will we will
only have a brief overview of the strategy testor because it's such a complicated beast that you need
much more than just one to Tauriel to understand it properly and how to use it to its full extent but
will cover all the basics today just so that you can also quickly understand if your strategy is were
working on or not.
So I'm just going to bring up the magnifying glass and this should help you see better what's going
on so if you look at the bottom part of my screen you can see what I'm showing like it's it's magnifying
it a little bit so you can actually read text.
So this is a strategy tester and the way to bring it up.
There's a button over here up in Ameritrade or for which toggles the strategy tester here and the first
line you need to select your system.
Now for your expert advisor for us it's going to be system simple system.
Next you need to select the currency pair and which you want to trade for us is going to be British
pound or what you can select any other currency if you like model.
No we're not going to go into too much detail about this but just probably stick to either every ticker
and control points control points that foster every tick has more quality modeling.
So we'll stick it will go of control points for now.
Then on the right here we have a period is which period of the charge you want to use and this is important
because we were developing our system for the one hour chart.
We're going to be using the H1 period spread current well.
Check check with your broker what their average spread is and you can set it here if you want or you
can just use the current spread that they have on the market optimization.
For now we'll just keep that off use date is if you want to sort of specify a range of dates within
which you want to run the test visual mode.
I recommend keeping it on because that way you will see some charts similar to this so you won't just
see the results but you will actually see where the trades were conducted on the chart.
Skip to don't worry about that if that's that's rarely used That's if you want to skip part of your
testing and view a certain day is somewhere in the middle of your test.
So then you need to also remember about these buttons or here so modify expert that opens I'm kill for
open chart.
I never use that button actually.
Simple properties.
It tells you the properties of symbols.
Same thing I don't often use as an expert property is very important but if we click export properties
here we can set certain rules around the testing.
Probably you're more
your by default your expert Eliza has this checkbox ticked.
So I'd like to ask you to take that please because this is a genetic algorithm we won't go into detail
what it is now we just need to know that we won't be using a genetic algorithm in this for X tutorials
for beginners of course because it is a bit more complex and we'll talk about it in a more advanced
course so we can check that.
Probably leave the settings at 34.
Initial deposit and the currency and lower and short and balance just.
That's that's all fine optimization.
Also we won't worry about this in this beginner's course.
And these are just more
lie they're just a bit more complicated parameters or parameters that allow you to enhance your optimization
expert advisers so inputs.
This is the main screen that you you need to work for this is where you change in preprograming as an
expert advisor for testing.
So start hour is nine at the moment.
That's what we think is the best.
Our take profits stop loss that's what we have chosen for our expanded rise.
Those are the defaults and lots as one.
So I'm just going to click OK here and I'm going to run the test as we did last time just by clicking
Start.
As you can see up here what happened is the test has run and we were going to.
This gives us pretty much the same result as previously if we're going to Graaff here we can see how
the balance changed with time results results tabel just show you details on every order was open and
how it was closed but there was a stop loss on the right side of results.
You can see how the balance is increasing with time which is good.
That means the system is making profit.
The report will tell you a lot of details about what happened.
So if you look at the bottom where the screen is magnified I'll try not to move my mouse so that you
can read some bars and test tells you how many bars there were in this we won't go through in detail
through this report we'll just go through to the main point so an initial deposit is how much money
you had originally.
Total net profit.
How much money was earned and absolute drawdown is what the maximum drawdown was and total trades how
many trades were conducted.
So there's more details on this report which you can look up on the Internet or you're welcome to look
into my other courses where we discussed this in detail.
We won't be using these at this stage.
Journal is a trading Journal of the expert and the terminal and tells us what's happening in real time.
So what we're going to do now and why we have this tutorial and this course is because I would like
to actually use the strategy tester to validate our system and how how are we going to do that.
Well let's have a look quickly if we look at the chart now the way we conduct trades.
All right well let's go back to the original chart the way we conduct trades is we always look at a
certain hour we look at 9:00 right.
We try to enter at nine o'clock and that that is something we came up with by ourselves.
But now that we have an expert adviser created we can actually use it to validate and check if that
is indeed the right time to enter.
Maybe maybe it's it's not the right time.
Maybe 10 o'clock or maybe 15 or 3:00 o'clock in the evening is the right time.
So how are we going to do that.
We're going to go into expert properties and we're going to set some optimization parameters.
So we're going to optimize start our then we're going to optimize take profit and we're going to optimize
Stop-Loss that means we're going to ask the terminal to run through a lot like many many many iterations
of this or the system and run them on the British pound dollar.
All on the same time for all on the same period of time and see which ones are best.
So we're going to optimize toward our in the period between 0 between 0 and 23 with a step of 1.
That means that we all started 0 then would go to 1 2 2 to 3 and so on into 23.
And so we'll check all those hours.
Also we'll check the take profits so we'll start with 10.
We'll go for step of 10 and we'll go up to 120.
And same thing for Stop-Loss 10 10 and 120.
So basically this gives a massive combination of parameters so there's 24 here.
There's quite quite a few.
Here is what 10 12 12 here and 12 here right.
So if you multiply multiply all of those then you'll get a massive combination of parameters and the
tester will actually check all of them for us and tell us which is the best one.
And that way we'll know which is the best our take profit and plus to say that we're not optimizing
was because lots just depends on our initial deposit and we're just going to keep it at one lot.
So I click OK then we'll take this optimization box here and then we'll just start and as you can see
something's happening there's a total of three thousand four hundred fifty six parameters looked Mazowsze
results some results.
But the most important is the optimization graph.
So and this victimization graph it's telling us on the right you can see the profit and at the bottom
is the iteration that it's gone.
It's going through.
And so yeah we just have to wait and see which is going to be the most profitable.
Let's go back to settings and we're already halfway through or nearly nearly halfway through.
And these are the results so far and as you can see this there were originally negative and there some
very negative results.
If you look on the right here I'll try not to move again so that she can fall on the magnifier.
The hour is increasing take profit and Stop-Loss a fix and then take profit increases by one and then
our increases again.
So basically just running through all possible combinations of those parameters as we set them.
And this is going to get to 120 and then Stop-Loss are going to go up to 20 and and starts again.
So that's exactly what you're seeing on the chart.
And these blue dots are every single result that of those combinations.
All right so we're nearly finished.
There we go.
So we go optimization Grof and we sort by profit we can see that the most profitable combination yielded
eight thousand dollars in six months that's nearly double of our initial $10000.
So let's set those parameters and let's see what that is.
Or we can go back here.
As you can see here on the right start hours 8 type profit is 40 and Stop-Loss is 60.
So the actual best hour was actually 8 9.
And let's see how this goes.
Right click click said input parameters.
The optimization automatically comes off.
You switch original mode back on and then you click start and there you go.
So that is your best set of parameters.
You can't really tell much from here but you can see that trades are being opened at.
I'll go down on the magnifier you can see the trades are being opened at 8:00 which is correct.
And if we go to the graph you can see a wall that is very impressive that went from 10000 to $18000
in six months.
And that that not only not only validates our system we thought it was 09:00 but it's actually 10:00.
So it's actually 8:00.
So not that big a difference so we were very close and that means that what we saw visually and we thought
was right is actually a valid pattern on the market and it can yield results on the fact that it can
really results is backed by this amazing chart.
So that's simply how you test systems here we can choose another set of parameters.
Let's take this take this one for example.
And we set parameters here and if we run it again and we look at the result the graph you see now we
have a different chart.
And this one is more gradually increasing so it doesn't have that very rapid increase at the start but
it's gradually increasing throughout the year which is great.
So that's simply how that's how you optimize your expert advises in a nutshell.
And they are more Colma.
There are there is much more to optimization.
For example like we can change this to to the surface and change the axis around and see different results
here.
And like look at look at colors and up optimize that way we can export these results to excel.
We can go here and use the genetic algorithm we can play around with these optimization parameters.
So optimization is a really fun and interesting part of algorithmic trading systems and it is actually
very important because it allows you to make the maximum of your training system and also you don't
only or you can not only optimize your own system which you can optimize commercial systems which you
buy.
So having said that I would like to encourage you to have a look at my optimization course and you can
find the Course on w w w dot for explode dot com and have a look and think if it is relevant to you
and if optimization is something that you will be using going forward and if so then I do encourage
you to consider participating in that course.
So that's all for this tutorial in the next one we will finally complete our trading system by adding
an m a moving average filter.
Until then happy coding.