[Autogenerated] previously we learned about how Docker stacks
could be used with Docker desktop to take a Docker Compose file
run a simple command and voila!
As I like to say, we can get that up and running in kubernetes.
So we're gonna take a look at a different application like I mentioned earlier,
and we're gonna take a look at that Docker Compose file.
First you get a feel for the services in it,
and then we're gonna go ahead and get it up and running and you'll
see that it's a very straightforward process,
actually.
So I have the application open.
You'll see the is code with Dan Docker services up here,
and I have a Docker Compose file Now the composed file.
Let me go ahead and close the command prompt momentarily.
We'll show you some of the services here.
So if I come on down, I have an engine X.
That's kind of my port 80.
You'll see.
And that's gonna be used to be the entry point to this web app.
It's gonna call into a Node.js services and you'll see that right here
it's on Port 80 80 so this will not be called directly.
You'll always go through the engine X reverse proxy,
and then it will forward dynamic requests to the back end.
Services like note now note is gonna depend on two things.
A mongo DB database.
So if we scroll on down, we'll see mongo here, and a red is caching server.
And so you could see that right here.
Now, optionally you could get See adviser going If you're on Linux or Mac,
I'm gonna run this want to windows, though,
so this one doesn't work so well there, So I'm gonna leave it commented out here.
Now, everything is running in this code with Dan Network,
which is a bridge type of network.
Pretty standard for Docker Compose.
All right, So to get this going, you need to follow the instructions here.
Now,
we're gonna do a production build because I would want to get this up and
running in kubernetes with some production containers.
So I'm gonna go ahead and right-click and we'll open in terminal,
and the first thing we'd have to do is apply these environment variables.
Now, if you're on Mac or Linux, you could do the export.
If you're running on windows and in PowerShell,
which I'd recommend, I show you down here how you can use the dollar E N v.
So the first thing I'd have to do is type dollar envy,
colon,
and then app environment equals and I'm going to do
instead of development production.
And then we'd set that now the next thing we have
to do is set the Docker account, which is just kind of a made up one.
But we need it and thats code with ____,
so we'll do the same thing and we'll set that,
all right?
And that's really all we need to do.
Now.
If you're new to why we're doing that, let me show you real quick.
Here.
You'll see that I have some embedded environment variable references here.
So Docker account, you'll see app environment.
And if we scroll down, you'll see these in multiple places,
and they're used to load the appropriate Docker file.
So if I come to the top in the application,
you're gonna notice,
have a Docker folder and here's where you see the different Docker files.
Let me expand this just a little,
and you'll notice that I have a development and production
for some of these various Docker files.
Well, we want to run the production version,
obviously, And that's why we set the environment to production.
Now it will automatically load that appropriate Docker
file based on the environment variable.
So if you haven't seen that before,
it's a nice way to have one Docker Compose file that
could actually be used in different ways.
All right, so now that we've looked at that,
the next thing we would have to do is come down to the
node service and remove a volume.
Now, I've already done this, but let me show you real quick.
So you see that if you're running the development version,
you can actually develop against the live code that you see on the left here,
but because we're gonna do a production build,
I don't want that.
And so I'm gonna comment that one out now,
from there we would simply run Docker Compose built,
and I've already done this, But through the magic of video,
I'll go ahead and speed it up for you.
And there we do.
It looks like our services have automatically generated
the appropriate images that we need.
So now from here,
if we just want to make sure it runs locally we can do a Docker Compose
up and then we can go ahead and try it in the browser just to make sure
that the images are working properly.
So as this is finishing up and loading Quick reminder.
So we're gonna have engine Exxon Port 80.
That will forward calls to note that would be kind of RBAC end dynamic server.
It will then call into Red is and mongo db for different types of data.
Let's run off to the browser now.
We'll try it out.
All right, So I'm gonna go to local host because it's on 80 again,
and there we do.
It looks like everything's running.
You pretty much only get a home page for the data side of it.
The rest of these will just say apps.
No page found.
But all of this is being loaded from the database and from the red is cache.
And so that kind of shows that Yep,
we can get it up and running with Docker Compose.
So now the next step is Can we get it up and running in kubernetes though?
So let's go on back to V s code.
So I'm gonna hit control C.
We'll go ahead and stop that, and then we're gonna do a Docker Compose down.
All right, so let's run that.
That would get all our containers cleaned up, and we're ready to go.
So the last part of this is the main part we now have proven that Yep.
Are Docker Compose works?
We know how to get our image is built.
We know that it loads and all the different containers are running properly.
But can we get it up and running in kubernetes?
Well, the first thing I want to do is if I'm gonna use Docker stacks,
we have to make sure that the settings are right.
So I'm gonna come on down.
Well, right-click on our way, like on hair,
and we're gonna go into settings and then on settings,
we're gonna go to Kubernetes.
And, like we showed earlier, in the course,
you need to enable kubernetes and deployed Docker
stacks to kubernetes by default.
And that way we can use this Docker stack deployed command.
They're going to see me run now.
So since that's good, we should be good to go here.
Let's go ahead and close this.
And now we're gonna come on in and run this command.
So let me go ahead and close the sidebar to give ourselves a little more room.
And now we can run Docker stack deploy.
I need to put Dash C for the composed file and because it's just named normal,
we'll just put that and then we need to give the stack of name.
I'm gonna call this code with Dan.
You can call it whatever you like, though, and we'll hit Enter.
So this should kick off the process to automatically do the conversion
behind the scenes and then get our deployments are replica sets are pods
are services all that up and running in kubernetes?
All right, there we go.
Now, what's really nice about it?
You'll see it's going to give us a status and now our pods are ready.
Now let's prove that Let's use our kubectl command and we'll do get pods.
Alright, It looks good.
We have our mongo engine NICs nodemon read us so that looks good right there.
And then let's go do kubectl get services and notice.
We have our different services and one of these is a load balancer.
So this allows us to get to Port 80 which is that engine
NICs container running in the pot.
And then finally,
let's do kubectl get all and we'll see our replica sets that
are deployments down here at the bottom.
And there we have it.
So it looks like everything's up and running now.
And that was pretty straightforward,
even though there's a few more containers involved,
a little more complexity on the services and the cluster IP s and all that.
But it handled it really nicely and notice I didn't really have
to do much at all to my Docker Compose falsy.
So let's try it out.
We'll go back to the browser, and if it's working,
I should build a hit refresh now, all right.
And there we do and we should get a are got to going to these others?
Perfect.
And it looks like we are good to go.
So all this other data is loading properly and we're
now hitting kubernetes very nice.
Now let's kind of prove that.
Let's go on back.
We'll do a clear.
And now we're gonna do a docker ACM remove and then the name of your stack.
I called it code with Dan.
Perfect.
Now let's quickly run over again and we'll do get pots.
And there you go.
It looks like everything is terminating,
so we'll give that little bit more time and everything would be cleaned up.
If we come on back,
let's see where our pods are and looks like we're almost done.
It's finishing up the note and the Mongo DB pots so there would be an
example with a little more robust application of using Docker stacks to take
that Docker Compose file and get it up and running.
So now, for the last part, let's use the composed tool and see how we can convert the Docker Compose file.