[Autogenerated] to move from Docker Compose to kubernetes with scaffold,
there's only a few commands that you need to know.
In fact, the conversion part of it is a single command.
But then I'm gonna show you some others you can use to run and
development mode and more production mode.
So the first main command that you're gonna use is called scaffold in it.
Now, normally,
if your project is configured in a certain way like it
has a Docker file that it confined, then this might be enough to get you started.
But since we're here to talk about moving from Docker Compose into kubernetes,
fortunately they have an option for that.
And we can do this scaffolding it dash dash composed file.
So that's the flag we can use and then give it the name of your
Docker Compose file Now under the covers.
What this will do is actually used the composed tool that we
covered previously in the course and convert your Docker Compose
services into the kubernetes manifest files.
So it's really doing the same thing as composed,
But I'm gonna show you there's a little more to the story
here that we're gonna circle back to now.
If you already have the kubernetes manifest files and just
want to run your containers in kubernetes.
Then you can use this flag, dash k,
and this stands for the kubernetes manifest files,
and then we can give it the path.
In my case, I called the folder dot a a s,
and then we're gonna grab all the ammo files that happened to be in that folder.
Now,
the end result of any of these three commands is a scaffold dot
YAML file and this is the file we're gonna use with some of the
other commands we're gonna cover in order to very easily get our
containers up and running.
But instead of using Docker Compose to do that,
we can actually do it within kubernetes,
either.
A local kubernetes cluster like Docker desktop,
many Cuban a Rayvon a remote one.
Now,
in addition to defining the Docker Compose file or the kubernetes
manifest files that you want to initializer this scaffold dot YAML file
with you can also use a dash cache artifact or dash a for short flag to
actually define custom build artifacts.
Now defining the kubernetes files is good,
and we could do that with the previous flags that I showed.
But You also need to tell it.
Where are the Docker files?
They're gonna be used to build the images.
They're gonna run within kubernetes as containers.
So to do that,
we can either go into the Yamil that's generated from running scaffold .NET or
when we run the command we can add this flag So he would be an example of Dash A
And they were going to say our builder is Docker.
Now they actually support several different builders.
I'll refer you to the docks on that, but we're gonna focus just on Docker here.
Now, the payload for the Docker build is gonna be our Docker file.
So notice I have this engine x dev Docker file and the name of
the images going to make is in genetics.
Jump start in this case now,
what that will do is update these scaffold dot YAML file with
information about how to actually build the image as we change the
source code files so you can do live development Now,
we can make changes to our source code scaffold automatically kicks in,
builds our image and then redeploys it into kubernetes.
And so it makes for a really nice and smooth development
workflow between source code to kubernetes Once we've used
these scaffolding Nick Command, that will give us these scaffold YAML file.
From there we can go ahead and run different types
of commands such as Scaffold Dev.
Now,
this will be used just typically on your local machine to move
these images into kubernetes pods as containers.
And then again, every time you change your code,
it can automatically rebuild that image and redeploy it.
Now there's pros and cons of that,
and there's gonna be some scenarios that you'll see coming up where
doing a live rebuild oven image might take too long.
So, for example, if you do any front and type frameworks or libraries,
maybe Angular react view things like that Well,
because they typically do in npm install and some other things along the way
to build code that might take longer than you wanna wait.
So I'm gonna show you a few tricks we can use to work around that now,
if you're not doing development and you want to run it more like a
production scenario where it just runs at once,
then you could do a scaffold run,
and this just builds and deploys the project one time and then it's done.
So for the example coming up, we're gonna focus on the Scaffold Dev Command,
and I'll show you how it actually watches for these code changes
and rebuild your images and redeploys them.
It's pretty neat how it does it,
but keep in mind that there are other commands as well.
Such a scaffold run.
There's a scaffold, debug and even more that you might end up using.
But when it comes to just moving from Docker Compose to Kubernetes,
Scaffold can make that process very easy because it uses
the composed tool again under the covers.
But it takes it a step further and can actually make it where it
deploys your images and containers into kubernetes. So let's take a look at that in action.