[Autogenerated] now that the composed tools installed we can
use it to run decomposed convert cmdlet.
We're gonna look at how to run that command,
which out of the box is extremely straightforward.
But there's several different command line flags you can use.
We're gonna talk about those as well.
So first off, to get started with compose,
you can literally go to wherever you're Docker Compose.
YAML file is and run this command composed convert and,
as mentioned in the comment above that will automatically
convert the composed XAML to the kubernetes XAML.
And your deployments and services,
and possibly some other resource is would be generated now.
From there, you'd be ready to go.
You're more than likely going to want to Look at the Yamil and maybe modify it,
but it would be that simple now.
I mentioned that there's several different flags,
though, that you can use,
and at some point you're probably going to want to know about these flags.
So to learn more about those, you can type,
composed, convert, dash, dash help or dash H a lot of these flags.
I'll show you have a shortcut and a kind of normal version, if you will.
Now,
what are some of the different flags than for converting in maybe a little more
specific way from Docker Compose XAML to kubernetes XAML.
Well, here's a few of them.
First off, cache file or dash F works.
And this is useful if your file is not called Docker Dash composed
.NET XAML and instead you called it something else.
Maybe Docker Compose dot product Yamil or something like that, for example.
Or maybe you have multiple YAML file multiple
Docker Compose files that overlay each other.
I'll talk about that a little more momentarily so that one
could be useful in that type of case.
If you've done much with Docker,
very similar to what you would do with Docker Compose if your
Docker Compose YAML file is named different from the default.
Now, if you've ever worked with Helm before,
this is a topic that's outside of the scope of this course.
But it's basically a way to get re sources into kubernetes clusters,
and the flag you can use to generate a helm chart is dash dash chart
that would automatically generate what you need there,
and then you could publish that and have somebody else use helm to install it.
Moving on if you don't want YAML file you could select JSON.
You could say dash dash JSON and said,
the ammo your going to get the equivalent JSON files
next up would be the out or dash OAuth.
Now, this one is very useful because by default,
the files it generates just get put in with your
Docker Compose YAML file I personally like to have a
dedicated kubernetes folder and like to say,
Hey, put the output in that folder Now I'm gonna show You can also use this,
though,
to put all the resource is it generates in to one Cooper Nettie XAML file.
So if you just want everything kind of stacked up in one file,
that's an option as well as it's creating the deployments.
You could say how Maney replicas each deployment should have.
So you could say cache cache replicas five three whatever it may be.
And that would automatically update the deployment to say the
number of replicas that the pods should have.
And that way, if he said five, you get five pods.
Of course, another thing you can do is,
instead of actually writing the output to a folder or file,
you could just write it to the standard out just right to the console.
And then you could pipe it somewhere else if you want it to another file.
Now, if you're gonna do that, you might as well use dash, dash out or dash.
Oh, that I talked about above, but that would certainly be an option.
Or maybe you just want to look at the animal before you
actually go to the trouble to add a file,
a folder or whatever it may be for the official kubernetes XAML.
So this would be a way to kind of test it out, see what it outputs.
And then the final one we're gonna cover here is dash dash volumes.
If you have volumes in your Docker Compose,
then it will by default use a persistent volume claim.
If, however, you'd like more scratch pad type of volume such as an empty de ir,
you want something for the no Geron a host path.
You want a config map key value pair.
Then you could specify that by saying dash dash volumes and then a space and
then put the value that you'd want empty de ir host path,
whatever it may be.
If you're new to those,
that's something that I cover in the kubernetes for
developers Core concepts course.
So go check out that module.
If you'd like more details on the difference between all those,
So that's a few of the flags.
Now there's a few others,
but these are some of the more useful flags that you're
gonna come across if you do composed, convert,
dash, cache help.
So now let's take a look at how we can actually use some of these flags,
so the one that you'll probably use the most,
at least I find myself using it the most is the dash F or dash dash file.
If you have a Docker Compose file that's named differently from the default,
which is Docker Docker Compose YAML file,
then you could say dash cache file or dash href and give it that name.
That way, if you had a prod version or a staging version or something different,
whatever it may be, then you could easily tell composed,
Go look here and don't use the default one if there is one.
Now, some people use multiple Docker Compose files,
so let's say you had one called Docker Compose one and Docker Compose,
too.
What you can do with those is overlay keys so normally what will
happen is you'll have kind of a base Docker Compose that maybe is
used across all your environments.
And then you can import in if you will and overlay other Docker Compose files.
And what will happen is the last one wins.
So if you had a key called Fu and then the second one has a key called Fu,
then the second one will win.
Whatever that fu is would overlay the first one.
What we're doing here is we're applying that concept
by using dash dash file twice.
And if the Docker Compose to file does have a key that matches one that's in the
Docker Compose one file then would simply overlay that now,
when composed, does the conversion from Docker Compose?
It would use the most up to date version of that key,
which is the one in the last file.
So that's an example of some of the different ways we can
use the dash f for the dash dash file.
Now we could also go in and do things like standard out.
We would simply put standard out here,
and that will now not write it to a file or a folder.
Instead, it'll just dump it all to the console.
Now, you can't use this with dash.
Oh, by the way or dash dash out, you have to choose one or the other.
So this would be useful for a You just want to see the
animal before you actually go to the trouble To put it on
your hard drive somewhere or B,
you're gonna take the output of this and then maybe pipe it into another file,
using the appropriate syntax for your command prompt.
Now, the normal thing I do, though, is all create a folder such as Output.
I call mine 0.8 s.
I use .NET kind of puts at the top of the folder structure.
And then K s, of course, is kubernetes.
In this case, though, I'm saying, Hey,
we want to dump all the converted kubernetes XAML files into the output folder.
Now, if that folder doesn't exist,
what will happen is it will just create a file called output.
So you need to make sure this folder is their first before you run the command.
However, if you just want to update a file, you could do that, too.
Here's an example where I just wanna dump it out to a file
called K s or KUBERNETES for short .NET XAML.
And it would automatically handle that for me.
So you kind of have a choice.
Do you want all in one file or do you want separate files?
I personally prefer separate files, but of course,
each person has different references.
And then finally, while you're doing this conversion,
it's going to generate deployments and services by default.
Although you can override that behavior 2D.
But normally that's what we want.
So how maney replicas would you want?
Well, in this case, I'm saying, Hey, when you generate the deployments,
I want three replicas for each pot that would be created with
that deployment and the Associated replica set.
So that's how we could kind of override that behavior.
This defaults to one normally, but if you want more than one,
you can go ahead and do this.
So there you have it.
That's some of the different flags you can use.
I'll show you a demonstration coming up next. We're gonna put composed, convert into action