[Autogenerated] Now that we've seen how we can move from Docker Compose
to Kubernetes with Docker stacks or the composed tool,
let's take a look at another example of using the scaffold
tool that we covered earlier in the course.
So coming on into the same project code with Dan Docker services,
we have the similar suspects here in the Docker Compose file.
I have several different services available.
We've already seen these, but we have engine next.
We have knowed we have mongo we have read is and that's all available.
But I would like to run this using the scaffold tool.
Well, the first thing I did was run scaffold in it,
and I gave it a few of the command line parameters such as dash,
dash, composed file,
and that actually was used to generate the initial scaffold .NET XAML
that you'll see here now that will output using the composed tool
again the initial Kubernetes manifest files,
but already had some up here in the .NET V8 s folder that
you see here and we've seen these earlier.
So what I did is I went into the scaffold file it generated and just
changed the manifest to move to this .NET V8 s star .NET XAML versus it
before just listed all the individual manifest file.
So I took that out.
Now the next thing I did is I could have typed the artifact
cmdlet switched cache A that we covered earlier.
But it was just a ZZ to do that here in the Yamil.
So I have four different images I need built.
I have this code with that ninja NICs Notepad with Dan Mongo and read us.
So, as we covered earlier,
all I did was set the context to my current folder because
that's where it's gonna watch for changes.
And then I gave it the path to the individual Docker files
that you'll see up top here Now that took,
you know, a few minutes to just type that and all I did again.
It was just point that up to this Docker folder that
has my different build scripts Now, once that was done,
it's pretty much ready to go.
There is one more step.
There is a secret that's used by Mongo.
It's a very simple secret for this demo,
but in a real world scenario, you would,
of course, give a better password but we need to run this kubectl create secret,
and then give it the password here that you see now I've already run this,
so we'll probably get in are when I paste and then hit.
Enter.
And yes says it already exists.
But if you're doing this for the first time, you would need to run that.
Okay, so now that we have that ready and we have the scaffold YAML file ready,
Really?
All I have to do is the Scaffold Dev Command.
I've already pre built the images to speed it up,
but normally the first time you run it, If your images aren't there,
it's gonna go into your scaffold.
XAML.
It's gonna find those Docker files and do the build,
of course, But in this case, it should be pretty quick.
So let's start it up.
And there we go.
It's already starting to deploy.
So now it's gonna deploy my replicas Here.
There we go.
There's are logging.
And once this is all booted up for the first time and mongo DB is
ready to go we can run off to the browser and hit it.
All right,
so it looks like the database has been seated and we're all good to go.
So let me run off to the browser.
Now let's go ahead and refresh.
And there we do, just like you've already seen up to this point.
It's now running in Kubernetes.
Now there's really nothing special with that,
because we've already seen how to get this writing in
kubernetes using other techniques, I could have just done kubectl apply.
And given that the path to that .NET a s folder, we would have been good to go.
But of course, Scaffold gives us more functionality,
so let's go back to the editor and take a look at that.
So let's say that I am doing some development on this project.
And in the view that shows on the home page,
this happens to be something called handlebars.
But it could be anything.
Let's say we want to change it currently.
If I scroll on down, you'll see kind of a little slogan down here.
See it, learn it, code it, notice to see it.
Well, let's say I don't know.
We want to change our slogan to don't see it and let me save.
And now watch what happens down here at the bottom, so we'll save.
All right, there we go.
Now it's rebuilding that note container, and it's already redeployed.
It was that fast because it's able to leverage the caching that's going on.
And then this will fire back up, which will take just a second.
And we should be ready to do so.
Now let's go back to the browser Here.
You go ahead and refresh here.
Now, if I scroll on down, we should see.
Don't see it.
Learn it, coded.
Okay, so it works.
So let's go back and fix that, cause I probably don't want that is my slogan.
So we'll take that back out.
And as I save, watch down the bottom again.
You're going to see that it triggers that we're gonna get a
rebuild and then it's going to redeploy.
All right, there we do in the notes.
Server started back up in the containers,
and you could see it's almost like using Docker Compose.
But we're actually going and building and running against Kubernetes.
Let's go back one more time.
We'll refresh and there we go.
Now let's see it learning coded so RBAC to normal hair.
So that's an example of what we can do with Scaffold.
You've already seen how to get started with
scaffold in it earlier in the course.
But it's definitely something that if you have a lot of services,
for example, that you're building maybe APIs or something like that,
then this works great because now I can work on that individual API,
save it,
have that image rebuilt and then automatically redeployed to Cooper Netease.
Now, if there's a bunch of services I need to run in pods,
I don't have to worry about those.
It will deploy those,
and I could just individually work on the ones that I'm interested in.
So that's another look at Scaffold and, as mentioned earlier in the course,
there are other tools out there that you could take a look at that will do similar things.