[Autogenerated] Well, that's a wrap on this course.
I appreciate you taking the time to go through the course and hope
you learned a lot about different techniques that could be used to
move from Docker Compose into kubernetes.
So, as a final review,
we talked about how we can use Docker stacks with Docker desktop
to get containers up and running and Kubernetes by simply
checking a check box and then running.
A few commands talked about commands such as Docker,
stack, deploy, Docker stack removed and others that could be used to do that.
We also discussed the composed tool and saw how it could be used to convert
from Docker Compose XAML files into kubernetes XAML files.
And we ran the composed Convert Command and discuss that
there are some other commands as well.
They could be used to work with it, too,
and finally we talked about the scaffold tool and saw how it can also
be used to convert from Docker Compose while also enabling live
development against kubernetes we can use scaffolding it to actually do
that initial conversion if we need to, and then we can define our artifacts.
That would be our path to the Docker files any files sinking.
We want to do things along those lines.
And then we could simply run Scaffold Dev to bring that environment up.
Now, as we make any code changes,
it can automatically rebuild and then redeploy those images and
get that container running in a kubernetes pot.
Are there other tools we could use for these different techniques?
Absolutely.
There's always more tools,
but these are some of the main ones out there that will help get you started.
And I hope it will really simplify your process of
moving from Docker Compose to Kubernetes.
So thanks again for making time to go through this course with me.
I hope you enjoyed it.
If you're interested in keeping up to date on changes that are made,
follow me on Twitter at Dan Wallen.
I pretty much exclusively tweet about technical type subjects.
Or you can visit code with dan dot com and see the blog there as well.
Thanks again for watching this course and please check
out my other courses on Pluralsight. Have a great rest of your day