As you may recall from our first demo, in our RestController we had a
method to retrieve all of the rides from our system.
So we had this testGetRides that would eventually get a
list of rides returned from that response.
It went end to end in our application clear to our
RideRepositoryImpl that if you scroll to the bottom of this,
you'll see that getRides method that has our hard coded array list in there.
Before we modify this, let's open up our Ride object in our model and add one
member variable and a getter and setter for it in here.
Let's add a private Integer id in here, and if we scroll down,
give ourselves some whitespace, we can right‑click and say Source,
Generate Getters and Setters, and create the getter
and setter for that id field.
We can save this.
Now let's go back to our RideRepositoryImpl and we're going to
eliminate that hard coded information in here.
And I'm just going to eliminate everything but the return statement, and
we'll say List an import and java util list of type Ride, and let's name
this rides that will match our return statement that we left there, and
we can say jdbcTemplate.query.
Now we want to add a basic query here where we can just put some standard
SQL where we can say select * from ride. And that will actually suffice
for what we want to do with this select all.
Now, we're going to bind that using that anonymous inner class
that we talked about by saying new RowMapper, Ctrl+spacebar to
import that, and give it a type of Ride.
And if you haven't used the syntax of anonymous inner class before,
it looks a little confusing at first, but it's not bad.
Start with open/close parenthesis and then open/close
curly brace and close off that line.
Now, you will get an error at this point because it's telling
you that we have to add unimplemented methods,
so I'm going to go in between those curly braces and just give myself some
whitespace to work with. So I just took that curly brace,
closing parenthesis,
semicolon down to a new line, and then I can hit Ctrl+spacebar
and it will ask for the mapRow declaration. So I can go ahead
and select that one, and you'll notice we've gotten rid of all
of our errors at this point.
If you are still seeing errors,
you've possibly missed a step. From here, I can now implement this mapRow
method, and this is just a template method pattern.
If you're not familiar with this approach,
I encourage you to go out and look at what a template method pattern is in one
of the design patterns courses out here on Pluralsight. But suffice it to say,
we can go ahead and now create our ride object,
say Ride ride = new Ride,
and we can begin filling this Ride object up with the result set that was
returned from our query. So we can say ride.setId and use an rs from the
result set .getInt and we can just give it a column name,
which this one is going to be id. We'll do the same thing for the other
member variables here. We'll say ride.setName, and we want to use an
rs.getString for the name, and this column is named name, and then we'll
do a ride.setDuration, and we'll do an rs.getInt again on this and pass
in duration. And then make sure you don't miss this last step of changing
that return null,
which it defaults to to return ride. This is all we had to do
to change this to now use our database.
A couple things are going on here.
Since this is a template method pattern,
all we have to define is our mapRow method,
which takes these items from our result set and enables us to store
them in a Ride object. Behind the scenes, it adds this to an array list
and returns that out of our query to our list of rides, and then we can
return our rides array list at the bottom of this method. Let's save
this and get out of full screen and start our server back up if yours
is stopped.
Once this starts up,
we can go ahead and go back to our RestControllerTest and go to our
testGetRides, right‑click, and say Run As, JUnit Test, and this should return
all of our lists, so our test was green, and we can see all of our rides
returned from that list of our Bobsled Trail Ride,
our Willow Trail Ride, and our Round Valley Trail Ride.
Those were the three rides that we have stored in our database.
So again, really simple.
All we had to do was go through and we added that id to our Ride
object, which was just a basic integer ID, and that's so we could
return it to our UI, and then changed our getRides from being hard
coded to use that query and RowMapper to map that object and return that list of rights.