To get started downloading the project from GitHub,
I've gone ahead and navigated in my browser to github.com.
In the previous slide I gave you a shortened URL,
and this is the place that it resides at,
github.com/bh5k/ride_tracker.
Now,
you will want to go ahead and fork this to your own
repository so you can track your changes with it,
and then from there go ahead and clone it.
So I'm going to grab the clone URL and I'm going to go ahead and go
to the GitHub client and add a new repository.
Now because I have this synced over to my repository,
it's here available for me to already clone.
If you don't, you're going to have to go ahead and enter the URL.
So I'm going to click ride_tracker and I'm going to tell us
the directory that I want this to go to.
I like to put my projects under C:\dev\workspace,
so I'm going to navigate to that,
and I'm going to go ahead and click OK. Now it has
my project all synced in there.
We can minimize this, and now I can open up the Spring STS instance. As this
loads, it's going to ask us for that C:\dev\workspace again.
And now when I come in my project, it will go ahead and be able
to import that project from my file system.
There's a bunch of different ways you can do this.
I like using the external source tool for GitHub that shows
you the changes that you have in there.
You can do this directly from inside of Spring STS, but I can now go
ahead and say Import, Existing Project into Workspace through Maven,
so an existing Maven project, and it will ask us for the root
directory. We're going to look for our C:\dev\workspace\ride_tracker,
and we'll see that it finds our POM and asks us if we want to go ahead
and import that.
We'll click Yes. As this goes through, yours may take a minute
the very first time it does this because it will have to download
some libraries and things that your Maven library and repository
hasn't been updated with.
But once you have this set up, you should have a src/main/java
directory, src/main/resources directory,
a src/test/java directory, as well as a src/main/webapp and
WEB‑INF directory for configurations. From here, we can go
ahead and create our server. Now,
all of this I have covered in previous courses in my Spring MVC course
and Spring Fundamentals course, so I'm not going through all the step
by step of it because you should be familiar with that at this point in
this course. Let's go ahead and add a new server, and I'm going to
choose a Tomcat 8 Server,
click Next, and add my ride_tracker application to this and click Finish.
From this point, our application should be ready to be deployed and ran. I
can go ahead and click the Start server button.
We can verify that everything inside of here looks good.
I'm going to make this full screen for a minute to see. I don't see any
errors in here, so it looks like it's deployed correctly. And I have
created a small test under src/test/java for this RestController. Inside of
here, this just does a basic call that's currently not connected to our
database to verify that our localhost is returning a get on our
RidesController. So it's going to go through and pull this back and pull
back any rides we have, and right now I just have some hard coded
information inside of here.
So let's go ahead and run this as a unit test.
We can just right‑click on it and say Run As and JUnit Test should
be one of the options that comes up for you.
Once I do this,
you'll go through and see that it's loading up this runtime JAR the first
time, and our output should come back green just as it did.
If this is the first time you've ran your application and it times out for
whatever reason, you may need to run this unit test again because it does
have a timeout built in there of 1 full second. And my console will show that
it returned the ride named Corner Canyon.
We'll dive into what this functionality is, but our application is
now downloaded from GitHub, imported into our local Git repo, and
imported into our application as a Maven project now. So everything
should be configured here.
Now let's set up our database and get things tied to this so we
can start building out our connection pool, as well as our first instances of our create statements.