To execute the batch functionality, I'm going to start off by
adding a column to our database table that's going to give us
something to update with our batch statement.
So I'm going to switch to our MySQL Workbench and I'm going to execute this
SQL statement to alter the table and add a ride_date column to the table
after the duration column. So I'm going to select that field and execute
the statement underneath that cursor.
You can see that it executed green down below in our log statement, but
I'm going to double check that by saying select * from ride and execute
that statement, and we can see that we have a column, ride_date, that has
all null values inside of that table.
So it added our column, but we didn't populate that with anything.
Let's switch back over to our IDE and go into our
RestControllerTest. From here, we're going to execute a
call to trigger that batch statement.
Now I will tell you that passing an array list of variables across a
RESTful call is outside the scope of this course, and we're just going to
shortcut that by grabbing our get from up above and using that to call our
URL. So let's go up and grab our getRide and take a copy of that and paste
it down below. And I'm going to call this testBatchUpdate. And from here,
we can go through and say restTemplate.getForObject, and we're not going to
store this to anything because we really don't care that it grabs an object,
we're just going to use it to call the URL batch. So I'm going to
change that URL to batch. And say that it just returns an
Object.class, and save that. So, our testBatchUpdate method looks
just like that. Very simple,
I'm going to call this URL, we really just want to get it.
We could even trigger that from just a browser call and
have it issue the statement as well.
Now we can switch over to our RideController and we're
going to create a batch request down here.
I'll grab our getRide from up above again and paste
that down below. And the same thing,
I'm going to change that URL to batch, I'm going to leave the request
method type as GET, the response body is going to just be Object because
we don't care about it, we're actually going to throw it away, and we're
going to change the name to batch and just give it an empty set of
arguments that we call in there.
Now inside of here,
I'm going to just change the body of this method to return null.
And, then we can start by implementing our service calls that we're
going to execute in our service tier.
So I want to start off by saying rideService.batch, and
we're going to now create a method inside of our service
tier that does a couple of things.
So let's save this method,
click the red X to tell it to create a method batch in type RideService.
It will add that to our interface.
Once we save this,
it will now tell us that we have a problem in our RideServiceImpl.
I can switch over to our RideServiceImpl, hit Ctrl+spacebar,
and it will ask us for a batch statement. Now is where we can
start utilizing our services tier.
Inside of here,
I am going to now create a method to retrieve a list of rides, and we're
actually going to use the method that we created up above.
So we'll say Ride rides = rideRepository.getRides.
Now this will return our list of rides for us from up above, just like we had
used to return all of the rides to our test. From here,
I'm going to create a name value pair, and this is where it
might get a little interesting for you.
So I'm going to create a list of object arrays, and I'm just
going to call this pairs, and set that equal to a new array
list. And save that. Now from here,
I'm going to execute a foreach statement, and this is going to iterate
over the Ride objects from our rides array list.
So we'll save this. Now inside of here, we're going to create a name
value pair, and the order of this does matter.
So we're going to say Object [] tmp =,
and we're just going to use the array syntax and say new Date and then
ride.getId. Close that curly brace off. And then we'll say pairs.add, and we're
going to add that object array to our array list of pairs.
Now we can call the rideRepository.updateRides, and we
have not created this method yet.
We're going to, we're going to pass our pairs into it. Now we can save this,
click the red X, and create the method updateRides in our
RideRepository. Save that, and the same thing, we will get that
red X inside of our RideRepository.
Same pattern we've been using the last two examples. From here, we can hit
Ctrl+spacebar and say updateRides, and this will add the stubbed out
functionality of our updateRides method that we're going to use the batch
functionality from our JdbcTemplate in. From here,
let's say jdbcTemplate.batchUpdate, and we're going to use the SQL of
update ride set ride_date = ? where id = ?. Again,
that PreparedStatement syntax. We're going to pass in that
pair for the array list a pair of objects into here, and
this is why that order mattered.
The first order it's looking for is the ride date and the second
order of objects it's looking for is the ID.
So that object array that's inside that array list has the right setup for
the order of those elements. From here, we're ready to save that, exit
full screen, I'm going to start up our server,
everything looks fine on the startup of our server, and I'm
going to go to our unit test, right‑click on batchUpdate, and
say Run As, JUnit Test, and once that executes on our server we
can go over to our JUnit test, everything looks good there.
I'm going to switch back to our MySQL Workbench and execute that select *
from ride again, and we'll see that all of our ride dates are now populated
with a date. Now, I get that this example may not be quite as full featured
that you may be looking for because we are just taking inside of our
RideServiceImpl and putting in a new date, but you see that you could put in
whatever value you wanted there. We could calculate a date, or if you're
using a different type of column, possibly storing some other value inside
of there. For the sake of the example, we just shoved new data in here and
you'll see that it populated our database. Pretty simple.
All we had to do was go through in our RestControllerTest and create
a call to that URL, again passing those values through the JSON
instance and to our controllers, really outside the scope of what
we're doing inside this course.
But it calls the URL inside of our controller. And you can see here
we're just going to call rideService.batch, which eventually calls
our service tier where we go through and we can see that we're going
to get all those rides back,
create our array list of temp items. Inside of that we
have an array of those temp objects,
add that, and then call our batch statement, which eventually
goes through and executes our updateRides. Now, it should be
noted that the batchUpdate will work with both updating rows,
as well as inserting rows.
So maybe you had 20 rides you wanted to insert into this database at once, you
can use the insert statement. It doesn't care, the batch update will just
execute whatever you have based off that array list of objects that you're
passing into it and execute it for each row.
The order of those elements does matter, though, as it does look for those question marks in a specific order.