Every interaction with the database inside of Spring has
the possibility to throw an exception.
Spring handles exceptions differently than you're possibly used to.
They do not use checked exceptions.
Spring rather handles everything through runtime exceptions.
Runtime exceptions are not a checked exception and
thus don't require you to catch them, but they can still be thrown by your code.
Although not specific to Spring JDBC,
but rather Spring and Spring Web Development,
we're going to use an exception handler inside of our controller to
catch any exceptions thrown by our repository tier.
An ExceptionHandler is what we use to capture exceptions that are
thrown from other tiers in our application and still return an
acceptable message to our front end.
In this code snippet we catch an exception,
but still return an HttpStatus of 200 as indicated by the OK in our response entity.