Hello and welcome to the most exciting tutorial of the section.
Indeed that's And this is oil that we're going to build our progression of and it's going to be gradient
boosting gradient boosting is one of the best options to smash a regression problem or a classification
problem.
And the reason is that it has one of the best predictive powers among all the machinery models you can
find.
Actually we say today that the two best machinery models are extra boost and deep 30 miles an extra
boost is one example of green boosting it's actually the best version of Green boosting.
But the model that will implement right now in this toile is very close to actually boost but it's not
exactly actually boost it's just the gradient boosting moral integrated inside it learn and you'll be
convinced at the end of its power green boosting is like a team of what we call weak learners that are
like decision trees you can check out these trees on the Internet or in our machinery in course gradient
boosting is a team of weak learners which together form a powerful team to predict an outcome.
And so they're trained on random samples of the training set to make predictions.
Then we choose what we call a last function which measures the error between the prediction and the
real result because we have the real result in why train and then step by step we add one week learner
or one decision tree and we update the parameters in the direction of the last reduction that is we're
trying to reduce the loss we're trying to reduce the error between the prediction and the real result.
And by doing this step by step by taking each time a random sample of the training set without replacement
we form a more and more powerful team of these weak learners which progressively become machinery moral.
With great power of prediction.
And so you're seeing this we will train our great boosting moral on the training set and then later
on actually in the next toil we will make them predict new observations which will be of course the
observations of the test.
So just a few words I want to say about graden boosting.
I'm not going to say much more because this is the section on bison but just know that gradient boosting
is one of the best options.
If there was no prior analysis of your data because you know what happens in general is that you have
your data set you have your challenge.
You study it you analyze it to see which machinery model would fit best to your specific challenge because
remember there is not one best model for every mission or challenged each machine or in challenge has
its best model.
And that's why in our machinery course we introduce a lot of machinery models resizing the strengths
and weaknesses of each model and then depending on the problem to solve or a challenge to solve.
Well you can find the best model and that's why there is I remind this model selection module to find
this best model and actually it doesn't even have to be one more all you can use what we call and assemble
learning which consist of combining several models together which again form a great team at predicting
something.
And this is the same idea on which is based grading boosting and you will see that we will import the
gradient boosting moral from a module of psyche learned that is called and symbol.
And that's because gradient boosting is this idea and then symbol of weak learners predicting the same
thing but together in a team so that the prediction is powerful.
All right.
So let's do this let's build this grid and boosting morale.
We're going to use of course sikat learn because thanks to sikat learn we can build this model in just
three lines of code.
The first line will be to import the model from this symbol module.
The second line of cool will be to get our regressors which will be an object of the brain boosting
regressive class.
I'll explain more what this means.
And then of course the third line of code will be to fit our gradient boosting repressor to our training
set.
And basically what this means is that we are training our gradient boosting repressor on the training
All right let's do this.
If you're ready let's start right now.
So as we said the first line of code is to import our graduate tomorrow.
And so again we're going to import this from somewhere which is again sikat learn but then a specific
module by sikat learn which is as we just said and assemble because it's based on this machinery technique
which is called and Simbel learning.
So symbol and from this symbol module.
Well we are going to import gradient boosting regressors.
Perfect.
That's a first step done.
So I have to explain what is exactly this graduate boosting regressors So you guess that it will of
course contain our moral the gradient boosting the aggressor.
But technically this is actually a class because Python is actually an object oriented programming language
which means that it works with classes and objects and gradient boosting aggressor is a class.
So now the question is what is a class.
A class is basically an ensemble of instructions that define something you want to create because with
objects and classes you can't actually create anything.
You can create a self-driving car we do this in our artificial intelligence course you can build a block
chain.
We do this in our Plug-In course.
And how do you build all this.
Well you have this class that defines some parameters which define which one to create.
And then inside the same class you also have a bunch of functions or more precisely what we call method
which are like tools from which you apply your object.
So for example these tools can be the self-driving car move forward go left go right go behind or break.
All right so now if I give you the example of this gradient boosting regressive class.
Well of course this is a class that defines the gradient boosting regress immoral moral and inside this
class you have all the parameters that characterized the model.
The grading boosting regress model.
Then of course you have the whole algorithm of gradient boosting the one shown in the slide before with
the six steps.
And besides you have some tools like some function some method which are for example to fit to train
your moral on some data sets.
So actually this is a good example because that's the one we're going to use in this section.
There is the fit method and the fit method is exactly used to train the machinery model to any data
set.
So basically you take your machinery model you add a dot you add the fit method and inside the fit method
you include the training set.
And that will fit.
That will train your model to the transit and I'm saying machinery model in general because you have
this same method in any machinery model inside cycle.
All right so I hope you now get to classes.
It's really important to understand what this is because it's very powerful to create as I said anything
so great in boosting regressive of class.
That's great.
We have it and now we are going to create an object of this class.
So now the question is what is an object of a class.
Well that's an instance of the class because a class defines something.
But then if you want to have the object itself there is for example the self-driving car itself or the
block chain itself or this gradient boosting regressive model itself.
Well you need to create an instance of the class and that's exactly what we're about to do.
Now we have the class.
But our model itself will be the object of this class these instance of this test.
All right.
And so let's create this model that is this object which we're going to call re aggressor regressors.
So that's an object that's also variable.
And by adding this equal here I'm going to define it as an object of the gradient boosting regressive
class.
And then you add some parenthesis and there you go.
That's all you need to create an object of this class by just basically calling the class.
All right.
Perfect.
So we have progressed.
That's a really good step done.
And now of course the final step is to train this regressors on the training set.
Remember we train it on the training set and not the whole dataset because of course we have this training
set for the training and the test set for the testing.
So let's do this let's do this final step.
You can see how it is easy and you can see how sikat learn facilitated the life of many machinery developers
and data scientists because indeed we are about to smash this training in just three simple lines of
code and that's amazing.
So now let's do this final step to train our aggressor on the training set and to do this well is simply
to take your aggressor that is your object and then apply one of these you know tools of the class.
And as I said that's the example I give you the tool of the class we're going to use is the fit method
and to use the method you need Adhir dirt and then fit and then some parenthesis.
And then of course since fit is like a function we're going to hear some arguments.
And so these arguments are very simple you can guess what they are.
Basically we simply want to train this regressive to the training set and so there simply what we have
to put is the training set.
Nothing more complicated but you have to understand that the training set actually composed of X strain
and y train because the model needs to understand the correlations between the independent variables
contained in extraneous and the dependent variable contained in y train.
And that's why we have to precise extrem in why train but that's all.
That's the only thing you must not forget in order to train to fit a machine or immoral to a training
set.
So you take first the independent variables contained in X train and the dependent variable contained
in y train.
And that's it.
Congratulations you are now ready to fit to train your regress tomorrow on the training set.
All right.
So let's do this let's select these three lines.
And here we go.
You're about to get your very first but powerful machine learning model.
And here it is.
Welcome to graden boosting.
So all you see here are just the parameters of this grading boosting class.
I didn't walk you through all these parameters because these are slightly more advanced and actually
we don't need much to tweak these parameters.
You will see will get some amazing results.
That's because the deeper values here are generally the values use.
But just be aware that there are some parameters that you can tweak in order to make your model even
more powerful but you'll see that will already have a very powerful model.
All right so congratulations.
That was your first machinery model and we really started with one of the most powerful ones.
If you want to go further in all this well I recommend two steps or two path.
First if you're drilling for your business with a variety of problems for which grain boosting would
not necessarily be the best option.
Well I recommend to check out the other machinery models including some that might be a little less
powerful than grading boosting but would provide some better results for your specific problem because
of the way it is designed.
And the other path is of course to check out and study in depth deep learning.
Because as I said at the beginning of this it's oil it is the other branch of machinery that contains
the best and the most powerful models but that's only for complex problems.
And that's definitely only for nonlinear problems if you're dealing with some classic problem not too
complicated not too complex.
Well deploying will be too much you won't actually need it and therefore the classic machinery models
will be very relevant.
All right so just keep that in mind.
And now we're going to move on to the final step which is also a very exciting step because basically
we're going to test our model that we just built.
So we'll do that in the next it's oil.
And until then enjoy the science.