Come back to the intro to today's science course I hope you enjoy this section on visualization and
how it can be used in data centers.
And today what I wanted to point out is that visualization can use can be used in many different ways.
We only use it in one specific application which is visualization for data mining.
And as you can see we could we did come up with some very interesting insights and some valuable like
recommendations we're going to make some valuable recommendations from these insights.
However it did feel very repetitive like mundane.
And we just doing the same thing same colors same type of charts.
So it wasn't like it was fun from the point of view of the insides and finding them but it wasn't really
fun from the point of view of realisation and I wanted to use this tutorial to showcase that.
It's not always like this that in data science the other side of insulation creating beautiful stunning
images and dashboards is also very important and it is possible even with tools like tabel and and beyond
of course.
And so I want to start by showing this I remember how quickly we created how just by dragging dropping
a couple of things we created a chart which talks about the distribution of our customers across different
age groups.
Well you can trade more in tabel and here if you go to my profile on Paul Tuttle pub. I've got some
examples from one of our other courses on Tablo and they talk about different problems as well.
And here's a few illustrations from there.
So for instance this visualization as a challenge in the course actually created a time I was timing
myself when I created it and took me less than five minutes to create it with.
And it shows the profitability always a store across different states in the U.S..
And so again it's all just drag and drop and you have a map of the states.
Here's a chart which illustrates long term unemployment in the U.S. between 2005 and 2015.
And long term unemployment is 27 weeks or longer and you can see how it's changed.
You can see the huge spike after the GFC after the crisis or when the crisis was under way the spike
started this trend started we can actually see that and also it's split by age groups and this type
of charter school and area charter.
Then we've got an example of a dashboard is interactive and this is showing us different things like
information about a store so you know the ability of a store is in different parts of Europe so the
profit margin is shown here in color and the sales are shown as the size and then you get the customers
and so when you click it will highlight the different customers relevant to that store and then you
can find more information about them if you like.
So that's this position.
And finally here we've got another exhiliration a dashboard or actually a storyline which we've touched
on a little bit but we didn't explore it further so a storyline is like a dashboard you can also click
around here and things will will be interactive.
The storyline has raised some pre set informational preset insights here so you can just scroll through
it and you'll see different insights that have been outlined for the person reading it so you can see
different comments about the different parts of the UK and what's going on there.
So there we go.
Hopefully this illustrates that visualization and especially Tablo are not just as boring as just getting
like repeating the same visual all the time.
All of this all of these charts were also creating Tablo it's all possible it's all drag and drop and
these don't take that long.
So you can have a lot of power in your hands not just through an analytical sense but also from a visceral
zation standpoint and creating beautiful insides with tools like tabel and there's a couple of other
tools that are available on the market as well.
So there you go.
Hope you enjoy the section and I look forward to seeing them.
Until then enjoy design's.