Hello and welcome to this new lecture and this quick to tell me all I would like to introduce you to
a great member of the team Aleksey Jack.
The reason I want to introduce you to him is that he is not only a great contributor of the torch community
but he's also a great contributor of discourse.
He's actually the one behind the virtual platform and we gave him the responsibility to prepare the
right models for you.
So not only I'm happy to introduce you to him but also I would like to thank him so much for making
this course such a great course and decided to bring so much improvement to this course.
Thanks to the virtual platform.
So Alex thank you so much.
And now I would like to take advantage of this opportunity to show you his passion and his work so you
can find Alexi actually on two Web.
First his own Web site which you can find that HTP as Cullens fleshless.
Alexis dush Jack dad kid have that.
I know.
That's his Web site.
You can find a little bit of his passion his research.
Also his publications and in his research you'll see that he's actually a Ph.D. students at the EPA.
Felt one of the best universities in the world.
He's actually doing a Ph.D. in robotics about human robot interactions so you can be convinced of his
talent and his high skills in the machine learning and robotics world.
And funny note actually before doing his Ph.D. He was actually doing the semester of research as me.
And before that we actually did the same Bachelor of mathematics.
So there we go a very similar background as mine then you can see some of his publications and then
you can also see his get her page where you will see that he is actually a very active member of the
PI torch community.
You can see actually some by torche tutorials he did for Noorul style transfer It's actually the official
by torch to toil for transfer.
You can check that from the get her page this page you can find it at H to CBS Kunstler slash.
Get to have that.
Slash Alexie hyphen Jack I highly recommend that you have a look.
He's a great programmer great machinery and scientists and also a great pedagogue.
So Carol and I were super happy to work with him.
Thank you so much again.
Check its pages and we'll see him soon very probably for a new course.