Hello and welcome to the homework of module to object detection as you can hear by the sound of my voice
I'm super excited to start this homework because in this homework we're not going to try to build a
new state of the art 20:18 computer vision moral and therefore I'm giving you this homework for three
different purposes.
First to congratulate you for passing the first half of this course.
Indeed we have done the two first modules there are three modules so we are more than halfway there.
Then the second purpose is to make sure that you know how to use the SSD model if you want to apply
it on any other video to detect any other objects.
So that's what this homework is about.
I'm going to give you a new video and I just want to make sure that you are able to use the tool we
implemented in module to to detect whether objects you would like to detect in the video.
So that's the second purpose.
And then the third purpose is to give you some inspiration some excitement for module 3 because module
3 is going to be quite huge We're going to implement a model from scratch and not any model it's one
of the most powerful models in computer vision.
That's to Gannes generally adversarial networks.
And this time we're going to implement the whole model from scratch including the training that is we're
not only going to implement the code that will do the detections and this time it's not going to be
detection it's going to be actually creation.
So you're going to start doing some real creation with computer vision but there is not only that we're
also going to implement the training implementation that is the code that will do the whole process
of the training and therefore we need to fuel ourselves with energy inspiration excitement.
That's what I do in my day to day intrapreneur ship life.
I'm always seeking for some positive energy is inspiration and therefore that's exactly what I'm giving
you with this homework.
This is going to be an exciting homework.
We're going to do some object detection on an incredibly beautiful video of some horses running in one
of my favorite places in the world not going to tell you what it is now but it's really one of the most
beautiful places in the world and actually rode the horse there.
So let's do this let's do this homework.
As you can see I am starting from scratch.
The first thing we need to do is to open Anaconda.
There we go.
Anaconda is opening.
Now we're going to connect to the virtual platform because indeed we're going to use the SSD and we
need some pre-installed packages that are all in the virtual platform.
So there we go applications on virtual platform.
Here we are inside and now we're going to launch spider.
And this will open itself in the virtual platform.
All right so now spider is opened.
We are connected to the virtual platform.
Now the next thing we need to do is to find the homework folder for module 2.
So as you might guess I put it in.
The computer vision is that for that but then in Mudgal to object detection here it is.
That's the homework folder and it contains exactly the same codes as before except the object detection
code because we will implement a new code in the Statoil.
But you're going to see that it's going to be so simple we will just have one thing to replace and I'm
sure you know exactly what we have to replace.
So that's the code the solution of the homework that we need to implement to make that detection happen.
And now I'm going to show you the video of these horses these epic horses you see.
I named this video Ebeye horses and one of the most beautiful places in the world my favorite place
in the world that I visited.
And in case you don't recognize it in the video.
This place is Monument Valley a very mythical place.
You can actually ride horses there and you can do some other stuff like just driving but it's really
really really mythical.
So I'm going to open the video now.
The video is also mythical And so here we go.
Let's start the show.
So here is the video.
It's a 10 second video.
This time I'm going to press play I hope you will hear the sound because there is a beautiful music
with these horses running.
That's Monument Valley that's one of the big rocks in Monument Valley.
There we go play.
All right.
I hope you liked it.
I really like this video.
I think this is absolutely fantastic.
I'm going to put it again.
There we go.
Fantastic.
So of course we'll will have the video.
You can watch it as many times as you want.
And so now let's do the object connection let's see what our SSD is capable of doing if it's capable
of detecting the horses inside the video.
Well this should be actually good stuff for the SSD.
We're going to try.
And therefore we're going to implement the solution.
So I'm closing this.
I have homework solution that I opened.
And so now what do you think we have to do.
Well as you understood this is a very important thing to understand this computer vision.
It is a good package is not only of course it's also a toolbox that we're giving you so that you can
very easily reproduce the codes we're implementing in the course.
So that's why I want to highlight that the only thing that we have to do right now.
And actually that's the same as what we did in module one phase detection.
Well we only need to take our code from the module to which is here let's take the non commented version
then.
Exactly.
For module one we're going to copy the whole code and then going to close this.
And then we're going to paste it here and do the required changes.
But this time it's going to be even easier than Mudgal when we only have one change to make and this
change is not even technical.
It is just the name of the video.
Of course this time we're not doing some object detection on the video of the funny dog bouncing on
the field.
We're doing some object detection and epic horses.
There is this video in the homework folder.
And and as you can see the name of the video is epic on the score horses and that's exactly what we
need to replace here.
Funded by epic horses.
And that's it.
You're ready to detect the horses in the video.
So make sure you understand this.
You have a tool that contains a model that is already pre-trained and to use this tool you just need
to take your video include all these files here that are the same files as what we had in Mudgal to
put the video inside his folder and then just change the name of the video and then you're good to go.
The only thing that you have to do is select the whole code and execute.
And there we go.
The detection is on its way and you can recognize the same process as what we saw in module 2.
It is processing each of the images of the video and on each of these images it is detecting the objects.
So remember we had we worked on a two second video with the funny dog and this time we work on a 10
seconds video the two seconds video had about 67 frames.
If I remember correctly.
So here since it's 10 seconds video it should be around multiply by five.
That is something around 300 frames to detect.
So it should go up to 300 right now.
But it's OK it's going to come fast and it should take around five minutes on this computer I have a
pretty powerful computer so it might take longer for you but definitely you will get the result in maximum
one hour.
You don't have to worry about this it's not like training as easy as we saw in the previous tutorial.
You should get the result in maximum one hour.
I don't know how powerful is your computer but mine is pretty powerful but it's ok it's not a computer
from deep mind.
But anyway we're not going to wait for the five minutes here.
I'm going to accelerate the video and I'll see you at the end for the results.
All right.
So it's about and it should be according to my calculus a little more than 300 and up.
No actually it's already over.
So it's actually less than what I expected.
But anyway we have the results and exactly as in muchall too the result is given in the output that
MP for video which was created by the writer object from Image.
All right so let's see the results now.
Unfortunately we're not going to have the music because of course it's only taking the frames and not
the audio but it's ok what matters is to see if we get some detection.
So here we go.
All right so we can see a first preview of the results.
So far it's great great start.
We can see the detections of three horses here.
There is more but at least it can recognize some horses.
And so now let's press play.
Let's see if the detection is 100 percent perfect or if there is some false positive.
That's totally possible.
And also let's see if it was able to detect the birds here which I would be very surprised because they're
really small.
So I don't think I was able to detect birds but if it was it would be impressive.
So here we go.
Let's press play and SSD.
Let's see what you get.
All right.
So interesting interesting I can see well some detection of horses but some false positives.
We're going to play back.
I saw some cows and also some dogs.
So we're going to play that again.
I don't know if you saw this two horse horse cow cow cowhorse Doug.
Horse horse horse horse horse.
Yes.
So interesting.
Interesting.
So yeah the deduction is really really good definitely but we have some false positives.
This was expected.
It's hard to have a 100 percent accurate model today especially for these kind of tasks.
So let's have a look again at the video by moving the cursor.
So here it's perfectly well to take the horses and let's move forward a little bit horse so we can detect
this horse here.
This one and this one and that's it.
Let's move forward.
And here we go with the first false positive.
It is detecting right here a cow.
But actually he's pretty right when we think about this this this kind of wool here that we see on this
horse actually looks like the one of a cow right.
When many times in the countryside in France.
I'm sure that I've seen this wool on cows before.
So you play the game to isolate this one without the context and without everything around it.
Well we even humans well myself actually could confuse it with a cow.
That's pretty interesting.
It's actually a mistake that we could accept.
And then if we move forward again I think I saw some other false positives.
Horse horse that's perfect.
Great protection here and here.
Another cow and maybe that's because you know cows or there are a lot of white cows.
And here we don't see the head of the horse and therefore it's also easily confusable with a cow.
Well it's obvious here that it's a horse but due to it's white color and due to the fact that we don't
see the head.
It seems fair that the SS did confuse that with a cow.
Then let's move forward even more.
And there we go.
Some of the false positives but this time with some dogs.
So here nothing to say.
The horses here definitely don't look like dogs.
But this was not very easy for the SS because you know this red rectangle here detecting a dog is actually
for this horse here and since this horse is hidden by this horse right here.
Well it's actually pretty hard to recognize a horse.
And besides if we have a little imagination we can style transfer it to a dog.
So that would explain but again I'm telling you this is really really hard to get a 100 percent attention
so let's move forward.
Again cow another cow here.
We first went from a horse to a dog and now from a dog to a cow.
So a lot of style transfers happening here.
And another dog here actually.
OK.
Two cows now and one dog so that's a bad result.
Here we see on this frame.
So pretty bad.
But remember in the end we get some absolutely great results.
All right let's move forward a little bit.
Nothing here nothing on this frame.
Two dogs one dog and one cow.
One cow two cows or three cows.
OK.
Pretty bad.
It's actually a sequence.
You know it's actually this sequence that is pretty bad but then it's going to get better.
And here we go again.
The SS is coming back.
It actually got tired but now it is now back in the game detecting correctly one horse and now it's
not only getting back in the game but smashing the detection detecting three horses and again one horse
and one cow one horse this beautiful horse.
It's actually great horse running sequence here.
Then two horses three dogs one dog one cow two dogs one horse one dog and then actually I think it's
making some correct predictions.
So that's the horse.
Dark Horse Doug.
Here we see three horses and one dog horse cow horse horse horse horse three horses horse horse horse
three horses again three horses so as you can see the rest is really really good horse horse.
Some horses everywhere.
Everything is great horse.
And again while you're here it's very obvious.
We can see some really clear frames of horses and actually here we can see the perfect detection of
what is happening in the frame because we have three horses in the frame and it is detecting the three
horses.
And as I told you impossible to detect the birds here way too small.
It's only for the humans so far in 2017 at some I'm speaking.
All right.
And let's move on to the end.
All right so happy ending so perfect.
I hope you like this homework.
And mostly I hope you are now inspired for the third module this course you're going to need some energy.
You're going to need some focus and I can't wait.
Implementing the Ganns with you until then.
And Joe can do revision.