Hey guys welcome back to the deploring and Chad part is that of course.
Hope you're enjoying the show so far.
And in this video we're going to have a quick walk through Africa.
I wanted to show you around what life is like here.
Now while we have this walk I also wanted to give you a quick heads up.
You did me very soon is going to ask you to leave early for this course now.
I know it can be difficult to judge the quality and value of a course this early on.
However the enemy review system has simply changed and they're asking you to leave review earlier and
earlier on in the course.
Now having said that we're not going to ask for a five star review but what we would like to ask is
that if you are not yet familiar enough with the Course to rated 5 stars then please scroll through
tutorials.
Please have a look at the different topics that recover from both the intuition and practical side of
things.
All the wonderful things that you will learn in the course and hopefully seeing that will give you the
confidence to write this course after course.
If on the other hand you feel that something is wrong with the course if you are unsatisfied about something
then before you write the course please let us know.
You can contact the superdense and support team directly or you can leave us a message in the course
Q&amp;A.
We will see if you'd like and we will get back to you or fix whatever the issue is you're seeing is
and hopefully once that is done that will give you the confidence to rate this course a five star course.
Now on that note if something is on please let us know.
But if you are satisfied about everything if you're having fun and you're looking forward to the journey
ahead then and you think that this is indeed a five star course and police raid it appropriately so
that everybody else in the world will know that this is the FISA court and they can learn about Chad
boss from this course.
Once again guys thanks so much for being part of deep learning but it is very exciting having on board
you've got a super fun and exciting journey ahead of you.
And I can't wait for you to dive into it.
And I look forward to seeing you throughout the tutorials.
Until then enjoy Chadbourne.