Hello and welcome to this new tutorial and this toile we're going to create the brain of our discriminator
now that we have the class.
But the thing is I might break the record for the fastest to toil in the world because actually we already
have everything.
There is nothing more easy to create the brain of the discriminator because basically that's exactly
the same as what we did for the brain of the generator.
We simply need to choose a new name.
We're going to call it net D.
Obviously we need to create an object of the class corresponding to the discriminator that contains
the architecture of the neural network and the void function.
And then that's the same here.
We're going to take our discriminator object and apply the weights in a function that will initialize
the weights the proper way.
And here we are done with the creation of the brain of the discriminator.
So now huge congratulations.
You created two brains.
It's now time to train them make them smart and actually make them artists because they will actually
generate some art by creating some fake images.
But you're going to see that these are actually going to be some beautiful images.
I mean some images that look like something.
So again I have to insist.
Congratulations because not only have created two brains but also you are done with the first huge step
of this implementation.
If we want to divide this implementation into two big parts Well I would say that the first big part
is the creation of these two brains.
And the second part is the training of these two brains.
So you're done with the first big part because you have created these two brains.
And now we're going to move on to the second part to train these two brains.
And of course train them according to the process of degenerative adversarial networks and let's give
a quick reminder of what this process is about this process is two big steps.
The first step is to update the weight of the discriminator neural network and that consists of maximizing
the error calculated by the B.C.E..
You will see that.
And the second big part and then the second big step of this process is to have data weights of this
time the generator which again will consist of maximizing the area calculated by the bacillus.
All right so if you accept take the challenge to train this brain will join me for the second part of
this implementation and so I'll you very soon to make our decisions the greatest artist of all the computer
vision models.
Until then enjoy computer vision.