You did it, you completed this course and you therefore should now be well prepared to work with
mongodb in your next projects.
I hope you learned a lot about mongodb, the many features it offers, both for the database and now
towards the end with stitch, even outside of its core product, even outside of the database
and I hope that all the knowledge you gained here gives you everything you need to play around with it,
to dive deeper into mongodb and to use it of course in your projects. And I can really only encourage
you to play around, use the shell as a playground as we did it in this course basically, create a local
mongo instance and try out different things, insert data in different ways, update and delete it and then
try out all the different queries you have for narrowing down your data. Use indexes and measure their
performance,
use all these tools,
all these things I taught you in this course. And of course don't just try it in the shell, also build dummy
and demo apps that use mongodb, build a mobile app that uses
mongodb
or a web app using react or angular or a normal node app that renders its views or with PHP or with Python
or a desktop app, whatever it is,
build apps and use mongodb as your database. Possibly also use mongodb and stitch to not just work
with the database but also add user authentication and your server side code through stitch if you want.
So this is the practice practice practice part which is super important and which you have to do to
become a real expert with mongodb. Now which other resources besides this course can I recommend?
Well obviously dive into the official docs, they are
really good
and you can learn a lot there.
You find a detailed reference for every single operator, you find detailed docs on stitch, on the shell,
on how to set up sharding if you want to do that on your own,
so that's all in the official docs, definitely check these out.
Of course also dive into Stack Overflow for discussions or questions that are beyond the scope of this
course,
also dive into blogposts, google for problems you encounter and chances are you'll find a stack overflow
thread or an article in some blog that provides a guide on how to solve that or how other people tackled
something,
this is great to build an understanding of available patterns and best practices. And also use YouTube
and other courses to learn more about specific topics.
Want to learn more about stitch?
Check out stitch courses or YouTube videos.
Want to learn more about sharding?
Well take a database admin, a system admin course on mongodb.
So these are the other resources I can recommend to you
and with these two building blocks, practicing and knowing the right resources as well of course with
all the knowledge gained in this course,
I'm very confident that you are on the right way to becoming a mongodb expert and use it to its
fullest potential in your upcoming projects.