We learned how we can insert documents and how we can find them. Now
another typical use case obviously is that you want to change documents, therefore in this module
we'll have a look at how you can update documents and how you can use different operators to well, apply
different kinds of updates to your data because you will see there's more than just overriding the existing
data.
You'll learn how you can update fields, for example by setting a new value or by incrementing a number,
there are different tools that help you with that and you will also learn how to specifically update
arrays, for example add a new element to an array or remove one.
These are all things you can do with the update one and update many methods provided by mongodb
and before we dive deeper into the different update operators, let's simply start by having a look at
these methods really quick again and then,
well let's start updating.