This will be a fun module because in mongodb,
you cannot just query text, booleans, number, states,
you can also query locations
and with this, I really am talking about queries like find me all restaurants in this radius or find
me the nearest location to my current location.
So there are a lot of fun queries you can do with this so-called geospatial data.
In this module, we'll have a look at how we can store geospatial data in the special geo json format
and you will also learn how you can then efficiently query this geospatial data with the help of
indexes and a couple of special operators that are suited to work well with geospatial data.
So let's dive into this and let's start working with some locations and places.