That's it for this module.
Now in this module, we talked about security and obviously, security is more than what I talked about
in this module but this course is also for you as a developer and therefore, I want to touch on the things
that are important for you to understand as a developer.
Other things are important for database administrators and these things go beyond the scope of mongodb
even, securing something like the network itself is something where mongodb can really help you.
Now for mongodb developers, it's important to understand that you work with users and roles in mongodb
.
and I can't stress this enough that users here does not mean the users, the customers of your application
but instead it means the application itself or data scientists or the database administrators,
so the different users or parties that do interact directly with your database and there, mongodb
uses as a role based access control approach to control who's able to do what. You create users on
databases and you can then log in with your credentials as a user against those databases and you can
use the admin database for generally global users you could say or you can even say this user should
log in against a shop database to make it really clear that this user is meant to mostly work or
only work with the shop database. And talking about that, users by default have no rights to do anything,
you need to add roles to allow certain operations and the permissions that are granted by those roles,
also called privileges are only granted for the database the user was added to
unless and you saw that in this module too, unless you explicitly grant access to other databases with this more
verbose approach of describing a role where you had the real name and the database to which it
applies, then a user that was added to a database can even work on a different database.
You could also use these any database roles you saw for cross database access which typically do
for your global user manager or anything like that.
Now we also had a brief look at encryption and there, we can encrypt both data during transportation,
so whilst it's on its way over the wire and at rest. During transportation, we use TLS SSL to encrypt
that data with the help of that SSL certificate and for production,
you should not use a self-signed certificate as we did in this module
but you should get one, buy one most likely from a SSL certificate authority and then use that along
with that CA file you get to lock down your server and connect to it safely.
Now for encryption at rest, you can encrypt both the files that hold your data and that is made simple with
mongodb enterprise and the values inside your documents,
this is also possible.
So you can encrypt both the values inside your document is something you have to do on your own as a developer
and we will see that in the from shell to driver module of this course. The other part is something you can easily
add with them mongodb Enterprise Edition
and again as I mentioned, you find a link to that in the last lecture of this module.
So with that, I hope you feel a bit more secure now.