So now that I introduced mongodb, what it is and how it roughly works,
let me take a step back and go back to the mongodb company. As I mentioned, the company behind the
mongodb database solution is also called mongodb
and actually, they have a couple of other products too
and I will have a look at them throughout this course.
So how does the mongodb ecosystem look like?
Obviously we got the mongodb database which is the core asset, the core feature and the core topic
of this course and probably the reason why you took this course.
There you have a self-managed and an enterprise solution, we'll work with the community, with the free
community version in this course which has all the features we need
but of course I will also dive into deploying that and showing you a way of getting your local database
with which we'll play around in this course into the web and how to use it on the real app,
no worries. Then they have some tools that are related to managing that database, that is more of a system
admin database admin task, I'll not cover it in this course because this is a course for you as a developer
and they have a cloud solution, that is something I will cover because this is an amazing solution for you
as a developer, because all the managing a system administrator would have to do is done for you there
and you can focus on the data and your logic there,
so this is awesome and we will use that in this course too but we'll also work locally,
no worries.
They also have a mobile solution which basically means you can install mongodb on a mobile device
to store data there directly and even work without an internet connection.
They got a graphical user interface,compass which allows you to connect to your database and look into
it with a nice user interface,
we will also use that in the course but most of the time, we will not because as a developer, you of course
write code, you don't click around in graphical user interfaces and therefore, we will well write code
in this course. And we get also some other tools like BI connectors or Mongodb charts
if you're more on the data science area,
this is not really something where you will write a lot of code,
these are more tools that allow you to connect different analytics tools if you need that.
Now this is the entire database world and this is of course their core feature
hence they have a lot of products there as you can see. Now
they also got a relatively new offering which is called stitch and stitch is
basically their serverless backend solution,
so this is a bit decoupled of the database, still strongly connected but also it offers you more than
just data storage. Stitch for example gives you a serverless query API and you will see this towards the end of
the course where I have a whole module about stitch and where I introduced the core products I have
having the stitch environment.
So there you will see that this is essentially a toolset, a tool which you can use to efficiently query
your database directly from inside your client side apps,
so from inside your react app or anything like that but this will become clear in the stitch module
of course. You also have serverless functions which allows you to execute code in the cloud on demand
so now this is totally unrelated to the database, you can execute any javascript code in the cloud there
and if you know something like AWS Lambda or Google cloud functions, this is your equivalent.
We also have database triggers which is basically a service that allows you to listen to events in
a database, like document was inserted and then execute a function in response to that and that function
could then maybe send an e-mail to a user informing him about that document being inserted, something
like that
and there is a feature called real time sync which basically is built to synchronize a database in a cloud
with that mobile offline supporting database
you might have on mobile devices. This is the current snapshot of their ecosystem,
the focus of this course is on the mongodb database which we'll use locally and in the cloud with Atlas
and how you can work with that, how you can use crud operations, how you can retrieve your data efficiently
and all of that
but I will also dive in the compass.
I will also dive into the stitch world and introduce you to that in this course.