In this section, we are going to explore a variety of topics.
These topics do not need a section dedicated to them.
However they are important to cover.
This section will be all over the place, regardless our theme and plug in and we'll need some finishing
touches.
The first set of topics will explore our format types.
A format type gives users the power to modify portions of text with different formatting.
For example, if we were to type inside a paragraph block, we have various formatting options available
in the toolbar we can bold in italicize or highlight the text.
These options are known as format types.
WordPress gives us the option of adding new format types for this demonstration.
Let's add a new format type.
We're adding a neon effect to the text.
Switch over to the editor inside the source slash block editor directory.
Create a new file called Neon Format JS.
Next, let's add the success for achieving a neon effect.
In the resource section of this lecture, I provide a link to the CCIS.
Copy the CSS to your clipboard.
Head back to the ED in the source slash block editor directory.
Create a file called Neon CSIS.
Pace the CSIS into this file.
Lastly, back in the neon format js file import the neon CSS file.
After preparing the files.
Let's import the JS file into the index file.
Open this file in your editor.
Import the neon format JS file.
This import statement will cause a new CSS file to be generated with our bundle.
If the file does not appear, you may need to restart the command line.
Otherwise we can begin and queueing the csv file.
Open the register assets dot php file.
At the bottom of the function.
Run the WP Register style function.
The name of our asset will be called up.
Ed.
Next, the URL will be the plugins URL function with the following value slash build slash block editor
slash index CSIS up plug in file.
Lastly, open the editor assets stock php file.
Inside this file called the WP NQ Style Function.
The name of our file was called Up Editor.
Our script is ready.
In the next lecture, we will begin registering a new format type.