In this lecture, I want to quickly discuss what the next half of this course covers.
It's time to get into plug in and block development.
Unlike theme development, plug and development requires more involvement with code, specifically PHP
and JavaScript.
So far we've covered PHP but haven't had the chance to cover JavaScript.
In this section we are going to cover JavaScript and react.
Both technologies are going to become relevant for plug and development.
You won't get far without knowledge of these two topics.
If you already know JavaScript and react, you can skip this section.
I won't be teaching anything groundbreaking.
Only the fundamentals will be covered for the rest of you.
Let's get into it.
We won't be touching WordPress for a while.
Our primary focus is going to be JavaScript and react.
Once we have become comfortable with JavaScript, we'll hop back into WordPress development.
Once you're ready, I'll see you in the following lecture.