Congratulations.
You've made it to the very end.
We spent a lot of time developing a single theme and plugin.
Hopefully this knowledge can help you develop your own plugins.
You should be ready to tackle any project thrown at you.
We reviewed translations, explored the various APIs, developed custom blocks, and customize the full
site editing experience.
I hope this course was exactly what you were looking for.
I wish you a lot of luck in your career as a WordPress developer.
If you have any questions, please feel free to ask in the comments.
Also, if you can please take the time to rate this course.
That encourages me to keep improving this course.
It's much appreciated.
Thank you.