In this lecture, we are going to explore a language called SAS.
In the resource section of this lecture, I provide a link to the official site for SAS.
SAS is a programming language for CSIS, which might sound strange.
CSIS is one of the simplest languages you can learn.
There's not much to it.
On the other hand, it's not a powerful language.
SAS aims to solve CSIS issues by adding features found in programming languages.
SAS supports functions, loops, directives, inheritance, etc. For this course we decided not to use
SAS.
In my opinion, I prefer another tool called Post CSIS.
However, you're likely to find SAS and other plugins for this reason.
Let's try learning SAS.
Typically the first step is to install SAS browsers.
Do not support SAS code written with SAS must be compiled in CSS.
By using the Create Blocks package, we can skip this step all together.
The developers of this package have added native support for SAS with blocks.
We can start writing SAS immediately in our editors.
Let's open these style SCC file.
SAS files can be written inside files with the SAS or SAS extension.
The SAS extension is more common.
If you were to look through this files code base, you're going to notice that SAS is very similar to
CSS.
You can think of SAS as a language that extends CSS.
All CSS features are supported.
The SAS syntax rules apply to SAS.
Let's look at one of the most common features available inside the WP block u plus alert box class.
We have a list of CSS properties.
However, things don't stop there.
An additional selector has been added inside the curly brackets of the current selector.
SAS supports nested selectors.
The idea of nesting was inspired by HTML and HTML.
We can add elements inside elements.
Children elements would inherit properties from parent elements.
The same idea applies to nested selectors in SAS.
A nested selector is a shortcut for producing a long selector.
For example, the first nested selector will produce the following selector WP lock you plus alert box
is style accented.
In the child selector, we have an ampersand character.
This character represents the parent selector.
SAS will convert this character into the parent selector during compilation, thus giving us the final
selector.
As you can see, it's shorter to right this selector.
Let's look at another example below this selector.
The child selector does not have the ampersand character by not including this character.
A space will separate the parent and child selector.
This example will produce the following selector WP Lock U plus alert box dash icon.
By using nested selectors, we can quickly create long selectors.
In addition, this feature provides clarity on the relationship between selectors without nesting.
It can be difficult to organise CSIS.
It's very clear that these properties will only be applied to these classes.
This is just one feature of SAS.
Since this is not a SAS course, I won't be diving any deeper.
However, feel free to continue learning about SAS after finishing this course.
There are many developers who enjoy using this language.
Don't worry, we won't be using any advanced features of SAS.
The purpose of this lecture was to just give you a taste of this language.
Now that we've covered SAS, let's get back into block development.
In the next lecture, let's talk about Ed Styles.