In this lecture, we are going to quickly discuss a file called Ed Success.
You can find this file within the source directory.
This file contains styles for the Gutenberg editor.
The Scripts package will search for a file called Editor that asks if this file exists within our project.
The compiled CSS file will not be bundled with the other files.
The package will extract this file into a separate file in the build directory.
A file with a similar name cannot be found behind the scenes.
The builder has renamed the file to indexed CSS.
If you look inside this file, you'll find the same styles from the editor SKS file.
It's a simple feature for separating editor styles from the main styles of a block.
There isn't a reason to load styles for the editor on the front end.
They take up an unnecessary amount of disk space.
For this plugin, we do not need editor styles.
Let's remove this file from our project in the source directory.
Delete the editor dot access file.
Next.
Open the block, Jason File.
Towards the bottom of the file.
Remove the editor style option.
The editor's style option will load a CSS file in the editor.
The scripts package will add this option for loading the indexed CSV file.
Since we do not need editor styles, this option can be safely removed.
The last step is to remove the import statement for this file from the edit js file.
Inside this file.
Remove the import statement.
After making those changes, your project should be fully functional.
You can check the command line for errors.
If you spot errors, you may need to restart the NPM run start command.
After restarting, the error should go away.
In the next lecture, let's start modifying the styles of our block.