In this lecture we are going to load a schema for our JSON file.
Schemas are optional, but they're incredibly helpful for avoiding spelling errors and debugging.
So you find out why.
Let's open the theme JSON file in our editor's.
Next, let's add an object with a property called version.
The first property in your themed JSON file should always be version.
WordPress is constantly evolving, however it tries its best to be backward compatible.
The settings of the theme JSON file have changed over time.
The early adopters may still be using an older version of the theme JSON file.
Therefore we need to tell WordPress what version will be using.
The latest version is to the value for this property should be a number.
So far, so good.
However, it's possible we may have made a mistake.
For example, what if we capitalize the V in the property name?
Property names are case sensitive.
WordPress will not be able to detect the version of our property.
Let's try creating another problem instead of a number.
Let's wrap our value in quotes.
Our JSON file has two errors.
Unfortunately, they will go unnoticed.
Neither WordPress nor our editor will inform us of our mistakes.
For these reasons, we should use a schema in the resource section of this lecture, I provide a link
to the documentation page for the schema.
According to the documentation, a schema is available to help us address these issues.
Schemas are not specific to WordPress, they apply to all JSON files.
The purpose of a schema is to double check your properties and values.
A schema can help the editor understand the structure of a JSON file.
They can validate a JSON file.
If you make a mistake, an error will notify you of your mistake.
A schema can be applied to a JSON file by adding the dollar sign schema property.
The documentation provides an example that we can copy.
Let's grab it.
Next.
Let's paste it at the top of our object in the theme JSON file.
Be sure to add a comma after adding this property, Visual Studio code should begin validating your
file.
For some of you, this may work immediately.
For others, you may receive an error.
This error will appear if the editor is unable to download the schema.
There are two solutions for fixing this issue.
The first solution is to convert the URL from the HTTPS to HTTP.
However, you may not be comfortable with the idea of using an unsecured connection.
An alternative solution is to grab the full URL.
The URL provided by the WordPress documentation is a proxy URL.
To better understand, let's click on the link.
In our browser, the URL will redirect us to a GitHub page.
The URL in the address bar is completely different from the URL provided by the documentation.
This URL is the true location for the schema.
Rather than using the documentations URL, we can switch over to the true URL.
Our editor will be able to grab the schema by doing so.
It'll be able to validate our JSON file.
There are two new errors that haven't been there before.
If we hover our mouse over the opening curly brackets, the error will state our file is missing the
version property.
Sounds strange, right?
The aversion property exists in our file.
However, look closely at the casing.
The original name has all lowercase letters, whereas our property has a capitalized V.
It becomes clear as to what's wrong.
The names don't match.
Let's quickly fix the casing.
After making those adjustments, the errors have gone away.
Perfect.
Well, almost another error has appeared.
This time, the error is related to the value.
According to the error, the type is incorrect.
The data type for the version property should be an integer.
Let's remove the quotes from the number.
Voila.
Our file is error free.
Prior to adding the schema, these errors remained undetected.
While optional schemas are incredibly valuable for developers.
They allow us to quickly debug our JSON files.
This reduces the likelihood of WordPress not understanding our settings.
I highly recommend keeping the schema option in your file in the next lecture.
Let's continue with extending the global styles for our theme.