In this lecture, we are going to start adding category suggestions to the query controls block.
The goal is to give users the option of filtering recipes based on a specific cuisine.
They may want to display popular recipes for a cuisine.
We should provide that option to them.
The query controls component can help us with this situation.
It can render an input with a feature for suggesting cuisines.
Let's explore this feature in the editor.
Open the index JS file.
First we need to grab a list of all cuisine items from the current site.
The query controls component does not automatically grab terms for a specific taxonomy.
We must manually perform this query at the top of the file.
Import the use select function from the WordPress slash data package.
Any time we need to perform a query to the database, this function will help us.
Next, let's begin using this function inside the edit function create a variable called terms.
The value for this variable will be the use select function.
Passing a function to begin handling the query.
The function will be provided a function called select for performing the query.
Inside this function, let's return the following value.
Select core dot get entity records.
We're already familiar with creating a query for taxonomy terms for the recipe summary block.
We performed a similar query.
The first step is to select the core storage, which contains a method for retrieving terms for a taxonomy.
Next, we can call the get entity records function to initiate the query.
Inside this function, we can pass in the type of data to grab.
Let's set the type to taxonomy.
Next, we must specify the name of the taxonomy, which is cuisine.
Lastly, we can pass in an object to filter the results.
By default, WordPress will limit the results, but that's not what we want.
The query should grab all the taxonomy terms.
We can add a parameter called per page with a value of minus one.
The per page parameter will limit the results to a maximum threshold by setting it to minus one word.
Press will not impose a threshold.
All terms available within the taxonomy are grabbed from the database.
The query is ready, but we're not finished yet.
There's one problem with the data retrieved by the query.
The data is not formatted correctly.
The use select function will return an array of results.
You can log the array to view the results in the array.
An object represents a single term.
I've simplified the results for the sake of clarity, you may find more properties than the ID and name
the query controls component.
Want an object, not an array.
Each term must be stored in a property.
The property name must store the name of the taxonomy term.
Our next step becomes obvious.
We are going to convert the data from the current format to the desired format.
Otherwise, the query controls components may not behave correctly.
Below the terms variable.
Define another variable called suggestions with an initial value of an empty object.
Next we are going to loop through the terms array.
On each iteration we will add the term to the object.
Let's begin looping through the terms array with the for each function.
I'm going to introduce a new feature called Optional Chaining.
Optional Chaining is a feature for accessing a property or method without throwing an error.
Initially, the use select function will return null.
This means the terms variable will have an empty value.
Retrieving taxonomies terms can take a while, since that's the case before each function will not be
available on the terms variable.
If we were to access a method that doesn't exist on a variable, the browser would throw an error.
We can resolve this issue by checking the terms variable for a value.
There are different ways to write a solution.
For example, we can wrap this function with a conditional statement to check the current value of the
terms variable.
However, there is a cleaner syntax called optional chaining after the terms variable.
Add a question mark character.
This operator will instruct the browser to check the terms variable.
If this variable is an object, the browser will proceed to run the line of code.
On the other hand, if the variable is empty, it will not run the for each function, thus preventing
an error from being thrown.
It's a simpler solution for accessing a property that may or may not exist on a variable.
Let's assume the variable contains an array inside the for each function pass in an arrow function.
I'm going to reference each item in the array as term.
Next, let's add a new property with the following syntax suggestions.
Term dot name equals term.
Throughout this course, we've been pushing items into an array.
But what if we need to add a property to an existing object?
There are two solutions for adding new properties.
The most common solution is to use dot notation.
For example, let's say we wanted to add a new property called Foo.
We could write it like so.
If the property doesn't exist, it'll be added to the object.
However, this solution does not work for our purposes.
The name of the property should be based on the name of the term.
For this scenario, we can resort to square bracket notation.
Within these square brackets, we can add a string or use a dynamic value to represent the properties
name.
After adding the property, we are setting the value to the term object.
Let's log the value.
It's going to help us understand the outcome.
Next, refresh the page.
And the popular recipes block.
Open the console panel of the developer tools.
If we were to look at the logs, the suggestions variable starts as an empty object.
At this point, the request for the terms has not been completed.
After a few moments, a new object should be logged in the console.
As you can see, our terms have been formatted into the format expected by the query controls object.
The name of the term appears as the property name.
Each property contains the term object.
Let's pass these values onto the query controls component.
Head back to the editor.
Scroll to the query controls components on this component at a property called Category Suggestions,
the value for this property will be the suggestions variable.
By providing a list of suggestions, WordPress will compare the user's input with the suggestions.
If there is a partial match, WordPress will recommend the term.
Next, we must add an event called on category change.
Without this event, the input will not appear.
The minimum requirement for the input to appear is to have the category suggestions, property and the
on category change events on the components.
Let's pass in an arrow function that accepts the new terms as an argument.
Inside the function long the new term's arguments.
This event is emitted when new terms are added to the input.
Let's try testing our components in the browser.
Refresh the page.
Next, add the popular recipes.
Lock to the page.
Initially the input will not appear on the sidebar.
This is because the category suggestions property is given a null value.
It will not appear until the request for the terms has been completed.
After a few moments, you should see it appear.
We can type inside this input to add a new cuisine.
If we type an existing cuisine, the component will suggest it.
That's perfect.
We've successfully suggested cuisines to the user.
In the next lecture, let's begin saving the cuisines into our attributes.