In this lecture, we are going to add settings to a site.
We can create a page for modifying a plug in settings without storing the settings values.
For this step, we are going to create our plug in settings during plug in activation.
It's the best possible place to create new settings.
In your editor, open the activation file.
At the bottom of the file, let's create a variable called options.
The value for this variable will be the get option function.
Before inserting data into the database, we should check for existing data.
It's possible that users may be reactivating our plugin.
If that's the case, we do not want to override the existing values.
The get option function accepts the options name to retrieve from the database.
The name of our option will be called up options.
The name of our option has been prefixed with up.
It's common for plugins to add settings to the database to prevent naming conflicts.
It's recommended to prefix your option names.
If this plugin is activated for the first time, this option will not exist in the database.
The against option function will return false for non existent records.
After the variable, let's create a conditional statement.
The condition will check if the options variable is false.
If it is, we can safely insert data into the database.
It's the first time this function is being activated on a site inside the block of code run a function
called ad option.
The ad option function will add a new record to the WP options table.
There are two required arguments.
The first argument is the name of the option.
Let's call our option of options.
The second argument is the value to insert.
You may be wondering what type of settings are we creating?
Almost every business has a social media presence.
It's not uncommon for visitors to share links with others.
There's a protocol called Open Graph.
In the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to this protocol.
Open graph is a standardized solution for exposing the information on a page to a social media platform
whenever you paste a link into a social media post.
Platforms will send a request to the page for information.
This information is displayed along with your posts.
Let's look at an example.
In the resource section of this lecture, I provide a link to a tool for viewing a site's open graph.
I'm going to paste in a link to a random site.
On the right side of the page, we're given a preview of the content retrieved by the site.
For example, Facebook will display an image URL, title and description.
This information is not random.
We can configure the data that will appear in the preview by using the open graph protocol.
Open graph is very simple to use for our plugin.
We are going to add settings for modifying a site's open graph settings.
There are dozens of options available.
Let's keep it simple.
By allowing users to modify the title image and description, you can check out the documentation for
a complete list of configurable options.
Head back to the editor.
The second value of the ADD option function can contain any data type we can add strings, numbers,
etc. Our plugin is going to store an array of options.
There isn't a point in creating multiple records.
Everything can be stored in a single record in this array.
Add an item called OG title.
The value for this item will be gets blog info function.
We were familiar with the get blog info function.
This function will retrieve different pieces of information about the current site by defaults.
We are going to set the title of the preview to the site title.
The title can be retrieved by passing in a string called name.
Next, let's add a key called OG image with an initial value of an empty string.
Lastly, add a key called OG description.
The value for this key will be the get blog info function with the description item.
All sites have a description which can be retrieved with the get blog info function.
We are going to add one more option called enable OG.
The value for this option will be one.
Site owners may prefer another plugin for adding open graph tags to a site.
If they have another plugin for handling open graph tags, we can run into problems for this situation.
We are going to give the user the option of disabling this feature from our plugin.
By default, the option will be enabled.
Let's try testing our work in the browser.
Navigate to the plugins page.
Deactivate and reactivate the Udemy plus plugin.
Without a problem.
The plugin has been deactivated.
Just to make sure.
Let's view the database from the database page.
Inspect the data from the WP options table.
New records are inserted at the end of the table.
Try viewing the last page if we scroll to the bottom of the table.
Our record appears in the last row.
Strangely, the value is different from the value in our PHP file.
Databases do not support PHP arrays before inserting our data into the database.
WordPress will perform a process called serialization on our array.
Serialization is the process of transforming the value to be compatible with another language or database.
We never have to worry about manually serializing our data as long as we're using the functions supplied
by WordPress.
Serialization is handled by WordPress.
In the next lecture let's begin creating an admin page for modifying our new options.