In this lecture, we are going to add a template to the inner blocks component.
At the moment, the team members group block is always empty.
Users must manually add blocks.
We can safely assume that users may want to add blocks upon inserting this block.
WordPress makes the same assumption for its own blocks.
For example, let's try adding the buttons block to the page.
After adding this block, the parents block will have a single child lock.
Upon insertion, we can force WordPress to add blocks to the inner blocks component by specifying a
template.
Let's give that a try in your editor.
Open the index js file for the team members group block.
Scroll to the edit function, let's modify the properties of the inner blocks component on this component
at a property called Template.
The value for this property will be an array of blocks to add to the inner blocks component.
In this array we can specify a block by adding another array.
Let's try adding the team member block.
The first item in the array must be the full name of the block, passing the following Udemy plus slash
team member.
The second item in the array can be an object of attributes to override from the block.
This value is completely optional.
If you don't provide values for a block's attributes, WordPress will use the default values.
For this example, let's add an object.
Set the name attribute to John Doe.
The title attribute will have a value of CEO of Udemy.
Lastly, the bio attribute will be set to the following value.
This is an example of a bio.
Just so that our block isn't alone.
Let's add two more copies of the team member block without attribute values.
Well for testing our code.
There's another property worth looking at for this block.
We aren't going to need it, but it's still nice to know.
I'm referring to a property called Template Lock.
We may want users to change the templates by adding or moving blocks.
By default, users will be able to remove the blocks or add new ones.
We can set this property to all to completely prevent blocks from being removed or added.
Alternatively, we can set this property to insert to prevent removal.
Users will still be able to add new blocks for this block.
This option won't be necessary.
We are going to give users complete freedom over the blocks.
Let's try refreshing the page in the browser.
Insert the team members group block.
After doing so, three blocks have been added to the inner blocks component.
The first block will have the attribute values from the templates, whereas the other blocks will fall
back to their default values.
Adding a template is a great way to push your users in the right direction.
Let's continue working on the block in the next set of lectures.