In this lecture, we are going to begin generating dummy content.
Fake content is going to help us test our theme.
We could write some content, but that will take up a lot of time.
Luckily, there's a plug in that can generate some content for us.
This will give us a better idea of what our site will look like with content.
Open the WordPress Admin Dashboard.
Navigate to the add new plugin page.
Search for a plugin called Finger Press by a user called Gustavo.
This plugin will generate dummy content for your site.
I find it perfect for quickly generating fake content.
Let's install and activate it.
After activating the plug in.
Let's generate some content.
We'll start by creating some terms.
Terms are the categories and tags associated with a post.
Before generating posts, we should generate terms for the posts on the sidebar.
A new menu item called Figure Press will be available under this menu item select terms.
We have a couple of options we can set.
We're going to set the quantity to between five and ten.
The name size will be between one and two.
The taxonomies will be set to categories and tags.
Everything else is fine as is.
Let's click generate.
We can move on to generating posts, navigate to figure press posts.
This page will allow us to generate posts.
We're going to set the quantity to 20 and 30.
Afterward, we'll set the date option to last 15 days.
Up next, the post type field should include posts and pages.
The author fields should be set to admin or whatever account is available on your WordPress demo site.
Scroll to the Taxonomy Field Rules section.
This section is where we can add categories and tags to a post under the rates field.
Let's update the rate to 100.
We're almost finished under the meta field section.
We can configure the images generated for a post.
The default settings are fine as is.
There's only one option we'll modify change the weight field to 100.
The rest of the fields are finances.
We're finished filling out the form.
Let's click generate.
This process may take a while because WordPress is downloading images from the web.
Hopefully you've received a success message.
If you're experiencing problems, you may need to reduce the number of posts generated.
We're finished with generating fake posts.
I recommend deactivating fake press.
We don't need it anymore.
I'm going to quickly deactivate this plugin.
Let's begin working on our theme in the following lecture.
We'll continue our journey with WordPress development.