In this lecture, let's start creating a custom admin page for displaying our plugins options.
We can create a new page by using a function called Add menu page.
Before using this function, we should use it from the correct hook.
Since not all requests are not for the admin dashboard on the sidebar, click on the more information
section.
The second note states the following The hook you should use is admin menu.
If we were to use a different hook, we might receive an error based on the advice of this function.
Let's use this hook in your editor.
Open the index plug and file.
At the bottom of the hook section.
Run the add action function.
The name of the hook is called Admin Menu.
This hook runs during the initialization of the WordPress admin menu.
The name of our function will be called up admin menus.
Next let's define this function in the includes slash admin folder.
Create a file called menus PHP.
Define the function from within this file.
Next, let's call the add menu page function.
This function has a few arguments.
The first argument is the page title.
The value passed into this argument will be inserted into the title tags of the tab.
Let's pass in the following translated message You to me plus.
The second argument is the title of the menu item.
This value will appear in the admin menu off the dashboard.
Let's use the same value as the first argument.
In both cases, we're translating the texts with the double underscore function.
The third argument is the capability of the user.
We haven't had the chance to talk about capabilities and the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to the capabilities documentation page.
Capabilities refer to the permissions of a user.
If you scroll through this page, you're going to find a long list of permissions available.
They range from reading posts to creating new users.
WordPress assigns capabilities by roles by default.
There are six roles which are super admin, administrator, editor, author, contributor and subscriber.
Let's scroll down to the capability versus role section of this page.
As you can see, a super admin can perform every action, whereas a subscriber can only read posts and
pages.
You can think of roles as a way to group capabilities.
WordPress recommends checking a user's capability as opposed to their role.
This is because capabilities can be modified for a user.
There are plugins for creating or modifying existing roles.
These plugins can modify the capabilities of each role, which can remove or add specific permissions.
It's always important to check a capability rather than a role.
Let's head back to our editor.
The function requires the name of a capability.
It'll check if the user can perform this capability.
If they can, they will have permission to access this page.
Currently, we're interested in limiting this page to users with the roles super admin or administrators.
Let's set this argument to the following capability.
Edit Theme Options.
This capability is available to both roles.
Let's work on setting the fourth argument, which is the menu slug.
You can think of this argument as the ID of the menu.
There are dozens of menu options.
WordPress needs help identifying our menu by assigning an ID to this menu.
Let's set the ID to up plug in options.
The fifth argument is the name of the function responsible for rendering the pages content.
Let's call our function up plugins options page.
This function doesn't exist.
Let's work on creating it inside the admin folder.
Create a file called Options Page.
PHP.
Next, let's define the up plugin options page function.
From this function we can output content onto the page.
Lets exit and re-enter page mode.
Next additive tag with a class called Wrap.
The rap class will position our content on the page.
This class is not documented by WordPress.
If you're curious as to how I know this class exists, I inspected the elements of other pages.
All WordPress admin pages.
Use this class for positioning the content of the page next to the menu.
Inside this tag, let's output a simple message.
We're almost finished.
The last step is to add an icon.
All menu items can have an icon next to the name of the menu.
We have two options at our disposal.
We can use dash icons or a custom SVG image.
I prefer using a custom SVG image and the resource section of this lecture I provide a link to an SVG
image.
Copy this image to your plugin folder under the name letter u dot SVG.
I'm going to quickly add it to my plugin.
The file should be inserted in the root directory of the plugin.
After adding this file, let's update the add menu page function.
There's a sixth argument which is a valid HTTP path to an image.
We can generate a path to our image using a function called plugins URL.
This function has two arguments.
The first argument is the name of the file let's pass in letter u dot SVG.
The second argument is the path to the plug and file.
This function does not know which plugin the file originates from.
Normally we would pass in the file constants, but we're not in the main plug in file.
Let's create a constant for storing the path to the file in the index plug and file.
Scroll to the setup section at a constant called up plug in file.
The value for this constant will be the file constant.
Next, let's pass this constant to the plugins URL function in the menus dot PHP file.
The return value of this function will be a full HTTP URL to the image.
We're finished creating the menu in the browser.
Refresh the admin dashboard.
Voila.
A new menu item has appeared.
We can click on this link to view our page on the page.
Our message from the function has appeared in the content area of the page.
It's positioned perfectly.
In the next lecture.
Let's begin working on rendering a form for this page.