In this lecture, we are going to update the cuisines attributes.
This attribute will store an array of objects where each object represents a term we left off with adding
an input for adding terms to the block.
Currently, I have the block on the page with the console panel opened from the developer tools.
I'm going to add a new term.
After adding the term, the input will clear out.
We haven't updated the attribute.
If we look in the console, the value is in array with the term as a string.
Unfortunately, that's not what we need.
In the future.
We are going to perform a request for a list of posts.
Filtering posts by taxonomies requires the ID of the terms, not their names.
Once again, we must format the value into an array of term IDs.
Let's get started in your editor.
Open the index JS file.
Scroll to the query control's component inside the EN Category Change Events.
Let's replace the console statement with a variable called New CUISINE'S.
The initial value for this variable will be an empty array.
Our attribute is an array.
As a reminder, we cannot partially update the array.
We must completely override the array with a new array.
This variable will store the new copy of the Cuisine's attribute.
Next, let's begin looping through the new terms argument with the for each function.
The value emitted by the event will contain existing and new terms.
Let's handle both scenarios as they come up inside the for each function pass in an arrow function with
an argument called cuisine.
Next, let's create a variable called cuisine term.
This variable will store the terms object.
First, we need to search for the term.
All we have is the name.
Luckily, that's enough to find the term.
Set the variable to the following value terms.
Question Mark dot find.
Arrays have a function called find.
This function will loop through the items in the array.
During the loop we can search for a specific item.
The item selected by the function will be returned.
This function has one argument which is a function to perform the search.
Let's pass in an arrow function that accepts the term object.
Our function must return a boolean value.
If the return value is true, we're telling JavaScript to return the item from the current iteration,
otherwise it'll move on to the next item in the array.
As I said before, all we have is the name.
Each term object has a copy of the name in a property called Name.
Let's perform the following comparison term Dot name equals equals equals cuisine.
If the term name from the current object matches the input from the user, we have a match.
The result is stored in the cuisine term variable, thus giving us access to the ID.
The last step is to push the object into the new terms array.
After the loop, add a conditional statement.
The condition will be the cuisine term variable.
It's possible that we may not find a term.
This can be due to a term that doesn't exist on our site.
Technically, it's possible to create new terms.
However, we're going to limit our block to existing terms.
New terms must be created beforehand.
Creating new terms can make our block more complicated.
Let's assume what term was found.
We can proceed to push the cuisine term variable into the new cuisines array with the push function.
After the for each function we can update the attribute with the set attributes function.
Set the Cuisine's attribute to the new cuisines variable.
So far so good.
However, there is one problem with our solution.
As they said before, the event will emit an array of terms.
This array will contain existing and new terms.
As we learned, new terms will be passed on as strings.
Existing terms will be our objects.
We have a mixture of objects and strings.
Existing terms are objects.
New terms are strings.
In our current solution, we're assuming the array contains strings.
By not taking into account of objects, the existing terms are completely ignored.
We need to handle both scenarios.
The solution becomes clear.
We should check for an object.
If the term is an object, we do not need to search for it.
We can go ahead with pushing it into the new array of terms at the top of the for each loop, add a
conditional statement.
Type the following condition.
Type of cuisine equals equals equals object.
The type of keyword will help us to detect the data type of a variable.
In this example, we are checking for an object.
If it is an object, we can proceed to push the object into the array without searching for it.
Call the new cuisine.
Stop push function with the cuisine variable.
We should return this statement from the function.
There isn't a reason for the current iteration to continue running.
We can move on to the next item by returning the function early before each function is not going to
do anything with the value.
It's safe to return it.
Let's remove the console statement before testing our code.
Before I forget, there's one more property that should be added to the query controls component.
We can set the initial values of these selected terms by adding the selected categories property.
Set this property to the cuisine's attributes.
Time to test our code.
Refresh the page.
Add the popular recipes block to the editor.
Lastly, try adding cuisines to the page.
We can safely add and remove cuisines from the block.
New terms can't be added, but that's to be expected.
We haven't added support for adding new terms to the site.
In the next lecture, we are going to begin performing the query for posts.
Once you're ready, I'll see you in the following lecture.