In this lecture, we are going to insert data into our custom table before doing so.
There is an important concept to understand.
We should wrap our heads around this concept before proceeding with additional queries.
I'm referring to a concept called CRUD.
It stands for Create, Read, Update and delete.
These are the four pillars of database operations.
In most cases, you're going to perform any of these actions onto your database.
My SQL and Maria DB support CRUD operations.
In this section, we are going to explore each action for this lecture.
We are going to start with creating data.
We have a table for storing products.
Let's try inserting a product.
Currently, I'm viewing the query page for our database.
A new record can be inserted into a table by typing the following keywords insert into.
Next, we must provide the name of the table.
In our case, we are going to insert data into the products table.
On a new line.
Let's add the values keyword with a pair of parentheses.
The values keyword will allow us to start providing data for the new record.
Inside the parentheses, we must provide a list of values separated by a comma.
The order of values does matter.
Databases will insert the value in the same order as the columns for the table.
For example, the first column in the products table is the ID column.
Therefore, the first value will be inserted into the ID column.
The second value will be inserted under the name column, so on and so forth.
If you don't remember the order of columns, that's perfectly fine.
In another tab, I recommend opening the structure of a table by default.
Most clients will provide the order of the columns.
As you can see, the order of our table is the ID and name.
Back to our query.
Let's set the ID to one.
The name of the product will be called hats.
The ID of the product must be a numeric value.
It's because the column has a data type of big ints which accepts numbers.
If we were to insert a different data type, the database would throw an error.
Similar to other languages, strings are created with double quotes.
The var in data type is analogous to strings for PHP or JavaScript.
After creating the query, let's add a semicolon to end the statement.
Next, let's execute the query.
After a few seconds, the data should have been inserted into our table.
Let's click on our table to view the data as clear as day.
A new record has been added to our table.
There is an alternative syntax for inserting data.
Let's give it a try.
Head back to the query page inside the input.
Add the insert into keywords with the products table.
By default, we must provide a value for every column in our table.
However, we may not have data for every column.
We can specify a list of columns by adding parentheses after the table's name.
Inside these parentheses, we can write a list of columns separated by a comma.
Let's add the ID column to the list.
Next, add the values keyword with a number for the ID.
There is a limitation to this syntax.
If a column is required, the query will not work.
For example, let's add another query for inserting data.
First, add the semicolon after the first statement on a new line.
Add the insert into keywords for the product table.
This time, let's insert a value for the name column.
Next, add the values keyword with a random value.
During the creation of our table, we specified that the ID column could not be null by adding the not
null keywords.
This query should result in an error.
Let's try running the query.
The client will inform us that the first query was executed successfully, even though we did not provide
a value for the name column.
The database will attempt to add a null value.
However, this action did not work for the second query.
Unlike the name column, the ID column is required.
The database was unable to add our record.
We can verify the insertion by viewing the data for the products table.
The second row has an ID, but no name.
A column without a value will have null.
As you can see, inserting data into a table is as easy as two keywords in the next lecture.
Let's talk about reading data in a table.