In this lecture, we are going to add column support for our blocks.
Currently, the children blocks are stacked vertically.
The orientation should be modified to horizontal stacking.
We can fix this issue with CSS.
In my editor, I'm viewing the main CSS file for this block.
We are going to use CSS grids for creating columns in this file.
I have three classes called columns, two columns three and columns four.
We're going to allow users to toggle between these classes.
Let's open the index JS file.
Our block has an attribute called columns.
This attribute can be a number between two and four.
I've already added a control for modifying this block from the edit function.
Check out the inspector controls component.
We have a component called range control for modifying the columns attributes.
It has the usual properties for creating an input.
However, it's missing two properties as it stands.
Our CSS only supports two, three or four columns.
The range control component will allow users to select numbers beyond this range.
We can limit the range by adding two properties called Min and Max.
Let's set these properties to two and four respectively.
This will limit the range of values.
Moving on, let's begin applying the classes to the templates.
We must apply classes to the root element.
Luckily, we do not need to directly modify the root elements.
The root element has the block props variable.
The use block props function accepts an object of properties to add to the root element.
Let's add the class name property.
The value for this property will be a template string with the following value columns.
Columns.
The class will be dynamic.
We are going to interpolate the columns attributes into the class name.
Let's make a copy of this object.
The same classes must be applied to the save function paste the object into the use block props dot
save function.
One more thing they say.
Function does not have access to the columns attributes above the save function.
The structure.
The attributes object for the columns attributes.
Our luck is ready in the browser.
Refresh the page.
And the team members group block to the page.
This time, the blocks are arranged horizontally.
Our columns are working as expected.
On the sidebar, we can modify the columns by moving the slider.
As we do so, the blocks should adjust accordingly.
If you're interested in having additional columns, you're more than welcome to modify the classes and
range.
There's one more thing I want to mention.
In an earlier lecture we set the orientation to horizontal.
By doing so, we can hover our mouse between the blocks to insert new blocks.
Previously, this element would appear underneath the blocks.
This time it appears in between the blocks.
Setting the orientation is optional, but I recommend setting it for a better user experience.
The parent block is mostly complete.
In the next set of lectures, we will shift our focus to the individual team members.