In this lecture, we are going to dive into variables.
The concept of a variable in JavaScript is the same as the concept of a variable in PHP.
They are a feature in a language for storing data.
We can store names, addresses, prices, images, etc. Let's try writing a variable in JavaScript.
In my browser I have these sources panel opened from the developer tools under the snippet section.
Let's edit the index JS file by deleting the files contents.
We're not going to need the code from the previous lecture.
Let's start fresh next.
Let's type in the following code.
Let my name equals John.
Variables are created with the left keyword.
It's a strange keyword name.
However, the idea is to read it as let my name be the value of John.
By typing the let keyword, we're giving instructions to the machine to store a value in memory.
Next, we need to provide a name for our variable.
In this example, we're setting the name to my name.
There are rules for variable names.
The name of a variable must begin with a letter, underscore character or a dollar sign character.
The rest of the name can contain letters, numbers, underscores or dollar sign characters.
Spaces and reserved keywords are not allowed.
For example, we can't use the word let as a variable name.
JavaScript would not be able to run your code.
Lastly, variable names are case sensitive.
The last step for creating a variable is to give it a value.
This step is completely optional.
Variables can be declared without being given a value.
By default, JavaScript will set the value to undefined.
In most cases, you will assign a value to a variable.
In this example, we're setting it to a string.
There is a famous analogy for describing what variables do in a programming language by typing the word
let's.
We're creating a box for storing items.
Next, we are labeling the box with a variable name.
In this example, we are setting the boxes label to my name.
Lastly, the data is stored inside the box.
The text that appears after the equal sign character is considered the value.
Variables can be referenced later in our program.
Let's try using the alert function to output the variable from the my name variable below the variable
definition.
Run the alert function with the my alert variable.
Next run the script.
After doing so, the alert box will display the value from the variable.
Perfect variables are incredibly powerful for storing and reusing data at later points in our application.
Let's keep exploring Java Scripts features in the next set of lectures.