In this lecture, we are going to have the option of modifying the background color of the search form
block.
Previously, we used the color palette component to render a color picker.
It's a recommended component for adding color options to your block.
However, there's another component that's not well documented.
I'm not sure why, but the WordPress team has obscured it.
Despite that, I think it's an extremely powerful component.
It's called the Panel Color Settings Components.
This component will create a panel that has a color palette.
The UI will be similar to the color palette component.
Describing the differences is difficult.
So rather than describe the component, let's give it a try in your editor.
Open the block JSON file.
For starters, let's define the attributes for storing the colors.
Our component is going to have two attributes for modifying the colors of our block.
Clients will be able to modify the background and text color inside the attributes object at a property
called BG Color.
Color values will be stored as strings set the type property to string.
Next, we should add a default color and the default property with the following value hash.
f87171.
By default, attributes are stored in the content of a block.
Unlike client side rendered blocks, we should never change the resource of a server side rendered block
attributes for server side render blocks must be stored in the comments.
It's because the block doesn't have anything else.
It's impossible to retrieve attribute values from different sources.
Therefore, we should leave the source alone.
Let's add the next attribute.
The name of the next attribute is called text color.
Same as before.
Let's set the type property to string.
Lastly, set the default property to hash f.
F f.
Our attributes already we can begin to update them from the indexed JS file.
Let's open this file with our editors.
First things first we should start grabbing the components we'll need for the block from the BLOCK Editor
package.
We are going to update the import statement to include two components called inspector controls and
panel color settings.
We're already familiar with the Inspector Controls component.
This component will add content to the sidebar.
It's the ideal location for adding options to modify a block's behavior or appearance.
Next, we're importing the panel color settings component.
Strangely, it's been defined from the block editor package.
Next, let's import the double underscore function from the WordPress slash IE 18 RN package.
After importing these components.
Let's update our block in the edit function's argument list.
We should structure the props object for the attributes and set attributes function.
The attributes object will contain the current values of our blocks attributes, whereas the set attributes
function will help us with updating our attributes.
For readability, we should structure the attributes object at the top of the function d structure the
attributes object for the BG colour and text colour attributes.
Everything is ready.
We have our components and attributes.
The last step is to add the panel color settings component for manipulating the attribute values.
First, we are going to update the return statement by wrapping the existing HTML with a fragment.
If we plan on adding the inspector controls component, we must add a fragment, otherwise react with
throw an error for having multiple parent elements.
Next, let's add the inspector controls component.
It's going to sit above the block from within the inspector controls component.
Insert the panel color settings component.
The panel color settings component has two properties.
The first property is called Title.
The value for this property will be the double underscore function.
The title will get rendered at the top of the panel.
Let's set the arguments in the double underscore function to the following colors utility plus.
Next we can add a property called Color Settings.
The value for this property will be an array.
The panel color settings can display multiple color options.
We don't need to duplicate this component for each color in our block.
It can handle everything inside this array.
We can add an object for each color.
For example, let's try adding an object.
Inside this object we must add three properties.
First, we must add a property called Label.
Since the panel color settings component can display multiple colors, we should add a label for each
color setting, otherwise the client may not understand each option.
Let's set the label to the double underscore function.
We are going to set the translatable text to the following background color.
The text domain should be set to YouTube plus.
Moving along.
The second property is called value.
Let's set this property to the BG color attribute.
The last property is called on change.
This property is an event.
During this event, let's run a function that accepts the new value parameter.
As the name implies, this event will be fired when a new colour is selected.
The new value parameter stores the new colour on this event.
We should update vb g colour attribute.
Let's update this attribute with the set attributes function inside this function.
Set the BG colour attribute to the new value parameter.
Our first object is finished as an exercise.
Try adding another object for modifying the text color attributes.
The object should look similar to the first object.
Pause the video and give it a try.
Good luck.
Welcome back.
If you're able to add a new object, that's great.
If not, that's fine.
Let's try working on it together.
Inside the array.
Add a second object.
Next, create a property called label.
The value will be translated with the double underscore function.
The translatable text will be the following text color.
Afterward set the text domain to Udemy Plus.
The next property is called value which will set the current colour.
Let's set this property to the text colour attributes.
Lastly, we must add the on change event.
The value for this event will be a function to update the text color attributes.
It will be very similar to the function of the first object instead of updating the BG color attribute.
We are going to update the text color attribute with the new value parameter.
After making those changes, we're finished.
Your solution should be similar to mine.
If the order of the properties is different.
That's completely fine.
As long as you have the same properties, you should be good to go.
Let's save our changes and refresh the experimental page.
In the editor.
I'm going to insert the search form block.
The locks should have been inserted without a problem.
If we select the block, a panel should appear in the sidebar for the block settings.
Immediately you'll notice differences from the previous color palettes.
Unlike previously, we did not provide a custom color palette.
The panel color settings component will borrow the palette from the current theme.
In my opinion, this behavior is preferable.
Clients will not have to switch back and forth between color pickers.
Under this panel, we can modify the background and text colors.
The editor shouldn't throw errors.
As you can see, the panel color settings component is a very powerful component for rendering this
UI.
You may want to use this panel if you have multiple colors.
However, if you need to override a themes color palette, you can stick to using the color palette
component.
Either option is viable.
This lecture is starting to get long.
Starting in the next lecture, let's apply the colors to our template.