In this lecture we will prepare our plugin to load the translations from the languages folder.
At the moment, WordPress does not automatically load translations.
We must instruct WordPress where to find our translations.
Like most situations, there's a hook for loading translations.
Let's get started by opening the main plugin file.
At the bottom of the hook section at an action hook called in it.
WordPress recommends the init hook as the most appropriate hook for loading translations.
The name of our function will be called upload PHP translations.
As the name suggests, we are going to load translations for our PHP code.
Loading translations for the front end is a different process.
For now we are going to focus on loading translations for the server.
Let's create a file called load translations.
PHP inside the includes folder.
Nix.
Define the upload php translations function.
Inside this function, run a function called load plugin text domain.
This function will load the translations for our plugin.
There are three arguments.
The first argument is the text domain.
Let's pass in the utility plus text domain.
The second argument is deprecated.
WordPress does not recommend providing a value for this argument other than false.
The third argument is the path to the languages folder relative to the plugins directory for our plugin.
The path is the following Udemy plus slash languages.
We're finished with registering our translations.
However, we don't have translations for any language.
The file in the languages directory is a template.
The purpose of this file is to be a starting point for translations in other languages.
In the next lecture, let's begin adding a new language.