In this lecture we are going to handle the form submission.
PGP is a language that can easily handle form submissions.
Typically, it's the developer's job to handle most of the steps for processing forms.
P PHP is not like other languages.
It's capable of formatting the data in a variable.
Let's get into it.
The first step is to define a function for handling the form submission.
In the resource section of this lecture, I provide a link to a hook called Admin Post.
This hook will run during form submissions to the admin post PHP file.
It's a dynamic hook.
The placeholder can be replaced with the action of the form.
Let's try adding this hook and your editor open the main plugin file.
At the bottom of the hook section at the admin post hook.
For the placeholder, let's refer to the options page file.
In the form search for the input with the action on this input, the value for this attribute can be
added to the hook.
Let's copy it over to our hook.
Next, let's set the function name to up save options.
The name of the function matches the hook.
This is not required.
It's a personal preference.
I like to keep the name consistent to easily associate the function with the form.
After adding this hook, let's define the function in the include slash admin folder.
Create a file called save options dot php.
Inside this function, let's run a function called print r.
Before updating the data, we are going to verify that our function has intercepted the request.
The printer function allows us to output the contents of an array or object form.
Data is formatted as an array in this function, parsing a variable called post.
Afterward.
Let's exit the scripts.
Let's talk about the post variable.
This is not a feature of WordPress behind the scenes.
PHP will work with the server to retrieve the form data.
Browsers will send data from the input elements in the form.
This data is stored in two types of variables.
If we're sending a git request, the data is stored in a variable called gets data sent with a post
method will be stored in a variable called post.
Other methods do not get dedicated variables.
Let's try submitting the form without modifying the values.
Our function has successfully intercepted the request.
As you can see, the form data has been formatted into an array.
This data will be used for updating our option.
In the next lecture, let's begin updating our function to modify the plugin settings.