In this lecture, we are going to talk about deprivations.
Throughout most of this course, we've developed dynamic blocks there, blocks that use server side
rendering.
If a block was rendered on the client, it's considered static.
Dynamic blocks are easier to work with.
They do not require as much maintenance as static blocks.
If we modify a block, this can cause our block to break in.
The Editor.
This is especially true for static blocks.
It's not something we encounter often but can happen.
Let's look at an example in your editor.
Open the block JSON file.
Inside the attributes.
Let's say the blocks content should be stored in a div tag.
At the moment the content is stored with a paragraph tag.
For this example, change the selector from the P to div.
It's not uncommon to change the template of a block.
You may need to move, add or remove elements after updating the block file.
Our functions should be updated to reflect this change.
Open the edit js file.
Scroll to the rich text component in the function.
Change the tag name properties value to div.
Next, open the saved JS file.
Search for the rich text content component.
Set the tag name property to div.
Let's refresh the page in the browser.
By making a single modification to the template.
Our block is completely broken before a block is rendered on the page.
WordPress Performance BLOCK Validation.
WordPress will output a message on the block.
Validation Failure.
Looking closely, the error states the output of the block failed.
The content generated by the save function is different from the content saved in the database.
Let's talk about the validation process.
After the content has been retrieved by the database, WordPress will begin processing each block.
First, it will extract the attribute values from the template saved in the database.
After every attributes value has been extracted, these values are passed onto the current save function
of the block.
Lastly, the output of the save function is compared with the template from the database.
WordPress performs validation to guarantee that a block has been successfully saved.
If the outputs are different, WordPress may have made a mistake during the extraction process.
Validation is a great solution to help developers upgrade their blocks.
Blocks passing validation means that users can use the latest block version without the block completely
breaking for your convenience.
I formatted the templates produced by the error.
The first template was produced by the save function.
The second template was the template saved in the database.
Notice the difference between them.
The template created by the save function does not contain the content from the original template.
The div tag with the class alert box content does not contain content.
Without validation, the content would have disappeared completely.
Users would experience inconsistent results.
Whenever we update templates, we must provide a smooth upgrade path.
In the next lecture, let's begin working on upgrading the block to the latest version.