In this lecture, we are going to add a new language.
Our translations have been extracted into a single file.
However, this file does not get loaded by WordPress.
The purpose of a pot file is to serve as a starting point.
If you were to look inside this file, there's a lot of information.
It's not common to modify this file directly and said there are dozens of tools available for creating
new languages from the pot file.
In my opinion, the best tool is called Local Translate.
Best of all, it's completely free.
We can download this tool as a plugin in the WordPress admin dashboard.
Navigate to the add new plugin page.
Search for a plugin called Loco Translate.
Install and activate this plugin.
After activation, a new menu item will appear at the bottom of the sidebar called Loco Translate.
Let's click on it.
On this page, we are given a list of themes and plugins with translations.
Technically, all plugins have translations.
However, this plugin will only list plugins that explicitly register a text domain.
Our plugin should appear on this list.
Click on it.
On this page.
We have various options at our disposal.
Let's try adding a new language.
Local translate is capable of scanning our plugin for a hot file.
It can load this file into WordPress with a simple interface for creating a new language from this file.
In addition, local can create the pot file.
However, I've had mixed results with this plugin.
From my experience, generating a pot file with the CLI is more reliable than local translates.
The configuration page will ask us to select the language for our demonstration purposes.
Let's select the French language.
Next we can select a name for our file.
The recommended file name is the name of our plugin, followed by the locale of the language.
The locale is written with the name of the language followed by the region.
Multiple countries can speak the same language.
However, there may be slight differences between pronunciation and tone.
In these cases, countries can have different locales.
The locale for French spoken by France is f, r, f, r.
Local translate will handle setting the locale for you.
You do not need to memorize the locales yourself.
Let's continue with the translations.
We will be taken to a page to translate each piece of text.
We must manually go through each phrase to translate them into French.
I highly recommend hiring a translator for the best results.
For this example, I'm going to translate the word all recipes with Google Translate.
Google may not always provide the most reliable results.
However, it's better than nothing.
I'm not going to translate everything to keep the lecture brief.
After adding my translations, I'm going to click on Save.
At the top of the page, a message will appear.
The message indicates that APO and ML file has been created.
Let's head over to our editors to view these files.
As you can see, dozens of files have been created for our new language.
Our plugin has been successfully translated to French.
The PO file can be considered the official file containing the translations.
The ML file is the finalized version of the translations.
This file will always be loaded by WordPress.
I do not recommend opening this file since it is not readable by humans.
Opening this file may cause it to become corrupted.
Let's test our translations by switching the language on our site.
In the admin dashboard, navigate to the General Settings page.
I'm going to switch my language to French.
After doing so, I'm going to click on the recipe menu.
If we look at the sidebar, the translation has been applied.
Other areas may not have our translation.
Since we didn't translate everything, we've successfully applied our translations.
With the help of a few tools, we can easily apply translations to our plugin.
In the next lecture we are going to wrap up our discussion of translations by loading them for our JavaScript
files.