In this lecture, we will quickly add the toggle control component for toggling the show register attribute
for the off modal block.
I know I could have provided the code for you.
However, I want to give you another opportunity to practice writing components for manipulating attributes.
Let's get started.
The attributes have been prepared ahead of time.
We don't need to add this attribute.
We can begin adding the component inside your editor.
Open the index, not JS file.
At the top of the file.
Let's update the import statement for the components package to include the toggle control components.
Next we can start adding the component to the inspector controls components.
Typically we would add the attributes.
However, I've already included the attributes for you.
We can start inserting this component into the sidebar inside the panel body component and the toggle
control component.
Let's quickly run through the properties.
The label property will be set to the following.
Translatable Text Show Register.
Next set the help property to a ternary operator.
The condition will be the show register attributes.
If the show register attribute is set to true, let's render the following translatable text showing
registration form.
Otherwise, the message will say the following Hiding registration form.
Afterward.
Let's set the check attribute to the show register property.
The property will configure the current value.
Lastly, let's add the on change events to update the attributes.
As usual, we're going to pass in a function to accept the new value.
The argument will be called Show Register.
Inside the function's body, we can call the set attributes function to update the show register attributes.
We're finished.
Let's try refreshing the Gutenberg editor to test the block's options.
Before adding the block.
Let's remove the other blocks from the page.
It's starting to get cluttered.
Next we are going to add the header tools and authentication modal blocks to the page.
Our focus should be on these two blocks.
Upon selecting the authentication modal block, we can toggle the show register attributes for this
course.
We are going to enable the registration form.
As for the header tools blocks, the log and link is enabled after making those changes.
Save the page.
There's not much else to the authentication modal block.
We are going to have a single setting in the next set of lectures.
We are going to work on making the log in and registration forms functional.
This is where things are going to start getting challenging when you're ready.
I'll see you in the next lecture.