In this lecture, we are going to update our function to update the plugin settings.
Before doing so.
We should take the time to secure the form submission.
It's completely possible to spoof our form.
We should take steps to validate the user's permissions in.
Your editor, open the save option.
Stop PHP file.
At the top of the function.
Add a conditional statement with a function called current user can.
First we are going to check the users permissions with the current user can function.
This function we'll check the user's capability.
We can pass any capability as a string.
Let's use the same capability for the menu, which was called edit theme options.
Next, let's add the knot.
Operator If this function returns false, the user does not have permission to submit this form.
But what if the user is not logged in?
In that case, this function will assume the user does not have permission inside this conditional block.
Lets run a function called WP die.
The WP die function will stop a script from executing.
In addition, it'll render a formatted message at the center of the page.
It's better than producing a blank white page inside this function.
Let's pass in the following translated message You are not allowed to be on this page.
This conditional statement should effectively stop unauthorized users from submitting the form.
Next, let's check our knots below the conditional statements.
Run a function called check admin refer.
Our non-school send along with the form.
This function will verify the nonce.
If the nonce is invalid, the function will immediately kill the script.
Let's pass in the name of the knots which was called up options verify.
After verifying the validity of the form submission, we can finally start updating our plugins options
below.
This function create a variable called options.
The value for this variable will be the get options function with a name of our option.
Next, let's update the OG title item with the sanitized text field function.
In this function, we can pass in the post up OG title variable.
As usual, we're sanitizing our data before inserting it into the database.
Sanitising data is optional.
The options API will automatically sanitise data on your behalf.
However, it doesn't hurt to sanitise the data ourselves.
The form data can be found within the post variable.
The values for each input can be found under their respective name.
The value of the name attribute will be the name of the key in the array.
You can refer to the options page file for the list of names.
After setting the title, let's update the OG image option to the sanitize URL function with the post
up OG image variable.
I'm using a new function called sanitized URL for sanitizing a URL.
Next, let's update the OG description option to the sanitize text field function with the post up OG
description variable.
Lastly, let's set the enable OG option to the ABS end function with the post up enable ogg variable.
The options variable is ready.
We can begin updating the options with a function called update option.
This function will perform a query for updating a specific record in the WP options table.
There are two arguments.
The first argument is the name of the option.
Let's pass in up options.
Next, we need to refine the new value for this option.
Let's pass in the options variable.
After updating the options, we should redirect the user back to the form.
WordPress has a special function for helping us redirect the user below the update option function run
the WP redirect function.
This function has one argument.
It's a valid http url.
The user will be redirected to this URL.
In this function, let's pass in a function called admin URL.
The form is located in the admin dashboard.
The admin URL function will generate a path to the current site's admin dashboard.
It has one argument which is optional.
We can point to a specific page within the dashboard pass in the following path.
Admin page.
PHP question mark page equals.
The Admin P file is responsible for displaying various pages from the dashboard.
We can specify a page by adding a query parameter called page.
The value for this parameter must be the ID or slug of the page.
And the fourth argument of this function we passed in the ID of the page.
This value appears as the value for the page query parameter.
Let's copy and paste this value into the admin URL function.
There's one more parameter we will add to the URL.
Add a parameter called status with a value of one.
The user should be notified that their submission was a success.
If this query parameter exists within the URL.
The page will display a message to the user.
Let's update the options page file.
Scrawled to the h one elements below this element.
Add a pair of PHP tags.
Next, add a conditional statement.
The condition will be.
The following is set.
Get status and get status.
Equals equals one.
The EGP will store query parameters in the get variable as an array.
Each query parameter will be added as a key to the array.
We can reference the query parameter by its name and this example we're performing two conditions.
The first condition will check for the existence of the status parameter.
If it does, we can proceed to the second condition, which is to check the value.
Keep in mind PHP follows a fast exit strategy.
The order of conditions does matter.
If the first condition fails, PHP will not perform the second condition.
Reversing the conditions will cause an error.
Attempting to access an item in a variable that doesn't exist will cause PHP to throw an error.
For this reason, it's considered good practice to check the existence of the variable before comparing
it to other values.
Let's render a message inside the conditional block.
We can safely assume that the form was submitted successfully.
Additive tag with the following classes.
Notice.
Success in line.
These classes will produce notices in WordPress that are defined by WordPress.
I recommend checking out the WordPress admin styles plugin for a complete list of notice classes.
Next, add a pair of paragraph tags.
Inside these tags, run the escape html e function with the following message options updated successfully.
We're finished with our form.
It's time to resubmit the form.
Your browser should allow you to resubmit the form by refreshing the page.
If it doesn't just submit it through the page, I'm going to quickly refresh the page.
After doing so, the values should remain the same.
Above the form, the notice appears with our message.
Perfect.
We've successfully submitted the form.
We're not done yet.
The last steps are to update the image.
At the moment, clicking on this button does nothing.
In the next lecture.
Let's finalize our form by working on the image.