In this lecture we are going to update the PHP render function for the authentication modal block.
We've repeated this step numerous times.
We are always going to be using output buffers for rendering a block on the server.
I think it would be a good idea to create a code snippet to expedite this process.
Let's get started in your editor.
Open the authentication modal PHP file.
Inside this function, we are going to quickly create the output buffer.
Let's call the OB start function to open the buffer.
Next, add closing and opening up tags.
Afterward create a variable called outputs.
The value for this variable will be the return value of the object contents function.
Let's close the buffer by using the OB and clean function.
Lastly, let's return the output variable.
This is the standard setup for adding buffers.
It's not going to change for the rest of this course.
Repeatedly writing these lines of code can feel monotonous.
Let's convert these lines into a snippet, select the inner contents of the function, but do not select
the function itself during the selection.
Include the indentation for the first line, otherwise it will not be included.
Next under the View Menu.
Select the command palette option.
Search for a command called generate snippets.
For the name of snippets, let's call it block output buffer.
The scope option can be left empty.
We do not need it.
Next, we can add a prefix.
Let's set the prefix to block output buffer.
Lastly, we can give a description.
Set the description to the following.
Adds an output buffer for blocks.
After entering our options, the snippets should have been generated.
Let's add our snippet to Visual Studio code under the file menu.
Navigate to preferences.
User Snippets.
Visual Studio code will ask for a specific file type.
Our snippet is written with PHP.
Let's select PHP from the list.
Inside the JSON object.
Paste the snippet at the bottom.
After adding the snippets, we can begin using it immediately.
Let's try testing our snippets back inside the PHP file.
Let's remove the inner contents of the function.
Next, let's begin typing our prefix.
As we do so, the option for adding the snippet will become available.
If we select this snippet, the file will be pre-filled with our code.
Awesome snippets can work for any language.
We're not restricted to a specific file type.
The final step for our function is to add the templates in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to the templates.
From this gist.
Copy the template to your clipboard.
Next.
Head back to the editor inside the buffer zone.
Let's insert the template.
The template is very large.
You'll be able to view the design after we've refreshed the page in the browser.
Before we do, let's conditionally render the registration form.
As a reminder, we provided the option for disabling the registration form at the top of the function.
Let's grab the attributes by adding the attributes arguments.
Next we are going to disable the link for the registration form.
As you'll soon see, the forms are wrapped with tabs.
Visitors will be able to switch between forms.
You must conditionally render the tab for the registration form.
You can find the tab by searching for a comment that says Register Tab.
Under this comment, we are going to find a list item element.
This element should be conditionally rendered.
Above the comment enter pvp mode.
Next, add in if statements.
Inside the condition of the if statements.
We are going to check if the show register attribute is true.
Inside the block of code.
Add closing and opening.
PHP tags.
Lastly, let's move the list item element inside the conditional block.
We've taken care of the tab.
However, the form will continue to appear.
The form should be conditionally rendered to inside the template.
You can find the form by searching for an HTML comment that says Register form.
Below this comment.
There is a form element.
This entire element should be conditionally rendered.
The process is going to be exactly the same as before.
Enter php mode above the comment.
Add in if statement with the show register attribute as the condition.
In search.
Closing and opening tags.
Lastly, move the form into the conditional block.
After making those changes, we can finally test our block and your browser refresh the experimental
page.
Initially, the authentication modal block will not be visible by default.
I've hidden the modal with CSS.
We can temporarily view the modal by modifying the CSS and the developer tools.
Open the elements panel.
Search for an element with a class called WP BLOCK Utility plus off modal.
On the sidebar search for the styles that we've applied to this element.
There are a few properties.
However, the property we care about is the display property.
Let's disable this property from the element.
After doing so, the model should appear on the page.
You should be presented with the same UI element as me.
Perfect.
By default, the registration form should appear if it isn't double check list settings for the block.
You may have accidentally disabled it.
After verifying the block has been added, we can start to work on the forms in the next lecture.
We are going to begin with the registration form.