In this lecture, we will begin rendering the template for our block.
The process will be very simple.
The data is readily available.
Our job is to loop through the data with the templates in the block.
Let's get started in your editor.
Open the index JS file.
Next scroll to the diff with a class called Single Post.
This tag contains the template for displaying a single post for each item in the posts array.
We are going to render this element.
Let's create the loop above the div tag.
Add the following expression posts.
Question mark dot map.
The Post's variable may be null.
If that's the case, the map function will not be available.
This function is only available for arrays.
Next, let's pass in a function to handle each loop.
Let's refer to each item in the array as post.
Within this function, let's return the templates, cut and paste the template into the return statement.
The next step is to update the template to dynamically render the values.
Let's start with the image.
Not all posts will have an image.
Images are entirely optional.
Before rendering the image, we should check for an image.
Define a variable called featured image.
The value for this variable is going to be very long.
Type the following code post dot underscore embedded and post dot underscore embedded WP Colon Featured
Media and post dot underscore embedded WP Colon Featured Media Length Greater than zero and Post dot
underscore embedded WP Colon Featured Media zero.
Pause the video if you need to copy this value.
Let me break down what's going on.
First, we're checking the post for the underscore embedded property.
This property contains information on the featured image.
If this property does not exist, we cannot grab the image.
The second condition we'll check the underscore embedded property for a property called WP Colon Featured
Media.
Once again, if this property does not exist, we won't be able to grab the image.
Next, we're checking the length of the WP Colon featured media property.
This property is an array of images.
Typically there's only one image.
If the array is empty, we can assume the image does not exist on the post.
Lastly, we're grabbing the first item in the array, which is an object representing the featured image.
You're more than welcome to launch this variable to view this information.
Admittedly, it is a hassle to grab this information.
Let's move on to rendering the image in the templates.
There is an anchor element with a class called single post image.
Above this element.
Add an expression to conditionally render the image with the following code featured image and.
Next move the anchor element after the and operator.
If the featured image variable is empty, we don't have an image, therefore nothing should be rendered.
Let's assume there is an image.
We can proceed to update the template with the values from the post data.
First, set the h rf attribute to the post dot link property.
The link property contains the URL to the post.
If you're curious about how I know where to find this information, you can always log the post variable.
It's as simple as looking through the data to find what you're looking for.
Next, let's update the image elements source attribute to the following value.
Featured Image dot media details dot.
Sizes dot.
Thumbnail dot.
Source URL.
In this example, we're grabbing the images thumbnail URL in addition to the URL.
It's considered good practice to set the alt attributes.
The value for this attribute will be the featured image alt text property.
The image is ready.
Let's work on rendering the title of the post and author below.
This expression There's another anchor element set the ref attribute to the post dot link property.
Inside this element, we can render the Post's title with the following expression Post dot title dot
rendered.
The rendered property can contain HTML by defaults.
React does not allow HTML to be inserted from an expression.
It's extremely dangerous to allow data sources to insert HTML into a component's templates.
However, WordPress will store the title of a post with a HTML.
If we were to enter this expression, the HTML would be escaped.
The title may appear awkwardly.
To get around this, React has a component for addressing this issue at the top of the file.
Import a component called raw HTML from the WordPress slash element package.
The raw HTML component will render an expression without escaping the HTML.
Let's head back to the expression for the title.
Let's wrap the expression with the raw HTML component.
Like I said before, it's not considered good practice to render HTML in a block.
Unfortunately, WordPress does not give us a choice.
The last piece of information to render is the author.
Let's update the ref attribute to the post dot link property.
Lastly, we replace the inner checks of the anchor element with the following expression post dot underscore.
Embedded dot author zero dot name.
Once again, we are grabbing this information for the underscore embedded property.
Unlike the image, we're not going through the process of checking the properties for values.
Every post will have an author.
It's improbable for a post to be submitted anonymously.
I don't think it's necessary to perform checks on this chain of properties.
The author property will be an array of authors since a single post can have multiple authors.
In this example, we are grabbing the first author of the post.
Let's proceed to give our block one final test in the browser.
Refresh the page.
Next, add the popular recipes block.
Initially the list of posts will be empty.
The request is still being processed.
After a few moments, the list of posts will appear.
You can freely modify the block to update this list.
For example, let's try filtering the posts by a taxonomy term.
This time, the list of recipes is different.
Our block is working exactly as intended.
Perfect.
The last step is to render the block on the front end with server side rendering.
Before moving on to the next lecture, I'm going to save the post with the block.
You should do the same in the next lecture.
Let's begin rendering the block with PHP.