In this lecture, we are going to add the media library to our page for the team members.
BLOCK We added the media library pop up for selecting an image.
This library is not exclusive to the Gutenberg editor.
We can render the library on other pages.
First, we need to interview the files.
WordPress already registers the script we can jump straight into and cueing them in your editor.
Open the index plug and file.
WordPress has a hook for interviewing files on the admin dashboard at the bottom of the Hooks section.
Add an action hook called Admin and Q Scripts.
The name of our function will be called up admin and queue.
Next.
Let's define this function in the includes slash admin directory.
Create a file called nq php.
Define the up admin and q function.
This function will run on every admin page.
That's not what we want.
We shouldn't queue files for other admin pages.
Luckily, this function will be given an argument called hook suffix.
Let's add it to the function.
This variable contains the name of the current admin page.
Every page is given a name, including custom pages.
Let's echo this variable onto the page to inspect its value.
Next, refresh the custom admin page.
The variables value may be obscured behind the menu.
To view the full value, you may need to inspect the body tag in the elements panel of the developer
tools.
The text should appear at the top of the body tag.
Let's copy this name to our clipboard.
Next.
Head back to the editor inside the function and add a conditional statement.
The condition will check if the hook suffix variable is equal to our page's name.
Inside the conditional lock on a function called WP in Q media.
Typically we would call the WP and Q script function to add a script to the page.
However, the media library has a few dependencies to save time.
WordPress has defined a function for queuing everything at once called WP Ink Media.
Let's try refreshing the page.
Initially, nothing seems like it's changed.
Before moving on, we should verify the files have been added to the browser and the developer tools.
Search for an ID called Media Editor JS.
If a script tag has this ID, this means you include the files for the media library.
That's great.
We can begin opening the media library whenever the user clicks on the button.
On the page.