In this lecture we are going to recreate the mid section of our header.
The process is going to be the same as before.
Currently I'm viewing the home page on the front end to get a good idea of what we need.
Let's quickly review this section of the page.
We're going to need blocks for the logo, search form and login link.
Simple enough, right?
Let's check out the templates.
In your editor, you can open the parts slash header, HTML file inside this file.
You're going to find a comment that says mid section from the HTML block.
This part of the template contains the mid section of our header on my screen.
I have a simplified version of the mid section before inserting the blocks for the content of the mid
section.
We must wrap them with an element that will center the blocks into the center of the page.
Unlike before, we don't need to worry about the background color, therefore we can get away with using
a row block.
An extra group block will not be necessary.
The row block will contain the classes from the div tag.
Let's try adding the roadblock to the header.
The roadblock should sit between the first roadblock and HTML block.
Make sure the new block does not get nested with other blocks.
It should be added to the root level of the template.
Next, we're going to modify the block settings.
The classes that exist on the original div tag will apply several properties similar to before the block
settings can configure most of these properties, therefore we're going to apply them through the settings
by default.
WordPress uses Flexbox to organize elements in a row.
We can configure the content justification under the layout panel.
Set the justification to space between.
This setting will evenly distribute the children blocks with the justified content CSS property.
Next, we're going to disable the ramp option.
This option will set the flex rap CSS property to no rap, thus preventing children blocks from appearing
on a new line.
We are trying to restrict the blocks into a single line without overflowing.
Up next, we are going to modify the dimensions of the block.
One of the classes adds padding.
We are going to set the top and bottom padding properties to 1.25 REM.
The left and right sides of the block will be set to zero.
In some cases, WordPress may add awkward margin spacing to the block.
To prevent this from happening, we should reset the margins to zero.
You can find the margin settings under the dropdown menu for the dimensions panel.
All margin values should be set to zero.
Lastly, the block spacing should be set to zero since there's enough breathing room for the elements
without it.
All values are based on the CST properties from our classes, we're simply transferring them.
The last step is to apply the classes that don't have settings and the HTML block search for the root
element of the mid section.
We're going to copy all classes from the div tag.
Next, switch back to the roadblock under the advanced panel.
Add the classes.
The following classes can be removed.
Flex.
Flex no wrap items centre pi five justify between.
These classes are not necessary anymore.
The lock will handle configuring these properties for us.
We can begin to add additional blocks to the row block.
As mentioned before, the image section comprises the logo search form and login link.
Let's go through them one by one.
The first block should be the logo.
We have two options at our disposal.
Logos can be created with text or images.
Our theme is going to support both options to get started.
We're going to use a text logo.
If our theme is installed on a fresh site, clients may not have a logo ready.
Let's add the site title block to the row block.
Afterward, we will configure this block to match our static design.
For reference, here's the HTML for the logo.
We're applying three classes called Text Red, 500 font bold and text three Excel.
These classes will modify the color, font, weight and font size of our logo.
Luckily, we enabled all typography settings for our theme.
We can modify these styles without resorting to classes.
On the sidebar, we're going to modify various settings.
First, we're going to enable the link setting.
The logo should be clickable afterward.
Set the link color to Udemy Primary.
Next, let's modify the typography settings.
The font size should be custom.
The value for the font size is 1.875 REM.
Update the appearance option to bold.
Lastly, toggle the line height option.
After doing so, the value should be set to 2.25.
This should effectively match our design.
Transferring the classes from the element to the block is not necessary.
However, once again, it'll be easier for clients to modify these settings without knowledge of CSS.
We've achieved the desired effect.
Let's move on to the search form inside the row block.
Add a new block called Search.
The search bloc will add a search form to the header.
However, it's not as flexible as we may need it to be.
Unfortunately, it offers minimal options for modifying its properties.
As a result, we will need to heavily rely on classes.
For reference, here's the original markup found in the header html file.
The form is very minimal.
For this example, I've kept it simple to a single class.
Let's apply this class to our block.
Under the advanced panel.
Add the header search form class to the block.
Nothing's going to change with the editor.
There's a good reason for that.
We'll get into the details in the next lecture.
For now, let's keep moving forward.
There's one final UI element in the mid section.
Switching over to the front end, we have a link for logging in.
The UI is more complicated than the other elements.
We have icons, different font sizes, background colors, etc. Creating this UI with WordPress blocks
is going to be difficult.
It's going to involve several group blocks.
Creating a UI with multiple nested group blocks can be difficult to maintain in these cases.
There are two options at your disposal.
In an earlier lecture, I described the process for transforming a static template into a block template.
There's one step that was overlooked for complex UI elements.
It won't be possible to follow the first three steps.
Therefore, you must either use the HTML block or create a custom lock.
Trying to use several group blocks will make your life hard, even if you manage to recreate the UI.
It's not going to be easy to customize.
Furthermore, modifying the structure can break the entire element.
For this reason, it's better just to use raw HTML or create a custom block.
I know I've said this before, but I promise we are going to get into custom block development in a
future section.
For now we are going to use the HTML block in your text editor, open the header dot HTML file.
Search for an HTML comment that says header tools.
The log in element is housed under a single div tag with a class called Flex.
Let's copy the entire div tag.
Next.
Head back to the Gutenberg editor at the end of the row.
BLOCK for the middle section.
Insert the HTML block.
Inside the block paste the HTML.
Lastly, you can save the templates.
This solution is not ideal.
The presentation of the template is not clear until viewing the front end switch over to the front end
and refresh the page.
After a few moments, the header should look closer to the original header.
Slowly but surely the page is coming together in the next lecture.
Let's fix some of the issues with the editor.