In this lecture, let's begin working on finishing the popular recipes block by rendering it with the
server.
We've taken the first steps of accomplishing this task by defining a function for rendering the block
in your editor.
Open the popular recipes dot PHP file.
First things first.
Let's grab the attributes by accepting the attributes argument.
Next we can begin extracting the attributes, starting with the title.
Create a variable called title.
The value for this variable will be the escape html function with the attributes title variable.
As usual, we are escaping the title before rendering it on the screen.
This step is to reduce the likelihood of malicious HTML being inserted into the document.
Next, let's grab the cuisine IDs.
Create a variable called cuisine IDs.
The value for this variable should be an array of cuisine IDs in our attributes.
We're storing an array of objects where each object represents a term from the cuisine taxonomy.
Let's create a new array where each item is the ID.
Let's set this variable to the return value of the array map function.
This function is defined by the PHP language.
The array map function will loop through an array.
On each iteration, we can return a new value to replace the current value of the item.
For our purpose, we're trying to grab the ID.
There are two arguments which is a function for handling each iteration of the loop and the array.
Let's pass in an anonymous PHP function.
Next pass in the attributes cuisine's variable.
The function passed into the array map function will be given each item in the array.
Let's reference each item as an argument called term.
Within the function.
Let's return the term ID item.
Technically the items in the array are objects.
However, WordPress will convert the JavaScript objects into PHP arrays.
The property name will be converted into an array key.
We can reference a specific item from the object by its name as an array key.
The value returned by this function will be a new array of term IDs.
We can finally begin initiating the query for posts.
Previously, WordPress would create the query for us.
We did not have to create the query ourselves with the rest API.
This time we must manually create the query with the WP query class.
After the variables define a variable called query, the value for this variable will be a new instance
of the WP query class.
New instances of a class can be configured by passing data inside the parentheses.
We haven't had the opportunity to discuss this feature.
However, the PHP classes can support arguments similar to functions by default.
WordPress will query the database for a list of posts for our block.
We're not interested in posts, so let's modify the query by passing in an array above the query variable.
Define a variable called arguments with an initial value of an array.
The query can be modified with an array.
In this array we can add parameters documented on the page for the WP query class.
Most of these parameters are going to be familiar to us.
First, let's filter the posts by the recipe post type by setting the post type key to recipe.
Next, we can limit the number of posts to retrieve by setting the posts per page key.
The value for this key will be the attributes count variable.
After limiting the results, we can start sorting the results by the rating of the recipe.
Set the order by parameter to meta value num.
Next set the meta key parameter to recipe rating.
Lastly, set the order key to descending.
The query is almost ready.
There's one piece of information to add to the query.
The results should be filtered by a specific taxonomy term.
If the block has cuisine IDs, the query must be altered to filter the results below.
The arguments variable create a conditional statement with the following condition not empty cuisine
IDs.
Before altering the query.
We're checking the cuisine IDs variable.
It's possible that the user may not want to filter their results by a specific cuisine.
If that's the case, the query should not be altered.
If the array contains at least one value, we can begin modifying the query in the conditional block.
Let's add a new key called tax query.
A new item can be pushed into an array with this syntax.
We do not need a function to push items into an array.
Pjp is very flexible with its arrays.
The value for this new item will be in array within this array.
We can add more arrays with configuration settings in each child array.
We can filter the results by a specific taxonomy.
As you know, a post type can have multiple taxonomies.
The query can be refined for multiple taxonomies.
However, in our case, we're interested in filtering the results by the cuisine taxonomy.
Inside this array, let's add a parameter called taxonomy.
Set this parameter to cuisine.
Next, we need to specify the field to filter the recipes by taxonomy.
Terms can be sorted by their name, slug or ID.
We only have their ids, so let's set the field parameter to term ID.
As a reminder, the information for these parameters can be found on the WP Query Class Documentation
page.
Next, let's add a parameter called terms.
The value for this parameter will be the cuisine IDs variable.
Let me break down the query we've created.
Starting from the Loop, we're performing a query for recipe posts.
The number of results should not exceed ten posts.
The order of the recipes will be sorted by their ratings.
The highest rated recipe will appear at the top of the array.
If the posts should be filtered by a specific taxonomy term, we are adding to the query by adding the
tax query parameter.
In this parameter, we are filtering the posts further by a set of terms within the cuisine taxonomy.
Overall, we have a query for grabbing the most highly rated recipes on our site.
Let's pass on the arguments variable to the new instance of the WP query class.
After the instance has been created, WordPress will initiate a query to the database.
This query will return a list of posts which are stored in the query variable.
We are starting to run short on time.
In the next lecture, let's begin looping through the results.