In this lecture we will cover one more feature of PHP before moving on to WordPress.
It's a very simple feature called Comments.
PHP comments serve the same purpose as HTML and CSS comments.
They are a feature for providing notes and documentation in our code.
There are two syntax for writing comments.
The first syntax is called a single line comment.
Single line comments are written with two forward slash characters.
Single line comments apply to one line.
If we attempted to write more text after the comments, it wouldn't be interpreted as a comment.
Instead, it will be interpreted as code leading to errors.
For example, above the defined function.
Lets add a single line comments.
My editor highlights the text as green.
Your editor may highlight it differently.
Regardless, we've written a comment.
Anything goes on this line, subsequent lines remain unaffected by our comment.
In some cases, you may want to write a long comment.
Single line comments aren't suited for this type of action.
The second syntax is called a block comment, which allows us to write multiple lines of comments.
They're written with forward, slash and asterisk characters.
Here's an example.
BLOCK comments when she opened and closed with the same characters.
In between these characters, we can write as much gibberish as we'd like.
Some developers like to add an asterisk character on every line.
This does not do anything.
It's just a style preference that about does it for comments.
It's time to jump into WordPress.
See you in the next lecture.