In this lecture, we are going to start getting into dual tones.
This is probably one of the most interesting features for customizing a site with colors.
The idea of a duotone is simple.
A duotone is a filter that can be applied to images or videos.
Essentially, the filter applies to colors.
On this slide I provided some examples.
Do tones are similar to Instagram filters, but there is a big difference.
An Instagram filter will adjust the color levels of an image, whereas a duotone filter will completely
override the colors of an image.
For this reason, duo tones are recommended for images with high contrast.
This feature can be cool, but be warned this feature is experimental.
The WordPress team has stated that there are some bugs.
You should be cautious with this feature.
Regardless, let's learn how to add duo tones to our theme.
In your editor, open the theme JSON file by default.
Dual tones are enabled.
We can apply them to blocks that add images to a template such as the image cover and site logo blocks
similar to colors.
We have the option of adding custom duo tones.
Let's give that a try.
Inside the color object, add a property called Duotone.
Its value will be an array.
This format for adding a duotone tone is similar to registering a colour.
The array must contain a list of objects with the properties, slug colours and name.
Let's add our first duotone for the slug.
Let's set the ID to you.
Pink sunset.
Next, add an array called colors.
Here's where things become different.
Duo tones are created with two colors, which are the shadow and highlight.
The shadow represents the dark color and the highlight represents the lighter color.
Inside this array, we must add shadow and highlight in this order.
If you forget the order, you can hover your mouse over the colors array for a hint.
Keep in mind duo tones offer limited support for color values.
Only hex and RGV values are accepted.
The colors for our duo tone will be the following 11245e and DC 4379.
Lastly, let's give our Duotone a name.
The name will be the following to me.
Pink sunset.
Before testing our dual tone, let's learn how to disable this feature in our theme.
As I said before, dual tones are available for most blocks that have images.
The cover block is one example.
Lets disable dual tone for this block in the blocks object.
Add a property called Core Slash cover.
To save time, I will give you the name of the cover block.
You can verify the name with the reference inside this object.
Add the color object.
There are two settings for completely disabling the block.
The first setting is the dual tone property.
If you were to add this property without a series of dual tones, WordPress would not provide a list
of duotone colours.
However, users will be able to select custom duotone colors.
We can disable the custom color picker for duo tones by setting the custom duotone option to false.
Alternatively, you can disable the custom color picker while providing a series of dual tones.
It's completely up to you.
Let's try testing our new features in the browser.
I'm going to quickly upload an image through the image block.
A dual tone can be applied to an image from the toolbar.
If we were to select this option, our dual tone should appear as an option.
Let's try applying it to our image.
Pretty cool, right?
Duo tones can be a great way to enhance the appearance of an image.
There's not much else to say about duo tones.
They are an experimental feature for applying colorful effects to an image.