In this lecture, we are going to explore a raise.
I bet you can guess what an array is without looking at the syntax we learned about them in PHP.
Arrays are a feature for storing a collection or group of data.
Creating an array is super simple with JavaScript as usual, we are going to continue working with the
snippets file from the developer tools.
There are various options for creating an array.
However, the preferred solution is to use square brackets inside the script.
Create a variable called states.
The value for this variable will be a pair of square brackets.
By setting the variable to a pair of square brackets, JavaScript will assign an array to the variable.
At the moment our variable is empty.
We're not restricted by the type of values that can be inserted into the array, strings, numbers,
booleans, etc. Inside our array, let's store a list of states.
Next, let's try rendering an item from the array below the array.
Run the alert function.
Inside the function, we can reference a specific item from the array by typing a pair of square brackets.
JavaScript uses zero based indexes for its array.
Therefore, the first item of the array can be retrieved with zero.
The second item has an index of one.
The last item has an index of two, so on and so forth.
Let's grab the second item in the array by typing one.
Lastly, let's try running our script.
The alert box will contain the second state from our array.
Another feature checked off our list in upcoming lectures.
We're going to start getting into more advanced features.
When you're ready, I'll see you in the next lecture.