In this lecture we will modify the character set of our document similar to before.
The character set should be dynamic.
Luckily WordPress stores the character set for a site in its database.
The goal is to grab this information and render it in the browser.
As always, WordPress has a function for addressing this specific problem.
In the resource section of this lecture, I provide a link to a function called log info.
The blog info function can retrieve data from the database.
It is limited, but it can grab the character set to better understand.
Let's read the documentation together.
The best skill you can pick up as a developer is to learn how to read the documentation according to
the description.
The function will display information about the current site.
The most useful section is the parameters section.
The parameter section will provide a list of values we can pass into a function.
In this example, the blog info function has a parameter called Show.
The show parameter allows us to specify the type of value to display on the page.
We'll find more information under the more information section.
WordPress will provide a complete list of values that we can pass into the function.
Different values will be rendered based on the value passed in.
If we look through the list, we will come across an option for grabbing the character set called care
set.
Perfect.
It's exactly what we were looking for.
Let's give it a try in your editor.
Open the indexed PHP file.
The meta tag for adding the character set is already in our templates.
The blog info function will output the value but not the entire meta tag.
Therefore, we need to write the function inside the character set attributes.
Replace the value with PHP tags.
Next call the blog info function.
Lastly, we can pass in a string to the function.
The character set can be retrieved by passing in a string called care set.
Time to test our code in your browser.
Refresh the page.
We can verify the character set has been added by viewing the elements panel in the Developer Tools.
Search for the meta tag in the head tag.
As expected, the character set has been correctly configured.
In most cases, the character set should be UTF eight.
It accepts a wide range of characters.
Let's continue working on our template in the next lecture.