In this lecture, we will finalize the search form block by adding dynamic data to the form.
Let's examine the form in the browser above the input.
We have static text.
Inside this text, we should render the search term written by the user.
This term should appear inside the input.
Two.
Lastly, the form should be fully functional.
If a user submits our form, the page should refresh with the search results.
Luckily, WordPress offers various functions to help us achieve the desired output.
It's going to be a breeze.
Let's get started in your editor.
Open the search form php file.
Let's start from the top and work our way down.
First, let's update the H one tag from the templates.
The word search should be replaced with PHP tags.
Do not remove the colon character from the text.
It'll act as a separator.
Next, let's run a function called Underscore E.
WordPress has dozens of functions for translating texts throughout this course.
We are going to explore most of them.
The first function we encountered was called the double underscore function.
It's the most straightforward function available for translating texts.
It'll return a translated string.
The underscore e function will echo the translated text, not return it.
However, there's one problem with this function.
It will not escape the output.
As mentioned in the previous lecture, we should attempt to escape output from our blocks.
This includes translated strings.
Fortunately, there's another function for escaping the output of a translated string called Escape
html.
E.
The escape html e function will perform the task as the underscore e function.
In addition, it'll strip HTML tags from the string.
This can be a great way to prevent unsafe content from appearing on the page.
The arguments for this function are the same as the double underscore function.
Let's pass in the word search as the translation.
The text domain should be set to Udemy plus.
After translating the text.
Let's move on to the other portion of the text.
The search term should be added after the colon character.
Let's add a pair of PHP tags.
Inside these tags, we are going to run a function called the search query.
The search query function is considered a template tag.
In the resource section of this lecture, I provide a link to a complete list of template tags.
A template tag refers to a function for rendering a template to the page.
They're mainly utilized from within themes.
However, it's perfectly safe to use them from within plugins.
As I mentioned before, WordPress allows developers to access the same APIs from plugins and themes.
Template tags will output various pieces of information.
For example, we can output the title of a post, a list of categories or render comments.
If you were to explore the various functions listed on the documentation page, you may notice a pattern.
WordPress defines two functions for grabbing the same value.
For example, there are two functions for grabbing the user's search query.
We can use the the search query function or the get search query function.
The first function will echo the search query, whereas the second function will return the search query.
Aside from those differences, the value will be the same.
Functions that begin with the word get will always return the value.
If a function begins with the word the, you can expect the value to be echoed on the page.
For example, there is another set of functions for grabbing the title of a post.
The the title function will echo the post title in comparison.
The get the title function will return the post title.
Feel free to explore the other functions.
For now, let's keep working on the form.
The H one tag is complete.
We can start working on the form element.
The form must be submitted to the home page.
The home page will be responsible for accepting the search submission.
Let's look at a demonstration by using the search form in the header.
Keep in mind this form comes bundled with the core of WordPress.
I'm going to search for a random word.
Looking closely at the URL, we can clearly see where the request is being sent to.
By default, WordPress will send the request to the home page.
It uses a query parameter for storing the search term.
The name of the query parameter is called TSS, which is short for search.
Our block should send the form data to this URL.
Let's head back to the editor.
On the form element.
Add an attribute called action.
The action attribute will tell the browser where to send the form data.
Let's set the value to the following code in a php tag.
Echo Escape URL home url forward slash.
We are using two functions for producing a URL to the home page.
The home URL function will return a URL relative to the home page.
This function accepts a path.
We're telling WordPress to return the root path by passing in a forward slash character.
Next, we are passing on the value to the escape URL function.
This function will strip characters that aren't related to a URL.
Lastly, we're echoing the results.
We're not finished yet.
The data is being sent to the correct URL.
However, the input element must be updated to add a query parameter.
On the input element, add an attribute called name with a value of s.
By adding the name attribute, the browser will store the value from the input in a query parameter.
The name of the parameter can be configured through this attribute.
The query parameter must be called SE.
WordPress is expecting this query parameter name.
Otherwise the search results page will have nothing.
Afterward, let's pre fill the input with the search query.
This way visitors will be able to modify their search queries, add the value attribute to the input
element.
The value for this attribute will be the the search query function.
You may be wondering why aren't we escaping the value from this function?
It's because WordPress already escapes the value in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to the the search query function documentation page.
If we scroll to the source section, the official function definition can be found.
Looking closely at the return statement, the value is being escaped with the escape attribute function.
It's always good practice to read through the code of WordPress to verify the behavior of a function.
Let's head back to the editor.
There's one last step and the placeholder attribute and the inner text of the button element.
We are outputting the word search.
This text should be replaced with a translation function.
Luckily, we've already prepared the translation.
Let's copy and paste the translated text into these two locations.
Our block is finished.
However, we can't test our block yet.
The template needs to be updated to use this block.
Let's start adding the block to the template in the next lecture.