In this lecture.
Let's talk about what's coming next.
PHP is a language designed to render dynamic HTML pages.
This section has covered the most common features you'll use in WordPress development.
If you understood everything thus far, you're well on your way to becoming a professional WordPress
developer.
Before moving forward, I want to set your expectations.
It's entirely possible to create sites without WordPress.
After all, WordPress is written with PHP.
There's nothing stopping us from creating our own system for generating pages.
However, WordPress is not just popular with users but with developers.
WordPress introduces a complete suite of APIs for extending its behavior.
We can leverage WordPress system to create the additional features.
Therefore, it's not necessary to learn every feature in PHP.
WordPress Abstracts The Complicated Technical Details.
As you'll soon discover, we can tailor WordPress behavior with a few lines of code.
Is a complex language with hundreds of features, there's a lot to discover.
Despite that, we're going to jump into WordPress.
I don't want this course to get too dull.
Therefore I'll be introducing additional PHP features as we work on the master project for this course.
If there's something you felt was missing, don't worry, we may cover it in a future lecture.
Our PHP journey doesn't end here.
I hope you're excited.
I know I am.
When you're ready.
I'll see you in the next section.