In this lecture, we are going to begin looping through the results in the query variable before writing
a single line of code.
I want to quickly mention a concept called the Loop.
WordPress has a term to refer to what we're doing in our block.
The idea of querying the database for posts and looping through the results is known as the Loop.
This concept is mainly for theme developers.
However, it can apply to plug in developers too.
This documentation page will describe the proper method for querying the database and looping through
the results.
Feel free to read through this page for more info.
For this lecture we are going to be adhering to the process recommended on this page.
Let's get started in your editor.
Open the popular recipes dot php file.
Inside the function.
We will begin writing the template after the OB start function.
The block will be wrapped with a div tag.
This tag will have a class called WP BLOCK Utility plus popular recipes.
Next we can render the title by adding a pair of H six tags.
Inside these tags, let's echo the title variable.
Afterward, we can begin displaying the posts for this task.
We need to go back into PHP mode inside a pair of PHP tags.
Add a conditional statement.
On the query object.
There's a method called have posts.
Let's call this function from within the conditional statement.
Before looping through the results, we should check the query for results.
It's possible that WordPress may not have been able to find recipes.
In this case, we should not bother looping through the results.
This function will return a boolean value.
If there are results, the value will be true.
Inside this conditional block, we can begin looping through the data with a while loop.
Inside the wild loop called the have posts function again.
Once again, we're calling the half posts function.
The half post function performs another action.
It'll check if the posts have been looped through.
If every post has been looped through, this function will return false, thus causing the loop to end.
At the moment, the loop will run infinitely.
We are not moving on to the next post in the wild block.
Run a function called the Post.
The the post function will check if the loop is running for the first time, if it is, the first post
is grabbed from the results, otherwise it will move on to the next post in the list of results.
It's always important to call this function at the beginning of the loop.
Otherwise, you may experience inconsistent results.
Now that we have our data, we can begin displaying the template for each post.
First, let's exit out of PHP mode.
Next at a div tag with a class called Single Post.
Afterward add an anchor element with a class called Single Post Image.
On this element.
Let's set the h ref attribute to a function called the permalink.
The the permalink function is a template tag.
We talked about template tags before.
There are functions for rendering specific pieces of content.
There are a series of template tags that can run inside a loop.
These functions will be able to detect their inside a loop.
If a template tag detects a loop, it'll attempt to grab the post in the current iteration.
This is the main benefit of using the loop.
WordPress has designed its functions for handling most of the work.
You do not need to provide the ID of the post or any other piece of information.
It's capable of doing the heavy lifting as long as we're calling the the post function on each iteration.
Everything else is handled for us.
This function will return the URL to a specific post.
Let's render the image from within this element.
Inside the anchor element.
Run a function called the thumbnail.
The the thumbnail function will generate an image tag with the source pointing to the image of the post.
This function has an optional parameter which is the size of the image.
Let's set the size to thumbnail.
We've successfully rendered the thumbnail.
Let's proceed to render the title of the post and the author below.
The anchor element added div tag with a class called Single Post Detail.
Next, add an anchor element with the H ref attributes.
The value for this attribute will be the the permalink function.
Inside this tag, we are going to render the title.
The title can be rendered by calling the the title function.
For your convenience.
I provided a link to a page with a complete list of template tags in WordPress.
Feel free to check it out.
Most of these functions will handle grabbing the information for us.
Next, let's render the name of the author below.
The Anchor Element.
Add a span tag.
Inside this tag and the word bye, followed by an anchor element.
One more time.
Set the h ref attribute to the the permalink function.
Inside the elements, we are going to render the name of the author.
The author can be displayed by calling the author function.
The template is ready.
There's one more crucial step below the loop.
Let's run a function called WP Reset Post data.
We've talked about this before, but I want to mention it again.
Regardless of what page we're viewing, WordPress will always perform a query to the database for a
list of posts.
This query is considered the main query queries written by a plugin or theme.
Developers are considered secondary queries.
Whenever we create a custom query, WordPress will shift its focus from the main query to our secondary
query.
This shift in focus allows us to use template tags without worrying about informing WordPress of the
current post.
This behavior does have consequences if another developer performs the loop, the data from the loop
will contain the data from our query.
That's not what we want.
It's likely that other developers will want data from the main query.
By calling this function.
We're telling WordPress that we're finished with the secondary query.
It can go back to focusing on the main query.
The function is ready in the browser.
I'm going to refresh a page with the popular recipes block.
While are the most highly rated recipes are being displayed in the block, we've successfully queried
the database for this information and presented it to the user.
The block is complete.
We can start working on the second block for this section when you're ready.
I'll see you in the next lecture.