In this lecture, we are going to talk about an error with the media placeholder component.
You may have caught it.
Let's take a look.
In my browser, I added the team members group block to the page.
So far we've been adding images by selecting them from the media library.
But what about uploading an image?
Let's see what happens when an image is uploaded.
In the console, an error gets thrown.
Let's review the error together.
The error states the image sizes.
Property is undefined.
Whenever you encounter an undefined error, the error is telling you that a property does not have a
value.
Sounds strange, right?
In an earlier lecture.
The image object had a property called sizes.
Things are different with images being uploaded.
To understand what's going on, let's open the index JS file for the team member block.
Scroll to the on select event for the media placeholder component at the top of the function.
Lets log the image argument.
Next, let's test the media placeholder component in the browser.
Refresh the page and add the team members group block.
I'm going to quickly upload an image.
After uploading the image, the argument gets logged into the console.
This time the object is different than before.
By selecting an existing image, WordPress does not need to upload a file to the server.
The image is ready to go.
However, if we're uploading an image, the image is not going to be immediately available.
Uploading an image takes time.
For this reason, WordPress will create a blob.
Sounds silly, I know, but that's what it's called.
Lamps are not specific to WordPress, they're a feature available in browsers.
Blob is short for binary large object sounds complicated, but most of the details are an important
to us.
To put it simply, blobs were introduced for storing file data.
We can store various files from images to videos in a blob.
The purpose of using a blob is to create a temporary placeholder for a file.
You can use a blob to represent a file while it's being uploaded to the server.
That's what WordPress is doing.
WordPress creates a blob from our image file.
We can use this blob to display the image onto the page.
In the console.
We have an object with a URL to the blob.
Browsers will generate a URL for viewing the file.
It's perfectly acceptable to render an image with a blob URL.
You can detect a blob URL by checking the beginning of the URL.
All blobs start with the blob protocol.
So what does this have to do with our error?
As you can see, the size property is not existent with this object.
This is because WordPress has not uploaded the file to the server.
A URL is not available for previewing the image.
Instead, WordPress will give us a blob URL to act as a temporary preview.
Once the image has been uploaded, the size property will be accessible from the object.
In the meantime, we should display the image with the blob URL.
In the next lecture, let's begin previewing the image.