In this lecture, we are going to begin working on the form by waiting for the document to load.
Before we do, let's talk about using React versus plain JavaScript.
Throughout these past few sections, we've been relying on React to help us build blocks we are required
to use React with the Gutenberg editor on the front end.
It's a different story.
WordPress is frontend agnostic.
We are allowed to use any library or framework for building interfaces.
It's completely up to you if you would like to use React.
In our theme for this course, we are going to explore two options.
First, we are going to build interfaces with plain JavaScript.
Secondly, we will build interfaces with React on the front end.
Both options are viable.
By experiencing both options, you will be able to decide what best suits you for this block.
We are going to use plain JavaScript, no libraries or frameworks.
The first step in our journey is to wait for the document to load.
To understand why, let's open the elements panel with the developer tools.
Next, let's search for the front end DJ's file.
The file gets loaded with the scripts tag.
That much is obvious.
However, the location of the scripts tag is not ideal.
If we look at the parent element, it's the head tag.
Previously we talked about loading scripts in the footer by adding a script in the head section.
We may experience issues with blocking.
As of the recording of this lecture, there isn't a solution for forcing the script to be loaded in
the footer.
Luckily, there is a solution for waiting for the document to load inside your text editor.
Open the front end JS file.
Replace the long statement with the following function document dot add event listener.
JavaScript is a language that has an event system.
We can listen to various events on the elements in our document.
Normally we would add a property to a component or element.
However, that's the react way of listening to events.
With plain JavaScript, the syntax is different.
We can call the add event listener function to listen for an event.
This function must be changed to an element.
In this example, we are changing the function on the document object which represents the entire documents.
The document object has a special event inside the first argument of this function, we must provide
the event's name as a string.
Let's pass in an event called DOM Content Loaded.
This event will be emitted after the entire document has been loaded.
This is perfect.
By waiting for the document to be loaded, we are safe to begin executing JavaScript.
It doesn't matter if the script was added to the head section of a document.
You may be wondering why haven't we use this event earlier?
Beforehand we relied on Gutenberg to wait for the document to load.
This means we never had to worry about waiting for the documents.
We benefited greatly from Gutenberg's behavior.
However, we're not loading the script for the Gutenberg editor.
Therefore, we must handle this process ourselves.
The second argument to this function is a callback function.
The browser will run our function after the event has been emitted.
Let's pass in an arrow function.
Lastly, let's log a message to the console.
Let's test our code by refreshing the experimental page in the browser.
Inside the console panel.
The message from our file has been logged.
This indicates the event was emitted after the document had been completely loaded.
We are safe to execute additional code.
If you're ever working on the front end, you should always load scripts at the bottom of the documents.
If you can't, you can resort to this event.