In this lecture, we are going to update our function for handling uploads.
As we learned earlier, WordPress does not always provide the same object during the on select event.
If a file is uploaded, the image argument represents a blob until the upload is complete.
Let's update our function to detect a blob in your editor.
Open the index JS file.
WordPress has a function for detecting blobs.
We don't need to curate a solution of our own.
At the top of the file import a function called is blob URL from a package called WordPress slash blob.
I'm introducing a new package called Blob.
This package has functions for dealing with blobs.
The is blob.
URL function will check if a URL is a blob.
Let's give it a try.
Scroll to the on select function.
At the top of the function, let's create a variable called new image URL with an initial value of null.
We are going to store the URL in a variable.
Next, let's create a conditional statement with the IS blog URL function.
This function returns a boolean value we can pass in the URL as an argument.
Let's pass in the image url property.
Regardless of an image, is a blog or not.
The URL property will always exist.
If the image was selected from the media library, the URL property will store the path to the original
image on the occasion this function returns.
True, we have a blob URL on our hands.
Let's set the new image url variable to the image url property.
Next, add an LSS block.
If the image is not a blob, we can safely set the new image URL variable to the image sizes.
Team member URL property.
We have a simple function.
We can detect a blob image in either scenario.
The image should get displayed on the block inside the set attributes function update the image URL
attribute to our variable.
Let's try testing our code in the browser.
Refresh the page and add the team members group block.
Next, try uploading an image.
The image gets rendered on the block.
However, not everything appears as it seems.
The on select event gets emitted twice for file uploads.
The first time it gets emitted is when the upload is initiated.
During this process, the image data is not available.
WordPress will provide us with the blob image.
The function works perfectly during the event.
The second time occurs after the upload is complete.
If we look in the console, an error gets thrown by the on select function.
This error gets triggered during the second execution of our function.
At this point, the upload is finished.
If we read the error, it states that the size property is undefined.
Above the error we are given the image object.
The image object has an ID property.
This indicates the image has been uploaded.
So what's going on?
Shouldn't this object have the sizes property?
If we look through the object, the size is property is absent from the object for uploads.
The image object will move the list of images sizes to a different property.
In this object there's a property called media details.
Within this property, the size property has been defined.
The media placeholder component can be tricky to deal with.
Finding the image URL can be defined in different locations.
It's up to us to find the image, which can be annoying.
Fortunately, the goose chase has ended.
After adjusting our function, we will not need to search for the URL.
Head back to the editor.
Inside the L block.
Let's set the new image URL variable to a ternary operator.
Let's set the condition to the image sizes property.
Undefined properties will evaluate as false.
If the property does exist, the condition will evaluate to true.
Let's set the variable to the image sizes.
Team member URL property for a truth value.
Otherwise the URL can be found in the images.
Media Details.
Sizes.
Team member.
Source URL property.
Hopefully this will fix our block before testing our code.
I'm going to remove the console statements.
They're no longer required.
Let's try testing the block one more time.
I'm going to upload an image after refreshing the page.
This time, the image should have been uploaded successfully.
If we look in the console, an error never gets thrown.
We can verify an image has been uploaded by inspecting the image element with the developer tools under
the elements panel search for the image tag for the block.
The source attribute should not start with the word blob.
If it doesn't, this indicates the image is stored in the database.
Perfect.
We fixed our block.
Users have the option of uploading a new image or selecting an existing image from the media library.
Let's continue working on our block in the next lecture.