In this lecture, we're going to explore an object available in JavaScript for debugging and application.
Thus far we've been relying on the alert function to view our data in the browser.
While useful, it has its shortcomings.
The browser does not allow us to interact with the page while the alert box is opened on the page.
For example, let's try running the script from our snippets.
While the alert box is open, the page is completely unresponsive.
We can't scroll, click on links or type in forms.
The alert box is holding us completely hostage.
Interacting with the page isn't possible until the alert box goes away.
Another shortcoming of the alert box is the limited space of the box.
Oftentimes we may want to view the contents of an object or array.
The alert box may not have enough room to display this information.
The purpose of the alert box is to display a short message to visitors.
It's not meant to debug an application.
JavaScript has a special feature dedicated to viewing data called the console.
The browser has a dedicated panel for this feature.
Up until now, we've been writing into the console through the browser.
However, it's completely possible to write data from our code, so let's give it a try.
Back in the snippets section, we will replace the alert function with a function called console log.
As you might expect, the console keyword is an object.
It's an object defined by the JavaScript language.
This object gives us access to methods and properties for interacting with the console of the environment.
In our case, the console is available through the browser's developer tools.
The log function is considered the most common function when available in the console object.
It will allow us to write a message to the console through our script.
Let's try running the script.
The alert box never appears.
Instead, the balance gets logged in the console.
The console will provide us with two pieces of information regarding the message.
Firstly, the message appears on the left side.
On the right side, we're given the file's name and line number.
This information can help track down a log.
Throughout your career, you're going to be writing dozens of long statements.
It can be challenging to find where a message is coming from.
Clicking on this link will direct you to the exact location of the log.
Unlike before, the page is completely free.
The console does not block us from interacting with the page.
The messages from the console do not go away with our interactions unless we navigate to a different
page.
In my opinion, the console object is superior to the alert function.
For the rest of this course, we are going to debug our script with the console object.
In the resource section of this lecture, I provide a link to the documentation page for the console
object.
You're more than welcome to explore this page for the various methods available.
The most important method is the log method.
We'll be using it often.
Let's continue exploring objects in the next lecture.