In this lecture, we are going to start loading additional tags in our document.
We're not the only ones that need to add tags.
The WordPress core and third party plugins may want to add meta tags, load style sheets and load scripts
by default.
WordPress does not inject tags into our templates.
We need to provide a location for safely loading additional tags.
Once again, WordPress has a function for tackling this problem and your editor open the indexed PHP
file.
Below the Maytag running PHP function called WP Head.
The WP head function will allow WordPress and plugins to load tags into the head section of our documents.
I highly recommend calling the WP head function after adding your own tags.
A themes tag should take priority over tags from third party plugins.
In most cases, developers will call the WP head function at the end of the head tag.
We're not finished yet.
Some plugins may want to load scripts.
It's recommended that we load script files at the bottom of the document similar to before.
WordPress does not automatically inject scripts into our documents.
We need to provide a location for loading scripts before the closing body tag.
Run a function called WP Footer.
DWP footer function performs a similar operation as the WP head function.
It'll allow plugins to begin loading scripts into the documents.
We haven't had the chance to jump into JavaScript for now.
It's enough to understand that we're providing a location for plugins to load additional tags and files.
Let's try loading our theme in the browser.
After making those changes, WordPress has loaded the admin bar.
If you don't see the admin bar, it's likely that you're not logged in as an admin.
Regardless, WordPress will still inject tags into our documents.
Open the elements panel in the developer tools.
Our document looks vastly different than before.
WordPress has injected several tags into the head and body sections of our document, which is great.
Our theme is starting to become extendable.
If a plug needs to load additional tags, it'll be able to without a problem.
We're getting close to finishing the templates.
In the next lecture, let's wrap it up.