In this lecture, we are going to quickly add the search form block to the search template.
This process shouldn't take long, so let's get into it in the full site.
Editor Open the search template for our theme.
On this page, we added the search form template with the HTML block.
This block can be found above the list of posts.
Let's remove the HTML block.
Next, let's insert the search form block above the list of posts.
Feel free to modify the colors.
I'm going to leave the block in its default state.
Next from the list, sidebar, select and copy all the blocks into your clipboard.
After copying the blocks to your clipboard, open the unity theme folder in your editor.
We are not inside the plugin folder.
Make sure you switched over to your themes folder inside the templates directory.
Open the search dot html file.
Replace the existing content with the new set of locks.
Our template is ready.
Time to give our form a test in the browser.
Navigate to the home page.
In the header.
Let's search for something random.
This will take us to the search page which contains our form.
Inside the form, the search query has been added to the input.
We can freely modify the input to view a different set of results.
Let's try submitting this form to generate a new set of results.
Perfect.
Our block has a fully functioning search form.
We've completed our first block with server side rendering.
It's a completely different approach than client side rendering.
The process heavily involves PHP.
It's a great solution for developing blocks that require dynamic content.
Let's start developing our next block in the next lecture.
Before moving on, you can point your text editor to the plugin file.
We are not going to work on the theme.