In this lecture, we are going to make a quick adjustment to our theme templates.
Currently, I'm viewing the home page.
The log and link in the header is completely static.
The same goes for the highly rated posts on the sidebar.
In previous sections, we've taken the time to develop custom blocks for these areas.
I think it would make sense to update our template by replacing the static template with the completed
blocks in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to the updated files for these template parts.
The header html and sidebar html files should be updated with the code from this page.
The updates I performed on the template will replace the static version with their respective block.
Let's quickly update our theme first.
Copy the code for the header html file.
Mixed.
Open the header.
HTML template part.
Replace the contents of the file with the new set of blocks.
Head back to the browser.
Copy the second code snippet.
Open the sign.
HTML template part.
Once again, her place de file's contents with a new set of locks.
After making those changes, we can move on to the next lecture.
I'll see you there.