In this lecture, we are going to learn how to bundle our plugins with a theme.
There are two plugins that should be bundled with our theme.
The first plugin is the YouTube plus plugin.
This is a custom plugin that's exclusive to our theme.
The second plugin is called Regenerate Thumbnails.
This plugin helped us reset the dimensions for existing images.
It's common practice for theme developers to recommend this plugin.
Both plugins should be easy to install.
Forcing the user to manually download each plugin would be a pain.
Ideally, we should provide a simple interface for downloading each plugin for a theme to be fully functional.
The most efficient solution would be to use a class called TG plugin activation.
In the resource section.
I provide a link to this class.
This class was introduced to help theme developers bundle plugins with a theme.
It'll create an interface for installing plugins that are required or recommended to avoid redundancy.
It'll check if a plugin has already been installed.
If it has, the plugin will not be installed again.
It's one of the best solutions available.
I find it extremely easy to use.
Let's try integrating this class into our theme.
First, we must download the file at the top of the page.
Click on the download link.
The page will help us integrate the class with our project.
First, we must select where the class will be utilized.
Let's select the theme option.
Next, we are asked where we plan on distributing our theme.
Feel free to select any of the options.
I'm going to select the some other way option.
Afterward, we must provide the text domain.
Set the text domain to Udemy.
Filling in this field will cause the other fields to be pre-filled.
I'm fine with the default values.
Let's click on Generate.
This will cause the browser to download a zip file.
Let's check out the contents of the zip file.
In the zip file.
We are going to find a few files.
However, we only care about a single file called class TG JDM Plugin Activation PHP.
This file contains everything we will need.
Everything else can be ignored.
Let's drag and drop this file into the includes folder of our theme.
If you want you can also grab the example.
PHP file.
This file provides a real example of how to use this class.
It can be helpful later down the line after copying the files, open the function's PHP file in your
editor.
The first step is to include this file in our theme under the includes section include the class TG
Plugin Activation PHP file.
By including this class, a custom hook will be emitted.
This hook gives us the opportunity to register plug ins under the Hooks section.
Add an action hook called TX GMP to register.
The name of our function will be called You Register Plug INS.
Inside the includes folder.
Create a file called Register Plugins php.
Inside this file.
Define the you register plugins function.
Next.
Head back to the function, start php file.
This file must be included for the function to be available.
Great.
We can begin in registering plug ins back in the register plug ins function.
A new function will become available called DT GMP.
Let's call it.
This function has two arguments.
The first argument is an array of plug ins.
The second argument is an array of configuration settings.
It's recommended to outsource these values into separate variables.
This practice keeps our code readable.
Let's give it a try.
Above this function, create two arrays called plugins and config.
Next.
Pass these variables into the function.
Let's begin updating the plugins array.
As I mentioned before, we're going to recommend to plug ins.
The first plugin is the Regenerate Thumbnails plugin.
A plugin can be registered by adding an array to represent the plugin settings.
Lets pass in an array.
In this array we must add a key called name.
The name option must be set to the name of the plugin.
In this example, the name of the plugin is called Regenerate Thumbnails.
Next, we must add an option called slug.
The slug options value must be the path to the plugin from the WordPress repository.
This class will handle searching for the plugin from the official repository.
However, we must provide the URL in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to the regenerate thumbnails page.
All plugins have a similar URL structure.
The difference between each plugin is the path after the plugins segment of the URL.
Copy this path into your clipboard.
Next set the slug option to the value we copied earlier.
There's one more option we'll add called required.
We have the option of requiring or recommending this plugin.
By setting this option to false, the plugin will be recommended.
Setting this option to true will force the user to download this in.
In my opinion, it's never a good idea to require a plugin unless it's absolutely necessary.
The more plugins installed on a site, the more bloated the site can become at most.
Your theme should never rely on more than two plugins to be usable.
We're finished with registering our first plugin.
Let's begin registering the custom plugin for our theme.
Add another array to the plugins array in this array.
Set the name option to utility plus.
Next set the slug option to Udemy plus.
This plugin is not publicly accessible from the WordPress plugin repository.
If the plugin cannot be downloaded publicly, the slug option must be set to the name of the plugin
folder.
After adding this option, set the required option to true.
We're going to require this plugin for our theme.
Next, let's add an option called source.
The TG class is capable of grabbing plugins from various sources.
It can grab a plugin from the official WordPress repository and external source, or it can search for
a file from within.
Our theme for this course, we're going to include the plug in with our theme.
If you haven't already, create a zip file of the Udemy plus plugin after doing so, grab the zip file.
We're going to add the zip file to the Udemy theme.
I recommend creating a folder dedicated to plug ins, zip files and the root folder of our theme.
Create a folder called Plugins.
Add the zip file to this directory.
Back in the editor.
We must provide a full path to this file.
Set the source option to the following value.
Get template directory.
Dot slash plugins.
Slash Udemy plus dot zip.
After adding this path, the TG class will download the plugin from the local source.
Including your plugin as a local source is not a bad idea.
However, you can outsource it to a GitHub repository.
That's another option at our disposal.
I recommend checking out the example PHP file from the TG zip file.
This file includes examples of how to grab a plug in zip file from various sources.
For our purposes, storing a copy of the plugin as a local source is more than enough.
We're finished registering our plugins.
The next step is to begin configuring the TG class in the configure array at an option called ID.
It's completely possible for third party plugins to include the TG M class.
In these cases we do not want our lists of plugins to clash with another set of recommended plugins.
This library is extremely popular among the WordPress community.
We can give our list of plugins and ID.
Let's set the ID to Udemy.
Next, we can set the ID of the menu by adding the menu option.
Behind the scenes, the team class will register a menu in the admin dashboard.
This menu will be dedicated to installing and activating our plugins.
The value should be a unique menu name.
Let's set the menu option to jump to install plugins.
Next we can set the parent slug option to theme start up.
By setting the parents log option, the menu will appear as a sub menu item to an existing parent menu.
In this example, we're using the themes app parent menu.
This will cause the menu to appear under the appearance parent menu.
Up next, set the capability option to edit the options.
The capability option will limit who can install and activate plug ins by a specific capability.
In this example, we're using the edit theme options capability.
This capability is available to users who can configure a site's theme after this option set the has
notices option to true.
This option will display notices to the end user.
If the user has permission to install and activate plug ins, they'll be shown a notice for activating
a plugin required for a theme.
Along with this option.
Set the dismissible option to true.
The dismissal option will allow users to dismiss the notices.
We're not going to annoy the user if they're not interested in activating our plugins.
Let's allow them to dismiss the notices.
That's it.
We've configured the TG class with our theme.
Let's refresh the plugins page in the admin dashboard.
At the moment, nothing will happen.
Both plugins are activated.
Let's try deactivating the utility plus plugin.
After deactivating this plugin, a notice will appear.
The notice instructs us that the utility plus plugin is required for our theme.
We can click on the link to be taken to a page with a list of required plugins by using a single class.
We do not need to generate a UI or handle verifying a plugin activated.
The team class is completely capable of verifying the current site's plugins.
If a plugin is not active, the class will help the user install and activate the plugin.
I highly recommend checking out the example php file for a complete list of settings.
This experience can be customized further.
We're officially finished with our theme and plugin.
Congrats.
It took dozens of hours, but it was well worth it.
In the next section, let's finish the course with some final thoughts.