In this lecture, we are going to create a custom rest API endpoint for grabbing a random recipe.
We'll be using our function to help us generate this information.
First, let's register a new route in your editor.
Open the init dot php file.
At the bottom of the function at a new root with the register rest root function.
Next let's set the namespace to up slash v one.
The endpoint will be set to daily recipe.
Afterward.
Let's pass in an array to configure the settings of our new route.
First, we'll set the methods option to the WP Rest server.
Readable constants.
The readable constant will set the method of a route to get.
This makes sense for our new routes.
We aren't going to allow users to create new daily recipes.
The end point will always return a single recipe.
Next, let's set the callback option to the following function up rest API.
Daily Recipe Handler.
Lastly, let's set the permission callback option to the return true function.
This end point will be accessible to all users.
Users will not need special permissions to view the recipe of the day.
Our route has been registered.
Time to handle the request by defining the function inside the includes slash rest API directory.
Create a file called daily recipe.
PHP.
Inside this file.
Define the up rest API daily recipe handler function.
Typically we would send a response with a key called status.
Unlike the other endpoints we've created, this endpoint will return post data.
It's not going to contain a status.
Let's create an array called response.
Inside this array, we are going to store the URL image and title of a post.
We're not going to include everything.
It's not necessary for the block.
This information is plenty for displaying the recipe of the day.
After defining the response, create a variable called ID.
The value for this variable will be the get transient function.
The get transient function will return a transient value from the database.
The name of the transient must be passed in as the functions first arguments.
In our case, the name is called up daily recipe ID.
However, as mentioned before, WordPress will delete the record from the database as the transient
expires.
If WordPress is unable to grab a value.
It will return false, which is not what we want.
Just to make sure let's verify the contents of the variable with a conditional statement.
The condition will check if the ID variable is false.
If it is false, we should generate a new transient by sending the ID variable to the up generate daily
recipe function.
At this point, we are always guaranteed to have a post ID.
The last step is to update the response with the appropriate values.
After the conditional statement, set the response URL variable to the get permalink function with the
ID variable.
We can use template tags to help us get the relevant information on a post.
You'll notice that we're not using this function in the loop.
If we're not using a template tag in a loop, we must provide the ID of the post to these functions
to retrieve information related to a post.
Next, let's set the response image variable to the get the post thumbnail URL function with the ID
variable.
The second argument is the size of the image by default.
WordPress will return the URL to the thumbnail.
Let's change the size to full.
This size will return the size of the original image.
Lastly, let's set the response title variable to the get the title function with the ID variable.
After updating their response, we can return it from the function.
Let's try testing the endpoint with Postman.
Postman should have saved your previous session.
We can modify the current URL to our new endpoint.
Change the path to the following up.
Slash V one slash daily recipe.
The parameters from the previous session will go away if they haven't manually clear them from the request.
After making those changes, let's send the request.
In the requests body.
We are given a random recipe from the post.
Let's try sending the request again.
The same post should appear in the body.
A new recipe will not be selected until 24 hours have passed, which is perfect.
This is the exact behavior we were looking for in the next lecture.
Let's begin displaying this information in our block.