In this lecture, we are going to begin switching tabs.
Let's look at the modal on the front end.
There are two forms inside the modal.
You may not be able to view the other modal.
I've hidden it with CSS.
The modal should display one form at a time.
The form that gets displayed will be based on the current active tabs.
At the top of the modal we have two tab links.
The active tab will have a bright text color.
Let's inspect the element for the tab.
The links are created with anchor elements.
We can change the color of a tab by adding a class called Active Tab.
As you can see, this class has been added to the login link.
By default, the log in form should be displayed.
There's another useful piece of information on the link.
The H ref attribute contains the ID of the form.
If we look below the unordered list element, there's a div tag called Modal Body.
Inside this element there are two forms.
Looking closely, the IDs match the values from the ref attribute.
Changing tabs will require adding and removing the active tab class from the links.
Afterward, we can hide or display a form by toggling the display property.
The ref attribute will help us decide which form to display.
Let's get started in your editor.
Open the front end JS file.
We are going to add our code at the bottom of the function.
The goal is to listen for clicks on the tab links.
Therefore, we should select the links.
Create a variable called tabs.
The value for this function will be the document query selector all function.
The selector will be the following tabs.
A.
The unordered list element has a class called Tabs.
Inside this element, we are selecting the anchor elements, which are the links for the tabs.
After making this selection, we can begin looping through the elements to apply click events.
Let's call the for each function on the tabs variable.
Passed in an arrow function that accepts the tab element.
Previously we used a generic name for the selection.
This was because the open modal class could be applied to any element.
This time we know what kind of elements will be selected from our query whenever possible.
I prefer specific names inside our arrow function.
Lets call the add event listener function on the tab variable.
The name of the event will be called Click.
Lastly, passing a function to handle the event.
We are dealing with links.
Clicking links can cause the page to refresh.
To avoid this behavior, let's accept the event object.
After doing so we can call the event dot prevent default function to stop the browser from updating
the page.
Great.
We can start to toggle the active tab class from the links.
Here's where things are going to get tricky.
We must remove the active tab class from the other links before adding it to the current link.
Otherwise, multiple links may have this class.
The question becomes how do we know which tabs have this class?
The answer is we don't.
The solution to our problem is to remove the class from all links.
We are going to need to create another loop for the tabs.
We can't reuse this loop because the loop runs once we need to loop through the tabs after a link has
been clicked inside our loop, let's call the tabs dot for each function.
Passing a function to handle each iteration, we are going to refer to each item in the array as current
tab.
The class can be removed by calling the current tab class list dot remove function pass in the active
tab class.
Once again, we are looping through the tabs to remove the active tab class.
At this point, all links should not be active.
We can proceed to add this class to the tab that should be active below the loop.
Lets log a property called event dot current target.
Next, let's refresh the experimental page with the console panel from the Developer Tools.
We can open the modal and start clicking on the links as we do so.
Both links should not be active inside the console.
The event dot current target property has been logged.
JavaScript is aware that multiple elements can have the same events without JavaScript help.
It can be difficult to determine which link was clicked.
Luckily, the event object has a property called Current Targets.
This property is an object for the element that triggered the event.
We don't need to guess which element emitted the click event.
The current target property will contain the same methods and properties for interacting with the elements.
Thus we can add or remove classes through this object.
Let's give it a try.
Back in the editor, we're going to replace the event's current target property with the following function
event.
Current Target dot class list.
Dot Add active tab.
After routing the class.
Let's try testing the links again.
Head back to the browser.
If we open the model, everything appears fine.
Clicking on the tabs should cause the scripts to update the link with the correct color.
So far, so good.
We're halfway there.
The last step is to display the correct form.
Luckily, we have most of the information we will need to accomplish this step.
Let's head back to the editor.
First things first.
We must get the h ref attribute from the link clicked.
Grabbing this information will be easy.
We already know how to grab the element that triggered the event at the bottom of the loop.
Create a variable called active tab.
The value for this variable will be the events dot current target property.
We're not interested in grabbing the entire elements.
The attribute can be retrieved by training a function called get attributes.
This function will grab any attributes value from an element.
It accepts the attribute name as a string.
Let's grab the ref attributes.
After grabbing the rough attributes, we will be able to update the correct form.
Before doing so.
We're going to need to select both forms above the loop.
Let's create variables that store references to the form elements.
First, let's grab the login form.
Create a variable called sign and form.
The value for this variable will be the following value.
Document dot query selector sign in tab.
I've given both forms IDs.
You can check out the template for their respective IDs for the login form.
The ID is sign in tab.
Let's create another variable called signup form.
The ID for the registration form is sign up tab.
Let's select it with the document dot query.
Select your function.
Great.
We've got references to the forms back in the loop.
Let's add a conditional statement.
We are going to check if the active tab variable is strictly equal to the sign in tab.
If it is, we can assume that a visitor wants to view the sign in form.
Previously, we toggled an element's appearance for our class.
We could use the same solution again.
However, I want to show you a different approach.
By manipulating an element styles, one solution isn't better than the other.
I just want to show you your options inside the conditional statement.
Set the sign in form style dot.
Display property to block.
The sale property is available on all elements.
This property is an object of style applied to the elements.
However, it doesn't display styles from classes.
The style must be applied via the style attribute for it to appear.
Within this object, we have the option of adding styles to this object.
The name of the style must be a valid CSS property.
In this case we are adding the display property.
The value for this property must be a valid CSS value.
JavaScript will handle adding the style to the element before moving on.
We must hide the registration form.
We're going to assume the registration form is appearing.
We can hide the form by setting the register form style dot display property to non.
We're almost finished.
The last step is to hide the log and form.
If the register link tab was clicked, let's add an else block.
The code will be the same, but with the values reversed, we can copy the code from the if block to
the else block.
Lastly, reverse the values.
We're finished.
Head on over to the browser to refresh the page.
This time we can fully test the tabs.
Upon opening the modal, let's try switching tabs.
As we do so, the forms will change.
The correct form should appear in the modal.
As we switch between them.
You can even click on the same tab twice to test if the form stays around.
Perfect.
We've successfully created tabs with plain JavaScript.
In the final set of lectures, we can start submitting the form data to WordPress.
When you're ready, I'll see you in the next lecture.