In this lecture, we're going to apply styles to regular elements.
Thus far, we've been applying styles on a global level or block level.
In some cases, you may want to apply styles to specific elements.
At the moment, WordPress supports custom styles for links and headings.
Other elements are not supported for this demonstration.
We are going to change the default color of our links.
Let's set the text color to the primary color from our theme inside your editor.
Open the theme JSON file.
Next inside the Styles object.
Add a new object called Elements.
Inside this object, we must specify the name of the element we'd like to apply styles to.
Surprisingly, WordPress has a special name for links.
Technically, the name of the element for links is called anchor.
However, WordPress uses the word link.
After adding the name, we can start applying styles to the link.
Before we do, I want to quickly mention the names of headings.
We can change the headings of a document with their HTML names.
For example, if you would like to change the color of the H one tag, the name would be H one.
Back to our previous example.
Inside this object we can change the colour and background.
The text colour can be changed with the text property.
The value will be the following.
WP presets colour you primary.
Next.
Let's refresh the full site editor.
Our site title block has been modified.
The color has changed from blue to our primary color.
Changing the links will apply to all blocks for further demonstration.
Let's try adding a paragraph block with a link.
Perfect.
The link for the block matches the color from our theme settings.
Hopefully as time goes on, WordPress will support styling for all or most elements.
In the next lecture, let's finalize our discussion of colors by applying them to borders.