In this lecture, we are going to clear the blobs from memory.
As mentioned before, blobs are stored in the client system memory after the image is finished uploading
the URL for the image swaps from the blob URL to an http url.
However, just because the URL changes doesn't mean the blob disappears.
There's a concept known as a memory leak.
A memory leak is when data is not released from a system.
Browsers must allocate resources for files and variables.
If the user navigates away from a page, these resources are released by releasing memory.
New data can be stored.
Otherwise, a user system may become congested.
This can lead to slow performance and sluggish behavior.
Browsers do an incredible job of releasing memory.
React also releases memory on our behalf.
However, that doesn't mean we can be lazy.
We have a memory leak in our program.
A blob will continue to persist.
Blobs are released after the browser has been closed.
However, the user may not close the browser after uploading a file, they may want to continue editing
their site.
Files can occupy large amounts of memory.
It would be a good idea to release a blob after the image is uploaded.
WordPress has a function for releasing memory.
Let's try using this function to fix our memory leak issue.
In your editor, open the indexed JS file for the team member block.
From the WordPress blog package.
Import a function called revoke blob URL.
This function will release memory for a blog URL, scroll to the on select event from the media placeholder
component.
We are going to call this function at the end of the block.
We can safely assume that this lock is executed after an image has been uploaded.
This function accepts the blob URL as an argument.
Let's pass in the image preview state which contains the blob URL.
Even if this variable does not contain a blog URL, WordPress will not complain.
It's perfectly safe to call it.
After making those changes, let's test our code in the browser.
Refresh the page.
I'm going to upload an image with the console panel opened from the developer tools.
As the image is uploaded, an error should not be thrown by the block.
As long as an error is not thrown by the browser, we can consider our solution a success.
In the next lecture, let's begin implementing a solution to replace the image.