In this lecture we're going to discuss WordPress coding standards in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to the WordPress Best Practices page.
We're going to be writing a lot of code along the journey.
We should adhere to certain practices.
If we're on a team, it can be annoying if everyone writes code differently.
Code should be consistent across the board.
WordPress outlines some guidelines for how you should write and format your code.
On this page there are guidelines for different languages.
We should follow these guidelines to the best of our abilities.
Keep in mind that these are recommendations.
You're not forced to write your code in a specific way.
If you want to, you can completely ignore these recommendations.
However, adhering to a standard will provide the best experience for everyone.
If you plan on contributing to the core of WordPress, you must follow these guidelines if you plan
on releasing plugins and themes independently.
These guidelines are optional.
I'm going to click on the PHP Coding Standards link.
You're more than free to review these standards.
Don't worry if it doesn't make complete sense throughout this course, I will try my best to adhere
to these standards.
As long as you follow along with me, you should be fine.
Let's begin coding themes in the next section.