In this lecture, we will register our option with a group.
To understand why, let's look at the pages created by WordPress.
For example, I'm viewing the page for the general settings.
On this page we have multiple fields.
Each field can modify a specific record from the database.
If you were to look through the WP options table, most of the records contain a single value.
WordPress does not know how to group options for a single page.
We must teach WordPress what group of options it can modify from a page.
This is known as an options group.
Technically, we have a single record containing our plugins options.
They're spread across multiple records.
Regardless, the first step for using the Settings API is to register our option with a group.
Let's get started in your editor.
Open the indexed PHP file.
At the bottom of the file.
Add an action hook called admin in it.
WordPress has a hook during the initialization step of the admin dashboard.
We must register our option group during this hook.
The name of our function will be called up settings API.
Next, let's define this function inside the include slash admin folder.
Create a file called Settings API php.
Inside this file, define the up settings api function.
Afterward run a function called register setting.
This function will register an option with a group.
The first argument is the name of the group.
The name of our group can be anything we want.
Let's set the name to Up Options Group.
Next, we must register a single option with this group by passing in the options name as the second
argument.
The name of our option was called up options.
If you have multiple options, this function must be called for each option.
For example, let's say we had an option called B, we would call this function like so.
The second invocation of this function would belong to the same group.
However, the second argument would register the second option.
In our case, we only have one option.
So calling this function once is more than enough.
After registering our option with a group, we can render this group in our form open the options page.
Alt dot php file.
Inside the div tag.
Add a form tag.
On this tag set the method attribute to post.
Next set the action attribute to options, not PHP.
Here's a huge difference between the Settings API and manually creating a form for modifying options.
Forms created with the Settings API must send data to the options php file.
This file is dedicated to handling form submissions for the settings API.
If we're creating a form without this API, the data must be sent to the admin post's PHP file.
Inside this form, let's run a function called settings fields.
This function will tell the options php file which option group will be modified by this form?
This function has one argument which is the name of the options group.
Let's pass in the name of our group.
This step is very important.
Otherwise, WordPress will not know what options group to modify.
After registering our option with a group, we can begin rendering the sections and fields in the next
set of lectures.
We will finish our form with the Settings API.