In this lecture, we are going to add a component called toggle control.
I'm viewing an example from WordPress Storybook.
The toggle control component will render a slider for turning an option on or off.
Next to the slider, there's a label.
Overall, it's a simple design.
Our goal is to ask the client if they're interested in displaying the category.
This option will be presented with the toggle control component.
If they enable this option, the page header will display the current category.
Otherwise, clients will be able to write custom content.
Let's get started in your editor.
Open the block JSON file.
As usual, we should create an attribute for storing the options value.
Create an attribute called show category.
The type property will be set to boolean.
A Boolean is a perfect data type for our attribute.
I always recommend using booleans for inputs like the toggle control component or a checkbox.
Next, lets set the default value to false.
By default, the page header block should not show the category.
It should allow clients to write custom content after adding our attribute.
Let's switch over to the index JS file.
First let's import the contents we will need for our block from the block editor package.
Grab the Inspector Controls component.
Next, we are going to import the panel body and toggle control components from the WordPress slash
components package.
These components will be necessary for building our block settings.
Let's move on to the edit function from the attributes object.
Add the show category attribute to the structure list.
We are going to need this attribute for the toggle control component.
Next, let's add the inspector controls component above the template for the block.
This component will help us insert content into the sidebar before rendering the control.
Insert the panel body component for isolating our block settings from other panels.
Next, we should add the title property for the panel's title.
Let's set the title to the double underscore function with the following text.
General.
The typical setup for the sidebar is ready.
Let's get into using the toggle control component by inserting it into the panel body component.
The toggle control component will add the UI element we saw at the beginning of the lecture.
This UI element can be customized with a few set of properties.
For starters, let's add a label with a property called label.
As we do with all text, we are going to call the double underscore function with the following value
show category.
The label property will render the text next to the slider.
After adding the label, we should allow the control to manipulate the show category attributes.
At this point, you may have noticed a pattern with components defined by WordPress.
Most components have a property for setting the initial value of a control.
In addition, there is any event for updating the attribute after the controls value has changed.
This is a very common pattern you'll come across for most components.
The toggle control component is no difference.
On this component, we can set the checked property to the show category attributes.
This property will set the current value of the control.
It's expecting the value to be a boolean.
Luckily, our attributes data type is also a boolean.
Moving on, let's add an event called On Change.
This event gets fired on updates.
We can execute a function on this event.
Let's pass in an arrow function that accepts the new value.
Next, we can update the show category attribute with the new value.
As we learned before, we can shorten this syntax by renaming the argument to show category.
Afterward, the property can be inserted without a value.
This is the equivalent of what we had before.
I just wanted to show you the shorthand syntax again.
After making those changes, our component is ready.
It's that simple.
And the browser.
Let's refresh the experimental page.
Next, let's add the page header block.
On the sidebar, we are going to find a panel called General.
The toggle control component will render the UI we saw on WordPress Storybook.
We can interact with this component to enable or disable the category option.
Let's verify the attribute gets updated.
I'm going to enable this option next from the block list.
Copy the page header block to your clipboard.
If you were to view the block's HTML comment, you should see something like this.
Originally, the default value of the show category attribute was false.
However, by enabling the slider, the attributes value has been set to true.
This means our control is working as intended.
That's awesome.
We can start applying this attribute to our block.
In the next lecture, let's start using our attribute to toggle the content.