In this lecture, we are going to finish our block by rendering it with our PHP function.
Most of these steps will be familiar to you.
We're going to fly right by the solution to get started.
Open the daily recipe dot php file.
In the beginning, we created this file to define the function for rendering the block on the server.
Let's update this function to output the same template from the block.
First, let's add the attributes argument to the function.
Next, let's extract the attributes.
There's only one attribute which is the title.
Define a variable called title.
The value for this attribute will be the escape html function with the attributes title variable.
After grabbing the attributes.
Let's grab the ID, define a variable called ID.
Its value will be the get transient function.
Our transient was called up daily recipe ID.
Similar to before.
It's possible that the get transient function may return an empty results.
To avoid this scenario, we can create a conditional statement for checking an empty value on the ID
variable.
If the value is empty, we'll update the ID variable to the return value of the up generate daily recipe
function.
This was the main reason we outsourced the code into a separate function.
We are going to generate a random recipe from the rest response and render the function for the daily
recipe block.
Our data is ready.
The final step is to begin rendering this information in the templates inside the buffer zone.
Add a div tag with a class called WP BLOCK Udemy plus daily recipe.
Inside these tags, add an H six tag with the title variable echoed in between the tags.
Afterward add an anchor element below the H six tag on this element.
Set the H ref attribute to the the permalink function with the ID variable.
Next, add an image element with the source attributes.
Here's where things get interesting.
WordPress is known for being helpful, but sometimes it can be inconsistent in the resource section
of this lecture.
I provide links to two functions called the post thumbnail URL and get the post thumbnail URL.
Both functions will produce a URL to a post thumbnail.
As we learned before, the Gantt version of the function will return the value.
The non git version will echo the value while both functions produce the same results.
There is another difference that affects the way we'll write our code.
The the post thumbnail URL function does not allow us to pass an ID.
It completely relies on the loop to output an image.
Normally we would use this function for rendering an image.
Since it does not accept an ID, we will resort to the get version of the function.
It's strange because there are other functions that can accept the ID.
This inconsistency can be annoying to deal with.
I always recommend viewing the documentation of a function before using it.
Let's head back to the editor for the source attribute.
We are going to echo the get the post thumbnail URL function with the ID variable.
Next, let's set the size to full.
Afterward.
Let's render the title by adding a pair of H three tags.
Inside these tags echo the get the title function with the ID variable.
We're finished.
Let's try testing our code by refreshing the page with the daily recipe block.
We've successfully finished the daily recipe block.
Overall, the process is very simple.
The main takeaway for this block was learning how to use transients.
They're a great feature for temporarily caching data before moving on to the next block.
Let's talk about performance in the next lecture.