In this lecture, we are going to begin toggling content from within the Gutenberg Editor.
This is where things can become tricky.
We are going to toggle the blocks content inside the page header.
If the show category attribute is enabled, the client should not be able to edit the header.
Therefore, we must disable the rich text component.
Initially, we might use a conditional statement to accomplish this behavior.
However, Gsx does not support the if statements.
Conditionally rendering content requires a ternary operator.
The ternary operator is not unique to PHP.
Various languages support this operator.
This includes JavaScript.
Surprisingly, the syntax is exactly the same.
You will feel right at home to get started.
Open the index dot js file.
Let's scroll to the edit components gsx.
We are going to modify the rich text component.
As I mentioned before, we should enable or disable this component based on the value of the show category
attributes.
If the client wants to show the category, this component should be disabled before the rich text component.
Add an expression with a ternary operator.
The syntax for a ternary operator is the exact same as the syntax for a ternary operator in PHP.
Keep in mind the ternary operator is a JavaScript syntax feature.
It's not specific to react or gsx, however, it's a popular syntax feature in React.
If you look at examples online, the ternary operator is the primary choice for conditionally rendering
content to the right of the question mark symbol.
We must add a condition.
The condition will be the show category attributes.
If the condition is true, thi we should display the current category after the question mark symbol
at a pair of h one tags.
The page header block will be applied to the category templates.
Unfortunately, the full site editor does not provide a fake category to display on the page.
We won't have access to a category, therefore we will need to display a dummy category inside these
tags.
Add an expression with the double underscore function.
The translation will contain the following text category.
Some category.
Let's assume the option is turned off.
At this point, we should render the rich text components.
We can move the rich text component from its current location to after the colon symbol.
The formatting of our ternary operator may seem strange.
Normally, the ternary operator is written on a single line of code.
However, our code would be difficult to read on a single line.
It's perfectly valid to break the ternary operator into multiple lines.
In addition, the template will always be provided the latest value of the attributes.
We won't need to check if the value has been updated.
WordPress will manage providing our template with the latest value.
Before testing our code, let's try an exercise.
Scroll to the toggle control components.
This component has an additional property for displaying help text at a property called Help.
The Help property is similar to the label property.
You can use this property to provide additional information for helping the user.
The text will appear below the control with light colored text.
As an exercise, I want you to tell the client if the block will render the category or custom content.
The solution will be vastly similar to the blocks template.
You can use the ternary operator for toggling the value.
Give it a try and good luck.
Welcome back.
Hopefully you are able to tackle this challenge.
If not, let's try tackling the solution together.
First, we must provide a condition.
The condition is going to be the same as before.
We are going to check the show category attribute for a true value.
If it is, we will tell the client that the category will be shown.
We are going to translate the text with the double underscore function.
The translation should say the following category shown.
If this option is disabled, we should tell the client that they can add custom content.
Let's add the double underscore function again.
This time the translation will say the following custom content shown.
Great.
We are able to tell the client what will be displayed in the block.
Let's try testing our block in the browser.
Refresh the experimental page.
Next, let's add the page header block to the page.
If we look at the sidebar, the show category option will tell us that we can add custom content.
Let's try enabling this option.
After doing so, the help text should change.
In addition, the category is shown in the block.
The content is no longer editable.
It's completely static.
If you would like to edit the content, the show category option must be disabled.
We can toggle between options with minimal effort.
Perfect.
We've successfully finished the block.
The final part is to render the block on the front end.
Since we're trying to dynamically grab the category, the block must be rendered on the server.
Let's get started in the next lecture.