In this lecture, we are going to add the blocks for the post template and the past few lectures we've
been adding blocks one by one to save time.
We are going to add everything.
After adding the blocks, we will move on to styling them.
This will make the process go by faster.
Let's get started to get an idea of what we'll need.
Let's study the post templates.
Design.
The layout of the post is complex.
If you think about it, we have two columns of data on the left column.
We have the author's profile, image, author, name, post title and post date.
On the right column we have the post image tags, comment, count and excerpt.
To achieve this layout, let's try adding the columns block.
In each column, we can add blocks for loading each piece of data.
Let's give it a try.
Switch over to the block editor under the post template.
BLOCK We are going to add the columns block.
Keep in mind, the blocks for rendering content should be children of this block.
The block is responsible for rendering the content of each post in the array of posts.
Next, let's move this block to the top of the template.
The editor will ask us to select a preset of options for our theme.
The column widths should be 33% and 66% respectively.
If this option is unavailable, the widths must be set manually.
Select the 5050 option.
After doing so, select the first column block from the list on the settings sidebar.
Set the width to 33.33%.
Next, let's update the width for the second column.
The width should be set to 66.66%.
Perfect.
We can start moving on to adding blocks to each column.
As we discussed before, the left column should have the author's profile, image, author, name,
title and date inside the first column.
Insert the post author block.
This block will render the author's image and name afterward.
Let's move the title and date blocks into the first column.
They should sit below the author.
The order does matter.
Otherwise, our template styles will not work.
Make sure the order of your blocks matches mine.
Once you've got that confirmed, let's begin adding blocks to the second column.
The second column contains the post, image tags, comment counts and excerpt.
WordPress has blocks for each of these sections.
First, let's add the post featured image block.
Next we need to add the tags and comment counts before doing so.
Let's check out the front end one more time.
If we look closely at this part of the template, these elements sit on the same row.
Unlike the other blocks.
We can't stack these blocks without grouping them, otherwise they will not be able to sit in the same
row.
We have a few options at our disposal.
The row group and columns blocks are viable.
These blocks will allow us to achieve the same layout.
For this example, let's go with the row block.
I think it offers enough features for creating this layout back in the editor at the row block to the
second column.
Inside the row block.
Insert the post tags block.
Lastly, insert the post comments count block.
We're almost finished.
There's one more block to add, which is the excerpt.
The excerpt will appear below the row.
Insert the Post Excerpt BLOCK.
While the layout is ready, all that's left is to apply styles to the blocks to consider our template
complete before moving on.
Let's save the templates.
After saving your template, let's begin styling the blocks in the next lecture.
Also you there.