In this lecture, we are going to refactor the team member block in my editor I have the index JS file
opened.
This file is starting to get large.
It's going to continue to grow in future lectures.
We are going to start adding code for modifying the team member image.
In addition, the social media links must be functional to reduce bloat.
I recommend separating the edit and save functions into separate files.
It's common practice to create separate files for each function.
You will see this practice implemented in various blocks.
It's a great way to refactor a block.
Let's give it a shot inside the directory for the team member block.
Create two files called Edit JS and Save JS.
Next.
Let's switch back to the index file from this file.
Cut the edit function.
Paste it into the edit file.
Next, replace the name with the function keyword.
Lastly, export the function under the default namespace.
Back in the index file.
Grab the save function.
We are going to do the same thing as before.
Export this function from the saved file.
Both files won't be functional without the proper import statements.
Let's start moving the import statements to their respective files in the index file.
Grab the import statements for the block editor, i.e. 18 n components, blob and element packages.
Paste these import statements into the edit file.
Next pace these same import statements into these saved file.
They say Phil does not need the components blob and element packages.
We can safely remove them.
From the block ed package.
Remove the inspector controls and media placeholder components.
After moving everything over, we can start importing these functions back into the index file at the
top of the file, import the edit and save functions from their respective files.
The last step is to add these functions to the register block type function.
Hopefully nothing is broken just to make sure.
Let's try testing our block in the Gutenberg Editor.
Try adding the team members block to the ED.
The block is fully functional.
Everything we've worked on still works.
We can add an image or modify the bio.
The block is working as intended by refactoring our code.
It will be easier to navigate around.
This step is completely optional.
You can continue working within a single file.
However, splitting your code into files will make it easier to develop blocks.