In this lecture, we are going to talk about an important concept called a rest API.
Rest stands for representational state transfer.
That's a mouthful.
It sounds like a complicated concept, but I promise it's not.
Let's dive into why a rest API is useful and how it's relevant to WordPress.
As we've learned, servers are capable of sending files to the client.
We can send HTML video, image and audio files.
The list is endless.
We can even send executable files.
Some files can be previewed from the browser such as an image.
But what if we don't want to send a file?
Is it possible to send data?
The answer is yes.
Instead of sending a file, servers can send and receive data via HTTP.
This is known as a rest API.
Sending data over HTTP is considered to be more efficient than sending an entire file.
Typically the size of a file can range from a few kilobytes to megabytes, whereas data can be compressed
into a few bytes.
For this reason, sending data is better than refreshing the page by refreshing the page.
The HTML images, CSS and script files must be re downloaded.
By communicating with data, we can quickly receive a response from a server.
This performance can enhance the user experience.
Rest APIs are very popular with developers in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to a popular rest API playground for beginner developers.
This site offers examples of various URLs that can accept and send data.
If we scroll down the page, there's a section called Resources.
Let's click on the posts link.
Almost immediately we are going to be greeted with JSON.
Your page may not look like mine by default.
Most browsers do not format JSON data in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to an extension called JSON Formatter.
This extension will add syntax highlighting to a JSON response.
If you're not using Chrome, don't worry.
In a moment I'll be introducing a tool for viewing data from a rest API.
Back to the playground, we are presented with an endless sea of data.
In a nutshell, this is what a rest API looks like.
We are not presented with a document for viewing a page and said the server is sending data to the client.
It's up to us to present this data to a client.
This begs the question what does this have to do with WordPress?
Like I said before, rest APIs are very popular with developers.
This includes WordPress developers.
WordPress adds a rest API for developers to take advantage of.
We can perform requests from grabbing a list of posts to adding media and the resource section of this
lecture.
I provide a link to the WordPress Rest API handbook.
Everything related to the rest API can be found in this handbook.
On the sidebar, there's a section called endpoint reference.
The word endpoint will pop up a lot in the documentation in regards to rest, APIs and endpoint refers
to the path for a resource.
For example, let's say we had a URL for retrieving a post.
The full URL could be example slash post.
The path appended to the end of the URL would be considered the endpoint.
This section of the handbook will likely be the most useful resource.
It will provide a list of URLs with additional information on data that can be sent to each URL.
The responses are also documented in the next lecture.
Let's get some practice with the WordPress Rest API before trying to register and log users in.