In this lecture, we are going to begin adding fields to our form.
This step is very easy.
Similar to other steps, WordPress has a function for adding a field.
Fields must be added to a section.
Luckily we have a section on our page.
Our fields can be added to this section.
Let's get started by opening the settings api php file.
At the bottom of the function, run a function called add settings fields.
This function will add a field to a section.
There are five arguments.
The first argument is an ID for the field.
Let's set the ID to ogg title input.
Next, we must add the text for the label.
The label will sit to the side of the input.
This input will represent the title of the open graph.
Let's use the following translatable text open graph title.
Up next, we must provide a function for rendering the input.
The input element is our responsibility.
The Settings API does not render this element, but it will help us with setting the value.
The name of our function will be called OGG Title Input CB.
In a moment, we will define this function.
Let's move on to the next argument, which is the pages name.
WordPress doesn't know which page the input will appear on.
Therefore, we must provide the name.
The value must correspond with the value passed into the due settings section's function.
In our case, the page's name is called Up Options Page.
Lastly, we must provide the name of the section.
Our section is called Up Options Section.
Great.
The last step is to define the function for rendering the input below this function.
Define the OGG title input CB function.
In this function, we can output an input element for storing the value.
First, let's grab the option.
Define a variable called options.
The value for this variable will be the get option function.
The name of the option is called up options.
Afterward.
Let's render the input element.
On this element set the class attribute to regular text.
The input will have similar attributes to the element from the other page.
Next, let's set the name attribute to the following value up options OG Title.
Here's where things become different.
Normally, we would give our input to a custom name.
However, we must set the name attribute to the name of the option.
WordPress handles processing the form.
We do not need to intercept the request.
For this reason, the name of our input must match the name of our option.
If our option is an array, we need to add a pair of square brackets to specify the item in the array.
The last attribute will be the value attribute we should output.
The current value of this function.
Echo the options OG title variable with the escape attribute function.
Let's test our input before adding the other inputs in the browser.
Refresh the page.
Our input appears in the section with the original value of the option.
Great.
Let's try adding the other fields to our form.
The process is going to be very similar.
Back in the editor, let's make three copies of the add settings field function.
In total, we are going to have four fields.
Each copy should reflect an option from our plugin.
Let's update these fields first.
The second field can be updated by changing the word title to image.
Next, change the third field by changing the word title to description.
Lastly, change the fourth field by changing the word title to enable.
We're almost done.
The last step is to define the function for rendering the inputs of our other fields.
To save time, I have prepared these functions for you.
In the resource section of this lecture, I provide a link to a gist.
This just contains a list of functions for the inputs.
Copy them to your clipboard.
Next paced them into the settings api dot php file.
If you were to look through the functions, you'd notice one thing they're very similar to the inputs
from the original page.
We can safely copy and paste the inputs from the original page to these functions.
The modifications I've performed on these inputs are by changing the name attribute to the fields respective
option.
Other than that, they're mostly the same for the image.
I'm using the button to change the image.
However, this solution will not work.
The script for handling the media library will not be in queued on our page.
Let's update the and queue PHP file.
Inside the conditional statements and the following condition or hook suffix.
Equals equals equals.
Utility plus page up.
Plug in options alt.
Ahead of time.
I echoed the hook suffix variable for the other page.
The name and our condition is the name assigned by WordPress for our page.
Let's refresh the page in the browser.
As you can see, the fields appear in the section.
We can freely modify the values, including the image.
After modifying these values, we can submit the form.
Like I said before, we do not need to intercept the request.
The Settings API is capable of updating our options.
This is one of the benefits of using the settings API.
We can avoid processing the request.
We've completed the form with the settings API.
In this section.
Both forms perform the same action.
The first form is a custom form.
The other form was developed with the Settings API.
Each developer is different.
Some might like the Settings API, but others may not.
There isn't a wrong answer.
Use whichever solution suits your plugin.
I just wanted to present both options in the next set of lectures.
We are going to begin adding these options to the Gutenberg Editor.