In this lecture, we are going to add a toolbar option for replacing an image.
The toolbar is extendable for blocks.
We're not limited to the options created by WordPress.
The Gutenberg Editor provides an option for adding custom buttons in the toolbar.
Let's add a button for changing the image of a team member in your editor.
Open the edit Edge's file.
First we need to import two components from the components package import to components called block
controls and media replace flow.
Next, let's use these components in our block at the top of the fragment element.
Add the block controls component with opening and closing tags.
The BLOCK Control's component will allow us to insert elements into the toolbar.
This component must sit at the root level of the edit component.
Anything written inside this component will be inserted into the toolbar.
WordPress will handle positioning our content in the correct location inside this component.
Let's add the media replace flow component.
The media replace flow component was introduced for adding a button in the toolbar.
This button is capable of opening the media library.
It's very similar to the media placeholder component.
The difference is that the media replace flow component outputs a button.
It does not output a complete interface for uploading a file or inserting a link.
It's just a simple button.
This component has a few properties.
First, we can configure the text inside the button by adding the name property.
Let's translate the text with the double underscore function.
The button text will contain the following message replace image.
Next, the media library can preselect an image.
I think it would be a good idea to preselect the currently uploaded image.
This way users can modify the alt text without selecting the image again.
We can preselect an image by adding two properties.
The first property is called Media ID.
The value for this property must be the ID of the media file.
As mentioned before, WordPress stores a record of a media file in a database.
Every file uploaded to WordPress has a unique ID associated with it.
We stored this ID as an attribute.
Let's set this property to the image ID attributes.
The next property is called media URL.
The value for this property must be the URL to the image.
Let's set this property to the image.
URL attributes.
The URL does not need to be the URL to the original image.
The URL can be to any of the image sizes.
After adding these to properties, the image will be pre selected before going further.
This button should not appear if an image has not been uploaded.
The purpose of this button is to replace the image, not set the initial image.
Let's conditionally render the media replace flow components above this component.
Add the following expression image preview and.
Next move the media replace FLO component after the and operator.
Great.
Let's keep working on the media replace flow components.
The next step is to limit the file selected by the component.
This component supports the accept and accepted types properties that are identical to the properties
with the same name on the media placeholder components.
Let's copy these properties from the media placeholder component to the media replace flow component.
We're almost finished.
The next properties are events similar to the media placeholder component.
The Media Replace Flow Component has an event for errors and image selections.
Let's add the on air event.
For this event, we are going to pass in an arrow function to handle the event.
This function is provided the error as an argument.
Inside the function's body.
Lets log the error with the console dot error function.
Next, add the on select event.
The value for this event will be the same function passed into the media placeholder component.
However, I don't think it's a good idea to have two copies of the same function.
One of them changes.
The other needs to reflect those changes.
Oftentimes, developers will outsource the function into a variable.
This practice keeps our code base readable and maintainable.
Scroll on to the media placeholder component.
Let's grab the function from the on select event.
Next above the return statement, create a variable called Select Image.
The value for this variable will be the function from earlier.
Next, let's set the on select event from both components to this function.
We are going to do the same for the on select URL event.
Grab the function for this event from the media placeholder component.
Next, create a variable called select image URL with this function as the value.
Lastly, set the on select URL event on the media.
Replace flow component to this variable.
Update the media placeholder component to use this variable.
These steps are not required, but it can make it easier to maintain our block by adding these two components.
A button should appear in the toolbar.
This button will allow us to change the image.
Let's give it a try in the browser.
Refresh the page.
Next, add the team group members block.
We can select an individual team member to view the toolbar.
So far the button does not appear, which is what we want.
The option for replacing an image should not appear until an image has been uploaded.
Try adding an image.
After selecting an image, the button appears in the toolbar.
We can click on this button to view a dropdown.
We are presented with the option to open the media library or upload an image.
Let's open the media library from the media library.
The image has been pre selected.
We do not need to select the image again if we want to change the details.
Alternatively, we can select a new image.
Let's give that a try.
Upon selecting a new image, the image appears in the block.
Perfect.
We've successfully added the option to replace an image in the toolbar.
In the next lecture.
Let's set an option to delete the image from the block.