In this lecture, we will review the other settings for enabling or disabling typography features.
There's not much to say.
Let's quickly run through them in your editor.
Open the theme JSON file.
All settings will be applied to the typography object under these settings object.
The first setting that can be toggled is line height.
The value for this property must be a boolean.
Let's set it to true.
This setting will allow users to modify the line height see property most blocks with typography settings
can have their line height modified by default.
Customizing the line height is disabled.
Up next, let's add a property called drop cap with a value of true.
The Drop Camp property will enable the option of enlarging the first letter of a paragraph.
Currently, the paragraph block is the only block that supports this option.
Afterward, we can enable the font weight option by setting it to true.
The font weight refers to the text thickness.
Next, let's add the font style property with a value of true.
The font style property allows users to add italic text.
The next property on our list is called text transform.
The value for this property will be true.
This property will change text casing such as uppercase, lowercase or capitalization or almost finished.
The spacing between letters can be enabled by setting the letter spacing property to true.
Lastly underlines and strike thrus can be enabled by adding the text decoration property with a value
of true.
To be clear, most of these settings are already enabled.
Setting them to true is redundant.
However, I'm including them.
For example purposes.
Let's check out the ED in the browser.
The best way to test our settings is by adding a paragraph block to our template.
The paragraph block has support for all typography settings under the sidebar.
You should be able to find the typography settings.
Initially, most settings may be hidden.
You can toggle their appearances under the more menu item from this list.
We can modify the line height, letter, case, letter, spacing and drop cap.
As you can see, WordPress provides us with plenty of options for modifying the appearance of our text.
Keep in mind these settings can be modified on a block level too.
These typography settings should cover most use cases.
We're almost finished with our discussion of typography.
I'll see you in the next lecture.