In this lecture, we are going to add a custom endpoints.
At the moment, WordPress does not offer an endpoint for registering a new user.
We must create a custom endpoint for handling user registration.
New endpoints can be created with a single function.
Let's get started in your editor.
Open the indexed PHP plugin file.
Under the hook section.
Call the add action function.
We are going to register a function for a hook called rest API in it.
The rest API it hook is triggered when a request is made to WordPress as rest API.
At this point we can register a new endpoint before WordPress sends a response.
Let's set the function name to up rest API in its.
Afterward, let's create a file to contain the function definition inside the included directory.
Create a folder called Rest API.
We are going to be defining a few endpoints, creating a directory dedicated to the rest API.
We'll keep our code base organized inside this folder.
Create a file called in its PHP.
Define the up rest api and it function.
The file does not need to be included.
It's already included with the glob tool.
The last step is to define a new endpoint.
In the resource section of this lecture, I provide a link to a function called Register Rest Routes.
This function will register a new route with the rest API.
According to the description, we should not call this function before the rest API init hook.
Luckily we're using this hook for registering our routes.
This shouldn't be an issue.
Let's scroll to the parameters section.
According to the documentation, we must provide a namespace end arounds.
Let's try using this function.
Head back to the PHP file.
Inside our function.
Let's call the register rest root function.
The first argument is the namespace, as we've learned.
Name spacing is a technique for preventing conflicts with other functions, variables or classes.
The up rest API init function is an example.
We are pre fixing our functions with up the rest API is no difference.
Other plugins may introduce new endpoints to prevent conflicts with other endpoints.
It's recommended to add a namespace to our endpoints.
For example, WordPress reserves, the WP slash v two namespace.
The format for a namespace is the name of our plugin followed by the version.
Earlier I mentioned that rest APIs are popular.
It's common for rest APIs to evolve.
Similar to plugins.
We should add a version to help other developers identify the latest version.
This is a fresh plugin.
It's fair to say that we're on v one.
Let's set the namespace argument to up slash v one.
Next, we must add the endpoint.
Let's set the endpoint to slash sign up.
These values will register a new endpoint.
For example, let's say our site was hosted on a domain called example.
The full URL would be the following example dot com slash wp json slash up slash v one slash sign up.
The WP JSON segment must be included with the path it applies to core and custom endpoints.
After registering a root, we must provide a function for handling the response.
We can configure the root by passing in an array to the third argument.
Inside this array.
Let's set a key called Methods to Post.
We can configure the HTTP method with this key.
The route we've created we'll register a new user.
Hence we are creating a new resource on our site.
The post method is the most appropriate method for creating resources.
Next, let's add a key called callback.
This key will contain the name of function to run when the endpoint is visited.
We are going to call our function up rest API sign up handler.
There's one more key that we should add called permission callback.
Security is very important.
Custom endpoints must have this key before WordPress runs the callback function.
It'll check if the user has proper permissions for visiting this route.
The value for this key must be a function.
The function must return true to allow access to the root.
We can deny access by returning false for this route or going to allow anyone to visit it.
Let's use a special function called underscore.
Underscore return.
Underscore.
True.
This function is defined by WordPress.
In the resource section of this lecture, I provide a link to this function.
As the name implies, this function will return true.
If we scroll to the source section, we can take a look at the body of the function.
It looks like a weird function to define.
However, we're allowing anyone to register on accounts.
Our function should return.
True, rather than being redundant, we can leverage word press functions.
It's quicker and easier.
The round has been successfully created.
Let's try testing it with Postman in the Postman app.
Navigate to the workspace for our site.
The previous session should have been saved.
If not, you can re-enter the URL to our site inside the address bar.
We are going to replace the path with the following path.
WP json slash up slash v one slash sign up.
The new route will start with the namespace afterword.
The end point is appended to the namespace.
Let's update the method to post.
Inside the query parameter section.
Remove any parameters.
After doing so, let's send the request.
After a few moments, WordPress should receive the request.
The response from the server will be a 500 error code.
A 500 error code is thrown when the server couldn't properly process the request.
Inside the responses body, a JSON object is returned with details of the error.
Let's read the message property.
The handler for the root is invalid.
The problem stems from not defining the PHP function for handling the new endpoint.
That's perfectly fine.
As long as WordPress has identified our new routes, we're good to go.
In the next lecture, let's define the function for handling the response.