In this lecture, we are going to add a custom toolbar button for removing an image.
So far we have added the media replace flow component to render a button in the toolbar.
But what if we need to output a custom button?
WordPress has you covered in your editor.
Open the editor JS file.
From the components package import a component called Toolbar Button.
This component will render a button for the toolbar.
We can use this component to add custom behavior to our block.
It's a very simple component.
Let's scroll to the block controls component below the media replace flow component.
Let's add the toolbar button component with opening and closing tags.
Inside the tags add the double underscore a function with the following translated text remove image.
Lastly, let's remove the image on a click event.
The toolbar button component supports the on click event for handling clicks.
Let's add this event to the component with an arrow function for handling the event.
Inside this function, we can reset the attributes with the set attributes function.
The image ID attribute will be set to zero.
The image alt and image URL attributes can be reset to empty strings.
Next, let's update the state by calling the set image preview function with an empty string.
This function should be called from the select image URL function.
I forgot to update it from the previous lecture.
Scroll to this function and our function.
Call this function with the URL argument.
Perfect.
Our code should be functional.
There's one more adjustment than I would like to make.
We have multiple buttons in the toolbar.
The more buttons there are in the toolbar, the more difficult it can be to read the toolbar.
For readability, we can separate our buttons by adding the group property to the block controls component.
The group property will surround our buttons with separators.
It's a subtle change, but will help make our buttons stand out.
The value for this property must be set to in-line.
Let's try testing the block by adding the team members group block to the page.
Next, try selecting an image.
After selecting an image, an option will appear in the toolbar to remove it.
We can click on this option to remove the image.
We've successfully added an option to remove the image.
After removing the image, the media placeholder component will reappear.
Adding a button on the toolbar is as simple as using a single component.
Let's continue working on our block in the next lecture.