In this lecture, we are going to start adding the fields to the Gutenberg editor by creating a script.
Unlike before, Gutenberg does not support the Settings API.
We must use JavaScript and react to add forms to the page.
Therefore, let's create a script for adding these fields in the source folder.
Create a new directory called BLOCK Editor.
We are going to store files related to the editor in this directory.
Blocks are not our only option for extending the editor.
Other areas of the editor can be modified.
For example, we can add a custom sidebar.
This allows us to add settings that are independent of a block.
Files that are not for blocks can be created inside this directory.
Let's create a file called Index dot js.
Next, let's create a file called Sidebar JS.
The index dogs file will be considered the entry point for organization reasons.
We are going to separate the code for the sidebar in a separate file from the index file.
Import the sidebar js file.
Afterward log a simple message from the signed bar file.
Next, we should process these files through Webpack.
The files we're creating are not blocks.
Therefore, Webpack will not bother processing our files.
Open the webpack config dot js file.
Inside the entry object at a property called BLOCK Editor Slash Index.
These files will be stored in a separate directory from our blocks.
Next, let's set the value to the following dot slash source slash block editor.
Let's verify the files are being bundled by restarting the NPM run, start command and the command line.
New entry points will not be picked up by Westpac any time the configuration file is modified.
We must always restart the command for the changes to take effect after the command has been restarted.
Let's check out the build directory.
As expected, the files have been generated.
The last step is to queue these files.
Let's quickly do that.
Open the register assets, not PHP file.
At the bottom file.
Let's register the script with the WP Register script function.
The name of our handle will be called up.
Ed.
The path to the file will be the following plugins your URL slash build slash block editor slash index
dot js up plugin directory.
Next, let's include the PHP file for this script.
It'll include the list of dependencies and version far scripts above the function.
Define a variable called editor asset with the following value.
Include a plugin directory dot build slash block editor slash index dot asset php.
After including this file, we can set the third and fourth arguments to the editor asset dependencies
and editor asset version variables.
Lastly, let's set the fifth argument to true.
This argument will force the script to load in the footer.
We do not want to block the Gutenberg editor from loading.
The last step is to queue these files.
WordPress has a special hook for queuing files in the Gutenberg Editor.
This saves us time for checking the current page.
Open the main plugin file.
At the bottom of the hook section at an action hook called in Q BLOCK Editor Assets.
The name of our function will be called up in Q BLOCK Editor assets.
Let's create a file called editor assets php inside the admin folder.
Inside this file defined the function from the hook.
Before interviewing the files, we should perform a single check.
I wasn't being completely honest.
This hook runs for two different types of pages.
It'll run for the full site editor and the page for editing a post.
These settings should be available for individual posts.
It doesn't make sense to add Field for modifying a page's open graph settings from the full site editor.
Let's create a conditional statement for checking the current page.
Unfortunately, the hook is not provided the name of the page.
There is an alternative solution inside the function.
Define a variable called current screen.
The value for this variable will be the get current screen function.
The get current screen function returns an object with information on the current page.
This includes the name of the page.
We can use this information to identify the page.
You're more than welcome to.
Well, put this variable onto the screen.
I've already done so.
To save time, I will provide the name of the page.
In a conditional statement, write the following condition Current screen base equals equals appearance
page.
Gutenberg Dash.
Edit Site.
The object has a property called base.
This property contains the type of page and this example we're checking if the page is the full site
editor.
If it is, we are going to return the function.
This will immediately stop the function from running after the conditional block lets in.
Q The script with the WP and Q script function.
The name of the script is called Up Editor.
After renewing the script, we can try testing our scripts in the browser, trying viewing a random
post with the Gutenberg editor.
The script should load for any page.
Open the console panel from the developer tools within the panel, the message from our script will
appear perfect.
We've successfully created and include a file for handling the custom fields.
In the next lecture, we are going to begin adding a sidebar for rendering the fields for modifying
a post's metadata.