In this lecture, we are going to register a sidebar.
At the moment I'm viewing a random post with the Gutenberg editor.
At the top right corner, there's a button for toggling the sidebar.
This sidebar contains the settings for the page or block.
The sidebar can be toggled by clicking on this button.
WordPress offers us the option to add a custom sidebar.
Within this sidebar, we can render custom field for modifying a post metadata.
Let's try rendering a sidebar in your editor.
Open the sidebar JS file.
At the top of the file import a function called registered plugin from the WordPress slash plugins package.
WordPress provides this function for registering plugins with the Gutenberg editor.
It'll allow us to render a React component from within the application.
Our goal is to create a signed bar below this import statement.
Import a component called plug and sidebar from the WordPress slash edit post package.
The plugin sidebar component will create the interface for rendering a sidebar.
WordPress will handle positioning and toggling the appearance of the sidebar.
It's an incredibly helpful component.
There's one less thing we'll need.
Let's import the double underscore function from the WordPress slash IE 18 and package.
We can begin rendering the sidebar below the import statement.
Run the register plug function.
Registering the plugin is the first step.
We don't want to render the component immediately.
It should render after the editor has been loaded.
The registered plug and function will make sure our component gets rendered at the right time.
There are two arguments.
The first argument is the name of our plugin.
Let's call it up sidebar.
The second argument is an object of configuration settings.
In this object.
Define a function called render.
The render function is responsible for rendering a component within this function.
Let's return the plugin sidebar components.
This component has three properties.
The first property is called name.
Multiple sidebars can be added to the editor.
The name of our sidebar should contain a unique name.
Otherwise WordPress may be confused as to what sidebar to open.
Let's set the name to up sidebar.
Next at a property called Icon.
The value for this icon can be a valid icon.
Let's use the share icon.
I think this icon is appropriate for our sidebar.
The open graph protocol was introduced for displaying previews of a site on social media platforms.
Lastly, let's add a property called Title.
This property will display text at the top of the sidebar.
Our title will contain the following translatable text Udemy plus sidebar.
Lastly inside the component, lets add random text.
Before proceeding further.
Let's test our sidebar in the browser.
Refresh the page.
At the top right corner of the page, a button with the social icon has appeared.
We can click on this button to open our sidebar.
As you can see, WordPress has successfully rendered our sidebar.
The next step becomes obvious.
We can start rendering a set of fields for manipulating the metadata.
In the next lecture, let's begin rendering fields.