In this lecture, we are going to start rendering the fields for modifying the Post's metadata.
To get started, we'll need to ground the metadata.
Without this information, the fields will appear empty in your editor.
Open the sign bar JS file.
At the top of the file.
Import the use select function from the WordPress slash data package.
This function will help us select the metadata from the current post back in the function run the use
select function with an arrow function.
The arrow function will be provided the select function for selecting a storage from the application
state.
Let's return the following value.
Select core slash editor dot get edited post attribute meta.
We are familiar with this function.
We used it for retrieving the Post's metadata for the recipe.
Summary BLOCK Lets store the metadata in a variable for readability, the metadata should be structured
the structure the following metadata values.
OG Image.
OG Description.
OG Override image.
After grabbing the values, we can start rendering the fields.
In the resource section of this lecture, I provide a link to a gist.
This just contains a couple of components for rendering the fields to save time.
I prepared the inner components of the sidebar.
All of these components are familiar to us.
We've used them dozens of times for other blocks.
Copy this code to your clipboard.
Next.
Head back to the editor.
Paste the code into the plugin sidebar component.
Lastly, the components must be imported at the top of the page.
Add an import statement for the WordPress components package.
Import the following components.
Panel Body Text Control.
Text Area Control.
Toggle Control.
Before previewing our code.
There's one thing I want to highlight about the components.
If you look through the templates, the components have empty on change events.
In the next lecture, we will update the components to update the metadata.
For now, the fields will not be modifiable.
Let's refresh the page.
We can click on the button to open the sidebar.
As you can see, there are three fields.
The only field missing is the image.
We'll work on that in the future lecture.
As long as you can view the fields, you're good to go.
In the next lecture, let's begin updating the metadata during updates on our fields.