In this lecture, we are going to dispatch updates for updating the metadata of a post.
Thus far, we've created custom endpoints for modifying the data of a site.
In other situations, we created hooks for intercepting requests.
From these hooks, we performed updates to the database.
This time we're going to look at a different solution.
WordPress is capable of updating metadata without a custom end point.
By using the register post meta function, WordPress will allow users to modify metadata through the
rest API.
It'll handle performing updates on our data.
All we have to do is send the data to the appropriate end point.
WordPress has a set of dedicated functions for sending requests to the rest API.
Let's give them a try in your editor.
Open the sidebar JS file.
At the top of the file.
Import the used dispatch function from the data package.
WordPress separates the functions for updating data in another storage.
If we're trying to select data, we must use the use select function functions for updating data can
be retrieved via the used dispatch function.
Let's look at an example in the render function.
Call the used dispatch function.
Similar to the use select function.
We must provide the storage name typically if we're interested in updating data selected earlier.
The functions for updating the same data can be found from the same storage.
For example, metadata can be selected from the core slash editor storage.
Therefore, functions for updating metadata can be found within the same storage.
Let's pass in the same name to the used dispatch function.
This function will return an object of functions.
These functions can update various pieces of information on the editor.
Let's structure the object for a function called edit post.
If you're curious as to how I know what the function names are, you can refer to the documentation.
In the resource section of this lecture, I provide a link to an official list of storages.
On this page we can click on the link for the storages respective functions for each storage.
There are two sections.
The first section is called selectors.
Functions listed under this section can be retrieved by selecting the storage with the use select function.
The other section is called actions.
Under this section, there's a list of functions that can be retrieved by selecting the storage with
the used dispatch function.
Under this section you will find the edit post function.
In my opinion, the page isn't well documented.
Hopefully that'll change in the future.
Let's head back to the editor.
We can start using the edit post function for modifying a post's attributes.
We will call this function from the events emitted by the controls.
The first control is for the title of the Open Graph Preview in the on change events.
Run the edit post function.
This function accepts an object of properties that can be modified on the post.
We're not limited to modifying metadata.
Other attributes can be changed.
In our case, we're attempting to change the metadata.
Let's add an object called Meta.
In this object, we can change any of the metadata values.
Let's set the OGG title metadata to the OGG title arguments.
The process will be the same for the other events.
We can copy and paste the solution for the other events.
The second control will modify the description.
Let's paste the code into the on change events.
Change the metadata key from OG title to OG description.
The last field is for toggling the override option.
Paste the snippet into the on change event.
Lastly, change the key from OG title to OG override image.
After modifying the events, we can try testing our code in the browser.
Refresh the page.
If we look inside the sidebar, nothing changes.
However, we can freely modify the fields as we do so.
The update button at the top right corner will light up.
Our updates are not immediately applied to the post.
They're queued in the background.
It would be inefficient to update a post on every keystroke.
WordPress will update the post all at once.
The moment we press update, the metadata will be updated.
Let's refresh the page.
If we check the sidebar, the new values for our option have persisted.
That's exactly what we wanted.
The only field missing is for the image in the next lecture.
Let's begin working on allowing users to select an image for the Open Graph Preview.