In this lecture, we will add a button for adding new social media links for a team member.
For additional help, let's create this button with a tool tip.
WordPress has a component for easily adding tooltips to an element.
Let's get started in your editor.
Open the edit JS file.
First, let's grab the components we're going to need for this lecture from the components package.
Grab the tool tip and icon components.
The icon component will render an icon from the dash icon font set.
This icon set has a plus icon which is perfect for our needs.
Next, scroll to the loop for the social media links.
Below the loop and the tooltip component.
The tooltip component is responsible for rendering a tooltip.
The component must be wrapped around the element that will have the tooltip.
Before adding the link, lets add the message in the tooltip.
The message can be customized by adding the text property.
Let's set this property to the following message with the double underscore function add social media
handle.
Next, let's add an anchor element inside the tooltip component.
Set the ref attribute to the hash character.
If this button is clicked, a new social media link will be added to the current array of links.
Lets add the on click event to the function with an arrow function as the value.
And the argument list except the event argument.
Clicking on a link will cause the URL to change.
To prevent this behavior.
Let's call the prevent default method on the event object.
Next, let's update the social handles attribute using the set attributes function.
Unfortunately, the set attributes function will completely override and attributes value.
That's not what we want.
The goal is to add a new item to the array.
We can achieve this result by setting the social handles attribute to an array.
In this array, we can spread the current value of the attribute into the new array.
Next, we can add an object to add a new item in this object.
Let's set the icon property to the question.
Icon.
The IRL property will be an empty string.
This solution will add a new item to the array.
Next, we can begin rendering the icon inside the anchor element.
Add the icon component.
The icon can be configured by adding a property called icon.
The value for this icon must be a valid icon.
Name from the dash icon font set.
The name of the icon for adding a plus symbol is called plus.
Let's test our code in the browser.
Try adding the team members group block to the page.
We can hover our mouse over the plus button to view the tooltip.
The tooltip renders without a problem.
WordPress can handle toggling the tooltip based on mouse events.
Now that we've confirmed the tooltip works, let's try clicking on the button to add a new social media
link.
The new links will have question mark icons.
Perfect.
We've successfully added an option for adding new links.
Let's continue working on this section in the next lecture.