In this lecture, we are going to create a custom interface for opening the media library.
Previously, we used the media placeholder component for generating an interface.
This interface had a button for opening the library.
However, this component is not our only option for opening the media library.
We're more than welcome to create a custom interface.
You may prefer to develop a custom interface over using WordPress interface.
Let's try creating a simple interface for opening the media library in your editor.
Open the sidebar file.
At the top of the file import to components called Media Upload and Media Upload Check from the WordPress
slash block editor package.
There's one component we will need from the components package.
Import the button component.
Now that we have our components, we can begin rendering them.
Head back to the panel body components at the bottom of this component.
Add the following expression ogg override image and.
The interface for selecting an image should not be rendered unless the user wants to use a custom image.
There isn't a point in rendering this UI if the user prefers the featured image.
Next, add a fragment element with the image tag.
React does not allow us to render multiple route elements.
In our case, we're going to need to render the image and the interface for selecting an image on the
root level.
So we get around this error.
We can use the fragment element for grouping our elements.
The image tag will render a preview of the selected image on this tag.
Set the source attribute to the Ogg image variable.
Next below this image and the media upload check component.
Not everyone has access to the media library before rendering the media library.
We should check the user's capabilities.
This component will validate the user before rendering the media library.
Previously, we did not have to check the user's permissions.
This is because the media placeholder component performs this check for us.
If we're not using this component, we must perform the check ourselves.
The media upload check component was designed for this purpose.
If the user has permission, the content written inside the component will become visible.
Let's render the media upload component.
This component will allow us to create a custom interface for opening the media library.
In addition, it can communicate with the media library to configure its settings.
Let's add a few properties.
First, let's set the accept property to an array of valid file types.
We are going to limit the file types to image types.
Next at a property called Render.
The render property accepts a function for rendering the interface for opening the library.
We have complete control over how the media library is opened.
Let's pass in an arrow function.
From this function, we must return gsx.
Let's return the button component.
On this component.
Let's add a property called is primary.
The IS primary property will change the colour of the button to blue.
This property is optional.
However, I think it worked for our interface.
Inside the button add the following translatable text change image.
Next, we should start opening the media library.
Conveniently, the function is provided an object with various methods for interacting with the media
library.
Let's structure the argument for a function called Open.
By calling this function, we can open the media library.
On the button component, add the on click event.
If this event gets triggered, we'll call the open function.
The interface for opening the media library is ready.
There's one more property we'll add to the media upload component called on Select.
This property is an event that will get emitted when an image is selected.
We can pass in an arrow function to handle the selection.
The arrow function can accept an argument called image.
This argument is an object with properties related to the current selection.
Let's call the edit post function.
In the object.
Add the meta object.
Next set the OG image property to the following value image sizes.
Dot open graph dot url.
You can long b image argument for a list of properties available.
It'll contain the typical properties for any media item.
Let's refresh the page to test our code.
Open the custom sidebar.
Initially, the button will be hidden from the user.
We can click on the override option to toggle the visibility of this modal.
It should appear, since we have proper permissions for interacting with the media library.
Let's select an image.
Next update The Post.
Lastly, refresh the page.
Our image continues to persist in the sidebar.
The media library is completely functional.
With a few lines of code, we're able to create a custom interface.
We may not need all the bells and whistles of the media placeholder components.
In some cases, you may need to create a custom interface that's completely possible with two components.
We're almost finished with our open graph solution.
The final step is to render the tags for adding a preview to the page in the next lecture.
Let's handle this step.