In this lecture, we are going to explore the idea of components.
HTML was never designed to be scalable.
Like other languages, files can easily become thousands of lines long.
Trying to find an element within a document can be tedious.
The larger your file becomes, it isn't possible to split your HTML into separate files for a single
page.
React has curated a solution for tackling this problem.
Components are supported and React.
What is a component?
A component is a feature for teaching the browser.
New tags browsers will have various tags from paragraph tags to video tags.
Each tag will create a UI element on the browser.
Some tags will render text.
Other tags will render fully functional video players.
With React, we can create custom elements.
For example, we can teach the browser to render a login form.
Best of all, we have complete control over the behavior and appearance of a component.
The sky is the limits.
I've got a secret for you.
We have already created our first components.
The page function can be considered a component.
Components are created with functions.
There's just one rule.
The function must return JZ X Other than that, React will recognize our functions as components.
To prove it, let's update the render function inside the first argument.
We're going to replace the page function with a self closing page tag.
If we were to look at the page, our app is fully functional.
That's incredible.
React was able to detect that we are writing a custom components.
It'll search our application for a function definition that shares the same name.
If it finds a function.
It'll invoke the function and render the returned value.
We're not limited to a single component.
An unlimited number of components can be created.
Let's try creating another component above the page function.
Defining a function called header.
It's considered standard practice to capitalize the name of a component.
The names for regular high HTML elements are all lowercase.
This naming convention helps developers distinguish custom component names from regular elements.
This component will be responsible for rendering the H one tag from the page components.
Let's move the H one tag over to our new component.
Lastly, we're going to return the elements unlike before.
We're not going to wrap the element with parentheses.
A pair of parentheses are optional.
If you're writing multi line X, the heading element can be returned on a single line.
After making that adjustment, the heading should disappear from the page as an exercise.
Try adding the H one tag back to the page component by using our new function.
Pause the video and give it a try.
Welcome back.
Hopefully you were able to take on the exercise.
Don't worry if you couldn't.
Let's tackle the solution together.
Back in the page component, we can load the header component by adding a self closing tag with the
same name as the function.
In a few seconds, the page will refresh.
As you can see, the heading is back.
Creating components is very easy.
React makes the process painless by leveraging existing features in JavaScript.
Before ending this lecture, let's create a dynamic components.
Previously, our component was displaying the current time.
We've lost that functionality.
Let's add it back in.
Inside the header function.
Define a variable called clock.
Its value will be the date dot to local string function.
Next, we need to inject this variable into the H one tag.
The question is how J6 has a special syntax for adding expressions at the end of the H one tag.
Add a pair of curly brackets inside these brackets.
Insert the clock variable.
The curly brackets act as a placeholder inside the curly brackets.
You must add a valid JavaScript expression before the content is rendered on the screen.
The expression will be processed.
Whatever value was returned by the expression will appear on the page.
As you can see on the page, we have a fully functional clock again.
In a nutshell, components are a core feature of React.
We're not forced to place our entire document structure in a single function.
The UI of the document can be split into various components.
This feature gives developers a maintainable and scalable project.