In this lecture, we are going to work on saving the block in the database.
Unlike previous blocks, this block can be saved with client side rendering.
We don't need access to the server for this block.
In that case, we can safely save the blocks content in the database.
Let's get started in the editor.
Open the saved JS file.
I've done most of the work for us.
The name, title and bio are saved in the block.
Our job is to finish the rest of the block by saving the team members images and social media links.
Let's start with the image.
First, let's create the classes for the image.
As a reminder, we applied classes to the image to change the shape.
Create a variable called image class with the following value.
WP Image.
Image.
ID Image.
The name of the shape must be added after the second class.
Here's where things become tricky.
The shape of the image comes from the parent block.
This information is accessible via the blocks context.
However, the block context is not available from the save function.
It's only available to the edit function without the block context.
We can't set the images shape.
The solution to our problem is to store the images shape as an attribute.
The team member block will not be able to change the shape.
The parent block will continue to be responsible for setting this information.
We're storing a copy of the shape.
For the sake of the save function, let's add the attribute to the block.
Open the block JSON file.
At the bottom of the attributes object.
Add an attribute called image shape.
The type for this attribute will be string.
The default value for the attribute will be hexagon.
The attribute is ready.
The next step is to update this attribute.
Open the edit file.
Before returning the templates.
Let's call the set attributes function to set the image shape attribute to the context utility plus
slash image shape value.
Whenever the attributes change from the parent block, this information will be sent to children blocks.
The attributes stored locally in the block will always receive the latest updates from the parent block.
We can safely head back to the save function.
To use this attribute, the save function will have access to the latest value of an attribute.
First, lets D structure the image shape attribute from the attributes object.
Next, let's update the image class variable by inserting the image shape variable into the string.
Lastly, we can update the block's template by adding the image at the top of the div tag with the author
meta class.
Add an expression.
Write the following expression.
Image your URL and.
Before rendering the image, we should check for an image.
If an image is not available for a team member, we shouldn't bother rendering an image after the and
operator add the image tag.
Set the source attribute to the image URL attribute.
Next set the alt attribute to the image alt attributes.
Lastly, set the class name attribute to the image class attributes.
Great.
The image is ready.
The next step is to render the social media links search for the div tag with a class called Social
Links inside this tag.
Let's begin looping through the social handles attribute with the map function.
The solution is going to be similar to the loop in the edit function with the exception of the input
field for modifying the attributes links inside the map function pass in an arrow function while accepting
the element as an argument called handle.
From within the function, return and anchor element.
Set the h ref attribute to the handle dot url property.
Next, add an AI element with a class attribute.
The attributes value will be the following byebye handle dot icon.
After making those changes, the save function is complete.
We've successfully saved the image and the social media links and the next lecture.
We're going to optimize our solution by modifying the attributes sources.