In this lecture, we are going to add one more feature to the team members group block.
WordPress has a feature for generating previews of our blocks.
Let's look at an example.
If we were to view the list of blocks, we can hover our mouse over any block.
As we do so, a preview is displayed to the right.
This preview is not a screenshot.
WordPress is generating a preview of the block in real time.
Previews can be a great way to quickly view a block before adding it to your page.
I think it would be beneficial to add a preview to our block.
Despite not configuring our block for a preview, WordPress will create a preview anyway.
For example, let's search for the team members group block.
We can hover our mouse over the block for preview.
The block looks very empty.
We have the option of modifying their preview with custom values.
Let's give that a try in your editor.
Open the block dot JSON file.
At the bottom of the object at an object called example.
The example object can contain configuration settings for the block preview.
For example, we can modify the attributes by adding a property called attributes.
For this example, let's set the column's property to two.
By default, the column's attribute is set to three.
The preview is very small.
I don't think three columns will fit within the preview for the best results possible.
We are reducing the columns to the bare minimum.
The size of the preview will probably affect the design.
I think less is more.
Moving on, let's modify the attributes for the inner blocks.
We can configure the inner blocks of a block by adding the inner blocks array.
Inside this array, we can add blocks to the current block.
As long as the block has an inner block's component, WordPress will be able to render the blocks in
the correct location.
Let's add two blocks.
Since we have two columns, a block is represented by an object.
We can configure the name of the block by adding the name property.
Let's set both objects to Udemy plus slash team member.
In the first object.
Let's set the name to John Doe.
Next set the title attribute to CEO of Udemy.
Afterward set the bio attribute to the following text.
This is a short description of the team member.
Lastly, let's configure the image of their preview by setting the image URL attributes.
For previews.
We should not select an image from the media library as users will not always have the same images.
I recommend using an image available online in the resource section of this lecture, I provide a link
to a site called Pick Some.
Pick some is a free tool for grabbing random images for development.
The dimensions of an image can be generated in real time.
Feel free to look through the site for more info.
I've already grabbed an image I liked.
I'm going to copy the URL next.
I'll head back to the editor to paste in the URL for the image URL attributes.
Let's make a copy of this object.
The settings are going to be exactly the same with the exception of the name.
After copying the object, set the name to Jane Doe.
The preview is ready.
Let's test our code by refreshing the Gutenberg editor in the page.
Let's search for our block from the sidebar.
This time, the preview uses the settings from the block file.
By configuring the preview, we can give users a better idea of what a block will look like.
Keep in mind this is a preview.
If we were to add the block to the page, the block on the page looks nothing like the preview.
The settings are only applicable to the preview.
We're finally finished the block.
We have spent a lot of time configuring the block, but the effort was well worth it.
I know block development can be tricky, but hopefully you're starting to get the flow of things in
the next set of sections.
We will work on a few more blocks before considering our plugin and theme complete when you're ready.
I'll see you in the next lecture.