In this lecture, we are going to finish the log in form by submitting the values to our custom endpoint.
The process is very similar to the registration form.
For this reason, I think this is a great opportunity for an exercise.
Try tackling the solution, pause the video and good luck.
Welcome back.
Hopefully you were able to submit the form without my help.
If not, that's fine.
Let's tackle the solution together.
The first step is to listen for the form submission at the bottom of the function.
Let's run the sign in form.
Add event listener function.
The name of the event is called Submit.
Next pass in an arrow function with the async keyword.
In a moment, we're going to be running an asynchronous function ahead of time.
We are adding the async keyword.
The next step is to disable the default behavior by accepting the event object as an argument.
Inside the function run the events dot prevent default function.
So far so good.
We've got a function for capturing the form submission.
Our next move is to update the form.
Users shouldn't be able to modify their input while the form is in submission.
In addition, we should inform them of the submission.
First, we need to select the elements for performing these actions.
Create a variable called sign in field sets.
The value for the variable will be the dot query selector function.
We're going to select the field set elements.
Similar to the registration form.
The log in form has the field set element wrapped around the inputs.
Next, create a variable called sign in status.
The element containing the status has an ID called sign in status.
Next, let's update the elements.
For starters, we can disable the form by calling the set attribute function on the sign in field set
variable.
The name of the attribute is called disabled.
Its value will be true.
This attribute will disable the form.
Next we can update the sign in status dot inour html property to add a message.
The message will be wrapped with a div tag.
It'll contain the following classes.
Modal Status.
Modal Status info.
The message will contain the following text.
Please wait.
We are logging you in.
Now that we've prepped the interface, the request can be sent to the server.
However, we don't have the URL.
Let's inject the variable into our script by updating the NDK php file.
In an earlier lecture we called an array called off the URLs.
This variable gets injected into the document as a JavaScript variable.
Most of the work has been performed.
We can update the array to include another URL for the log in endpoints inside this array at a key called
sign in.
The value for this key will be the following code.
Escape your URL raw.
Rest your URL up.
Slash v one slash.
Sign in.
After adding the URL, we can head back to the script.
Let's create a variable for the form data below the updates to the form elements.
Create a variable called form data.
The value for this variable will be an object with two properties called user login and password.
The name of the properties is very important.
Our End Point is expecting properties with these names.
Otherwise, our request may be rejected.
The value for the user log in property will be the following sign in form dot query selector hash c
email value.
In the form, I have given each input an ID the value for the password property will be the same, except
the ID is called c password.
Lastly, we can start sending this data to the end point after the variable call the fetch function.
The first argument is the URL.
Let's pass the up off rest sign in variable.
Next pass in an object for configuring the request.
The endpoint only accepts post requests.
Let's set the method property to post.
Afterward.
We must change the file type of the request by adding the headers object.
The file type can be modified by setting the content type header to application JSON.
Lastly, we can add the body property for sending data with our request.
The value will be the JSON string if I function with the form data variable.
The fetch function returns a promise by sending the request as is.
The browser will not wait for the request to be completed before running the next line of code.
We can wait for the request by adding the await keyword.
The value resolved by the promise will be returned.
After adding this keyword, let's store the response in a variable called response.
The response object returned by the fetch function will contain various pieces of information.
However, we're not interested in most of the information.
The body of the response contains the data we'll need to process the response.
Let's extract the body by creating a variable called response JSON.
The value for this variable will be the response JSON function with the await keyword.
Adding the a weight keyword is a must without this keyword.
The variable will store a promise.
The JSON function will grab and format the responses body into an object.
The final step in our process is to check the status of their response.
If the form was submitted successfully, we will refresh the page.
Otherwise the form must be re enabled.
Below the variables create a conditional statement with the following condition.
Response JSON status equals equals equals to.
A successful authentication will have the status properties set to two.
If this is the case, we're going to update the sign in form status property to a div tag with the following
classes.
Modal Status.
Modal Status Success.
The message will say the following success.
You are now logged in.
Lastly, let's reload the page with the location reload function.
The authentication may fail.
If that's the case, let's add an LX statement for handling failures.
Firstly, the form should be re enabled.
This gives the user the opportunity to modify their info on the field set element.
The disabled attribute was applied to the elements.
Let's remove this attribute by calling the sign in field set.
Remove attribute function with the disabled attributes.
Next we can update the sign in field set inour HTML property to update the message at a div tag with
the following classes.
Modal Status.
Danger.
The message will say the following invalid credentials.
Please try again later.
We're finished.
That was a lot to go through, but nothing you shouldn't be unfamiliar with.
Overall, we're sending a request to our End Point.
Afterward, we're handling the response by checking the status.
Let's try testing this form in your browser.
Refresh the experimental page.
Next, let's open the modal to view the login form.
I'm going to submit the form with invalid credentials.
As expected, the authentication will fail.
Next, I'm going to submit the form with valid credentials.
Great.
We've successfully logged in at the top right corner of the page.
The user username or email should appear.
This indicates we're logged into the system.
Pat yourself on the back.
We've completed the forms.
There are some finishing touches that will apply to our solution before considering it complete.
Once you're ready, I'll see you in the next lecture.