R-squared this is a very interesting parameter.
A lot of people use it.
And sometimes the user of not knowing the underlying principles of Our Square.
So let's quickly get a understanding of what R-Squared is because we will be using it too.
So time we stopped over here we talked about the simple integration being constructed through the ordinary
least squares method where we are Mizzy minimizing the sum of squares of those differences.
Why I minus why I had.
And basically we are looking at what the model is predicting.
And what is actually happening at a certain level of experience or at a certain level for the independent
variable.
And we look at that difference.
We're squaring it we're summing it for all of the observations we have.
We were counting that sum and then the line that has them smallest sum will be the best fitting line
or will be this simple linear regression model.
So let's get rid of that call out for a second and let's remember this value so we'll need it just now
.
And in fact this value has a name it's called the sum of squares of residuals.
So we'll just labeled SS arrests and now let's do something else before.
We'll get rid of those lines so this is our rule chart with those are aeration and instead of drawing
the regression line let's draw the average line.
So this is your average salary across all of your observations.
Now let's do the same exercise and project our observations onto this line.
And now if we calculate the distances the red distances and we square them then we'll this it will look
like this will be a Y I minus Y average squared and then we'll take the sum of all these distances.
Now this value also has a name and it's called the total sum of squares.
And what r squared is R-squared equal to 1 minus sum of squares of residuals divided by total sum of
squares.
And so what this is saying is that there will always be a sum of all total sum of squares right.
So the average not all your records are not always going to be all equal to the average although it's
a very boring data set.
So some of the total sum of squares will you know will always be some sort of value.
And what you're trying to do with your regression is you're trying to fiddle a line to minimize as we
discussed previously to minimize the sum of squares of residuals to make it as small as possible.
Right.
So in a way the way to think of it intuitively is the average line which we have on the child right
now is also a type of trendline is just horizontal right.
It's not sloped it's just a horizontal trend.
But it kind of also is so you can think of it as a as a model that is fit to a dot.
It's not the best model but you know it's just why average.
So what you're trying to do by fitting a slow line and minimizing the sum of squares of residuals is
you're trying to fit the best line.
And what R-Squared is telling us is it's telling us how good is your line compared to the you know average
line which anybody can think of.
Right so it's not hard to take the average you take a calculator you get the average.
But in order to fit the best fitting line you have to actually run a linear regression.
And if you look at the formula so you tried to minimize s s residual right so somewhat because of residuals
So on the right over there that's part of the formula as you minimise SS residual it goes smaller and
always becomes smaller.
And that way as this residual boy I do bias's total becomes smaller and the one minus SS residual divided
by his total becomes greater.
So ideally if if your SS residual is zero.
So basically your trend line that your modeling goes through all your records then in that case R-Squared
is equal to 1.
And thats the ideal scenario.
But that not normally never happens.
So the closer R-Squared is to 1 the better the further away it is from 1 so the lower It is the worse
.
A good question is can R-squared ever be negative.
The answer is yes of course R-squared can be negative and that is if your for instance SS residual actually
fits your daughter worse then your average life.
Its hard to do but you got to you got to try because if you if you just draw a random line of guess
then facing the wrong way.
So here we be going downwards and probably yes you would get in a negative R-squared.
So thats.
That means that the model is completely broken.
Its better to the average and even to the model.
But normally so our square is normally between zero and one never gets greater than 1 and the closer
is to 1 the better