Hello and welcome to the final tutorial of Part 1 data repossessing.
We finally completed all the steps that there is to do to prepare any data set on which we will build
our machine learning morals.
And now what we only need to do left is to prepare a data processing template because we learned a few
stuff.
We learned how to import a data set to take care of missing data to encode categorical data to split
the data set into the training set and the test set and to apply feature killing to put all of our variable
on the same scale.
However in the data processing template we're not going to include all of these.
We're only going to include the importing the libraries.
Then of course you need to import the data set then regarding missing data.
I just wanted to show you how to take care of that in case you have some missing data in your data set.
You know in your work so we're not going to include this in the templates it's just good to know how
to take care of this but then we will focus on the machine learning models themselves.
And if in your work experience you encounter missing data you know how to handle this any missing data
issues.
Then ask for categorical data.
We won't include it either in the template because we are going to find very few examples of data where
we have to encode the data.
There will be some examples but we won't include it in the templates because our data sets are going
to be well-prepared so that we can mainly focus on the machine learning models and get the maximum fine.
And then of course we will include this in a template splitting the data sets into the training set
and the test set because that's a very important step.
You need to split your data set between training and test because you need to evaluate your model on
a different set than the set on which you build your model and feature scaling.
Okay So Fitch's scaling I hesitated to include it in the template but we are going to include it only
we're going to put that as comment because you're gonna see that there are several libraries and are
in Python and some of them require us to apply features getting to the data and some of them don't.
So most of them don't actually.
Most of them take care of that for you.
You don't have to do it manually but you will see that some libraries don't apply the feature scaling.
I won't tell you which models there are right now because I will let you find out the surprise but keep
that in mind and you will see that sometimes you will have to use feature scaling.
Okay.
So let's start making the template it's going to be very quick.
Let's do it right now let's jump to r All right.
So here is all the steps that we did together so importing the data sets.
Yes we're keeping it of course taking care of missing data.
That was just to show you we won't need it in the future so.
But you will probably need it in your future.
But in the future of this course we will need it.
So we will remove it coding categorical data.
Same here.
We will have to do it once or twice but not all the time so we will remove it.
And as I told you I am putting this in a separate file so that you can still use it if you need it for
your work.
All right.
And now I think we have everything splitting the data set into the training set and to set of course
we are keeping that and feature scaling feature scaling.
As per Python we are going to put that in comment so then the three double quotes is not a way to put
multiplying comments in r so unfortunately we cannot do it.
What we need to do is this is a good trick.
You select the two lines here and then you press command and control plus shift plus C and that puts
all your lines in comment and eventually will just add a final touch to this template which is the case
where we need to take a subset of our data set.
And in that case we will add the line data set equals.
Then we take the same data set and we use the square brackets to select the indexes of the columns we
are interested in to build our model.
So let's just put some numbers here.
And if we need to select specific columns of interest in our future data sets we will change those indexes.
But for now let's just put this line in comment.
All right.
So the template is really on our as well.
We are ready to start our machine learning models.
You have no idea how I'm excited about that.
I can't wait to show you how it's gonna be a lot of fun.
We're gonna make awesome predictions.
You know we will.
We will have some kind of scenarios business problems and we will have to solve them and we will use
the power of machine learning to solve these problems.
You will see how machinery is powerful.
It gives you amazing predictions amazing results.
And keep in mind you will never be lost because we will always know what we are coding.
We will always visualize it.
There will always be some visual graphics of what we are doing when we make every machine learning model.
So I can't wait to start this with you.
This was the boring part but a very important part to do so.
That's great that we did it and now it's time to have fun.
So thank you for watching this data processing tutorials.
Congratulations for completing this part.
You are now ready to make machine learning models.
And I look forward to seeing you in the next part.
Until then enjoy machine learning.