All right.
Let's do this.
Let us predict the test set results.
So as I said in the previous story all we're going to do is play two vectors.
First one being the vector of the real profits and the test set and the second one being the vector
of the predicted profits in the same test set and we're going to compare next to each other to see if
our predictions are close to the real results.
All right.
Let's do this.
Let's start by creating a new Kotel.
So the first thing I ask you to do was to indeed get that vector of predictions.
So first since we want to get a vector I'm going to introduce a new variable which I'm going to call
as usual y pred that's going to be the vector of the predicted profits in the test.
And now how do we get our predictions.
Well you know the solution.
It's actually exactly the same as with simple in our regression we first need to take our regress or
object you know are multiple in our regression model from which you know adding a dot here we're going
to call that predict method parenthesis.
And of course in this method we have to input Well the features of the test set you know exactly these
ones not including the prophet of course.
These are all the features with first the encoded variables for the state then the RNC spend and the
administrations ban and the marketing spend.
All right so these are all the features which we need to input in our predict method here in order to
predict the profits.
So let's do this X test.
Right.
Because we're predicting the test results we want to check the predictions of new observations.
And there you go.
Now we get our vector of predicted profits.
Perfect.
And now the next step.
And you know here we're going to do it together because it is quite specific.
And mostly I want to display some nice vectors with not a too complex notation like you know remember
this one in the data repressing tools when we applied feature scaling.
You know we had all these decimals after the comma.
Well I want to avoid this and therefore here the thing that I'm going to do is I'm going to call number
by which has a shortcut MP from which I'm gonna call one of its function which is set underscore print
options as Google cooler guesses perfectly.
That's great.
It helps me.
And now in the parenthesis I'm just going to enter.
Precision equals two.
All right.
And this will display any numerical value with only two decimals as a comma.
All right so this will be much more beautiful to visualize and mostly much easier to visualize.
Okay.
Good.
And now final step this is a step where we're going to display the two vectors of the real profits and
of the predicted profits together next to each other and to do this well we're going to use you know
a classic trick with NUM pi.
I remember that num Pi has a lot of tools to handle arrays and one of these tools actually that we need
right now is concatenate concatenate is a function of number that allows to concatenate either vertically
or horizontally to vectors or even arrays.
And so now we're going to use the CONCATENATE function to concatenate vertically are two vectors of
the real profits and the brings it profits.
All right so let's do this.
Just follow me I will explain everything as I'm coding.
So first we're simply going to start with the prince you know because we want to print that concatenation
of the two vectors so print.
Then here we go we're going to call that concatenate function by num by.
So that's why I'm calling it a shortcut MP now from which.
Yes.
There we go.
We call the cat tonight.
Function perfect parenthesis and now be careful because this is always a bit confusing.
The concatenate function by num by actually expect as a first argument.
Check this out here.
The sample of arrays you want to concatenate or you know vectors.
So actually all the description is here.
You know a one a two is a sequence of arrays.
You want to concatenate and that must have the same shape.
Well that's perfect for us because of course our vector of predicted profits in the vector of real profits
have exactly the same shape meaning they are one dimensional vector containing the same number of profits.
OK.
So that's good.
But these vectors that we want to concatenate have to be in some parentheses and these are actually
the first argument you know this couple of arrays of vectors is the first argument input in parentheses.
So here I'm gonna add new parentheses.
All right.
This is the first argument and what is going to be inside this parenthesis.
Well of course are two vectors.
The vector of predicted profits and the vector of real profits.
All right so let's first at the vector of predicted profits.
This is of course why Fred and now because we want to display them vertically and not horizontally remember
that you know actually I can show this to you in data repricing tools we actually printed why at some
point.
There we go.
You know remember when we print the dependent viral vector since it is vector it is displayed horizontally.
I actually prefer to display you know our two vectors of predictions and real profits vertically.
So now I'm going to add another trick to put that vertical you know to convert that from being horizontal
to vertical.
And the trick is to do that is just to add dot reshape reshape is an attribute function that allows
to you know reshape your vectors or arrays and in order to reshape a vector from being horizontal to
vertical well we're just not add as input of this function first the number of elements in widespread
and that's actually so far the number of columns because you know it is horizontal.
And to get that number we can simply use the len function which returns the length of a vector.
And therefore here I'm going to input y print.
Okay.
So this is the first element of the reshape function and the second one is just one.
All right.
So what does it mean.
That means that you want to reshape your wiper vector into an array.
Having Len wipe red rows meaning you know that a number of rows will be equal to the number of start
ups.
And then just one column.
All right.
That's what it means.
So it's good that you know this reshaped trick.
Now you know how to reshape your vectors and you will see that it is actually going to be much nicer.
All right.
That's four.
Remember the first element of this couple that is actually the first argument of the CONCATENATE function.
And now next one is going to be well the other vector we want to concatenate to that vector of predicted
profits which is the vector of real profits.
All right.
So here we can do this very efficiently because this is exactly the same trick I'm going to copy all
this and paste that here and just replace widespread by.
What do we have to replace white bread by.
Well of course we had to replace it by whitest because whiteness contains of course the real profits
in the tested.
All right here we are evaluating our moral on the test.
So here we go replacing white bread by white test.
And here as well.
Actually we could keep that because the length of whites is the same as the length of white bread.
But there we go.
Now we have a beautiful concatenation of two vertical vectors.
But remember this.
You know this up to here is actually the first argument of the CONCATENATE function and therefore we
need to add the second one which is the axis as you can see.
So axis here can take two values 0 0 1 0 means that we wanted to a vertical concatenation and 1 means
that we want to do a horizontal concatenation and since here we want to concatenate two vertical vectors
together.
While that concatenation is actually horizontal and therefore we have to input here.
Axis equals 1 and we don't have to specify the name of the argument because this is input in the same
order.
All right.
And that's it.
I told you that it was better that we do it together because there are actually a lot of tricks done
here.
But don't worry for all the next times when we want to compare to numerical vectors we will just do
some copy paste and apply this.
You know the purpose of this course is also for you to have some code templates which can use efficiently
on your data sets.
All right.
Okay.
Good.
So now we're going to observe the final result and see if our model was able to return some predictions.
You know some predicted profits close to the real profits.
There we go.
I hope I didn't make any mistakes with all these parenthesis.
Let's press play to run the sale and awesome.
I didn't make any mistake.
Perfect.
So let's recap.
We can clearly see that we have two vectors here.
That's the first one and that's the second one on the left.
We have the vector of predicted profits and that's why pred and other the right we have the vector of
real profits for of course the 10 startups of the test set.
All right.
So let's see let's see what we get.
Let's see if our predicted profits are close to the real profit.
So for the first drop of the test set well the predicted profit is around one hundred and three thousand.
And the real profit is actually one hundred and three thousand two hundred.
So very close.
That's perfect.
That's an amazing first prediction.
Then second startup of the test set to break the profit is one hundred and thirty two thousand five
hundred and eighty two.
And the real profit is actually one hundred forty four thousand so not a great prediction like before
but still not too bad.
Third startup 132 146.
Still not great but not too bad either for startups 71 actually 72 and seventy eight.
All right.
So pretty close then one hundred seventy eight.
One hundred and ninety one.
Okay.
One hundred and sixteen one hundred and five.
So actually the first petition was amazing.
But then you know the other ones are still quite good.
Then sixty seven sixty eight actually eighty one okay ninety eight thousand and ninety seven thousand.
Very good one hundred and thirteen thousand actually one hundred and fourteen thousand one hundred and
ten thousand.
Very very good.
And one hundred and sixty seven thousand and one hundred and sixty six thousand.
Amazing predictions.
So we have some you know amazing predictions very close to the real profits and some okay predictions.
Okay is there are not too far from the real results so here.
From what we see well we could say that the multiple in our regression is well adapted to this dataset
the dataset does not necessarily have some perfect linear correlations.
However you can be assured that with this linear regression class well it was able to select the right
features with the right parameters to make these predictions.
And even if you tune your linear regression model by for example applying backward elimination to selection
of a team of more statistically significant features you will actually get similar results.
You can try.
That actually would be a good practice.
We actually do that in our section but in terms of performance this won't change much.
And remember your goal is to be efficient when building and testing your machinery models.
So when you get such results with your multiple in a regression you know in real life you will actually
try other models.
You will actually try other modules which can tune also and then in the annual compare the performance
of each of these models and select the best one.
So we'll talk about this again at the end of this section and also a lot in ports and on moral selection
and so now I have to say congratulations because we now know how to build another missionary model which
is multiple in our regression and therefore which you can add in your toolkit.
Thanks to this new coat template.
Perfect.
So now we're going to move on to our I remind that you don't have to master the two programming languages
if you want to master two that's fine.
Join me in the toils and otherwise if you want to stick to python.
Well feel free to skip the R Section and join us here I in the next section on polynomial regression
where you will learn how to make predictions on a non linear dataset on a dataset with non linear relationships.
Therefore with which a multiple in our regression model would not be relevant.
So it's an absolutely necessary model to add in your toolkit and you will add it the next section.
Until then enjoy machine learning.