Hello and welcome to the arts or Tauriel.
So now in this new step of the cleaning process we will remove all the punctuations and the reviews
of the corpus and it's going to be as simple as before we will copy this line pasted below and instead
of remove numbers here we will and put remove punctuation as simple as that we don't need anything else
and that's ready to remove any punctuation in all the reviews of the corpus.
All right so let's check it out.
We can actually check it out with the first review while thrilled.
I love this place.
And so what we're supposed to obtain after applying this remove punctuation function and all the reviews
of the corpus through the TMI function.
Well the three little dots are supposed to disappear.
All right so let's check it out.
So remember in the actual version of the corpus right now the first review is wow three little dots.
Love this place.
So now let's select this new line of code execute your corpus of review created with all the punctuation
removed.
So let's go back to the console and let's press the up arrow to get the line of code that is giving
us access to the first review.
Here it is.
So let's press Enter NOW and as you can see the three little dots disappeared.
Therefore that's exactly what the removed punctuation function does here.
It removes any kind of punctuation including dot comers Collins semi-colons or any other kind of punctuation.
All right.
So next up done we are ready to move onto the next step which will be to remove all the non-relevant
words in the reviews.
So for example if we have a look at this first review here.
Well this is not very relevant.
You know this doesn't give any hint on knowing whether the review is positive or negative.
So this is typically a word that we don't want to have in the final sparse matrix because this is not
relevant.
So we will remove it and the next step of the cleaning process and we'll do the same for all the other
words of the same kind.
So let's do that in the next tutorial.
And until then and you're learning