Hello and welcome back to the course on machine learning.
And in this section we're kicking off the tutorials for hierarchical clustering.
All right so another very interesting topic ahead of us and as always let's make the complex a simple
and demystify what it's all about.
All right so what is hierarchical clustering.
Well believe it or not.
But if you have points on your scatterplot or data points like we looked at previously this is a two
dimensional space.
If you apply a hierarchical clustering or just say H.C. for short.
What'll happen is you will get clusters again a very very similar to Kamins In fact sometimes the result
of no results can be exactly the same as k means clustering.
But the whole process is a bit different.
So let's talk about it in a bit more detail.
So the first thing that we need to note is that there's two types of hierarchical clustering agglomerative
and divisive.
So agglomerated is the bottom up approach and you'll see in more detail just now what that means so
we'll be starting at the very bottom and then building our way up device of his opposite starting at
the top and devising a Klosters into multiple in this course we'll be focusing on our glomerata of approach
the divisive or we'll mentioned Ebbetts just now where we're talking about a glitch but it's basically
the same thing.
But the other way around it's the reverse of the glummer trip.
And if you like you can definitely research more about the device approach.
But for now we're going to focus on the glummer of one.
All right.
So the glomerata of hierarchical clustering How does it work well to start off we're going to break
it down into step by step approach and then we'll look at an example and manually perform the classroom
.
All right so step one in H.C. is to make each data point a single point cluster so that forms and or
and data points.
Your first step is to look at each one of them as an individual cluster.
Then Step two is to take the two closest data points and make them one cluster to combine them into
one cluster that forms and minus one clusters then sip that is to take the two closest classes out of
the ones now that you now have and make them one cluster that forms and minus two clusters then it's
a to repeat step 3 until there is only one class to basically just keep repeating step three and combining
points into bigger and bigger and bigger clusters.
And so there's only one huge cluster left.
So you just keep repeating step three.
And at the end you're done and you'll have one huge cluster left and how to get from one to two or three
classes.
How do you get the final result that you actually want.
We'll talk about that in this section as well so that's that's the goal of course.
But one thing that stands out here is the words closest clusters.
Now we've already talked about distances and we mentioned you clearly that you can use Euclidean distances
or other distances and that's totally fine when you're working with the usual point.
But here we're actually going a step even further we're talking about not just the proximity of points
but actually proximity of clusters.
And this is something worth noting so I'd like to pause here for a bit and or I kind of step to the
side and talk about the closeness of clusters and how you measure distance between clusters because
that can really affect your algorithm if using hierarchical clustering.
So let's talk about that for for a few minutes.
So first of all Euclidean distance just to get this out of the way once and for all Euclidean distance
is in a two dimensional space it's calculated like that.
So the distance so x if you got two points one with the coordinates x 1 and Y 1 p to coordinate x to
y to then nuclear and distance or the length of this line is calculated as X to minus x 1 so that the
distance between the x's squared plus the distance between Y is squared.
So basically and then you add them up and then take the square.
So basically it's that and you've got a right angled triangle over here and you've got the cattle out
here and you've got another one catgut here.
I hope I'm pronouncing it right and then this is the hypothenuse right.
So that is how you calculate the distance between the two points.
So it's a basic geometry back from high school.
And there you go that's just how Euclidean distances calculate and that's what we're going to be working
with.
But again there are other types of distances that you could be invoking in your algorithms and it really
depends on the scenario and what exactly how your algorithm is going to be structured but in our examples
we're going to be working with Euclidean distances because they're more natural type of distance.
And now let's talk about the distance between two clusters so let's say you have two clusters the red
and the blue.
How do you measure the distance between them.
What is the definition of the distance between two clusters.
It's not as obvious as it might sound at the start because there can be a couple of options for instance
you can.
Option one is to take the two closest points and measure that and call that the distance between the
two clusters.
Option 2 is actually take the two further points and call that the distance between two classes is also
a valid approach.
Option 3 Take the average take the average of all the distances between the different points in the
classes all the combinations of different points and take the average of that distance.
Option 4 is take the distance between the centroid and find the Central is and find the distance between
the centroid and call that the distance between the two clusters.
So it's a very important part of her called clustering what you define as the distance between two classes
because that can significantly impact the output of your algorithm.
Now we're not going to delve much deeper into this.
It's just something to remember to note.
And based on your particular situation where there's a business problem or other type of data science
problem based on what exactly do you think is the best approach you're going to need to define that
in your algorithm so just keep that in mind that for the hierarchical clustering algorithm the distance
between clusters is a crucial element and you need to remember what exactly you are setting at is you
setting it to be how you defining it in your approach.
All right.
So we talked about that.
Now let's move back to our example so we've already looked at the step by step rules and I I'm a big
fan of step by step approach.
Now we have this step by step approach and it might have seemed a bit overwhelming as always because
we didn't have an example.
But now we're going to have that example and we're going to look at how to build those hierarchical
classes.
So step one make each data point a single point cluster that forms a six clusters Let's have a look
at that.
You can see every single point is a separate cluster.
Next take the two Close's data points and make them one closter where we can see that these two points
are the closest.
So we're putting them together in one class and now we have five classes one two three four and these
two are one class.
All right.
Step three take the two closest clusters are the ones we had and turn them into one cluster.
So out of the classes we have because remember each point are these four.
So if we go back here each point here is a separate class and this is a classroom.
So now just measure the distances between clusters and let's say in our example we're going to be talking
about the distance between clusters as the minimum distance so that would be the distance between those
two classers that would be the distance that would be that that would be an Sanchi measure all the difference
between clusters and you find out that these are actually the closest clusters and you combine them
into one class.
Next you repeat step three so next out of these have coursers out of one two three four clusters you
can see we had five.
Now we have for every time we reduce the number of clusters by one of these four classes which are the
class as well.
The this seems as the closest cluster so we're going to combine that.
Now out of these three clusters which of course it looks like these two are.
So combining them and now we've only got two classes left so the last step would be to combine them
because they are by default going to be the closest.
So there we go.
And so that is the end of our algorithm.
That's how it converges.
You've we've gone through the process of CRE of going from all points seen as an individual cluster
so each point is an individual cluster to now we only have one cluster that combines all of the points
.
And so what's the purpose of all of this.
What's the purpose of this exercise.
The way the hierarchical clustering algorithm works is that it maintains a memory of how we went through
this process and that memory is stored in a danger gram and that's exactly what we're going to talk
in the next tutorial and once we've covered the Dendron grams it will make total sense why the hierarchical
clustering algorithm does what it does and how it works.
So we enjoy today sectorial can't wait to see the next one.
Until then enjoy machine learning.