Hello welcome back to the course of machine learning in the breeze tutorial we talked about the hierarchical
clustering the intuition behind it and how it works.
But at the same time we didn't quite understand what the whole purpose of H.C. wasn't what the benefit
of it was yes we went from a huge amount of classers where every single point or data element was considered
a cluster and then to one big cluster but as a result and now we have one huge costs are what's what's
the point of all of it.
How do we get to the result we want.
The actual clustering so I can Kamins For instance we would have two or three closer's.
How do we get to that right number of clusters.
So this is where the Dinda Gram's come in and they will help us understand everything.
So let's get straight into it.
So here I've got a chart on the left which contains six points and on the right of the go to another
chart we're going to use this chart to create a Dendron Graham.
Now I know it might sound a bit confusing at first especially because we haven't talked about that diagrams
but through creating one we will learn what they are.
So first off just to make things a bit more legible I'm going to add the points at the bottom so that
they're a bit bigger so you can see them better.
And so there they are.
There they are just listed on the bottom on the vertical axis.
We've got Euclidean distances and it'll all make sense just now.
So we're going to now go through the H.C. algorithm and slowly create those clusters.
So to start off with every single point is an individual cluster.
Right so every single one of these points is an individual cluster.
Next what we're going to do is we're going to find the two closest points which are these two and put
them into one cluster.
So that's our step too in our algorithm.
So there we go.
That's the two closest points.
And now we're putting them into one cluster.
Now what we want to do on this diagram here on the ground is we want to somehow signify that these were
indeed the two closest points because the DNA gram is kind of like the memory of the AC algorithm.
Going to remember every single step that we were performing.
So there they are those two boys P2 and P3.
How do we signify that we've just connected them and that they were the closest well to connect them
would use like a horizontal line.
But then where would we put it would you put at the very bottom would we put a bit higher.
What's going to determine the distance.
How high are we going to places like.
So this line is actually placed this height actually has a meaning this height is the median distance
between them.
And it also represents the computed dissimilarity between the two points are the two clusters.
And what that means is the further away two points are.
So for instance P2 is that far away from P3.
And this could be a variable for us it could be the age of a person.
Right.
And this variable could be for instance the salary of a person.
Or this variable could be how long a person has been in the company and this.
This variable could be the salary of the person.
Or something like that.
So basically we can see that P2 and P3 are they have that distance between them whereas P2 and P4 have
a greater distance between them and that means that these two points P2 and P3 they have a certain dissimilarity
which is measured by the distance between them so the distance represents the dissimilarity between
the two points and P2 and before also have a dissimilarity and its greater because you can see that
the distance is greater.
So lets say if this was age and this was salary these two points even though they are not identical
they are less dissimilar in terms of age and salary than P2 and P4.
And again these variables are just arbitrary just calling arbitrary variables that could be anything
else and this data set could not be complete.
It could be a machines it could be CERN observations from nature and pretty much anything.
The point here is that they are further away two points are the more dissimilar they are.
And that is been measured or captured in identity Gramp by the height of this bar how high we're setting
it.
And then the bar itself just shows us that we connected P2 and P3.
All right.
So that's our first step in the Denver ground.
Next we're going to move on and we're going to proceed to the next step in our shelter and we can perform
step three.
So we're going to find in the next two closest clusters and connect them.
So here we've got all each each point out of these four is a cluster.
Then we've got this cluster.
Now we need to find the two closest are all of them.
And let's say or from what we see these two other closest So let's outline them.
There we are.
And so now they form their own cluster.
Now we want to point that out in the den trigram as well.
So again we're going to places vertical or horizontal line again.
How high do we place it to replace it.
Higher or lower than this line.
Well we agreed that this vertical axis represents the Euclidean distance and Euclidean distance represents
the dissimilarity between two of our observations.
So here we can see that P5 and P-Six are actually further apart than between three and that is of course
natural because if P5 and P-Six were closer then in the in the previous step we wouldn't have put two
and three in one closer we would have put P5 and six in one cluster remember.
We're always looking for the closest and then we're moving on to the next step.
So between B-3 we're the closest and that's why this distance is such P5 and D6 are further apart from
each other than P2 and P3 so the distance has to be greater.
And that's why we're going to show that on the diagram you can see that this bar is set higher.
All right.
And the next step is to again repeat step 3 so we're going to look among these.
All of these clusters of which are the closest.
So there we go.
So this one is the was the closest I'm going to back here.
This cluster is closer to this cluster containing other closer and pretty much out of all the distances
between the clusters.
This is the lowest again a lot here is determined by how you measure distances.
You can see that the distance between before and this cluster is quite close to this distance.
But so we're going to say that this distance is the last.
All right.
So what do we do next is we combine these clusters into one cluster.
There's that there it is.
So now we have one cluster.
Now we need to represent that somehow here so what we just did is we took this cluster that we have
to be connected with P1.
So again we're going to draw a line and we're going to draw vertical lines here again and was once again
in the distance here from P1 to the top of here represents the dissimilarity between that cluster that
we had.
And what's the point that we connected it to.
All right so now let's connect.
Let's find.
What's the next step next step again is step three and we're going to look out of one two three clusters
that we have which are the closest.
Well this is before and it's the closest to these.
Again there it is.
We're expanding that cluster.
Now we're going to represent on the Denver Gramp as you can see the line is about the same height as
this previous line because the distance between P1 and this cluster was about the same as the distance
between four and five and six.
Maybe this one was a bit greater.
Sometimes it's hard to tell and that's why we have algorithms that's why machines do it for us.
One of the reasons that's what our datagram look so far and our final step is to combine these two remaining
clusters because by default they are going to be the closest since there are no other clusters.
So we are going to combine them and represent that on Adinda gram.
So here the hotline is very high because the distance dissimilarity was very high between these two
clusters.
And there we go.
So that is how we construct our DNA Graham slowly from the bottom up is being constructed.
And at the end we've got that one cluster or so all of this is one cluster and that is what I mean when
I say that the underground contains the memory of the hierarchical clustering algorithm.
So you can just by looking at the Denver grammar understand in which order these classes were formed
and here I've got an example so this is the actual example generated by computer generated by an algorithm
showing us the hierarchical clustering.
So we've got the points here and we've got the pentagram over here so this is what it actually looks
like.
All right so now we know how dense the Grahams are constructed in the next tutorial we will learn how
to use them to enhance our or actually execute our hierarchical clustering algorithm.
So there we go.
Hope you enjoyed today's tutorial are forcing you next time.
And until then in Germany learning