And now we're going to tackle very quickly the very first step of this toolkit which is the library's
how to import the libraries how to have them ready.
Any time we start building new machinery morale will There we go.
I will show you this right away.
It's actually very simple.
We're going to import three libraries now which are named by Matt lib and pandas none by will allow
us to work with arrays because indeed you will see that your future machinery molds will expect some
arrays as inputs.
And therefore we need the library to work with these arrays.
And that's not by then we'll import much plot lib which is the library that will allow us to plot some
very nice charts you will see that we will plot actually many charts and graphs in this course.
And finally bend us which will allow us to not only import the data set but also create the matrix of
features and the dependent variable vector.
I will explain of course all these concepts later.
All right so let us import these libraries in order to import a library in Python.
It's very simple.
You start with import.
That's just a command that will allow to import a library or even a function or any type of modules
by the way a library is an symbol of modules containing functions and classes with which you can perform
some actions and operations.
For example the most well-known library in data science is cited learn and this is a library that contains
actually all the missionary morals that you can build by simply creating an object of some classes.
So don't worry about all this now we will see that in great detail.
Each time we build the machinery models.
But there you go you will see that libraries will be super useful for us in order to build our machinery
models.
There we go.
Import then you need to follow by the name of the library you want to import and the first one we want
to import is called Name by.
And then what we usually do is we add a shortcut because each time we will use a function of the number
library.
Well we'll have to call first number.
And in order to call it faster.
Well we can add a shortcut here so that each time we want to call them by we will actually call it with
its shortcut and the shortcut we usually use for known by is empty.
And as you can see to add a shortcut is simply to add as.
And then the shortcut name.
All right so each time we will call them by will actually call MP then next library import.
So that next library is mad plot lib.
And actually as I told you a library is an int symbol of modules.
And here we're interested in a particular module called by plot and that's the module that allows us
to plot very nice charts.
And so here we're not only going to import matte plot lib but particularly well the pie plot module.
And as you can see in order to get this pilot module I added a dot here which allows you to access the
different modules of the MATLAB library and the module we chose is by plot.
And again we're going to add a little shortcut here which we're gonna call TLT.
That's the usual name for this pilot module.
All right.
And finally we're going to import a final library which has defenders library a super useful library
to pre process your data set and mostly to import them.
And same for this library we're going to add the simple shortcut name P G.
And there you go.
Congratulations.
Now not only you know how to import the libraries but mostly you have your very first data pricing tool
in your toolkit.
So now we're going to move on to the second tool which will be to import the dataset and that's exactly
what we'll do in the next tutorial.