Hello, welcome back to the course on deep natural language processing.
And today we're talking about classical versus deep learning models.
So let's have a look.
As we discuss, we've got this diagram.
And on the left, you've got the natural language processing models overall.
And on the right, we have the deep learning models or also there overlap is the deep natural language
processing.
Those are the very advanced types of natural language processing models which use deep learning.
And then finally at the bottom here, we've got the sequence to sequence models, which will be interested
in that.
And so I thought that this tutorial would be fun if we had a look at a comparison between a couple.
So we'll look at a couple of examples from here.
We'll look at an example from here.
And then finally, we'll mention the sequence to sequence just to kind of lay out the playing field
so we know what we're dealing with and what types exist, because we could definitely just jump into
sequence to sequence and look at the most powerful things.
But then it would still be a mystery what our national language processing models, how they're different
to deep natural language processing models and how they're different to sequence, to sequence.
What their applications and so on.
So let's have a look at a couple of examples.
All right.
Some examples.
We're going to have our diagram on the right.
And we're gonna start going through these examples one by one.
So number one is the if else rules.
And this is a way that we used to create Chad bots back in the day.
So if El's roles are looking over here on our diagram in the just the MLP part.
And what they entail is a huge list of possible questions and answers to those questions.
And so once somebody in the chat asks a question or we can identify that part of the sentence is the
question that we have recorded, then we will give them the correct answer, the answer that is associated
with that question.
But as you can imagine, such mechanics, such a mechanical approach to answering questions or chatting
with people does not result in anything human like anything realistic.
And it results in something like this, rather, where you have questions and then you have the predetermined
answers.
But people wants something tailored to them, something specific.
They asking about something else but doesn't fit into that list of questions and answers.
And it just very quickly becomes a mess.
But that's how we used to create Chad, the next type or the next natural language processing model.
We will look at is called an audio frequency components analysis, and it's used for speech recognition
and sits over here.
So we're specifically looking like we're purposefully looking at different examples, not just childbirths.
We're looking at different applications.
So you can see that an LP can be applied to speech recognition.
And there used to be or still are algorithms that use non deep learning methods for speech recognition.
And one of them is audio frequency components analysis.
So in essence, what happens is we look at the sound wave of somebody talking some prerecorded or Real-Time
audio over human speech.
And then we try to identify what wave forms exist in there.
So in a very kind of simple way of explaining it, let's have a look at, for example, here.
We've got a four year transformation and we've got there's our frequency over there says like one of
these is going over there.
Of course, this is this doesn't even look like human speech, to be frank.
But the concept stay.
So, like, we look at what frequencies it can, it consists of.
And then we compare them to like the pre recorded frequencies.
So we know that, for instance, certain certain combinations of frequencies means this type of word
or this type of word.
And it's just about the frequencies.
Of course, it's it's much more complex than that.
But this is a very general overreach of what happens.
We look at the frequencies, certain mathematical operations.
This is the key point that we're not doing any neural computations.
We're not creating new neural networks.
We're just doing mathematical calculations around the frequencies that we can observe.
Comparing them to the mathematical calculations we have in a library of pre analyzed frequencies.
And then we're matching it up.
We're finding what word the person is saying, what question they're asking or what the sentence is
meaning.
And then that is how we recognize speech.
So there's another version of natural language processing, which is in the green area.
Next one is the back of words model, which is used for classification, a very, very popular approach
for text analysis or natural language processing.
And what it does is basically it also sits in the MLP part and just the green area, although as we
will see for the on, it can sit both in the green area and in the purple area over here.
But that's something for discussion.
What's the bag of words model does is there's a bag of words.
And the way it works is a you might have like lots of text.
For instance, here we've got tutors or lecturers or examiners who marked grades.
So who gave a pass or fail grade to different papers or different assignments that were submitted.
And then they also left the comments.
So somebody said great job and left a comment on one meaning a pass.
Somebody said amazing work left to come out of one.
Well done, one.
Very well written one.
And then poor effort zero could have done better.
Zero, try harder next time.
Zero and so on.
And so from this, what the bag awards model will do is it will put all these words into a bag and it
will remember.
So how often does the word grades come up with a one?
And how often does the word grade come up with a zero?
This is, again, a very general explanation, a very high level explanation of what happens.
But in essence, this is the concept that.
We'll look at the words and it'll look.
Try to classify these words ill timed, Ill try to associate these words with either positive results
or negative result in our case.
And so in this case, like amazing would be most likely associated of positive.
You don't often see amazing when you're trying to say when when the sentiment is negative, when you
try it, when the person was trying to say something like the work wasn't well done or well would be
associated with one, like the word work could be associated with both.
But then these other words, they would be mostly associated with past some like words like poor or
harder or could have maybe you would be associate zeros.
And so then it will remember that we'll keep these words in a bag and next time something comes up.
For instance, somebody says, good, a good job.
Keep keep it up or something, that it will analyze the words that are in that new sentence by pulling
them out of the bag and looking at them and understanding are they mostly associated ones or zeros.
And then we'll be able to predict it will be able to classify the new new comment even without knowing
what the mark was.
Pass or fail will be able to say based on the communal tables, say, is it a pass or fail?
So that's like a very simplistic application of the bag of words model.
But there's another one and OPIS model.
OK.
So let's look at a deep national language processing model.
And this one is going to be over here.
It's called convolutional neural networks for text recognition.
So they take the model we're going to be looking at further down is indeed a deep national language
processing model.
But I was I wanted to give an example of a different model.
So not not just the one that we're looking at, but like also a deep natural language processing model,
but a different one.
And when I came across is when we use convolutional neural networks for text recognition.
And then for the classification.
And so if if you're familiar with conventional networks or even if you're not, what they're used for
is it's a neural network that is used for mostly image recognition for like videos.
Self-driving cars using to detect obstacles and roads, people and so on.
So mostly it's used for image processing or video processing.
And so it is very interesting to see how convolutional neural networks can actually be useful text processing.
And the way it works is.
It's these words are transformed into a matrix, and that's done through an operation called embedding
of words.
And then once they're in a matrix, the same principles as kind of evolution as we would apply for images
and convolutional neural networks are applied.
So there's a convolution operation going through these images.
Then they're they're pooled.
Max, pull them in, pull their some pull.
And then they're flattened.
And then, you know, then we have the prediction.
So we won't go into detail right now of how convolution convolutional operations work.
There's lots of tutorials out there and so on.
And it's just not in the scope of this.
Because in this case, we'll be looking at mostly recurrent neural networks, which is Ahran in a different
type of know.
But I just wanted to put it out there that you could technically use convolutional neural networks for
text recognition, just as you would do with images and very interesting concept.
That was one of the earlier ones that was explored.
And then we moved on to recurrent neural networks, as we'll see down the track.
So there we go.
That's another one.
And then finally, the main model that we'll be looking for working with sequence to sequence has many,
many, many different applications, as we'll see down.
And that's the one that's over there.
So I'll give you a short preview of what's coming up.
Looks something like this.
And don't worry.
It might look very complex right now, but in a couple of tutorials from here, we'll be very, very
comfortable with what's going on here and how this whole construct is working in what's called sequence
to sequence.
And what exactly it allows us to do.
So there we go.
I hope you enjoy this quick overview and comparison of the different types of models and different applications
that they have.
And we'll continue next.
Then I'll look forward to seeing you there.
And until then, enjoy Deep and OPIS.