Hello and welcome to this art tutorial.
So in the previous section we implemented the a priori model to find some relevant association rules
that could help us find a more strategic placement of some products in a grocery store in the south
of France.
And therefore thanks to these association rules the manager of this store is likely to optimize the
sales and therefore increase the revenues and accordingly we manage to create some added values in this
business thanks to association rule learning.
And today we are going to implement a new model of associational learning which is called the Ekla model
.
So the first thing I want to say is to prevent any disappointment you might have.
The A-Class model is actually very simple compared to what we did previously because the example is
basically the apriori model simplified because previously we had two parameters.
We had the support and the confidence and we also had the left.
By the way when we ranked our rules by their decreasing list.
But here in the cloud we will only have one parameter which will be the support parameter and therefore
when we obtain our rules that will not be the rules that we obtained earlier or like people who bought
this also bought that but we will just get some different sets of products frequently but together we
will get the different sets of products there are the most frequently pre-Chase together.
So that's what we'll get.
We have to expect this.
But you know the can be very useful if you don't have much time if you want to get some simple results
.
If you don't want to play with too many parameters like to support the confidence here we don't even
have to compute the value for the support.
And moreover we don't even have to choose a value for the confidence because there is no confidence
parameter.
So you'll see this is the way of using Association rule learning in the simplest way.
So let's do it right now.
You'll see what I mean at the end of this tutorial.
So let's start with the very first step.
Setting the right for there is working directories will go to our machinery the fuller part 5 Association
rule learning.
And right now we are in a club.
So here it is we have the market basket optimization will work on the same business problem.
And so we can click on this more button here and now set us working directory.
And you know since I told you the example is a simplified version of the premium or or what we'll do
now is take our a priori model and you'll see that it will almost be the same and we will just need
to change one thing.
So I'm going to select everything from here to here.
Copied and pasted in the clamorously.
All right.
So here in this section data pre-processing we don't have anything to change.
We are just going to import the data set with the regions actual functions be careful not with the results
we found because we still need to have our sparse matrix that will also be an input of the Ekla function
like here for the a priori function.
So we will select this and executes.
And of course we get the same number of duplicates the CSP file hasn't changed.
We have five duplicates and no triplicated just five duplicates.
OK.
Then of course we can use the summary function to get some info about this dataset but of course these
are going to be the same for us before.
So we have 7500 transactions a hundred and nineteen products and the density is 0.03 that means that
the proportion of non-zero values in the matrix is 0.03 3 percent.
And then of course we have the most frequent items.
Mineral water comes first and eggs and we can actually have a better look at these most frequent items
by selecting this line and executes.
And of course we get the same frequency plot.
So that's exactly like before.
We don't have anything to change here however.
Now we enter the second code section which is to train the eclat model on the data set so for us we
will just replace a priori here by a clock.
Here we go.
And guess what it is so simple.
Here we have the a priori function to train the pre or model.
And guess what the function is going to be to train the Clamato.
It's going to be Ekla.
So very simple.
We are almost ready to train Ekla on our dataset but of course the cameral is much more simple.
It doesn't include the confidence and the parameters.
If right now we get to the slide of the eclat algorithm from the intuition tutorial.
Well we can see that the Ekla algorithm has three steps and the first step is to set a minimum support
.
Remember before for the apriori algorithm the first step was to set a minimum support and a minimum
confidence.
Now we only need to set a minimum support so we don't need this.
Actually this parameter is only for the a priori model so if we keep that we'll get an error so I'll
just remove this and we can leave the minimum support to 0.04.
But you'll see that it's even not necessary here.
You'll see why at the end however we might need to add another parameter because since you know I mentioned
that the algorithm is just going to return a set of items most frequently bought together.
Well it wouldn't be interesting to have a set of only one item.
So in order to get some sets of at least two items we will add another parameter here which we actually
encountered earlier and which is the main line parameter and we will set it to 2 because we want to
have the different sets of at least two items most frequently pre-Chase together.
OK and now we're ready.
See how it was simple.
So let's select this and train the Clamato on our dataset done.
OK.
So now things change a little bit.
First of course we see that we just train the camel obviously then we have the parameter specification
like before but this time we don't have the confidence parameter.
We have the support that we set to 0.04.
That is the minimum support.
And of course this time we have the minimum equals to remember before the millin parameter was set to
1 but we didn't have any problem with that because all our rules contained at least two products but
when using Ekla we need to set this minimum parameter to 2 because otherwise we'll get some sets of
only one item.
OK then we have these other more advanced informations here.
And then there is something that I would like to highlight here.
It's the number of sets and not rules.
Remember before we had you know let's say we had eight hundred forty five.
It was written eight hundred forty five rules because we had the rules of the forum.
If people lie like cream then they're likely to buy chicken with the confidence of 40 percent that is
with 40 percent chance.
And here since you know we don't get these kind of rules of this form and we only get sets of items
.
Well this time we have indeed.
Eight hundred forty five sets.
So even if A-class considered as the Association of rule early model Well this doesn't return rules
does actually return some sets.
OK so we're going to have a look at the sets right now.
We are ready to move to the last step of our role where we can actually jump back to the slide and as
we can see the step two is to take all the subsets and transactions having higher support than minimum
support.
So that's where the function éclat is itself.
And then the last step step three is to sort the subset by decreasing support.
So this time it's not by decreasing left like for a priori there is no lift in a cloud.
So this time we're going to sort the rules by decreasing support.
All right.
And we're going to take the 10 first worlds with the 10 highest supports So we are actually ready.
Well the whole code is actually ready.
We did it very efficiently Well it was very simple.
So eventually let's have a look at the rules and you'll see that it's much more simple and honestly
less interesting than a priori.
But that's what we'll get.
So I'm going to select this line and execute.
And as I just told you we simply get different sets of items most frequently purchased together.
So for example the set of items most frequently purchased together is mineral water and spaghetti with
the support of point 0 5 9.
And then it's chocolate and then it's chocolate and mineral water then eggs and mineral water.
And that's of course strongly related to this.
Most frequently purchased products in the store.
So that's the results much less interesting than the a priori.
But that can be very useful if you are looking for some very simple information.
And by the way since I was telling you if we you know changed the support and set it to 0.03 like we
did for the a priori model in the first place.
Well you'll see that we'll get the same ranking here because as you can see the supports of these 10
first sets of items most frequently pre-Chase together all have supports higher than 0.04 or 0.03.
So indeed if we retrain the Clamato with the minimum support of 0.03 And if we select that again and
executes we get the same ranking with mineral water and spaghetti coming first and then frozen vegetables
mineral water as the tenth set of products most frequently pre-Chase together.
All right so that's what the Clemenceau.
Again if you want to have a serious analysis about how to create some added value for your business
optimize the sales and the revenue you should go for a priori.
But if you are looking for some very simple informations like the sets of products most frequently pre-Chase
together then you can go for a cloud.
So congratulations anyway.
You now know how to implement to association role models the apriori and Ekla.
And you know what to use them for.
So thank you very much for watching these tutorials and I look forward to seeing you in the next part
.
Reinforcement learning.
Until then enjoy machine learning.