Hello my friends.
Congratulations again for completing part 1 data processing.
You are now ready to build machine learning models and the first models that we're going to build together
are regression models.
Welcome to part two on regression.
This is the branch of machine learning that aims to predict some continuous real numbers like for example
a salary or a temperature or any kind of continuous numerical value.
And together we will build the best models to make these predictions.
And so now first of all let's make sure we're all on the same page.
This is the whole machine learning it is that folder containing all the codes in Python and R and the
data set I gave you the link of this folder right before this tutorial you know in the article to make
sure to connect to this folder and also make sure to download the whole folder in order to get the data
sets because we will have indeed to import them whenever we build a machine learning model.
All right.
And so now since we're all on the same page let us start our new journey within regression Part Two
regression.
There we go.
There are several sections inside each section corresponding to a different regression model.
We're going to start with simple in our regression which is the simplest machinery model you could ever
build.
And so it's good that we start with this because indeed with this one we will only have one independent
variable you know one feature and of course one continuous real value to predict.
Then we will move on to multiple linear regression which is based on the same equation than simple in
our regression.
Only this time we will have several features instead of one then we will move on to polynomial regression
which will allow us to tackle some nonlinear datasets you know datasets with nonlinear correlations
as opposed to previous models simple in a regression and multiple in your regression which can provide
some amazing and accurate predictions for linear datasets you know datasets with linear correlations.
Then after polynomial regression we will move on to support vector regression which is another kinds
of nonlinear model that can make some accurate predictions for nonlinear datasets with nonlinear correlations.
And then finally we will move on to Decision Tree regression and random forest regression which can
provide an alternative to predict an outcome for nonlinear datasets.
So you'll have many options you know after this part 2 you will have basically a toolkit of several
regression models.
And so whenever you end up with a new dataset where you have to predict a real continued outcome well
you can just try all of them and select in the end the one that has the best accuracy and thanks to
the code templates that will result from each of these sections you know you will get very clear code
templates that you can adapt to your own data sets so that you can try these models on your own data
sets in a flashlight quickly and efficiently so that you can select the best one giving you the best
accuracy.
And so now in this first section in regression we're going to start with simple linear regression of
course.
So there we go.
Make sure to go inside this folder.
We're gonna start with Python so let's go inside it's Python folder and you will find inside two files.
First the dataset salary data that Sizwe and of course are Python implementation which has the AI Python
notebook format which I remind you can run on either Google Q lab or Jupiter notebook.
And of course we're going to implement this model together on Google color.
But first let me explain the dataset and the problem that we're going to solve with simple in a regression
and to do this I'm going to open our data set here and explain what this is about.
All right.
So first I want to reassure you that indeed this is a very simple dataset you know with only three observations.
And of course in real life the datasets are more complex.
But I want to start working on a simple dataset so that we can really focus on how to build the model
itself.
You know because if we had a complex dataset we would lose a bit or focus on the model.
And I really want us to focus on the model.
So let me describe the dataset it is a dataset containing as you can see 30 observations and two columns
with of course one feature.
This is the feature years of experience and the dependent variable which we want to predict which is
the salary.
So let's say that this dataset belongs to a company that gathered data of some of their employees collecting
for each of them their years of experience and their salary.
So you see each row of the data set here corresponds to different employees corresponds to one employee
of the company and for each employee of this company we have indeed the number of years of experience
in the company and their salary.
OK.
And so the goal very simply is to build a simple in your regression model that will be trained to understand
the relations between the number of years of experience and the salary so that it can predict for a
new employee you know having a new number of years of experience well the corresponding salary or the
salary that this person should get.
So you see that's a very easy problem but at least you'll know how to build a simple in a regression
model and perfectly master it in all the detail.
And then I want to say something very important.
Remember that we're going to build each time some code templates which you can adapt to your own datasets
so that when you want to use the code on plate on your own data set you will only have one thing to
change which will be the name of your data.
I will always make sure to make the code templates as much generic as we can so that you only have one
or two things to change when you want to deploy them on your data sets.
All right.
So great.
That's for the dataset.
And now we're going to move on to the implementation simple in our regression I Python notebook which
we're going to open with Google Code laboratory.
If you don't like collaborate to read that story fine you can open it with Jupiter and notebook and
you also have the python thousand folder that was also given to you in the previous tutorial if you
want to run it for example on an icon the spider or even the classic Python terminal.
Okay.
All right.
So that's simple in a regression.
Let's see how this implementation is structured.
First we're going to import the libraries.
You recognize the first steps of the data processing phase which we covered in parts one second.
We're going to import the data set then.
Third we're going to split the dataset into the training set and test set.
Then we're going to train the simple in our regression model on the training set.
Then we're going to predict the test result.
Then we can visualize the training that results and visualize the test results.
But I don't want to show you this too much right now because I want to keep the surprise for the end.
And so what we're gonna do now.
Because remember this is given in read only mode so you can not code or do any modifications inside.
But remember I want this course to be as much practical as possible.
I want you to really learn by doing and therefore what we're going to do now is implement this whole
simple in our regression model from scratch together and to do so we are going to create a copy of this
file by clicking here on Save a copy in drive.
This will create a new copy on your drive in which you will be able to do some modifications or implement
the new model.
All right.
Great.
Now we just have to do one thing it is to remove all the code cells because we are going to re implement
it from scratch.
Step by step.
So let's do this.
We just need to click this trust button here on only the good cells.
Make sure to keep the texts in order to highlight you know the structure of this implementation.
There we go.
Let's just delete everything here and one last.
Perfect.
So now we have the whole structure of the implementation you can clearly see the different steps that
we're going to implement together.
I will ask you to implement some of them on your own and of course then we will implement a solution
together.
But that's because I really want you to learn by doing.
I really want you to take action and try to implement some parts of the models on your own.
All right.
Perfect.
And now I want you to think what is going to be our first step here.
Based on you know what we covered in part 1.
Well our first step is obviously the data processing phase in which we have to import a data set and
maybe use some tools in order to pre process it the right way so that our future is simple in a regression
model can be ready to be trained on this data set.
All right.
And now I'm excited because I'm going to show you the efficiency of the data processing template and
how easy and fast it will be for us to process our data set here.
So what we're going to do now is we're going to go to that previous folder in the data processing folder
which was in part one data processing accessing the python section and there we go.
Now we're going to open that template.
Perfect.
And you're going to see we're simply going to do some copy paste and you'll see that we will only have
one thing to change and then the data repricing phase will be ready and done it will be done for us
to move on with the next step which will be of course to train the simple in a regression model on the
training set.
All right.
So now I'm going to show you what I've just said.
I'm simply going to do some copy paste here.
There we go to import first the libraries and then adding them in a new code sale then to import a data
set.
I'm simply going to copy paste this second coat sale and you'll see that I will have almost nothing
to change.
So creating a new coat sale here basting it.
And finally let's do that final step step of the day repricing phase to split the data set into the
training set and the test set to ignore.
I remind had the separate entities where we're going to train separately the model and then evaluate
it.
So there we go.
Let us based it.
And now as I've told you we only have one little thing to change which is of course the name of the
dataset.
And I remind the name of the dataset is we're going to go back to our regression folder here very quickly
or to regression simple in a regression python.
And there we go.
Here we are.
And as you can see this is salary underscore data.
So the only thing I have to change here is the name of dataset.
And then voila.
Everything is ready the data depressing phase is ready because indeed this takes automatically the features
because it selects all the columns except the last one.
And this select automatically the dependent variable vector because it selects the last column.
So here of course we have only one feature therefore one column for the features and one column for
the dependent variable.
But you'll see for example that from multiple in our regression it will be exactly the same.
We will have absolutely nothing to change here.
Okay.
So now let me show you the beauty of the result.
Don't forget of course to upload the dataset before you know running these cells here.
So to upload the data set you indeed need to click this folder here.
Then it's going to connect to a runtime to enable file browsing after which you'll be able to upload
your data set.
There we go.
So you click this upload button here then you go to you know this whole machinery is at for there which
was provided to you in just the previous tutorial you know which had to download if not already.
So indeed we're going to go inside this further than we're going to go to part two regression than simple
in our regression than Python.
And there we go.
We select our dataset salary data.
We open it and now it is indeed in Google collab.
So perfect.
And now we're simply going to execute each of these cells first importing the libraries then importing
the data set perfect.
And now splitting the data set into the training set and tested and done.
Now the data repricing phase is over and we can move on to the next step.
Training the simple in our regression model on the training set.
So we're going to train our simple in our regression model to understand the correlations between numbers
of years of experience of these employees in the companies and their respective salary.
So it will understand and calculate all the correlations after which we will be able to predict some
new observations on which the model wasn't trained.
So I can't wait to start this new step in the next material.
And until then enjoy machine learning.