Hello my friends.
Welcome back to this implementation.
Are you ready to start that big full loop which will iterate through all the rounds in all the 10000
rounds meaning the 10000 customers to which we're going to show the ad and therefore in this loop at
each step.
Well we have to implement the three steps here.
Well we already implemented step 1 but we have to implement step two and step three at each iteration
of the loop.
Let's do this.
Let's start this for loop starting with 4.
Then we need to choose a variable name for you know that iterated variable.
And this time instead of calling it I you know as the classic name we will call it in because clearly
what we are iterating through are the round in the round from round one the first user to round 10000
the last user to whom we should be at.
Okay.
So for n n.
And then of course range from zero because you know indexes in Python start from zero up to.
And here you can either put 10000 but we already put 10000 in a variable so let's put and so that you
know then if you want to try another number of rounds you can just change the value of n here.
Okay so for n in range from 0 to n then Colin and there we go.
Let's start that for loop.
All right.
So I'm gonna scroll down a bit you know from here.
Perfect.
And there we go.
Let's do this.
All right.
So what do we need to start with.
Well you know right now what we want you know what we ultimately want you know within this particular
iteration of number and what we want is to select and that right.
We want to select and add and we're going to select it according to these steps you know we will select
the add it has the maximum UCB upper confidence bound.
So the first thing that we'll do is start from the first ad you know ad number one but since we're going
to work with indexes the index of this ad will be zero.
So I'm going to start from this ad equals zero here I'm introducing of course a new variable ad which
is initialized as zero but then you're going to see that we will do a second for loop which will loop
over all the different ads one by one you know starting from this one at number one of index zero then
going to this one at number two of index 1 and etc. up to add 10 because indeed in order to get the
maximum upper confidence bound we will need to compare the upper confidence bound of each of these ads
and therefore we'll have to iterate through each of these ads to find the maximum upper confidence balance.
And that's why right now I'm initializing this new ad Bible a zero to start with ad number one and then
we'll compute the UCB of this ad number one and then through the for loop you know we will get the other
upper confidence bounce and we will get the maximum one you see the idea very simple.
We just have to follow you know a certain logic where we know that the ultimate goal is to select the
ad that has the highest upper confidence mount.
All right.
So then do you think we have to already start that second for loop.
Well almost.
But we need to do something else.
We need to introduce a new variable which will be you know that maximum of the upper confidence bound
because for each of the add through that second for loop we will compute the upper confidence bound.
But in order to compare them to the maximum upper confidence bound.
Well a smart thing to do would be to introduce a new variable here that will be that maximum upper confidence
bound and which will be compared to each of the U.S. because of the ads.
And therefore here I'm introducing a new variable which I'm gonna call Max.
Let's say upper bound.
All right.
And which I'm initializing to zero because indeed at the beginning.
Well let's say that the maximum you know the highest upper confidence bound is zero.
And then of course once we get an ad that has a higher up we convince abandoned zero.
We will update this value of Max upper bound to this new higher output continues down.
All right.
So all logic here then.
Now we can start to.
You know the second loop that will iterate through the different ad from one to 10.
So there we go we start the second for loop for then a new looping variable you know iterated variable
which we're going to call this time of course.
Well either ad but ad is already taken you know that's already an existing variable.
So let's just choose I for I in range from zero because indexes and by then start 0 up to either 10
here or you know D because we already introduced that D variable which is equal to 10.
And if you want to do that same UCB implementation on a different number of ads imagine you have you
know five hours or even 50 AD while you simply have to change that deep value here and nowhere else.
All right so that's the purpose of introducing these variables here.
So for I in range from zero g and there we go.
We can start the second full loop and it is now in the second for loop that we will really implement
each of these steps.
So now now is the time you're going to press pause on the video to indeed implement that.
Step two First I would like you to implement from scratch.
No.
You can totally do this because you have everything here.
I would like you to implement that step too.
You have also all the variables so it should be all fine and then don't implement Step 3 because that
will be done for next exercise.
And besides it is not that direct you know we will have to use a certain trick in order to implement
that step 3.
All right.
So please implement Step 2 now please press bus on the video and implement Step 2.
But let me just give you two hints.
You know because maybe you will encounter issues with something in this part as you can see you'll have
to compute the square root of that value here and you have to know that in order to use the square root
in Python you have to import a certain library which is simply called the math library and from which
you can use a lot of mathematical tools like the square root.
So actually let's do it right now so that it's done we can either imported here or you know since I
prefer to keep the essential libraries here.
Let's just import it at the beginning of this implementation.
All right.
Right here.
So that it's done you know so that you can be ready to use that square root function.
And then I will let you of course look in the documentation online.
What is the exact function name.
So math.
There we go.
And then the second hint I wanted to give you was the fact that you have to start the step two with
an if condition.
Right.
Because at the beginning no add was selected and therefore this you know this quantity is equal to zero
for all the ads.
And if this is equal to zero.
This doesn't make sense you know it will be equal to plus infinity.
So you have to start with this if condition to make sure that the add we're dealing with in the second
full loop was already selected so that this is different than zero.
And this exists.
And so that then you can indeed compute the confidence interval.
All right so that was the last hint.
And now your turn.
Please press pause in the video and please implement this step 2.
All right.
Perfect.
So now let's implement the solution together of the step two.
All right.
So as we said we have to actually start here with an if condition that will check if the add we're dealing
with right now you know the add of index I has already been selected.
It's not the case at the beginning you know but over the round it will be the case you know the ads
will already have been selected.
But at the beginning for the first round we need to check that indeed the ad has been selected.
So in order to check this well that's very simple.
You know we have these variables that gives for each of the ads.
How many times they have been selected so far.
You know at round end up to round n and therefore we're going to take this now you know and then we
will check that the index I.
Which is the index of the ad we're dealing with right now in this numbers of selections list well we're
going to check that the element of index I in this numbers of selections list is indeed larger than
0 because if it is larger than 0 then that means that the ad was indeed already selected at least once.
Okay.
And now if you want but that's totally optional you can put this condition in parentheses right.
And then you add just a column and now now you're gonna say to python what should happen or what must
happen if indeed that at I.
Which we're dealing with right now in the second for loop was already selected.
All right.
So now now is it time we can implement all this because indeed this is different than zero.
This is larger than zero.
So very simply let's just follow this step by step.
First let's you know create a new variable for this which we're going to call average reward you know
because this corresponds to an average of the reward because it is the accumulated reward here of this
add up to run and divided by the number of times it was selected.
So that's nothing else than an average.
And therefore let's create a new variable here which we're gonna call average underscore reward.
And it is simply going to be equal to.
Well the accumulated reward of that specific ad I up to round n which is given exactly thanks to this
variable here of which we're going to have to take the index I write that at I which we're dealing with
right now.
So I'm basing that here and I'm taking of course in pair of square brackets the index I.
Because this you know all this corresponds exactly to the accumulated reward of that specific ad I up
to run in.
Okay.
So some of rewards I.
And then of course we need to divide that by the number of times that same ad I was selected.
And this is given of course by this again.
Right.
The numbers of selections of index I.
Which corresponds to the number of times the out of index I was selected.
And that gives you exactly the average reward that gives you exactly that value here.
Okay.
So very easy so far.
Then next step the next step is to get the confidence interval.
And more specifically we're going to get that value.
So right now we're going to compute this value here.
All right.
So let's simply call it Delta.
You know as a new variable Delta underscore I equals.
And now there you go.
That's where you needed to take that square root function from the math library.
So first we have to call indeed that math library.
And from which.
Well we need to call this function that allows to compute the square root.
And I'm sure you've found very easily online that this function is called as Q R T.
And then parentheses right.
This computes the square root of a value and the value we have to put inside this function is of course
exactly this you know three divided by two multiplied by the legality of the round and divided by the
number of times that I was selected up to round n.
Okay.
So let's do this.
First we start with this three divided by two then multiplied by then.
There you go you need to call the luck function which is another function of this mass library.
So actually this math library is used twice.
I'm calling it now to indeed be able to call that log function.
And now inside this log function well be careful maybe I should have given you another hint here but
be careful we can not input end here.
Why is that.
That's because actually.
And you know in this range here this first range starts from zero.
The first value of n is zero and that's you know because of the indexes in Python and you have to know
that the logarithm of 0 is actually minus infinity.
Therefore it would be very dangerous here to only put n in order to protect us from this.
We're just going to start from one.
Okay.
That's one way to do this the other way is of course to you know make that first for loop going from
one to and plus one so that we can go indeed from round one to and plus one.
But you know with Python we always work with the same indexes starting from zero.
So that's why we go with the first option here.
All right.
So all good so far.
And then of course we have to divide that by Well let's look at it again the number of times the ad
I was selected up to round in.
And that's of course exactly this value.
So I'm copying this again and pasting that here and there we go very quickly.
We got our Delta I we got exactly this value and now we have a final value to compute which is of course
well you know that long awaited upper confidence bound.
That's exactly what we have to compute right now.
And it is going to be simply the sum of that average reward plus that delta here.
So let's hear at a new line of code and then introduce a new variable which we're going to call upper
underscore bound not Max upper bound but upper bound and which will simply be equal to the sum of the
average reward.
There we go.
Plus the Delta high end perfect.
And now you know thanks to this for loop the second full of iterating through all the ads from zero
to nine but from and number one and number 10.
Well we have the upper Bell.
We have the upper bound of each of these add and the upper bound at that specific round.
And we're dealing with right now inside this first for loop.
All right so basically we're done implementing this step two.
We implemented a step two and we even got that value here you know the upper bound but now step three
is not implemented yet because it did step three consist of selecting the add that has a maximum Brooke
conference.
So now we need to add one trick you know which is kind of classic in Python but do we need to add one
trick to select the maximum upper confidence bound of these ten at.
So going back to here.
Well we will surely take a little break here and actually I will directly ask you to try to implement
that step three you know between this literal and the next one before you start the next material.
Please try to implement step three.
It's not that direct it's not that easy but you know you have to use some kind of algorithmic logic.
Okay.
But I'll give you of course some hints unless you don't want to hence and therefore you can directly
press pause or quit this video now but I'm going to give you some hints if you want the first hand.
Is that right now you're done with this if condition so you can go back here you know inside this second
full loop and then you're gonna have to start with of course and else.
Right.
Which is the condition where you know that ad we're dealing with right now has not been selected yet.
So what you'll have to do and that's my last hint will be to use a trick to select the ads that have
not been selected yet.
Why do you need to select these ads.
Well the answer is here.
That's exactly because of this.
You know this denominator which shouldn't be equal to zero.
And since this is exactly the number of times the ad I was selected well we need this to be different
than zero in order to compute this average reward and therefore in order to compute then the confidence
interval with the upper confidence balance.
And that's why in the UCB algorithm it's compulsory to make sure that during the first round all the
ads are selected.
So actually during the first 10 rounds we have to use a trick so that we make sure to select all the
ads so that this way well all that and I end here you know for all the different ads will be different
than zero.
Okay.
So basically the exercise for next time you know the next material is to indeed implement that step
three to compute the maximum of the upper confidence balance.
Well at the same time implementing a trick to make sure that all the ads are selected in the 10 first
rounds.
So pretty challenging but at least try at least try as hard as you can.
And I promise you that you will progress and improve your skills in machine learning.