Hello and welcome to this art tutorials.
So in the previous tutorials we solved our business problem in Python using hierarchical clustering
.
And this time we're going to solve it in our.
And you're going to see that it's exactly the same.
We are going to import a small dataset first then we're going to use the DNA program to find the optimal
number of clusters that we will fit hierarchical clustering to our small data sets.
And then finally we will visualise our results.
So in this tutorial we're going to do the first step which is to import the small data sets.
So let's start doing it right now.
But before that let's not forget to set a working directory.
So here I am on my desktop.
This is my machine learning easy folder.
Let's open it then let's go to Part 3 clustering then hierarchical clustering.
And now we click on this more button here we click on set has working directory and that sets are hierarchical
clustering folder as a working directory.
So let's make sure we have our small data set in the folder.
Here it is perfect.
We are ready to start.
OK so let's introduce a new section with a Cummins importing the mall data set.
Here we go.
And now let's import our dataset.
So we create this new variable dataset equals read Dotsie S V and in parenthesis we put the name of
our dataset Model T as V in quotes.
OK so let's select this line and execute.
And now our data set appears in data.
So let's click on it and here it is.
So for those of you who didn't follow the Python tutorials I just gave a quick reminder of what this
dataset is about.
So basically these are informations of customers in a mall which are customers that not only subscribe
to the membership card but also come often to the mall and the mall gathered some information up to
hundreds of these customers their gender their age their annual income.
And then for each of these customers they computed a spending score.
So this spending's cortex values between 1 and 100.
And the closer to spending scores to one the less the customer spends and the closer to spending scores
to a hundred.
The more the customer spends.
OK so we have these informations and now our mission is to find some groups of customers.
But since we have no idea of what kind of groups we're looking for or even the number of groups of customers
we're looking for.
This specifically makes this business problem a clustering problem because we don't know the answers
.
We don't know the final results and more precisely we don't know the final categories of our customers
OK so we imported our data set and now what we have to do is to prepare our data because we want to
do this clustering only based on the annual income and the spinning score.
So let's create a new variable x equals data set and then in square brackets we're going to put the
two indexes or columns of interest which are let's see let's go back to our dataset indexes and are
started 1.
So customer ideas index one gender as index to Ages index three annual income as an x 4 and spending
scores the next five.
OK so here in the square brackets we add four column 5 that takes our Culham annual income and spending
score.
And now let's select this line of code and execute it.
And here it is our x variable appears in the data.
Let's click on it to make sure everything is fine.
Okay perfect.
We have our two columns annual income and spending score and our 200 observations.
Perfect.
So we completed our first step.
So that's the end of this tutorial.
And in the next tutorial things are going to get more interesting.
We're going to use the DENTRO gram to find the optimal number of clusters and you're going to see what
a danger a gram looks like in our thank you for watching this video.
And I look forward to seeing you in the next tutorial