Hello and welcome to this art tutorial.
So in the following tutorials we're going to implement a simple linear regression model on our.
So it's going to be the same steps as in Bison.
And let's start with the first step.
So the first step is to actually set the working directory as you can see right now.
I'm on my desktop so I'm going to go to my machine or an easy folder for two regression and then Section
4 simple in the regression.
And here we are.
That's the folder we want to set as a working directory.
Make sure that it contains your salary data.
As we file that's the data on which we will build our simple regression model.
So make sure it's here and now to set this folder as working directory just need to click on the small
button here and then click on set as a working directory and that's it.
That's done.
Now we're ready to start.
We're ready to start with the real first step of making a machine or any model which is the data pre-processing
step.
So we're going to use Of course the data pre-processing template that we made in part 1.
So I'm just going to use a template here on this copy and then paste it here.
All right.
And now we just need to change a few things to adapt it to our dataset.
So of course we will need to change the name of the data set here.
It is not data dot csv but salary underscore data.
OK.
So then I'm going to select this to have a look at the dataset.
Here we go let's have a look.
Here's the dataset.
OK so just to remind what this dataset is about this dataset contains some information of employees
in a company.
And these two informations are the number of years of experience the employee has and the salary.
So we are trying to understand if there is a correlation between the salary and the number of years
of experience and mostly we're trying to see if it's a linear correlation.
That means it fits.
That means that there is a linear dependency between these two variables.
And so what we need to understand that the first reflex that we must have when we make a model is that
we must understand which is the independent variable and which is the dependent variable.
So the independent variable is the number of years of experience and the dependent variable is the salary
.
And so what happens is that we are trying to predict the dependent variable salary based on the informations
of the independent variable.
Years of experience.
Okay so thats the data set.
Now let's continue with our model.
So let's go back to simple regression here.
And we don't need to specify any column of interest we have.
All we need.
So we won't use this line here.
Okay now we're ready to split the dataset into the training set and the is set.
So we perhaps need to change the split ratio and see the data set contains 30 observations or what what
would be a good split ratio.
It's really as you prefer.
I know that I told you that a good split ratio is 75 percent.
But just for the sake of beauty let's take 20 observations in a training set and 10 observations in
a test set.
So that would be that the split ratio would be to surd.
Okay.
And of course let's not forget to change the name of the dependent variable because this was the name
of the data in the template.
And now it's what the name is the name is salary.
So here you know that's the name of the dependent variable.
So we need to change purchased into salary.
And now I think it's ready we're ready to split the data sets into the training set in a set.
So let's do it and let's see what happens.
Here we go.
It worked perfectly.
So now let's have a look at the trainset and the test set.
OK the training set contains the 20 observations generated from the splits and in the test set we have
our 10 observations.
So we are going to train our simple in the regression model on the training set.
That means that our model is going to learn the correlations between the number of years of experience
and the salary in the set here in the training set and then later we will test its performance its power
of prediction on the test.
So let's continue the last step of the data pre-processing is features scaling but the simple in their
regression package they were going to use here and Our Takes care of this.
So we won't need to apply features scanning manually so we will be fine with that.
And actually the data preprocessing phase is ready.
So awesome.
We are ready to start building the linear regression model.
We're going to do that in the next tutorial so I can't wait to see you there.
And until then enjoy machine learning.