Hello and welcome to this art.
So today we're going to implement our second non linear regression model.
It's going to be that as we our support vector for regression.
So let's do it.
We're going to use our regression template and you're going to see how it's going to be so easy.
So let's start by doing the basics.
Set the right folder as working directory so we'll go to machine running a Z or two regression and then
suport vector regression.
Right.
That's the rifle third position sorry we.
All good.
Let's click on set as a working directory to set the folder as a working directory.
Great.
And now we can start.
So we're going to take our regression template and we're going to take everything from here to here
.
Copy and paste it in our SVR model.
Here we go.
And now we just need to change a few things.
So let's start by changing the basics.
We're going to replace regression model here by as we are.
Okay.
And same here as your results.
And same here.
All right.
That was the easy step.
And now let's get to the interesting step.
So this interesting step is of course to create are as we are the aggressor and we are creating it here
.
So I am going to remove this.
And now let's create this regressors.
It's going to take three or four lines as usual.
It's going to be very simple we're going to use a function which is the SVM function very simply because
as we are you know is a support vector machine algorithm but for regression That's why we call it as
you are.
And therefore we are just taking it from the SBM function and you will understand why perfectly.
So first let's import the required package because this function is contained in a package which is
the intent 71 package.
So let's go to our packages here and let's check if we have it.
So I have it because of course I used it before but you might not have it.
So in case you don't have it I'm going to type this line here that you will need to execute to install
this package.
So you install that package here and then in the parenthesis and then the quotes you type the name of
the package which is 10 71.
All right.
And then you just select this line and execute.
And this will install the package.
Not going to do it because mine is already installed and therefore I'm going to put that in comment
just pressed command shift plus seat.
All right.
And now let's actually also add this line library and in parenthesis Eatons 71 not in quotes.
And this will select automatically the package here intensively one because this will not always be
selected.
But by including that in your script you will be fine.
This will always be selected.
OK.
And now let's start creating our SVR aggressor.
So as usual we are going to start by defining our aggressor regressors and then you equals and then
as I mentioned before we're going to use the SVM function which is actually this.
And then in parenthesis.
Now let's press here for one to have a look at the arguments and see what we need to input.
So the first argument is formula.
So you start to know perfectly what it is.
Of course the formula is our dependent variable which is remember salary and then tell the.
I just pressed out and and then it does here and that specifies that we are taking all the independent
variable of our dataset.
We actually have one independent variable which is the level independent variable.
So we could also type here level but most of the time we used the dot because of course we have a lot
more than one independent viable.
But as a reminder I'm taking one of the variable here so that we can clearly see the visual graphic
results of the different non-linear models that we're building.
OK so now let's add the second argument.
So I'm adding a comma here and then next argument.
So the next argument is data.
Ok I guess you know what this data argument will be.
It's going to be of course our dataset dataset here because we did not create any training set or test
sets you know before we used the training set.
Here is the data.
But here we don't have any training set so of course we're going to take the whole data set because
we want to make very accurate predictions.
OK.
And now finally most important arguments.
Well all the arguments are important but the most relevant for this section about as we are is actually
the next arguments we are about inputs.
So this argument is actually not X or Y these are optional arguments.
The most important argument I was just talking about is this one the type because this argument type
will actually specify if you're making an ass VM model which is used for classification or as we are
model which is used for regression.
So here since we're building a non linear regression model we will choose the EPA s regression type
we could use actually regression or new regression as you can see you want to take the most common one
.
The EPA has regression.
And if we were making as a model for classification then we would have chosen C classification here
as you can see sophistication is the default type for classification.
So in short if you want to do regression you choose time equals regression.
And if you want to do classification you choose type you cause C classification and actually and the
next part about classification will make an SVM model.
And for this specific model we will choose the C classification type.
Ok but here we are doing regression so we choose the regression type.
So let's put it into type here type equals EPEAT as regression.
Right.
And you need to put that in quotes.
Actually don't forget the quotes to prevent any error from happening again.
That's actually the final arguments if you want we can add the kernel argument here just to specify
that we want a gaussian kernel because here we're using Galchen kernel but it's the kernel selected
by default here so we don't actually need to put it but just keep in mind that we are here using the
Gulshan kernel far as we are model.
Ok but here we're all fine and actually our model is ready to be created.
So actually this is all we had to change in this regression template and now we are ready to execute
the sections one by one to create our model and find out about the final result and the final verdict
whether it's truth or bluff.
So let's do it.
I'm going to import the data set first.
All right here we go.
Well-reported we can have a look.
So these are days that with the levels as the independent variable and the salaries as the dependent
variable get great and no need to split the deficit into the training set and said no need for future
scanning because we're using the very popular Eatons of any one library that includes it.
And now let's create our model.
So I'm going to select this whole section here for us command control center to the truth done regrets
are created great.
And now let's break down your results would you like to start by visualizing that as we are results
first or predicting the new result well let's actually predict the result because this is the most exciting
step.
And let's keep the best for the end.
But this step is actually very exciting also because we're getting the final prediction we are getting
the final predicted salaries.
So you know it says you won't if you're doing actually this code by yourself before me.
That's actually a very good exercise.
I really encourage you to do this.
Choose whatever you want to execute first it's ready anyway.
You don't need to change anything more now.
So I'm going to execute that right now.
And actually we obtain a predicted salary of a hundred and seventy seven thousand dollars.
Great.
So remember this employee who we are negotiating the future salary right now said that it's pretty salary
was 160 Okay.
And our model predicted that it's pretty salary with a hundred and seventy seven.
OK.
So first of all that's actually close to what this employee said.
And besides it's on the good side of the negotiation.
So that's actually pretty good.
And then we can be satisfied with this result and our model.
But to be really satisfied Let's see what's happening with the graphic results so I'm going to execute
the section and let's have a look at the SVR model and here it is.
I'm going to zoom on it and better.
Okay.
So first of all this model fits very well.
Most of the data points as a reminder the real observation points other red points here and all the
points in this blue curve here which is the as your model itself our prediction point.
So for example if we're taking this red observation point here well the prediction is perfect because
the prediction point is the projection of this red point on the blue curve.
So it's actually the repoint itself because the red point is on the blue curve so that makes a perfect
prediction but here for example if we take a less accurate prediction but still a very good one then
we take the real observation point here the red point we projected on the blue curve and that's the
difference between the real salary and the predicted sorry which is here.
If you project it back on the y axis which contains the salaries but you can see that for all of these
points from this one to actually this one the blue curve is actually getting very close to the real
observation points the red points.
And so the predictions are very close to real results but that's for all these points of the data set
except for this one here.
This one is left alone which by the way corresponds to see.
So I'm sorry for the CEO but the reason for what is happening here is that this is actually an outlier
not to call this year not liar but this is an outlier because as you can see this point is actually
far from the other points in terms of salaries.
The CEO has a much higher salary than the previous positions.
So for that as your model that's an outlier and therefore he actually didn't consider it.
It's like it excludes at this point no moral by not looking at it and making its predictions on these
points here.
So that specifically due to the your algorithm itself but there are a lot of parameters and you can
actually play with the parameters to change the way as your model perceives outliers.
So for example these parameters are the penalty parameters the regularization parameters it's most of
the time well described in the description and of course Eaton 71 library includes such techniques.
But we're not going to do it here in this tutorial because we actually don't need to get a good prediction
of the CEO's salary.
And remember what we actually needed was a good prediction of the previous salary of this employee we
were negotiating with and this employee has a level 6.5.
And around this point we can see that the model fits very well to our dataset and we actually get a
prediction of 177 K quite close to the real or the mentioned salary of this employee which is a 160
k.
So that's actually pretty good.
And therefore the verdict of truth of bluff according to our your model is rather truth.
OK so not bad as you are made a good job here.
Now let's see how decision tree regression and run them for us regression will do we'll see that in
the next sections.
So I'll see you there.
And until then enjoy machine learning