In this video you're going to learn how to create a business account on Instagram.
And this is the first step to using Instagram as a powerful marketing tool to grow your business.
So the first thing you want to do is download the Instagram and to do that you can just open up any
browser type and download Instagram up.
It should pop right up and you can get it absolutely free on iPhone or Android or any other device.
So once you've got the app downloaded you want to go ahead and then open it up and what you actually
want to do here now is log in with your personal Facebook profile still see this option here continue
as your name and you want to go ahead and click that.
And then once we're inside our personal profile we can add up to five business accounts so and the click
the option to continue with my facebook account.
Then you want to go ahead and click open click on your icon in the bottom right hand corner to open
up your personal profile and then inside your personal profile you want to click on the settings gear
icon and the top right hand corner.
Scroll down.
And then you click on Add in that case.
Now what we want to do here is go ahead and click on sign up and the bottom of the screen next you want
to add in a phone number and an e-mail and it's best to make your business phone number and e-mail because
they would need to be different to your personal account.
Once you've out of those you can just click next.
And now you want to add in here your business name and a secure password.
So for this example just put in
a fictional business name here and secure a password and then click Next here we can see that we have
created our account now.
Now you can see that it's given me a business name I can change this if I want which I think I'd like
to do so I can change this to something more like my business name and I can see if that's available
which it is that little green tick.
So and then then I can just click next.
Now there are going to be options here to add Facebook friends etc. you can just skip all of these and
we can just click on the top right hand corner we can click Cancel and now we can really come in and
see our business profile.
To do that we can click on the bottom right hand corner and we can see.
Here is my business.
I can set up.
There is one further important step that we need to take and to do that we can click on the gear icon
in the top right hand corner once again and you're going to see this option to switch to a business
profile.
So this will allow us to advertise on Instagram.
It'll allow us to get access to the inside sick cetera.
So this is an important step to do in order to access all a lot stuff.
So you can click continue.
It gives you a little bit of an overview of the benefits of switching to business accounts.
And then this is an important step as well.
We need to choose the page to link it to from Facebook.
So Facebook owns Instagram now and a key part of that buying when they bought them.
They really are now forcing an integration between Facebook and Instagram see need to create or link
a Facebook page.
So it should show up all of the Facebook pages that I've created.
If you haven't created a page you can go ahead and click Create one at the bottom there.
But I've just set up a Facebook page.
You'll see all of the pages you're not been for here you can just select it and then click next and
then you can import once again.
Your business
e-mail and phone number and this information will be visible to your Instagram followers.
So it is important to put this in accurately a phone number and address.
And you just need to just put it in one click Don.
And then we can go to the profile and there we go.
Now we have set up our business account on instagram.
I know there was a couple of steps in there so you can go back over the video if you need to to set
it up for yourself.
But the key reason though we've set it up this way is now I can switch between my personal profile and
any other business accounts that I set up.
And as I said you can add up to five business accounts within the one up here.
So that makes it much easier for your workflow day today to set it up this way.
So now that you know how to set up a business account for Instagram.
Go ahead and set one up for yourself or for a client or a company that you're working for.