Welcome to Twitter marketing by the end of this training you'll be confident using Twitter as a powerful
marketing tool to drive Web site traffic and generate sales for your business.
You'll learn how to add valuable content to Twitter so you can build an audience on a track.
Genuine followers.
I'll show you how to set up your profile.
Post your first five tweets and how to get your first followers.
You'll also learn how to search for potential clients on Twitter how to engage with top influencers
and how to use Twitter analytics to grow your account.
I'll even walk you through how to integrate Twitter right into your web site.
We'll be covering all of this as well as plenty of other tips and tricks so that you can get the most
added Twitter.
Let's get started.