In this video you're going to learn why you should be focusing on building up an email list as a priority
and how it is actually the biggest asset that you're going to have as a business or personal brand.
So you can see I have an email list here and essentially this is a list of emails for existing or potential
customers.
Now why would I bother to do this.
Why is this fall unable.
Well with this list I can notify them every time I send out a blog post that gets trafficked to my Web
site any time that I've a market research survey for want to figure out what products to sell.
I can e-mail the my e-mail list and help and ask them what they want and that really helps me reduce
the risk and create a positive product that people are actually going to buy.
I can reengaging existing customers and say hey you know you bought the last product.
Here's another one that would really suit your needs as well.
And it's not just me that is saying that building an e-mail list is important.
It's actually this great article seven experts on why building an e-mail list is so important.
Neil Patel here a well-known marketer and he says Out of all the channels I've tested as a marketer
e-mail continually performs most of them not only does that have the highest conversion rate but as
you build up your list you can continually monetize by pitching multiple products et cetera.
It's a great example just look at e-commerce sites like Amazon.
One way they continually get you to buy more products from them is e-mailing you offers on a regular
basis so perfect example for it.
It's perfect for e-commerce.
You bought this why didn't you have a look at this.
You know so for a blog for an e-commerce site for services business it doesn't matter what type your
business is you have an email list is going to be your biggest asset because it can drive traffic and
sales and that's good.
And I think that was one of the good well known here.
Noah Kagan another very well-known marketer as he says after you wake up in the morning what's the first
thing you do.
I know it's for me it's checking email I'd have to agree to that.
I check my emails first thing in the morning as well.
And he's a seven figure business and 90 percent of their revenue comes from e mails.
So if that rings true for you you check your e-mails a lot.
I definitely read all of my e-mail subject lines even if I don't open them and I look at this a lot
more than I do personally in social media because there's so much content on social media.
And that's the maybe file reason you want to build up an email list as essentially an insurance policy.
Because on Facebook there is so much content being submitted that Facebook have to filter content and
so they're only going to show the most highly engaged content in someone's news feed.
So even if you build up an audience on Facebook you make a post.
Not everybody is going to see your posts because Facebook have to filter it and there's just too much
content they have to protect.
The experience of the user not so with an email when you send an e-mail it's going to hit the inbox
of everybody on your list whether they open it or not they're going to see as an on on platforms like
Facebook.
They might not even be aware that you've created a post.
So in terms of visibility as well just the email is just trumps all of the other platforms because they
have to filter and contact that content is just too much there.
So if your content is not getting a lot of engagement your followers are not going to see it.
And that's why email is so so valuable it's still extremely useful to use Facebook and other platforms.
But just in case they decide to change the rules they limit the filter the content even more.
You might even get kicked off Facebook for breach of policy terms you could get kicked off amazon for
breaching their Terms of Service.
It happens and you don't want that to happen to you.
You have no backup plan.
And that's why even if you don't plan on sending a lot of e-mails it's just an a great insurance policy
to have an e-mail list built up that you fully control and that you can use to send e-mails and reach
your customers directly.
So hopefully us convince you why building up an email list is so important it's going to be the biggest
asset you have.
You can use it sell products drive traffic to blog posts drive traffic to YouTube videos get responses
to market research surveys.
It's a fantastic asset to have.
Whether you are a personal brand or a company you need to focus on this as a priority to build this
up.
It's key to really growing your business.