In this video you're going to learn how to set up e-commerce tracking in google analytics so you can
measure the number of transactions on revenue that your Web site generates.
And the first step to setting up e-commerce tracking is to come down into the admin section of your
Google Analytics accounts come up into e-commerce setting.
Just click to enable e-commerce and enhance e-commerce reporting and click save.
And that wraps up the first step to setup e-commerce tracking in Google Analytics.
Before we move on to Step Two let's just take a minute to explain the difference between e-commerce
and enhance e-commerce reporting.
So coming into the developer guide here for Google analytics we can see that e-commerce tracking really
allows you to measure the number of transactions and revenue that your Web site generates.
Now enhanced e-commerce reporting will really give you information about user interactions as such as
product impressions product clicks viewing product details adding a product to the shopping cart initiating
checkout process transactions and refunds.
So that really goes beyond just the basic transactions and revenue and gives you a whole load of information
about the user's behavior leading up to the purchase.
So that is really the difference between e-commerce and enhanced e-commerce reporting in Google Analytics.
The second step to set up e-commerce tracking in Google Analytics is to add the tracking code to your
Web site or app to collect e-commerce data and send it to Google Analytics.
Now the great news is is that if you are using an e-commerce platform like Shopify or Magento you don't
need to do any additional steps here.
They have built their platform so it's very easy to send not e-commerce data.
All you'll need to have done is really enable those reports and you're going to see that e-commerce
data in your Google Analytics reports.
So what I suggest you do is if you're using Shopify or Magento or woo commerce or another shop system
like that is to go ahead and check their help center to see the easy steps to really send that e-commerce
data to your Google Analytics account.
Now if you're not using a shop system like that you have to manually add in the e-commerce tracking
code to your Web sites and to complete this task.
You need to be comfortable with editing HDMI all on coding in JavaScript or have help from an experienced
web developer.
So this is the type of additional code that you need to put into your Web site in order to track that
e-commerce and data.
So if you're not familiar with coding javascript and hatred UML than history look for a freelancer to
do this for you.
This is a fairly standard thing on all you need to do is find someone who's familiar with your shop's
system.
So what I'll do is put this developer guide in the description if you want to go through this detailed
guide and implement those steps for yourself to add the tracking code to your Web site or app.
Now the final step to really set up e-commerce tracking is just to come into your Google Analytics account.
Once you have completed those setup steps and just verify that it is working.
So where you're going to find these reports is under conversions e-commerce.
Once you have those setup and it's collected data for a couple of days then you'll be able to see things
like know how much revenue and conversion rates the order value the top products etc. In all of the
e-commerce reports.
So that wraps up the three steps to set up e-commerce tracking in Google Analytics.