In this video you're going to learn how to get reposted by topic cance on Instagram.
And this is probably the number one strategy that you can use if you are running in Strohm have no audience
and you've no audience outside of Instagram either.
So this will help you get in front of a big audience.
Very simple strategy and very very effective.
And let me give you a couple of examples to bring this to life.
So I'm just going to show you a quite a simple example of this from Tim Ferriss is again he's an author
and you can see that he has a post here and this is actually a repost.
You can see that he's said that in the comments of the image and he's actually mentioned the original
poster which in this case is Jaydee poor pere.
So if I click through I can see here from Jane Cauley that this was her original post same image and
all she said is I love the holidays and she's hashtags for his hashtag tribe of mentors.
So why would Tim Ferriss repost this.
Well because it's essentially a mini testimonial.
It's somebody who is enjoying their products.
You see all of the holidays that's kind of a perfect post for Christmas time.
It's a subtle way for him to remind his audience that the book is XYZ and then they can get for Christmas.
So essentially if you want to get reposted by big cats you've got to give them a post that is going
to make them look good.
That reminds people to buy their products or services.
That's essentially a mini testimonial essentially where you're going to be the poster boy for them that
they can then resell right now in this case here.
I don't think Jade McCauley kind of uses strategically.
You see him is impersonal.
But if you're even a business that can't or a personal brand that you want to grow why you can do is
identify topic cats in your niche and say something good about their product or service their book their
course whatever it can be.
So then they have the opportunity to read posters.
So that was one example there.
You can see Tim first and author he has a book.
So anybody who says something good about his He's probably going to reposes.
And even if I look down here you can see that he's reposted somebody else which is the Christmas tree
in the books.
Again a great way for him to his mind his audience to buy the book for Christmas.
And so what you can do is even look at these top accounts look at the types of posts that they have
re posted before.
And if you wanted to get in front of them you could create a post similar to that and you could just
make sure that you put in the hash tags or whatever that get their attention that they'll be monitoring
on their notifications or other way.
And let me give you another example of this just to make it really clear again.
So here's another account this guy Dave Ramsey and you can see here that this is another post.
So they they said that paid off 61000 in 2017.
Now that is a great achievement.
Obviously that is something that was a result of the work that this guy does.
He's the kind of help people get out.
Yes.
This is a success story a case study someone who is a poster boy for what he's trying to do and encourage
his audience to do so.
Of course he's going to share that.
This is exactly the outcome that he is trying to get his audience to.
So this builds his authority.
It also shows that his products or services work etc. and so of course he is going to repose.
So if you wanted to get the attention of this guy Dave Ramsey and get reposted Well then you create
a sex success story from his products or services.
Make sure you tag him onto the hashtags.
And then there's a good chance that he's going to repots that eyes they can see that's the original
post there and you can see that they said we were happy that we were able to continue our Debt-Free
Gjert journey.
We're shipping a way that I hope would be done a couple of years and you can see them below then they've
actually tied that big top influencers.
Dave Ramsey So that was kind of two examples there of maybe an online influencer show you another example
of this because it really does work for whatever type of product or service you have.
This is an e-commerce products.
It's kind of camping attendance up off the ground looks pretty cool.
To be honest and you can see here is a picture of their product in action that one of their customers
took and the way we know this is because you can see PC Photo Credit comping intense.
Now I think this is an example of someone using it quite strategically.
Now we can see that this 10 Cylons 186 thousand followers we can see that this got 280 are 2008 832
likes.
That got quite a lot of engagements and you can see the photo credit going back to the original account
which if we look here I'm guessing has a much smaller audience 447 followers.
So this is the perfect example of the much smaller can getting the attention of a massive change by
really showing them showing their products in a positive way.
So if we come back to the original post here we might have scroll and find this.
Here we go.
This is the original post.
And they're saying Check out this setup.
Spread the word.
They put in even the link to the to the company account.
They plant a tree while you're at it so it's a customer really spreading the message positively and
you can see that they have even shown where it is weak park trees snow hammock.
So it's kind of like a pretty interesting way that they've shown the product.
And essentially again it's a success story it's a testimonial a visual testimonial of the product.
And as a result that much bigger account is going to share that out and the benefit for this morning
is that it puts them in front of the big cance audience.
So if you want to use this to grow your own in ceramic can watch need to use firstly identify those
big accounts that you want to get in front of you could be following those they're going to be slightly
different for any type of business Daryn.
And once you've identified them what you want to do is think about how you can create a set success
story a mini testimonial that will catch their attention and that they're are going to want to share
action and you can do this over and over and over again.
It is a fantastic way to grow your Instagram account by simply being reposted by top Instagram account.
So go ahead and use that for yourself for these clients for your companies.
It's one of the fastest ways you can grow on Instagram.