In this video you will learn how to analyze your curious stats in order to know how to grow.
And also I'm going to show you how to tracking Google Analytics how much traffic all these curagh answers
are actually delivering to your site and I'll show you had to set it up so you can even track how much
traffic one individual question is bringing in.
So first let's get started by looking at the curious stats to access them.
You can just come and click on your icon and then click on Staats and you can see your answer views
of votes and shares over the last 30 days and you can extend that out if you wanted three months or
all time as well.
Now below here you can just see a view by day by day.
A graph of that.
And then over here perhaps the most interesting part is the number of answer views by question.
And so the top question here has the most amount of cancer views.
This is really helpful to know because then you can continue to answer more questions like your top
questions and that will allow you just to get a lot more answers views and exposure across curagh.
So what I would do is have a look at my top question look at the way that I laid this sage and maybe
use a similar format in future because obviously this was successful and it's got a lot of votes.
It's got a lot of views.
And what I could also do is not only look at the format of how I answered that but also come into the
question as well.
And maybe I could have a look at these questions.
That are related.
I continue to answer those related questions.
And again I could answer those later if I wanted to add those to the list.
So the easy way to grow and cure is just to do more of what is working and continue to answer related
questions to your top answers.
Now the Stotts is pretty basic.
Here on Q&amp;A.
But probably that's all you really need to see.
You just want to see what your top answers are and answer more questions like that.
Now it is interesting to see how many views we're getting.
But the real test of the return on investment for our cure a marketing efforts is to understand how
much traffic that is actually driving to our Web.
And so we but we really want to see like I can see here in Google Analytics is how much traffic an individual
question is bringing.
And so this is pretty good I can see that.
Four hundred and fourteen sessions in a 30 day period just from one questioning curagh and also that
this has actually led to 54 e-mail sign ups.
So that is a really great result from answering a question on curagh and I'll show you the question
here.
OK.
Is Google Analytics.
And so the way that I can understand and get that information in Google Analytics is really by using
a special link at the end of my question here.
So if I open this up I go to edit this I show you what the link looks like and then I'll show you how
to create that link.
So maybe I can see this.
I get it.
Well essentially this is the way that we understand and get this information in Google Analytics is
by creating this special link.
So to create a special link what you want to do is go ahead and type into Google Google Analytics you
are our builder.
And that's going to bring up this free tool from Google Analytics where we can really input the page
on our Web site that we want to send people to from our cure.
QUESTION So the next thing we need to put in is our campaign source.
So it's going to be curagh our medium is social I mean meaning people are coming here organically through
that social network and then we want to put in our campaign name and I'll show you what this looks like.
You can see our campaign name.
We can see in Google Analytics under our campaign's report and then if we click in we can see the source
we've put in and the medium curagh social.
So the information that you put into this your builder is what you we're going to see in your Google
Analytics reports and if you use this link then if you copy this link and then you paste you use that
link in your cure answer.
So I'll paste this in that.
Now anytime anybody clicks on this link and comes through to my Web site that's going to be recorded
in Google Analytics and then I know definitely where I'm getting my traffic from curagh how many visits
and email sign ups that is contributing to and even what individual questions are delivering the most
amount of traffic and that is really the most accurate way to make sure that your cure efforts are paying
off and we to see which are the questions not only get the most views but the questions that really
get you the most.
Web site visits and say e-mail sign ups or even a Cobi sales on your product.
So now that you understand how to analyze your curagh stats and to create the links with the world builder
so that you can track this in Google Analytics.
Go ahead and do it for yourself so you can really track the return on investment for your cure and marketing
efforts.