In this video you're going to learn how to set up an email address that uses your own domain name.
And this is absolutely free to do with blue hose and the benefits of doing it are that your e-mails
can look more professional it's easier for people to remember if you're saying it in a conversation
and it's going to be a lot more relevant if you're sending a newsletters and e-mails from your site.
You can also use this process to set up say info at your domain or support it's your domain and that
allows you to delegate work to other people can free up a lot of time for you and also you can set up
e-mail addresses for other team members and you'd be surprised at how something as simple as having
a common e-mail address can really make you feel like a team.
So the steps to set this up are very simple.
Firstly log into your blue hosts portal and if you don't have the link that check your email again that
you have got from registration you can click straight through.
Then you want to come don't e-mail.
Here in the sidebar.
But we want to do is go ahead and add an e-mail account.
So I'm just going to set one up for example support W.P. set up a dot com then you want to enter your
password.
Very simple make it something secure and just make sure that it's the same and then you can go ahead
and click Create it can't.
So now we can see that the account is being created.
We can go ahead and viewers on what you can do now is go ahead and click access web mail.
So this will bring you to your inbox.
Essentially it's the same as something like a Gmail inbox.
You need to choose a web mail application and all of these are pretty much the same.
There's no difference between them and they're all free.
So you can select that and come on in.
And once you're inside you're just going to see one e-mail here which includes some details about your
e-mail account.
Now one thing you might want to do just for convenience is to set up any e-mails that arrive at this
e-mail address and forward it to maybe an e-mail account that you check more regularly.
So what we can do is come down to forward forwarders here and what I'm going to do is forward any e-mails
that I get so I'm going out of order here and forwarded from this account that I just set up support
a W piece set up demo and I can afford it to my personal account.
Let's just say that I check all the time.
So that's all I simply need to do.
And any time I get an e-mail sent to support a WP self demo it'll forward to my personal account which
I check much more regularly.
And then I can come back in and really respond to that e-mail.
So one thing you might be wondering is how many e-mail accounts can you set up and that really depends
on the hosting package that you selected.
So if you have the basic plan you can get five e-mail accounts if you the plus plan then you can have
unlimited e-mail accounts and that is the benefit once again of checking and selecting the plus plan.
So to sum up setting up an email account that use your own domain name not only looks more professional
it's easier to remember it's more relevant to readers when you're sending out newsletters and then really
allow you to delegate work to team members.
So go ahead and set one up following the steps in this video.
It's absolutely free to do with most.