In this video you're going to learn how to moderate comments and reviews on your Facebook page sort
of get started.
Let us look at how to moderate Commines So any time that you make a Facebook post underneath you're
going to see comments from other people here.
Now a lot of the time these comments are helpful they're real comments but in some cases you actually
see these kind of spammy comments and usually they are are bots or paid services that people use.
Just to comment on a load of different Facebook pages in order to give some visibility to their business
her Facebook page.
So to avoid this and to really keep your comments section as something useful and not just allow to
spam comments what do you news actually start to moderate comments.
So every time I make a post made to come back the day after and you can look at the cons and you could
have the option to hide a comment.
So let me have a look here.
So I'm just going to hide the comments and then you're going to see that you have the option to hide
the current elitist reported or ban that person from commenting on your Facebook page.
Now I'm just going on behind this for the moment because I think that is a general comment.
But you can ban people from your Facebook page and this is the best way to get rid of those obviously
spam comments from the current post and from all future posts.
If the Commons had one as commons my policy is just look you're just banned.
And then if they reach out to me I can unlock them and I will show you that in a second.
So you can ban people when you ban people they're no longer able to comment on any of your posts.
They won't see your posts in their news feed but they can still come to your Facebook page.
So I'm just going to unhide that because I think it's just a normal comment.
Now if you want to moderate your comments even further are unblocked as people who want to come into
the settings section at the top right hand corner of your page you can see that even number of options
here.
Well first let's show you how to unblock people so you come to people and other pages in the right hand
side you select from the dropdown menu here and people on pages and then you can see a list of people
and pages here and you can select from then you can have the option to on them if you want.
So if you made a mistake on the message and say hey why did you ban me then you can ban them if it was
a genuine and comments.
But as you can see I've been quite a few people so this ban comments are a real thing on Facebook and
if you have a Facebook page is something they just want to moderate to really keep your Facebook page
looking good and helpful to your target audience now as well as being able to Un-Band people what you
can do in your settings section under the general section is hardy in a couple of more settings just
to keep your comments section helpful and family friendly.
So if we moved then you can see that there is a profanity filter.
Right now I've just kind of turned all known seems to now.
But if you were getting some kind of hate comments or just not good comments that reflect in your business
you can increase the profanity filter to medium that's going to filter out a lot of typical hate words.
Or you can even then put it up strong.
Maybe start a medium and move up to strong if you need to.
Personally I haven't had a problem with that but it's something that is built into Facebook to help
people with that the need is now moving on.
Dan am we can see there was an option here you can restrict countries or different ages if you want
as well.
And there was one other option I wanted to show you here which was yes the page moderation.
So you can actually block certain words from your page if you see them coming up quite a lot.
They could even be competitors names potentially.
But if there are certain words like see S.K. things like that you can fill in the blanks.
You could easily just block that right.
And if they are caught by the profanity filter so that's another setting within Facebook page that can
really help you keep it clean keep the family friendly.
So that is really a couple of additional settings that you can turn on if you want to really moderate
those comments and in terms of reviews We'll come back to our Facebook page you can see in the sidebar
here click reviews and then here you can respond to reviews on your Facebook page if you want and we
can be filtered by most helpful most recent.
And you can even filter them damn with a star rating and you can have a look at the lowest ones essentially
and respond to those people on this page.
I personally don't respond to the reviews because a lot a lot of them are coming in but particularly
I think for a local business or hotel or restaurant and I think it is important to show that you are
listening and that potentially are taking action to resolve that problem.
So you could respond back say this.
This was a two star review and it was of her hotel and they said breakfast was cold than you could say
something like.
Thanks very much for your feedback Mark.
Sorry to hear that your breakfast was an up to what you expected and it was a bit cold.
We are implementing steps to make sure that doesn't happen again for future guests.
So it's a way to turn a negative review into a positive because you are really showing the reviewer
that you listen to their feedback and you've taken action and you're trying to correct it from other
people and instantly their perception of your business will improve dramatically because they'll say
OK hey they made a mistake but at least they're trying to make it better.
And when they talk to friends they might say actually that place wasn't too bad and they might even
upgrade their rating based on your productivity to help solve those problems.
So once again to respond to those reviews you can just come in here and respond to those if you want
and pay particular attention to those negative reviews.
If you do have a low score and you want to get a lot higher now on average as I said and anything above
4.6 is probably very positive.
But here it's four point eight.
If your ratings so high.
Well maybe there isn't a need to spend time in this but if it's dropping a bit low.
Then take that action and actually implement those things in your business as well.
So that is really how you moderate comments on reviews on your Facebook page.
Now that you know had to do is go ahead and do that for yourself.
It's just those settings if you need or implement these steps for any coins that you have or for your
companies page.