Adding coworkers freelancers or clients to a YouTube channel that you have created is very simple.
First you just want to log into your YouTube accounts under your personal profile.
Then once inside you want to click on the icon for your channel and come down to switch it Cance.
It's in here that you're going to see all of the YouTube channels that you've created or are the owner
for.
And so what you want to do is just click on the channel that you want to on.
Owners or managers to once you see that you're logged into that channel you want to click the icon again
and come down into settings.
In here you'll see the option to add or remove.
Managers.
So just click on that and click again on managed permissions.
You can see here that you're on the primary owner and if I do want to invite new users I can just click
on this icon.
Then you just want to put in the email address of your colleague.
Who are clients and then you want to choose a role.
There are three options owner manager and communications manager.
Now if you want to get more details on what all these mean you can just click on the learn more and
you can scroll down to see them here.
In most cases though an owner is going to be appropriate.
If you're leaving a company and you want to hand full ownership back to a colleague or if you created
a YouTube channel for a client and you want to hand it back to them they can then afterwards remove
you as an owner if they don't want you to have access.
Managers is probably most appropriate then for colleagues so that they can upload videos respond to
common success.
Tara So once you decided the role you just need to select this and then hit invite and see put their
email address in and they will get a notification.
So that is how you add owners or managers to YouTube channel that you've created.