In this video you're going to learn how to create your account on Twitter.
So to get started go to Twitter to come on.
If you're brand new we really want to be filling up this box here that says Sign up.
So if you are signing up for a business account Well then you really want to put it in your business
name.
I'll just put in demo for the moments and then you want to put in your business email address and then
you really want to go ahead and create a strong password for yourself.
So we've got our details here then we just click sign up then you'll be asked to fill in a phone number.
You can do that if you want or go ahead and click skip the next step then is to choose a username and
the great thing is that you can always change this later so don't worry about it too much but you may
see this option here if you put in your own name or a business name that this user name is already taken.
So you may need to be a little bit a bit creative here about how to adjust this.
You will get some suggestions down here but it's probably best to ignore these because you don't want
a big string of numbers in your username so you can try it a different thing.
Couple of things you could maybe put in something like the official afterwards that may be taken.
You can put it in things like Q Or you can use maybe another word at the start to the end until you
find something that is really going to be free.
So once you're happy with your username you can just click next and remember again you can always change
this later on.
So we're glad you're here.
Let's go now you will be asked what you're interested in and you're going to select a couple of these
things here.
Technology tech news.
Let's see.
And then really continue there.
You can add your friends to Facebook if you want from GMO or I'd look if you want to that you can.
I'm just going to click.
No thanks.
Then you can really start to follow so McCants I'm just going to answer like these.
And we should be able to just continue through their.
And here we go.
They've kind of have a tour where you can go in and they'll walk you through the process.
For now I'll just skip that.
You'll also see that you'll need to confirm your email in order to get set up.
But that's really it.
That is how you create your can for your personal brand or a business on Twitter it's the first step
in getting front in front of the 300 million active monthly users on Twitter.
So now that you know how to set up your Twitter it can go ahead and do it for yourself following the
steps that you've learnt in this video.