In this video you're going to learn one of the most effective marketing strategies out there.
You can use it right away.
Even if you've no audience I've used it personally here to get on a podcast that gets over two million
unique downloads a month.
I've used it to be featured on other blogs that has thousands of email subscribers and the exact target
audience that I want to get in front of.
And it is called the poster boy formula.
Now I originally found out a it is through this site video fruit Brian Harris is the author there.
So I'm going to link this article because he explains it really well.
But I do want to add my own twist and show you specifically how I've used it.
So there are four steps to this strategy.
Firstly pick a target.
So choose a company with a target audience.
So for me I knew that this podcast had my target audience people who want to start a business people
who want to market.
I also know that this company has a really MCO CEO companies web designers digital marketing agencies.
These are their audience not the exact audience that I wanted to get in front of.
Now we have to document everything.
This is the key part of the strategy for you to become a poster boy for them essentially a case study
for them.
You need to record a one big win with their product or service.
And the more details the better.
So to get on this podcast what I actually did was I recorded a YouTube video showing how I use one of
their products.
This was a journal that helps you to complete a big goal of yours.
And I really made this quick video.
It was less than one minute long just explaining how I'd use their products and how would it helped
me to create a big course in 100 days.
That was a huge achievement for me at the time.
And this journal really helped me to do it.
So I just created this video.
I shared it with them through their email and then boom they got in touch with me and wanted me on the
podcast.
Now the second option here.
How what big win did I record.
Well these guys they have a white label SVOD tool.
If I show you it here this is what it looks like.
You can put it on your site and through this tool I was able to collect 12000 leads or email addresses.
So again what I did is I just got in touch with them and said hey you know I've had amazing results
with you were with your tool.
Let me share my stories to your your potential customers and your customers can really understand how
to use it.
And that's the key thing.
And that's really why you're being a poster boy because you're showing how you how you got this big
win.
And of course they're going to want to have you on the podcast.
Of course there.
I don't want to write a blog post about it because you were an example to show their potential customers
on their existing customers about the potential of their product and service and what it can do if it's
implemented in the right way.
So the key thing about this strategy is really creating a success story.
And of course you're going to want to share that because everybody wants to share success stories to
really convince their audience that what they have created actually gets results.
If you put it to work now step three in the process is let them know.
So as I said I just sent this video to them thought that would definitely catch attention.
Send it by email and also then I just got in touch here with the option for guest posting a lot of sites
will have the email available and you can easily contact people through LinkedIn etc..
Now prepare for traffic.
So have a high volume downloadable downloadable on your site in order to capture the traffic.
So this is what I did.
I actually didn't do a particular downloadable but I offered a coupon to my course which is essentially
what I was what was the call to action at the end of the podcast.
People get a coupon discount to enroll similarly for this article as well I gave them the option to
click three straight through.
Now the great thing about this is as well as getting traffic as well as building relationships with
these top influencers.
I also got a back link to my site and that is extremely valuable to get from a very high authority site
like this.
So this is poster boy formula not only gets you traffic not only gets in front of your target audience
not only helps you build relationships with these big influencers but you also get that SEO advantage
by getting this back link to your site from a huge site.
So it is an extremely powerful strategy is only four steps to it.
And the key thing is then to just really pick a but it's going to be different for every type of business.
You know it's going to be this blog podcast.
Maybe not this blog but every company will want to share a success story whether that's at a conference
maybe all flying whether it's just via Twitter when they retreat to whether it's on Facebook whether
it's they bring you on to Facebook Live video whether it's they bring you on to whatever it can be the
application where it actually appears can be slightly different depending on your industry.
But think about what are the products that you've used that have a similar audience to you and maybe
suppliers maybe people are not direct competitors but they're kind of friendly.
And so really think about what are the things that you could get a big win out of and share the success
story with and you don't have to be using the product in these cases I actually was.
But you can really search out people who have their audience just look at what products they have or
what wins you could share and be quite strategic about it.
You don't all automatically necessarily need to be using their product or service.
You can actually go and use it with the intention of creating a win story and then using the poster
boy formula.
So I linked this article does a few more details there but I've had amazing results out of it and I
highly recommend use the poster boy formula as well.