In this video you're going to learn how to use one of the latest features from Google Analytics.
It's called analytics intelligence and this is a very impressive development from Google Analytics.
They have built this feature using machine learning to help the better understand and act on your data.
There's two main parts to this.
Featuring Google Analytics.
You can get answers to plain-English questions and we'll go through some examples of those and they
even suggest questions that you can ask and also as well as that they have an insight section and really
want this analytics intelligence does this inside's part is that they'll crawl through your data and
surface insights on any major changes or opportunities that you should be aware of.
So let's have a look at some of these for example so I can see a notification here that I have a SightSpeed
issue.
And then the top page loads slower now.
So we click into this.
It gives me more information on this.
It says this exact page on my web site is loading slower meaning that it's taking longer for people
to access the page.
And that has changed quite dramatically in the last month.
So in October it was reasonable but now it's become much longer loge load speed in the last month.
So that's something that I need to go and investigate.
And it's just very helpful for me to really understand what this is what the changes and even I get
an explanation of why this is important.
So it's essentially like having your own personal google this assistant who is surfacing this information
for you and bringing it to your attention.
And one thing I did actually want to show you here is if you see an issue like that you can save the
inside and you can go and look at that later.
So it can be useful to go through a lot of these different inside's you can read all them here again
or you can just focus on the new ones and you can also see see those saved ones that you've seen.
So let's have a look at some of these other insights.
I can see even at opportunities that I can maybe really work on.
For example it's saying that referral traffic from this particular site is performing better than other
referral traffic.
It says that the average session duration is longer or not the band's rate is lower.
So those are very good signals that this is a good web site that is sending me quality traffic.
And so if I want to grow my business and get more ideal customers to my web site then I can focus on
growing this particular marketing channel or getting more referral traffic from this site.
Similarly I can see another source of traffic which is not performing as well.
The base rate is higher than the average and the session duration is shorter so maybe I can focus on
that one.
We have a bit more information about that loading speed issue here as well.
It's telling me the exact page you can and showing me a comparison to the other top five line pages
those pages that Soman is coming into my website on.
So again just extremely helpful.
It's like having your own Google Analytics assistant really telling you what you should be focusing
on now as well as them surfacing these type of insights and opportunities.
You can also go ahead and just type in any questions into the search bar here.
So let's have a look and show you a couple of the examples of these just to see the range of questions
that you can pass this on medic's intelligence.
So let's start to ask some questions here.
If we click on the search bar here we can actually see some of the questions here that I've asked before
and we'll have a look at those and they also suggest some questions that you can ask as well.
It's kind of a different icon.
So you can really type in plaining and ish questions here.
And let's start with something pretty basic.
Like many users did we get yesterday.
And I can see 723 users yesterday on that particular day.
Okay and that's pretty cool.
Let's have a look at something different because we don't just get single numbers like that.
We can actually get graphs as well as a trend of new users
new users
this month so you can also get that graphical representation as well of different pieces of information.
You can also compare different things.
So here's what I asked earlier.
Conversion Rate of referrals versus organic search.
So I can see by looking at this information that my referral traffic is actually converting better than
my organic search traffic.
So maybe I want to continue to build that referral traffic seeing as it is converting and getting more
people to complete the goals of my web site than organic search.
Now we can look at say percentage questions or percentage of users on desktop
and here we can see that eighty eight point to 2 percent of visitors over the last week were on desktop.
So as you can see you can really just keep asking as many questions.
Not every question is going to have a perfect answer and if it isn't helpful you can just click no.
This one was sold just click yes.
And as more people contribute feedback and ask questions and say yes or no if it's helpful it's just
going to just become better and better and as I said it's like having your own personal Google Analytics
expert who is showing you you know what to do in order to grow your site and optimize your site.
So to recap unlikes intelligence is a new feature from Google Analytics and I think it does really highlight
how interactive and useful Google Analytics can be on why you should really take time to set it up correctly
and to learn how to use it.