In this video you're going to learn about Facebook video that's why you should be using them as part
of your Facebook advertising campaigns.
You're going to learn three tips to create powerful videos the use cases for them and step by step how
you can create a video ad very very quickly and easily.
Now the first question you might have is why should I be using video ads as part of my Facebook advertising.
And the reason is very very simple.
There has been an explosion in the consumption of video content on both Facebook and Instagram.
And the proof of that is right inside of your Facebook news feed.
If you come into your Facebook news feed you're going to see that almost every second post is now a
video.
This is the format of content that people are consuming on Facebook.
Now this is the big trend and the reality is is that a lot of advertisers haven't caught up with this.
So if you want to get ahead of the competition using video ads is a very good way to do that.
So key question you might have as well is how to create powerful video ads in a great place to really
understand what is inside of the insides of your Facebook page.
So to get here just come into the insides of your Facebook page and down into this tab which shows the
metrics related to videos.
Now you have to have a couple of videos on your Facebook page in order to see these but I'll show you
through a couple of mine samples so you can understand three things that are really important to do.
So once you're in your insides tab you can click in here to an individual video.
And one thing you want to look down on straight away is in the video views here.
And one important thing to look at is the sand off or sand on now watch you can see here is that this
video has got around 1400 views on 78 percent of those views 1200 views were watched with the sound
off.
So you probably noticed this from being on your Facebook feed that a lot of videos now how captions
on them and from this example as well you can see the importance of that.
So my recommendation is that if you are creating a video ad you'd be wise to put some captions on to
the video in order that people can really understand the content when they have the send off.
Now the great news is it is very easy to add captions.
You can just come back to your post edit the post you'll see the option here for captions.
You can order generate the captions just by clicking on a button here.
I've done an already certain that says edit captions and you can watch the captions that are auto generated
and really edit them to make sure that they work there correct.
So if you have a video on your Facebook page and you want to promote it best good action to take straight
away is to come in update those captions make sure they're all OK and then save them to the video.
Now the second tip is to really understand the average watched time of videos so you can see here that
this video is one minute and thirty four seconds and the average watch time is just 12 seconds.
If you click through here you can see a chart for audience retention which is really how long the average
person watched the video and you can see here as I move down 100 people watched the first two seconds.
But as I go down to say 10 seconds here you can see that already 60 percent of people have stopped watching
the video.
So watch this show be signaling to you is that the first five seconds 10 seconds are critical if you're
creating a video and you're not capturing people's attention or to quite question or a fact or some
figures or something.
Nice imagery.
Then you are going to lose because a lot of people watch past that and you probably know this from your
own Facebook browsing that you will see a video coming up maybe in the news feed you might watch a couple
of seconds with the sound off if it doesn't look interesting.
You're not going to continue on if it does look interesting.
Might read the captions or flick the sound on and that is generally more people do.
So having a powerful first five 10 seconds and putting some thought into that or if you're cutting down
a video make sure that you're coding it in a place where the first couple of seconds are really going
to capture attention.
So the second tip make sure those first five ten seconds really grab attention.
Then the final tip is in terms of targeting to look at who's already engaged with existing videos so
I can see for this particular video the top audience was men of this age group here and I can even see
a breakdown of it.
And if I go back as well I can see the top locations as well.
So a lot of people watch this from the U.K. and I can see the other places where it is popular so far
I want to use this video to broaden the reach and put it into Facebook.
I can use this information in order to inform those decisions.
So Tip Three is use existing demographic information to help target your ads.
Now that you understand those three tips to create powerful video ads.
Let's look at the use cases for videos in Facebook advertising.
Now you can use videos in a variety of different campaign objectives in Facebook as you can use videos
to help get up in stores.
You can use videos Helka clicks to Web site.
But the primary objective and the primary use for them is to simply get video views and raise awareness
about your brand.
That's the primary objective for a lot of people when they use videos in their Facebook ads and in terms
of how we can target these ads to where you can use interest demographic targeting.
You can target existing Facebook fans you can remarket to Web site a mobile app for visitors you can
use video views custom audiences and target people who have watched previous videos you can use look
like audiences.
You really have all of those targeting options available to you.
It's really going to depend on your own needs and goals which targeting option that you use.
Now in terms of what content can you use in your video as well you can remix content.
Think one common thing and barrier to making people use videos is they think they need to create something
completely new.
Well if you've a longer video or a longer promotional video or sales video or whatever it is you can
cut that down into smaller videos that you could use as part of your video ads.
So in terms of just raising awareness cutting up bite size videos putting them out.
That's something you can easily do.
You don't have to create brand new content.
You can also use behind the scenes footage stuff that would help your product launch raise awareness
updates on how your product launches going.
You can use customer success stories.
So really there is a huge amount of variety in the types of content that you can use now that you understand
the use cases.
Let's have a look at how you can create a video views campaign.
First step is to log into your ads manager and come up and click on create ad you want to select select
your marketing objective and maybe just start over.
If you have any previous campaigns popping up so in terms of remarketing objective you want to see like
the video views option here and click on continue.
Now in terms of setting up the targeting for your audience here for your placements for your bhajans
and schedule that is all going to be the same process as we've learned previously.
What is a little bit different to where there are some other options are down here at the level of a
video views campaign and I want to point at some of these for you see have the option to use a carousel
here so you can add have an ad with two or more scrollable videos in here.
You can use a single video which is probably the easiest option to use.
You can use a slide show option and this is worth having a little bit of a look out here because you
can create a slide show very very easily and this is perhaps maybe one of the easiest ways that you
can create a video for your Facebook site so you can use 9:57 images to create a slide show and you
can see Facebook is walking you through the process here you click on Slide Show you can select the
image to ration how long you want to last.
One second is probably a good idea.
You can maybe select the fade you can and the photos then using your own images that youve uploaded
or from your own image library or you can use this free stock images once again.
So even if you don't have any good photos you can put together one of these slide show video ads very
very easily.
Now once youve got that done you can just create the slideshow and that is the video you can use for
your campaign.
Now you can also use an existing post has a video.
So just make sure that your Facebook page is connected and then you can scroll down and select any of
these videos for your video.
Once again you might want to just check that you've got those captions on the video before you hit the
publish button.
Finally let's have a look for a look at some of the limitations for your video.
You wonder if you're uploading it yourself a Chevy daughter movie an MP for one high quality or aspect
ratio should be as such in Facebook.
Your video views can be maximum 16 minutes in Instagram the maximum of 60 seconds.
It's a key limiting factor there if you want to place your video on both Facebook and Instagram make
sure it's maximum 60 seconds.
As always when you go to place your iPod.
Just make sure that the text is appropriate.
Maybe show people watch this video and you will learn a four step process to do x y z.
Or watch this video and learn whatever the benefits are of it.
So remember you need to put in the text and really sell the benefits and explain to people quickly why
they should view the video.
Once you've gathered all them as always review the order before you go ahead and place it and it'll
go into the normal review process.
So now you know why you should be using video has 3 tips to create powerful video ads.
The use cases and the pings to look out for when you're setting it up for yourself go ahead and create
a video and following the steps that you've learned in this video.