In this video you're going learn about lead adds a very new and exciting format that Facebook have released.
We'll start by understanding Rini Watervliet it is then we'll look at some of the key benefits of it
and then we're going to look at some case studies in how companies big and small are really getting
amazing results from lead ads in this and would be some really good hands on strategies.
I'll show you in these examples.
And then finally I want to show you how to set it up believe that some of the extra and additional things
you'll need to do when you set that up in the create tool.
So let's start by really understanding what our lead is and a great place to do that is inside the Facebook
guide.
This will give you an overview of all of the type of ads and objectives that are available.
I'll put a link to this in the resources section in this lecture so you can check it out at any time.
And for this particular video we're coming down here to lead generation to look in particular at these
lead.
That's really the purpose of this is to form our out of form to your ad to collect information from
people interested in your business so this is a way that you can collect email addresses phone numbers
for people who are interested in your business and the primary objective is to get those names you can
call them back.
You can put them into a C or M or you can follow up with them.
Now if we look at how it actually looks here you can see that this looks like a normalized nothing looks
any different to maybe a Clix to Web site.
It's just an image that you click on.
However the big difference here is what happens after the click.
And really we look at the odd form here to really understand that.
So what we are seeing here is the full lead form and you can see that there are various steps and screens
in that process.
Once a person clicks through on the and this is the process and the step that they really go through
what we have to start off with is a contact's context card here.
And if we click in here we can see this in more detail.
This is essentially a welcome screen and you can see that there are some explanations about the business
and what happens if they click to get this deal to click to get a consultation to click to get a quote.
It's really explaining some of the terms and conditions and just letting people know what's going to
happen when they submit their e-mail that is optional.
You don't need to put that in there if you want but maybe as lead outs are quite a new odd format this
can be good to include So people really know what's happening after they click through this then they
click get deal they move on to the form itself.
And here's where the magic starts to happen because Facebook has your name and your e-mail your date
of birth and maybe even your phone number.
It will pre fill this form for you.
And that is great for the person who's filling out the form.
A lot of the work is done for them and it's also great for the business because much more people are
going to be likely to hit that submit button.
If all of the work is already done and we know that it's going to be accurate information as well if
people have already submitted it to Facebook.
Once you hit or the person hits the submit button it's on to the next step which again is optional.
A custom disclaimer which you can include.
And then finally there is an end card which really things confirms that the submission has happened.
And it gives people a chance to visit the Web site if they want that.
So as you can see the ARB itself and the image looks normal but this is where the magic is starting
to happen in the lead.
And here are some of the key benefits of having this form.
Here is a quote from our land rover the digital and social media manager who is really talking about
the benefits of the lead.
And I think this really sums it all up.
That's why I want to show to you.
So Facebook natives lead.
I would perform with Link ads driving to the Web site to fill out a lead form in terms of total leads
and conversion rates.
While driving a 4 x reduction in costs per lead compared to previous social lead generation tactics.
So this is the key thing and I think this is important to understand what is the alternative to that.
Well clicks to Web site campaign and encouraging people to fill out a form on the land rover Web site.
In this example you can see that keeping it in Facebook pre-filtering not data is one of the reasons
that they for X their results and that's how powerful lead form is although it seems like a very simple
thing.
Let's start to have a look at some case studies now and see how some big companies are really using
these Livan forms very effectively.
This is Toyota Italy and we can see that they generated two thousand five hundred leads in seven days.
Ninety five percent lower costs than other benchmarks for digital channels and 59 percent of those leads
resulted in test drives so they're not just picking up leads that didn't result in a business outcome.
They are getting a 60 percent conversion on the lead to the action that they want which is pretty amazing
as scrolling down.
Let's look at the actual tactics that they use because this is pretty interesting what a lot what Toyota
actually did is first they started with a video.
And there is an overview of it there.
So the car maker tested a potent combination of video and Leanne's and this is the more tactical strategy
stuff that you can maybe implement for yourself.
So the first thing to do is use a beautifully shot video or a video which really the purpose of was
to build awareness and interest for the new model of their car.
Then what they did is they actually used a lead dad to remarket to the custom audience of 1.7 million
thirty to 65 year old Italians who'd been reached by the video.
So this is a really good strategy and will help you build up a targeted audience to put your dads in
front too.
First you start with a video out showing just creating awareness then you remarket to people who watched
the video out with the lead ads.
That's a very smart strategy.
Any body could use that.
You don't need to be a big car maker like Toyota.
Let's move on to another case study which is a local business the evoke who clinic day two cosmetic
surgeries and stuff like that.
Let's have a look at how they used this.
They use more cord targeting so interest demographics may be people with in the radius of their clinic.
And so you don't need to just use the video views custom audience.
You can also use lead ads based on demographic targeting.
In this case probably targeting women from cosmetic surgeries within a radius of the clinic.
So you can use these lead ads with normal CT targeting or custom audiences as well.
So Nadya you understand the benefits of lead ads and some examples of how to use it in a campaign strategically.
Let's come into the ad manager and look at some of the things that you need to think about when you're
setting this up.
Now like every campaign that you will set up on Facebook you're working through the three levels campaign
ads set on ads at the start at the campaign level.
All you're doing is coming down and selecting the lead generation and then you're just clicking continue.
Now as you get into the onset level all the same steps apply.
You'll want to select an audience you want to select the placements for your god.
You want to select the budget and schedule none of that stuff is different.
It's the same as every other odd format that you use.
However when you come down into the ground level there is an additional step and you can see it and
hear the lead form.
So maybe what I'll do is just set up this image so we can see this properly what I'm going to do is
just in a free stock image and run through a little bit of the text that you might want to use for this.
So here's an image we can use I don't want to give you an example of some of the texts that you could
be using.
So the headline here for example could be get a free
get a free Skype consultation or something like that is it doesn't have to be to get quote.
If you are in the business maybe a digital marketing you are a coach of some sort.
You can get a free 15 minute
Skype consultation I can type OK.
So something like that is something that you could offer to get people to really sign up.
Obviously you can put the text in there as you want.
You can change the call to action put in.
So is it worth it.
Thinking about the headline and what are you actually offering people for them handing over their email
address or phone numbers etc. but the real different part is down here.
This final part the lead form and this is where you really decide and feel like this information for
your own flow here.
So if we come in here you just need to click on a new form.
Then you can see you have these options for the welcome's screen which is optional.
You can see the image from my ad as being pulled through here.
You can write in the text whatever you want and it could be good to come back to these examples here
if you want to get more understanding about what you should maybe put in there when you come down and
then you just put in the questions that you want to ask.
Is it email.
Is there something else that you want to ask people you can add in any custom questions there if you
want private policy again what you want to do is because you're collecting customer information you
will need to include a link to your company's private policy showing that you're not going to be reselling
their information or that type of thing.
So you can put in the linked text and you can put in the link or else if you want that it to appear
a little bit easier.
You can put that in there.
And the real thing to go to is here if you also wanted to track how many people actually click through
you could use UTM tracking and then have your looking link there.
Really click and see how many people actually click through and read that.
You can also add in a custom disclaimer which as we saw here is optional once again.
And then finally you can putting your time cues screen and put in the link to your Web site so that
at the final stages people can click through and go to your Web site if they want to read more and you
can put that into any particular length that you want.
So you might set up a unique page about buyers by the offer that you're giving people maybe more information
about what they can expect.
Or a link to your services page.
In my example if I was giving a free consultation I could send them to maybe some success stories or
maybe further information on the packages that I offer so that before we even get on the free call or
whatever it is that you're offering they have a sense of what you offer so that you understand what
leads.
Odds are the benefits of of them and how to tactically use them in your campaigns.
Go ahead and set one up for yourself.
Following the steps that you've learned in this video.