In this video you are going to learn about Instagram odds and how you can reach 150 million daily active
users on Instagram through the Facebook platform.
We'll start by understanding a little bit more about instruments and when and where you can use them.
They're not available for every single objective so that's worth just reviewing quickly.
And then we're just going to start jumping into some case studies and looking at how some real life
businesses are using Instagram as part of their campaigns and I've got a number of examples here to
go through quickly and then we want to finish up looking inside the ads create to about how you can
select for your campaigns to appear on Instagram and some of the requirements and restrictions that
you think about an order of your content if you want to do that.
So let us start by looking at the Facebook guide here which is always a great place to start to understand
different formats and objectives.
And the key thing to understand straight away about Instagram is that Instagram ads are not a completely
separate thing.
You don't have one particular objective if you want to use an Instagram account.
They are really just one of the five places where your Facebook ads can appear and where you can choose
for your Facebook ads to appear.
So here are the five here your mobile news feed on Facebook your desktop news feed for Facebook.
The right hand column on Facebook on Instagram as well and the audience networks.
So those are the five different places.
Remember Instagram is just one of the five places you could create a campaign where your ad only appears
on Instagram.
But if you want to do that just remember that you can't use Instagram as a placement option for all
of the out objectives and I want to quickly go through that with you because there are some limitations
on that.
So in terms of if you wanted to promote app engagement you can do that on Instagram as well.
There's no problem.
Opon.
Great place to do that on Instagram and as possible clicks to Web sites.
You can get people to click on a link in Instagram and go to your Web site.
Here's where here's a couple of examples where you can use Instagram as a place to show your ads lead
generation for now and lead ads are only available in the Facebook dustoff news feed in the Facebook
mobile news feed.
Now this will probably change over time.
So always good idea to come back into the Facebook's guide and just type it into Google to find it to
check if Instagram is available for the ad objective that you were really aiming for.
Another place where Instagram is not available as a placement for ads is Page Likes.
And this is probably pretty obvious.
But if you want to get more likes for your page you're going to be much more successful doing that on
Facebook itself and you can see that those are the options right now just for that.
You want to get web site conversions and drive people to the store.
You could do that on Instagram as well.
So good to know some of the limitations for Instagram and using it as part of your odds.
Now that we understand those ins and outs let's have a look at some case studies and really understand
how people are using Instagram as part of their campaign.
So we have put a video bracelets here and we can come down and see the ads here on both Facebook and
Instagram.
And if we scroll down a little bit there is quite an interesting quote here from the CEO and co-founder
who says that they use lookalike audiences to reach people like our Web site visitors.
So they're using custom web site audience and they want to reach people on both Instagram and Facebook.
And here's really the interesting part for you.
Our cost per order for instruments is the same as it is for Facebook ads.
So in fact Instagram has expanded our ability to drive orders and revenue from our website visitors
and new customers.
So that's the key thing to understand the advantage in this case of instruments was not that they're
10 times cheaper or anything like that.
It's that they allow you to extend the reach of your campaign to that massive Instagram audience.
Let's have a look at another example to see how people are using Instagram ads as part of their campaigns.
You've got wonder here which is a app and they wanted to accelerate sign ups in the Philippines.
Now once again you'll see here that they didn't use Instagram in isolation.
It was really part of a bigger campaign.
And you can see here that the team extended the campaign to include Instagram ads and the audience network
which allowed them to drive sign ups beyond Facebook.
And you can see that they use a lot of different type of ads like carousel.
They use the conversion trapping video ads so you can use that as part of your instagram placement.
Let's have a look at another example here.
Mentor Danmark which is a Danish tutoring company.
What these guys did is they really focused on video arts to raise awareness about their tutoring company
and then to support these.
They used photo wants on Instagram to showcase some of these personal bonds so you can see them here.
So in this case once again you can see that the Instagram was more of a supporting role for this bigger
campaign.
Let's finish up in the ads created here crystal clear on how to include or exclude Instagram from your
campaigns.
I'll select the example of creating a campaign to get some video views continue with this and then we
come into the Azza level and this is the place where you really decide where your ads will be placed
under the Plaisance section here.
Now what may surprise you is that by default your odds will actually appear on Instagram.
You can see that by default all odds are placed automatically which is recommended mean that your odds
will automatically be shown to your audience in the places they're likely to perform best and the places
where they will appear are those five places that we saw at the beginning of this video.
Facebook feeds the right hand column Instagram on the audience networks.
So by default your ad is appearing on Instagram if you select this option.
Now you may be surprised I would say hang on I don't have an Instagram account so how is that happening.
What Facebook will actually do is pull the profile image from your Facebook page and the name and present
that as an Instagram account on Instagram in an ad so you don't have to do anything to start advertising
on Instagram which is really handy.
Now if you want to exclude Instagram from your ad campaigns or focus on it alone you just need to comment
edit placements.
For example I can remove Instagram.
Soon my ads won't appear there.
I can select Instagram and remove everything else and then my adult only appear on Instagram.
Now if you select that option or you want to include Instagram There are a couple of other things that
you need to look out for and that really is in relation to the content of your AD.
So for example if I select a single video that I want to promote here's one thing you want to watch
out for.
If you want to use a video in your campaign on Instagram it can only be 60 seconds max.
So if you want to promote a video on Facebook on Instagram make sure it's just 60 seconds so it can
appear in both places and that's simply it very simple to include Instagram as part of your campaigns.
Remember it's not a stand alone odd that has a unique objective.
It can fit into almost all of the objectives with some of the restrictions we talked about and it's
just one of the five places your odds can appear so now that you understand much more about Instagram.
Think about how you can use them as part of your next campaign.