In this video you're going to learn about event response sides and how you can promote your event with
Facebook ads.
So you get more response and have a successful event.
We'll start by really understanding what events responses are and some of the benefits of them.
Then we will look and get some examples and understand some of the copy that you can use for these type
of ads to make them more successful.
We're going to look at a couple of case studies here just to get some ideas in terms of targeting and
other type of event ads we could set up that we'll look into Facebook and show you how to set up an
event on your Facebook page.
That's the first thing you need to do before you can actually promote it.
And then we will finish up once again inside the ads create to walk you through the process of setting
up events response.
And some of the things to look for when doing so.
So what is an event response.
Well it's as the name suggests you're really promoting your event to get more people to attend.
Now that could be an opening day.
It could be a launch of a product line in store.
But this is all going to happen off line these are off line events that we're really talking about here.
No as I said the first thing to do is create an event directly from your Facebook page and then you
spread the word with the adverts and you can choose your audience.
It can be based on age gender interest location you can use custom audiences as well.
And when a person joins your event or shows your interest it will automatically be added to their calendar
on Facebook.
So by promoting your event you're going to boost the awareness of it you're going to allow people to
say they're coming in a very simple way and then you have all of the insights and analytics on your
Facebook page to understand how many people are coming how many people have accepted as well.
So it's kind of it and a bad management solution as well.
Let's start to dig into some of the examples and have a look at what these really look like.
So I'm inside of the Facebook Ads guide you can come here anytime you want.
Just type it into Google and have a look at these great examples so you can see join us.
That's probably a good piece of copy to start with.
Join us at our Open House we'll be dishing at famous apple pie to show our thanks.
So there's a great free incentive for people to come in and you can see that there is a nice picture
of the event that's relevant.
You have a date here.
Very easy to see the time.
You can also see how many people are interested in going and how many are confirmed that they're actually
going.
So this is what looks like a desk top.
This is what it looks like on the news feed.
Here now let's have a look at a couple of case studies now in this case study.
They don't actually use this event response feature but I thought it was pretty interesting to just
look at some of the targeting that they did for this so they were really promoting ticket sales.
They did it in a slightly different way.
But you can see that the main target for their campaigns was a custom audience created from people who
have likes their Facebook page also ice hockey fans an online ticket buyer database that was there people
who'd bought the tickets previously.
And then what they also did is they targeted ads to a lookalike audience based off of this custom audience
so for your own event when you're setting that up you can target people who are your Facebook fans.
Create a custom audience for that.
You can create people who are interested in what you're offering.
And also if you've any customers you can target them as well from that database he can combine a number
of custom audiences into one audience for this campaign and then you can also in a separate set build
a look alike audience based off that as well.
So I wanted to show you this just to give you some ideas in terms of the targeting for this type of
event response.
Now let us look at another case study here's this from Miami Dolphins.
And again they were really trying to to to get people to an event and this event wasn't actually a game.
It was a tour of its new stadium.
And really what they did here was they generated 4600 high quality leads.
Now what was the goal of this.
Well the goal was to ultimately drive new season ticket memberships.
So a pretty smart strategy.
It is an event essentially it's a tour they have that incentive to get people involved.
Maybe like the the free apple pie that we've seen.
But really the goal was to drive those season ticket memberships.
Now once again they didn't actually use the event response feature.
But what they did is that they run a number of lead ads in inviting fans of the Facebook page I guess
to sign up for the new tour stadium.
So I wanted to show you this example just to show you that you don't have to just use the event response
feature to really create these type of ads.
You can be pretty creative in terms of using the lead ads as well.
If it's something more like you need their details and you want to keep the numbers down you can also
use the event response.
And if it's quite an open event and you don't need to really manage the numbers like you would here.
Now let's look into a Facebook page because the first thing you need to do to create an event response
is to actually create an event to come into your Facebook page and down on the side bar on the left
hand side here you can see events just click on that then you just need to go ahead and click Create
event.
Now you will you can change this photo as you want.
You can edit the name as always these fill these fields are really going to be dependent on the event
that you're setting up.
So you just put in your band name location the day that's perfect tomorrow.
And any details category's about if you want to include this stuff so maybe people think they can really
understand what this type of event is you can put a description and some keywords in there you can say
if it's kid friendly and free admission important things to to out in if people need to buy tickets
or even just reserve a ticket.
You can pop that in there and there are loads of online services where you can get you know free ticketing.
You can just look them up on Google in terms of cohosts and you can add people to help manage this.
Now here's a cool thing that you can do instead of publishing it straightaway to your page you might
want to work on it for a little bit maybe show some colleagues as you can save the drafts
and maybe show this to some colleagues work on it is a clear.
Are those exact dates we want to work from now.
Once you do publish what you want to do then is push it through the organic channels onto you know get
people posting on your Facebook page encourage people to to share to friends.
Then you can come in to your Facebook ads create two and really start to promote it through Facebook
ads so what is your marketing objective.
It's going to be engagement here.
And we're really looking at an event response here so selecting agent event response and click continue.
Now in terms of the audience for this as we said in this example here you could select a custom audience
so web site custom Orlean's people have engaged with your Facebook page youve talked about setting those
up before she can include numerous ones here if you want your local audience even except to trust you
like this example of the at Elsy Hage line here you can add that in and coming back here you can even
include location interests etc as well.
So weve gone through those type of things previously to him setting up your audience in terms of your
placements.
Then you can set these up as we discussed before your budget and schedule and identity and format this
is the piece thats a little bit different for this type of.
And you can see you have to select the Facebook page that you're promoting and then if I publish that
event that will be showing up here and or I could just paste the URL straight in.
So in order for the events to show up here it personally has to be published.
So that's really the steps.
But from there it's fairly straightforward you just need to enter the text as usual and there's nothing
really different then from there on Cinelli you understand what event response ads are the copy that
you can use targeting options and even some alternatives on how to set it up inside the ads create to
go ahead and set one up for yourself.
If you want to reach more people who are likely to attend your next event.