That once you have distributed your survey the next step is to analyze the responses and you can analyze
them right here inside Google Forms.
Just click over the responses tab and you can see the different responses to your questions plus any
e-mail addresses that were submitted.
So you can analyze them here and this can be fun to look at as the responses are coming in.
But what I would recommend you do is wait and see when the responses stop coming in.
You'll notice that because this number stops going up and that will probably be one to two days depending
on how much you've promoted the survey.
So to look at it in a deeper level and really analyze it I would recommend you view the responses in
Google sheets.
Open that up right away.
And the first thing that you want to do is select the top row here on what you want to do is really
put on a filter.
And the reason you want to do this is because we want to filter down our responses and really just look
at the responses that say people have a problem that they find very difficult to resolve.
Now why are we doing that.
Well remember we if we want to create a successful product or service or even a piece of content like
a blog post or video we need to be solving problems that are not well solved in the marketplace.
And that's why we why we really want to focus on this and you can see if we scroll down here just to
the third response give you a visual we can see that around 30 40 percent of the answers.
People said it's a very difficult problem for them to solve.
So by just filtering that there we removed 60 percent of the problems that people don't think are that
important or not that hard to solve.
And we're just focusing on at 40 percent which for this survey is about 80 responses as opposed to over
200.
So just makes it easier to analyze it as well.
And the next thing you want to do is go ahead and open up a different tab here.
You can use that like that.
What we're going to do in this tab is just write down problem and why resolves.
So these are two important things that we want to get out of this survey.
When we look at it we want to know what the problem actually is and why it's going to be important for
them to resolve it so that really come from these two columns.
So let's just go on have a look at it here.
So again not every response is going to be perfect so you're going to just have to go through one by
one and through them and pick them.
So let's see the problem here.
What's your biggest challenge.
Can you show me the most direct path towards getting a minimal viable product in the marketplace.
Okay.
That's a great problem to solve.
So what we can do is I always like to frame the problems as like how to delete this when I did earlier.
So we can start fresh.
And while we can just pop this in
and what I like to think about is if I was writing this as a course or a piece of content or you'd like
a blog post or a YouTube video what would the title be.
It's always just easiest to started but had to.
So how to get a minimal viable product into the marketplace let's say in one day because they're looking
for speed.
That's what they said in their response here.
Let me get back to this.
OK.
It would save me save time and aggravation.
So that's a benefit.
I'm going to close this down actually because I keep thinking back to it.
So you know why would they why do they want to resolve this why would they buy our product or read a
blog post to save time and aggravation.
And they're really looking for a streamlined process.
So that's another benefit of them maybe buying our product or service or reading or blog posts so get
a streamlined process so you can see already here.
Just reading one response what I've got first for me is a potential course that I could make or even
a potential section or lecture within a course of potential blog posts a potential YouTube video that
is tailored to my audience and that would really resolve a problem that they have.
What are some of the benefits that I could mention at the start of the video or course or put on a sales
page or in a Facebook ad.
Look this is going to save you time and aggravation.
You're going to get a streamlined process to get a minimal viable product into the marketplace in one
day.
That's a very good pitch an offer and it resolves a pain point that people have.
So that's only one answer.
Now let's go down and have a look.
OK.
All beginning again same process I'm just going to do three of these to give you examples of what you
should be looking for.
And then obviously your responses are going to be different so hard to obtain and Kline's trust I guess
as a digital marketer is really what they're asking here.
And why would they want to do this you know grow your business steadily.
That's.
That's why they want to resolve this because they think trust is a big barrier to signing clients.
And that's true.
How can you get them to trust you.
They're going to hand over money and access to you know their analytics or whatever.
So this is a big barrier for a lot of people how do you overcome that.
That could be a great lecture or a course or a blog post or whatever could be a great Something piece
of sales coffee on a course or Facebook gods.
Again you just copy and paste this is the why this process is so beautiful powerful because there's
very little work for you to do.
Once you start to analyze this.
So let's have a look here this looks interesting.
How does Voice Search affect SEO.
This could be something interesting.
You know how to hide two benefits.
Moyses SEO maybe
or two ranked number one
phone voice the CEO on mobile.
Safe for example.
So I'm just thinking about you know what does the have to look like to resolve that problem.
And why would they want to do this.
You know leverage voice
leverage voice voices the show to get to that leverage voices here in NY to get free traffic to your
site.
So you can see I'm using what I'm hearing from the customer here and adding how you know putting my
spin on why they would want to do that.
And this allows me just looking at three responses to find products and services that people desperately
need and will pay money for and also gather powerful sales copy that I can use on my sales page and
Facebook ads in emails and other marketing materials.
So that is the process to analyze your survey results in order to find those product ideas and get that
powerful sales copy.