In this video you're going to learn about Facebook Marketing Partners and the huge ecosystem that has
grown up around the Facebook platform was Starpower really understanding what Facebook Marketing Partners
are or FM Pease's they're known for short.
And then you start going to start individually looking at some of these to really understand why you
would need to use one of these Facebook Marketing Partners and the value that they're really bringing
to the table.
So let's start for really understanding what these Facebook Marketing Partners are.
Well the key thing is that they're not just agencies.
This is not a list of agencies that you can use.
These are actually marketing partners who have additional technology features or services that are built
on top of the Facebook platform.
See you could maybe compare it to something like either or both for that you might be used to using
on social media.
It's a similar type of volume that's built on top of the Facebook platform and really connected into
it through an API as you can see here there are only 171 partners so it's quite a small number of partners.
And there are a number of different categories of partners as well.
Specialisations is what they call them.
So the technology community management content marketing small business solutions audience onboarding
audience data providers and measurements.
Let's just take a look at these small business solutions because you might be familiar with some of
these names on espresso our role in constant contact.
Now the key thing about these Facebook Marketing Partners is if you are just advertising for your own
business you may not ever need to use these and you don't need to understand them in a lot of detail.
But if you are working in the industry in an agency or in a company you maybe need to understand at
least what these are so that you can engage conversations about them.
So let's jump straight into actually looking at some of these individually to really understand the
value.
And some of the reasons why you might consider using them.
So the first one here is our espresso and this is actually by now the key advantage of our espresso
and it's listed right here in the home page is that it makes AB testing painless and the key thing is
that you can create thousands of variants of your Facebook ads in only three clicks.
So an example of how this might work is there is three fields.
They just put in they say put in three different headlines and they automatically create three different
odds based off that.
Or you just upload three images and then they automatically create three Cadsoft that.
So it's a way to really automate the process of HIV testing and it has a better interface that's really
geared around.
The thing that we have to remember is that the odds create two or the power editor tool is really designed
to serve all of the marketing objectives in one interface.
It's really at a platform to serve every single person.
Whereas a lot of these platforms are really broken down to focus in on a particular feature like AB
testing on Hazon interface that's more geared around that and makes it much easier to do.
Now in terms of some of these Facebook Marketing Partners an honest person in particular let's have
a look at the pricing for some of these.
So we can see that the base is $49 per month.
You are Facebook Ads Ben is up to 3000 and you can see all the features there.
Then it goes up to 150 and then to 9.
So I think for a lot of these Facebook Marketing Partners the best practice is to make sure you have
proven your aura y inside Odd's create two or power Ed..
And then once you got that done and you want to start to automate it and make it an easier thing to
do and scale then you will start to use partners like this.
Let's look at another example.
Drif track here and these guys are pretty interesting and they focus down on really lead generation.
So if we come into our odds create tool here we can see that this is just one single marketing objective
and this is what these guys really focus on.
And they have built bigger solution to really support the whole life cycle of the generation.
So in terms of acquiring them not just from Facebook but also from Instagram and rolling in lead forms.
Then in terms of what do you do afterwards converting them and there's all sorts of really trainings
and guidelines and all of that stuff to really get those leads converted so really building a whole
solution around that one marketing objective.
Now let's look at another example of a Facebook marketing partner which is Wallner and this really helps
with content creation and what Walter does is helps you find exceptional Instagram content creators
for your brand.
So it's really providing a simple structure a safe marketplace to collaborate with.
Instant Instagram content creators so Centier sourcing content creation you upload a brief you send
it to creators.
You agree on who it's going to be and then you prove the content.
And that's really a marketplace.
In order to do that and outsource some content creation work.
Let's move on to another example here which is a smartly Daddario And once again these guys are really
focusing down on one particular thing and objective and Naish really which is e-commerce that is the
key additional features that I have that they have are really around dynamic adds and scaling this on
automating this whole process.
So we can see in this example here that a Norwegian mobile phone provider started automating their advertising
after running Facebook on its mind for a number of years and I think this is the key phrase to really
think about.
You would never consider using these guys straight away once youve kind of proven your understanding
of it and proven in worldwide then you go to automate it because I think the price tag on this is something
like that ties and dollars and want a minimum level.
So these are definitely for bigger bigger companies.
Next up weve got an odd row and you might have heard about these guys before and not know exactly what
they do but they really focus in on retargeting now as we looked at it in the course this is just one
of the many things that she can do.
They really focus in on and thats the core of their business and they enabling you to reach your customers
everywhere and serve personalized ads across devices.
On the odd roll premium network including 500 networks and exchanges so it's not just for Facebook on
Instagram.
So for Twitter Tumblr AOL Google Linked-In etc. So that is really what they do focus on retargeting
across all networks not just the Facebook network.
Finally we have constant contact and you may have heard of these guys before they really focus and are
known for email marketing but their Facebook marketing partner as well are hooked in.
And I find an interesting case today just to highlight some of the things that they can do here.
So from this case city because they were integrated with the platform.
Constant Contact automatically Puplick populates odds with copy an image is drawn from email campaigns
so that really allows you to use previous email campaigns to populate odds and you will probably understand
which of those email accounts delivered the bass which headlines etc..
So its a way of really connecting these things together.
Now that you know what Facebook Marketing Partners are youll be able to discuss them at work or in business
and you can come in anytime to the Facebook marketing partner directory.
Look at all these guys individually if you wanted to take them on and use them as saw as part of your
Facebook advertising solutions.