In this video you're going to learn how to build up a list of questions that you can answer in order
to get traffic back to your Web site.
And I'm going to show you a secret strategy.
So get your pen and paper out because this is really going to save you a huge amount of time.
So what you want to do is come into your profile and then you want to come in to the topics that you've
added that you know about and click on.
So for this example I'll click into Facebook ads and really what you want to do is come across to the
most viewed riders.
Now this is really going to accelerate the process for you and help you identify those questions that
you can get a huge amount of answer views on.
So what we're seeing here is the most viewed riders in this topic that's going to be the same for any
topic you click into.
And I can see that top 10 riders are the 10 riders with the most answer views in the last 30 days.
So really what we want to do here is identify those questions where they're getting all of these answer
views from and then we want to go ahead and answer them.
So let's click into this guy's profile and really answer the questions that he's answered and you can
see that by default it shows you the most recent answers and that is answer.
But we really want to click into that 30 day view so we can see how is he getting so many answers or
answer views and we can do that by sorting it by 30 day views.
So if we open this we can see that he's the top answer and that's really where we want to be as well.
We can see that this question only has 10 answers on it.
So that's a low amount of answers for a question.
That means it's easy to get to the top vote for it.
And if we come down we can see that this question has over 200000 views so that is why this guy is getting
so many views on this question because there's not many answers but it's getting a huge amount of views
and supply and demand basically.
That's why he's getting so many honest views because it's not very competitive.
So what we can do is really save this to answer for ourselves and because it gets so many views and
there's not many answers and it's easy for us to get to the first spot if we answer and structure our
question well where even for us to get into that second or third position.
It's going to be pretty easy.
And when you're looking at these questions you can also have a look at not just the number of answers
but how good is the answer.
And could you do it better than that that they've done and also something you might want to note as
the number of votes now an up vote is just when somebody reads a question or an answer if they like
it they'll up voters and that helps to really push good answers to the top that 13 is not much but we
can even rank maybe the second question with the low number of votes.
So an up three up votes is very low.
And so even if we have no votes on transfer we're still going to be able to get into that position pretty
easily.
So I batted that answer in.
Now let's just go to the second question that he's got the most answer views on in the last 30 days
and we can see he's not number one on this.
He's number two here and he's got 15 up votes.
But this question again only 11 answers and it's got 50000 views.
So again that's a pretty good question that we could answer.
Now let's continue on and maybe return to some of the other top riders from our group so let's click
into this.
Again we don't look at his most recent answers and look at his 30 day views to see where he's getting
all those views views from so he can come in here at 11 answers on this question 13000 views so that's
a good one.
And once again you need to be picking questions that you think you could answer and that would make
sense for you to link back to your product.
But 13.
It's not too much and even the second and only to school we could easily get that second spot and maybe
over time get to that first spot.
Let's go back and maybe have a look at another question here.
So any three answers on this question 60000 views.
He's the number two with only four up votes.
So again this is a great question that I could potentially add to my list.
And you don't have to think about it too hard.
You can just begin to build up less.
Answer questions and see how you rank so you could go to and through the top 10 here see what is the
question that they're ranked that they're number one on and getting all those fees from.
So let's just do one more 30 day views were my first Facebook messages being delivered 50 answers and
a million views.
OK.
So this is going to be more competitive.
Again I would I would encourage you to stick to that.
Maybe 10 answers and what you can do is if you see that this is a good question but it's too competitive
you could maybe look at the related questions in the sidebar here.
And maybe you could answer these one so let's click into this.
There's only 10 answers.
There is 46000 views.
I can see the question in the top 1 has really no images in it.
It's not formatted Well it's not very eye catching.
It only has three votes on it but there's 50000 views.
Almost 46000.
So I can answer this later and really stick to that.
Less than 10 answers.
Loman's of up votes in the top answer.
And more than a thousand views and the higher the better.
You're always looking for that higher views with a low amount of answers.
And that's really how you're going to get ton of answer views very very quickly on cure.
So as you go through and look at those top riders and even maybe identify those related questions too
to those questions you're going to build up a list pretty quickly and you can come back.
Then click on answer and you can see these questions that you have selected to answer later.
And that is how you build up a list of questions to answer very very quickly.
So go ahead and try that for yourself in order to build up your list of questions.