In this video you're going to learn how to add an About section to your Facebook page to give you an
example of why this is important.
Let's have a look at an existing Facebook page and you can see down here in the right hand side that
there is an Abiud section which includes a map an address a phone number and even the opening hours
in the popular times.
Now this is going to be especially important if you are a local business so people can easily find your
business.
And if you want to add this and come back to your Facebook page click on the bad section in the left
hand side bar and you're going to see the option to opt in misinformation here.
You may also see some other options like this a way to add in the story and tell more people about your
business and Facebook are always adding little features like this in.
So if it appears slightly differently when you see it don't worry.
Now you can see here that you can edit the phone number email Web site.
You can even add some other information there as well if you want and if you're not seeing an option
to buy a location you can just click on the three dots here and you can come and edit page info and
then you will see the option to the phone number of Web sites.
Select or de-select if this place has an address on it so you can just add it in and you can even add
ins any opening hours here.
So that really appears like we saw in the example.
So it's the same information there.
It really just scrolls down.
So for every business it's going to be slightly different.
What do you put in here.
And once again the best way to really know what to do if you're not so certain is to use that search
bar to look at a top competitor and really have a look at what they are doing.
But it is another piece of prime real estate on your Facebook page and it can really help drive traffic
or sales because it's telling your customers exactly where to go.
So once again to set this up come down into the left side bar click in the band section and if you need
to click the three dots here and edit your page in for.