In this video you're going to learn how to get blog traffic from LinkedIn and I'm going to show you
how to use one of the latest features of linked in where you can write an article and essentially publish
directly on LinkedIn.
This is like just a blog publishing platform built into LinkedIn and linked in or got it giving this
a lot of visibility.
So it is an excellent feature that you can take advantage of in order to get more exposure.
So before we get into kind of looking at this I just want to show you a couple of examples.
So Richard Branson is the founder of Virgin Group and he's actually extremely active on LinkedIn.
He publishes quite a lot of articles and if you go to his profile you can see them below down here.
He's got over 13 million followers for his articles.
And so this is a great way that he's built up his influence on the platform.
So if we look at the articles here we can see Catching up at Bill Gates and climate change and if we
click into this again we can see that this is that this is an article published on Linked-In publishing
platform.
Now in terms of what type of content should you put ash.
Well you want to be quite targeted and your content should really accomplish two girls.
First it should teach people how to solve a problem or do their job better.
And then it establishes you as a thought leader and that each aspect is naturally going to lead to more
business.
If you offer them real value on it's basic psychology and it just gets results.
So Richard Branson is probably extremely well known already to a lot of people and he's just continuing
to create this content to raise issues with people.
But for a business you maybe want to get a little bit more strategic in terms of the content that you
create and also the call to action for these posts.
So the reason I'm showing you Richard Branson here is more just he's using it as a blogging platform
on Linked-In itself and extending his influence there.
But here's an example of someone who's been using it more strategically and using it to get blocked
blog traffic.
And this is very interesting as guy Neil Patel if he come in to his articles you can just click on the
latest one here.
So this is much more specific and targeted how to find new customers using these nine Google Analytics
reports.
So you can see that compared to Richard Branson catching up of Bill Gates.
It's kind of more informative.
This is much more an article like how to do your job better and get results.
And this is the type of article that I encourage you to use.
Now if you scroll down you can see that this is a good article.
It's got a good amount of likes and comments.
But here is where it gets really interesting and this is the strategy that I encourage you to use.
In fact the opening paragraphs of this article don't really teach anything.
There is no 9.
Analytics reports that is jumping into here is just setting the stage.
Given the context and then he says luckily Google Analytics has the answers you need.
Click to continue reading.
Now if we look at this it's the same post essentially But this time on his Web site.
So what he's doing is he's giving some of the article away on linked in maybe 20 30 percent of us.
And then he's encouraging people to continue reading to click back to his Web site so you can see that
that's a lot more strategic than the way.
Maybe Richard Branson is using it.
Richard Branson doesn't need web site traffic.
But as a business owner he will.
And so the idea here is to make it much more focus in terms of enabling people to get results on a good
headline will always help capture people's attention.
Then most importantly after 20 30 percent of the top of the article gets them to click to continue and
really the meat of the article should be back on your Web site and not allow you to get people back
to your Web site and the beautiful thing about this strategy is if you already have a lot of blog posts
who are taking over from a client or you're coming into a company they might have a lot of content on
their blog but it's just not getting that much visibility and through LinkedIn you can repurpose the
same content.
You don't even need to create new content share it.
And he can get a lot more traffic from the content that you've already created.
And the cool thing about these articles and the reason that you want to use this rather than just putting
a link to your web page here is because if you publish an article so if you go ahead and write an article
here everybody that you were connected with will actually be notified that you have created an article
so this is a new feature from Linked-In.
They're obviously trying to push adoption of it on as an incentive for people to use it.
They are notifying all the connections.
Any time you publish something so that is why you would want to publish it here and not just share a
link to the same article which you could do here.
You could just copy that and say paste that in and it shows the same thing and looks quite similar but
the key difference is that if you publish it as an article and even just share 20 or 30 percent of all
of your connections are going to get a notification if you share it just does a post like I've done
here.
They will not get a notification but it may end up in their news feed as well.
But the key thing I'm trying to stress is that the article has much more visibility for your connections
and that is why you should really publish it as an article and just like this example here.
So if you want to create content that gets a lot of exposure on Linked-In write an article put 20 or
30 percent of the article there.
Leave the meat back on your Web site and encourage people to continue reading back on your Web site.
So go ahead use astrology for your own business for clients for a company that you're going into in
order to get much more visibility.
Extend your influence on help people solve their problems on Linked In.