In this video you are going to learn how to create a YouTube channel for your business or for a client
that you're working for.
So the first step is to come over to YouTube dot com and log in with your personal google account.
So this would be the candidate you personally use to log into your G-mail or other Google products.
Now if you don't have a Google account you can ask searching Google create Google like can't.
And then you can create your Google can't open that up and you just fill in the steps there with your
personal details.
You don't fill this in with your company details because you actually create the channel for your company
here inside your personal account.
So once you're inside you and you sign in with your personal account you want to come then and then
click on settings and down here you want to click on see all my channels or create a new channel.
Then you can click create any channel and then you just want to give your channel a name.
So I will just put in you to demo and then you just click Create
and might take a second to load up here.
But there we go.
Now we have created a YouTube channel for your business or for another brand.
And it's that simple.
It's that simple to get up and running on the third biggest Web site in the world so that you can promote
your products or services there.