In the last place she learned how to create an email campaign.
And in this lecture we're going to complete the very important step to actually analyze the results
of the campaign because this is the key opportunity for you to analyze the data learn from your successes
or failures so that you can really get better as you go forward.
So there's two places that we're going to look at the data one here is in MailChimp and you can see
already we can see the percentage number of opens and clicks.
There's also been a report here we're going to look at.
And then also in Google Analytics if you come down to acquisition campaigns all campaigns you can see
in the information free email campaign that we sent out.
And remember that this is coming through because we have added Google Analytics to our MailChimp pecans
So that was why it was important to do that.
So we can really see the number of people that came to the Web site from that email campaign and also
the number of people who eventually signed up.
But let's go back and start with MailChimp.
So with a high level here in the campaign we can see the percentage opens in clicks but we can click
through to the report to see a lot more detail.
Now if you have a professional or pro MailChimp account you can set up a kind of revenue goals etc.
and really see revenue driven.
But I haven't done that so and we'll just be looking really at the information here.
So you can get a sense of how good your open rate is but by using these benchmarks here.
So it says the industry average for education and training which is the market I'm in is at thirteen
point eight percent open race.
So I'm well above that's obviously a much smaller list but I think that's not too bad.
So I think the key thing that gets people to open emails is the subject line.
So at least now I have a benchmark going forward that I can get a sense of you know are my subject lines
getting better or more open them.
Or are people starting to trust me more and like me more.
Or is that something I need to work on.
Now we've got the click rate then so that was actually the call to action five point six percent versus
1.5 percent for an industry average.
So that's probably a little lower than I would have liked.
And so that's what I can really think about.
Now how can I make it more exciting for them to actually click on that button.
Can I make it something you know like they have to click.
Now if they want to take advantage of whatever the offer might be but thinking about haggling to get
more people to click because that's ultimately what I want people to do.
So it's good to see the numbers have a baseline there.
Now looking across I can see that there was one on subscribe.
So one person when they got the email decided to unsubscribe from the list starts.
Only one person out of 71.
That's not bad at all.
Happy enough with that.
Now if you want further explanation on all of these metrics you can see that there's a little icon here
that you can click around and it'll help explain those more for you.
You also can see a 24 hour performance.
It's not quite being 24 hours.
It's been about 12 hours since I sent the e-mail so I would expect these numbers to Bombo palatal a
bit over the next few days because not everybody opens the e-mail.
You know the minute it goes that they come back to it later.
But interesting to see not about an hour after I sent the e-mail.
There was a spike so maybe next time I will push my e-mail campaigns to be in one hour later and props
and that is a better time where I would get more options.
So there's some great information here in this report alone that can help you improve your next e-mail
campaign.
For the subject lines getting people to click that call to action the the time that you send it out
etc..
And so as you do more and more campaigns you want to keep going back to this learning from the data
now as well as the analytics here in MailChimp you might want to come into your Google Analytics account
under our acquisition campaigns all campaigns and you will see the results here for the actual email
campaign so you can see that there was five new users came to the site as a result of the mail campaign
spending an average time of three minutes and 43 seconds on the site which is pretty long.
And then actually two people end up signing up for the e-mail list.
So that was the main thing that wanted people to see you can see that all the way from that number all
the way back to the full list of the email subscribers is a pretty small percentage.
But essentially that is kind of the baseline we're working with right now.
And remember that there are a lot of steps in the process to get people to that point.
And if you can tweak all of those steps in the process and then are going to get better results as well
as email being the source of traffic we can use email and the figures we've got here now as a baseline
to compare our other sources of traffic whether it be social media you know wherever at least we have
a great baseline to compare them with.
And so that is really really useful to have.
So that really wraps up this whole section on email marketing.
This is a very important piece of is understanding and analyzing the metrics and that is how you're
going to learn if you're not quite happy with the results that you got.
Don't view that as a failure view that really as an opportunity to learn.