Now that you set up your Wordpress Web site and you were logged into the backend I want to bring you
on a tour of the Wordpress dashboard so you can really understand how easy it is to change the look
and feel of your site.
So the first thing that I want to explain to you is if you come into appearance and PMS is really the
most radical way that you can change the look and feel of your site and that is to change the team so
we can see right now that we have the 2017 2017 team installed on our site it's active and this team
comes free with all WordPress sites in 2017 and also you can see the previous versions here as well
which you can activate if you want.
Also you can add themes that you find online.
And I'm also going to show you how to install a premium corporate team in a little bit as well.
But the key message that I want to say is that if this is not the type of site that you want do you
not worry about it at all.
You can install a team that transform this into a fully functioning e-commerce site.
You can change this to a corporate Web site or whatever.
Wordpress is definitely not just for blogs and just bytes changing the team is really a radical way
that you can change the look and feel of your site.
But before we get into that I just want to walk through some of the more basic steps that you can easily
change right away and play around with.
So let's come up to our posts and have a look at all of our posts here.
We can see that we have just one post or blog posts or site called Hello world and this will come the
default swell so we can see it here.
That's the title and this is the content of the post.
So if we want to change that we can come in to address what we can do now is to edit the title of this
post.
So let's just change this first post.
And if you were typing a blog post this is where the title of your blog post would go.
And we can just say this is my first post.
This is my first post.
Yea what we can also do is change the L of this post as well.
So what we can put in here is first Dasch post.
So let's update this and see how it changes on our site.
So there we go.
Change the title on the post and even if we click into this we should be able to see the URL that is
changed as well.
Now what you are seeing in the see where L is the days and it is possible to remove that so it's just
our Web site dot com forward slash whatever we've put in there and so to do that I would highly recommend
you do this just even for the search engines.
So combined settings.
And then we can set the URL as the post name and then we can go ahead and click save changes and now
let us come back to our posts to make sure that it is changed.
So we edited again so open that up we can see that that has been changed and if we get a read we'll
have to change the URL here.
And we can see that that's coming up.
And that is showing much more cleaner and easier.
And that's actually much more search engine friendly.
So I would really recommend that you come in to your settings and change those permalink settings to
the post name so there where you've edited the post.
Now what about if we wanted to post.
Well again we just come to the sidebar.
We can add new and we can just type in second post.
We just wanted to see the content again.
And you can see that now because we changed the permalink settings that it's just showing up as forward
slash our keyword or title.
So we're going to go ahead and publish that and if we come into our site preview we can see that showing
up here now in the recent posts.
And even if we just come back to our home page we should be able to see the second post.
And the first post.
So there you go.
That is how you add a post to your site and already that's how we're starting to build up the content.
Now you're going to learn how to add pages to your Wordpress Web site to come back into the dashboard.
Once again you want to come to pages this time and then that's firstly have a look at all the pages
on our site.
So right now we can see that we just have one sample page and again we can click into edit this and
if we want to really preview the page we can just open it up as well.
So here we can see it's just a sample page with the title of the page and looks like kind of an abiders
section.
So what we can do is change this page name again to bite us.
We can also change some of the text here as well.
So I'll just delete some of that just to show you the difference or maybe let's just keep this part
here.
And we can write this text as well when we can just make sure as well that this changes to about us
now where we can go ahead and do is update the page and let us preview the changes.
As well so we can really see it there.
And so they changed to about us.
And we can see the text there that you either imported yourself or that I just just left in there.
So if we come back to our just normal page though we can't actually see this about us page it's kind
of hidden away somewhere.
So what we want to do is insert a menu appear at the top so we can really see the pages of our site
across the top.
And before we do that we might end up in one more page.
So let's just put in services
our services and again what we can do is previous to see how it looks like something there now.
But essentially we've created another page and we can just go ahead and publishes.
Now as we said we can see those pages from our home page.
So how do we get those visible to our visitors.
Well what we can do is come down to appearance and then menus and what we want to do is go out and create
a menu.
We can call this main menu and then create it now what we want to do is add our pages to our menu.
And then we can go ahead and click display location top menu and save the menu.
And then if we open up our site and refresh the page we can see the menu items appearing up here on
if we click through we can come and see our bios page or our services page.
Now if you want to adjust how those appear if you want to put the About Us page first then you simply
just rearrange the order.
Click Save and take refreshed just to see those changes.
Now what we might do actually is want to put in a menu item for our home page or our blog as well.
So what we can do is come across to our menu click fuel quick home quick add to menu and then we can
see that that's been added.
Click save and click refresh.
And now we can see the home page which we can get back to quickly from any page on the site.
So what about these links in the sidebar here how could we change the appearance of this or the order
of these or what we want to do is come into our dashboard.
Once again this time come down to widgets and in here we can see the blog sidebar and we can add widgets
in just to drag and drop them in if we wanted to see a calendar we could add that in.
We could just give it a title
Collender say if we refresh our site we can see the calendar appears up here.
So you can add in different things like a list of categories for your blog post custom hatred email
which you maybe might use to put in as a sign up form for an email.
You can put in images caught recent Collin's different things like videos etc..
Now what if you want to change the order where you simply just rearrange them here.
So if we come back in we can see the search bar is at the top.
And if you want to delete any of these widgets you can just go ahead and Salita very easily and it will
instantly update.
Now there's one more important thing that you might want to change and that is up here and you can see
it's as welcome just another WordPress site.
So we do want to change that and to that we can come to appearance once again come to customize and
in here you can come into site identity.
And so what I'll put in here is the name of the site.
WP Septem or dot com.
And then they can say
learn how to set up a word press site.
Then I can just click save and publish.
Now if I come to my site once again refresh the page can see this change.
Now that we've made all those changes.
One things you might want to do and just make sure is that your site is live.
So if you come to blue house right at the top here you may see this here that you can launch your site
your site is currently displaying coming scene page.
So I'm going to go ahead and click on the syce and once again we can go and view the site here.
So already you've learned how to change the tag line on your side menus posts pages change the widgets
as you can see it's very simple to work with wordpress even if you're non-technical like me.