In this video you're going to learn how to get your first followers on Instagram.
It's a pretty cool strategy and I'm going to tell you about it just in a second.
Before we get into that I do want to answer a common question that does come up is can I just buy my
Instagram followers to get some social proof.
Just what I'm getting started.
And yes of course you can you can go to Crome or your browser or type in by Instagram followers.
You can see they look great like a great ad and he can get them for 799 or for whatever you want.
Now the reason that I wouldn't recommend you do this is number one.
Numbers aren't really important on Instagram.
It's not about the number of followers.
It's really more about the engagement that you have on each post.
So if you look at some topic cance No it's not really the number of followers that is important.
It's really the engagements that those posts get.
That's the real signal that people are engaging with your content.
So if you buy a lot of followers and they don't actually engage your content then they're basically
worthless.
Now the other reason you don't want to just buy a lot of followers is because that's going to mess up
your own lyrics later on.
It's not going to give you a clear indication of the age the demographic of your audience.
And that can cause problems and for misunderstanding your audience are or if you want to retarget your
Instagram audience what have Facebook God et cetera.
It just messes up everything.
So it's really not worth doing although those advertisements online etc. are quite attractive and it
looks like a pretty good shortcut.
So I would advise not to buy by Instagram followers.
That would be my advice.
So how do you get them then for free and that are going to be real people in a targeted way.
Are going to watch you want to visit your web site or buy a product or service.
Well the first thing you want to do is find those big accounts that have the audience that you want
to really engage with.
And just for example I'm just going to open up this account here.
This guy is kind of helps people get added that he's essentially a financial planner but he has his
own app etc. that does that.
Now I wanted to funnel his audience back to my Instagram account.
This is what I would do.
I would start to come in to each post.
And I would start to look at the comments and what I would do is start to actually go ahead and start
to follow the people who have engaged with the content and I go ahead and follow those people and then
they're going to get a notification on their account that I've followed them.
And once they get that notification they're probably going to want to check.
Well who is this person to follow who followed me.
And then they're going to click through to my profile here and if I have a good bio if I have a good
profile picture if I have maybe 3 to 5 posts that show that type of content that I'm putting out and
if that's relevant to them and it should be if I funneling them from a similar top account on instagram
then they're going to go ahead to follow me back.
So that is a very simple way to get real genuine followers.
It is a good manual but I can guarantee you it's just going to help you understand even by going through
even going through these influencers of cancer what is the type of content that gets so much engagements.
So let me come back to some of those topics.
So if I was trying to do something similar to Tim first by going through each post I'm going to notice
which ones are the ones that get the most amount of engagements so that's the first thing I'm learning
by doing this then I'm not just copying his followers or automating a tool to do that.
I'm actually following the most engaged part of his audience on Instagram which are the people that
are actually commenting and then I'm going to either follow them directly or just go ahead and reply
and start to engage with them and slowly over time then aton of his audience are just going to funnel
back on start following my account.
And if there was more than if there was three to five topics like this that had a similar audience mine.
This is just something I can do every single day maybe take half an hour follow maximum maybe 50 people
in that half an hour and then you're just going to slowly build up your kind.
Not only are you going to get the followers you're going to get reengaged followers and also in the
process you're going to learn what is the content that really gets these topics.
So much engagements and you're going to learn that through this process as well.
So that is how you get your first followers on Instagram.
Identify those top influencers who can't follow that people are engaging with their content.
Reply to them and then they're going to funnel back and start falling again because they're going to
see that notification that you follow them they're going to check out your profile and what is really
important before you even start this whole process off is that you've optimized your bio your profile
picture or call to action buttons.
Now you've got at least three to five posts.
They can see OK well this is available.
I can't it's active.
It has good content and I'm going to follow and keep updated with them.
So go ahead and use our strategy to get your first Sensurround followers funnel them really from the
top accounts.
That's really what it sums up to.