In this video you're going to learn a very simple strategy to get 1200 targeted Pinterest followers
in just 30 days.
So the first thing that you want to do is come up to the Pinterest search bar and type in your keyword
really the niche that you were in.
Now what you want to do then is come across to people and in here you're going to find cance on Pinterest
in your niche and you're really looking for those people who have quite a lot of followers.
He can go through these accounts and really want to come in and identifying a can that is very similar
or has a very similar audience to the audience that you were trying to capture the attention of on Pinterest.
Now once you find that I can't you can come in and look at their followers for the total accounts where
you can actually do this as well on individual boards.
So if we come into this board we can even just target the people in this individual board.
So what I can do then is start to follow some of these people.
You can see I've been doing a little bit of it already on what is going to happen is when we follow
these people they're going to get a little notification on their account and it will say Darrell Walsh
or whatever your cat name has followed you they'll see that notification of a good percentage of them
maybe 20 or 30 percent will click through and follow you back.
If you've got your profile laid out that explains in your bio the volley offering on Pinterest and they
can see the board set up with some of the pins in them.
So roughly 20 percent of the people are going to follow you back.
And so what I recommend you do is you follow 200 people per day that's really the maximum that Pinterest
will allow you before they start to maybe see your account as spam and don't go overboard 200 today.
But if we do the math on that we 200 people a day that we follow.
When you multiply that by 30 days that's six thousands and 20 percent is on the low end are going to
follow his box and multiply by 20.
So that's twelve hundred people there.
And that's really the simple strategy to get.
Twelve hundred targeted Pinterest followers in just 30 days.