In this video you're going to learn how to get your first followers on Twitter.
And this is going to be genuine followers that are going to engage with your profile and before you
go ahead and do this remember that you should have does your profile image created a bio filled out
your website etc. and created a base of content on your profile maybe five or 10 posts this is just
a demo can have everything but really you should be at that stage before you begin to try and get followers.
The reason is because when people come to your profile you've got everything set up.
It's a real act if it can't and that creates a much higher chance for them to follow you.
So how do you get the followers.
Well once again you want to open up the influencer accounts that you have started following.
And really what you want to do is funnel followers from their hands to your account.
So the way that you do that is open up.
One of the influencer can sit your following go to one of their posts and now you want to start to follow
people who are actually engaging with content that they might have a lot of followers on their profile
but not everybody is going to engage.
And so as a new Twitter profile you really want to focus and try and build the relationship with those
people who are engaged.
So if you click on a post you can actually see anybody who's commented on the posts and you can begin
to follow them and you can just keep keep moving then.
So you know these people are quite engaged.
And you might have to do a bit of clicking around to make this work.
But essentially this gives you the opportunity as well to see exactly who are these people who are engaging
with your influencer and you can see the size of their accounts here.
You can see their bio on so you can start to get a sense of who they really are.
So we can really just keep going and following them and what's going to happen is a lot of those people
are going to get this notification that they have they have been followed by you.
And then once they see that notification they're going to want to check you out.
And then in most cases if they see that your profile is relevant to what they're into which you should
be if you are following people on a cancer that are similar to yours then they're really going to come
and follow you back.
So it is a bit of a manual process but I really recommend you do this to get started.
So you can really see the exact profiles of these people really understand even some of the conversations
that are happening here.
And it's a way to attract people to your profile that are really engaged on Twitter and not just against
them maybe would have followed a while ago.
So if you want to attract engaged followers This is the best strategy.
Just come to influencer accounts and look at the comments of people and really start to follow them
and then they're most likely going to follow you back.
You can also start to engage your own comments replies on.
Not again.
They're going to get a notification of that.
And as a result they're going to come and check your profile.
So we have set up a Byard five influencer accounts here and so you can start to go in and maybe start
to follow maybe up to 200 people a day maybe just take 10 15 minutes to do that.
I think it's really going to help you understand what type of engagements on Twitter and it will really
help you attract those initial followers to get things kicked off.
So now that you know how to attract your initial followers on Twitter go ahead and try that for yourself
or just put it in your back pocket for later.