In this video are going to learn how to use cue or to find and discover really good headlines for blog
posts or even YouTube videos that you want to create.
So what you want to do is come into the search bar in cure and just type in the topic that you want
to create a blog post or a video bag.
So it's just typed in instagram.
Now what I want to do is just click on the word to search an up I'm going to see all of the most popular
questions for that topic head of can't I consume kise.
Can you see who views your instagram.
Now what we're really looking for are those questions that have a lot of answers because we can see
in the search results how many answers those questions have.
And if we open this up then that gives us an indication of the popularity so we can see almost 3 million
views on this post.
So how do we turn this into a headline.
Well all you need to do is really add a how to in front of the question to turn it from a question into
an educational type posts.
So if we go to how to see who viewed your instagram we can see that there are some articles about it
but maybe not the exact language that people are really searching for here and that's a proven question
that a lot of people are clicking on and even you could maybe write a blog post on that or as you can
see a video here if you wanted to rank in the search engines even for that.
Let's have a look at this video
37000 views.
Very simple video less than two minutes long and I mean that's how easily you can find a headline for
your blog posts or video that people are searching for a lot and are going to want to click on now in
terms of even if you don't even know how to answer this question and create a video or blog post on
this headline what you can do is come down.
Read the answers and take maybe the top three answers.
Build a list of bullet points and you can use those bullet points or steps to explain to people how
to check is read your Instagram and you can even use that same line for maybe a video as well.
So the key point is here that Corra is not only a great place to drive website traffic it's also a fantastic
place to do research because these are real questions that your target audience are asking.
So if you create educational content or maybe a blog post or videos then you're going to get a lot of
views on those that content outside of curagh as well.
So let's have a look at another example here.
Why aren't hashtags working on Instagram.
So if we just copy this we could actually even use that as a title for a blog post.
But let's have a look down here.
Instagram tips how to fix an Instagram hashtag problem.
So that's something you could easily do to turn it from a question into a more how to post and even
we could probably make it quick with you on this.
Hashtags don't work solution.
So this is back into 2014 you maybe do an updated version of this again.
It's only a minute on 24000 views.
So there's definitely room even though there is a video here on it to improve on this.
This is this is three years old it was four years old.
So don't be don't be put off if you do see there's one or two blog posts or one or two videos because
there's such a demand for answers to a question like this.
You can see these 32 answers 300000 views.
So if there's room for 32 answers here there's definitely room for more than three or four blog posts
and three or four videos.
So that is how you use curagh not only to drive traffic but also to find and discover headline ideas
and even mordent not to really quickly create content by using the answers there as guidelines for how
you can put together your content as well.
So now that you understand how to discover those headline ideas come into your search for a topic and
start to have a look at those some of those headline ideas and turn them from questions into how to
headline's.