In this video you're going to learn how to set up goals in google analytics on why this is probably
the most important step for you to complete when you are setting up a Google Analytics account so goals
measure how often users complete specific actions on your Web site or app and a goal represents a completed
activity called a conversion that contributes to the success of your business.
So for example making a purchase for an e-commerce site that could be a specific activity that will
really contribute to the success of that e-commerce business.
Completing a game level is a specific activity that will contribute to the success of that mobile gaming
app because it shows that people are engaged and potentially then you can get them to upgrade to the
paid version or just continue to advertise to the users in the mobile gaming app and submitting a contact
information form is a specific activity that contributes to the success of a marketing or lead generation
site because you can then contact those people by email or phone and market to them or just send that
blog post to them and can keep them continued continued in the site and grow your audience.
So hopefully now you understand the importance of setting up goals in Google Analytics and I think it's
important to know that if you don't set up goals all you can measure is how many users are coming to
your site and obviously could be focused on growing not.
But if those users are not completing these specific activities that are growing your business and you're
not going to see any growth so that's what is so important to set them up.
And also as you can see now the goals that you set up are really dependent on the type of business that
you have.
And that's why goals are not set up by defaults and Google Analytics.
That's why you need to go and set them up and tell Google Analytics specific activities that you want
to track setting up goals in Google Analytics is very simple.
What you want to do is come down into the admin section then come up across two goals and then go ahead
and click on Add a new goal.
Now you've two options here when setting and free goals you can select from template here or you can
create a custom goal which basically just leaves everything blank and you set it up from scratch but
I would recommend that you have a look down through this template list here because they've pre fields
the name of the goal and also the type of goal which I'll show you in a second.
So this just helps speed up the process so you can see there's lots of different types of goals here
that you can select from as just make a payment register on line schedule visit visit donate create
an account etc..
So what I would say about making a payment is that if you have an e-commerce site instead of setting
up this specific goal it's better for you to enable e-commerce tracking and I've got a separate video
on that.
However if say you are a business salesman in one or two products or you sell one to one coaching or
maybe of course it will be very easy for you to measure how many people complete that action by setting
up a revenue goal here.
So for this video I'm going to take the example of setting up a newsletter sign up and even though the
name is different actually the process to setting this up is very similar to the other types of goals
listed out here.
So just select your goal and then click continue.
So we can see the name of the goal is pre filled and also the type of goal is preselected as well which
is a destination goal.
And as I said the type of goal is actually going to be very similar whether it's an account creation
or payment completed or a donation made or newsletter sign up because what you are really tracking is
the destination that people arrive at after completing that goal.
So for example a thankyou page.
So if they sign up to my email list they'll hit a thankyou page and I want to track how many people
reach that page because that will allow me to measure how many people completed that specific activity
that's important to my business.
Now the next step is to input our destination and this as it says here is the app screen name or web
page you were all that people arrive at after completing these specific activity that we want them to
such as making an online payment donation or signing up period Millis and the vast majority cases this
is just going to be a thankyou page like it suggests here.
And if you haven't got a thankyou page set up in your site just go into the back and set that up and
then paste that in there.
So by setting up this goal what we will know that is every people whose arrive at that Thankyou page
we know they can only of arrive there if for example they sign up to my email list and then I can really
track how many people are doing that.
And there off some off optional options here to add a value or add a funnel.
I'd say for the moment you can just skip that on what you want to do is just re verify the goal and
verify the goal to make sure that it's working should see a small percentage like this.
If you've had data over the last seven days and then you can just go ahead and click save.
So now I can see that the goal is set up and also that it is active.
And also I can see that I've 18 goals left.
So you have 20 goals per for each.
Google Analytics property that you set up.
So although we've set up a goal to track newsletter sign ups the process is almost going to be identical
for people who register for an account or make a payments or online donation because you're always looking
at how many people reached a specific Thankyou page or check out page.
So to recap in this video you have learned how to set up goals in Google Analytics and also why it is
probably the most important step for you to complete when you set up a Google Analytics account.