In this video you're going to learn how to use Twitter poles to create tweets that get a lot of engagements.
I'll show you a couple of examples and then I'll show you how to set up a poll on your Twitter account.
To find some examples of successful polls on Twitter we can just come into the search bar and type in
hashtag polls and hope is going to pop.
Then some accounts that are related as polls on some actual polls down here.
So let's come then and just find an example.
So here's a good example of simply just a question who's going to win the election.
And then there's two options.
And then people are really just voting on this so I could select this as somebody.
And then just vote and then I can see the percentage of people who think that that is the likely outcome.
So for me as a viewer this is very engaging because I'm actually doing something and engaging with you
on Twitter and then I'm also learning a little bit about what other people think.
And that gives me that little bit of an incentive to click through.
So you can see once again when you see the poll you don't actually see the answers.
You can see the number of votes.
But when I select my answer then I can see the percentage of people who agree to me.
So there isn't a built in incentive there for people to respond because then they can see what other
people are seeing and that is why it's such a powerful feature and why get so much engagements.
Now what can you do with these polls.
Well you can do pretty much anything you could get people to vote on content that you wanted to create.
So here you could say what what what blog post should I write next.
Instagram marketing Twitter marketing and you can see where the votes are.
You could ask for predictions like this who's going to win the election.
You could ask for feedback on a feature.
So.
And do you use this feature on Twitter polls.
Yes.
You can react to realtime events anything that happens in the news.
You could say do you think this is a positive thing or did he get that decision right.
Yes or no.
And then the cool thing about these polls as well as you can actually take a poll your poll or anybody's
poll and embed them onto your Web site.
So you could put this just take the code copy it and paste through it onto your Web site.
And then this poll will appear on the Web site so you could create your own polls put them on a blog
post or put a collection of polls to really highlight.
OK well this is what some people think is going to happen.
And here's what I actually think is going to happen.
So there's a lot of interesting ways that you can use these polls and even there it actually is an account
on Twitter here not shares that the most important polls on Twitter brought to you by BuzzFeed so we
click into this.
We can take a look at some of these.
So 3000 243 votes that's a lot of engagements and this is now over.
You can see it that's the final results final results.
So all of these I think they're sharing them magic when they're done.
But if it wasn't the final result you're going to see like one day left to the left and that's when
you can see the results there.
But even if we just scroll down through these you can see that there is a lot of engagement 17 under-votes
4100 10000 votes.
So this one's just kind of funny.
Some can be more Seer's 3000 votes 11000 votes.
Now I think what you'll see is the consistency between all of these is it's a simple question maybe
even a couple of words and then there's maybe one or two options maximum.
So if you want to get a lot of engagements keep it a simple question one or two answers.
And I think that's going to make it very easy for people to respond.
They don't have to think a huge amount about it.
They can just click and you can make this fun like hell yet.
And even if we scroll down a little bit I think I saw a good one down here.
You can put emojis in here.
Are you ready for this end it now.
It's over.
And scroll down even more what is the future of the U.S. look like you know it looks bad or it looks
great and you can see that that got a huge amount into engagement as well.
So let us come in and create a poll for ourselves then we can come in and click tweet at the top right
hand corner here.
You can select this option to add a poll and so you want to ask the questions so walk towards maybe
should I make next.
And then you can say something give two options
Google Analytics I can create the whole length and that's probably a good idea to leave it up there
as long as possible maybe five to seven days and then you can just go ahead and tweet that.
Now if we come to the profile
you can see that that's going to appear there it's going to say four days left and then people are going
to vote.
You're going to see the results straight away.
But the viewers once seen their results until they click through an answer now that you know how to
create Twitter polls come in to your account and create a poll for yourself so you can get a lot of
engagement on your tweets.