You've already learned how to target your odds by location age gender and demographics.
And in this lecture you're going learn about interest targeting.
This is where it really starts getting interesting.
Excuse me excuse the pun but this is where Facebook has a lot of power because they have a huge amount
of information on people and interest targeting is not just the Facebook pages that people like.
They actually have much more data.
Not so any information that they've added to their timeline.
Keywords that they use and their status updates the apps that they use and even odds that they have
previously clicked on.
So what Facebook does is categorize people into different categories based on these interests and you
can use these categories and pull these interests into your campaign.
So you're getting your ads in front of people who were interested in those things that you know are
going to be relevant to your product or service.
So one thing to do before we get started is once again take note of your potential reach.
So it's 27 million.
For example here.
And you see that how this changes as we look at certain things.
So interest targeting to really add this to your audience.
It's down here under detailed targeting.
And if you click on the search box here you're going to see the dropdown come up and you will see the
interests here.
So the type of stuff that we're talking about is you can target people based on all of these interest
categories here.
CC Business and Industry family and relationships fitness and wellness technology.
There's more categories down here as well.
But really this is the first way that you can do it through the interest categories here.
Now I'm going to click into business here.
Scroll down a little bit.
What I want to look for here is online interest so people are interested in online stuff.
And in particular digital marketing this is suitable for me because this is the type of interests that
I hope my audience are going to be into because this is what I am really creating my out about.
Now the cool thing is is that when I'm click to add this interest to my ad I can get to see I get a
sense of how many people are interested in this.
Thirty nine million people.
Now you'll notice that as I clicked that my potential to reach reach has dropped a lot.
So this is the total audience who we're interested in this.
But in terms of the location and age settings that I've made the people who are interested in this plus
much the options that I've targeted is now 1.9 million so 27 million and don't point nine million you
can see a massive drop.
So as well as using these egg drop downs and categories to select your interests watch you can also
do is just type something into the interests search box here.
So this could be products that are related to your Facebook pages maybe competitors or people with in
your field who you think if they're interested in that then they're going to be interested in me.
So let me type in digital marketer.
This is a Facebook page that covers similar stuff to me.
And so I can see that success 164 people are interested in this.
And if I click on this this is where it starts get really interesting because Facebook starts to give
me suggestions here.
So these are different categories that I could add to my campaign.
There are even well-known people within this industry sharp starting to show up here.
So are a couple of these.
And as you are these as well you can start to see how many people are interested in that particular
person or that particular Facebook page or their particular product.
And it's fascinating to really see how many people are interested in one person or another.
So if you think somebody is the biggest in your industry you can just be interesting to come in here
and actually test that with some data and see it as well as Facebook.
What is the data that they have and who do they see as being the bigger well-known person where the
bigger page etc..
So looking over the fuel gauge you can see that it's gone up from 1.9 to 3.8 and that is because I've
added in and these additional interests here.
So what is important for you to understand is that this when I add in interests like this as you can
probably guess from the number it's not that people who are interested in Amy Porterfield and digital
marketer and Gary Vaynerchuk it's just people who are interested in either one of those three things
or even digital marketing in general so that's a really important thing to understand as you are in
interest.
You can actually be making your audience broader rather than being people who like all of those three
things.
So because these all these people are quite broad I'm going to start to remove some of them and kind
of get it down to something more suitable for me which I think is this.
So what I would recommend you do now is have a look at the entries targeting.
Think about the Facebook pages of competitors that might be relevant or relevant companies or products
are wiling to keep in mind as you search in here for interest.
Not every single well-known celebrity or page is going to show up here.
Facebook only has information and a certain amount of people.
So you've got to work around the data that is available but play around with the interest targeting
here.
Remember you can still use all these tools even if you're not considering putting this on live.
So I really recommend you do that.
And in the next Lion's share we're going to move on to behavior targeting which is the final way that
we're going to look to you to find your audience for your out there.