Hello and welcome back as you can see you have Microsoft skills Server Management Studio load it up
and this can mean only one thing that today we're going to be working with practice.
We're going to actually be putting in all of this we've learned into practice through writing our equerries.
So I hope you're very excited about it.
Before we go any further let's check that we have the refrain the same as you can say have consumer
complaints that a base loaded up and inside of it I have a table called consumer complaints.
So if we go ahead and just right click on it to like top falls and droves this should give us enough
information.
What are the table has appropriate information and the data inside of it is correct.
And as you can see if we just scroll down on the results tab everything looks fine and normal.
So we had to close this query and started writing our own queries for our own hands without needing
to help from the Microsoft Asgill through her managers to.
So first thing first you want to either press control or just left click this button right here that
says new query.
And inside of here the first task we're going to do is that we want to select every single row inside
of this database we want to display all the data that's contained inside the stable called consumer
complaints.
As you know we can go ahead and say select and just open this column's up and then start typing all
of them one by one so they receive it and then comma then probably name and then Colma and subproject
comma issue comma and so on.
Or alternatively instead of typing our cells what we can do is just drag and drop put.
Come on.
Don't worry about the brackets.
You can write it both ways in brackets or about the rescue all just minor stuff with a scale sort of
management studio just puts this practice here.
When you drag and drop to identify where the table came from but because we're only working with one
table it's not important.
So right now we can just drag and drop separate them by comma and I'll speed up this process so you
are not stuck with me doing this.
So I'll see you in a bit so as you can see now I have all the columns written down and it took me quite
a while to just drag and drop them as you can see mostly just drag and drop them instead of writing
them.
And still it took a lot of time and I could have easily made a mistake by either not dragging one of
them out or duplicating some of the columns.
And just to finish with this query Let's go ahead and write our second part of Slick's statement where
we select from.
In our case it's consumer complaints.
So again you can either start typing it and type it all yourself or you can select it from the dropdown
menu.
In our case it's not the database It's the table or he can just drag and drop it from the screen right
here.
In my case I'll just use the down arrow press enter and it'll work again.
Let's execute it.
And as you can see we have everything displayed correctly appropriately.
There seems to be no mistakes.
All of the columns are presented correctly in the correct order.
And as you can see we have sixty five thousand five hundred rows.
So everything works perfectly fine.
But let's just quickly zoom out here and you can see the size of the square is just insane.
Imagine if you had to.
All of that down yourself.
Or imagine if you have 40 50 100 columns in your table in your database.
Obviously that will not happen a lot and that should never happen.
You have such absurd amount of columns in any given table.
But just imagine if you do in this case you don't want to be writing them all one by one out.
So as you can already guess there is another way of timing going to ask you all because you're working
with big chunks big amounts of data all the time.
So instead of writing all of that all that we could have driven is select star and select story gives
us exactly the same results as selecting every single column we want.
So again let's return let's copy this.
So we're going to do select Star Control.
Control C and then legis control Z.
A couple of ways back.
And as you can see this is our initial inquiry.
Now let's run the new query in which we'll just say it's like old from consumer complaints.
It gives us exactly the same amount of columns exactly the same information and the actually the same
order and it gives us everything correctly.
The only thing is that instead of writing all of this down instead of having to worry about if we've
made any mistakes or not we just can press simply type and select all.
So now I hope you understand the basic the most common select query where you have this like all of
the data from the table and now let's move on to something more interesting.
Let's just close this query Let's close this query just if you want to save them go ahead save them
this menu will pop up.
You can choose where to save them.
In my case just I don't think we need to say such a simple query such fundamental queries.
So let's just open a new query window and inside of it.
I'll zoom in a bit so it's easier for you to see.
And inside of Atlus work with specific data.
So for example let's say I don't want to display every single column inside this table.
I only want to see the product that issued this product had and the company that produced the product.
So in this case of course they need the select.
So now instead of writing down all the columns and then looking at them from the table and trying to
just scroll for the table and pick the columns that we need.
We just can't understand that.
All we need is product name again just dragging dropping very easy easily made in Microsoft's scale
Server Management Studio.
Alternatively we can write it down so for example when it is like product name then we need to select
issue and then we need to select a company name.
So there we go.
Company just the company as it's written here.
So now if we finish writing this like curry all we have to do is select all of these free columns from
consumer complaints table.
So I just like this one and let's try it.
As you can see now it gives us way more manageable view of the same database just because there's only
free column selected.
And it gives us all the correct information.
And I would say that from this table this is probably the most important information you will be working
with.
Of course you can work with a lot more data and we will work a lot more data and combinations of different
columns trying to find specific patterns as issues.
Were any of the mellitus with data but this is just like in any company that you would go.
Most of the time they want to find an issue of the data and that's just done by simply writing this
small query.
After that we will learn how to manipulate it to get results shorten it down.
But for now I think this is a very good result.
It's your first time writing a query in Microsoft I ask you all and you all ready perform the most fundamental
the most powerful and the most important tasks that any company can have.
So now just to make sure we understand what we want to do.
Let's go ahead and just delete this Dubrow because we're obviously going to be working with consumer
complaints for this lecture and for the whole rest of this section and inside of it.
This like statement.
Let's start this like something else.
For example let's see what the product was.
What was the product what was the issue and what was the state that it all came from.
So in this case again what do we need the key elements of this query product subproject issue and state
name.
In our case the columns are written in a very understandable fashion.
So if one product we just have to drag product name here put a column up then drag the subproject in
here as well to separate them by space and put a call drive in issue and then put a call and drive and
state name.
So in other tables or in more advanced examples that are tasks what you might need to be might need
to understand that which columns represent what or maybe a combination of some columns represents something
else and then you'll have a bit more difficult time with identifying the key elements.
But with any ESC you will query you will ever be working with as long as you identified the key elements
as I like to call them the stuff you need to find and the stuff you have to work with.
And the stuff where you have to work it from you should be right.
Everything else is just logical.
You have to take logical steps that you need to combine those or shorten this or maybe just narrow the
search results is dumb.
So coming back for example as you can see we have the like product name product and state them.
Let's run it as you can see it gives us no mistake.
Also you can already know this that some fields in the Sampradaya column are empty.
Nothing to worry about.
As you can see a lot of products will never even have an opportunity to have a sap product.
Or maybe the people that put them in the database just put them as we need in order to put them in or
put them with initially some mistake that had to be eradicated later on these fields called nulls and
we'll be working with them later on in this course.
But they're nothing to worry about.
Nulls are very common in this.
Q All in pretty much any database you come up with.
So I hope this lecture made you understand as well better and most importantly drove your fear of quirkiest
if you had any a way because as you can see programming languages are very logical.
School is not different.
All you need to understand is what you need to find and what elements you need to use in order to get
those results.
And then you just need to add different tools.
And we're going to be teaching you all the tools all the different functions different statements all
the different tricks and tips.
So again don't worry if you think school is difficult if you think you will have any issues you won't.
It's very logical if you do it right you will get the correct result 100 percent of the time.
If you do something wrong it's very easy to go back and fix it.
And I hope you enjoy this lecture.
It's very interesting to be actually working inside the mildest of the scale management studio.
It's a refreshing and I think it's always better to practice more rather than just sit for a few to
read about having any real world data to work with.
And as always I hope you enjoyed today's lecture and I'll see you in the next one.