Hello and welcome back as you can see I'm working in Microsoft as kill Server Management Studio.
I have my database consumer complaints loaded up inside of it.
We have consumer complaints table which has a lot of different columns ready to go.
So first things first let's try on a new query in which will say select all.
So select all from consumer complaints.
Again just use the down arrow enter and exit it as you can see we get sixty five thousand five hundred
rows of data.
That's an absurd amount of data to be working with as a data analyst.
As a scientist you will not be able to get any insight even from just one column consisting of sixty
five thousand rows of data just insane just the amount of time you'll have to spend going for it without
remembering it.
Make sure you've put in every row of data correctly memorized it and then hopefully get some insight.
It's just insane.
You will not get anything from it.
What do you need to do in order to get any inside's any good results from working with data is you need
to narrow it down to only the data that you need to work with.
That will be of a small amount and that will actually be necessary for you.
So of course select statement by itself does nothing in order to achieve that.
This is why and as you well we have a where so the shindigs behind us is as follows.
We have select all from consumer complaints and then we say where also where it can go in any other
statements.
For example if you don't want to display anything and you will not have select here still where just
goes after something is performed because first you need to state what you need to perform.
Is it a data manipulation getting read of data or showing it to the user and but only after you state
what you are doing with this data.
You need to put a rule in it and that's where does exactly that.
It puts a rule on this data so only the data that succeeds this rule that satisfies this rule can go
through and be worth them.
In our case let's start with something simple and take a look at all of this columns and I think the
easiest one is stating because we're working with data from America.
This all came from American real world data as you know.
There are a lot of different states and they are represented in this table by unique identifier of combination
of two capital letters.
In our case let's say what you want to do is I want to select everything.
Or rather not a Rifi.
I just want to select the product name and I want to select the issue that the product has from this
table from consumer complaints where the state that they came from there was state that the product
came from.
Is New York so in here we put in state name because we need to put constraint we need to put a rule
on the state name and then we need to say equals because it has to be exactly New York.
It cannot be NJ because that will be New Jersey a completely different state it has to be exactly and
why.
So as you can see right here.
So because it's the type of state name is Wotcher it's not integer it's not that it's text.
Basically text type what do we need to do is we need to put it in apostrophes and then just type it
in like this.
As you can see it's highlighted in a different color red means text blue means functions and black.
This means nothing basically.
Most of the time it will be your columns your tables your databases.
So now let's execute it and see what that gives us.
As you can see it returned tells only 4400 rows which is way better than working with sixty five thousand
rows.
But what happened behind the scenes.
If we want to see that and I'm sure we want to see that.
Just make sure that you put in stage name into select statement and here you can see that all of this
products all of these issues come from the New York State.
So that was pretty interesting wasn't it.
Now let's just quickly change ahead and just change this to New Jersey.
Run it now we only have two thousand five hundred DROs of data and now all of them come from the state
of New Jersey.
As you can see where is another pretty much not a fundamental function of a skew.
Because on one hand you do want to be displaying all of the data and then you need to always specify
where you're working with the data from where it comes from.
But most of the time if not all the time what you want to be doing is you want to be narrowing it down
or showing only the specific data.
So in our case let's practice again.
Let's go ahead and change this.
Let's actually create a query which will say select all from consumer complaints press Enter execute
it and in our case here let's think about this as a Pasch from your employer.
So what they want to know is they want to know what complaints war received by the companies on the
same day that they were sent.
So in our case what you need to do right is first you need to identify key elements of this query that
you'll be running.
Obviously the first one will be complaint.
So let's go ahead through this.
Results like this table and look for complaints.
You can also do it in the column menu.
So inside of here we can see that there is complaints right here.
Consumer complaint Meredith and then we also have a deal.
So we will be working with one of them or maybe both.
What else do we have to be working with.
Well we have to be working with.
They sent and they received.
So here is they received.
And here as they sent.
So let's go ahead instead of a star.
Start putting them all in here.
So when they receive one they send I want an plain a D and that one consumer complaint narrative.
So it's right here.
So now if it's like this we can get a bit better understanding of the task.
As you can see consumer complaint narrative is almost always empty it's almost always now.
And just it doesn't work for us.
For this task we don't need it.
So we can immediately go ahead delete it.
Make sure you delete the comma as well.
Now we have free of these key elements to work with and which ones or other what do we do now.
As you can see we still have sixty five and a half thousand rows of data.
What do we do now since we have to narrow it down.
We need to use a WHERE function.
In our case what the employer wants to see is all the complaints that they were sent on the same day
they were received.
So what we have to do is we just have to copy this into here put an equal sign and just copy this into
here.
As easy as that.
So basically what we're saying here and if we run it you can understand it a bit better.
We're saying that like these free columns from consumer complaints table where they've received equals.
They sent so they've received has to be exactly the same as they sent in our case it works.
As you can see we have only 28000 rows of data left.
Still a very big amount of data but way way better.
Now another thing that I just want to show you right now is instead of doing all of this what you would
present to your employee select count complaint 80 pro-consumer complaints were data received equals
they sent a very nice consigns query that it gives you it gives you the number of complaints that were
sent on the same date they were received.
Of course as you saw previously we can see that number right here and it is the same number that we're
seeing now but calland function just basically count the number of rows that the query would initially
display do and displays that number instead of older rows of data.
So don't worry about it for an hour too much.
We'll we'll learn about that later in the course.
It's a very interesting function and has a lot of other aggregate functions alongside it.
But for now just remember where function is extremely powerful and that's one of the most fundamental
functions in the school.
So where data received equals data sent or where state name equals New York or where they send is less
than 2012.
There are just countless ways of using where function and most of the time in as well.
Working with SECU all working with this key elements identifying what the put in the where function
will determine your success.
I hope you learned a lot in this lecture and slowly start to get familiar with different functions and
feel good about them and I hope you enjoy this lecture and I'll see you in the next one.