Hello and welcome back.
Today we will be working with workers.
As you can see I have Microsoft skills or a management studio loaded up in a half console game database
and console games table ready to go as always.
Let's quickly go ahead.
Run select all from console games
Querrey loves executed and so with we see that all of our data is safe and solid.
The table looks nice.
Everything looks neatly organized.
So now if we go ahead and actually before we go any further let's quickly order by game on again know
we don't have to go to Sunday because it goes by default.
And now it looks neat indeed.
So if we go ahead and take a look at our columns here just looks at this and right.
We can see that we have different columns here and they have different data types.
So game rank has integer game name as worm type or name as which her genre is worked for a game years
integer and cells are most refloat.
Today we'll be working with March or data type.
As you remember with float we can do multiply or divide by or subtraction and adding different float
data types columns together before char everything is WAY simpler.
Which are basically as well as string data type consists of any number of characters or a specified
number of characters.
So it can include letters numbers symbols and is treated as text.
In our case in S Q Not lot of functions.
There's not a lot you can do with Tex.
Just logically thinking about it.
What can you do.
Maybe you can combine first name and last name to be full name to be.
And you call them called full name.
A still of data type works.
But apart from that there's really not that much you can do and will just quickly go through several
functions that you can use with torture to broaden your function.
Pool a bit.
OK so let's get to actually writing this function.
Now let's delete order by delete this like all and just go.
Select game name is quickly around the Square-D make sure it works perfectly fine.
It gives those 16000 rows of data.
It all seems normal here.
Let's put a coma and let's say I just want to for some reason I want to only see the first five letters
of every game in which case I need the left.
So what we do is I need to write the left put brackets and in brackets.
I want to write what I want.
In our case I want to see again the first five letters so I need to specify that that's five letters
of every game.
If we execute this we can see that we have not because you don't have to write this like game name in
here but we are just writing it down to understand how it works.
Basically left the operator is very simple.
What it does it gives Taus first five letters of every game name.
There's really nothing more to it.
And as you can see it includes space.
It includes any other symbol such as dash and it can be quite useful sometimes.
For example we can see maybe we can compare what letters game start with to them out of sale they have
in different countries.
But it's certainly a very specific field of use for this function.
It's very difficult to find a really good use of this function so I'll go ahead and run right.
As you already guessed right.
Function gives tours.
The last letters of any column in either case let's increase it to 10 and see what happens.
It will just basically give us a bit more information about each column.
Finally let's go have some fun.
The reverse function in it.
We don't need the number input we just need to call them that who traverse.
And now you can see total mayhem going on in this new column because it really makes them pretty much
unreadable.
So these functions are fun not so useful.
They can be very useful in very specific cases and that's why it's important to remember that they exist.
So I hope you enjoyed this lecture and I'll see you in the next one.