Hello and welcome back.
Today we'll be working with implicit data conversion in school as you can see I have Microsoft Asriel
Server Management Studio loaded up inside of it a have console games I like that inside of it.
I have a table called console games and I will be working with this table today.
So I go ahead and run an inquiry in which we'll say select all from console games and drag and drop
with here.
Run it.
See that all the data is still in place.
Nothing has changed.
Nothing significant has happened.
Now if we open up console games in here and in columns we can see that there are 12 different columns
in here and they have different data types.
So we're have game ring that's integer plus or minus watcher and a cells that's plot.
So let's go ahead and say I want to change name Year from integer to float.
In this case what I need to do is I need to select all who can actually leave this code in here and
then just put a comma here and say cast open brackets and say what we're casting in our case we're casting
game here.
And then we can press as.
And then we say the new data time the twant in our case is going to be decimal flow.
Decimal doesn't really matter.
When they convert integer to something different had run it.
As you can see Game year nothing changed but Game year is of a type decimal right now.
But what's interesting about us if it were pressure here nothing will show.
Nothing will change.
And this is due to the fact that if you want to change the data type in the column permanently you will
have to do that later on you will have to run a very specific commands that ultra commands update commands
and even maybe go to the database or table design and change it in there.
This is just temporary.
This is just for this query.
For example if we need to run some more specific functions or integer specific functions or decimals
specific functions for this glary that's where you're going to be using this functions.
Most of the time again converting data types is not something you will do every day.
It's something you will do on very rare occasions but it's good to just remember how it's done and understand
the simple logic behind it.
So again this is how it's done.
Cast selfing as there is also a convert command in which you specify convert to want to type and then
you put the comma.
And what you want to convert.
So it goes like this.
Convert.
And then you will put in game year and then you'll put Kahwa and then you put decimal.
So there's just a different way of doing the same function.
But the most important part of it is when you're going to be working with the same query and in the
square you want to do some for example in this case we could have converted game year to float and work
with adding it up to North American cells or European cells.
But as you can see that makes no sense.
So again it was a very brief short lecture about introducing you to implicit data convergence in Microsoft
as CULE server.
I hope you enjoyed it and I'll see you in the next one.