Hello welcome back to the course on databases in today's tutorial we're going to talk about some tips
and tricks of Joines.
We've already started the practical part of Joines but I thought it was a good idea to talk about the
tips and tricks early on because they will be handy for us going forward and they will simplify the
following tutorials in the section.
So right away let's at the top put a comment here and say this part was about left joins And so this
part now is going to be about Joines tips and tricks.
And also talk about right.
All right.
So let's get started.
So what are our tips and tricks.
Well first of all let's take this this take this code and here we're going to say no actually let's
take this call.
Let's take this code and Coppins.
And here we go into Razzy remember this is the code that selects the name of the pet and the name of
the owner.
What we want to do next is we want to add some additional information or additional code to this part.
And why is that.
Well I just want to illustrate that sometimes these joints can actually be quite complex so this one
has four lines already but they can grow really quickly.
So let's say if we want to set a condition where the first letter of the pet's name is the same as the
first letter of the author on his name so let's have a look an example of that cookie and Charles like
they both start with C and we want to pick out all of the elements or all of the rows from this table
where that is the case.
So how would we do that.
Well we would add a WHERE clause and here would say where left then we would say pets names are left
of this column.
Comma one.
So this left function.
It will take the first letter of this string and why the first.
Because we are specifying what are we here and here we're going to say left PED's name equals and we
say left owner's name.
So if we have this condition in the SO X state and run it you'll see that we've now got a result with
only the rows are we looking for where the first letter of the pet's name equals to the first letter
of the owner's name.
In fact he's actually one pet owner combination where they have the same name which is quite funny.
All right.
So that's that's how we do that.
And once you can see from here so this isn't the tip or trick yet this is just a normal wear condition
which you can see here is that this joint is growing quite quickly.
And so every time writing out this PED's dog name owners not name can be tedious because it's just it's
just a lot of clutter in your code.
So what can you do about it.
How can we fix it.
Well there's a very convenient way of going about it in a scale you can.
You can give aliases to these tables for specifically the purposes of this join.
So here you can go you can say from Pat's as a and from owners as B and now everywhere else you can
just take pets and replace it with a the actual table.
Except for this line of course.
And here and then take owners and replace it with B.
And what that does is it saves space it makes your code easier to read and is faster to code so.
So if you want to just add another condition you just simply instead of specifying the whole name of
the table you just specify the alias and it's much faster.
So that is tip or trick number one that is alias's for tables.
So trick number 2.
Have a look at this result that we've got here here in the results everything is great except for the
names of the columns.
Both of the columns are called name and that can be confusing especially if you want to save this table
into another table.
Or if you want to present this result to somebody it's not intuitive which is which.
Right.
Especially you know when you're dealing with names of with names or roof other columns that actually
contain symbol values.
So here we're going to talk about aliases for columns and you guessed it right.
You can actually specify them right here or you can say as a pet name that name and as owner name so
if you run this now you'll see you've got pet name onery where it doesn't look that good because we
don't want to capitalize this try this
owner.
So far on this.
Now you'll see that we've got a beautiful table with pet name and owner.
Beautiful.
And another little hack over here is that as he'll isn't advanced programming language and you don't
really have to write the word as it allows you to admit that word and still understand exactly what's
going on and it will therefore Ill just make your coding experience easier so you can just remove as
like that and it will understand that that is what's assumed if you run this everything is.
But personally I don't take it that far I prefer to keep the AS because it's in a different color and
because it's it's just easier to separate the two it's visually easier to see that you are using an
alias.
And personally I prefer to use as here.
All right.
So that was our trick number two.
And before we proceed to number three actually what I wanted to show you is you see these red underlines
they're a bit you know getting in the way there are actually no errors but a skill is still underlining
them and that happens sometimes so if that happens to you as well then you can switch it off you just
go to Tools Options and then here in text editor.
So you go to text editor transacts skill Intellisense and uncheck underline errors that way these errors
are not going to be underlined and it's going to be easier to code and see everything.
So there we go.
That's a little hack for you just in a scale hack.
And finally what we're going to talk about is a third trick or tip is right Joines.
So let's create a right join and see what it's going to be.
It's going to look like.
So we're going to take just simply this whole code and remove the WHERE clause.
And here we're going to replace left join with a right join.
And we're also going take pets and put them on this side and owners.
We're going to put them here.
Now one more thing we need to remember to do is to switch the alias's as well because you can see this
Aliase is a dog name as pet name so that came from a pet table and that came from the pet table so you
may remember in this specific procedure if you were doing it to replace the aces as well.
So right now what we did is we took this code and we replaced the left turn.
And we also switched the tables around including the alias's.
So if we run this now we'll get exactly the same result as we had with this query.
So if out the where clause if you run this you'll see you've got 100 rows and you've got the pet name
you got the owner name.
If you run this you got 100 rows again and again you got the pet name and onery on the name and the
result is exactly the same simply.
Well just because the way we did it is we took a right join and we switch the tables switch places of
the tables and that's a good illustration of the fact that a right join is identical to live joins just
the tables are switched positions or the tables are switched and that is the reason why.
In school you will rarely see a writes join.
Most of the time people use left joins because you can replace your I join the full left join and simply
because we've all Always were always used to reading from left to right and that's how we write code
and so on.
And we used to thinking that way.
So most of the time you'll see left joins the only time you will ever or the one of the reasons you
will ever see a right join is.
For example when you have a huge select huge like a huge join where you've got a table and then adjoining
to another table and another table and another table is growing like it's growing to many many lines.
So it's like that big already and then you need to add another table but you want that table to be the
primary table in the join and instead of like revamping the whole code and putting that new table on
the left and then the result the existing join on the right sort of doing that.
Sometimes it's just easier and it's more convenient to add the table as a right join to this final query
and that's one of the rare cases when you will see a writer and other than that it's most of the time
it's a left join.
So there we go that's all we had for today.
Let's just quickly recap so we talked about quite a few tips and tricks.
The main ones are listed here so we talked about aliases for tables which help you save time.
Talked about aces for columns which allow you to rename the columns in the output and make your results
more presentable and more intuitive.
We talked about right joins that in fact they are the same as left joins.
Plus we also covered a few little tricks.
One was that you don't have to say the word as a skill or understand what's going going on anyway and
also how to remove those underlines from the errors or the formatting of your text editor.
So there we go.
Hope you enjoyed today's tutorial.
I can't wait to see you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.