Hello and welcome back to the course on databases.
So the Tauriel we checked that this table is in first normal form and we confirmed that.
So let's go ahead and at the top type in a comment I will say check one and F..
And now we're going to check for the second normal form a check to N.F..
So let's quickly bring up the slide for the second normal form and here's the definition.
A table is in second normal form.
If it isn't first on the form which we have confirmed and every non-prime attribute of the table is
dependent on the whole of every candidate.
So if we remember the mnemonic every non-prime attribute must provide facts about the key the whole
key and nothing but the key.
So we're talking about the whole key.
And as we remember here it's every candidate.
So this should be replaced with the whole of every candidate.
So that's what we're going to be looking at.
Let's go and investigate.
So here's our table once again.
Let's make some room so we can analyze this better especially these first couple of columns.
This is going to be the very important ones and here.
So basically what this is is we just ran a select store from transaction's so we can just reposted here
so that we know that we ran it.
And in fact we can run it again.
The only thing is that we're going to have to adjust these columns again but that's ok.
All right so what do we want to understand here is that first of all we need to find the primer non-prime
attributes right.
And to do that we need to find the candidate keys.
So let's let's go ahead and do that.
Let's find out which of these columns or combinations of columns are our candidate keys.
So obviously of this column right away is a candidate key because it identifies every single row uniquely.
That's that's the design of this column that's what it's made for right transaction IDs.
So this is a candidate.
But the question is does it stop there.
Or can we maybe find another candidate.
Q So how do you go about these things.
Well let's let's try just randomly picking some columns and thinking about it that way and then we will
go about it a bit more logically.
So let's say we pick first name right.
Could first name be the candidate key here right.
How do we think about that.
Well first them cannot uniquely identify every column because here it is the name of the person that
made the purchase and a person can make several purchases right.
So therefore this column would work neither would the column first name surname if you combine these
two columns.
Again it wouldn't work because this is not a table about people sort of table of our customers.
This is a table about the purchases they make.
And if a customer makes two purchases then you will not be able to identify.
You will not be able to separate those two rows if your candidate is going to be first name and surname
and therefore first name plus surname is not a candidate key.
What else.
Well let's say item could item be a candidate again item cannot be a candidate for that same reason
that this is a documentation of this table.
Documents all of the purchases that happened and a certain item can be purchased several times because
those items are not unique those items are just in stock.
And this is just an item called that doesn't mean a unique item it just means a type of item that you
know a coat and there's hundreds and maybe thousands of those coats in the warehouse.
And every time it's purchased the same code is used you can see that there's duplicate in this column
already.
And so you can go about.
Think about it that way and just look at individual columns or combinations of columns but the same
time it will take quite a lot of time because there's lots of combinations of Kolb's that you can imagine.
And therefore the best way to think about it is just to think logically like what is this table about
what is the purpose of this table.
Always think of the purpose the purpose of this table is to document all of the transactions to have
a trail or a trace of all of these transactions that occurred right.
Hence the transaction ID over here at the start and hence the name of the table is all transactions.
So basically the intention of this table is for every single transaction to be unique in the same.
All right so an intersection isn't based on a person isn't based on the item.
It is based on when that transaction happened right.
And who made that transaction.
So those are some of those things that that can help us identify if that transaction is unique.
So let's let's start looking at that.
Right so it is somebody goes on line somebody's purchase an item and has to be sent to them.
And so here we've got an interesting column time stamps which tells us at which point in time a certain
person purchased a certain item and then it also has the idea of that person.
So the interesting ones that we will want to look at here is the combination of times.
Well first of all can timestamp on its own be a candidate.
Well the answer is no because even though it's to the second because we have quite all of country customers
some over like nine hundred 960 I think 962 customers there is in this database in this table because
we have so many customers it can hypothetically happens.
So that's two different customers purchased in the same time at the same time all the way to the second.
So at the exact same second two customers could indeed purchase it is probably hard to find.
And like you could look through and maybe you'd find that one or two of those examples but the point
is that theoretically it's possible and therefore timestamped cannot be the candidate key.
Right.
If that wasn't possible if we knew for a fact that two customers can purchase same time timestamped
would be a candidate because it would be unique and be real.
But what if we combine timestamp and for example item right what if we say those two fields are those
two attributes are accounted.
Can that be the case.
Well is it is it is more it is much less likely that the the two rows would have the same timestamp
and the same item but it still can happen so two different customers could at the same time purchase
the same item right.
And that could happen.
And therefore this combination wouldn't be a candidate.
But now if you look at timestamp Plus customer ID that's much more interesting because if you think
about it a customer cannot physically make two purchases in the same second.
Right because you have to click the checkout button and clicking the checkout button takes at least
one second.
Right.
So we're going to go off that assumption maybe there are some crazy customers or if you're dealing with
like crazy quick customers or if you're dealing with machines right.
If you're if you're transactions these transactions happening business to business and they're happening
through robots maybe they could purchase in one second.
But in our case we're going to assume that an individual customer a human sitting in front of the computer
for example here Amy Wilkins cannot make two purchases in one second and therefore the customer ID plus
the time stamp will become a unique identifier for every single row because there are no two rows with
the same time stamp and the same customer ID because if there were that would mean that that customer
had made two purchases in one second which we assume to be impossible.
So therefore the timestamp Plus customer id combination the combination of these two columns is another
candidate key of this table.
So what we have is the result is that we have two candidate keys this call by itself and the combination
of these two columns.
Very interesting isn't it.
This whole I like the way you need to think about these things.
I like the logic that goes into coming up with these solutions and these ideas.
And like if you don't you don't even need to check the rest of the rows you can by looking them understand
that there are no more candidate keys in there right.
So but you do need to like practice a little bit to get the hang of it with time.
And that's exactly what we're doing so we're practicing.
And so now we know that there's this is a can do these two the can.
So the question is which of these columns are our prime attributes and which are our non-prime attributes.
So our prime attributes are the first three.
Right so the prime prime attribute is a column that is part of any or part of at least one candidate
key.
So these three columns are all parts of candidate keys and non-prime attributes are comb's which are
not part of any candidate keys and that these columns are here.
These are non-prime attributes.
So now we're going to go back to our definition and check if this table is conform to a second normal
form and our definition said that every non-prime attribute of the table is dependent on the whole of
every candidate.
All right so we're looking just at these columns now because they are the non-prime attributes these
columns and so on from 4 and all the way to the end.
And the question is is each one of these columns dependent on ever on the whole of every candidate.
So here's our first candidate and we're going to investigate all of these calls against this candidate.
Well the answer here is obvious.
The answer is yes because the whole of this candidate key is in deed this candidate key itself right
because it only contains one call me cannot split it apart and therefore because it uniquely identifies
every single row so meaning that this column the first name will depend fully on transactional the surname
and so on.
So by default if the if the candidated consists of only one column by default
that condition is met.
Now let's have a look at this candidate key which consists of two columns.
Right so now we're going to go through all columns here and see if they depend wholly on fully on this
candidate key or part of the candidate keys sufficient to identify them.
Right.
So first name right away let's start here.
So first name does it require both of these columns for.
Do we require both of these columns to identify the person's first name.
Well the answer's no.
We are the customer ID is sufficient to identify the first name.
You don't need the timestamp to the first name will not change if the time stamp changes.
OK.
Interesting.
So there we go we already found one case where the second normal form conditions met.
Let's keep going.
So surname do we need both of these columns to identify surname.
No we don't.
We actually only need customer ID.
Again another call shipping state.
Do we need both or is one column sufficient.
One Colma sufficient the customer ID is sufficient to identify the state item.
Do we need both columns or is one enough in this case we need both.
Right.
We cannot say that by knowing customer I.D. We know what that person purchased because we need to know
at what time they purchased to know exactly what they purchased right.
So you cannot identify that just through the customer ID and also cannot identify just through a timestamp
because again if they could hypothetically be a situation where two people purchase at the same exact
time and they purchase different items then you would not be able to identify what item was purchased
just through the timestamp.
So this call meets the criteria the description of the item.
The same thing basically just like the item that meets the criteria the price.
Again same thing.
You need both of these and the loyalty loyalty discount actually is interesting because loyalty discount
does.
Let's have a look.
So do we need both of these columns to identify the loyalty discount.
Well let's see is the time stamps sufficient.
No the time is not sufficient because just by knowing at what time something was purchased You wouldn't
know you.
You are not able to identify uniquely the loyalty discount.
Why.
Because again that could be hypothetically a situation where two purchases were made exactly at the
same time and they would have different loyalty discount.
That's possible.
So that's how you think about it.
You don't think about it does time to find loyalty discounted.
You just think about what happens if there's two two rows with exactly the same timestamp.
Will it work.
Is it possible that the words you just come can be different.
Yes it is possible that the old discount can be different.
But what about if we take two rows with exactly the same customer ID will it be possible that the loyalty
discount is different yes.
In that case actually no.
In that case it's not possible that the world is going to be different because the loyalty discount
is actually tied to the customer and hence it's tied to the customer ID.
So in this case for the lower discount it is sufficient for us to use just one column to identify the
loyalty discount and therefore this column attribute does not comply with the criteria of the second
normal form.
So our conclusion is that this table is not in second normal form and that these are for column.
So first name surname shipping state and loyalty discount are the columns that do not wholly or fully
depend on every single candidate key and in this case is this candidate that they don't fully depend
on.
And so what is the result or what is the recommendation here that needs.
What do we need to do to make this table conform.
Well it's pretty straightforward.
What we need to do is we need to separate out these four columns these three and this call.
They need to go into a separate table.
Right.
And so that's our conclusion that's how we think about it.
And it does take some time but I find it quite interesting it's like a little little challenge or a
little riddle you have to solve another We've identified the comb's the final step for the second normal
form would be to make this table or turn this design of this current database which only contains one
table.
Turn the design into a different design which would be in second normal form and we're going to continue
that in the next tutorial.
I look forward See you then and until next I'm happy analyzing.