Welcome back to this course.
Super excited super pumped to have you back on board.
Today we're into mania.
This is a Cradle Mountain.
That over there my friends is Crater Lake.
And what is this tutorial like.
Well this trial is all about you because I wanted to say a huge congratulations on completing this course.
I know it wasn't easy.
It was possibly a very difficult journey.
But you've got us through these complex tutorials you made the complex simple you've got to the end.
And you learned all these things from this course and I'm sure you learned a lot.
And I really truly hope that you enjoyed the journey along the way.
So what we're going to do in this tutorial is we're going to throw in quite a few compilations from
Tasmania.
So if you've never been to this part of Australia's island at the bottom of Australia then you'll get
a feel for what it's like here because it's beautiful so just sit back relax and enjoy Tasmania.
And one final thing I did want to ask you before you leave this tutorial and this course is that if
you did enjoy this course and you think that this is a faster horse please read it appropriately we
would love to see your reading and review and hear your feedback.
But most importantly it will help other people from around the world understand what the quality of
this horse is like and so that they can come and learn all these things from here as well.
And I really hope that you can help us out of that.
And on that note let's get started and happy idolizing.