Care I'd like to discuss quickly.
Important Notice before we get started all recommended links and or graphics can easily be found in
PTF format for that lecture.
However not all lectures will have external links or graphics.
Therefore if a lecturer has no PTF then that lecture had no recommended links or graphics for it.
All the external links found inside this course are extremely relevant to each lecturer that has them.
But that being said some of the external links you will obviously need to sign up to access their services
many of which offer free trials.
Some are paid.
I felt it prudent to explain this to you up front.
So things are crystal clear between us.
There are no affiliate links involved inside the main course material.
However I will disclose here that there will be one affiliate link only found in my bonus section.
At the very end of the main course and the link will always be marked as an affiliate.
Next to the link.
The small fee that is paid to me will always go towards my favorite charities such as feeding the homeless
children and seniors worldwide.
All these companies are very relevant in helping you my students succeed in this type of business.
I've included also a table of contents for you to quickly find and locate a topic you wish to refresh
your memory as well since this course is quite extensive and constantly growing.
That's all.
And I'll see you in the next lecture.