In this video then we're going to see how to show and hide user interface elements with our code.
I'm going to do this slightly differently to use you.
And for once I'm going to try not to teach you anything at all so I'm going to suggest that you go to
Google and figure out how to do this.
It really is not that tricky.
And then what I want to end up with is an app with two buttons one saying show and one saying height
and then a text label it doesn't matter what it is.
That of course when you tap hide it hides when you type show it shows.
Simple as that.
And I want you to make the whole thing yourself without me telling you how to do it.
Best of luck.
Go for it.
Did you manage it.
I do apologize if you feel that I'm getting you to do things that you don't know how to do.
But here's how easy it would have been.
I would expect you to search for something like Android.
Show Hide UI elements which is indeed the title of this video and that very top result there how can
I hide show an element when a button is presumably clicked or press Yep.
Perfect.
Then we have a little look there and we see.
Interesting so I don't really care about this table layout stuff but this set.
Visibility sounds perfect.
So that was it.
That's the only new bit of code which was very easily find a ball by Google.
Obviously I'm not doing this because I want to be lazy and to force you to work everything out for yourself
but I'm doing it because I want you to see how easy it is to learn new things completely on your own.
And of course at some point you're going to get to the end of this course and there's going to be a
bunch of new things that you still want to learn.
So learning this technique of what to search for what to look for going online and finding the answer
to your problems is very very important.
It also helps when debugging.
So now that we've seen that let's create application sharing and hiding UI elements.
And then all we need to do is create our two buttons and I'm going to use the default text that appears
there as my element to show and hide.
So it should be fairly straightforward.
Here we get sort of caught Hello World them double click to see the ID.
It's my only text view so I'm just going to call it text.
And then we're dragging two buttons.
So that first one is going to be show with an ID of show button
and you will update all of those and then hide it and we'll give it an ID of Hide button every guy.
Then we just need to set the own clicks.
Hyde
is going to be hide and show he's going to be show.
All right.
So now what we need to be is set up
reference to the label.
Now we're going to need to access that from other methods.
So let's set it up here first off is going to be a text
and it's called textfield
and then we find it down him so text free.
His equals a text free
find view by id Artaud ID dot text view.
OK then we just need to create our methods for the buttons.
So public Foyt show
it's called by the view.
So we need to be ready to accept that
the framework for a view and then we just need to take a text view.
And just in case you've forgotten what the code was it was set visibility and then viewed or visible
so set visibility few dot visible Exham sounds promising.
And then public voit hide exactly the same.
Well the text VI don't set visibility I don't think we need to google this separately.
Few dot invisible seems like it would be the code to make it invisible right.
So let's just check that.
Make sure it's behaving as we want it to.
We use the same device we use for the time app.
There we go.
So if we stay on the top hide first to do something and show hide show wonderful.
Simple as that.
I hope you did manage to figure it out using a bit of Google X to get to make a fairly substantial app
is going to be our brain train app.