Let's talk about app ratings now app ratings much like app reviews is another strong social proof indicator
for new users to drive them to want to download giraffe.
If your ratings were low it's going to suck to be quite honest.
You can never force your users to want to rate your app but it can never hurt to ask them though so
please do the following.
Always ask your buddies or mates for a few five star reviews to get started and give you a much needed
push.
Hire someone for a few bucks to give you a five star rating.
Find my highly recommended place in my bonus section at the end of this course.
This is black hat so use with caution.
Make it easy for unhappy users to contact you before they leave negative ratings or reviews offer upgrades
and promo codes for five star reviews display a pop up asking for a review from people who use your
app often.
This can however annoy people if done too much.
So be careful on the timing.
OK I'll see you in the next lecture.