Lists another user interface type that's really handy for displaying information and getting interaction
with the user.
In Android where.
So they look something like that and they're pretty easy to create mostly because they work in exactly
the same way as list views.
So I'm just going to copy the code for the wearable list view down here and the next it goes inside
frame layouts.
So we can leave it frame layout as it is but we can add in our list view.
That is the idea of wearable underscore list and I'll just do the same for our rectangular layout as
well.
There we go and I'll get rid of the fragment code from the previous video and also get rid of text view
as we're not using that anymore.
The process of setting up a wearable list view is a little bit different and rather more convoluted
than setting up a normal Android list.
So let's go over to our guide here and use the sample code to get this all set up.
So we've already added to the wearable list view in our lay out CML.
We now need to set up a layout implementation which is simply which essentially will just define the
layout of each of the items in the list view.
So I'm going to copy this code and then we'll run through it and see what it means.
So this will be a new class so I'll add it here.
So we just want a new Java class
and we'll call it the same thing as it did up here so wearable list item lay out
OK I'm going to keep a package at the top but I'm going to paste in everything else.
So we're going to simplify this AFAB it will just add everything in
to get started.
OK.
So let's take a look.
We've created a class called wearable list item layout which extends linearly outskirts based upon linear
layouts and it uses the on center proximity Lisner which essentially looks to check which item in the
list view is in the center.
So you can see that we've got a different layout for the center item.
It's got a different color circle it's bigger and bolder than the other list items as well.
So that's what the on center proximity listener is then we've got our image view and text view the image
view is the icon there and the texture is obviously contains the text list item one list item 2 etc..
Then we've got some numbers here to represent how much the faded text should be faded.
The faded circle color and the chosen circle color it's all reasonably self-explanatory.
This defines the context for the item lay out which is going to be the wearable list view and this defines
the attributes for the list item layout.
Now in this method we're defining the style which essentially involves defining the colors and faded
ness of the circle.
So we've got our grey and blue here.
Now that's fine but we don't have the actual text faded Alpha integer built in to this version of Android.
So I'm just going to change that to say no point seven and we'll see how that looks.
I mean you need to specify that that's a flight.
So the bigger the number here the darker the faded text will be the smaller the number the lighter it
will be.
All right working our way down now the finish inflate method is called When The View has been inflated
which you'll remember means either selected to be a rectangular or round view and then created sets
the same as the what will happen when the on lay out inflated listener is called.
It just means it's chosen the rectangular and round all round layout and then created the views within
those.
Now you can see we're expecting an image view and a text view in those layouts but we haven't added
those yet.
So that's why we've got this area here.
Don't worry about that we'll add them in a minute and then we've got on center position that this will
be called when a certain item in the list view becomes central and that essentially just changes the
circle to blue and sets the Alpha to 1.
So it's going to be fully dark and then when it goes off center the circle becomes the circle color
which is gray and sets the Alpha to our.
Now for that we set up there which is no point 7.
OK.
So that's what this new class is doing for us.
Let's now at
the lay out.
So this is where we add our image view and our text view.
So we're going to create this as a new layout and we'll use the same lie naming.
Here's a list underscore item to SML.
So let's add our new layout a new Windows file and list underscore item axonal.
It doesn't matter all of the settings because we're going to get rid of the default code anyway.
And then let's scrap all of that and paste in what we've got here.
OK.
So all of this should more or less make sense.
We've got less width and height there and then in each list item which is what this is it's a list item
layouts.
We've got an image view and a text view.
Now errors here are to do with that particular text follow color which isn't in our strings because
we haven't added it so I'm just going to get rid of the text color.
Now this circle doesn't exist either.
And so we're actually going to need to create it which is something that we haven't done before.
But I'll show you how to do it here.
We can actually create shapes inside the drawable directory so we can create a horrible resource file
I'll call it circle or SML and then we can use SML to draw certain shapes.
So if for example we want a circle
we can look for Android SML or circle something like that.
And then this start one here.
How can I draw a circle through Ex-Im eligible.
Let's find out.
So that one's got a gradient which we don't want.
So let's try and keep it simpler.
No I think that one is quite the answer that we're after.
So let's go for the second one.
Here we go.
This looks more straightforward.
So this will create a general oval shape.
But if we don't set different widths and heights then it will just be a circle and we'll leave for the
moments the color width and height setting we might need to change those later on.
But the important thing is now we can go back to list item and select drawable circle and that will
then link up to this circle Torex metafile that we created up there.
So that's how you add a general circle to your apps without having the need for a circle image.
OK so now we specified the layout of each individual list item.
So next we need an adapter.
And it's a fair bit more complicated than how simple array adapter that we created last time.
So we need a separate class for it.
So I'm going to add that in the same way here.
So a new Java class and we'll call it adapter
and then again Alief the package definition and then paste in everything else.
That all of the classes
nearly that you'll run through and see what this code is doing.
And we don't need that to be private or static so it will just define it there.
We can make it public.
OK.
So this class adapter is similar to a re adapter but it takes the wearable list view adapter and provides
some customizations.
So first off it's got an array of strings called data set.
That's what we're going to use to contain our content.
It's also got a context and I lay out inflata which will use a little bit later on here.
We're defining a constructor.
So this is a definition of how we would create an adapter and we're saying that the code would need
two things that would need to know the context of the adapter and it would need to know the data set.
So the array of strings with which we want to populate our list view then it takes the context from
that it takes the lamp infer data from the context the context of course would just be our main activity
and then it takes its data set from the set that we passed to it right.
Then it creates a number class called item view holder which is how we work with the list item direct
XML which is what controls the layout of each individual list item.
And then
the main thing that we're doing here is finding the text view within that view holder or just within
that list item.
And the reason that we're not finding the image view here is because we don't need to do anything with
the image the image is just built in to each list item and doesn't change from one list item to the
other.
But we do want to try and change the text view for each item member the image view does change but it
changes here when they send to position on the nonsense position is detected.
So now that we've got the text view we're going to be able to do something with it.
So here we are inflating our item view holder which is just another way of saying create the individual
list item and it creates it with a layout of the generic list item which allows us to put whatever we
like inside it.
Then this method is called when the individual list item is created and what it's doing is create creating
an item holder which is this class up here which you can say has just got a text view inside it and
then it finds the text view and replaces its contents with the item in that dataset which is the data
that we passed to this class to appear on the list view.
And it also sets a tag which is quite handy so the tag is going to be the position 0 1 2 3 etc..
And then finally it's got a method which is required for adapter's get item count which obviously just
returns the number of items in M dataset.
So the number of items in our list view.
OK.
A lot to get to grips with.
We will miss them.
So that's our adapter to populate the list.
And then finally we have our code in the own create method.
So I'm going to copy that first
and we'll deal with the last bits afterwards.
So that goes back in main activity and we'll do it here.
So we tracked down our list view which is out wearable list so that's what we're working with.
And then we set our adapter so this is we're now creating our adapter class or our custom adapter class
that we've just made and we're passing to it.
The context this and this is where we create our list of items that we want to appear on our list view.
There's a code for that.
So they've defined it up there which is fine
I think I'll make it a little bit more custom
I'll have the usual suspects.
Rob Caston Tommy and Ralphie and we got a couple of issues here.
The first is actually I've made a mistake creating this adapter class where I did it should actually
be inside the main activity class so that we can access it from there.
So I'm just going to cut everything from there and then delete that class and then I'm going to paste
it just inside main activity there and it does indeed actually need to be private and static so that
we can instantiate it down here.
OK.
So you move your code over to there.
Now I've got an issue here because there are various built in classes called adapter as you can see
there.
So I'm actually going to rename it to my adapter capital M because it's a class just so that I can
be very clear which one way using.
So now we've got my adapter instead of adapter.
One remaining issue is that the this here refers to the on Louds inflated listener because we're inside
that method at the moment.
We want to refer to main activity so we'll use main activity at this.
And similarly here for the set click listener we want main activity this but that will give us an issue
because we need to implement the click listener to main activity but we can do that automatically.
There we go.
So our main activity now implements wearable list view Topcliffe listener and that gives it two methods
on click and on top empty region click.
And if we just go back over to the code that we didn't copy there it is.
So there's a on click.
So this is what's going to happen when the user taps on one of the items in the table.
So they're using the we're using View holda So that will get the tag of the item that was tapped.
And I think we'll just log it for now.
Say in Faye
Ambleside item tappets
is an integer so we'll convert it to a string and get the tag.
And then on top empty region click it's just if the user clicks on the empty region at the top of the
screen.
And as they did we'll just leave that blank because we're not interested in that.
We're only interested in them clicking on the list.
Fear Itself
OK.
So let's just move these imports to where they should be up here.
And then let's get this again.
So we've written a lot of code then unfortunately because of the way it all interacts with each other
there wasn't an easy point at which we could test it.
So we'll test it now and keep our fingers crossed.
To check that we haven't made any mistakes.
We've done quite a lot of advance work with classes there and we've also created our circle drawable.
So there's a few new things going on and we do have an area I'm afraid.
I thought I'd leave that in for you because it's a reasonably used for one to debug So if we have a
quick look at the error message didn't find class condoled example the Android support wearables occasions
don't wear list item.
And if we scroll up to see where that's actually being generated it's when we're trying to inflate an
SML file.
So my suspicions go towards this list item which you remember we just copy and pasted right in and there.
In fact you can see we've got an example the Android support et cetera.
That's the wrong package name.
So all we need to do is change that to our package name rather than the example one which of course
we should have done earlier.
So Conder example the Ropers of older Android where demo where a list item lay out so that's the one
that we want and then we need to change the closing tag as well.
Let's do that automatically.
So now down at the bottom we've got the right closing tag to.
All right let's try that again
and there we get we've got our really nicely laid out list and we can browse through it and see what
happens when we do our topping
or tap on.
We get item number one tapped noticed that we can only tap on the central item if I tap on Tommy then
it just selects Tommy in the middle it doesn't actually consider that a tap as far as we were concerned
there.
I'd have to tap on it again to get actually something to happen.
That's just how the UI works.
All right so I hope you managed to follow me through with all of that.
A lot of new stuff that you might want to watch that video again if you want some clarification on some
of the issues or have a read of the Android Developer material on lists.
So I wanted to do a separate video on that one because it is such a big set up process but hopefully
that makes reasonable sense now.
And you can see how to use lists which are a really useful user interface element on Android where.