All right it's now time to finally start building our Instagram up and we're going to begin with the
log in and sign up screen which will look like this.
So it's pretty straightforward in terms of layout.
We've got our Instagram logo at the top.
We've got usernames and passwords filled with nice hints to tell the user what today.
And then we have a sign up button to run the process.
I've also added a text view which will switch between Sign up and log in Moat's.
So it's a nice easy way to display two different modes on one screen.
And the way it works is the way you would expect if we enter a user name
and maybe we don't enter a password then it tells us that the username and password are required.
If we do enter a password and attempt to sign up then from now it just looks Sign-Up successful.
So it doesn't go onto a second screen or anything we'll do that later on.
But if we try and do something it Arrhenius like sign up with a user name that already exists it will
tell us the message directly from Pos.
Similarly with logging in I can log in using a correct username and password and that will give me a
logon successful message but if I try and use an incorrect one then I get a message saying invalid username
and password and that's returned directly from pass.
So that's what we're trying to do.
All the knowledge that you need.
We have already covered.
So best of luck time to pause the video and give it a shot go for it.
All right.
Well I'll begin over an activity maybe direct them out and I'll start by grabbing a nice image to pop
at the top them.
So as always the warning when you're using Google Images If you're just making an app for fun that's
fine.
But if you're using the image in a real app
make sure you have the rights to say so so I'm just going to grab the Instagram logo and pick one that
I think will work.
Well have a look.
This one Greg
a thousand by 4 6 4 which is about right.
So save image as.
And I'll just put it that
on the desktop
and then find it in find the old Windows Explorer if your windows and just before I add it I'm going
to remove the underscore and the hyphen as they can cause problems.
Android studio so I'll just call it Instagram logo top PMG and then command control C to copy it and
then back over to Android studio.
And if we don't have a drawable folder there we need to add one control click new directory or right
click new directory on Windows and then we'll call it drawable and then control or command V to paste
our Instagram logo image in.
Great.
Now we're going to delete our text you.
And we're going to drag in an image for you in the usual way.
And because we're now running Android studio 2.2 it's going to automatically request an image.
So just start typing Instagram and there it is
so click OK and there we go.
So let's just adjust this slightly.
So let's just change out with too much parent and then our height or try changing it to say 50 piece
ok maybe a little more 70 deep.
We're not really worried about layout here it's the log in and sign up the way I'm most focused on.
OK.
So that will do.
Now let's bring in
our text field.
So we'll start with a plain text one for the username
game
I will put the instructions right in there into your user.
And we don't want a default value every day.
And then same for password
yeah we'll keep it as text password and enter your password.
OK.
And then finally we'll need a button
which will initially say
Sign-Up.
All right.
So that will do for our layout.
Now we'll just need to set some IDs so this will be a user name and it's text update that everywhere
in
password and it text
update that everywhere and then sign up
button with an on click of sign.
All right.
So that all looks good.
Now let's go back over to Main activity and write out code.
So essentially we want to run all our code when the sun button is tapped and we want to attempt to sign
the user up using pass.
So let's have a go.
We'll get rid of the code we had before.
And then we'll create a method
which I just remind myself what it was called
Sign up
and this of course will be called by a view that is the button which will just call.
So we'll need to get the username and password values from the added text Sam
so that's defined dies.
So use a name and it text
and this is going to be an added text.
Found by its ID and the ideas Oh Id dot use and I'm at it text
and the same for the password at it text.
This is going to be an added text.
Find it by its ID ID dot password and it text.
So I'll start by doing a quick check to see if either of those will be blank.
So if
use an added text doc get text doc to string is equal say an empty string or
password at it text.
Don't get text dot to string is empty.
Then we'll do a toast
username and password required.
If that's not the case then we'll attempt to sign the user up
so we'll create a new parse user called up she's going to be a new person on
them will set the user name to use a name and it text don't get text dot to string will set the password
to password and it text or get text to string then we'll take you to and sign them up in the background
with a new sign up Colback and then we'll check to see if
our error is null and if it is for now we'll just log
Sign-Up
successful
and if it's not we'll let the user know so toast
creates a new taste.
And I'm just going to display the message from the past exception so let's see how we might do that.
So we don't want quite the two string.
We saw that before and that gives us a bunch of extra bits of data that we probably don't want to display
to the user.
But if we look here I get a message that looks like a very relevant thing.
So let's try that out and see if that works.
All right so now we should have a working Sign-Up up system that checks for the existence of a username
and password.
And if these are entered both then it attempts to sign the user up and if that fails then it will display
a message to the user.
All right let's have a look.
And here we go.
So first off let's test what happens if I try and sign up.
And interestingly we get this error here.
The user name cannot be missing or blank.
And I thought I'd leave that error in because it's a very common one that if you want to check a string
is equal to a number string in Java.
You should use match's.
So we use dot matches and then the empty string
just like that.
So if you try to use the double equals that does work in some circumstances.
But here we need to use dot matches and then the empty string.
So let's try that again.
Sign up and now we get a username and password are required.
So now let's put in a new username and a new password.
And click sign up and then let's have a quick look in the logs.
Sign up successful that looks promising.
So now we jump over to the Firefox and have a quick refresh.
We should have a new user.
There we go with the right user name in our user class and then we can actually do a test for an error
just by clicking sign up again because now there should already be a user with that username.
Excellent.
So we get a nice error message as well.
Great.
So now sign up system is working fine.
We just need to add the facility to log in as well.
And the way I'm going to do that is to add the facility to change this from a sign up form to a log
in form.
Now we could do that via a button but then having two buttons that do such different things but looks
similar would be a bit strange.
So what I'm going to do is bring in a text view just to the right of the sign up button.
Just scroll around.
There we go like that.
And this text FYI is going to have an ID of change sign up mode.
Textfield and the text
is going to be or logon
and irrigations is going to move it slightly to the right a little bit away from the button.
You can see it's nicely positioned relative to the button.
The other thing I'm going to do is just change its color a little so it looks like something that you
might click rather than just some text
they click on the three dots color and I'll go for that dark blue there.
That would get
and then get rid of the properties and just copy the ID because only need that.
So we have made a text view interactive before.
But if you don't remember how to do it don't worry we do it using the general on click method and to
use that we need to implement few dot on click listener and we can now use the general on click method
and this method will now be called when ever there is a tap anywhere on the screen.
And we want to check.
You can see this is going to be called by a view.
We want to check to see if the view was the
or logon text view so we can do that by looking at the ID of the view that was tapped.
So if you don't get I.D. and see if that's equal to the resources ID thoughts change sign up text textfield
and Finnell let's just log
on the app info
change sign up mode.
So just to be sure that that connection is a wired up correctly and that this method is being called.
And then just before we run that in the uncreate method we need to add an on click listener to our text
view.
So let's create a text view which will call change sign up text me.
And this is going to be a text view using find VBIED resources dot ID to change sign up mode text.
And then we're going to change sunnat mode text VI and we're going to set an on click listener and the
listener is just this I need this activity because this has got this on click method within it.
OK so now we've applied our own click listener to our change sign up mode.
Text me and we are checking just to be very sure.
Even though the text is the only thing with an on click listener we are still verifying that it is indeed
the text view that's been tapped.
So let's have a let.
Once this is up and running we're going to change our code so that when the text is tapped it changes
sign up to log in and we're going to have a boolean to essentially store the state of the app to tell
us whether we're in sign mode or logging mode.
For now though let's just tap check that that's working.
And it is wonderful OK.
So now we'll need our Boullion.
As I mentioned So let's create a boolean variable and I'll call it sign up mode active and initially
we'll set it to be true.
OK so now we'll check to see if it's on up mode active is true.
In fact we could make that even neater and just use sign mode active itself as it is a billion.
So if it is we want to do a few things
first we'll change the sign up button text to logon.
So the ID is sign up button.
So let's get that.
So we're going to need a button called Sign up button which is going to be a button using find view
by id and then the idea is to ID dot sign up button.
And in fact we're going to need that either way.
So I'm going to define that out here.
And while we're defining things we're also going to need this change sign made.
Text V.
So actually what alday is o define it out here so we can access it from both locations.
And then if the sun is active if we want to change to logon mode.
So first we'll set sign up mode active to volts then we'll take our sign up button
and set the text to logon and then we'll change our change sun mode text V and we'll set the text for
that too.
All comma
Sign-Up.
So there's three commands combined should changes from sign up mode to logging mode
and if Sun mode is not active then we need to do essentially the opposite of those three.
So switch from logging mode to sign up mode so sign up mode active becomes true again
when you sign up for the text of the sign up button and or Colmer log in for the text view.
All right.
So let's just check that that that works.
And once we've done that we've only got one thing left to do and that is change our sign up method to
check to see whether we're in sign mode or logging mode and sign up or log accordingly.
And here we go.
So let's give it a try top day or log in and there we go.
So you can see that switch is nicely for the user.
Now let's do our check over here.
So we're going to want to check for the presence of a user name and password.
Either way there's only here that we want to see if we're in Sign-Up mode or not and if we are
we'll run our sign up process or if not we'll now write out log in code.
So hopefully you remember this past user dot log in in background and then we'll start with the username
so that username and it text don't get text talk to stream then the password so password at text doc
get text to string and then call back.
So I knew Logan Colback
he would go.
So again I'm going to check for the existence of
a user.
And for now
we'll just log log and successful
and if that's not the case then we'll do the same as before.
So I sent the message of the exception.
All right.
So let's have a look.
We should now have a complete sign up or log in system using past server.
All right.
So let's try out a Logan first try a blank one.
Excellent.
That is good.
Then we'll try one that won't work.
Log in and a valid username password.
Brilliant.
And now I have to try and remember
what I said.
For my username and password log in.
So it looks like that's worked.
Let's have a look.
In successful.
Wonderful.
So you now have I sign up and logon system that could be used for absolutely any app.
So feel free to use this as a basis for any app that you're making that requires a sign up or logging.
OK we're now going to divert slightly from our Instagram app and just improve this log in and sign up
set up in a couple of ways.
So first I'd like the user to be able to remove this keyboard when they tap elsewhere on the screen
just in case this keyboard hides the logon button.
That means that they wouldn't be able to log in.
And secondly I'm going to make it so that when we tap the tick button there it actually attempts the
log in process.
There's more of a natural flow for a log in an app.
We'll see how to do both of those things in the next video.