This we we're going to look at as you liked and a bit more detail and see some more advanced things
that we can do with it.
The First off very quick challenge.
Can you change this code back into the users database and add two more users with any name and age you
like go for it.
I'm sure you manage that one.
So all we need to do is change everything back.
In fact we don't need this line at all anymore because the table that we need definitely exists.
And then we want to insert was just name wasn't it that we had and H.
And then we will add cost and we'll give her the young age of 21.
And we mustn't forget Ralphy of course
we get.
And then we just take these two name
and age
and name and age should probably update as well although of course it will work fine.
I use
That's what they were.
OK so just checking that we've got all of the uses.
I'll probably have a couple of other uses as well for my testing and it would be good to update this
as well to the correct table name.
And there we go.
We've got our users there.
We've got Kirsten a couple of times which is not a problem and all I'm going to do is apply this to
use the results so we can get exactly what we need.
All right so the first thing we're going to see is some more advanced queries.
So let's say we wanted to get everyone below the age of 18.
That's very easy today using ask you Will we just put a command at the end of how queried that says
where and then we want age to be less than 18.
Simple as that.
And this general welfare clause we can use to restrict the search for any particular type of data in
our database.
And you can see it's only returned Tommy and Ralphy that we could search for a particular user name.
That's obviously very useful if you're trying to lock someone in or something like that.
So we would just say where name is equal to a Keston
and then we check that out.
And that should just return the to Keston entries.
And there they are.
OK.
If you want to combine more than one search criteria you can do that with the end command.
So if we wanted to look for the name being cast and the age being say 22 we know that that's not going
to return anything.
So we get no new results there every day.
But if we search for a name is and age is 21 then we should get to cast on results.
There again we can also do fancy things and for example if we wanted everyone that had a user name that
started with k then we can do names like and then K and then a percent symbol and the percent symbol
essentially means anything.
So that will search for anyone who has a user name with a K at the beginning and then anything.
So we've got cast and again that we could also search for anyone who had a user name with an O in it
for example never got 2 percent signs present at the beginning and said percent at the end and that
just searches for anything and then an O.
And then anything else that should return me and tell me there we go.
So Rob and Tommy returned we can limit the number of results here.
So let's say we just want one person with an 0 in their in their name.
We just put limits one there so that should return just me began
so that basic database queries.
There's much more advanced stuff that you can do.
But that should cover the vast majority of what you need.
And if you need to do anything else just search for Eskew well and then whatever you want to do because
this is as I say a standard server query language that has been around for a long time and is well-documented
on the Web.
OK.
So a couple of other things then.
First off let's see how we delete a user.
So for example we've got these duplicate caissons him I begin to get rid of one of those so there's
any one of them so we can do that.
Using events D-B exec as well.
And we're still using events maybe I think that's not a major problem even though we're using the user's
D.B and the commands to delete from a database it just delete from and then the table name so users
and then you just pick your limitations.
So I'm going to say when name is equal to
Keston if I do that of course it will delete both of them.
So I'm going to put a limit one on the end and that will delete only one Caston.
In fact whenever you're updating or deleting a database I would always recommend putting a limit on
the end because if there's a tiny chance that you've forgotten your where clause or there's just some
bad code.
If it ends up deleting your whole database by mistake or updating a value to the same thing for every
row for example that can be a bit of a disaster.
It's happened to me before.
And so I would always strongly recommend putting limit one at the end of all your delete or update statements
where you expect a new one row to be deleted.
OK.
So we'll just run that again.
And we should now get all of those users.
But we'll have just the one Caston.
Now it's actually getting a little bit tricky to see which are the results from this running of the
app which are previous ones so I'm going to show you a way to clear the logs every time we run the app.
So I just went to run and edit configurations and then I'm going to click like cat and click log before
launch.
So that's probably quite a good default setting because it's unlikely you're going to want the logs
of previous launches for very long anyway.
So let's say we wanted to update one of these values and say change the age of someone in our database.
Then we take events TV and execute execute and Eskew statement which would look like this.
So we update users and then let's say we want to update after being to say we set
age is equal to 2.
And then we give our limit.
So where name equals Ralphy.
Simple as that.
And that as I say is very standard as well.
So let's have a look now you can see I've got the same results but Ralphy is now two and we can use
exactly the same where clauses as we looked at when we did they select statements.
So now we know how to update existing records add new ones do quite advanced queries and loop through
the result of them as just a couple more things I want to show you.
And first of all is deleting from the database.
So let's say for example we want to delete Ralphy for some reason then all we do is delete from
uses.
And then I wear clothes so I wear name equals Ralphy
simple as that.
Now when we run that we should get the same results as before.
But with no Ralphy that we get.
So Rob told Tommy and Keston one slightly odd thing or at least I think it's slightly odd about eschewing
light is that you can't just pop a limit on the end of a delete query.
So for example I wanted to get rid of one of the questions there then you might think I do that.
And indeed that works fine in my school.
But we can't do that on a school like so before we see how to do that.
I'm going to introduce the idea of an ID and really recommend having an ID in any table that you use
because it's a way of referring to each row uniquely which may be difficult if you've got two rows that
are identical like we have here.
So before we try and delete Caston or at least one other.
Unfortunately we can't add a primary key column to a table after it's been created.
So we're going to need to create a new table which is fine.
Reminds us how to do it.
So we want to create a table if it doesn't exist.
And I'll just call it new uses and this is going to have the same as before.
So it's going to have a name which is a.
And integer.
Sorry.
H.
Which is going to be an integer with three digits.
But now we're also going to have an ID which is going to be an integer and also a primary key.
So this primary key will auto increment which means it will start at 1 and then increase by 1.
Every time we add a new row to the table.
So let's just add a couple of ways.
OK.
That all remains the same.
And then we just close that bracket so if we take a look now we should find that we have Kasson and
Ralphy in our table and
nobody else but they will also have primary keys
so that they are Keston Ralphy
let's just create a column here so that we can see our primary key.
So is the idea.
And I'm happy to add them again because I'm going to delete one of them anyway.
There we go.
So you can see we've got cast and Ralphie cast and Ralphie.
But this time they've got an ID which is always unique.
So even if I started eating or messing around with various that ID will always be unique.
So now if I wanted to get rid of one of those curtains instead of having to refer to their name or age
I can
refer to the idea which is a much better way of deleting anyway.
So if I delete where ID equals one then that will only delete the one user.
And so because the ID key is unique that will only ever delete one item in the table.
So lets take a look.
We should now have just one Keston and two Rafi's but it would help if I change this to new users.
Otherwise I'm deleting from the wrong table.
So checking that now.
We really should just have one Caston and two Rafi's And there you go.
You can see the first one is gone but we're left with the rest and that's probably all you'll need to
do with databases in your apps.
We can now create them we can create tables within them we can add items to those tables.
We can update and delete items as we need to and then we can select the items using a range of criteria
and then loop through the results and do something with them.
All right so we're going to be using all of that and how how can you use app that we can make at the
end of this section.
But we've got one more thing to learn about before we can do that.
And that is where the views and we'll see what they are and how we can use them in the next lecture.