All right let's talk about expert app pricing strategies here choosing the right business model plays
a big part in your app success journey.
There are several models paid fleetly free free with ads.
And lastly freemium.
The last free with in-app purchases is said to be the most profitable if you choose to go the paid route.
You can always start out free to build up ratings and reviews and then test the waters and say 50 percent
off this week only for air launch or particular holiday or Black Friday here in the USA.
For those who choose the paid model there are a few circumstances when you can go down to this route
and they are if you have an extremely unique one of a kind that a huge following such as on YouTube
or Facebook Twitter or any other social media outlet or when you just dont have an app purchase strategy
viable for your app.
The going rate is 99 cents or a dollar ninety nine and 299 for paid apps for both Apple and Android.
But it can range anything higher will be a problem unless its a super dynamically unique app that doesnt
have any free or non-free competition.
Obviously games that have hundreds working on it.
That took a year or more to build.
Can ask for a 999 purchase and its from a well-established company.
So even if you choose to go paid.
I always start out the first week free to get much needed downloads and reviews to boost your rankings
and success.
Always schedule any price changes to coordinate with your own promotion activities or holidays or special
dates.
Always consider temporary price cuts to boost downloads which helps increase your downloads in the hopes
to increase your ranking in reviews.
You must do market research on apps in your category to discover the best pricing practices and always
offer your users a good deal and that keep it on the low side because asking for that extra dollar may
cost you a few negative reviews that will do more harm than good.
And I'll see you in the next lecture.