One of the big new features added in Android New up is multi window support and this allows your apps
to run side by side with other apps and even share information with them.
So in this video we're going to see how to enable that in your apps and customize the user experience.
For example setting default and minimum widths for your apps in a split screen mode.
So let's jump right him over to Android studios start a new project and we'll call it a split screen
demo.
Next and he will switch to Android 7.
You don't need a minimum SDK of Android 7 here if you want to support other devices then you can do.
And if it is not running Android 7 then any attempt at doing the split screen mode will just fail but
will go for Android 7.
The purposes of this demo and then our usual empty activity with main activity here we go.
So we begin in the Android manifest file where we set the attributes that allow us to use the split
screen modes and the first one is resizable activity and will set that to be true.
So this will allow your app to use the multi window mode.
There's also another mode we can activate within the activity itself called Picture in Picture So if
we enable that as well.
That's ideally used for something like watching a video and then you can have that video appear over
the top of for example a web page.
So once you've been able to both of those you can of course just choose one but you can have picture
in picture without resizable activity being true in the documentation for multi window support it gives
the option to add layout instructions here in as well where we can do things like Android default height
and then give it a default height of for example 500 pixels.
We can also set the gravity if we want that to work differently to usual
in split screen mode and we can set
the minimum height and the minimum width to say 300 pixels.
So I'm actually getting a message here saying that the layout element is not allowed here.
So I suspect this has not been officially added yet but you should definitely try that out if you want
to specify the full height of gravity or minimum weight or height.
All right so now we've enabled multi window mode.
There are a few things that we can do in code as well so we can call the method is in multi window mode
to find out if we're in multi window mode.
We are in
multi window mode so if you want your app to behave differently in multi window mode then you can use
this boolean to detect which measure in and act accordingly.
You can do the same thing for it in picture in picture mode.
So if you are showing video there you might want to reduce the video controls for example.
We can also use the on multi window changed method.
And this will be called whenever the mood changes so you can then call one of these to see whether we've
gone into or out of multi window mode or into or out of picture in picture mode.
Has Changed.
All right.
So that's pretty much all there is to it.
Actually quite easy to activate in order to test it out.
We will need a new DVD and or a virtual device because we'll need one fast running Android and so I'll
download the 60 bit version of nigger there and this will then just download and install and enable
us to use that in our virtual device.
And then again I finish and then most select system image next and finish
and then we'll press play to launch that virtual device.
And when it's ready will run up on that emulator and TV again we're up and running.
So let's now run our app on the new Android 7 device.
And here we go.
So to activate our split screen mode we long press on the square but man you can see it turns into a
split screen symbol and then we can select from our recent app so I've just used the gallery then if
you haven't used any recent apps then nothing will appear there.
So you just need to use something else like the gallery or the browser.
So if we tap a map
simple as that we've now enabled split screen mode with another app we can obviously get rid of split
screen right if we want to just by dragging down from the center.
That again
that will move us back into a normal full screen mode.
All right so that's how you enable and manage multi window mode on your apps.
I hope you enjoy that and in a good way of integrating it into your latest app.