This video we're going to go back to our x y dot com because we're going to be looking at something
which is pure Java and not really to do with Android specifically.
Having said that we're going to use what we're about to learn in Android to download some web content
and we'll use the same structure in lots of the lectures and projects throughout the course try and
catch might sound like a fun ball game.
But actually it's a way of stopping our app from crashing if it experiences an era.
So let's jump straight in and see how it works.
So click try next to Hello World to get our basic hello world code which you should remember from the
first few videos.
And then just run that code clicking Start and you can see we get the output Hello world.
So now I'm going to give you a couple of very small challenges.
And the first is to create an integer array which has room for three different objects.
So an integer array that has room for three different numbers.
Remember it's an array not an array list.
So if you can remember how to do that.
Go for it.
I hope you managed to create an integer array we use it.
And then the square brackets to show that we want an array and then I'll call it array but of course
you can call it whatever you like.
And then it's going to be a new integer array.
And we're going to specify that it has room for three numbers like that.
So remember an array is different to an array list because it has a fixed number of items in it whereas
an array list we can have as many different items as we want.
All right.
I'll forgive you if you didn't remember that because we haven't used arrays since we first met them
back in chapter 3.
This next bit though should be fine.
Can you create a for loop which sets the values of the three integers in our array to 0 1 and 2 respectively.
Go for it
OK.
How do you manage that one.
So we're going to use a for loop.
And in our follow up we're going to create an integer i which is initially going to be 0.
We're going to keep going as long as I have less than three.
You could have used less than or equal to two there but OK for the Possibly simpler option of less than
three.
And we're going to increase I each time.
So I plus plus
10 we use our Kelli brackets to contain our folly.
And we're just getting to set array by equal to.
Simple as that.
And then just to make sure it's worked I'm going to use a system out to print line and to print that
to the console.
We're going to need to convert it to a string which we do with arrays dot to string and then our array.
So that just converts the array to a string so we can view it in the console in order for that to work
we're going to need to import the arrays package.
So that's import.
Java don't you tell Dot arrays OK.
Let's take a look.
We should now see our array is filled with 0 1 2.
Fantastic so all all well and good so far all fairly straightforward.
What if for some reason in our code we've decided to try and add four items into this integer array.
Now obviously that's not going to work because we are only allowed three.
So let's just see what happens if we run our code now we get what's known as an exception which is essentially
just an error in our code.
And if we got this in one of our Android apps the whole app would crash just really the one user experience
we want to avoid at all costs.
So obviously the best solution for that is to not get the error in the first place.
But there are some cases in which we can't guarantee that we won't get an error if for example we try
and download some information from the Internet and the user doesn't have their Internet connection
up and running.
We're going to get an exception.
We don't want our app to crash just because that happens.
So this is where I try and catch come in.
And the way it works is quite simple.
We take a try.
And then we put curly brackets around the code that we want to try.
So we are literally trying out this code and we accept that there's a chance that this may fail.
So what we then D is catch the exception or catch the error essentially and we normally put it like
that say catch and then we create a variable of a type of exception so exception with a capital A.
And then we normally call the exception literally to keep things simple.
And then what we then do is put our code that we want to happen if we get an error in here so for now
we'll just print it to this console system out to print line.
There we go.
So let's run that now.
And you can see I've got a separate area.
Maybe you spotted that I actually put my try curly brackets around the whole thing rather than just
the folder.
So leave that in because some of you might have done that.
There we go.
So you can see what's happened now is that we've printed out era just there but crucially the app hasn't
crashed.
We haven't actually had an exception because we caught the exception and in this way in this case we
just printed it to the logs but we could have done something that we could have alerted the user to
something that went wrong.
If for example they didn't have their internet connection.
So the most important thing is that it hasn't crashed.
But we've also been able to alert the user to a problem and hopefully they can change whatever it is
about their system that caused that problem in the first place.
So this try catch system is really useful when you're doing things in your apps that you know have a
chance of failing like downloading content from the Internet.
How are we doing in the next lecture.
One last thing I'd like to show you is that you can catch specific exceptions as well rather than just
catching a generic exception.
You could catch the specific objection exception that we're getting here which is this array index out
of bounds exception.
So if you want to catch a specific exception then you use then
array index out of bounds exception.
So that would then catch that specific exception and then if you wanted you could have a general catch
exception there that just caught any other exception that you hadn't anticipated.
So for this one we could say index
out of bounds like that.
Try spelling bounds right.
So then we've caught that specific exception but we still have a backup in case there was another problem
that we didn't foresee.
But the show does go on and the script or our app will keep on running even though we've had an exception
in our code here.
So that's what we use to try and catch for in the next lecture.
We'll apply that directly when we try and download some content from the web see it there.