Now that we're comfortable working with sound we're going to change tack slightly to prepare for the
last app that we're going to make in this section which is going to be a basic phrases app.
So essentially the app is going to have eight buttons two long and four down which we want to stretch
to the whole width of the screen and then you're going to be able to tap those buttons to say basic
phrases.
That's one of those apps you might take with you on holiday or even use to learn some basic phrases
in a new language.
So the challenge there then is the set up we want to make sure that our buttons cover the whole screen
whatever the screen size.
In a kind of grid and indeed there is a layout in Android particularly or specifically designed for
this.
And that's what we're going to investigate in this video.
So it's called grid layout so I'll call my new app Gridley's out demo
and we'll go for it.
As usual the default options so there are a few subtleties to the great lay out demo.
And it's always good to see a new way of laying out your user interface elements.
So here we go.
I'm going to start by removing the default text view then and then surprise.
I'm going to add a grid layout so I'm just going to drag that in and will align it to the top left and
you can see by default it takes the whole width and the height of the parent.
So we could change that here.
That's what we wanted but actually that's exactly what we want.
We want the grid layout to stretch to the edges of the screen minus the menu bar the top of course.
So while we're spending a bit more time looking at lab it's always good to compare but we've just added
to the text SML version of that as we've seen before.
So this is our grid layout code that has just been added to our app by dragging that in.
So it's very simple we just use grid layouts to define a grid layout and then we've set the width and
height to match the parent and then aligned to the top and the start we could actually do without those
lines because they will happen by default anyway if we match the parent.
So let's add a button to this grid layout and see how it does.
See how it behaves.
So I'm going to drag it in like that into our grid layout and you can see this time we start getting
these boxes appearing.
So this tells us where this item is in terms of the grid.
So if I add another one
you can see this button is the second one along.
But still in the first row there whereas this one is in the first row and the first column as well.
So what we want is to have as many buttons as we like in this case it's going to be eight but we want
them to stretch to the whole width of the screen and the height of the screen as well.
So the easiest way to do that is to go to the X and L and for each of our buttons we're going to specify
a few different things.
So first of all we're going to specify where they are in the grid layout.
So this first one's going to be the top left.
This is going to be a layout column.
There it is.
It's going to be zero or
the next one you won't be surprised to hear it's going to be lay out.
And that 0 as well.
So that hasn't changed anything.
It's just specified which button this is.
And then the next thing we're going to specify is the gravity we talked about gravity before but this
time we want to use it to fill and this will fill both horizontally and vertically.
The space that it's in.
So you can see what it's done there it's filled the whole screen vertically and horizontally up to the
width of that new button there which is the behavior that we want.
We'll obviously need to update that the new button code to make that work has a couple of pictures I'm
going to add that's worth bearing in mind and that is the
column white and we want all of our column whites to be equal because we want them all to be the same
size.
So I'm going to set them all to be one.
Just to point out there there's a column span so if you wanted one of your buttons to spend two columns
for example then you could use your grid layout to do that but we're not going to do that here.
We're just going to set the very weight to be one as well just to show you what you can do.
There's a little image there so you can see that part is twice as wide as the ones below and you would
do that using span's.
OK so now I've got my button behaving as I want it to be.
I'm actually going to just copy and paste that code.
So I've got rid of the second button.
That's going to give me a problem with IDS.
So just update the IDs temporarily.
And we've got this one is going to be column 1 and 0.
So now we've got two buttons together which side by side take up a whole screen.
So the third one I want to have a column of zeros and a row of one.
Now this is working.
I'm actually going to ignore that Id problem for a moment because I don't need to worry about it.
We're going to add the ID's later on.
But now I'm just going to update that says column one and row one.
There we go.
So that's how you would get four buttons or these and have to be buttons they could be images could
be anything you like but that's how you would get four equally spaced boxes.
So now I'm just going to add four more
and then update them all.
So say gave this one is going to have a row of two and a column of one.
This one is going to have a row.
Sorry this one's two in one.
This one's two and 0.
And we've got 3 and 0.
And three and one.
There we go.
So now we've got eight buttons.
Don't worry about the I.D. problem will solve those later but they fill the screen very nicely and they
will do that regardless of the screen size of the device that's being used.
So that's a really useful layout if you want your interface elements to stretch to the edge of the screen.
I'm not going to go through this with you but a quick challenge might be to try and recreate that grid
lay out there.
So you've got a grid with a span of two across the top and then one with a span of two down the middle
there and that the other ends all spans of one type of guy if you want to practice your lay outs but
I'm going to stop the video here and we will then go on to create our basic phrases AB.