Now we're the final video in this Instagram section of the complete Android and develop of course and
we'll be focusing on viewing photos posted by other users.
So this is definitely one I'm going to set as a challenge.
We've got our familiar user list and a new title notice up there and see if you can figure out how to
do that.
We also have a new little feature to allow users to log out.
I definitely recommend adding that in.
And then when we load back in again if we click on a user who's posted a photo then we'll see that photo.
And of course all there are others flowing below.
Note I'm using a vertical linear layout here to display all the images and I suggest you do the same.
One thing that you will need to work out is how to add image views to the app.
We haven't set up individual images for potentially many many pictures that people will post here.
So we need to create one each time and that's something you need to figure out how to do.
Of course if you can't figure it out don't worry just follow along with the video and I'll show you
how it's done.
So that will take us to the end of our Instagram app.
So I wish you the best of luck.
Time to pause the video and give it a shot.
Go for it.
All right so that one well I'm going to start with a new activity.
If you are using feet's
I will look at the gallery and go for our usual empty activity.
And I'm going to call this use a feed activity
every game.
And I'll start by using As I mentioned the vertical Linnea out
can be gay and we'll go for a full width and height.
And I'll even go so far as to get rid of the padding.
In the relative layout just get rid of that.
To make it stretch
to the very edge of the screen
OK.
Then let's give it an ID.
Just scroll down to the bottom your properties and then we'll just call it linear lay out and let's
just start by seeing how we can add an image to that linear layout programmatically.
So first off let's create a linear layout to reference that's
And then we're going to create a new image.
Pull at MTV and this is going to be a new image for you.
So we're not finding it by its idea anymore we're creating it.
Within the application context.
And then we take an image view and we set a few basic layout parameters
set layout parameters
and then we want a new view.
Grape
dot Lao programs
and then you can sense looking for width and height to the full width we'll choose.
Match parent.
So it's going to be full width of the screen and then height of choose wrap content.
So that should make it full width of the screen and a proportional height and then we set and then we
set the image drawable.
So later on we'll be setting a bitmap for now just to see how it works.
We'll set the image drawable and we've only got one drawable here so we'll use that Instagram logo PNB
to access that we use get resources don't get drawable.
And then the ID.
So our talk drawable thought Instagram logo.
And then finally we add that to our linear layout
so we can add a view and then add the image we.
All right so that's how we programmatically add an image view and then fill it with an image to our
linear lay out in order to access that we're going to need to be able to click on an item in the user
list.
So one of the uses and then jump to the user feed activity.
So that's just set up that code over in user list activity.
So we're going to do that in on create which is down here.
So let's do it just where we define or use a list we use a list view it set on item click listener
and a new adaptive view on item click listener.
And we want to set up an intent to go to the use of feed activity
and intent which will be new content using the application context and we want to jump to user feed
activity class we don't need to know right now just use the user clicked on but we will definitely need
that later on.
So let's add that in while we're here intent to put extra I'll call it username and then we're going
to access the names array list and we want to get the one that was clicked on and that's this I hear
we get so that will pass on the username and then we just need to start activity
for the intent.
All right.
So let's take a look.
We should now find that when we tap on any username in the user list activity it will jump to the use
of field activity which will then dynamically create an image be populated with the Instagram logo and
display that to the user.
Let's take a look.
OK.
So let's try this out.
We'll tap on Michael there.
And there we go.
We've got our Instagram logo as we wanted.
Terrific.
So now we want to update this code so that instead of doing the Instagram logo it shows the feed either
photos posted by that user.
So let's start by getting the user ID that our user has selected.
So we want an intent which is going to be the intent that we use to get to the user feed and then we'll
need to know the user name that was selected.
So let's create a string to reference that I'll call it active user name and this is going to be intent.
Don't get string extra string we're looking for is using it.
And one small change I'm going to make here is rather than have pass start a project at the top there.
I'm going to have the user name that's been selected said we know who we're looking at and we can do
that very easily using Set title.
So I'm going to use that title and then active use named feet that should set the title to the feed
of the user that's been selected.
Or just run that and make sure that's working before we go any further.
And here we go.
So let's tap on Michael and then we get Miko's feet at the top there.
And of course I can go back and view Tommy's feet as well.
Now we need to set up a past query to get all the images posted by that user.
So it's a past query on pass objects coolit query and it's going to be a new parse query on Parse objects
and the class that we want to query is the image class
and we want to find all the images by the user name that they use to tap on.
So we'll set where equal see.
And we want to set the user name equal to that user.
So remember we've got a field here called username
so I will use user name to be quilty active username
and we also want to put the newest ones at the top.
So let's use Querrey order by descending and then you would have noticed that we've got a created out
there that we can use to order these by date.
We could also use the updated at time stamp but we're not planning to edit these.
These are essentially the same for us.
So we'll stick with created at
OK.
So that's how queery Let's run it.
So Querrey find in background and then we'll have a new find Colback
and then when it's done as usual we'll check for a being no.
And then we check to see if objects our size is greater than zero.
And then Mulek 3
the object variable which will be a list of past objects.
So let's create a past object called object for each of those
and then we need to get the file i.e. the image over here that was created and download that.
So we do that using past File.
We're going to create a file
which will be a pass file and we're going to get that from Object get.
And then the fill we want to get is image
and now the file itself is not actually downloaded yet.
We have to do that separately.
So we use file docs get data in background
with a new data callback
and you can see this returns a byte array called data.
So let's check to see if he is no.
And we'll also check that the byte array is not.
No.
And if that's the case we'll create a bitmap
which I'll call bitmap from the bitmap factory.
How am I going to decode how byte array using data starting at zero and keeping going throughout the
whole length of data.
All right so now we've got our image.
So now we're going to create our image view.
So I'm going to copy this carryed up here to do that and we'll just move our linear layout definition
to the top of our own create method so we can access it here as well.
And needed in order to do that it will need to be a final.
So we need to change here is that instead of setting the image drawable to image we we're going to set
the image bitmap to bitmap.
Simple as that.
So that should do the trick.
You're welcome to put in a few messages here.
So for example if the user doesn't have any voters in their feet it might be nice to pop up a small
message saying this feed is currently empty or to give a user an error message if indeed it is not.
No but that's reasonably straightforward.
I'll leave that for you to do if you want to
find out I'm going to cheat slightly and change the user name of this posted image to Michael so that
I don't have to fuss about with logging in as a new user and then viewing Rob's photos.
So we should be able to now click on Michael and view that lovely image that we stored from the camera
earlier on.
So let's tap on Michael and there we go.
So that image is at the top.
Obviously if there were more images they'd fly on down the screen.
All right.
So we're pretty much there without basic Instagram functionality.
The one thing I'm going to add before we consider this done is a logout button.
So at the moment it's a little bit incomplete because the user can't log out.
So let's add in a look at button to Menu say open up menu
and we'll do it in the text VI so will add an item with a title of logout and an ID of logout.
OK.
And then we've already got the menu inflator methods up here.
So I just need to check
here to see if item don't get item ID is equal to Odda ID dot log out then we want to do two things.
Firstly we want to lock the user out which is very easy to parse user dot log out and then we want to
jump back to our main activity so the user can log in again if they want to.
So we'll do that with an intent
your intent using the application context and we want to jump to main activity doc class
and then we're just going to stop that activity.
And while we're here I did just notice as we were looking at the app that is still says Pass start a
project up there which isn't great.
So let's change
that
here to set title.
So we'll set this to use a feed.
And over in main activity we'll set the title to Instagram.
All right.
So let's have a final check and see if our logout button works as desired.
And here we go.
So let's look at ourselves out and there we go.
We're back to the main Instagram screen and then we can look back and if we want to switch over to logging
mode and there we go and we of course can view the feeds again if we want to.
And there it is.
Excellent.
So that takes us to the end of our Instagram app and you've now learned a huge amount about setting
up a pass server on AWOS working with the data browser and the easy to management console as well as
of course actually building apps using pass for in and sign up and data storage as well in the next
section we're going to take this even further and make a rather popular cloud based app and that is
uber.
So take a little break have a cup of tea and a biscuit and I'll see you at the beginning of the next
section.