A good title is crucial if you don't optimize your title and you can forget about a good ranking on
an AppStore.
Unfortunately there is so much confusing information about this around the web.
It can be hard to figure out what is good practice and what isn't having a key word in your title can
improve your apps search ranking for that key word by an average of ten point three percent for IO apps.
There are actually two names associated with every iOS app.
The first one is called the app name.
It has a maximum length of 255 characters.
The app store product page will display about 75 characters or less.
And keep in mind that the App Store search results on people's iPhones will show 35 characters or less.
The second is known as the bundle display name.
This is the name that appears under your app icon on the home screen of an iPhone iPod or iPad.
Here you don't need to worry about this name for ASIO purposes.
This will show only 12 to 14 characters for Android Google Play app titles have 35 characters allowed.
This makes it much harder to squeeze in your key word.
Compared to Apple for both what you need to know is make sure you put the essential key words in the
beginning.
Don't use names that are already in use.
It won't win you more downloads if you use the name of a popular app.
It will simply mean you get lost in the crowd.
Make sure your app name is short easy to spell and easy to remember.
Try to reflect the nature of your app in its name.
You don't want users to get confused.
Always split.
Test your apps title.
OK I'll see you in the next lecture.