With the complete Android and develop because you get a lot more than just the best learning experience
for Android and available you get $50 free credit to spend on AWOS to host your cloud storage based
apps.
You get a year's free web hosting on the ETEO web hosting advance package worth over $100.
You get a copy of the second edition of my highly rated ebook how to earn $10000 while learning to code.
You get a range of thousands of graphical assets that you can use in your absence backgrounds and icons
worth over $500 dollars and you get two free certifications from the CCI.
So to get all of that just go to eco web hosting Dakoda UK forward slash C-p forward slash Android and
then scroll down into your email address and password and then you need to enter your utility username
to verify the purchase of the course to find you or you to be username go to any page only to me when
you're locked in and click my profile.
So hover over your face at the top right click my profile and then click View Public Profile that will
take you to your public profile page and you'll then be able to find your username.
The last bit of that you are out there.
So in my case it's Rob Percival.
So once you've got that get back over to the eco repasting on a page and paste that in and then click
sign up.
If all goes well you'll then see this page telling you that you'll sign it was successful and giving
you the option to get some extra getting started guides and leave us any comments if you'd like.
Then just jump over to the update account details page top of the right hand menu and scroll down past
the various courses to where Says course extras.
And then you can get links to download various versions of my ebook you get instructions and a special
link to get the free AWOS credits you get instructions and a unique code to get your s.c.i accreditations
and you get links to download the graphical assets and some extra sound effects as well.
So enjoy all of that but now it's time to get down to business and start learning how to make apps for
Android and.