I'm sure a lot of you have been looking forward to this one.
We're going to create a flappy bird clone.
So really this is an opportunity to see how you can create games on Android and flappy bird is a relatively
simple game to create if you haven't heard of it.
It was released in 2013 to the frustration of many IRS users because it was fiendishly difficult at
the same time being very simple.
It was very popular.
And actually there's an interesting story behind it about the developer actually removing it from the
App Store because of all the criticism that he got because people found it so difficult to play.
But anyway you can go away and Google that if you want to find out more.
I just want to show you very briefly how the game works.
So here's a flappy bird or you can go and have a look at it now.
And this just shows you an online version of the game which is pretty similar to the one that we're
going to create.
So you press that.
I didn't even get past the first two.
You keep pressing or clicking on the screen to keep flappy moving up and down.
And then the idea is that you've got these randomly positioned pipes.
They got past one which then you have to get there.
And obviously if you hit the pipe you die.
So it's very simple but it will allow us to see all of the basics of android game creation how we can
do collision detection have sprites animating around the screen et cetera et cetera and scoring of course
up there.
So it should be a lot of fun.
We're going to start by downloading live GDX which is a Open-Source gaming library which I thoroughly
recommend if you're going to be hand-coding games.
It's actually cross-platform as well so you can build not only Android apps but apps which work on Windows
Mac Linux iOS as well so it's a really good system to learn.
But we're still just using Java and we're very much creating a native Android game here.
It just gives us a lot of features that we would otherwise need to code ourselves on the Android system.
So if you haven't already go to lib GDX dot bad logic games dot com and then click download and then
download the set up app.
I'm just going to save it right there on the desktop.
It's just a small little java application.
Fortunately you've got Java installed because you've got android studio up and running.
So you should just be able to tap the
downloaded file and then you'll get this.
So this allows you to set up your app.
So let's call it
flappy bird and then package remember it's something like com.
And then your name or your company name and then the app name.
So flappy bird and Game class can be whatever you like.
It's just the name of the class.
I'll call it flappy bird.
And then you just choose where you want it to appear.
And then to get the Android SDK path we can actually get that from Android studio.
So just load up and click Tools Android SDK manager and then right there at the top is your STK location.
So that will be very similar to this.
If you're on a Mac obviously be something different if you're on Windows.
So just copy that and then paste it back in and then I would just stick with whatever the latest version
of Liber GDX is.
And we really want to develop for Android here so to simplify things.
I'm going to get rid of the other three.
There's lots of support online for other platforms if you want to start developing for those as well
but we'll stick with Android for now.
And all the other options I just keep to the default and click generate.
Now you'll likely get this message you have a more recent version of Android build tools than the recommended
version.
I would definitely go for yes there.
And similarly Yes for the using the more recent Android API version that would just mean that it's easier
to run an android studio without doing any tricky alterations on the app.
So this will then generate the app for you.
And there we go.
That's done build was successful that's sounding promising.
So now we just go back to android studio and open that in the usual way.
So over to desktop and then let's put it in test for some reason.
Well I will be fine and then choose that and in this video we're just going to go as far as having a
quick look at what it actually includes And what we get if we run the D4 project and then we'll actually
start building flappy bird in the next video.
So here we go.
Let's have a look and see what files we've got so straight away you might notice some differences here.
There's no rez folder that we're used to.
We do pretty much everything in Java.
And here is our flappy bird class which looks a little bit scary compared to everything that we're so
used to.
We've still got our create method which as you can imagine runs when the app is run and now we have
a render method as well which is what will mostly be coding in the render method essentially gets run
again and again and again.
So you can think of it as an ongoing loop and that's where we'll put our code to animate our stripes
to do our collision detection and everything like that to see where the game actually works.
So we'll keep it on the same emulator I had open just for convenience there's no need to do this in
API 21.
It'll work fine and API 22 as well.
So we've got a few new classes there as well.
Spryte batch you can maybe imagine that that's essentially a batch of Brandt's that then process to
the screen.
And we've got textures which are basically images that we work with and think of them as sprites as
well.
So like a flappy bird hoopy our first texture of sprite that we're going to work with.
So all this does it creates a new sprite batch called batch and then it creates a new texture on image
which is from the bad logic to J pick J pedofile then it creates a background color which I think is
red.
And then it draws the image at position 0 0 and then ends the process of drawing the batches.
But I'll pass Geo points from Cuba displaying Merilee them.
So let's take a look.
So the output is simply that.
So first off notice by default that we're locked into landscape mode.
So 0 0 here is the you can think of it as the bottom left.
Really even though it looks like the top left.
If you take that round up with the bottom left.
And so we've got this red background and the bad logic logo there as well.
So that's it we've now set up GDX and we've got the code that we need to get our app working and we're
going to start in the next video by changing the background and displaying an animating our little flappy
bird sprite should be fun.
So here the.