So the first thing we're going to learn in Section 5 is about list views.
Now I'm going to create a new project straight away because it'll be much easier to show you what a
list view is than to explain it to you.
But essentially a list view is one of those big tables that you can have on your phone which will show
you a large number of items of data or occasionally a small number but if you imagine scrolling through
your contact list for example with all your numbers on your phone then that will be a list view.
So they're extremely powerful very useful and will use them in a number of apps from now on if you're
coming from Iowa as developments then known as tables in Iowa.
So it's exactly the same thing as a table.
But one good bit of news compared to IRS development is that working with less views is much much simpler
than working with tables.
In my opinion.
So it's really easy to set up a list history and really easy to add your own content to it as well.
So without further ado let's get one going.
So we'll go over to how design view and activity main and then we've got let's remember already we don't
really want that text view this time so I'm going to get rid of that and then I'm going to scroll down
in my palette here and drag in a list view.
OK.
So by default it will align itself.
I'll never get to the parent top and you can see we've got all those demo items already.
So that's just an example.
If we run the app then we wouldn't actually see these demo items.
We have to add those ourselves but this is what appears in the
design view so that we can at least get an idea of what atlast view is going to look like.
So that's absolutely fine.
Well that's just running so we can see our blank list view.
I'm just going to add an ID to it.
So the default is List view which is pretty good.
I'm just going to change that so it's at least something slightly Kustom my list view.
I wouldn't say if we just jump over and look at the emulator you can see so far we've got nothing.
We don't have those evil items we need to add them ourselves.
All right.
So let's get at it.
So my list view is the name of our list.
So I'm going to add my code in the uncreate method.
I'm going to have a few tiny mini challenges here.
So the first one is can you create a variable called my list view which links to the list view that
we've just created.
I mean is that just going to create it with this view.
And then my list view I should go back and just improve that.
So remember old enter in parts that automatically and then we're going to get this from.
Find few by Id just like we normally do.
And then our thought Id dot my list view and that of course is going to be a view.
But we wanted to be a list view.
So we need to cast it to a list view like the OK.
So now we can refer to our list view using the variable My List View the next mini challenge is to create
an array list which contains the members of your immediate family or some names of people that you like.
It doesn't really matter.
But for three or four names of people in your list go for it
all right.
How do you manage that.
I'm going to do.
By creating an
array list of strings like that and I'm going to call it
my family.
And I'm just going to import that.
And this is going to be a new array list of strings
because we're initialising a new array list hey this is a method which is why we've got the parentheses
at the end there.
So now I've created the array list does need to add my content to it.
So I'm going to do that using my family it's at and then start with me.
Cast an
Tommy
and finally Ralphy begin.
So you might have done that very differently you might have created the array list and added those all
in one go.
But I just wanted to to show you that way.
Right.
So now for the clever stuff we now want to put these items in our list view so display them on our table
essentially and we can actually do that in two lines.
Believe it or not and if you've done iOS development before you'll know that eating a table in iOS takes
a lot more than two lines.
So I really like the way that it works in Android.
What we're going to use is something called an array adapter.
And what this essentially allows us to do is to convert our array list which we already have into a
different format.
In this case we're going to convert it into a list view format or at least a format that we can use
to display content in our list view or come across a red chapters again later on in the course we'll
use them for all sorts of little things.
But this is our main use of them and it does make adding content to a list view really really easy.
So let's create our array adapter.
And again we're creating one with an array of strings.
And let's just call it array adapter and this is going to be a new array adapter with strings.
And we need to give it two things to create our array adapter.
We need to give it the array list that we're creating it from.
So my family and we we need to give it the format that we want.
And we also need to give it the context that we're creating it in so context as usual is just this.
So within this app and then the new format that we're creating it in we get from Android dot dot layout
and then you can see there's a bunch of different layouts that we can create.
So a bunch of different types so you can start to get an idea what you might use array adapters for.
Just by looking at this list we're going to just look at the basic one which is simple list item one.
Feel free to play around and see what the other ones look like.
I would just use the standard one here.
And then finally we give it the name of the array list that we want to create our re-adapt from.
And that of course is my family.
So just to recap what we've done is we've created an array adapter called array adapter which is a new
array adapter of strings and we've created this from the my family array list and we've essentially
converted that array list to a new style which is a simple list item one which we're then going to be
able to apply to our list view.
And we do that in one line of code.
So my list view don't set adapter and the adapter of course is array adapter and that's it.
And I really love that way of doing things.
I think it's a really intuitive and simple way of adding code to a table so let's have a look.
If we're lucky and we've done everything right app should appear just as it did before but we'll actually
have some content in our table which will be taken from this array.
And there it is.
Fantastic.
Rob Caston Tommy Ralphy.
So that's how you add content to your list view.
Super simple.
The other thing I want to show you in this video is how to make your views interactive.
So at the moment we can tap on them and they do respond like that but oversweet don't do anything but
we can fix that with just a few lines of code.
So what we do is take our list view my list view and we sat on item click to so that creates a listener
for a click on the list view.
We can then work with
and for this we're going to create a new on item click listener as it is.
We've got some different code in there that may just sort of have indenting so that it looks a bit clearer.
So it's an overwrite.
We're used to those Hopefully now
that we get because of course some code is being run already when the items are clicked because this
animation is taking place.
So we're just adding our code to code that already exists.
So let's take a quick look at the on item click code that's been created for us is a little bit complicated.
But first off we've got our adaptive view.
And then this question mark here.
Essentially this adaptive view is in our case the list view that's been tapped.
It's called an adaptive view because it's not necessarily a list view it could be a spinner or a grid
view or any other kind of interactive user interface element.
And that's what the question mark there represents.
So it's an adaptive view we don't at this point know in our code what type of view it was even though
we actually know that it was a list view because that's the only type that's been created.
But this here is a what's known as a generic because we don't know what type of view it is.
And then the name for that is parent.
So just for an example if for some crazy reason we wanted to make the table disappear whenever the user
tapped on one of the items in it we could use parent to represent the table and then said feasibility
and then we use a few dot gone to represent disappeared.
Sorry if you don't go on in capitals that day.
So essentially we can use parent in this code exactly the same as we would use my list view to represent
the list view that's just been tapped.
So that's where that first bit is then the view variable here which is a view represents the thing that
was actually tapped.
So in this case a row of our list view.
So that's the role the position integer is the number of the row that's been tapped.
It starts at zero for the first row and then 1 2 3 et cetera.
So we're actually going to use position to work out the name of the item in the array list that's been
tapped and then this ID Alcaeus is actually going to be the same as position.
But in some of the cases this idea would be different.
So I'd recommend using position in our case not going to go into here.
The cases where you would use ID but feel free to have a quick google of that if you want to get a bit
more information on it.
But really at this stage all we need is position
so very quick challenge then can you make it.
That's the name of the person that was tapped appears in the locks as soon as it's tapped for it.
I said easy.
Should have been so LOEG taught I information and then all these person tapped to be the instructions
old and to import the log framework and then we just need my family and then get the item that we want
to get is the one that was tapped on which remember is this position variable that so that's it let's
just run that and see if that works.
We should now have an interactive table that when we tap on it it locks person tapped and then gets
the name of the person that was tapped.
OK.
So Robin Kesten that Anita just scroll that up.
Every gay person tapped rope and Keston
fabulous.
Now his views are very important and the code that we've just introduced there is not not necessarily
straightforward so I'm going to give you another challenge to get this really clear in your head.
I want you to get rid of all the code that we've got him and your last few
go.
And then I want you to start from scratch and add a new list view which will contain the names of four
friends this time rather than family members.
Then when you tap on them I want you to create a toast.
Remember that's a little message that appears at the bottom of the screen that says hello and then the
name of the person that's been tapped on a little challenge there to remember how to do toasts as well.
Feel free to have a Google if you can't remember how to do it.
But best of luck.
All right.
I do hope you manage that.
Let's get cracking straight away.
I'm just going to track that up and then all I'm going to do is change the ID to
friends list for you.
Let me that's all I need to do that.
And now I'm back in the
uncreate method of my main activity touch of a file and let's start by getting our list of the list
view.
And then I'll call it friends list view to match up with the idea that we're going to need to cast it
as a list view and we're going to get it using find view by id and then also is taught ID taught friends
list V.
Now that's create our list of friends you may have thought that the way we created derailers last time
was not particularly neat.
We had to create it and then add each value individually on a separate line.
Unfortunately in Java there's no easy way to create an array list and impose values to it straight away
like there is in a number of other languages.
But I'm going to show you another way just for a little bit of variety.
Essentially this involves creating a list and then converting it into an array list.
And remember a list is like an array but it's immutable.
So you can't change it.
So here we actually could use a list because we're not planning to change it.
But I want to stick to using array lists because then we can use the same object type regardless of
whether we're planning to change it or not.
But the way I'm going to show you here is to take an array list of strings just as befool and I'll call
it my friends this time and this is going to be a new array list and I do like to specify you don't
have to specify the type but I like to specify that as strings and then we're going to create that from
a list and we can do that using as list
and let's just import we need them so as list and this is then where we put our four friends.
So I'm going to put John Paul
George and we can go.
So a bit of a mouthful there.
And that's not as nice as a lot of other languages but it is the simplest we can do if you want to create
an array list in one line and essentially you need to create it in just the same way that we did before.
But you create it from a list and you use as a list to create that from your individual values.
All right now we have our frailest.
So let's create our array adapter.
So as before.
And create an array adapter of strings or call it array adapter and it's going to be a new adapter and
exactly as before.
We use this for the context and then Android dot dot lay out
dot simple list item one.
So that's the type that we're creating here.
And then we're creating it from my friends
and now we've got our re-adapt to let's attach it to friends list view
just like that.
And before we create our toast code I just want to check and make sure that that's all working OK.
I'm fairly convinced it is but worth checking I think I would get as my lovely list of friends
get rid of that.
And now we need to create how unclick listener so friendless feud set on item click listener and then
new on item click list every day and there's a lovely default code.
So all we need to do is add our toast code here and I'm going to do that in one line so taste
make text and we want the first of those too.
And we also want to import ticed framework
and then we're going to use get application context to get out of context just as we've done before.
And now we want the text for
outposts.
It's going to be hello.
And then we want the name of the person that was tapped on.
And we're going to get that from my friends sorry dog get
and then position
and then we just want to decide how long it's going to appear.
And I don't really care for length alone and we want to show that ticed says is good quick recap of
how you display tastes but that's nothing new for us we've done that a few times now.
If your code looked more or less like this with any luck that will now display table and then we can
tap on these Hello Paul hello george.
Fantastic.
So you're now pretty comfortable hopefully with this fuse and how they work in the next video we're
going to use that knowledge to create a mini times table testing app so that.