Our next challenge involves making a guess the celebrity app for which we're going to need to download
the names and images of a bunch of celebrities.
Now I found this web site 24 dot com slash celebrities which gives a list of apparently the top 100
celebrities I'm not sure how they're ranked but there they are.
So that would be a very useful list for us for our app.
Now what we'll need to do is look at the code of this page which we can do as we've seen before by control
clicking or right clicking and
clicking view page source.
Make sure you click on that wipe it there and then you can see the familiar h h d l of the page.
And if we look here you can see this is the Nicki Minaj section.
And we've got the source image there.
So we're going to need that and we're going to need the name which we can get either from there or from
the old tag of the image itself.
So we're going to need to be able to extract those two bits of information for each person in the list
so there's the next person there's the next one et cetera.
So to be able to do that we're going to need to be able to manipulate strings in a rather more advanced
way than we're currently capable of.
So let's just see how we do that.
And again this is Java rather than anything Android specific.
So it's a little bit easier if we work in pro x y dot com.
So click try to get the Hellewell project and then just start just to make sure everything's looking
good.
All right.
So the first thing we're going to need to do is to split the single big string into lots of smaller
strings.
So like the last one this one and that one.
And fortunately there's a method in Java that does that for us which is called split.
So let's quickly see how we use it.
Let's create a string which I'll call my string which I will have a bunch of strings.
Have names and will separate those names by the letter X
names that you're probably fed up with having shoved down your throat for the moment but there we get.
You can obviously choose your own names.
So for some reason I seem to have a string with a bunch of XS in and names separated by those Xs.
So if I wanted to separate that into an array which contained each of the names and what I could do
is create an array of strings like that and I'll call it split string.
And then I'm going to take my string and split it
by the letter x.
So what that does is hopefully fairly straightforward it takes my string and then it splits it into
an array by the letter X..
Then we just need to display that in the logs.
So we use system thought out to print line and then again we can convert our array to a string.
So will use arrays to string and we want to convert split string
and to do that we'll need to import Java.
Don't you tell Dot arrays.
OK let's take a look that we get.
So we've got Rob cast in Tommy and Ralphy as an array.
Now there's a slight problem here.
Before I tell you what that problem is and see if you can work out why we've got this kind of weird
spacing issue here and what we could do here to solve it.
Go for it.
Did you figure it out.
The problem is of course that between Rob and Kersten is not just an X but there's a space as well as
Rob Space X space Keston so simple fix would be to instead of just splitting it by X split it by Space
X and then space and then you can say we just get the names in an array like that.
All right.
Quick challenge for you then let's get rid of that.
Can you create a string which is equal to the name Mississippi and then split it according to the letter
S and before you do it try and write down what the result is going to be.
So try and create a string which is equal to Mississippi and split it according to the letter S and
before you do it try to anticipate what the result is going to be.
Good luck.
All right.
I'm going to create a string.
I'll call it River.
The big challenge here of course was spelling Mississippi correctly.
I did have to look it up.
I have to admit but I would get.
And then we'll create our array.
I'll call it split up and we're going to take river and we're going to split it by the letter S.
Go and then system taught how to print line and then Jorge's taught to string splits river
and let's have a look.
Hopefully it will be what you guessed so slightly strange your way.
So obviously before the first s We've got just an eye which goes there then between the first and second
as there's nothing.
So we've got an empty portion of our right that then between the next two S's we've got an eye which
is that then between those two S's we've got nothing again.
And then after the final last week I API.
So that's why we get that strange array that hopefully that's what you guessed.
OK.
So that's the first part I'm just going to comment that out for now.
So now we can now split strings
by another string saying we're going to need to do is to get a portion of a string.
So we're going to need as I mentioned that piece of the string and also that bit.
So let's see how we do that.
Let's start by creating a string again.
And actually I think I'm going to use Mississippi again mostly because I just like saying it.
So if we want to return a part of that string
you might call it rip apart.
Then we can take how Reeva and get a substring of it
and for example we could do something like substring to comma five.
Let's just have a look and see what that gives us.
We don't need to convert this time we can just do it directly because it's a string.
So that gives us s s o.
So what's going on there is that this is returning.
If we think of these letters as being 0 1 2 3 4 5 et cetera then the zeroth letter is M and number 1
is.
So it starts with number 2 which is that first X and then it keeps going until the one before the last
letter.
So we've got two three and then four.
But not including five so quick challenge then can you change the numbers so that instead of getting
SSI we get.
I asked as I said that middle portion there different
you manage that.
So this will be 0 1 2 3 4.
So our first number is four four five six seven eight.
So we want to go up to but not including eight that's just check that you give us SSI.
That we go.
So that's pretty useful in itself but it doesn't quite solve the problem that we have because we don't
necessarily know exactly which number which character is going to be the ones that we want.
So we actually want to track down a particular string of characters.
So I'm going to show you a third way of working with strings which I think is more powerful than the
first two put together by a little bit tricky to get to grips with.
It's known as rejects.
Sure.
For regular expressions and is actually a cross language way of manipulating strings.
I'm just going to show you the basics of it here.
But if you do a google for Java rejects e.g. X then you'll get loads of ways that you can do more advanced
things with strings.
What we're going to do here.
So with the way it works is we start off by creating a pattern.
So let's actually create a string to work with first.
So let's stick with Mississippi.
Why not.
And then we normally call our pattern P and that is a pattern and we're going to compile a pattern from
a piece of rejects.
Now rejects is a kind of a language as I say all on its own.
But the most important thing that we're going to use it for is for finding the content between two other
strings.
And so let's say we want to find what's between MRI and PIII.
So that is obviously we know that it's there.
So as I said IP but if we wanted to find that for our general string then what we would do is type II
and then the rechecks code forgetting the string between those two which is brackets.
And then inside that brackets dot star question mark and then PIII.
So what this means is find M-I and find PIII and then return whatever you find between the two of them.
Simple as that.
I'm not going to go into details of where that comes from.
Again you can look that up and find information of what the DOT stock question mark is actually doing
but it's pretty complicated and we don't really need all that detail of rejects right now.
We just need to use it to find the strings within our string.
So now that we've got that pattern we create a matcher call it m which is P L pattern and then we're
going to match it against our string.
So river so I'll match just matches our pattern against our original string and see if it can find anything.
Obviously it might find something it might find nothing or might find more than one thing if we had
the word Mississippi twice then it would return to different results.
So the way we do with that is we use a while loop and then we take our Maacha and we find with it
so this will set our matcher going so we'll look for matches to how pattern in our original string river.
And it will keep doing this loop as long as it finds them.
And we just want to output the results of that.
So we do that using system out of print line and we take how matcher and to get the actual result that
we want.
We use matcher group and then 1 so that will return the result itself.
And as before we need to add the import for that.
So that's import
Java.
Don't you still dot rejects thought pattern and all say we need java or you to talk rejects don't match.
All right let's take a look them.
We run that code and you can see what is returned is SSI.
SSI P which is everything between MRI and PIII.
And if we had all of that twice and we run it again it would print it twice prints it every time it
finds it in holstering.
So that's an extremely powerful process.
And as I challenge I'm going to require you to actually use it in our Kate
over here.
So let's say we've managed to get as string and we want to extract the SIRC here.
And the old tag.
So to get the name essentially.
One quick thing we're going to need to do first is escape all of these
double quites as we've seen before
Java it would by default think that the double quote meant oh this is the end of the string but it doesn't
until the actual end of the string.
We need to put a backslash in front of it to say no this is just part of our string not a sign that
we want to end the string.
All right then.
So your challenge.
Preferably not looking at this code but use it if you need to is to extract the two bits of information
that we need.
So that is the you are all there.
And the nine Caitlyn Jenner.
Good luck.
All right.
Well that was a pretty tough challenge.
I'm actually going to do it by just renaming that first of all.
It's not it's not really a river.
So let's start off by getting R C source u r l and we'll do this by creating a pattern P and we're going
to compile a pattern.
And what we're interested in I'm going to have the start of al-Qaeda's S R C equals and then backslash
double quotes again and then we have the parentheses with dot star.
Question mark in and then we want to have everything up to the next double quotes
and then we end the string with an actual double quotes and then that's our pattern.
So what we're going to use to compile our pattern with.
So that's the bit that we're looking for before the bit that we're interested in.
And then we want everything up to the next double quotes within the string.
OK.
So that's the tricky bit.
The rest of it is exactly the same as before.
So much.
M is equal t p don't match the h t m l.
And then while M dot find
and we want system out dot print line and Dot group 1.
All right.
Fingers crossed.
OK now we've got an interesting error there so I thought I'd leave that one in because you may well
have seen something like that if you copy it all of that and what actually happens there is this line
break breaks our code because Java thinks we want to go into a new instruction.
So what I'll do for now is just remove all the line breaks in that string so it becomes just a single
long string and then our code is more or less unchanged by that.
We'll see how we actually get to deal with that in the app itself later on.
And there we go you can see that now without those errors we've got the you are all that we need.
Fantastic.
So that's the you are el I'm going to actually just copy and paste because my code next time is going
to be pretty similar except we're not going to create PNM this time because they're already created.
So now what we need to do is work out what we need to get Caitlyn Jenner and I think we'll use the old
equals and then they escaped quotes there as are set up to the string before the bit that we're interested
in.
And the bit after is actually the same as before.
So those double quotes once again.
So that with any luck should get us the code that we need.
Fantastic.
So there's the u r l and there's the name.
So that is actually all we need to get all the data that we're interested in for our app.
Guess the celebrity.
So now we're ready to go and let's make it in the next lecture.