So now that you've learned how to use Jason and how to get some Jason's data from the web and then interpret
it and use it in your app we're going to apply that to our What's the web app.
So we're looking for something like this where you can enter a city and then we can enter a city name
such as London tap water the weather and then the weather is displayed right there underneath.
So pretty much everything you've done before.
So it should be reasonably straightforward to make.
I'm just going to very quickly show you where I got that background image from.
I like this Web site on Splash dot com if you want sort of quite generic backgrounds that are completely
free to use in any apps really can make your app look a lot more attractive.
And of course we're going to be using the open weather map API which we saw in the previous lecture
which has content like that.
So as always strongly encourage you to have a go at this yourself.
Best of luck.
All right.
I hope that one well I'm going to begin of course by creating a new project and I'm going to call it
what's the weather.
I'm just going to avoid the apostrophe there because it can cause issues in package names.
I'd recommend not putting punctuation in that if you can avoid it and then blank activity
same one that.
OK.
So as I mentioned I'm going to try and make this app look a little bit prettier.
So I'm going to get to Sunsplash dot com we have a bunch of fairly generic but often very pretty photos.
And I'm going to find one that might have something vaguely to do with whether that one is nice but
it's going to cause problems when we try and put text over that I think depending on where the text
ends up we need something a bit more generic.
I think this will be great.
I like the look of that one.
OK so I'm just going to save image as I'm just going to put it right there on the desk top.
And I'll call it background
OK.
Back over to Android studio here we are.
So let's start by importing our image.
So remember we're going to drag that into trouble.
So just control clicked can right click on Windows and then reveal and find them or Windows Explorer
and then
I'm going to open a new tab with command T.
Contest's shop and then just drag in my background taught jpeg image.
There it is.
It's in Africa back I have to studio with any luck it'll be there.
Lovely.
Yep.
If it's not remember you can just synchronize it to make it appear that great.
So let's get rid of hello world.
Let's drag in our lovely image for you.
Goes without saying that making a simple app it looks a lot prettier if you can get a nice pretty image
in the background and it's very easy to do as well.
So I change the width and height to fill parents and then we'll set the SLC weps.
I do find that annoying.
I have a background
just see how that looks in the default.
So that's not quite what we are going for.
But I am worried we can it that way that scale type.
So here you can see if we want to stretch it x and y.
That looks pretty good.
Fits start fit center and fit and obviously not quite what we wanted.
We could try a center.
I like that t center inside.
Not what we want.
So now I'm going to go for center Kropp.
I think that looks nice with this particular image.
And then let's drag in what we need.
So we've already got the title we don't need that again.
I'm going to bring in a text view.
I'm going to want to be scented
into a city
and then here I definitely want a margin at the top.
Then let's try 50 the page.
Yeah I like that and when it began I tried 20 recipe a little bigger I think even than that trifecta.
Yeah.
I like that.
And I want to change the color.
I think it would look good if we make it completely white.
So we did that with bringing everything to t 5:5
Yeah I like that then we'll have
textfield to get the weather up.
So again we want to send it and we want it's not to the left of texture we want to directly underneath
text.
That we can change it to the width
of the whole screen.
Actually maybe that might look a bit weird that's a padding to the left of let's try 40.
DP Yep I like that so I noticed because it's scented it's automatically added a right to one as well.
And then finally we'll just need a button
to find out the weather.
So again we want it scented and Polow
the text input and we'll say what's the weather
and actually we can leave the idea button.
That's fine.
But we're once of course an on click
call Find web.
OK.
And then I think I just want to add a little bit of a margin to the top of that button.
Just tell me that down slightly.
That's maybe a little too much
OK.
Lovely.
And then finally we'll have a label which will appear down here to give us the weather
say actually I want to align it to the bottom this time
I will have a margin on the bottom to bring it up.
Let's try 100 tepees maybe slightly more.
Great change the text size again.
That I think there might be a little bit large as we to have quite a bit of information then.
And finally it will change the with
to actually leaving as web content should be fine because then it will grow as necessary.
But I will actually change the color.
I think the white works better against that background
lovely.
All right.
So we'll try now adding the code to find the web
so you'll be relieved to hear that I'm not going to take you through the whole process of downloading
our Jason and then purchasing it line by line because we've done that several times now.
I hope you think that you're reasonably expert on that.
So I'm just going to copy that over from Jason demo and then add it's
and you can see very nicely it's added all the classes that we might need.
So we don't have to do that manually.
So now let's create a method for finding the weather.
So we call that find whether
that's going to be called by Button view
and the one variable that we're particularly interested in is the city name.
So we need a way to get that.
I think we should
give that a better idea.
It will update those so city name
and then
we'll just add that to our code.
So it's an added text.
And I'll find it up there.
City name.
And then on create we'll find it
as we know it's an added text.
Thein VBI ID says Dot ID dot city name
as we've done quite a lot of stuff here.
Well I'm going to do you find out is log the valley of city name
so city name don't get text
it's too strong to convert it to a string.
OK so we're not actually using our download task at all.
But I just want to see make sure everything looks OK on the emulator screen and then make sure it's
all connected up.
And when we tap the button we should find whatever the user has typed in the city name in the locks
right.
Let's see now I actually got a crash than I thought I'd leave it in just to show you.
We've got an out of memory error.
Now if you have a think about what could be causing that we haven't done a lot here but we have just
imported this quite large image so I suspect the problem is that our image is too big.
So in
your Mac as an easy way to resize images so you just double click on it and then Tools adjust size.
And yeah this is a lot bigger than what we need.
So let's try and reduce it to
maybe 500 pixels.
Now 21 kilobytes rather than 336.
So that should make it rather more manageable.
I don't know an easy way to resize images on Windows I'm afraid but a quick google on that should get
you should get you a way of doing it.
So fingers crossed we shouldn't get that crash this time
and then again I like the look of our app.
So let's just give it a shot.
And what's the weather.
And all we want is to see London somewhere down here.
There it is.
Fantastic.
So it's all working as far as we expect.
All that remains is to actually get the weather for that particular location.
So we might as well copy and paste the commands that do it
say they are here.
So now the only difference of course is that instead of London we want whatever the user has typed so
let's have in
City Name that we get.
So that should print the information to the logs from the Jason.
So let's check that.
Now you can start seeing hopefully where all these exceptions might come in useful because we're allowing
the user to edit essentially how you are l string here.
So that could really go horribly wrong if they either don't edit or anything at all or if they end to
something that's not going to allow this to be a valid you are l then we don't want our app to crash.
We just want to give them a message.
And of course we mustn't forget to set the permissions in the manifest every guy and race knows what
we want now.
So now we should find that we can log the weather of any city we like here we can't say let's try
Shanghai What's the weather.
OK let's take a look.
Fantastic.
So there's our main content and we've got clouds a few clouds.
That's that's all we've got about this particular weather.
It's quite brief.
This is.
But that's fine.
So now all we need to do is make sure that the weather is updated on the app itself rather than just
in the locks which isn't particularly useful.
So let's just jump back over the activity main and
check the ID text V-2 isn't great.
I'll call it results text for you.
And while we're here let's just get rid of the default text because we don't want any default text to
appear.
And then
we want a text view.
I've already forgotten what I just called it's text fi
and we'll find it here.
You
and we're going to find it using it Heidi.
All I'll say is ideas and results next few.
I do prefer space and
OK.
Now remember I said that in the on post execute method we can interact with the user interface.
So it's up to you how you want to actually display this information.
But what I'm going to do is create a string Maine which will initially be empty and the string description
which will initially be empty and then obviously I'm going to set mine to be the main part of the J-Zone
and then description to be the description part and then I'm just going to test to see if mine is not
an empty string and description
is not an empty string.
That means that we have a type or a mine and a description.
So if that's the case we can update our message string.
Which means we're going to need a message string.
So we'll set that initially empty up there.
So it sent a message
to have appended to its main and then I'm going to have a colon and a space and then the description
and then I want a new line and to do new lines I think we've seen before.
We use backslash or backslash and for a line break.
So this will give us a new line at the end of this bit of code which will have the type.
So that is rain or drizzle or whatever.
And then the description and then finally when we've looped through all of that we'll check if message
is not empty non-empty string.
Then we'll update
the result textfield with it.
Result
text the set text and then message
OK let's just have a quick look at that
and see if it works.
So let's try
Paris this time.
What's the weather.
And you can see we're in a fun situation here.
We can see the result whether or not it's worked because the keyboard is in the way.
So we need a way to remove the keyboard as soon as the button is tapped and we can do that and Android
fairly shortly although it's not that simple.
We need to create a variable of a type input method manager and we'll call that mjr short for manager.
And this is going to be an input method manager and we're going to get it from this time get system
service and the system service that we want to get is context Daut input method service.
So this gets the input method service that our app is currently using which is the keyboard.
And then we want to take that manager and use it to high eat soft input from window which does what
it says on the tin.
And then we just need to specify the window which we get from the name of the added text that we're
currently in.
So a city name and then don't get window token.
So that tells us which window.
And then we put a comma 0 because there are various other options or flags that we can put there if
we want but you probably won't ever use those.
So we'll just put comments there to hide the keyboard in the normal way.
Right.
So that's a very good skill to be able to hide the keyboard when you want to.
Usually it's when a button has been tapped.
Let's take a look now.
OK.
So I'm going to try again with Paris.
What's the weather.
There we go.
So it's not the fullest error message or not the fullest weather description as we see.
But it's what we've got.
I suspect if you have a look at the open weather map API in more detail we can get more detailed sort
of weather or just a general overall weather description.
OK.
So we're nearly there.
We just have
one thing that I'd like to deal with and that's what happens if the user into something empty or something
which isn't a city.
And the answer is nothing which is fine at least.
The app doesn't crash.
And the reason it doesn't crash is because we've got all our exceptions and driving catches everywhere.
But it would be nice to give a message to the user if that fails.
So I'm going to just add that feature in to add a toast to the user in case of exceptions.
So I'll have toast make text
and then get
application context.
And so here will say
could not find whether
And then we'll have just toast length long.
So you can get a more detailed error message in there.
I feel like I'm just keeping it very simple here.
And so that will occur if they enter something that's not a valid you are el
or if that data connection isn't connected but there's also a possibility that we won't be able to get
anything from the Jason.
So I'm going to add another message that I'm just going to leave the message at the same thing.
But again you might want to have a different error message there or if we actually get an error with
the Jason that we'll need an error message as well.
And finally what about cities that have spaces in their names or strange characters if we trumpet's
say San Francisco in that we'll currently give us an error because they won't be able to create the
U R L string because it has a space in it.
So what we'll do is we'll include it as a u r l and I'll show you what I mean by that.
So it will create a string
encoded city name which we're going to get from
that but we're going to use a u r l encoder.
Whoops
to encode it
and the usual format is UTF 8
and there's a possibility that will fail.
So once again we'll put it around try and catch and I'll pop these
in try and I'll just add the error message again to the catch.
And then we can put encoded city name in there.
All right.
Well of compiling.
I'll just show you what we're doing then.
So this is the u r l that we have when we don't need to come a UK at the end when we got something without
a space in like London.
If I try and put San Francisco in there and see what happens you can see it converts it to 7 percent
20 Francisco and put that percent 20 is an encoded space and it's encoded in a format that you are or
else can read.
So the API open weather map will be expecting 7 percent 20 Francisco rather than Sun spites Francisco.
And that's what
this encoding will do.
So it will replace any strange characters like spaces or apostrophe's or anything like that with you
are el equivalent.
So let's just check for now put in San
Francis.
There it is.
What's the weather.
And apparently it's misty.
OK.
Great.
So that is our What's the weather app which can now cope with spaces in names as well.
And that takes us to the end of this section.
So congratulations for making it this far.
We'll see what we've covered in the next lecture.
For now give yourself a pat on the back.
Go have a cup of tea before getting ready to weps with maps and locations in Section 7.