In this video I'm going to show you how to download and install Android studio on Mac OS.
So if you're running Windows then you need to jump straight to the next video.
Still.
And your studio is the only piece of software that you need for this course.
It includes both a coding environment and a simulator so that you can run Android apps on emulated devices
phones and smart watches right there on your machine to download it just go to developer dot Android
dot come Ford slash studio and then click the big green button to download Android studio
then click to agree that you've read the Terms and Conditions click the big button and then it will
download and voice studio for you.
It's quite a big file.
So you might want to go make a cup of tea while you're waiting for it to download while it's downloading.
I'll let you know a quick bit of good news and that is this version of I studio you don't need to download
and install Java separately.
You can just download Android studio itself and that's it.
Java comes pre-installed within Android itself and that's now downloaded so I can open up the DMG file
just by tapping on it then.
And then once that's extracted you'll get to a screen like this and you just drag Android studio into
applications.