All right let's talk about more ways on how to increase your social engagement for your app if possible
always enable chat inside your app.
This keeps your users engaged and talking to friends.
Maybe have tech support where you can answer questions inside your route.
Anything to keep your users enlightened engaged and spending a lot of time inside your app is always
being tracked by the App Store and calculates all of that data into your apps ranking on their app store.
Another way is to use push notifications.
But please be careful using this one.
This can scare them and delete your app.
So use this one wisely to lure them back to your app.
Always alert them for things they have opted into.
Or perhaps looking forward to in a positive way.
Email notifications should be used only after you have tried.
Push notifications because push works better to get your user back into your app.
You just have to think to yourself what features do you need to add to your app that will increase your
users social engagement.
For example offer your users a daily reward of some kind to get them back into your app.
Remember Android users must opt in to push notifications when they install the app they want whereas
on iOS the user has a choice whether or not to receive push notifications after they install their wrath.
Please note on the Android platform push notifications must be enabled and requires extra permissions.
This results in fewer downloads as a user doesn't want to be bothered.
Another way to increase your social engagement and keep your users inside your app is to show them videos
of a few minutes long.
Start your own YouTube channel and show all your vids inside your app for them to watch or for them
to watch video ads that you get paid for.
By now you should get the picture here and that's to come up with ideas to engage your users to stay
playing with your app.
This is tracked by the App Store a logarithm of which affects your App Store ranking.
Don't provide just the link or they will leave your app and that won't help your social engagement if
they leave.
Not everybody is going to have a game app.
So if you have to say a business app or any non game map you can provide YouTube video tutorials to
keep your users engaged inside your app.
Remember you can have all your written content coded so that your user doesn't need to connect to the
Internet.
Therefore keep adding fresh new written content that brings your user back on a daily basis which UPS
your apps ranking.
Be sure to check the recommended link below and I'll see you in the next lecture.