We're now going to be taking a little bit of a break from shared preferences and looking at how we can
add a menu to our Android apps in the top right which is the kind of standard location for a menu on
Android we're going to be using this in our notes app that we're making in a couple of videos time.
So let's create a new project to see how to customize the menu.
This is something that's changed actually in the most recent version of Android studio used to be that
you were given a menu by default and each app and you had to remove it if you didn't want it.
Whereas now the devil is not to have a menu and you have to add it in if you want it.
So we'll start with an app that doesn't have a menu and will create the code to add and customize the
menu.
And here we go.
So for a menu in Android we need to add one new file and we need to customize the main activity java
file as well.
So the new file is a simple layout file which just gives the layout of our menu and it's usual to create
a new folder so control click or right click on rez for resources and we're going to create a new directory
which I'll call menu.
And then we click File menu and menu resource file and I'll call this main menu
click OK.
And then you can see we've got this main menu SML file so I'm going to use the text view to add my many
and all we need to do is to create a couple of items.
So I will start off with I setting's menu which will also need an ID
it settings
and similarly we'll just create a second one
copy from the first call.
Help.
So you can see our menu.
Obviously we can customize this in the same way we would anything either in the design view or the text
view but I'll leave it as the default layout for now.
Now back in main activity we've got a few settings that we need to add before this will actually work.
And the first is to customize the on create options menu which will be run when the options menu is
created and what we mainly want to do here is link the options menu with how SML file that we've just
created.
And we do that using something called a menu inflator Djoko menu inflata and this will be able to get
menu inflator and then we'll take menu inflata and we'll inflate our menu then we want to access our
menu.
So we use resources top menu topped main menu and we want to link that to this menu here which is the
options menu.
The one in the top right.
There we go.
So now the menu will appear which is great.
Or just run it will be quicker to see it later on.
But at the moment none of the options will actually do anything.
So the final thing we need to add is on options item selected
and then here
will run superdog on options items selected.
And then we're going to check for which item was selected and we're going to do that using a switch
which you see once or twice before.
It's a bit like a big if else statement.
So we're switching on the ID of the item that was selected which is item dot get item id
and the first option quite literally is settings.
So if the item ID is our DOT ID dot settings
then for now it will just log
menu item selected.
And settings.
Another option is that
its our ID to help.
So in that case its copy and paste
menu item selected and help.
And then with a switch you always need a default.
And thats going to be return false doesnt really need to be returned foal's but
in case we do anything involving the menu from elsewhere in the app it can be useful to know whether
a successful selection was made or not.
So these returns dont particularly matter but they kind of make sense to returning true if the user
selects something and falls if they didn't.
All right so now we've got
you running.
And here it is.
So there's our menu.
We can tap on it and select settings for example and then we look in the logs.
With any luck we should see that settings every menu item selected and settings.
And similarly we select help and that will be shown there as well.
So of course just logging that the user has pressed an item in the menu of no particular use for what
we'd probably do there would be to display a new activity where the user could either look for some
help or change some settings or it might bring up a pop up or alert dialog which is what we're going
to learn how to do in the next video.
So you're there.