In the previous video we saw how to add a map to your app.
And we had a quick look at the code that made the map work.
In this video we'll be taking that further and we'll see not only how to customize the starting point
zoom level and markers on the app but also how to add different sorts of maps such as ones involving
satellite imagery.
So let's get cracking.
We're doing all our coding here in the maps activity java file which we looked at in the previous video
and we're going to start by creating a new location to send to our map on.
Now you may not know the latitude and longitude of any particular location so I'd recommend jumping
over to Google Maps and searching for whatever you want to choose as your starting location.
I'm going to go for Mt. Everest.
Why not.
And in fact right there in the you are l you can see the latitude and longitude if they're not displayed
in the U R L for some reason you can see them by control clicking on the market clicking what's here
and you'll see the latitude and longitude right there.
So I'm going to grab those and copy them into my app
get rid of the minus as well.
And paste them in there and I should really give that
a new variable name.
So call that Everest and then to add a marker in that particular location.
We use map at marker and then we create some new upmarket options.
That is a position which is now going to be Everest and a new title
which makes a bit more sense.
I mount everest Similarly we now want to move the camera to our new location so we'll just change that
variable name to Everest.
So very simple to create a new marker and zoom in on a new location.
Let's test that out.
We should be able to do it with instant starts and there we go.
So we're now centered on Mt. Everest because the mark there that if we tap on we get our Mt. Everest
label Sipa we can do a lot more than that.
First off we can customize the icon for our marker if we want to and we do that by notice we've got
new marker corruption's and a full stop and then position and full stop and title if we add another
full stop.
We can add for example an icon and then describe I can We need a bitmap descriptor
factory
and then we can choose a range of options that we can even pick an image from a file.
But I'm going to stick with the default marker and then pick a color and we get the color from bitmap
district factory and then you can see you've got a whole range there Azura the top blue sign Green et
cetera et cetera.
I'm going to go for orange.
So more code than you might think but actually fairly easy to change the color of the icon if you want
to.
Let's just see that action.
And there we go.
So now we've got a nice orange marker.
What do you want to be more zoomed in than this.
They were quite zoomed out of them and we can't really see where Everest is at least on a local scale.
But we do that by replacing New London with new flat line zoom.
You can see we've got a few other options that we can use bounds if we want to to specify that the top
left in the bottom right locations of the map but normally we're going to want something like new Laughland
zoom and then for the lat long we can use Everest and then the zoom level.
Let's start at something like 15 and you can see that that gives us a fairly zoomed in view.
In fact the number varies from 1 to 20 with one being completely zoomed out.
So you to see more or less the whole world and then 20 has zoomed in as Google Maps goes.
So you actually seeing buildings if you're zooming into a part of the world where Google has that level
of imagery that we get so we're now zoomed out as can be with our map.
All right so let's reset that as somewhere in the middle say 10.
And now for our final bit of customization We'll see how we can convert the map from just a plain map
to containing satellite imagery as well.
So we do that using Map dot and then set map type in fact have a quick look there at all the options
that you can set if you really want to get specific with your map.
We'll look at set map type and then we can just put an integer in there.
But better to choose one of the options here.
And then we've got a hybrid type non normal satellite or terrain.
So I'm going to go for a hybrid and then let's have a look.
We should now see basic roads and countries as well as
satellite imagery.
And there we go.
It's pretty impressive.
Wonderful.
So that's as far as I think we'll need to go with Google Maps for now.
We will definitely be returning to it shortly but we're going to take a brief diversion into something
that so much connected with maps and that is getting the users location.