OK so we're going to move straight on from our Twitter log in screen to use a list where we can follow
and unfollow users.
So for that we're going to need a new activity
so file new activity from the gallery and I'll choose the empty activity.
And this is going to be a fairly simple activity.
With just a simple list few
that we get taking up the whole screen.
All right now let's populate our list for you.
So I'll start by creating an array list of strings for our users.
And temporarily I'll just add a couple of uses in there.
So we'll have Rob
Caston and then we'll set up our list free.
We'll just call it LSV.
And this is going to be a list view from find by id and Ardo ID dot list V is our ID.
And then to allow the checkboxes we use List View and then set choice mode.
So this allows users to choose items on the list and we want them to be able to choose as many as they
like.
So we're going to use choice mode multiple.
And you can see there's a number of other modes there that we could use but we want them to have the
ability to follow as many people as they like.
OK then we're going to take our apps up
and we'll call it a write up and then we'll set it up here.
New array adapter
using this as the context and this time we're going to use Android dot dot layout but instead of a simple
list item one we're going to use a simple list item checked and that will give us a tick at the end
of each row which the user can select or de-select and as usual will assign the users a list to the
array adapter.
And then we'll take our list view and set the adapter to it.
OK.
We're almost ready to go.
But a couple of things before we run this up first first we're going to add an item click listener which
will allow us to do something when each individual row is selected or selected.
So we do that firstly in the normal way with a list view and an item click listener.
With a new adapter viewed on item click it's not.
And then we get the row that was tabbed using a checked
text if you will call it text checks.
And this is going to be a checked text view and we're going to get it from the view variable up here
which is the essentially the table row that was tapped or the list view item and then we can use checked
text.
The dot is checked to see whether or not it's checked.
And then we'll just log
row is checked
if it is or if it's not
is not checked.
There you go.
And then the other thing we need to do before we run the app is actually set up the redirect when the
user is located.
Otherwise we'd never see the new activity.
So I'll set this up as a method
redirect user.
And I'm actually going to check whether the user is logged in in the direct method here.
So if past user talk get current user it is not null then what creates our intent.
Which will be a new intent using the application context and we're going to redirect to main to activity
class
and then we just stopped that activity that we have.
And then we can call that in a number of places so fast when the user is logged in
second when the user is signed up.
And third we can just call it on the create method which will then check if the user is logged in and
if they are we direct them as well.
And one of the small thing I'm just going to change the title to use the list.
All right.
So let's give that a try.
As we locked ourselves in in the previous video we should already be logged in and it should redirect
immediately to the user list and we should see Robin Caston with a tick and we can either select or
de-select to them by tapping on a truck.
Let's take a look.
And here we go.
You can see we've got the check box is currently unchecked.
If we tap them then it's selected and we get our row is checked method as well.
Super.
That's a nice easy way to select and de-select are rows of tables.
Now all that remains for us is to synchronize this with pass so we get obviously the correct path she
uses.
And also that the selecting and deselecting is synchronized on paths as well.
All right.
So let's start off by getting our uses and to do that I'm going to jump sci fi folks for the posh dashboard
and just add in a couple of uses.
So we'll have Keston and password
and let's have a couple of more
Tommy with a password as well and we don't want anyone to feel left out.
We'll have
Raffi
There we go.
So now we need to do a user search to get all our users will we'll do that here.
So just get rid of the users that we had and then down here it will set up our pass query.
This is going to be on pass uses this time
and it's passes the dot gate query and the only thing we want to specify is we don't want to show the
current user in this list.
So they're will to follow themselves.
So
we're not equal to you.
And we will use a name
just make sure.
Yep there it is.
These are and we want that not equal to a
Pazienza don't get caught and use a dot get use and I'm and then we're going to run our queery.
So I find him background
with a new find Colback
and of course pull out check to see if he is no and then we'll check to see if we've got some objects.
There you go.
I'm not going to add in any error messages there but you're welcome to if you want to.
And then all we need to do here is loop through the objects list which is a list of past uses
and then we'll add them to the user's array list.
We want to add user dot get name that we gave one more quick thing I'll just Klea uses encases got anything
saved in it.
And then finally when that's done we just update the array adapter.
By notify.
Data set changed.
OK so let's just have a quick look.
We should now be able to see all our users apart from the current one.
So we should see
Ralphy told me and Keston
that they are super.
Now of course I can select and de-select them here but that's not saved on pass in any way.
So let's change that.
Now we're going to need a system to keep track of who is following who.
So I'm just going to jump over to our past dashboard and have a quick think about how we're going to
save this data.
So we want to be able to easily keep track of who our current user is following and then be able to
get all of that information in one go when we bring together the tweet so the users that our user is
following.
So I think the easiest way to do that is going to be to create and is following column which will be
an array or a list of items
that we have.
So then when the user checks a box what we need today is update the current user
and we're going to get a list or an array and the list that we're going to get is called is following
and we're going to add to that the user name of the user that they followed.
So that's uses don't get them.
We want to get the one that was tapped.
So that's I
there we go.
And then we'll just save it in the background
we don't really need a callback for that.
And then very similarly when they uncheck the and we'll remove that user so users don't get
there we go.
So let's have a quick look at that in action and make sure that that works.
And here we go.
So let's tap on Kesten ha we get a nasty crash.
Now some of you may have anticipated why we got that crash.
Let's have a quick look find what the messages right.
We're trying to add to a null object reference i.e. we're trying to add to the following list but we
haven't created that list in the app yet.
So to get round that's what I'm going to do is check to see here whether or not the user has the following
list attached to their current user object.
We can do that using if past user get current user get and then is following
and we can test to see if that's no.
And if it is then we'll create a new list for them.
So we'll have a list of strings and I'll just call it empty list.
It's going to be a new
array list.
And the usual way.
And then you take I-PASS user get current user and we'll put the following array as empty list.
And now we should be able to add to the following array when the user taps on one of the rows because
it is there we could say that to pass but we don't really need to because if by any chance these that
doesn't follow anyone here and then comes back to this page it will just add the following right back
into the current user anyway.
So let's try that again.
Here we go.
So I will tap on Kurstin and it hasn't crashed.
That's a good sign.
Let's do a quick
refresh of our use a class.
And you can see that Rob is now following Keston.
So that looks promising.
Let's just check a couple more if I choose.
Tell me and Ralphy and then de-select Kassen I should just be following Tommy and Ralphy and we get
Tommy and Ralphy on our being followed great.
So we're almost there.
And the final thing that we need to add in for this video to complete our list is that when the user
opens up the app it shows the appropriate people are ready to act.
So we'll do that down where the table is created.
So that's here.
And we can do this by checking for each of the users in the users list whether or not they're in our
is following a list.
So we'll loop through the array list the uses array list that is.
And this is going to have a bunch of strings in it which are all user names and we'll call it users.
And then for each of them we're going to check that our user is following them.
So we're going to look at pass use don't get current user.
And then we're going to get the following list.
And we want to look to see if that contains
the if that was a user name rather than user names.
We want to see if that contains the user name and if it does then we'll check the box.
So we'll do that using List View or set item checked and the item that we want to check is the location
of the user name in the user's array list and we can get that using uses dot index of.
And then use it name and then we add in either true or false depending on whether we want it checked
or not.
And if it does contain that use it we want it checked say let's have a quick look.
We should now see that when we restart
the app it will restart with Tommy and Ralphy already selected.
And there we go.
So we now have a user list that behaves exactly as we'd want it allows the user to check or uncheck
individual users to follow them or not.
And that is saved on our server.
And when the user reloads the app it reloads the correct information.
OK.
So we're doing pretty well.
Our next step is to allow users to actually post tweets and we'll do that in the next video.