Now that we've seen a little more about how Android layout works and we've seen the relationship between
the design view here and the text SML behind it we're in a position to see how we can do more to manipulate
the objects on our screen.
The views we're going to start by looking at a fading animation which is actually pretty straightforward
doesn't make this a little bit more interesting.
I'm going to get a couple of images of my favorite cartoon characters.
I suggest you get a couple of images that interest you as well so I've got Miss Simpson here on Wikipedia
and I'm just going to control click or right click and save image as and then just pop in there on the
desktop and the same thing with Bart click on him and save the image as
I.
You might be wondering why we've got two images that we're working on.
Well that will become clear in the exercise at the end of this video.
So let's create a new app
so a new project I'll call it animations all the different options and finish we get.
As this is being created for me.
Can you remember how we add an image to our app.
Well the easiest way is to find the image either in find out if you're on a Mac or explore if you're
on Windows.
I'm going to just remind them to two very straightforward file names.
So just Bart and Homer.
And then I'm going to select both of them and command C or Control-C if you are windows to copy them
and then we go into the drawable folder and command VI or control vi to paste them in so that Bart and
Homer that switch over to our design view and then we'll get rid of our
Hello World text VI and I'm going to create a full screen image of Bart.
To start off with.
So I redid that with an image view.
And so now we compare a bit more attention to what we can see there.
So I want it to be the exact top left
which is not one thing today.
So I'll just drag it in where I can and change the width to match parent and the height to match parent
as well.
And then you can see we've got top left on the alignment which looks good.
And if we just have a quick look at the text of our layout there's the code for our image.
And that all looks pretty positive.
So we've got aligned at the apparent top apparent left and parents start and there's no padding or margins
there despite what it implied when we dropped it in.
So that's exactly where we want it.
That's great.
And then we want to set the image here.
So if we scroll down
it's the SIRC remember that we're interested in so the source and we should be able to click the little
button there and then scroll down inside the durable folder down at the bottom should be Bart and Homer
that we get.
So we'll start off with Bart and there is wonderful.
Now you may have noticed as you've been messing around with your images that we have an on click property
here with images as well as buttons so you don't have to have a button to be able to click it.
So I'm going to assign the fade method to our Picture of Bhartiya.
So when we tap out the fade method it's going to be called.
Which means of course we have to go and create the fade method.
So let's do that.
We're hopefully pretty familiar with this now.
So public accessible from anywhere.
BOYD It's not returning anything.
And the name of the method is Faid it's going to be called by a view once again this is going to be
an image for you this time but that doesn't really make any difference to how code is recalled by View.
And we'll call the view view and let's import
Android to view a view to allow that.
So all that we want to happen is for the image to fade out essentially when we tap it.
So first of all we have to get the image just like we did with the added text fields before.
So let's just double click.
Get an idea of image view.
I think I'm going to change that to something a bit more specific so I call it Bart every day.
And then previously when we wanted to get a view we used text at it because that was the type of view
that we were getting but this time we're getting an image you start typing image view with a capital
I capital I remember because it's like class there go.
And again I'll call it Bart.
And to get this we're going to find view by ID.
And as we've seen before it's resources to ID.
And then the name of the ID which is bought.
So now we've got the image view.
But we've got it as a view.
We want it has an image view.
So we just put image view in parentheses beforehand.
There we go.
So now we've got a variable bot which is equal to our image.
And we just want to fight it out.
How do we do them.
Well we take boat and we're going to call the animate method.
There it is.
It's what you might anticipate we might want to use.
And all you have to do with the animate method is tell the compiler what you want to change and how
long you want to allow for the change to happen.
So let's say we want to fade the image out.
What we want to actually change is the alpha.
So I think we've come across Alpha briefly before but if you haven't seen it before Alpha is a number
generally from 0 to 1 which represents how transparent the image is.
So an alpha value of zero says that the image is invisible.
And Alpha value of one says it's completely visible.
So at the moment it has an alpha value of 1.
We want to change it to an alpha value of zero.
There we get.
And now you notice that we've got something here this expects a float value.
Now 0 will automatically be converted to a float.
But it's better to just specify that we want zero as a float.
And that's the conventional way of doing it even if you don't put that F in here.
That will work but it won't work with certain other numbers.
If for example you tried putting 0.5 in that wouldn't work you have to put 0.5 f to be clear that it's
a float that we want to put in here.
So 0.5 by default is a double.
We want to make it into a float.
So we use 0.5 half.
So generally we just put an F in every time just to make it clear that we want a flight and then we
set the duration
so set duration.
And then this is the number of milliseconds so thousandths of a second.
So if you wanted it to last two seconds for example then you would put in 2000 that we get and that's
it.
Semi-colon and that's everything we need.
So we take the variable part which is equal to our image view and we want to animate it.
We want to set the Alpha to zero which is basically making it invisible.
And we want that to happen over the course of two seconds or 2000 milliseconds.
That's it.
Let's have a look.
So now if we run this we should find that we get our body image nice and large.
And then when we tap on the body image we fight it out.
Let's take a look.
So there is there.
But if we now tap on him can see it slowly fades away over two seconds.
Fantastic.
So that's how you do fades.
And this is going to be the basis of pretty much all the animations that we do.
And we'll run through a lot of different types of animations pretty quickly in the next video.
For now.
I've got a challenge for you.
And it's not a completely straightforward one.
What I want you to do is change the function of this app so instead of just Bart fading out we've got
Bart fading into Homer.
So initially when you load the app you just see Bart just like now.
But then when you tap on him he fades out and Homer fades in.
This is known as a crossfade and is a really nice way to transition from one view to another.
So not straight forward but hopefully you can figure it out.
Best of luck
OK.
Did you manage I so the way I would do it is bring in a second image view which is going to be our home
image and will align at the top left and again will change the width to match parent and same with the
height.
So there we go.
And this time the SIRC the source is going to be home
Silis just laid him so scrolling down inside the terrible section there is wonderful.
OK.
Great.
So now we can see him on top of Bart there because that nice transparent images which is not what we
want.
We want Homer to not be visible at the beginning.
So what we can do a scroll up here and set the alpha for Homer to be zero.
There we go.
So now Homer disappears and you can have a nice little play there as well if you want to see what its
like with a Alpher of note point five.
Then you get this kind of semi visible humor there.
So that's that's what alpha values between 0 1 looked like.
But for now we want an alpha of zero for every game.
Let's just have a quick look and see what that looks in the XML.
So here's our Hoba code and you can see it's very similar to the bar code except we've got Alpha is
equal to zero G at the bottom.
So you could have done this just by adding that code at the bottom if you wanted.
So I'm going to change the ID this time using the ex-MIL because why not.
And all I do is change that to Homer there and everything else is the same as before.
So back over to design view.
And then over to our java file.
So we still want Bart to fade out in exactly the same way he did before but this time we want Homer
to fade in.
So we need to get home.
So we use the same code as before but this time we're going to call our variable Hyma and the ID of
the objects that we're looking for is also a.
And then this line fade home in is going to be very similar to the BART line say Herma and then animate
this time of course we're going to set the Alpha to one and we'll do it over the same duration say 2000
milliseconds or two seconds.
And that's it.
Let's just have a look.
Run it on the wall already running emulator and there it is.
So now we tap on bots and slightly airily.
He transitions nicely into how you met him.
So that's how we do a crossfade obviously tapping again doesn't do anything.
A nice extra challenge that I went through with you but might be to tap on Homer to get him to transition
back into Bart and then go back and forth.
That's fairly straightforward really.
It's just creating another method which would fade Homer out and bought back in and assigning that to
the homer image.
All right.
So that's fading transitions.
We're going to look at a lot more different types of transition.
All of which we can do within this animate method in the next video.