Now we're going to discuss apt key strategies.
OK.
This only applies to iOS at this time in iTunes.
They give you a field to include your key words you would like to rank for you have only 100 characters
a space under key words at the time I prepared the section of the course.
Google Play does not even ask the app developer for keywords.
They prefer to have people solely rely on your app title and app description instead.
However if they do in the future this section should help Android developers.
This part of ASIO is super important so be careful here and think hard.
Now I recommend using a service such as a mobile DV headquarters to help you track your search rankings.
Choose better key words analyze your existing keywords and spy on your competitors.
Another ASIO tool I suggest you use is called sensor Tower today finding single key words is going to
be a tough task to say the least.
So what I would highly recommend is start finding key word phrases or even longtail key words which
will help more people find your app and put your app in a less competitive environment.
Using keyword phrases will help you are ranking and giving you more exposure using relevant keywords
for your app in-app purchases.
I bet you didn't know that the app store actually indexes your key words you use for your in-app purchases.
Crazy I know but it's true.
So start using search friendly keywords that will help bring you more downloads.
Just don't use generic keywords such as full access or unlimited gems etc..
Now for Android.
Make sure you use your primary or most important key word you want to rank for in your apps title and
then mention your key words up to five times.
Only in your apps description.
It's been proven that mentioning your key word over five times has no effect in AppStore ranking.
Here are a few solid tips.
Use single words rather than multiple word phrases.
Mention your primary key word or key word phrase three to six times in your description and make it
look natural.
Research your competitors keywords and go for ones that are untapped and less competitive.
Don't repeat words used in the title put key words in priority order.
Keep playing with your key words the ones that do not convert now might convert in the future as your
app becomes more popular.
Separate keywords with commas.
Don't use spaces.
Be sure to check the recommended links below.
Ok I'll see you in the next lecture.