So now that you're an expert on variables Let's go and look at arrays which are an extremely important
way of storing information.
If by the way you're getting a little antsy because we haven't made an app in a while.
Don't worry you've just got two videos to go and then we're going to go back to enjoy studio and use
all of the Java knowledge that we've built so far to make a high or low a guessing game.
So just hold on till then.
And let's take a look at arrays first.
So we met the array a few videos ago when we saw this string and then square brackets.
But I kind of brushed over exactly what it was.
So let's look in more detail now.
Let's say we wanted to store a bunch of numbers.
So if for example I wanted to store the first few prime numbers that is the numbers that have no factors
other than 1 and themselves then this is going to be a bunch of integers whole numbers.
So I'll call it it.
And then I use the open and close square brackets to say the I want this to be an array of integers
and then I'll call it prime numbers.
So just in the same way as we did with variables.
So this is saying we want to create an array of integers which is called prime numbers and then we use
curly brackets to store all the numbers that we want to store.
So the first prime number is two.
Second one is three.
The third one is 5 and 7 11 and we'll do one more.
13.
There we go.
So that's it.
That's our array of prime numbers and it is just a collection of.
In this case integers 2 3 5 7 11 13.
So that's all an array is.
You can imagine that's a very useful construct for us if we wanted to have a list of images that we've
downloaded from Instagram or a list of our users or anything like that.
We can store it in an array and we can store as many different items as we need without having to create
new variable names for each of them.
So let's just print that to the console and see what the system does with it.
So systems are out of print line
prime numbers.
I don't need a semi-colon there as well.
It's easy to forget because it's a curly bracket.
So we get a collection of strange symbols here which is very useful for us.
This is because prime numbers is an array and not a string.
And so trying to print as a line doesn't work.
We get this strange object instead.
And let's try and display the second member of the array.
So prime numbers and then square brackets with two inside.
Now see if you can anticipate what number that is going to display which of these numbers will get pushed
to the console.
It's the number five.
That might be slightly unexpected for you if you haven't worked with a raise before.
So it's actually the third number even though we've got two here.
And that's because the first is considered to be the with number in the array.
So if we put prime numbers and then square brackets
and then Syrie then that will give us the two that we get.
So those are two target.
Zero is the number two.
And then one would be three.
Two would be five.
Three would be seven etc..
So that's a common starter error is to get confused as to which map of the array that you want.
And forgetting that it starts at zero.
So there are a few things that you can do with a raise.
First one is to find out how many items are in your right.
And we do that using dot length.
But this time we don't use the parentheses.
So let's take a look.
And that should give us the number of items in the right which is 6.
Excellent.
Now the main limitation with arrays as we're using them here is that they can't be altered.
That is have elements added to them or taken away from them after they've been created.
Now that's probably a deal breaker for most of the arrays that we'd want to use but we're going to move
quickly on from this primitive array type to the list type which does allow you to add and take away
and do a lot of other things to your arrays.
So in order to be able to use the list type we need to import a number of different frameworks and save
us importing all them individually.
We can use Java Util and then dot star and that will import a number of different frameworks that will
give us all the methods that we need and the classes that we need to create lists.
So let's get rid of the code that we have before and see how we create a list.
It's slightly more complicated than creating an array.
So now to create our list we write down the type.
First of all which is a list and then the name.
So I'm just going to call it a list with a lowercase L and this time we set it equal to a new array
list.
So this is a different way of creating an object instead of setting it equal to the value that we actually
want.
We just create the type that we're going to use so we're going to use an array list.
There are various other lists types but we'll stick with this one for now because it does everything
we need.
So we're just creating a new array list and this construct is something that we'll see again and again
later in the course when you're creating variables of certain types.
You can use it with strings and other variables that we've seen before as well.
And then to add items to our list we use the Add method so the list at.
And if we wanted to add the first item in our prime numbers list then we would add 2 and then we do
the same three
and the next one is a 5.
I'll stop there.
Feel free to add some more if you like but those are the first three prime numbers.
Felty.
And then if we wanted to print one of those to the console which you system start out of print line
and this time we'd use list dot get.
And then we give the number of the item that we want.
So a quick challenge for you if we wanted three.
What number would we use here.
I hope you said one because this would be zero.
This is one this is 2.
Cetera et cetera.
So a list to get and then one will give us the second item in the list.
So that should print three every day.
So now that we've got this slightly more complicated set up we can do much more powerful things so we
can add items.
Of course we can take them away as well.
To do that we use list don't remove.
And then we give the index of the number that we want to remove.
So let's say we want to remove this three here.
This has an index of 1 0 or 1 and 2.
So we use list don't remove.
And then one and just have a quick think what is this going to output now.
Let's run it and see if you are right.
The answer is 5.
Because this array has now lost the middle item.
So it's only a 2 and a 5.
So the item with index number 1 is the 5.
And just to prove that to you I'll show you how we can actually display the whole of this list rather
than just one particular item.
We use a function that we have seen before.
That's two string.
So that just converts our list to a string so that we can put it in the console and see what's in there.
So there we go.
So the items in the list are now just a two and a 5.
All right.
Quick challenge then can you create a list of 3 say countries and then remove an item from that list
and add a different one in.
So create a list of three countries remove one added in and then display it in the console.
Good luck.
All right well let's create a list so I'll call it countries and that's going to be a new array list
just like that.
And then we'll add our countries one by one.
Countries not at all put England
and then let's add another one.
So are people local say Scotland and then
Wales
OK I think while I'm here I'm just going to check that that's all worked OK.
It's just him out duck print line and then countries
to string a case let's just make sure that created it.
England Scotland Wales fantastic.
So let's remove Wales so we do that using countries remove.
And then I want to remove That's the zeroth one.
That's the first one that's the second one.
So now do we need to.
And then finally countries had Let's put Ireland there as a state like.
All right.
There we go.
So England Scotland and Ireland.
So we've created our right.
We've removed an item from it and we've added one in its place.
The last thing I want to show you in this video is maps which work in similar ways to lists.
But something is crucially different about them.
Let's find out what it is.
Let's get rid of our work on lists so maps we've already imported everything that we need for that because
we've been ported all at the Java utility frameworks.
We create a map in exactly the same way as we create a list.
So I'm going to call it math in lowercase.
And so it's a new something but it's not an array list it's a hash map so recreate that like that.
And now we put an item into this map and we do that using it.
And now you'll see the difference between the hash map and an array or a list.
So I'm going to add for example Father
Rob
say I just get my syntax right.
There we go.
So what this does is it maps farver to the value Rob.
So whereas arrays are lists that go 0 1 2 3 4 5 on the index here we can map a certain index to a certain
value.
So now if we take system how it's print line if I want to print a particular value I would use map don't
get and then the key which is father so let's just make sure that that returns roll up as we would expect.
So you can see what we're doing we're linking father to rob and then I can imagine what that
next might be.
So mother in this case will have as Keston and we can again use that to string function if we want to
look at the whole of Emap
So map talked to string.
Let's take a look.
So we've got mother is Caston and father is Rob and again we can use remove.
Not that I would ever want to of course but if we wanted to remove an item for this from this map we
would just use the key just like that and then that would remove that item and we're left with just
the first item.
And finally
as with arrays we can use map dot size to tell us the number of items in the map.
So in this case just one.
So that's as far as we're going to go with arrays lists and maps for the moment.
But later on we'll see how to do things like loop through an array or a list or a map find specific
values and a lot more.
Now we're getting close to being able to build our higher or lower app but we need one more important
programming construct and that is the if statement and we'll look at that and how it works in Java in
the next video.