Now that we know how to display and customize maps for our users we're going to find out how to get
the users location and then eventually to center that map right there on it.
This is the first the functionality that we're going to need to ask the user permission for as well.
We'll see how to request user permissions in order to get the location itself.
All right so I'm going to start a new project for our location demo
next we'll stick with marshmallow and I'm going to go for an empty activity this time just to separate
the location side of things from the map side to hopefully keep things a little simpler.
OK.
Here we go.
So we'll start by requesting the user permissions and we're going to do that in the manifest file that
we saw a long time ago.
Here it is Android manifest that SML and if you remember this contains various bits of information about
our app and we want to add a permission which I'll put at the bottom of the manifest and you can see
if we start typing uses.
And we've got users permission and then it will predict Android name and I'm going to go for the fine
location.
If you don't need a particularly precise location you can go for the course location which will give
you the location according to the Wi-Fi or network signal from the phone which is much more battery
efficient.
But if you're doing things with maps you're probably going to want the fine location and then more close
that to and a permission request.
So make sure you put your permission request in.
Otherwise none of your GPS GPS related code will work.
All right so now we're going to write the code to get the user's location and we'll do that in the uncreate
method so it will just run as soon as the app runs and the process is reasonably straightforward is
actually very similar to how it's done on iOS If you've done any iPhone or iPad app development before.
We start by creating a location manager which we normally call location manager with a little and we
get this from this to get the current main activity class and then from that class we get a system service
and then the system service that we need is context dot location service.
So that will allow us to access the location service on the phone itself.
We do need to convert this to a location manager.
So we do that in the way that we're fairly used to with location manager in parentheses.
We create a location listener which will listen for changes in location we'll call it location listener
with a little.
And this is going to be a new location listener and you can see where given the different methods that
a location listener needs which are on location changed when the phone moves on status changed which
is called when the location service is either enabled or disabled.
And then we've got some specific methods for when the location services enabled and when it's disabled
by the user.
So obviously the one we're really interested in here is they on location changed method.
And here you can see we've given a location variable.
So for now I'm just going to log
under the tag location
the location has a string.
So now we have a code for displaying the user's location in the logs.
But unfortunately we're not quite done yet because since Android marshmallow we need to explicitly request
the user's permission because their location.
So let's do that.
We start by checking to see if we already have permission.
And we do this using a class called context compact sure for compatibility.
So this will make our app backward compatible to the marshmallow versions of Android and we want to
check
self permission
and you can see we need two variables in this method that is the current context and the permission
that we want to check for.
So the context is just this i.e. our main activity and the permission we want to check for is manifest
got permission taught access fine location.
So we're checking to see if we have that permission or not.
So we're going to check to see if this is not equal to
package manager
Dot's permission granted.
So this is if we don't have permission if we don't have permission we'll have to ask for it.
And we do that using activity
combat for activity compatability and this time where requesting permissions and you can see we've got
an activity that we're requesting permissions for that is this and then we need an array of strings
to show what we want to request permission for.
So we're going to create a new string array like that and it's going to have one member in curly brackets
and that is manifest got permission to access fine location.
And then finally we need to give an interview and this can be any number you want.
It's essentially a number that we can check at the other end.
That was this particular request that was made.
We are only making one request so we don't really care too much about this number.
I'm just going to put number one.
So this will then ask for permission and actually we can see this in action if we run the app now we
should say that it asks us for permission to get the user's location and there we go.
So it's now asking us for permission so we're halfway there.
But I'm not going to press anything yet because we're not doing anything when they say yes or no.
So to do that we have to prepare another method.
And this is on request permissions result.
It is so we can use all the pre-created code there.
It's a method that already exists.
So we have to override it and it will give us the request code that is the number one and then the permissions
and the results.
So if we wanted to we could test for the request code being equal to one.
But we know that we only have one request here so we don't need to do that.
So.
I'm going to do is look to see if Grant results Daut length is greater than zero.
And we'll also be very sure by checking that Grundt results 0 3 is equal to package manager got permission
granted.
So both of those are true.
We have permission hurrah.
So what do we do if we have permission.
Well we can now start listening for the users location to do that we'll need location manager.
So I'm going to redefine location manager here in the class so that I can access it.
In both of these methods.
So to actually do the listening for the location we use location manager to request location updates
and we're using the fine locations.
Are we going to use the CPS provider which is in location manager at CPS provider and then we need to
give a minimum time and a minimum distance that will lead to us getting an update.
And I'm going to put 0 0 which will mean that we get every update.
But if we wanted to be careful of the use of battery and we only wanted to check for either say every
10 seconds or every 10 meters or something like that then we can change these numbers to use the CPS
less frequently and we need to link that up with a location listener which is this location listener
here.
So I'm going to do the same thing and define it.
Outside.
And then I can use it there as well.
And you can see we've got an error here.
That's because we need to explicitly check for permission once again even though we've checked the permission
has been granted.
We are actually for the code to work.
We need to do a check.
Very similar to this to check that we actually have permission.
So if you remember this was a check to see if we didn't have permission.
So now we'll change that to see if we do have permission and if we do
then we'll request the location updates.
So let's try this out.
We should now find that we get the user's location logs open
we go.
So we're going to allow the location to be read by the app.
And now you might be wondering how are we going to actually change the user's location.
I'm not going to run around the room with my laptop.
I'm going to click these three dots here next to the emulator which will bring up the extended controls
and allow us to update the user's imaginary location to whatever we like.
So if I change the latitude to 40 and then click Send You can see down here in the logs we get the user's
location that is 40 minus 130 point zero right.
Which is the location up here.
Fabulous.
So one more change I'd like to make and that is that at the moment if we run the app with permission
already having been granted we won't actually get the location updates because this method is only called
when the user explicitly gives permission to get the location.
So I'm going to add in
this line here.
As an else statement so here this means we have permission so we can do the location manager check.
So let's just run that for the final time and make sure that that works.
So now when we run the app we've already given it permission.
So we shouldn't need to do it again but we should have the location updates up and running
it we go.
So I'll update this just something like 45 and then send the updates to the device.
And then let's have a look.
And there we go.
You can see we've got the new location there so you can essentially use this as a boiler plate for how
to get the user's location in marshmallow and onwards.
There is of course a chance that your app will be running on a device earlier than marshmallow.
And so we should really check for that as well.
So I'm going to add in a quick check to see if device is running
STK less than 23 23 being marshmallow.
So I can check that with.
If build dot version dot SDK it is less than 23.
So if that's the case I can just request the location updates.
I don't need to do any of this messing around with permissions but if it's not the case then I do need
to do my permissions check.
So I'll put an else in there.
Fantastic.
So I hope that's all fairly clear and I hope that's all in your mind as well because I'm going to be
asking you to recreate this in the next video where we're going to be integrating location and maps
by creating a map which is centered on the user's location.
See that.