That very quickly before we look at working with text views I just want to show you how to open up the
sample projects that come with this course.
Essentially there are two ways to do it.
So if I start by closing down the current project which I'll just do by file closed project
so you can see what taken back to the under studio menu.
Now with a quick link to the app that we created.
But if we didn't have that quick link then I wanted to open an existing project.
I would just click that option and then find the project i.e. find the sample project that you've downloaded
and then I know it's an android studio projects and then if you've downloaded the project and unzipped
it it should appear right there with the name of the app and then you just click OK.
And that will open up the project for you.
The other way to do it is to find the file that you've just downloaded.
So in my case it's in Android studio projects and then open up the folder and double click on the build
dot cradle file and that will then allow you to essentially import the project from the cradle file
which essentially just creates the Android studio project for you to work with.
The first option opening from Andrews studio is a little bit faster.
So I'd recommend going for that one over the second but either will work absolutely fine.
So here we are back in our projects it's likely that when you open it up you'll see this big blank screen.
So you need to bring in project and then open up the app structure to get at whichever file you want
to get it.
To see how the appliques.
All right.
So that's how we open and work with the sample projects and with Andres Judaea projects in general in
the next video.
We'll see how to work with next few widgets and customize them to our desire.
So you.