The animate method that we used in the previous video is not only good for fades but we can use pretty
much any type of animation with it.
So in this video we're going to just look at a few different types and we're going to start with translations.
So I'm going see just comment out the lines to do with Homer.
We haven't actually seen comments officially before but they're very useful ways to entertain your code
to show what your code is doing and that will say quite useful for getting rid of lines of code that
you don't necessarily want to delete because you might want to use them later but you're not interested
in them right now and to create a comment.
We just use a double slash like that which is the same as pretty much every programming language out
there.
And that comment out the line following the double slash.
So let's say we wanted to move part of the screen so from his initial central position just drop him
off the screen using an animation.
Well obviously we don't want to fade him out anymore so we'll remove the alpha and then if you put a
y here you can see we've got a bunch of different transformations that we can use on y.
Now why is the vertical axis so from top to bottom of the screen.
And what we're particularly interested in here is translation y by so translation if you may remember
from your math studies is a movement essentially.
So we do it just moving it around the screen and then if we want to move it by a certain number of pixels
then we put those number of pixels in.
So if we want to move of the screen probably something like a thousand pixels is going to do a good
job.
Now as I said before we should clarify that this is a.
Even though it's a bit like an integer.
So we just put it half on the end just to be very clear that this is a flight.
So now instead of fighting it out this is going to translate him down the screen which will essentially
move him off the bottom of the screen.
Let's take a look.
So there is give him a tap and off he goes.
So two seconds off the bottom of the screen.
Fabulous.
So very quick challenge for you.
Can you make it so that instead of translating off the bottom of the screen he translates off the left
of the screen.
So off to the left not at the bottom.
Good luck.
Did you manage that.
There were two aspects to it.
One of them was the fairly straightforward instead of translation.
Why we changed the method name to translation X by
get rid of the bits we don't need but we may have anticipated or you may have realized when you run
your app that this is going to move it off to the right.
And I asked to move off to the left.
So we just change that to a minus and then a minus moves it to the left or up.
If you're doing a vertical translation.
So let's just check make sure that works that should animate Bart off to the left of the screen this
time
again.
So there is an tap on him and he goes to the left.
Brilliant So that's translations moving left right up and down.
Another useful thing to do with translations is move an object on to the screen.
When it's initially off the screen so maybe you want to have an object that slides in from the left
or from the top or something like that.
The way I would do that would be to initially take your object and move it off screen so we could do
that using an animation remember our own create method down here is what happens when the app itself
is actually run.
So if I copy that down and copy the image be set up as well.
So if I ran this code we'd find that as soon as the app was run but would be animated off the screen
with this generation.
However that's not really exactly what we want.
We don't want an animation to put him on the screen.
We want him to be invisible to the user at the very start.
So what we can do is instead of animating
we just use set translation X and that is basically the same as an animation but with a zero animation
times it happens instantly rather than gradually.
So if we want to set him of the screen to the left we might use minus 1000 and then have to clarify
that this is a float.
And then of course we want to change the animation so that it's 1000 f move him back to the right and
onto the screen.
One issue with the APIs we've got at the moment is that it's not actually going to work because we can't
tap on Bart when he's off the screen.
So what I'm going to do is just bring in Houma just a little bit to allow us to tap on him.
So we'll change the
way the alpha T.
No point to just so that we can see him there is just about and then we'll change the unclick
to that fate was the name of our method.
So now we can click on either Bart or Homer.
And this time when we run the app Bart will not be there.
Even though he's there in our design view AAP will be initially empty.
Oh no it won't be empty it will have faded Homer in there will be say just faded home but not bought.
So there we go.
And then if we tap on Homer and Bart animates in fabulous.
Of course you don't need a faded home to get the animation in.
You could have a button or just have it happen automatically however you want to trigger the animation
but that's how you animate something in from off the edge of the screen.
Let's look at some different types of animation.
So let's take rotations for example.
Now I want to get rid of this taking about off the screen.
I'm just going to show you another type of comment.
While I do that we can comment blocks of code using slash and then stop and then and comment using start
and then slash.
So again very standard almost all programming languages use something very similar to that and that
just allows you to block off the whole of the code in between those two lines.
Rather than doing it line by line.
OK so let's try a rotation
again.
We can just change that and rotation there.
So there it is and then all we need to put in the parentheses is the angle that we want to rotate.
So this is in degrees so a 360 would be a full rotation.
So let's try a 180 degrees and we'll put an F on again because this is a float so this should be a rotation
that turns him upside down because we're rotating half of a full circle in two seconds.
Let's take a look.
In fact just While that's lading I'll get rid of Homer for future apps because we don't need him now.
The parts on the screen let's take a look.
So there we go.
Lovely.
Just as you as you'd want a nice rotation.
You can experiment with that if you up.
The number of degrees substantially.
Then you can get any kind of spinning around as have a quick look of that.
It's quite good fun so that'll be a lot of circles.
In two seconds.
Then we shouldn't have Heimer any more visible at least here we go.
Hey good fun.
All right.
Lovely.
So there's our rotations.
The last type of transformation that we're going to look at is shrinking and growing so making something
bigger and smaller.
We do that using scale.
So we've got scale x and scale y so let's say we want to shrink him down to half his size.
So we'll go for scale x to nought point five and again f and we going to want to scale Y as well.
So let's put that M scale Y and 0.5 F..
And this also shows you how you can combine a number of different transformations very easily so we
could put an alpha in there to change the opacity of rotational value and we can put whatever we like
it and you can combine all those into just a single transformation.
So let's just have a quick look at that.
We should find that Bart animates.
You might want to think about what happens to Bart's position.
Is he going to remain in the center of the screen.
Is he going to move off to one corner.
If you can anticipate what he's going to do.
We go he does indeed remain at the center.
So the center point of the image is maintained.
So that's all the transformations we're going to look at.
I'm going to give you a very simple challenge to practice these and that simply is to create an animation
using three of the different transformation types that we've seen which results in Bart ending up full
screen and positioned as he was initially so he can be as creative as you like go for whatever type
of transformations you want but it has to be at least three.
And Bart has to end up in his original position.
Durford
All right.
Hope you had fun with that one.
So I'm going to start off by bringing back my code to move around the beginning and I'm going to give
him two translations to start with translation of x.
So off to the left of the screen and that's off to the top of the screen as well.
And then I'm going to bring him in and spin him at the same time.
So let's get rid of those.
So my two translations are going to be just put translation ex-spy and I want a thousand f that and
translation y by and a thousand deaths there too.
And finally I want to do the spin.
So that's rotation by and then we'll do 3600 degrees which will see him rotating 10 times in that two
seconds and you can see it's not that easy to see what's going on here when you've got these really
long lines.
So it's possible to break them into several different lines just by adding line breaks.
And that just makes the code look a lot nicer when you've got these long lines with lots of different
methods in there.
So I'd recommend doing that to keep your code nice and readable.
Now of course has Bart is offscreen.
We're going to need Homer again.
To have something to tap on so I'll give him his Alpher.
No point to just that he's there.
For us to make bot do his spinning and moving.
Great so let's have a look.
That should do what we want.
So when it runs we should just see him because Bart's been moved off screen and then when we tap him
that boss should come spinning into the area.
There comes.
Fabulous fantastic.
So I hope you manage to come up with something even more exciting than my transformation that we're
now going to use our considerable animation skills to make a really quite complicated app a game version
of Kinect for which if you haven't played before.
I'll explain the rules in the next one and we're going to make it on our phone screen.
So there.