A B split testing is a technique.
Many people use to see whether version A is better and converting into a download.
In our case for an app developer in comparison to Version B you're basically comparing how version A
does against version B.
For example let's say Version A of your app icon has a red border and version B has a blue border through
split testing.
You see the red border converted in to 10 more downloads then version B's blue border.
You can do this with everything such as your apt description screen shots video previews names call
to actions colors sizes pricing landing pages headlines a set or the bottom line here is you want to
test everything so you can increase your downloads and social engagement.
Please no.
While testing versions and be your only changing one thing at a time it's also best to split your traffic
to both designs.
So 50 percent see version a 50 percent C version be best.
Nest is a company that allows you to perform A B split testing for free but you can always upgrade to
allow more apps to be tested.
They quote a five point eight percent increase in instillations due to a B splitting.
Anyway take a look at it.
It's very necessary you do this to increase your installs and social engagement.
Be sure to check the recommended links below and I'll see you in the next lecture.