Now that you've learned how to work with the shared preferences and also how to create menus and use
a lot dialogues we're going to put this all together and build a note taking app.
And here's how it works.
So when we started off we've got an example note that we can then tap on and end it using a full screen
edit text or leave it to you to figure out how to do that.
And then of course we can change this note to anything we like.
And then we can go back and see the changes that we can also add new notes using the menu.
So at night we'll add a blank note
and then we can go back and we can see both of those notes.
And indeed we can long press to get an alert as well.
And then if we tap Yes that's saved or this of course as well is covered by permanent storage using
shared preferences.
So you can shut down the app and you'll see actually the same set of notes when you open it up again.
So that's the challenge.
Best of luck.
Pause the video and off you go.
OK.
That one well as ever.
I'm going to start with a new project and we'll just call this notes next.
And we have the marshmallow SDK and an empty activity and our first activity then is going to be our
list view where we'll put our notes as the user saves them.
So let's start by adding that in.
We'll do that an activity main layout and then get rid of the text the
and drag in our list view.
If we get
and I'll give it an idea of list view.
All right.
So we need for now.
So back over to main activity and then in the create method just run it in the background that
things all set up will create a variable length or at least we could at least be
and we're going to cast this to a list view and we'll get it from find view by ID using resources IDs
dot V.
Now we're going to need as usual an array list linked to our list view.
I'm going to need to access it from all parts of the app so I'm going to define it up here.
It's going to be an array list of strings
and I'll call it notes.
And this is going to be a new array list.
OK.
And for now we'll just add two notes an initial note.
So I'll call it
Example night then we'll set up our array adapter
call it wrapped up
how this is going to be a new right adapter.
Using the main activity or this as the context and then Android
dot lay out that simple list item one as the format and then notes as the list array.
And then we'll take a list view and we'll set an adapter to it.
And that adapter will be array adapter.
This just ties in
and a very blessed
and then I'll just do a quick run of that just to make sure that Billis view is displaying correctly.
And there we go.
Everything looks great.
Then of course typing on an item in the list view at the moment doesn't do anything.
We're going to want that to jump to a second activity where the user can edit their note.
So let's create a new activity
and we want an empty activity as usual
and I'll call this the note editor activity
and every game.
And here we're just going to have a single edit text but it's an edit text that we haven't used before.
I hope you spotted it.
It's the multi-line text.
So that's of course ideal for adding things like notes where we want to use it to be able to add a large
amount of multi-line text.
All right let's make this full screen as well.
And I'm also going to take it a little bit further and take the relative lay out and remove the padding
so you can see some default padding them.
I'm just going to set the padding for all top bottom left and right to be zero.
And that will make it full screen and just look like we're editing the whole screen which is a bit nicer.
OK.
So now back to main activity.
And we want to now add the feature when they use the taps on an item in the list we like that it jumps
to the note editor activity.
And we should be fairly comfortable with this by now.
So we're going to take this view and set an on item click listener and this is going to be a new Adap.tv
dot on right and click listener.
And then when an item is clicked on item click method will be called and we're going to want to jump
to the note editor activity.
So we'll create an intent
called intent
which is going to be a new intent
using the application context as the context and then note editor activity class as the location of
the intent.
And of course we also want to let the new activity know which item was tapped.
So we're going to put an extra
I'll call it note I.D. and it's going to be high.
This variable here which tells us they wrote road number that was tapped and then we're going to start
activity and the activity we're going to start is the intent.
All right.
So just before we run and check that I'm going to jump over to our new activity and we're going to display
the text for the note that the user has selected.
So we will do that in the edit text.
So let's just give it an ID or sort of get an idea of added text.
I think that will define as is only going to be one added text in this app.
So let's create an edit text call that text is going to be an edit text and we'll get it from a find
view by ID card or ID at text then we need to get the note Id that was passed to this activity from
main activity.
So we'll do that by creating an intent which will be this time the content that was used to get to this
activity and then
we'll create an integer node ID which is going to be equal to the intent to get in extra.
And the name of the variable that we want to try and get the extra of is note ID.
And we want to be pretty careful here just in case we get an invalid note Id somehow passed.
So what I'm going to do is give that a default value of minus one which is impossible to get on the
main activity because the list view Id start at zero.
So then we'll do a check to see if Note ID is not minus 1
and if that's the case then we'll set the text of the text text to main activity dot notes and we'll
need to set that as a static variable type to allow that.
And then we want to get
the note ID.
All right.
So let's try that out.
So we've now created an edit text and we're getting the note Id value from the intent.
And if it's not minus 1 then we're getting the value of the notes text and displaying it in the edit
text.
So let's see this in action.
Here we go.
So here's an example note.
Tap on that.
And there we go.
So it worked almost exactly as intended.
We've got the content and we're ready to go to edit it.
But it is centered in the screen which is not exactly what we want.
So let's just go back and change that if you remember we change that with the prop..
Gravity which is currently center vertical.
So let's change it to top and left.
Right.
So now we've got our main screen up and running.
And we've got our note editor displaying our note the next step is to if the note as the user edits
it.
So as I mentioned this isn't something we've done before.
So let's see if we can figure out how to do it.
So we're working with an edit text here
and we want to run some code when the text is changed.
Something like that.
So let's see what we get here.
So point five seconds after text change that could be useful but it's not quite what we want.
Finished typing event.
Not exactly how to apply the text change event on edit text.
Probably that would give us a result.
But this one actually Android on text change.
Listener that sounds like the sort of thing that we want
and here we go look at a text changed listener and then we've got some methods there off the text change
before text change and on text changed.
I think that's ideal for us.
So add text change listener looks like what we want.
Let's see if we can add that in here.
So we'll take our edit text and add text changed listener let's just have a look.
So it looks like we need a new text Wotcha
every go so let's use that.
And it's giving us the methods that we need.
So before and after text change we're not that interested in what we need on text changed.
And I'd be willing to bet that this character sequence here is the content of the text which is what
we need.
So let's give that a try.
So we want to update the notes array list from the main activity.
So it will take main activity notes and will set and the integer the item in the array list that we
want to change is going to be node ID.
And the thing we want to change to this character sequence here
so that should do the trick but don't notice that character sequences of a type character sequence.
So we're going to need to convert that to a string.
So we use string dot value of to convert that character sequence to a string.
And then we just want to update the sphere itself via the Araya adapter.
So I will take main activity dot and then we want to access the array adapter to do that.
I'll need to redefine it
up here.
There we go.
And then we can get the array adapter and notify data set changed.
So now when we run the app we should be able to edit the note and the changes will be automatically
saved in the initial load field.
And then of course displayed on the list view.
And here we go.
So I will type example note.
It is displayed nicely now
so I'll change that to a hello world.
And then close the keyboard and go back and we should indeed see Hello world at the top of our list
view
so other than permanent storage We've got almost all the features that we need except for the adding
and deleting of notes.
So let's do that and then we'll add the permanent storage aspect at the very end.
So adding a note we're going to do as a menu item at the top right there.
So let's make that happen.
We're going to need to add a new directory inside the resources folder.
I'll call it menu.
And then within that we're going to add a new menu Rizzo's file
I'll call it add no menu can to be a very simple menu
with just a single item in that
with an ID of ADD at.
Note
and a title of that note and then we'll add it to our main activity
by adding our two methods.
First on create options many.
And then we use our menu inflator to link our menu with the menu that we've just created.
We'll call it menu later.
We use the get menu inflator method to create it and then we'll inflate our menu.
And we want to use our dogs menu dot add note menu.
I this one that I just created and we want to assign that to the menu that's just been created.
Okay.
And then we want to add our own options item selected
and we want to day any default code that's required and there's only one case that we're really interested
in.
So we're going to look for item darte get item ID and begin going to test to see if that's equal to
the DOT ID dot ad note.
So that was the ID of the menu item I just created them.
And if that's the case then we want to jump to the new activity.
So intent intent and this is going to be a new
intent using the application context.
And note we're going to GMAC note editor activity dot class and this time I'm not going to provide a
note Id.
So instead we're just going to start the activity
via the Internet.
All right.
So now we need to prepare our note editor activity to add a new note.
So we'll do this here.
So essentially he checks for a valid note ID and if there isn't one then we're going to add a new one.
So I'm going to start by adding it to the notes.
All right let's.
And initially is just going to be empty.
So I'm just creating an empty note here.
Now it's going to be updated here.
So we're going to need a note I.D. to be able to access it.
It's actually quite easy to set.
We just get note I.D. is equal to the main activity notes dot size minus one.
So if for example the notes that we've just added was the third item then it would have an idea of 2
and the size of the notes frailest would be three.
So minus one gives us the two.
Now we do have an issue here because we cannot edit final variables they're fixed in value.
So what we'll do is define my note Id up here as a global variable and then down here we'll just updated
and then we can access it from anywhere.
And I'll also update the array adapter to display
in the history
k so we will get that a quick try.
I do seem to have an error in main activity there let's have a look and see what's going wrong yes.
You've got a missing return statement here.
In the on line options item selected menu.
So I'll just return true if the appropriate item is selected and return false.
If it's not
easily forgotten so let's give that a try.
So we should now be able to use a menu item to add a new note and that will be correctly saved within
our app.
Let's give it a go.
Here we are so thick in the menu and at Note that then jumps around you note
I look at myself a reminder to get milk and then go back and there it is wonderful.
So we're looking at just two things left now.
One is to allow users to delete notes with a long press and the other is of course permanent storage.
So let's do the delete process first.
We're going to be running this in main activity and we're going to need an all night long press listener
so let's add that in a list view set on item long click listener and again we're going to need an adaptive
view on item long click listener
and here this is where we're going to use our dialog builder.
To give the user just an option to confirm that they want to delete that note so it will need a new
alert
dialogue builder
using the application context
and then we'll do the usual process so we'll set the icon to Android.
Doc drawable and I use the alert dialog icon
will set the title T.
Are you sure.
And what's the message do you want to delete this note.
And then we'll set the positive button.
Yes.
And we'll add
new dialogue interface on click listener.
There we go see if that one is pressed and we want to remove it from notes
so we'll use notes don't remove.
And the one that we want to remove is the one that was pressed.
So that's why
and then we'll update the data
OK.
That's what we need to do there.
Then we'll set the negative button to just know.
And we don't need anything to happen if they click no.
So we'll leave the method as no.
And then finally show to show the alert dialog and just before we run that couple of quick changes that
we need to make.
We need to change return false here to return true.
Otherwise when we do the long click it will assume that we want to do a short click as well.
So the return tree overcomes that and only does the long click.
And also in my testing we're going to get issues here with this application context being the context
for our builder.
So we actually want the activity to be the context not the application.
And we would normally do this to make that happen but we can't do that here because we're within an
on item long click method so that this would refer to that.
So to force the main activity to be the context we use main activity dot this.
All right.
So let's give that a try.
We should now get our alerts popping up and then
if we choose yes it will remove our example node.
So I've already got two example notes here.
So I'm going to Long press on the first one we've got the message coming up.
Click yes.
Ah we've got a crash which is curious but again worth leaving in I think and this is because we've got
two eyes here.
So when we're talking about eye in this context we actually want this one the one that was long clicked
on not the button that was clicked on to say yes.
So to get around virus or create an integer called item to delete and we'll set that equal to I.
And then here we'll use item to delete instead of.
So again easy mistake to make.
I thought I'd leave that in because I wonder if some of you might have done that too.
So let's try it again.
So now finally with any luck we'll do our long press on our example notes tap.
Yes.
And it's got wonderful.
Of course I can still add a new note.
Here we go.
I'll put learn Java as my instruction and there it is.
And of course a long press will get rid of that as well.
Quite so.
Now Notes app works exactly as we'd like but of course we don't have the permanent storage yet.
So let's set that up.
Now there's a few places we're going to need to update the permanent storage.
So one is right here when we delete an item one is here when we save the content of an item and possibly
we could save permanent storage here.
When a new item is added although if they don't actually get the note whether or not we want to save
a blank note for them permanently is debatable.
In fact I'm going to not do it there so I'm just going to do it there and over in the main activity
when the item is deleted.
But the code is going to be very similar for both.
And I'm going to use the string set this time.
You're very welcome to use the same method that we used in the memorable places app but just for a bit
of variety or so you have to do it with a string set.
So let's set up our shared preferences Gaulish preferences and this time we are going to use the application
context and we're going to get the shared preferences using the package Id say coma.
Percival notes.
And as before we'll use context dot
mode private to only our app can access the data.
And you'll remember hopefully that shared preferences allows us to get a number of different variable
types.
And the one we're going to be working with here is the string set.
So we need a set to be working with.
So I'm just going to create a set which is known as a hash set.
So it's a set of strings which I'll just call set and this is going to be a new Hash set.
Are we going to create it from now array list.
I mean activity dot next.
Simple as that.
So we create our string from a rightist and then we say it in shared preferences so shared preferences
or edits don't put strings at and the strings that we want to put is set.
And I'm going to call it next.
And then don't forget they apply at the end and that's it.
And then we'll just copy and paste that code over.
The main activity
and pop it in there with the necessary classes so that the set is updated.
When I know it is deleted.
All right so then the final thing we need to do is when we display the content of the list view we need
to check shared preferences and see if there's a set there and if there is then display the content
from it.
So let's get our shared preferences variable again here.
And then let's get our set say hash set of loops not string tokenize is just strings all the
and this is going to be shared preferences don't get string set.
And the strings that we're after is notes.
And if that fails I'm just going to bring out a no strings that.
And I think we actually need to cast this to a hash that's of strings to make that work.
So then we'll check to see if the set is no
then we'll do our full set up and just add the example note and if it's not we want to take notes array
list
and recreate it as a new array list at this time based on the set.
And that will then bring back all of the data from the set that's been saved and display it to the user.
So let's find the moment of truth and check to see that this works as intended with the permanent storage
now included.
OK.
So let's get through the whole process.
We'll add a note
I hope this works
go back and there it is and we'll even delete an item as well and then tap on the square button to get
multitasking and then tap the X to close the notes up down.
Then the second button to get back to the home page click the all apps button and then we open notes.
Keep your fingers crossed and then rejoice because our saved note is right there.
Wonderful.
So I hope you manage to make most of that one yourself.
And more importantly that you enjoyed the process in the second half of this section.
We're now going to go on and see a more complex but far more powerful way offering data that avoids
all of the complications that we've had to go to with sets get preferences.
And that is using databases and that see how today in the next video.