Now they going to look in more detail at our first widget the text view.
So we can see it right there both in the componentry and in the app preview.
That is the text view that we're given by default in this absolute zoom in and see it in a bit more
detail.
So hello world is a standard starting point for all new apps and new app developers.
But let's customize that a little bit so we can start by just double clicking on it and you can see
we're then given the option to change the text and change the ID if we want to.
So just to try it out.
I'll change the text too.
Hello Rob and the ID.
We don't actually need at this point but we will need it later on to be able to refer to this text view
in our code and maybe change it or make it appear or disappear or bigger or smaller or whatever we want
to do to it.
So
I'll call it Hello Rob text for you for now and then you can see that update straight away.
And let's just have a quick run of the app will choose our emulator that I've created a couple of years
ago just to make sure that the change that we've made here is reflected in the app itself.
And there we go that has updated.
I've also got a message that instant run has been applied to the current activity instant run is a new
feature in Android Studio 2 which makes changes to your app much much quicker.
So if for example I wanted to change this to Halo.
Dave you can then see that the play symbol has got a little lightning next to it.
And if I then click that and go back to the emulator then it's not exactly instant but it's pretty quick.
And what happens is just that activity is updated and restarted which means that when you're testing
around playing with an app you don't have to relaunch the whole app waiting 30 seconds or so for the
app to update.
So it's really great for experimenting and tinkering.
Although if you make major changes to your app it will in many cases have to do the full relaunch.
But for now this will definitely save us a lot of time as we're experimenting with text views.
So for now I'm going to hide the log area at the bottom because we don't really need it.
And let's zoom out a little bit.
All right.
So let's just first see how we can add a new text view if we want to.
So we just drag it in from the left hand side and then you can see as we drag it around we're given
various options.
You may remember I mentioned a relative lay out a couple of years ago and this is what we're working
with.
So we're dragging it in to our relatively out.
So for example if I laid it there that would be aligned to the parent which is the dotted orange box
around the edge there on the left and it will be
aligned below the Hello Dave label.
So if I now drag Hello Dave down then the new text is dragged down with it.
I'm going to use commands had to undo that.
Take it back to where we were before and the commands that again to get rid of in a text view.
And let's just drag it in again and just see what the options are I'm just spend a bit of time messing
around with this so we can align it to the top right for example.
So that is the top and right of the parent I in this case the relative lay out the container.
I drag it down a bit then that's aligned to the top of the hello Rob text view.
Or it could be a line to the bottom of the Hallard subtext V.
Or I can center it in the middle I can center it vertically as well.
Etc. etc..
So this is now centered in the middle of the activity.
And if I switch for example to a Nexus 10 tablet view then it's still centered.
In the middle of the screen.
So actually that makes making apps for different screen size is pretty straightforward because you know
if it's centered in this way it's going to be centered on every device.
So that's very simply how we can change the layout of our app when we're dragging in new widgets.
We'll see that a much more detail later on as we build more complex layouts.
For now they get rid of that textfield and go back to how.
Hello Dave as it is now and when you want to customize a widget its This properties area.
They are going to be spending most of your time.
So I'm not going to go into these in massive detail as you can see there's lots of them but I'll just
pick out the most important ones for now.
So with first of all this is the width of the whole of the text view.
So at the moment wrap content is just the width of the content.
But I could change it to for example Phil the parent and that would then fill the relative layout which
is the parent for this text view.
Same with the height I can use fill parent or match parent.
In this case that the same thing because there are no other elements in the relative layout which is
the parent for our text view.
So now got a very big text view as you can see that's the same but I'll get back to rap content which
is usually what you're going to want for a text view.
We can add in margins if we want.
So for example I could add a margin of 10 DP and you can see that's now moved it to the right and down.
It's worth getting clear.
What I dp is a DP issue for density independent pixel and the DP is essentially one one sixteenth of
an inch.
So 160 DP is of roughly one inch on any Android device.
So when you are designing your layouts DP is almost always the best option to use if for some reason
you need to be extremely precise.
You can use p x for pixels but that's generally quite a bad idea because it won't scale well on different
devices.
So UDP for almost all measurements except for the exception that we'll see in a moment.
Now with margins of course we could set the mood to 10 DP or we could for some reason set the left margin
to 30 and the top margin to 60.
You can see that you get that effect there.
And again let's just remind ourselves that we can use the lightning refresh to see that in action and
there we get that's happened.
Nice and quickly.
OK so looking back on the text view here you can change the alignment of the text.
That's a reasonably straight forward so I'm not going to look at that in much detail now but it's worth
looking at the style here.
So we can pick a particular style or we can click on the menu to the three dots then to pick one of
the many many styles that comes with the theme that we're working with.
So you can see there's loads of different styles there and that will just bring in a bunch of different
sizes colors.
In some cases margins and layouts as well.
So again feel free to experiment with that.
For example if I just go for a large then that will set a bunch of those styles for me.
And there's a big advantage to doing that because that means that specific devices can set appropriate
settings for those styles.
You're letting the device choose how your app displays which is often a good idea because it means your
app will display well on that device but sometimes you might want to be very specific about how your
app is styled and then you might want to specify it yourself.
Moving down we've got the alpha.
Now this is a very useful way of making your user interface elements transparent.
So if for example I put point five in as the Alphie you can see that that fades slightly.
And what is essentially doing is becoming transparent.
So if there was an image behind that I would start to see the image through the text we're using alpha
in many places in the course but we'll just leave it as the default for now.
Jumping now to background.
So again looking at the options in the three dots that's how I'd recommend using a background.
I can now choose from a whole range of colors.
I'll go for a sort of yellowy Mudie's sort of background.
And there we go.
You can see you've got a nice yellow background and it might be clearer now if I do an Alpha no point
five possibly that's now slightly yellow.
So that's how we set the background color.
There's some more options for the background if we want to then.
I'm going to jump through these ones.
Funt is obviously pretty useful.
It's nice to be able to choose a particular font got loads of fun.
Then
I'll just choose one at random.
It's pretty much like what I had before.
And gravity is essentially alignment within the elements.
So if for example I changed the with to a full width of a van the margin of course I can then change
my gravity to align to the right.
And as you can see there's various other options for gravity as well with centering filling et cetera
et cetera.
So gravity is how you align your element content within the element itself.
I can change the height.
We've got the ID as we saw before the various options for input which we don't really need here.
Let us speccing if there are links within it we can choose whether to make this clickable or not.
We've got maximum minimum heights.
We've got some padding which is much like a margin but
it's within the element itself.
So if you've got a background it's useful to have a little bit of padding that doesn't go all the way
to the edge of the element.
Various other options we can change the text from there if we want to change the text color.
So once again we click on the three dots we can change that too.
Ok so I read a bit of text and we can change the text size.
And this is the one exception that I mentioned earlier to DP.
And I'd recommend using espies for text.
So if we change this to something like 20 Espey then turns out to be a little bit smaller than the people
that we have them.
Now when espie is short for scale independent pixel and essentially is the same as DP but it's also
affected by the user setting for the text zoom level.
So if for example a user wants to have all of their text a little bit bigger they can set that in the
Android default settings and the espie will then be affected by that.
So again it will need your design to be a little bit more fluid but it will be more usable by the user
if they need larger text because they're visually impaired then that will be reflected in your text
if you use espies.
So essentially the short hand is to use DP for everything except text and then use espies for text only.
Then we've got some more options for style theme and with the bottom there as well.
So that's a bit of a whistle stop tour and I would thoroughly recommend playing with these in a little
bit more detail and just working out how they all fit together.
For now I'm going to give you a quick challenge and that is to recreate this text for you here.
So it's centered.
It's got a nice bit of padding.
It's pretty big.
The text itself is just off black and the background is green.
So nothing too tricky that you should be able to recreate that using what we've just learned.
So I'll give you a moment to pause the video and make the text for you go for it.
OK.
I hope that went well.
So I'm going to start by dragging in my text.
And we wanted it sent it.
So I'm going to go for sintered at the top and I'll start by double clicking to change the text.
To my great app fabulous.
And then let's start by changing the text size.
So if something
nice and big 50 espie that looks great and I'll change the text color as well
I'll go for that arc pretty much black color grates and then we won't see add in a bit of a background
say
that's choose the green that I suggested.
There we go.
Lovely green background.
And finally a bit of padding.
So scroll down to padding and of course the piece for padding.
There we go.
So very quick exercise doesn't look beautiful obviously but it gives us an opportunity to just practice
the various customizations that we've just learned.
Excellent.
So that sparely thought or introductions to text vees in the next video we're going to go on and look
at Buttons and this is where we'll actually start writing some code as well and start making our apps
interactive.