Now for a bit of fun we're going to use the animation skills that we learned in the last couple of videos
along with a lot of the Java techniques we learned in the previous section to build an app that I'm
going to call Kinect 3 level logic if the app is going to be exactly the same as tic tac toe or naughts
and crosses which if you're not familiar with it is a very simple game where you fill in a three by
three great with noughts and crosses with a friend.
And the first person to get three in a row either noughts or crosses is the winner.
I'm going to shake it up slightly though and we're going to use counters from the game connect 4.
And we're also going to use a dropdown animation to bring the counters into the game just to make it
a little bit more interesting.
So I've put together some graphics here.
We've got our yellow Kountze a red counter and a simple board that I've put together.
There you go.
And you can download those from the project in the next lecture if you like or you can of course download
or find or make your own to make it a little bit more unique.
So I definitely recommend giving this a try on your own.
But it is a much bigger app than anything that we've made so far.
It will be a big challenge.
So don't feel bad at all if you end up watching the video you'll learn a lot of techniques doing so
as well.
So best of luck get as far as you can on your own and then feel free to watch me putting together K'NEX
3.
Good luck.
All right.
Hey we got them sir as usual create a new project called Kinect 3.
And get it set up.
So I'm going to start by importing my images and getting the screen set up and then we'll start working
out the logic of the app and how we can make that all fit together.
The last part will be actually working out whether someone has one that's the particular challenge here
we have to keep up with what the players have actually done.
And then each time someone goes we're going to test to see if someone's got three in a row.
So we'll find out exactly how to do all of that as we go along.
Let's get rid of our text.
And John privity
our images and we get into trouble and just place those in.
So I'm actually going to start by adding a great layout.
This is something we haven't used yet but you can anticipate it might be useful for a three by three
grid which essentially this game is.
So our grid layout allows us to choose a certain number of horizontal and vertical rows and columns
to put our objects in.
Which is perfect for us it's just what we want.
So I'm going to set the column count on the grid layout to 3 and the count to three as well.
And then I'm going to select the background and I want the background to be the board image that we
just added.
So I would say that looks good.
Having said that I don't want the height to be stretched out so I'm going to manually set the height
to somewhere around 360.
So now I'm going to grab an image V.
This is going to be for my first counter and you can see even though we've set the grid layout to three
by three we've still got loads more rows and columns that we need don't worry about that we'll sort
that out in a minute so you can draft that wherever you like.
And then we'll just set the SIRC to a red counter that we added a moment ago.
It gets a little bit too large at the moment.
So I'm just going to make that a little bit smaller scale for about 90
tepees that we get.
And at the same time I'll go into the text field and then it's just a little bit easier to view it here.
I'm going to change the row and the column of my image to be 0 and 0.
Which means it's going to be in the top left of our table and then I'll manually set that again to three
by three.
So we should now find that this is the top left.
And now this is roughly right in terms of its size and positioning.
So I'm going to use command C to copy that and then command V and I'm going to pasted in or I want it
so 0 column 1.
If you get that wrong you can always paste it again in the SML and then Rozier column 2.
I can't find that so I'm just going to pop it in there and then change it.
So in fact I think I'll do that for all of these.
So one
I'm just pasting in each time here.
And now it's a little bit easier to find the one that I want.
Except I can't find very two.
Not a problem.
Now I can
and in fact I should be able to just drag these around roughly.
So the only problem is how griller is currently four by four.
I could change that down in the example but just to keep variety in we'll change it to three by three.
That we get.
So now we've got three by three great filled with counters.
Obviously the counters aren't quite in the right position so I'm just going to manually position all
of those using margin's So that first one I think it could probably do with 10 deep on the left.
Probably the same on the top and in fact
probably 10 deep all around will position it quite nicely.
And let's see what we need for the next one along.
So if we can't get away with just putting 10 deep ways all around probably not quite on this one we
definitely need 10 pages on the top but I think we need a bit more on the left.
Let's try 20.
It looks pretty good.
Are we up to see easier when we move this one along.
So again we're definitely 110 space on the top and on the left.
Let's try that to you this time
OK.
That looks pretty good.
I think I want this one to move slightly to the right.
So let's try 25 teepees and then this one can come back slightly.
Let's try twenty there.
OK.
Great ones go in a little bit too far back.
So let's put 25 phatty.
OK so I like load them on to be quite perfect but I don't really mind in terms of the left margins they're
going to be the same for all of these so ten twenty five and 10 should do the trick so I'm just going
to put those in really quickly.
And then we'll deal with the heights in a minute.
OK.
And down here as well
10 25
and 25
OK.
Now we just need to adjust the top margins.
So these are going to be the same for each one in each row at least.
So let's try 20.
See how that looks.
Yeah I think maybe slightly more
I think that looks pretty good.
So you have 24
and then 24 in this disarray to play and then it's probably going to be quite similar this time slightly
more.
I think
maybe even that a great
lovely OK you can obviously play around with those a little bit more if you like just to make them perfectly
centered.
But that will do for now.
Now what we're dealing with the design I'm going to patients in place so what we want.
Obviously we don't want these to actually appear at the beginning but when the use of taps on one of
these we wanted to change the appropriate color and then drop in from the top.
So how are we going to achieve that.
Well let's write our code with this central one here in mind.
So let's change the on click
and or call the method drop in.
So this is going to be our drop in method.
And as I say we don't want this to have an image to start with so we'll just remove
the source.
So it's still there is still got the width and height but I can't see anything which is how we want
it.
So now if we jump over to our Java file and then we'll create our drop in method.
So as usual public Foyt drop in it's going to be called by a view
chicken or keyhole view and let's import Android.
If you don't view that we get.
Now this time we are actually interested in which one the user tapped on because that's the one that
we want to bring in.
So what I'm going to do is get my image view
and I'm going to call it counter because that's what it is.
And this time it's just going to be equal to view because view is the thing that was tapped on.
But of course view is a view and we want an image view.
So we need to convert that just in the same way.
So this is exactly the same code that we used when we got an element by its ID.
But this time we don't need to search for it because it's just the one that was tapped on which is the
one that calls the drop in function.
So we can just use fee.
And then if I want to drop that in I need to do three things I need to move it off the screen so to
the top of the screen then I need to apply either red or yellow to it as an image.
And then I need to bring it back down again.
So let's take it to the top of the screen first of all so counter and remember how to do this translates
as it is set.
Translation why.
And when we get a thousand pixels off the top of the screen.
So minus 1000 f then we set the image.
Now I'm not certain we've done this before.
So let's have a quick Google Android set image.
There you go.
How does that image in image view in Android.
It sounds pretty perfect.
That's what we want.
There we go.
So set image results perfect.
So let's apply that counter set M.H. results and we want results is it was drawable.
And then let's go for yellow just to keep it a little bit different.
And then we want to animate it back in again.
So I counter it animates and we want translation y by and then one thousand as a flight and then duration
and let's keep it pretty pretty short.
We want this to be a snappy app.
It's about 300 milliseconds.
We can always change that if it doesn't fit right.
OK so when the use user taps on a space as far as they're concerned an empty image then this will get
the image that they've tapped on.
It will move it a thousand pixels up off the top of the screen then it will set the yellow top hangi
image to the image view.
And finally it will animate it back down so you should get this dropdown animation to it which is good.
Gives it that different sort of flavor to noughts and crosses it feels more like where we're playing
connect four or something like that.
That's just a little bit.
It'll be interesting and gives us a chance to use our animations as well.
So let's take a look at the moment of course this is only going to work on the middle one.
So we've got a gap in the middle.
We tap on it and there it is wonderful.
I like that.
Feel free you could do some rotations.
In fact a little bit of rotation sounds very easy to do and a little bit of fun as well.
So let's go for
10 spins.
So then we'll get a nice kind of spin rotation animation as well which is always a bit of fun.
The more sort of flashy You can make your apps probably the more fun they're going to be to play.
It's just have a quick look about
it.
So let's just quickly reduce that to a single spin.
I think it might just be that 10 spins and 300 milliseconds was just too fast.
If this isn't noticeable we'll get rid of the rotation and not worry about it.
I think that did a little bit to the to the whole thing.
I'm going to leave it there.
You of course can play with it you can change the size do whatever you like but we've got our basically
functioning droppin method now.
So unfortunately I'll have to manually apparat to each of these but it'll probably be a bit quicker
and give us an opportunity to remind ourselves about the text view if we do it there.
So if we look for the middle one
will be the one with the drop in function to use Command F to find it.
So drop in there we go.
So that's the only code that we need.
So if we just add that to the rest
to all the image views within a grid layout
while we're here we also want to remove this.
So let's do that at the same time.
So I'm removing
a Sassy's are the source of the red image so they're all going to be empty initially and then I'm adding
in the drop in method.
So you could argue it would have been more efficient to do this at the beginning but development doesn't
always work in the most efficient way.
Sometimes you have to do a bit of manual work like this
every day and be done
correct.
So now just check that we should find that initial board is blank and then we can tap on all nine of
these different squares and we'll get a yellow counter every time which isn't perfect obviously but
it's a step in the right direction.
Notice we've got our three by three grid displaying there as well which is nice.
So just to make sure that works fabulous
correct.
I'm really liking the animation effect.
I think it does add a fair bit to the game.
So now it's time to look at the logic of the game.
So say we're going to allow yellow's to go first then we need to have some system to know whose go it
is going to be yellow's first then reds and yellows and reds et cetera.
So let's set up something that can store that.
So I'm going to create a variable up here.
Which will be a simple integer and I'm going to call it active player like that.
And initially the active play is going to be 0 and I'm going to put a little note because it's not necessarily
obvious that 0 or what's yellow and one is red OK.
So now we can change our drop in method to see whose go it is.
And if it's zero we'll change it to go number one and we'll have a yellow.
And if it's a 1 we'll change it to 0 and we'll drop in a red.
So let's do that here.
So if active player Waziri
then
we want to drop in yellow.
And don't forget parentheses
and we want to set active player to 1.
So that means you'll be ready to go next.
If that's not the case we want to do the opposite.
So we're going to drop in a red counter and we're going to set then the active player back to zero again.
Right so that's simple.
Bit of code should mean that we get a yellow player or yellow counter and then a red and then a yellow
and then a red which will actually mean that the game will be broadly playable.
Obviously we're missing some fairly fairly critical features and we've got some
strange behavior if we tested the app of the moment but we can have a yellow and then red and then the
yellow and red etc..
So the app now does work as a connect three game.
Our main issues are when we get three in a way that doesn't realize.
So that's one major problem we need to allow the app to tell the user when they've won.
Otherwise it's going to be a bit unsatisfying.
And also if the user taps on a square which is already there they can replace it.
So that actually isn't a crazy game dynamic.
If you want to keep that there.
And I think that could be quite an interesting way to play tic tac toe with replacements but we'll have
a system for stopping the user for doing that.
And that's going to involve having some kind of memory for managing the game state.
So at the moment the phone has no idea which counters are where.
So we need a way for storing that and I'm going to do that with a simple array of integers.
And what I'm going to do.
Because yellow is zero and bread is one I'm going to initially set this to one two three four five six
seven eight nine to use like that should be curly brackets sorry.
And we could do with a name there as well.
So I call it game state.
And then we'll have another note because it's definitely not obvious to means unplaced.
So to means there's nothing in that slot.
And then we've got zero to nine.
So that's item 0.
Item one item 2 etc..
And that's going to represent all of these squares starting at 0 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 cetra.
OK so now we're going to need a way of knowing which counter has been tapped and then we can update
the game state to represent that.
So let's go back over to our main activity SML file.
What are we going to use to tell which one has been tapped is what's known as a tag.
So if we go back to our first image in the grid layout we can add on the SML Android tag.
And I'm going to give each of these a tag and that will represent that position.
And then I can get the tag in the code and that will tell me what the position of the user counter that's
just been tapped is.
So that's going to be one
to
three.
Six and seven interesting.
The last one must be 8.
I must have missed one out at 0 1 2 3 for every game.
I have six seven and eight.
So there's all nine with that tags.
And then we can get the tag quite easily.
Using counter don't get tagged.
Simple as that.
So for now just to show you how it works I'm going to convert it to a string and pop it in the console.
So let's run that.
And we should find then that the tag will display in the console so it will get 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 or 8
depending on which has been tapped.
And then we can use this to update our game state
and indeed to check whether that one has been tapped already and if so not allow any further tapping
every.
So that was number three which is correct.
0 1 2 3 and then 5 et cetera.
Fantastic.
So let's
get our tag and convert it to an integer which we're going to need to use it within our game state.
All right.
So let's create an integer I'll call it tapped counter and that's going to be counter dog get tag
and then convert it to a string.
Are we all going to want to get that to an integer.
So we use integer to pass.
And as we've seen before
there we go.
So now we've got a tapped count a variable which is 0 to 8 depending on which one has been tapped and
then
the first thing that we want to do with that is check to see whether that one has been already tapped
on and we can check that by checking for the game state and whether or not it's equal to 2.
So if game state tapped counter so if that is equal to 2
parentheses we're up
then we want to do all of that stuff plus something else.
We also want to set the game state of that number to either 0 or 1 depending on who's playing.
So again we get game state tapped counter and we're going to set that equal to what is it.
It's active player because active player does tell us who is currently playing.
So that's it.
We don't need an elf statement there because we only want to do this if a game state is too.
If the game is there is zero or one that means the point on the board has already been tapped.
So we don't want to do anything at all.
So no need for an hour statement.
That time round.
So here we go.
There's our yellow red yellow and if we tap on an existing one then nothing happens other than printing
to the console.
Wonderful.
OK so we're almost there.
We've just got to add this last bit of game logic which is working out whether or not the game has finished.
As with a lot of programming problems there's many different ways you could do that.
I'm going to use the fact that a very finite number of winning positions in tic tac toe.
So we've got three horizontal lines that could be one three vertical lines and then two diagonals.
So that's only eight different combinations so that's quite a manageable number to keep in the user's
memory.
So I'm going to create
a variable and it's going to be an array of arrays.
So we haven't seen this before but think of it as really a set of arrays inside an array.
That's become clear as we go on.
So I call it winning positions.
And then this is going to be just a way of storing all the winning positions.
So the first winning position I'll consider the horizontal ones versus the first winning position is
going to be 0 1 and 2 so 0 1 2 like that I'm in the second set of winning positions is going to be three
four and 5
like that.
And I do apologize.
Any brackets all the way
and the third winning position is three four five six seven eight.
Now let's see the verticals.
So this is 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 0 3 6 is the first vertical winning position
and then if we add one to each of those we'll get the next vertical winning position so 1 4 7 and then
one to each of those will give us 2 5 8.
So that's all they give us.
So let's do this diagonal.
So 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 0 4 8 is a winning position.
And finally it's 1 2 3 4 5 6 2 4 6 is our last winning position.
There we go.
So each time someone goes with them want to do a check to see if they've won.
So let's do that at the end of our code.
Not that it really matters but logically I'd like to get the counter in first and then do a check to
see if anyone's won.
And what I'm going to do is loop through the winning positions and just check to see if any of them
in the game state have the same value.
So if 0 1 and see if they are all ones for example that tells us that reds have one if they're all zeros.
That tells us that yellow has one.
So as you may remember we can use the for command to loop through an array and the array that we're
looping through is winning positions.
Each one of those I'm going to call winning position and then we use a colon to separate those two.
And then we want to clarify the winning position itself is going to be an array of integers.
There we go.
So we're using the full command to loop three winning positions and each array within winning position
within winning positions is going to be called winning position and then that's going to be an integer
array.
OK.
Have you with me so far.
Now we want to check whether that all the same.
That is each of the winning position values in game state.
So we want to check for game state
winning position 0.
And we want to see if that's going to be the same as game state.
Winning position 1.
So that's the second item in the winning position.
Many aere And
as I think we've seen before we use the double ampersand to represent n.
And so we want to also check that game state winning position one is equal to a game state.
Winning position too.
So that basically means that all three are the same and I'm going to put those on different lines so
we can see them more easily.
We need to do a final check as well to make sure that what is the final check and a check for.
We're going to check that game state could be any of them this time.
So let's just pick zero is not too because if it's two then that means no one's going there.
So that doesn't count as a win.
And I think I've missed out a square bracket there and possibly that the I don't need one that would
get easy to mix these things up and I've even got too many of them.
So if that's the case then someone has won.
So let's just for the moment print out the locks to the card so you can copy that down because we don't
want that one anymore anyway.
So let's have a states winning position zero.
Say that should print out either a 0 or 1 depending on who has one.
So this is just a check our logic and make sure that everything's working as we hope it would.
And then we can display something for the user.
To let them know who has won.
So let's take a look see if our logic holds true.
So let's go yellow and yellow and yellow.
Fantastic.
Every guy has one.
So we could just have a little toast popping up here showing something to the user saying that someone
has one.
But I think we could have something a little bit more grand.
And we're also going to want a button to allow the user to play again because our game is going to be
so massively addictive that we want to play again immediately after.
So what we'll do is we'll bring in a vertical linear layout and we want it centered but not actually
in the grid layout we wanted in the relative lay out
and we want to have two things in that I want to have just a plain text field which is going to be centered
at the top which is going to be the message saying someone has one say I'm just going to make that a
little bit bigger.
Even bigger than that I think greats.
And then we want to button to allow them to say play again.
And because this is a vertical linear layout that's going to be vertically below the other button.
Great.
There's not going to be any other option.
The only thing they can do in this app is play again.
So I think we need a question mark or anything like that.
And I'll give it an ID of play again button.
But really the main thing that's going to make the app work is adding the on click to play again.
So I actually want this to appear in the middle of the screen not at the top.
So I'm going to give it a fixed than height depending on the content.
There we go.
And I'm also going to give it a background color so it stands out from the rest
of the app.
Every day so just go for a nice yellow.
So it looks slightly horrendous but it'll will get the job done.
And then I'm going to add a bit of padding all the way around.
Yeah.
Lovely.
So it doesn't look beautiful but it's fine.
And then if we want to align that centrally we could have a look at the linear layout.
So this is what we've got for the layout so far.
If you remember the grid layout was centered horizontally and vertically so we can just take the SML
for that and copy it down.
So I'm just going to pop it in there and then have a look at that.
It's now centered horizontally and vertically in the screen.
So I'd like you to start getting into the habit of using both allow you when it's easier but also the
text view when that's easier as well.
Now of course we don't want this to appear
until we're ready for it.
So I'm going to initially set the Alpha to zero like that.
And then we're going to need to be able to make it appear so we're going to need an ID for it.
So I will call this play again lay out
and we need an ID for the text as well because we're going to want to update that so I'll call it when
a message OK.
So the main thing we need to do is make play again lay out display when someone has one.
So we're going to do that down here because this is where
someone has one.
So making a lay out a is not something that we've ever done before.
So let's have a quick google to see if we can find out how to do it.
So something like Android make lay out of here.
I should do the trick.
So I got a few general bits of code that make a layout appear with animation of the button click.
Sounds perfect
OK.
So this looks very promising.
So we've got some code here so we use fine view by ID.
Wonderful.
And then we're going to change the visibility.
OK.
Perfect.
So that's exactly what we want.
Let's jump back over and put that in.
I think that means that instead of using an Alpha will use visibility.
If we're using that code so it will initially set it to invisible which is pretty much the same as an
alpha of 0.
But it will allow us to use the code that we've just found.
So again don't be afraid to change your program slightly.
If you've found some code that allows to do it allows you to do it in a certain way so we could create
creating a lay out them we need
Android widgets linear layouts.
Let's put that in
every guy.
And
I lay out ID was play again lay out and let's put that in there it is.
So now we've got a lay out.
So let's jump back over to our code to make it a feat appear.
Say we're not going to bother with any animation here if you want to of course you are very welcome
to me.
But I think this is the code that we want.
So lay out set visibility and then view visible sir as we've just got back home from the internet.
I think we were just checking making sure it all works.
And then all that remains is to update the label to show who has one and to make the play again button
work.
Let's take a look.
So will the Reds win this time.
Fantastic.
So a new leader has indeed appeared to be quite nice if Wisden from the left or rotated or something
like that.
I'll leave that up to you.
But of course I'll play again button.
In fact crash is the app which is a bit worse than doing nothing.
But that's fine.
We haven't written the code for that yet.
So Thursley let's just update the Win a message so that it shows the correct winner.
So it's called Win a message we want to do that before the layout appears really.
So this is
a text if you
call it with a message.
And we're going to want to turn it into a text field.
But we'll get it from fine by id and then resources to ID when a message
that we get and then we just want to set the text of that
to
and keep that nice and simple.
But we need to know who's won.
So let's put a gap in here.
And then we're going to need to do a check down here to see whether this is a zero or one so let's get
rid of Lokes that we don't need any more.
So if game state winning position 0 is equal to zero that means yellow has 1.
So let's create a string called winner which is let's say by default is equal to red and then if game
state when you position 0 is equal to zero or all.
Winner to
and that's just a way of avoiding having the else code in there which is a bit unnecessary here.
And then we can use it that so that will display the correct way not with any luck.
Definitely worth checking that.
And then all that we have to do is to write out our reset the board code
makes sense to put our comment a little bit higher up there.
OK let's take a look.
Say hello.
Hello.
Hello has one.
Fantastic.
I don't want to make the app crash so I'm not going to click the play again button.
But now is the time to make that work.
So if we just remind ourselves the play again button
is they play again method.
So let's write that down here.
Public first and all of it and then play again.
So there's a few things we need to do here.
We need to make the message that we've just made appear disappear so we can do that.
Using this code I'm just going to copy that down.
And of course instead of visible we want invisible so that will make that disappear.
We want to set the game state and player back to the defaults.
So let's grab
these and copy them down.
Obviously we don't want to create the variable we just want to update it.
Now unfortunately as much as this may seem an obvious thing to do it's not possible because we're essentially
setting the game state array to another array which we can't do.
So we have to update each item within the array separately so we can do that with a flip which is good
practice.
So let's create a for loop.
So we'll set count a variable I initially equal to zero.
We want to keep going as long as it is less than nine or we could put state DOT length which might be
nice.
I really like Hardik hard coding that 9 in there just in case the game's date length changes at some
point.
And we want to
add one to each time and then all we want to say is that game state I equal to 2 and that will then
reset game state.
So the initial state.
So the last thing we need to do is to loop through all of the images and reset them to have no source.
So they're essentially invisible.
I'm going to show you quite a fancy way of doing that.
We want essentially all of the images inside this grid lock out.
So if I give the grid layout and ID
I'll just call it create lay out and then
if we create a variable to match that layout out.
So I would just like this line above.
We're going to use grid layout and then I'll call it great layout and that's going to be a great layout.
And we're going to get it by finding it by its ID so our ID to create lay out and then we can loop through
all of the items in there which I know are images so that all image views anything inside that.
So again we can use for and we're going to start again with an high counter variable which is initially
zero.
And then we want to keep going as long as I is less than the number of items.
Now we know that that's 8.
But if it changes at some point we can get that from grid layout don't get child count.
So that's quite handy.
That tells us how many views there are inside grid layout and we know that that's nine.
But if it changes then we won't have to update our code.
And then I plus plus and then we want to get each of those image views.
So we're going to cast them as views and to get them we use grid layout don't get child at.
And then the index is just high
so that just gets the youth child which is the imagery in this case and I want to take the whole thing
up a practice round it to bring it together.
And we want to set the image resource I guess it's as if it knew.
And interestingly here we can actually put in a zero set that to an empty image.
So that's exactly what we want.
I will reset it back to nothing.
And just before we run that I noticed that I've forgotten the
put the view in there that will give us a crash if we try and run that because it will be sending the
button to the play again method.
And if the plug and method isn't ready to accept it even if it doesn't use it it will still crash.
So they should now do everything we want.
It will get rid of the message saying that yellow or whoever has one set the active player back to yellow
reset game state and then set all of the images within the grid layout back to 0 or back to empty essentially
let's have a look.
So there's out yellow play again and testicular can get
beryllium.
Everything seems to be working fabulously.
There's one issue remaining I don't know if you've noticed it but once this has happened we can still
carry on playing which isn't great.
So we really want the action to stop until they start playing again.
So I think as always there's many of ways that we could do that.
The way I'm going to do it is have a variable that keeps track of whether the game is active or not.
So we could have a Boullion this time for a bit of a variety
game is active and generally that will be equal to a tree but we'll set it equal to folks when somebody
wins.
So the game is active.
Well then set to false and we'll set it to true again when they use a taps to play again.
And then we just need to check so we can do it at the same place that we check for the games state being
to we can check that
game is active is true as well.
Remember we don't need is equal to true we can just put and the game is active.
Right.
So hopefully for the final time let's run this and check and make sure that it all behaves as we would
want a.
So the only thing we really need to check is that you can't carry on playing the game.
Once somebody has one
every guys say well let Reds win for a change
that it one.
Fantastic.
And if I try and carry on it doesn't work.
But if I kick again and everything resets and I can start my great fun game again.
Now there is one more thing I really would like to change just before I let you go.
And that is that at the moment if we have a rule the game just stops
to make sure I can get a job.
Go and you can't do anything.
So I think we need one more check
to check to see if it's a journal and if so display the message and invite them to play again.
So we'll put this Kate down here
because we don't want it to run.
If someone wins on their final go here.
So if no one has won we want to check to see if we've had nine goals.
Now we don't have a go counter and I don't think we need to go counter because all we need to do is
loop through the game state array and check to see if everything is not true and if that's the case
then we finished the game.
So let's do that again to loop through an array we use for and this is an array of integers.
Say it and then
I'll call it counter state
and that's each position within game States.
And we want to check to see if counter state is equal to two because if one of them is equal to two
then the game is not over yet.
So the way I think I'm going to keep track of that is to have a temporary Boullion which is game is
over and we will initially set it to tree and then we'll just run through all of the items in game state
and if any of them ought to and we'll set game is either to be false
and then we want to check to see if game is over.
So if
game is over then we want to do many of the things that we did before here.
Say that should suffice with that line.
I don't really like repeating this code but we're almost at the end I don't think we need to worry about
making another method for it et cetera.
At this point
and we'll just change the message to it's a troll.
All right.
So now absolutely for the final time I'm not going to decide that I want to inflict anything else on
you but hopefully if you have followed through most of this video then you've hopefully learned a lot
quite a few new things that we've seen or at least new ways of using things that we've already become
familiar with.
And hopefully you've seen what level of complexity you can get with the relatively little Android knowledge
we have at the moment we can still do quite advanced things and quite big projects.
So let's have a look.
Hello.
I read you and I read you I read it.
It's fantastic.
And then play again and we can play again.
Brilliant.
OK well that was by far the biggest that we've built so far.
So thank you for staying with me.
We're now going to move on from images and animations to the related but in many ways more exciting
topic of video.