Now that we're all set up with firebase we're going to add the Google AdMob modules and set ourselves
up to show that within our app while it is possible to use AdMob without firebase they are now strongly
integrated and with firebase you get a lot of analytics which will tell you how well your ads are doing
and how you might make them more effective.
So to find out how to add them I would just do a quick Google search for something like AdMob Android
firebase and that should get you an introduction.
So I'd go for the QuickStart link that make sure the link they are going into is five based on Google
dot com rather than firebase dot com itself.
Otherwise you'll probably be looking at old documentation sort of scrolling down here.
See we need to start by integrating firebase and the mobile apps software development kits.
So we've already integrated firebase.
So now let's add in the x component.
So I'm just going to copy that over
and paste it in to help build the graded file
that we get and next for quite a few of the changes that we need to make.
But but just before we do will rethink
our cradle files that will bring in the firebase module.
Well that's going that's open.
Our main activity Java file and we'll get rid of the database code that we're no longer going to be
using and we'll add the next steps.
So first off we need to add the banner ID.
Now this one here is just a demo banner ID.
If you want to create your own banner ad ID you'll need an AdMob account.
And you can get one of those at apps dot AdMob dot com but it is a reasonably lengthy sign up process.
So I'm not going to guide you through the whole process here.
It's really straightforward because that's say quite lengthy.
You need to put in bank details and company details et cetera.
So go through that when you're ready to add a real ad.
But for now we'll just put in the test one and we'll do that down and strings direct Semmel where we
can store various important strings for our app.
So I'm going to paste that in there.
And this is going to be a banner ad unit ID and we can access that from anywhere within the app.
So getting back to our Atmore Quickstart Guide
we now need to place an ad in our activity out and also allow layout to access the ads schema so we
do that in lay out activity main as usual.
And then we'll add in the schema to the relative lay out we say and then we'll head back
and copy the options for our advantage.
Get rid of the text you them and replace it with the ADD V
so you can see it imported the unit ID there from the banner ad unit ID string variable.
And we've got some various lú guides there of course if you want to change the size or position of the
add.
Then you just change those in the usual way.
All right.
So we're nearly there.
We now need to initialize mobile ads within our app.
I'm going to copy that Kate into the main activity Java
and then old Enza will bring in the mobile apps module for us.
Okay.
And then
we need to set up our ad
using this card here.
So just pasting them as you can see we're creating an ad view called an ad view which we find it by
its ID.
So the ideas add value.
Obviously you can change that if you want.
That was created here when we pasted the code for the app view in
then we create an ad request which gets sent out for us and then we load the request in the AM and view
the ad view itself.
All right.
And that should do it.
So now let's just run it on the simulator.
And we should see our ad displayed at the bottom of the screen and there we go.
You can see they test displaying at the bottom of the screen there.
So it's a symbol of that to display ads within your app.
We're now going to go on and look at a great way of increasing engagement and interactivity with your
app and that's with introducing notifications.