Pass server users are one of the best features of Passover.
They allow us to very simply sign up and log in users.
And then those users remain signed up and logged in as long as they're using the app so lets see how
to create a user and sign them up.
We create a user in the way that you might expect.
So we use passive user and I'll call that she's a user and this is going to be a new parse user
and then we just set the two required variables.
That is the username and password.
So you can see we can also have an e-mail as well if we want.
But for now I'll just have a username and password so I'll use Rob Percival as my username and I'll
set my password as the highly secure my pass and then to sign the user up which use user sign up in
background.
And always good to have a call back.
So this is going to be a new Sign-Up callback hopefully you get any idea now how these callbacks work.
So if he is no
then let's just log
sign up successful else log.
Sign up failed.
Simple as that.
Let's take a look and see if it works.
Well that's compiling.
There's one thing I'd like to show you over in the standard application you may have noticed we've got
an option here could pantsula enable automatic user.
And that's what creates these users here that are automatically created.
So in some apps you might not want to do that.
If you want to control the sign up and the log in yourself then you just comment out that line.
And I'll actually use that setting for this app because we don't need automatic users.
We're going to be logging in and signing up our users ourselves.
OK let's give it a look.
All right.
So sun up a successful looking promising.
So let's refresh our user list and you can see what it's done is taken the automatic use of that was
already created and added a username and password to it.
So signing uses up is as simple as that.
What if we want to log them in.
That's also pretty straightforward.
So let's just comment out how sign up code
so to log users in.
We just use Pownce user dot log in in the background.
And then we give the user name.
So Rob Percival the password and this time I'm going to deliberately get the password wrong.
Just to see what happens.
And then we'll have a new logon callback
and this time I'm going to check for the existence of the User variable.
So if user is not know then I'll log
Logan is successful but if it is no
then
we'll log in failed and then we'll use the string to see what's gone wrong.
OK.
So let's take a look.
We should find that we get an error related to our incorrect password here.
OK let's take a look.
And there we go.
You can see we've got luggin failed and then invalid username password.
Excellent.
So we're pretty much there with what we need to do.
Just a couple more things I'd like to show you.
The first is how we test to see if a user is logged in when the app opens up.
And that again is very easy.
If past user don't get current user.
So if that is not know
then that means the user is logged in.
So let's log
user logged in.
And we can even get a user name using Parsees or to get current user dot get user name that if that's
not the case we'll just log
current user use are not logged in.
Right so that's have a quick look.
We should of course be logged in from when we signed up earlier on as repairs.
So let's find out.
And there we go.
So user logged in Rob Percival.
Excellent.
And finally the last thing I'm going to show you is how to log out the user if the user chooses to lock
themselves out.
And we do that using past user don't log out.
Simple as that.
So now if we run that then we should get user not logged in.
And there we go.
So the user is now locked down.
So that's how easy it is to sign up log in and log out users using pass.
And if you are creating your own system to do this it will take a huge amount of time.
So part is doing a lot of the heavy lifting for us here.
We're now finally in a position to start building our Instagram app and we're going to start with the
log in and sign up part in the next video.