All right we're pretty close now.
So we can obviously see the user list and follow and unfollow individuals and we can also post tweets
using the tweet dialogue that we've created.
So our final challenge is to allow users to view their Twitter feed.
All of the posts of the people that they're following so will need a new activity to do that.
They will go for a good old empty activity and give it a better name this time.
So I'll call it feed.
And again this is going to have a fairly simple lay out.
We're just going to use a list of the
and this one are called feed list.
But this time we're actually going to use both the item and the sub item for the first time.
So we're going to have the item being the tweet and then the sub item being the person who did the tweeting.
So let's see how we do that.
It is something we haven't done before so we'll create
our list view and that's feed a list fee
and it's a list fee.
Finding it by its id our ID don't feed you.
And now the data for our list you can't just be a simple frailest this time because we're having two
pieces of information by the content of the tweet and the user name of the person who wrote it.
So for that we're going to use a list of maps and our map is going to map a string to another string.
And I'll call this tweet data and this will be a new list again of maps mapping strings to strings.
So we have seen maps before.
They're like dictionaries in other languages and essentially they allow you to link a particular word.
In this case or string to another string.
So to set this up let's create a simple loop that will create five tweets for us so that we can see
how it works before we connect it to our past server.
So we'll start with an.
I less them one will keep going as long as is less than or equal to 5 increment each time.
And then for each one we'll create a map string to string which will be our tweet info.
This will be a new Ashmit
again string to string
and then we just add our data so tweet info to put and then we'll have the content of the tweet will
be
tweet the content and then just to differentiate between them will include the I.
When you talk about that to a string.
Say it to Joe at 2 string
I and then similarly for the use of we'll put the user name and that will be user plus integer to string.
So that should give us five tweets and then we're going to combine them all into tweet data.
So tweet data dart add and then we're going to add tweet info.
There we go.
So tweet data now contains five maps which themselves contain some content and a username that we need
to attach them to our list view.
And this time we're not going to use an array adapter.
We're going to use a slightly more complicated but ironically named simple adapter which is fairly simple
but it's more complicated than an array adapter.
So let's call it simple adapter and we set it up in much the same way as before.
So a new simple adapter using this as the context.
And then we use our list as you can see there.
So that's going to be our tweaked data and then we get the lay out.
So we're used to using Android to lay out a simple list item one
but this time we're going to use simple list items too because it allows us to have two different bits
of text and then we're going to create an array
of strings which is going to contain the names of the objects.
So the content and user name
so that will tell our code where it can access the variables that we want.
And then finally we say where we want those two bits of information to go through the content and the
user name and we want them to go in the default place i.e. we want the first one to be where item 1
is that and then the second to be where sup.
Item 1 is.
So we create an array
of integers
and this is going to be two integers which are essentially the IDs of the locations where we want the
tweet content and the user name to go and the IDs of these different options.
I that there are Android ID text 1 and Android that are not ID text to
few.
So a rather epic line to set up our simple adapter but hopefully that will make sense.
Then all that remains is to take a list view and set the adapter to a simple adaptive.
All right.
So now we should have those two bits of information for each row of our table.
Of course we will need to actually get to that location of our app so I'm going to add it to the menu.
I'll play the log out button
so it will have an ID
of
the feed and a title of your feet.
And then back over to main activity to activity actually and in the Options menu
will look to see if I don't get to my data that's the ID of the menu item that's been tapped his ID
dot few feet and we just want to jump to that new field activity.
So intent intent is new intent with the application context and feed dot clus
and then start activity
with that intent.
There we go.
So let's take a look.
We should now find that we've got this extra menu item that will jump us to our feet and show us on
a list view by the content and user name of these five tweets that we've just generated using our that.
And if that works all that remains is connecting this up to a Passover query so we actually get the
tweets live from the server.
And here we go.
So let's tap on the menu.
And your feet.
And there we go.
You can see it's created this list that we wanted with the tweet content and then the user underneath
superb.
So now all that remains is to change this code to actually get the data from our past server.
So we'll do that of course with I-PASS query and this is going to be on pass objects I'll call it query
and it's going to be I pass query get query on the tweet Clauss.
Now you'll be aware that we only have one tweet so far and that was done by me so we don't want to display
that.
So let's just add a few random tweets
so we will do one by one way around.
So we'll have a high data tweet from Tony
we'll have a tweet from Ralphy
saying I like digger's.
And then we'll have another one from Tommy just to show that we want to order them by date not by use
of they
saying well fitted OK so we should get the most recent at the top so we want what's for dinner.
And then I like digger's and then hide at the bottom.
Of course you could Oriole's different if you like but that's what I'm going to go for.
Say Let's write our query and we want to find where the user name is anything that we are currently
following so we can use
the method where contained in and then we're looking for where the user name is contained in the list
of people that our user is following.
So that's Parsees dot get Karen user don't get a list and then is following
that we want to order it by the date which if you'll remember that given an automatic date creates it
out.
So I'll use that
and then we just set the number that we want and I'll go for 20
like that.
All right.
Then we run our query I find them background with a new find Colback
and then as usual we'll check to see if he is no.
And then if we have some objects
and if that's the case we'll loop through the.
So for
past objects which I'll call tweet in objects.
So for each of those we want to create our tweet data here.
So I'm going to copy this down
because this is more or less what we want to do.
Harringay but we only want to create that list once.
So let's start by creating that and we don't need that for loop anymore because we're leafing through
all of the tweets on our past server.
So we still want to create the tweet info map each time.
And then the content this time is going to be tweets don't get string.
And then the string lets just check what it is it's tweaked
and then the user name is Tweet don't get string and use it I there we go.
And then we want to add that to tweet data.
And then when we're done we'll create our simple adapter
and then we'll update our feed list view and we may just need to update this.
T.
Feed this as we're inside a closure here.
And the field view I think we need to change to be a final so we can access it in that location as well.
All right let's take a look.
So remember if all is working we should see what's for dinner at the top by me and then I like digger's
by Ralphy and then hide that by Tommy as well.
Let's take a look.
And here we go.
So let's jump over to your feet.
And there we go.
That is exactly what we wanted in the right order.
I only saw one slight change that I forgot to set the name for the title of the activity so let's just
do that to your feet.
There we go.
And of course these are just press back to go back to their user list if they want to exit.
So that takes us to the end of our Twitter app.
I hope you enjoyed making this one.
And as always that you made a good portion of it yourself in the next section.
We're going to build a related but different in functionality app and that is a whatsapp clone where
you can message individuals directly.
For now I would take a quick break have a cup of tea and I'll see you at the beginning of the next section.