Android where apps are not generally aiming to be massive apps that you spend a lot of time on primarily
smartwatch apps are to show the user quick bits of information or allow them to do quick tasks without
taking their phone out of their pockets.
That's the idea and that's why cards are so central to how Android Wear works.
So a card is something very simple that looks more or less like this.
So it's how you would show a quick bit of information to the user.
So in this video we're going to see how to create cards and customize them a little bit.
And by the way this site developed the Android dot com slash training site wearables is really useful
if you want to figure out how to do anything with Android Wear.
So I would recommend checking this out if you have any problems.
All right so let's go and create our card fragment.
I'm going to go back to our Android where demo app and work on that one for now.
Get rid of the code that we added before.
And let's head to the rectangular activity and this is where we're going to be doing most of our work.
So first off you may have noticed that in the developing guide here we started off with something called
a box inset layout.
If I just jump over to again the Android training materials here in the box inset layout basically looks
like this.
So it's not the most efficient use of space but it will reasonably cleverly you fill in the gaps around
the edge so it doesn't just look like a box like that but it is a convenient way to get a square layout
on both screens so you could use exactly the same layout on your square and round screens.
And that's what Google are recommending here so I'm going to use that as well.
So let's just copy this carried over
and replace our rectangular activity mine with that.
I'm just going to get rid of that background there.
We're not using that.
You can see it's pretty straightforward.
The only two options there are match parent for layout width and height.
And similarly here we've now got a frame layout which simply matches the parent as well.
So so far that doesn't actually show us anything because there's no content in there is only the frame
layout.
But that's when we need our Java.
So let's copy this down.
And we'll put it in the on lay out inflated method.
And we'll just bring in
all the necessary classes
then let's just see what this is doing.
So we're creating a fragment manager which we've seen manages a lot before obviously allows us to manage
our fragment and that in this case we're creating a card fragment.
Then we begin what's known as a fragment transaction which allows us to work with the fragment.
Then we create a card fragment variable which is created with two strings and an image.
So let's create those ourselves.
We've got the title.
So I'm just going to put.
Hello Rob.
We've got a message
something like that.
Hello how are you today.
And you can see we can just leave it at that but we can also add an image which will be shown just that.
So we're just looking for a small kind of icon image there.
Just find one of the built in
Icons
how shall use
plus.
OK so now we've created al-Qadi fragment and then we're adding that to the frame layout which has an
ID frame underscore layout which we've added here.
So we don't need to change that.
And then we commit the fragment transaction which essentially just means apply this to our layout.
OK so let's check that out.
I'm going to run it on the rectangular screen.
Notice that what we've done so far will crash if we try and run it on a round screen because we haven't
got the frame layout ID while that's running.
I'm just going to copy and paste everything down to round activity.
So now it would work fine on both a round or a rectangular watch.
So I've got my round one running but I want to test that out on a rectangular.
So let's get the square one running as well.
Generally when you're testing Android where apps it's a good idea to have both emulators open at once
because you're probably going to want to be fairly constantly testing on both to make sure that it looks
and works well on both screen layouts and then you can see we've got our nice card out there.
The icon that we chose was probably a little large and makes it all look a little bit strange but you
can see how that would all fit together.
While we're here let's just try it on the round screen as well.
Make sure it looks good on that screen size too.
And there you go.
You can see that even though we're inside the box inside out.
We've got this nice rounded.
It doesn't just block it off at a box.
It's more intelligent than that.
All right.
So that's how you work with cards in your apps.
I'll just show you very briefly the card frame if you want to customize this layout then you can do
that pretty easily by just adding a.
For example here a card scroll view which will allow you to scroll 3 content within your card.
And then once you've added a card frame you can add whatever you like in there.
So they've added a linear layout with two text views so they've more or less recreated the default layout
about themselves.
But you could have whatever you like that images text anything.
So that's pretty straightforward and works in exactly the same way as the card fragment that we just
created.
All right.
So now we're finished with cards and we're going to look at another very handy map object.
The list.