Now we will, of course, take a look at unmarshalling XML back into Java objects.
Please open the example ps-jaxb-03-unmarshalling to follow along.
In the src, main, resources directory, there is an XML file, purchaseOrder.
xml, which contains the XML document from the marshalling demo.
Let's see how we can unmarshal that into a purchaseOrder object.
The first class to look at is class UnmarshallingExample1.
As you know, the first thing you need to do is create a JAXBContext.
Then we create an Unmarshaller object by calling
createUnmarshaller on the context.
Then we call the Unmarshal method to read the XML file,
which returns a JAXBElement that contains the purchaseOrder object.
Just like with the Marshal method of class Marshaller,
there are actually different overloaded versions of the Unmarshal
method that read from different kinds of inputs.
Class StreamSource, which I use here for convenience,
is actually from the XML transformation API.
There are also versions of the Unmarshal method that,
for example, read from a DOM Node or a StAX XMLStreamReader or XMLEventReader.
Let's quickly look at the second unmarshalling example,
class UnmarshallingExample2.
This example shows you how you can unmarshal from a DOM node.
In this example, we read the XML using the DOM API.
To do that, we need to create a DocumentBuilder,
which parses the XML file into a Document object.
We can then unmarshal the rootElement of the document by calling
the Unmarshal method that takes a DOM node.
That's it for now.
Please play with the marshalling and unmarshalling examples
yourself so that you get a good grip on how it works.
Consult the API documentation if you want to know the exact details of what the JAXB method should do.