Both in Java and in XML Schema there's the concept of inheritance.
In Java, you do this by creating a subclass that extends the superclass.
In XML Schema,
you can derive types from other types either by extension or by restriction.
We've already seen derived types by restriction in XML Schema
in many of the examples of this course.
For example,
the type of the loyalty element is a simpleType that is
derived by restriction from the type xs:string.
You can also derive types by extension in XML Schema,
which corresponds naturally to subclassing in Java.
When you generate Java classes from an XML Schema with such types,
xjc will indeed generate a superclass with subclasses in Java.
The next example, ps-jaxb-25-inheritance, shows how this works.
Let's once again switch to the IDE to work with the example.
In this example, I've modified the XSD and added two new complexTypes,
shippingAddress and billingAddress.
Both of these types derive from the type address by extension.
In the type customer,
I've removed the shippingAddress and billingAddress elements and replaced them
with an address element of the base type address and set maxOccurs to 2 so there
can be at most 2 addresses in a customer element.
First,
we are going to have a look at what Java classes xjc
will generate for this schema,
then we'll see what the XML looks like when we marshal a purchase order,
and finally, we'll discuss unmarshalling.
Let's start with running xjc to generate the Java classes.
I'll open a terminal and run xjc.
Besides class address, we now also get two subclasses,
ShippingAddress and BillingAddress.
There's not a lot to see that's interesting in the
source code of these two classes.
They both obviously extend class address.
There's one thing to note about class address.
As you see, it has a new annotation,
the XmlSeeAlso annotation that refers to the two subclasses.
I'll explain what this means.
When you create the JAXBContext,
JAXB is going to analyze the domain model classes.
It does this by starting from the class that you passed it a new
instance method of class JAXBContext or from the objectFactory class
in the package if you pass it a package name.
It will find all the other domain classes by looking at the
fields of the classes that it has found.
However, in case a class has subclasses that are also part of the domain model,
this is a bit more difficult.
There's no easy way in Java to find all the subclasses of a particular class,
so when JAXB finds class address,
it doesn't know that there are two subclasses that
are also part of the domain model.
The XmlSeeAlso annotation tells JAXB explicitly to also include the
classes that are mentioned by the annotation,
in this case, the classes ShippingAddress and BillingAddress.
In this example, we're working with the schema-first approach.
Of course, you can also use inheritance when you use the code-first approach.
In that case,
you would have to put the XmlSeeAlso annotation on the
superclass yourself to include the subclasses,
just like xjc has done it for us in this example.
In class customer, the two fields, ShippingAddress and BillingAddress,
have now been replaced by a field Address which is a list of address objects.
Let's now look at the marshalling example.
In the createPurchaseOrder method,
I now create a ShippingAddress and a BillingAddress object,
which I both add to the list of addresses in the customer object.
Let's run the marshalling example and see what the XML looks like.
When you look at the output XML, you'll see something interesting.
The customer element now contains two address elements,
and both of these elements have an xsi:type annotation
from the XMLSchema-instance namespace.
Remember that we saw the XMLSchema-instance namespace
before when we looked at nillable elements.
The xsi:type annotation specifies which subtype of the
type address each address actually has.
That way, we know that the first address is the shipping address,
and the second address is the billing address.
Finally, let's look at unmarshalling.
When you unmarshal this XML,
then by inspecting the xsi:type annotation on the elements,
the unmarshaller knows what the XML Schema type of the address element is,
and it can find the Java class that is bound to that type.
This way, the unmarshaller knows which subclass it should instantiate, ShippingAddress or BillingAddress.