Sometimes an XML Schema is left open to extra elements that
the schema itself doesn't know about to allow including
elements from other schemas in XML.
Let's see how JAXB deals with this and how you can
work with these extra elements.
In the complexType definition in an XML Schema,
you specify exactly what elements of that type can or must contain by
using xs:element and xs:attribute and other declarations.
One of the things that you can specify besides
xs:element and xs:attribute is xs:any, which is a more open-ended declaration.
What you specify when you use xs:any is that elements that are
instances of the complexType can contain other arbitrary elements
that belong to specific namespaces.
An example of this is the schema that defines XML Schema itself.
As you have seen when you were learning about customizing bindings,
it's possible to add the JAXB binding instructions into an XSD
by putting them inside an xs:appinfo element,
which is inside an xs:annotation element in,
for example, a complexType definition.
These binding instructions are XML elements from the JAXB bindings
namespace that XML Schema itself doesn't know about.
The schema that defines XSD itself contains an xs:any element to
allow these foreign JAXB elements inside an XSD.
We're going to look at how we can use this in our own
purchaseOrder schema and how JAXB maps this to Java.
There are two examples, and we'll start with the first one, ps-jaxb-26-xmlany-1.
Let's start with the purchaseOrder.
xsd.
In this example,
I've added an element named extra to the type
definition of the PurchaseOrder element.
The extra element has an anonymous complexType with an xs:any declaration.
The xs:any declaration has a few attributes.
The namespace attribute is set to ##other,
which means that any element is allowed here that is from a namespace
other than the target namespace of this schema.
The processContents attribute specifies how elements should
be validated if schema validation is used.
The value lax means that the validator should validate the
element that it finds in the XML if possible,
but it can skip validation if no definition is available
for the element to validate against.
Finally,
minOccurs and maxOccurs of course specify that there must be at least 0 elements
and that there can be an unlimited number of elements here.
Let's now look at the file purchaseOrder.
xml where you can see an example of what this would look like in a
concrete XML file that's valid according to this schema.
At the bottom of the purchaseOrder, I've added an extra element,
which contains a productStock element from a
different namespace with the inv prefix.
The idea is that inv stands for inventory,
and as you can see,
the extra information is about how many ballpoint pens
there are in stock at a given date.
We don't have a schema for the inv namespace.
This is just some extra data that the purchaseOrder schema doesn't know about.
First,
let's see what we get from xjc when we generate Java classes for the
purchaseOrder schema and then at how we can unmarshal this XML
document and work with the unknown elements.
Let's run xjc and then look at the PurchaseOrder class.
The class now has a new field named extra,
which represents the element that we added to the XSD.
Its type is PurchaseOrder.
Extra, which is a nested class defined inside class PurchaseOrder.
This type contains one field named any, which is a list of arbitrary objects.
The field any is annotated with the XmlAnyElement annotation,
which corresponds to the xs:any declaration in the schema.
It also has an attribute lax = true,
which corresponds to the processContents = lax attribute on
the xs:any declaration in the schema.
Now we know how xjc maps an xs:any to Java,
but the fact that the field any is a list of
arbitrary objects doesn't tell us a lot.
An interesting question to ask here is what kind of objects will actually be
put in the list if we try to unmarshal an XML document.
Let's run the unmarshalling example to find out.
What happens is that the inv:productStock element in the
XML is unmarshalled as a DOM element, so what's in the list is an org.
w3c.
DOM.
element object.
So this is how you can work with the extra elements.
The purchase order itself is unmarshalled into instances of
the classes of our well-known domain model,
and unknown elements inside the extra element are unmarshalled into DOM element
objects so that you can use the DOM API to deal with them.
We are not done yet with this subject.
There's a second example to look at, ps-jaxb-27-xmlany-2,
which shows some more possibilities.
Let's continue with the second example.
Suppose that the extra elements that we use are not completely unknown.
In this example, I've added a second schema, inventory.
xsd, which contains the definition of the productStock element.
To start,
we're going to run xjc two times to generate the
domain model classes for both schemas.
First, let's generate the PurchaseOrder domain model classes.
For this example, I'm going to put them in a different package, com.
jesperdj.
jaxb.
domain.
po.
Second, let's generate the domain model classes for the inventory schema.
I'm going to put these in the package com.
jesperdj.
jaxb.
domain.
inv.
Now let's look at the unmarshalling example.
It's important to note here that we now create the
JAXBContext for both packages by specifying the names of
the two packages separated by a colon.
Then we create an unmarshaller, unmarshal the XML,
and print the extra information we found in the purchaseOrder.
Let's run the example and see what happens.
Remember that in the first example where we didn't have a
domain model for the productStock element,
we got a DOM element object.
Now in this second example, we actually get a productStock object instead.
Because the JAXBContext now knows the productStock class,
which is bound to the productStock element,
the unmarshaller will properly unmarshal the element and
put the resulting object in the list.
Note that the extra element in the purchaseOrder is open to elements from
any namespace other than the purchaseOrder namespace,
so it's still possible to add other arbitrary elements here.
Of course, if there's no domain model for these elements,
they will show up as DOM element objects.
The list in the any field of the extra element may contain a mix
of different types of objects in that case, including unmarshalled JAXB objects and DOM element objects.