In this module,
you've learned how you can integrate the JAXB tools
into your Maven or Gradle build.
We first looked at Maven builds.
In the first Maven example, we've used the jaxb2-maven-plugin to call schemagen,
and in the second example, we've used the same plugin to call xjc.
Second, we've looked at gradle build.
In the two Gradle examples, we did the same thing as in the Maven examples.
First, we've used the jaxb.
schemaGen task provided by a Gradle plugin to call schemagen,
and then we have used the jaxb.
javaGen task from the same plugin to call xjc.
The examples in this module were small and just meant to give you a starting
point for configuring your own builds in your own projects.
You can find more information on both the Maven and Gradle plugins
on the web pages for the respective plugins.
I recommend that you look at the examples at your own pace and
study the documentation of the plugins to see what the best way
is to use them for your own projects.
With this,
you now know everything you need to know to be able to
use JAXB in real-world Java projects.
In the next module,
we'll be looking at a subject that is a stepping stone
for what might come after this course.
JAXB can be used for many different purposes,
and one application where it's often used is for XML-based web services. That's what we'll take a look at in the final module of this course.