Besides simple marshalling and unmarshalling to
convert between Java objects in XML,
you can do more sophisticated things with JAXB.
To show you an example of what's possible,
we are going to see what you can do using class binder.
Before we get to the code,
I'll explain what exactly the purpose is of class binder.
As you know,
you can parse an XML document in different ways using
the different Java XML parsing APIs.
For example, you can parse it into a tree of DOM nodes using the DOM API,
or into a set of JAXB objects by unmarshalling it using JAXB.
When you've parsed an XML document using the DOM API,
what you can do with a binder is translate the DOM tree into
JAXB objects while maintaining a link back from the JAXB
objects to the nodes in the DOM tree.
This way,
you can work with the JAXB objects and then update the DOM tree with
the modifications that you made in the JAXB objects.
In other words, it enables you to create a JAXB view of a DOM tree,
which is easier to work with than the DOM tree itself.
Also,
you do not have to translate the whole DOM tree into JAXB
objects; you can also convert only a part of it,
as we'll see in the example that we're going to work with.
In example ps-jaxb-28-binder, we're going to do the following.
First we'll parse a file purchaseOrder.
xml using the DOM API.
Then we'll look up the customer element in the DOM tree.
We'll use a binder to unmarshal the customer element into a customer object.
Then we'll modify some of the fields in the customer object,
and then use the binder to write those modifications back to the DOM tree.
Let's have a look at the example.
We'll start with class BinderExample.
In lines 31 to 34, we use the DOM API to parse the file purchaseOrder.
xml.
One thing that's important is that we need to enable support for namespaces
because this is disabled by default in the DOM parser.
If we don't do this,
then the namespaces in the document will be ignored during parsing,
and we'll get problems when we use the binder to translate this to JAXB.
In our domain model,
there's an XmlSchema annotation on the package which says that the
domain model classes map to our example namespace.
If there's no information about the namespace in the DOM tree,
then there would be a mismatch between the DOM tree
and our domain model classes.
After parsing the XML,
we find the customer element in the DOM tree by using getElementsByTagName.
Next, we create a binder object using the createBinder method of the JAXBContext.
And then we can use the binder to get a JAXB view of the customer element.
We do this by unmarshalling the DOM node for the
customer element using the binder.
You've seen before in the previous modules that if you want to unmarshal XML
into a class that does not have an XmlRootElement annotation,
you have to use JAXBElement.
Since class Customer does indeed not have an XmlRootElement annotation,
that's what we have to do here.
Now we have a JAXB customer object in which we can modify some of the fields.
The main purpose of class Binder is that it keeps track of the links
between JAXB objects and the nodes in the DOM tree.
We can now call the updateXML method on the binder,
passing it the customer object.
Because the binder knows which JAXB object
corresponds to which node in the DOM tree,
it can update the DOM tree with the modifications we've
made to the JAXB customer object.
This also works the other way around,
so class binder also has a method updateJAXB,
which allows you to update the JAXB objects if
you've made changes in the DOM tree.
I haven't included that in the code here.
The last few lines here use the XML transformation API to
output the DOM tree as XML to the console.
I'll not explain these lines in detail,
but I've set some properties to get the XML formatted in a readable way.
Let's run this and look at the output.
As you see, the name of the customer is now Susan Jones,
and the loyalty is now GOLD, exactly as we expect.
There are a few more things I want to say about class binder.
The API documentation of class binder talks about an infoset preserving view.
What is meant by this is the DOM tree.
The DOM tree is more or less a 1 to 1 representation
of the content of an XML document,
so there is a node in the DOM tree for each of the items in the XML,
including elements, attributes, text,
and also comments and processing instructions.
In other words,
the DOM tree preserves the content and structure of the XML document,
including items that do not contain real data such as comments.
On the other hand, a set of JAXB objects is not an infoset preserving view.
When you unmarshal XML using JAXB, then things such as comments are discarded.
So from the resulting JAXB object,
you cannot get back the exact content and structure of the original XML anymore.
The API documentation of class binder explains that you can make modifications
to the JAXB view of the XML that you get from the binder and that if you then
update the DOM tree using the updateXML method,
it should leave other parts of the DOM tree alone.
For example, if the DOM tree contains nodes for comments in the XML,
then the updateXML method is supposed to not touch these nodes,
and if you write out the updated DOM tree to XML again,
you should see that the comments are still there.
Unfortunately, this does not work in practice,
at least not with the JAXB reference implementation that's included with Java.
If you look at the file purchaseOrder.
xml, you'll see that I've added a comment there inside the customer element.
But when I run the example and look at the output, the comment is gone.
This looks like a bug in the JAXB reference implementation
because it's clearly not doing what is explicitly mentioned in
the API documentation of class binder.
There are other implementations of JAXB available.
The most well-known one is EclipseLink MOXy,
and if you use that, comments are indeed preserved as they should be.
To show you that and also to quickly show you how you can use
EclipseLink MOXy instead of the JAXB reference implementation,
I've added example ps-jaxb-29-bindermoxy.
The code in that example is exactly the same as in example 28,
except that I've added a dependency in the Maven pom.
xml to include MOXy, and I've added a jaxb.
properties file in the src\main\resources directory
to make JAXB work using MOXy.
If you run example 29 and look at the output,
you'll see that the comment is indeed preserved. You can find more information on EclipseLink MOXy at the following URL.