One of the things you saw when we used xjc in one of the first
examples in this module is that for date and time types,
it generates fields of type XMLGregorianCalendar.
This is an XML-specific and inconvenient type for
storing date and time information.
Since Java 8, the JDK contains the package java.
time,
which has a number of classes for dealing with dates and times that are much
more powerful than what was available in all the Java versions.
The old date and time classes, specifically the classes java.
util.
Date and java.
Calendar,
were not suitable for JAXB because they cannot contain all the
information that JAXB needs to properly map XML Schema date and
time types to Java and vice versa.
JAXB has not been updated yet to make use of the
new Java 8 date and time classes,
and maybe it never will because of backward compatibility requirements.
It would be great if we can find a way to make JAXB use
the Java 8 date and time types anyway,
so that we don't have to deal with XMLGregorianCalendar anymore.
Fortunately,
it is possible to customize bindings so that xjc will
use the Java 8 date and time types.
Let's see how you can do this in the next example, ps-jaxb-21-datetime.
XML Schema has a number of standard date and time types.
In our purchaseOrder schema,
we've used the type xs:dateTime for the orderDate
attribute of the purchaseOrder element.
Let's see how we can make xjc generate a field of type
JavaTime OffsetDateTime for this attribute.
The class OffsetDateTime represents a date and time with a time
zone offset in the ISO 8601 calendar system,
which is the same as what XML Schema is based on,
so this is a suitable type to use.
In the bindings file,
we'll add a jaxb:javaType element to the jaxb:globalBindings element.
With the javaType element you can customize how xjc maps
standard XML Schema types to Java types.
The javaType element expects a number of attributes.
We have to specify the name of the XML Schema type in the xmlType attribute,
which is xs:dateTime in this example.
With the name attribute,
we specify the fully qualified name of the javaType that we want to use,
which is, of course, java.
time.
OffsetDateTime.
There's one more important piece of information to the puzzle.
In XML, the value of the attribute or element that we are dealing with is,
of course, represented as text.
We need to tell JAXB how to convert the text content of the element or
attribute to and from the javaType that we want to use.
To do this, we have to specify two more attributes on the javaType element,
the parseMethod and the printMethod attribute.
The parseMethod attribute is the name of a static method which takes a
string and returns an instance of the target Java type.
JAXB will call this method during unmarshalling to
convert the XML value into a Java object.
In this case,
we simply specify parse because class OffsetDateTime contains a
method named parse that does exactly what we need.
It takes a string in ISO 8601 format and returns an OffsetDateTime object.
Note that the method we refer to here does not need
to be in the target Java type.
We could, for example, make a utility class with static methods.
To point to a method in the utility class,
we would have to specify the fully qualified name of
the class before the method name.
Another possibility is to use the special name new,
which means that JAXB will look for a constructor of the
target Java class that takes a string.
If you leave out the parseMethod attribute from the javaType element,
this is what JAXB does by default.
But we cannot do that for this example because class
OffsetDateTime does not have such a constructor.
The printMethod attribute is similar and refers to the method that
will be called during marshalling to convert the Java object to text
content for the XML element or attribute.
The method that this attribute refers to must take no
arguments and return a string that contains the
representation of the Java object in XML.
The method is normally called on the Java object itself,
but it's also possible to specify the name of a
static method in a utility class, just like with the parseMethod attribute.
If you do that,
then the static method in the utility class must take one argument,
which is the Java object, to convert.
When you omit the printMethod attribute from the javaType element,
then by default, the toString method is used.
I specified it here explicitly just to show you what it looks like,
but the printMethod attribute here is actually redundant.
Let's run xjc with this bindings file and see what we get so that you
understand what exactly this binding customization does.
Let's look at the generated class PurchaseOrder first.
It indeed has a field named orderDate now that is of type OffsetDateTime.
The field also has two annotations,
an XmlSchemaType annotation that specifies the
XmlSchemaType that this field maps to, and an XmlJavaTypeAdapter annotation.
You've seen both of these annotations before.
Remember that we implemented our own XML adapter to customize how
we wanted a hash map to be converted to XML.
Now xjc has generated an adapter automatically for us,
which is named Adapter1, as you can see here.
If we look at the list of generated classes,
we see that there is a class Adapter1 in the package org\w3\_2001\xmlschema.
Note that this strange-looking package name corresponds to the
namespace URI of the standard XML Schema namespace.
The generated adapter class contains marshal and unmarshal
methods that call the parseMethod and the printMethod that we
specified in the bindings file.
The marshal method calls toString on the OffsetDateTime object,
and the unmarshal method calls the parseMethod.
As you see, this is the schema-first equivalent of writing an adapter class.
Besides using it to make use of the Java 8 date and time classes,
you can, of course,
use this for your own data types that need custom conversion to and from XML text content as well.