Here we are again at the end of another module of this JAXB course.
In this module, you've learned about a bunch of useful, more advanced topics.
First, we've looked at validation.
You've seen how you can load a schema using the XML validation API,
and how you can set this schema on the marshaller and unmarshaller to
enable validation during marshalling and unmarshalling.
You've also seen how you can set a ValidationEventHandler to
handle validation warnings and errors.
After that,
you've learned how you can use the validation API to validate JAXB
objects in memory by using a JAXBSource object.
Next,
you've learned how types derived by extension in an XSD map
to a superclass with subclasses in Java,
and you've learned about the XmlSeeAlso annotation.
Then you've learned how JAXB handles xs:any declarations in an
XSD and how elements that are outside of the schema are either
unmarshalled into DOM element objects or to JAXB objects from a
different domain model.
Finally, you've learned about class binder.
This allows you to map a DOM tree to JAXB objects while maintaining
a link back to the nodes in the DOM tree so that it can be updated
with changes made to the JAXB objects.
As you've also learned, if you want to do this,
and it's important to maintain the structure of the original XML document,
it's better to use EclipseLink MOXy because the default implementation
of JAXB unfortunately does not do this correctly.
There are still a few bits that are missing.
In real-world Java development projects,
you'll be using a build and dependency management tool like Maven or Gradle.
In the next module, you'll learn how you can use the JAXB tools from Maven or Gradle.