In XML Schema, simple types can be defined with enumeration facets,
which naturally corresponds to Java enum types.
There are a number of ways to customize how these XML
Schema types are mapped to Java enums.
The correspondence between XML Schema simple types with
enumeration facets and Java enum types is not exact.
It is possible to specify things in XML Schema that cannot be
automatically mapped to a Java enum type,
so in some cases, it is necessary to customize the mapping.
Let's take a look at example ps-jaxb-22-enum to see how
we can customize the mapping of enums.
We've seen how JAXB maps the loyalty simpleType to a Java enum.
The loyalty type in the XSD has a base type
xs:string and three enumeration facets.
These three facets translate to three enum constants in the
Java enum loyalty with names that are the same as the
values of the enumeration facets.
So we get three constants, BRONZE, SILVER, and GOLD.
But suppose that the loyalty type in the XSD looks different.
Let's give it a base type xs:int and specify the values 10,
20, and 30 as possible values.
This definition cannot be mapped to a Java enum.
It is as if we have defined an enum that is derived from the type int,
which does not exist in Java.
Also, the values 10, 20, and 30 are not valid identifiers in Java,
so they cannot be used as enum constant names.
If we run xjc with this definition of the loyalty type,
what happens is that JAXB maps it to an int in Java instead of an enum.
You can see this in class Customer where the field loyalty is now an int.
Suppose that we want xjc to map it to an enum instead.
Let's see what we need to do to make that work.
By default,
xjc only takes simple types with enumeration facets that have the base type
xs:string into consideration for mapping to a Java enum.
As we just saw when we changed the base type of the loyalty type to xs:int,
we got an int field in class Customer instead of a loyalty enum.
We first have to tell xjc that it should also convert simple
types with base type xs:int into an enum.
We do that by specifying the typesafeEnumBase
attribute on the globalBindings element.
The value of this attribute is a space-separated list of type names.
Only simple types with enumeration facets that have one
of these types as their base type, or type derived from one these types,
will be taken into consideration for mapping to a Java enum.
So the first step we need to take is add xs:int to this list.
But this first step is not yet enough to make it work.
The second problem is that the values 10,
20,
and 30 are numerical values that are not valid as
identifier names for Java enum constants.
We have to tell xjc what to do because by default,
it will give up if it encounters values that cannot be
used as Java enum constant names,
and map the loyalty type to an int instead of an enum despite what we
specified for the typesafeEnumBase in the first step.
One way we can solve this is by setting the
typesafeEnumMemberName attribute on the globalBindings element.
This attribute can have three possible values,
skipGeneration,
which is the default and which means that if it encounters
values that are not valid Java identifier names,
it gives up mapping the type to an enum and falls back to
mapping it to the base type; generateError,
which means that it stops with an error if it encounters values that cannot
be translated to Java enum constant names; generateName,
which means that it will generate constant names automatically.
Let's use the generateName option and see what happens when I run xjc again.
As you see, we now get a loyalty enum, but the enum members are named VALUE_1,
VALUE_2, AND VALUE_3, which are not very meaningful and useful names.
So this solution is not very good.
There is a way to make this much better by adding a
customization specifically for the loyalty type.
Let's add a jaxb:bindings element for the loyalty type.
Inside this bindings element we can add a typesafeEnumClass element,
and inside that element, we can add a typesafeEnumMember element for each value.
Here we can specify for each value in the XSD what the
Java enum constant name should be.
When we do this and run xjc again,
we get a nice loyalty enum with constants BRONZE,
SILVER, and GOLD,
and XmlEnumValue annotations to map each of the
constants to their corresponding XML value.
We also get a few other autogenerated methods, value and fromValue, to get the numerical value for a constant and vice versa.