Welcome at the end of this module.
You have considerably expanded your knowledge of JAXB in this
module by learning about the schema-first approach.
We started by comparing the code-first and the schema-first
approach and looking at what the advantages and
disadvantages of both approaches are.
Then you've learned how to work with the schema-first approach
in practice by using the xjc tool and taking a look at how you
can work with the generated classes.
In the second half of the module,
you've learned a lot about customizing how xjc should generate classes from
an XSD by writing binding files to control what xjc does.
We've looked at many different possible things that you can customize,
for example, how to customize the names of generated classes and fields,
how to map a complex type to a class that you wrote yourself,
how to map a simple type to a class,
and how you can avoid having fields of type JAXBElement generated.
You've also learned how to automatically generate an adapter class by
looking at how you can map a dateTime attribute to a java.
time.
OffsetDateTime object.
Finally,
you've learned how you can customize how simple types with
enumeration facets are mapped to Java enum types.
Congratulations on making it this far.
You now already know enough to work with JAXB effectively with both
the code-first and the schema-first approach.
There are still a number of interesting things to learn.
In the next module, we'll take a look at a number of more advanced use cases.
It's useful to know about these subjects because when
you're going to work with JAXB in practice, you'll undoubtedly encounter some of these cases in your work.