Hello this is Kirill from forex boat dot com.
And welcome to the course on forex trading.
Today's tutorial will answer the question what is Forex and where it came from.
For extensive foreign exchange it is also sometimes abbreviated as simply FX investor period defines
foreign exchange as the exchange of one currency for another or the conversion of one currency into
another currency.
So simply put.
Foreign exchange is exchange of currencies.
Also a superior continues his definition by saying that foreign exchange also refers to the global market
where currencies are traded virtually around the clock.
So let's have a look at an example.
Say for instance you're going in a holiday to Europe.
In that case you will take your American dollars and go to the exchange shop and convert them into euros
.
By doing this you've conducted a currency exchange and therefore you have become a participant of the
Forex market.
We will talk about the participants of forex more in one of the future tutorials.
But today let's have a look at the history of how this used to be back in the day because it wasn't
always as easy.
So here's a timeline.
And a long long time ago there was no money and no currencies and people had to just exchange goods
and this was called Barter.
When some people would fish and other people would grow grains and crops they would exchange some of
their goods in order to have the best of both worlds.
Next around 2600 B.C. Egyptians discovered gold.
We're not really sure who discovered gold and when but it's attributed to Gyptian around that time.
People liked gold very much because it was very dense.
And it felt very heavy in your hands and it felt more valuable than other things around.
It was shiny and it was soft so you could molded into different shapes and most importantly was very
scarce.
It was very hard to find.
And that also increased its value.
Next around 1500 B.C. gold was used or countries started using gold for international trade.
So instead of just exchanging goods they would exchange gold for goods and goods for gold and that kind
of simplified things.
Then to simplify things even further around 700 B.C. The first gold coins were created and there was
a very handy thing to how because before that people had to check that the gold that they're receiving
is actually gold.
And also they had to weigh it up.
But by having gold coins they could already know what value those gold coins are carrying and that speeded
up the process of exchange.
So that's a bit of ancient history which now brings us to the modern world in about the 17th century
.
Paper money started spreading across Europe and around the 18th century it became so popular it started
causing tensions because some people in countries were still using gold and silver coins whereas others
were actually using paper money and there was no real connection between the two.
And that is when the gold standard came into play the gold standard was agreed upon or in 1875.
And basically what it meant was that currencies became backed by gold reserve of their countries.
In essence that means governments guaranteed conversion of currency into a specific amount of gold and
vice versa.
Let's look an example for for instance country A says that it's one 1 unit of its currency equals two
ounces of gold.
And country B says that one unit of its currency equals to four ounces of gold.
And that basically means that you now know how to convert currency of country into currency of country
B that made things more simple and also defined certain rules around how these transactions occurred
and it became the gold standard became the first standardized means of exchange in history so that there
was a good idea in general but then what happened was world where one struck.
And World War Two.
During these wars countries that were fighting with Germany spent a lot of money on their military and
basically they were printing more and more money and which they had to back by gold reserves and the
gold reserves were rapidly depleting and it got to a point where they couldn't actually guarantee all
that money with gold and therefore the gold standard lost its meaning.
And so to fix that issue in 1944 the Allies got together to sign the Bretton Woods Agreement and Bretton
Woods agreement simply put.
It's just the same as the gold standard Gold Standard Version 2.0 and all it did was it replaced gold
with the U.S. dollar and the U.S. dollar became the only currency in the world that had to be backed
by gold at a fixed exchange rate of $35 per ounce and all other currencies had a fixed exchange rate
to the U.S. dollar.
So let's have a look at a bit more detail into the outcomes of the burn Woods agreement.
So first of all fixed exchange rates all currencies were pegged to the U.S. dollar.
Second the U.S dollar became the primary reserve currency which meant that it had to be backed by gold
.
And three the creation of two organization the International Monetary Fund which is simply a pool of
funds where all participating nations contribute to on a regular basis.
And then if they have problems within their country they can take money out of that pool. Fix their
problems and then return it plus pay some interest and also the World Bank which is a financial institution
of the United Nations meaning that its main purpose is to reduce poverty around the world and help developing
countries.
By the way if you're wondering why it's called the burn was agreement as because it was signed in a
town called Bretton Woods in New Hampshire USA.
And as you can expect when you create something which is basically the Gold Standard Version 2.0 then
there's a very high likelihood of it failing just as the gold senator did.
And that's exactly what happened to the bread Woods agreement over the years after World War Two.
Gold reserves of the U.S. started depleting very rapidly and in 1971.
U.S. President Richard Nixon closed the gold window by telling all other countries that the U.S. will
no longer exchange gold for U.S. dollars held in foreign reserves.
This event marked the end of the barren Woods agreement and since then the world has been using floating
exchange rates between currencies what we now know as the Forex market.
The main two takeaways from this timeline are that first of all it hasn't always been that simple.
It took some time for nations to come up with the current Forex system that we have.
And secondly that there have been several attempts at creating fixed exchange rates between currencies
.
For example the gold standard and the Bretton Woods Agreement and all of these events have failed because
it is very artificial to put such constraints on currencies and try to control them.
It also illustrates that the Forex market that we currently have is by far the most natural thing that
should govern the exchange rates of currencies between each other.
This brings us to the end of today's tutorial.
I hope you enjoyed it.
And I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy trading.