Hey guys.
Welcome back to the caucus training course.
It's early morning.
These ghosts are still sleeping and I'm in Africa and I wanted to take you for a quick walk here just
to show around.
Show you what it's what it's like to live in Africa and in the meantime while we're on this quick walk
I also wanted to give you a quick heads up.
Very soon Tim is going to ask you to leave a review for this course.
Now I know it can be difficult to judge the quality and value of a course.
This early on however the unit review system has simply changed and they are asking to leave a review
earlier and earlier on in the course.
Now if they're minded we're not going to ask you to leave a five star review for this course.
But what I would like to ask is that if you're not yet familiar enough with the course to radio five
star of course then please scroll through the tutorials and have a look at all the different things
that we cover and all the exciting topics that you will learn inside this class and hopefully once you
see that it will give you the confidence to write this course a five star course if on the other hand
you feel that something is wrong with the course.
If you're unsatisfied about something if you feel that something's missing then please do let us know
before you write the course.
The best way to contact us is if you leave a short message in the course Q and A.
And we will get back to you or we'll fix up whatever the issue is and then get back to you.
Check out this this guy over here they love sleeping on walls on they.
So yeah I will get back to you and hopefully that will give you the confidence to write this course
the five star course.
Now having said that if if something's wrong please do let us know.
But if you feel satisfied of the chorus if you're enjoying the tutorial so far if you're excited about
the journey ahead and you feel that this is a five star course then please do read it appropriately
so that the rest of the world can also know that this is a five star course on forex trading.
So there we go.
Thanks a lot guys for being part of the forex trading course or courses if you're taking several of
us.
Really appreciate you being inside this lesson.
I'm very excited for the journey ahead.
And before we go I want to share one more cool thing.
So this box over here.
This is actually a TV and this is where people sit to watch the TV when there's a soccer match.
That's that's how to want you do.
All right see you guys have fun in the course.