Hello this is Kirill from Forex boat dot com.
And welcome back to the course on forex trading in today's tutorial we will talk about Forex brokers
and we will understand why we actually need them in our day to day trading.
So if we imagine the Forex market then has got lost.
Different participants such as major banks central banks and governments investment banks and investment
companies other normal companies that need to conduct foreign exchange transactions and these are all
the major players of the four exchange market and they constantly transact with each other and they
always transact in very very large amounts of money we're talking billions of dollars here.
And so together they comprise the Forex market.
So how does a person such as you and me get into this Forex market.
We even if we have a deposit on our account of $50000 and more likely than not it's often less than
that even if such a large deposit is hard to get into a market where an average transaction is several
billion dollars and the daily WM is measured in trillions of dollars.
So how can we get it there.
And that's where the broker comes into play a person such as you and me will go to a broker and the
broker will also work with a lot of other people individual traders who will also go to this broker
and the broker will then aggregate all these transactions and send them to a bank.
So a broker has an established relationship with a bank and because it can scale up all of these little
transactions that all the clients of the broker conduct then the bank is more willing now to work with
the broker.
There are many different types of brokers and different types of relationships between the broker and
the bank and they include the market maker brokers S2P brokers the C-n brokers and so on.
However at the end of the day the concept remains the same.
A single individual person cannot gain access to the Forex market and has nobody to transact with but
a broker can facilitate access to the foreign exchange market to each one of us by scaling up our transactions
over the past decade.
Brokerage services have become very competitive and there are lots and lots of brokers out there and
this makes it very important to select the right broker for your trading.
And if you're new to the foreign exchange market I recommend checking out my review which I did a couple
of weeks ago on my web site.
So in this review I compared the top three brokers that I've ever worked with in my seven plus years
of foreign exchange experience.
You can see here that it says best for its Broca's for algo trading and that's because my trading is
predominantly comprised of algorithmic trading systems and Forex robots.
However this review can help you select a broker even for manual trading because only one of the brokers
I talk about is dedicated solely to algorithmic trading and the other two you can both use for X robots
in them.
Or you can trade manually.
And I've tried and tested them and they are reliable.
So if you want to check out the story you just go to www dot forex boat dot com slash brokers.
And when you read this review you will notice that for each one of these brokers I specify exactly how
many funds I have held with them at the maximum and how much money I have withdrawn and how they have
gone about processing those withdrawal requests.
And so this serves as proof of their trustworthiness.
I'm pretty sure that this review will be worth your while because it will help you avoid the national
mistake most beginners make when they select an unreliable broker who basically trades against them
and makes them lose because of that.
On that note I'm going to finish today's tutorial.
Thank you for your attention and I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy trading