Types of orders on the forex market there are two main classes of warder's on the forex market and these
are market orders and pending orders and they're two sub categories in the pending orders.
These are stop orders and limit orders and we'll have a look at all of them right now.
So market orders you're already familiar with these orders these are the byte order and the sell order
stop orders.
So the first stop of stop order that I'd like to introduce you to is the Bicester.
So basically the bae stop is a pending type of water.
What that means is that when you set by stop you're not actually entering the market you're setting
a condition or a trigger or a future order.
So you're saying if something were to happen then I want my terminal to enter the market automatically
for me.
So basically what this in this case what's happening is you're saying that if the price reaches this
green line I want to enter the market with a buy order.
So let's see how that happens.
The price crosses the green line and that's exactly when you buy stop order turns into a buy order.
So from that Red Cross onwards your Buy Stop order no longer exists.
Now you have a buy order in the market sell order very similar.
So you're saying when the price crosses the green line I want the market I want to enter the market
with a sell order.
See when that happens you sell stop orders.
Turns into a sell or instantly.
So what's the benefit of these Buy Stop and sell supporters.
Well it's basically kind of saving you the effort of actually waiting for the price to get to that level
and then entering the market.
So if you're if you think that once the price crosses a certain price a certain price level or support
line you think the price will keep going downwards.
That's when you would want to set a sell stop order and catch that movement as soon as it starts.
Rather than having to sit around and wait for it to happen.
The other thing is that if that doesn't happen if the price for example in this image that we have in
front of us if the price were to keep going upwards then you would never enter the market at a sale
with a sell order because the price wouldn't have crossed your green line and wouldn't have triggered
the sell order.
So it's kind of a very convenient way to save your time and also check for specific conditions that
you're looking for.
Limit orders limit orders are similar to stop orders but they may be a little bit more complicated to
remember how they work.
But we'll we'll get the hang of it.
So a buy limit order is actually said below the market.
So what you're anticipating is for the market to go down.
Todd shorter cross'd touch it and then go back up.
So you kind of anticipating a recoil you think that yes the market will go up.
But first it will go down.
And instead of entering right away.
So you could have entered back here with her buy order.
You want to get the most of this movement.
So you want to actually let the market go down a bit then enter with a buy order and then you'll get
this whole movement rather than getting only half of it.
Once the Red Cross happens over here your buyer limit is no longer by limit or it transforms automatically
into a buy order and you enter the market.
That's the point when you enter the market when the transaction occurs.
The opening of the Order a limit.
It's a very simple concept.
You are anticipating an upward movement before a downward movement.
So you think that the price will go up.
It will touchiest sell limit order trigger it and then go down.
Once again you would do this if you're anticipating an overall downward trend.
But you think they will first be some sort of retracement upwards and instead of entering the market
back over here with a sell order you want to get the full movement so you let the market go up first
.
Touch your sell limit order and then go down.
So in this case even if the market price crosses your sell limit order it will still be triggered as
a sell order.
So there's always these risks that the market will trigger you or sell them at or turn into or sell
order and then keep going upwards.
That can also happen and your settlement order will be triggered and you will be in the market.
And that's why you should still use stop loss and take profits with your limits and stop order.
So even if you sell them an order for example you can tell it's to set a stop loss and take profit off
course a stop loss would have to be about take profit would have to be below.
And it works exactly the same way because remember once the orders triggered it will either turn into
a buy order or a sell order and all the same rules apply as before.
So with your pending orders you can also set stop loss and take profit levels which will be triggered
with the order.
Meaning that since order turns into a buy or sell order that take profit and stop loss levels will be
activated and they will be protecting your order as they would with any other market or.
And to sum up how we've got our different order Klaas's different or tops and anticipated market movements
.
So the first two are the market orders they're the buy and the sell we for buy we would enter into a
buy when we anticipate an upward movement and to sell when we anticipate a downward trend.
And then for pending orders we would open a Buy stop or when we think the market will go up and then
it will continue going up.
So we kind of want to check this condition that the market will cross some sort of resistance line and
if that happens then only real ones are by stop order to become a byword sell stop similar.
We expect the market to go down and then keep going down by limit.
We expect the market to go down first a little bit and then go up and sell it.
We expect the market to go up and then go down.
So that's the summary for order types don't get to lever you for this course if you haven't yet.
I really appreciate that.
And I look forward to your next tutorial Until then happy trading.