Hello this is Kirill from Forex boat dot com.
And welcome back to the course in forex trading today is going to be a very exciting tutorial because
we're going to be talking about people notchy numbers and they involve a lot of mystery and we're going
to have a lot of fun and I can't wait to jump straight into it.
However before we do proceed I'd like to ask you to leave a review for this course.
I know I've already asked previously and if you have left to review then thank you very much.
But if you haven't lived through a few hours I really appreciate if you could spend less than a minute
of your time to just quickly review and rate the scores.
It can be done very simply you just have to on the course page click this button up here write a review
.
Then you just select the number of stars you think the course deserves and type interview if you want
to if you don't you're just like the number of stars click at a review and that's it.
It really helped me out and it would also assist other students in understanding whether this course
is worth their while before taking it.
So I hope you can do that.
And now let's proceed back to the course so Fibonacci levels.
So who is this person Fibonacci.
Well the real name of Fibonacci is actually Leonardo of Pisa. Fibonacci is kind of a nickname which
he got and most likely it meant a good son was born he lived in the 13th century and he's most famous
for his Fibonacci sequence.
So what is the supernature sequence.
Well let's imagine a sequence of numbers which starts with the number one.
The second number is also one and then going forward.
Every next number is equal to the sum of the previous two.
So the next number in this case would be a two.
The next number after that would be three because one plus to three the next number two plus three is
five.
The next number after that is an 8.
Let you guess what the next number would be.
That's right the next number is 13.
And so on just keeps going forever.
So what's so great about this supernature sequence that makes it famous.
I'll show you right now.
Let's quickly plot the number one in number two on a horizontal axis.
Now what we're going to do is we're going to go through the sequence and take every number of the sequence
and divided by the previous number in the sequence and plot our answer on the same axes.
So one divide by one is equal to 1.
We've plotted with an orange cross.
Now let's divide to buy one and we get two. Three divided by two is one and a half five to over three
is 1.6 x 6.
They divide by 5 is 1.6 thirteen divided by eight is one point sixty five.
21 divided by 13 is one point six on five.
So you kind of see where this is going.
The Crosses are getting closer and closer to one specific certain number and that number is 1.6 1 8
0 3 3 9 and so on.
And this number is known as the golden ratio which is usually represented by the Greek letter fee fee
is equal to approximately 1.6 when it.
All right so by now you're saying Carol you're boring me for this math.
What's what's the purpose.
What's the point.
Well let's have a look at some of the examples of where you can find the golden ratio that will probably
blow your mind.
First of all if you measure the distance between the edge of your fingertips and your wrist and then
you measure the distance between your wrist and your elbow it will be approximately 1.6 when it go ahead
.
Pause the video and give it a go.
You'll be surprised at how accurate this is.
Next your fingers actually your phalanges on your fingers actually are in the same ratio as the Fibonacci
numbers.
So 2 3 5 8.
If you don't believe this picture then here's an actual X-ray.
Also if you take any starfish and you measure its base and take as a one then the distance between these
two limbs will be 1.6 point 1 8.
Now if you want to get even more depth then we'll take the Fibonacci spiral and you can read about it
separately but it's basically constructed of the Bonacci numbers and you can find the people not just
spiral in many many places in the world for example a lot of our shelves are full of the same pattern
as Banaszak spiral.
Some galaxies not all of them but some spiral galaxies also fall the golden spiral pattern.
So it kind of makes you wonder how come the Fibonacci ratio can be seen in so many parts of nature.
Let's take one more example let's take the human DNA and if we measure its width and its length then
they will be exactly 21 Armstrong and 34 and so we're as strong as a unit of measurement for very little
things.
And if you recall 21 and 34 or are actually in our Fibonacci Sequence a coincidence maybe but that's
quite a lot of coincidences.
And moreover what's not a coincidence is that there have been experiments that have proven that figures
and patterns following the Fibonacci ratio are much more appealing to the human eye than those which
do not.
So there definitely is some sort of mystery on the Fibonacci numbers.
Nobody knows exactly why they're so common in nature and in the world.
But what we can do is maybe take advantage of it including in trading.
So what traders and analysts did well they said if you've been watching numbers are in our DNA and if
they're more appealing to the human eye and if they're all over nature let's have a look and see if
we can actually find them on for X charts.
So let's see what they found.
If this is a just a random 4 x chart then very often you'll find that if you measure the distance in
your Trents So the main parts of the upper part and then take it as one unit and then you measure the
distance that the price traveled during the retracement phase.
You will often notice that the retracement is equal to 0.6 1 h.
It's not the best part is that if you divide 1 by the golden ratio you will get 0.6 1 8.
So this basically means that if you take your original trend as 1.6 1 8 then your retracement will be
one.
So basically you see the golden ratio here will just return back to 0.6 1:08 which is the inverted coloration
.
So how can you use this in your trading.
Well let's assume that we don't know any of that.
We know that has been a trend and we can see a retracement is starting Well now knowing about the gold
ratio we can predict that with a good chance the retrenchment is actually going to go just exactly up
to that 0.6 1 8 level.
And that means we can enter into sell order some over there and we can enter into or buy order once
the retracement has completed.
Knowing that there a high chance that from here on the trend will continue.
So that's all theory but let's have a look at a live example.
This is the euro dollar for our the chart which I took a snapshot of yesterday.
As you can see here we've got a downward trend.
First of all and then we've got a bit of a retracement.
So how about we go ahead and measure them.
So the downward trend started up here then the price went down went down a bit slower went down fast
went down a bit when actually up again went down and that was the end of the trend for now.
Then the price started moving back up went down a bit and then went back up.
So we're going to measure the distance between those three points and those lines indicate where our
measurements will be.
So if we take the first the original trend we take it as one unit then you will notice and you can take
a ruler and measure this on your screen if you like or even open up the same chart and perform those
measurements.
You'll notice that retracement was exactly 0.6 1 8 and I didn't have to look for this example.
This was the first chart I opened up Eurodollar for all the time frame January 2015.
You can scroll through any charts you like.
And sooner or later actually sooner rather than later you'll find one of these examples.
So the golden ratio is very powerful not only nature but also in all forms trading.
And we can use it to advantage and you will see examples of this in our life for accelerating further
down in this course.
By the way if you're using military metaphor there's a very handy way to measure these retracement in
search for beracha retracement.
You'll get a very handy tool which allows you to effortlessly measure Fibonacci retracement.
On that note we'll finish up today's tutorial please do liever review if you haven't yet.
I'll really appreciate it and I'll look for it next time.
Until then happy trading