Hello this is Kirill from Forex boat dot com.
And welcome back to of course and for training today I've prepared a really exciting tutorial for you
.
We're going to be talking about indicators.
So let's jump straight into it.
So as you can remember we talked about that the price has four main elements the high the low the open
and the clothes.
So indicators are basically aggregators of these values.
So you have a stream of values of high open low clothes coming into a terminal all the time.
And what indicators do is they process these values to kind of give you a different perspective on the
market.
So let's have a look at a particular example here.
Got the price chart and say For answers we take the most the bar that's most to the right and we take
its high and then we take it slow and we subtract the high from the low.
Well that difference is called the true range.
It just basically indicates what the volatility or the amplitude of the market movement was for today
.
So that's good.
So that's one of the things that you can derive from price and that's that's an example of an indicator
because that value.
The true range is not actually given to you by default.
But you can derive it from these two values.
Next let's take the two range for the next bar.
And then the sex change for the bar after that and then we'll take one more range.
So what we're going to do all of these for true ranges is we'll take the average of these for ranges
and that will give us the average true range in the past four bars.
So that tells you not only how volatile the market was in the in the current day but also how volatile
the market was over the past four days on average because if you take one day you can have an anomaly
or some some news might've come out but when you average it out it tends to smooth out the facts and
therefore you see a representative picture of the markets.
So what we can do now is we can pluck this average to range on our chart.
So let's make some space will move up this chart a bit.
And at the bottom we'll have a new chart.
So let's plot this calculate average should range under the last bar.
So this little blue cross at the bottom or presents the hours sure arrange for the previous four bars
.
Next we'll continue like that and we'll take the average to arrange for the full bars before the current
one so excluding the current one.
What's the average range before that will plaudit as well.
Let's do that again.
Once more we've got four bars we've got the average sheer range plot plotted under the last of the four
bars.
We can do that again and again and so on.
We just keep going as far left as we want to and we get all these little cross at the bottom.
So now we're going to do is we're going to connect the crosses with a line and that's what it looks
like.
So now what we've actually constructed is the average true range indicator with a period of four.
You can actually take this find the syndicator and mentored or four and then drag it on to your chart
and you'll see exactly this picture.
And sometimes traders they're a bit scared of all these complicated indicators and they know they kind
of learn the names.
They learn what they represent for the market but they don't know the calculation.
Well this example shows that the calculations behind these indicators are very often very simple in
most cases they're very simple you just take the sum of the values from the open low high and close
you do something with them.
You take an average and you plug it on the chart.
So it's a very good idea to actually understand what's behind the indicators that you are using in your
trading and not not only what they mean but also how they're calculated.
So right now we know that this average range indicator tells us how volatile the market has been over
the past four days and to finish off today's tutorial Let's have a look.
Quick look at that was strange on a real chart in better shape or form.
So here's a chart which snapshot from Editor for and at the bottom we've got the average to arrange
with a period of 14.
That means that every single element in the average range represents the smoothed out true range of
the past 14 bars and that's has been changing and that tells you of the market volatility.
So right now you can see on the right the range is somewhere about average meaning the market is not
in its most volatile time.
And you can use that in your trading so maybe a trading strategy tells you that you are trying to avoid
volatile times because there are more they bring more uncertainty and you want to trade during less
volatile times.
Or maybe you want to try doing more volatile times and take big movements and big impulses.
So there's lots of indicators on the market.
They're all constructed differently.
Have a look around you'll definitely find some that you like some that you don't like in our trading
.
The one we will focus on is the moving average and we'll talk about that in next tutorial.
I look forward to seeing you then.
And until next time happy trading