Calculating risk.
So this tutorial flows on directly from the previous one.
And if you skipped the mathematics at the end of the previous tutorial then not a worry because right
now I will show you the result that we got in the first tutorial and will pick up from there.
So the result that we got was a pip value is always equal to last times 10 and is measured in units
of quoted currency.
What this means is that if your currency moves a certain number of pips and you have a transaction in
the market the time which is which has a volume of equal two lots were lots is the variable in our equation
then the value of every single Pip will be equal to the number of loss in your transaction times 10
.
And it will be measured in units of course currency.
So if you're trading the euro dollar and you're in the market with one lot then every time the currency
moves one pip in your favor you're earning 1 times 10 equals to 10 units of quoted currency.
And in this case the quoted currency is dollars.
So every time the currency moves in your favour you're earning ten dollars.
If you're in the market with a transaction with a volume of ten lots that every time the currency moves
in your favour you're earning $100.
So that's a very simple concept.
And this is a very powerful formula for you to remember and for you to use in your trading you can always
very quickly look at the chart.
Look at the number of lots that's a trader is currently in the market with and you can very quickly
say how much he's earning or losing at every single movement of the currency.
And let's remember here this is Pipp value so not points but pips and it's not going to change whether
it's a four digit or five digit broker.
It's always point 0 0 0 1.
Ok so now we're going to create an even more powerful formula out of this and will be very simple.
We're going to create a formula to calculate our risks on the forex market.
So let's look at a very intuitive formula.
This one this read formula is very straightforward and easy to understand.
So the risk which is on the left or the amount of money that we can lose in one transaction on a four
on the forex market is equal to the stop loss measured in pips.
So for example it's 50 pips that you have a stop loss times a pip value so the amount of money you lose
per every Pip.
So for example it's like in a previous case $10 per pill.
So if you stop losses 50 pips and Pip value is equal to $10 per Pip then you will potentially can potentially
lose $500 on this transaction if you stop losses triggered.
And that means in Forex that means that your risk is equal to $500.
So basically in this case risk is the maximum amount of money you can lose on this particular transaction
.
And let's remember here that this is all still in the units of code currency.
So that is a very simple formula that does not require derivation because it's just intuitive.
Now how about we put these two to four months ago we know that p values lots times 10.
And we also know that risk is stop loss and pips times value.
So let's take value from the first formula plugged into the second one let's see what we get we get
risk is equal to stop loss in pips times lots times 10.
That's quite interesting isn't it.
And now let's take it a step forward.
Let's from this formula derive what a lot.
Would equal to if we know a risk and stop loss and pips and that case loss is equal to risk divided
by the stop loss in pips times 10.
And all of this is measured in what risk in this case is measured in units of quarried currents.
So this is a formula that I'd like to stop our attention on or draw our attention to because this is
a very very important formula and we will be using throughout our life Forex trading in the further
tutorials.
What this formula tells us is if we know how much we can risk on a particular transaction we know that
we are.
We have a certain level of confidence in the market in our signals in our decision to buy or sell and
we know that in this particular transaction we would like or we're prepared to risk say for instance
$50.
And we also know where we want to sell our stop loss.
We know that based on our signals our supply just has to be set at the Senate level then from that we
can derive the amount of lots that we have to enter the market with.
So you only have to do is you take your risk the amount of money that you prepared to lose in a particular
transaction.
If if the market goes against you and you divide that by the number of Stop-Loss number of people in
your Stop-Loss multiplied by 10 and that will give you the amount of loss you should enter the market
with.
And that's very powerful because that's the way you control your risks.
It's wrong.
One trader first things aren't going to enter the market with one lot or ten lots or 0.5 lots.
You can't possibly think that way.
You should always first think how much you're prepared to lose if the market does go against you.
And that should be a function of your confidence and your trade confidence in your signals whether you're
trading with the trend or against trend and so on.
And then you have to also know where your trading system is telling you to set your stop loss.
And that's the exact order in which these things done.
A lot of traders get it wrong and the first think of all Also I'll trade with this amount of lots and
wish rest at my stop loss.
No you should first think of how much you you're willing to lose if everything goes against you then
where you're setting a Stop-Loss and then you'll get your loss using this for.
Now an important thing to remember is that risk in this case is calculated in units of quoted currency
.
So in a lot of cases when the American dollar is the quote currency and your account is in American
dollars then the quote currency will be the currency on your account and will be American dollars.
But if you're trading a currency pair where the quote currency is not American dollars remember that
you've you also have to convert your thinking you have to convert.
You'll be thinking of how much you're prepared to lose in your account balance currency which is most
likely American dollars.
And then you'll need to convert that to the quoted currency and then plug it into the formula.
I do have to admit that sometimes I forget it myself.
And further down in these tutorials you'll notice that when we're trading the Australian dollar the
Canadian dollar I did make that mistake and I didn't convert American dollars into Canadian dollars
before plugging to formula.
So maybe you can pick up on that mistake and see what the proper calculation should have been.
But it didn't make that much of a difference in that particular case because the Canadian dollar the
American dollar are currently quite close in terms of price.
However do remember this for future uses of formula make sure risk is entered in units of the quarter
currency.
So that's it for today's tutorial.
Next time we're going to plunge in straight into live trading and a real account.
I hope you're super excited because I definitely am and I look forward to seeing you then.
Until next time happy trading.