Hello this is Kirill from Forex boat dot com.
And welcome back to the course of forex trading today a good opportunity presented itself and we will
be conducting our second trade on our real live Forex account if we look down here in the current history
tab.
You can see the result of our previous trade which was a Eurodollar sell order which was a take profit
and brought us a total of 56 dollars and 19 cents profit.
So now if we move onto the trade tab you'll see that the current balance on the account is five hundred
fifty six dollars and 19 cents of real money which we will be using today to conduct our second real
Forex order.
So as you can see in the middle here I've got British pound dollar and 15 chart open and I've already
got some markings on this chart which will help us conduct our trade today.
So what I have here is first of all and most importantly is this moving average it's a simple moving
average.
And the period is 96.
So I'm just going to double click that and you can see here that the period is 96.
And the reason why I chose 96 is because there's 24 hours in a day and there's four and 15 bars in an
hour.
So if we take 24 and we multiplied by four we'll get 96.
So that means 96 of these bars of these 15 bars actually represent one full day and it's always good
to have these reference points.
So you could use a 100 and it would look pretty much similar but 96 has an actual meaning behind it
.
It means that you're averaging your price at a daily kind of a rolling rate for daily rolling average
and that that's a good thing to just keep in mind so that you use it you use multiples for your moving
averages next.
So what we can see here is that back over here a couple of days ago the price crossed the moving average
downwards and this is something that using the moving average in trading is something we discussed previously
in the previous section of the course.
And just to give you a quick refresh what we see here is that the price crossed the moving average downwards
and it just kept tumbling down.
Then the price crossed the moving average upwards.
It was concern for a while but then it shut up and went really high and there's a significant movement
.
So that's exactly what we'll be expecting this time.
The price has just crossed the moving average downwards.
And there's a bit of movement downwards and there's now there's a bit of uncertainty but hopefully because
the prices below the moving average it will continue tumbling down.
Of course a situation like this can occur where there's a lot of uncertainty and the price just keeps
moving around moving average and this is a flat flat market.
However there are other factors on our side that kind of say that's probably the price will actually
move downwards that confirm our point of view.
So and those factors are one of the main factors is that if we zoom out and we go to for instance the
hourly chart you will see that the price is in a downward trend.
The British pound dollar is in overall downward trend so we're actually going to go to the daily chart
over here.
If I zoom in a bit back zoom back in.
You can see that the British pound dollars and downward trend and I've even highlighted this channel
over here so just ignore the moving average for now because it's a different moving average now on a
different time frame.
So on the daily timeframe you can see that the price is in a downward trend.
And I've highlighted this channel that the price is currently in.
And as you can see it's bounced off the borders of the channel a couple of times and now the price has
come to the top border of the channel again.
And that signals to us that probably it's going to bounce backwards.
So a very good confirmation from a higher timeframe.
That means that we are in a downward trend and there is pressure from the market to push this price
further down.
And that's not something that you usually do usually use lower timeframes to confirm higher timeframes
but it's also good to reference these things when you're trading on low timeframes.
It's always good to trend a trade in line with the overall trend and see what else is going on on the
other timeframes as well.
So we've got some good indication that probably the price is going to go down.
I have already chosen the take profit and stop loss and the stop loss.
We usually said just above the channel level and we've also got some quite strong resistance levels
over here as you can see the price was very uncertain around this level around 1.5 7.
Three hundred and 1.5 7 400.
So as long as we said it above over there we should be in the safe zone to take profits.
Well we basically kind of look at a strong level over here.
This looks like a strong area so if the price does get here it's to around one point five six five hundred
.
It might kind of slow down so we'll settle take profit conservatively just above that area and hopefully
if the price does turn around that it will first hit our take profit.
So that's the main bit.
Also because this isn't a very
solid kind of analysis it is it is in our favor.
We there's a high chance that the price will go down.
However it's not as strong as we had in our previous trades so in this case we would want to trade a
bit more conservatively so that we won't risk 10 percent of our.
Let's say for instance we'll risk 5 percent of our count to be a bit more conservative.
And the last thing that we have to do is check the volume or calculate the lots for this trade and for
that we will need pips of the Stop-Loss as you remember.
So currently the Stop-Loss will be set at about 38 pips.
So let's remember that when we're calculating the volume now to calculate the volume I'll bring up the
slides from one of the previous tutorials that we were already familiar with.
All right so not to calculate the volume of loss that we want to trade in this particular instance.
We've got to take the risk in dollar terms so the amount of money that we're prepared to lose on this
one particular trade and divide it by 10 times the number of people in the stop loss.
So the risk as we discussed will be setting at about 5 percent of our balance which is 5 percent of
556 dollars and that equals to twenty eight dollars.
Put that into the equation.
Now we've got a last name we got to input is a stop loss in pips and that's about 38 pips.
So let's put that now.
And so that gives us let's bring up the calculator.
Twenty eight divided by loops divided by ten times 30 a.
And you get us about zero point zero seven.
So let's put that in there.
Point 0 7
lots.
All right.
Perfect So now we know what our volume is.
We can go on ahead with our trade.
Click this button up over here.
New Order.
We're going to put in our lots right away so 0.07 stop loss as we agreed will be one point five seven
six hundred take.
Profit will be 1.5 6 6 5 0 Calment is second order.
Instant execution.
It will be a sell order so.
All set.
Everything's entered and we click sell out our sell order has been conducted 0.07 lots.
We can close this now.
And as you can see here our order is in our terminal in the trade tab.
So we're going to leave this order for a couple days and then come back and see how it's going.
Hopefully won't take long because this is a 15 minute timeframe and we're talking about movements of
about 55 people and 38 pips.
So hopefully the market does go downwards.
In this case and we'll catch up again in a couple of days to analyze this trade.
I look forward to seeing you then and until next time happy trading