Hello this is Kirill from Forex boat dot com.
And welcome back to a course on forex trading in today's tutorial we will be conducting our fourth live
trade on a real Forex account.
So as you can see here down at the bottom we've got our three profitable trades that we've had so far
and that have brought us a harder and dollars and 20 cents and currently on this account I have six
hundred and nineteen dollars and twenty cents of available funds.
So today we'll be looking at those trillion dollar American dollar hourly timeframe.
And here we will be investigating a very interesting formation which we have not talked about yet.
So this is a Gartley and person Vento harmonic patter.
And before we go into detail on this particular formation I just wanted to show you how you can read
a bit more about the step parents.
So if you go to Google and you type in harmonic patterns and then you go for it will go for the images
just to see them you can find a lot about these harmonic patterns.
And for instance here is a good summary of the six harmonic patterns the crab the butterfly the bat
the Gartley pattern the three drives Paran a BCT pattern.
So if you scroll down here you'll see that there's a lot of examples as a lot of analytics around them
there's lots of good explanations.
So in this particular case the turnaround we're going to go looking at is the butterfly the Gartley
butterfly pattern.
HARMAN Harmonix Perens a very interesting and they're based on Fibonacci numbers so there's a lot of
mystery around them.
I used to try them quite a lot back in the day.
You can write a whole course about harmonic patterns and that's why we won't go into too much detail
about them in general.
However today we will look at the butterfly because we are working with it.
So what you're looking for in harmonic patterns is either a kind of shape or kind information in the
form of the letter W for a cell or in the form of a letter M for a buy.
In this case we have a very very well pronounced garkey butterfly.
And the W formation is kind of just something to get your attention but that's not actually enough to
for or for a formation to be a harmonic pattern the word harmonic implies that they are Fibonacci numbers
and ball somewhere.
So how or how the numbers involved in this case.
So if we take the Fibonacci retracement up over here and then we drag them onto the very first movement
in this formation.
So we drag them here and then we move back.
You will see that this line sixty one point eight percent happens to fall exactly where the retracement
the second movement.
And so that's why marks at six to 1.8 percent here.
So that's no coincidence.
This is a downward trend the retracement sixty one point eight percent and that is if Banaszak phenomenon
call that if you will or is just a harmonic movement.
So but the interesting thing about 30 percent parents is that there's multiple ratios like this in one
parent.
And for instance if we keep expanding this to the right you will see that the last movement over here
the fourth movement was exactly a hundred and twenty seven point two percent of the original movement
here at the start.
And these two things happened at the same time.
So how do we get a hundred and twenty seven point two from the Fibonacci ratio.
Well if we bring up the calculator and type in one point 6 1 8 and take the square root of that there
you'll see that the square root of 1.6 1A is actually exactly 1 point 2 7 2.
And that again is not a coincidence.
That is where all the mystery comes in.
Nobody actually knows why markets move like that.
Why is it exactly sixty one point eight percent here and was exactly 127 point two percent here.
In fact this ratio can be a bit different.
Could be it can be the four hundred sixty one point eight percent can be another Hermana aggression
but the fact is that there are harmonic ratios involved multiple times in these formations regardless
of the fact that nobody knows why that happens you can still take advantage of them and use them as
strong signals for you to enter the market.
So in this instance we have a strong cell signal.
Oh by the way before we move on I just wanted to show you that in your Fibonacci properties if you ever
want to add a level like for example a hundred twenty seven point two is not a default level you just
click the levels tab and you click ADD and you can just add a new level of it here so that's pretty
simple.
OK moving back to our Paran we've got this pattern ready to fire.
And one more thing that it actually gives you is it gives you targets.
So fibonacci garkey patterns they actually give you targets which is such a take profit Stop-Loss which
is very convenient at times.
So the way you set the take profit is you take this last movement you drag another notch retracement
onto it and then you look where you have the once.
Point one sixty one point eight low.
And that's probably where the prizes are going to go up to.
Statistically it happens that way most of the time more often than not anyway.
So you might want to set the take profit here but in our case we have a very strong support level zero
point eight which the price was 0.18 actually which the price has not been able to surpass two times
already.
So it is quite a strong bet that we will go through this level and that's strong enough already so that's
why I wanted to set the take profit a bit closer a bit higher up because there's another level over
here which is zero point seventy nine which just happens to be on the one point sixty one 106 one point
eight line or just above it.
So I wanted to be above this other support line.
So if we do break the zero point eighty level then we don't have to worry about the 0.17 line level
.
So that's how you kind of establish just such a take profit is either at 160 1.8 percentage or hundred
twenty seven point two if you like.
I'm sitting over here somewhere in between.
Stop-Loss Well kind of similar similar thing.
If you drag the original three Banaji retracement the stop loss kind of it's good to set it above the
160 1.8 because this acts as the resistance line.
Also we've got a strong level here which is zero point eighty three.
And as you can see over here Zero Point 83 was a strong resistance line.
It's also a psychological level as well.
So it's good to protect our supply in that way.
Finally if we zoom out a little bit you will see that we are where we were in a downward trend.
And so there is a more kind of evidence or support for us to say that the trend will continue in that
direction which is good.
It's always good to trade in line with the overall.
So right now we're all ready to set our order.
And the last thing that we want to do right now is going to probably delete these Bonacci lines.
Last thing I want to do is we need to measure our Stop-Loss because we will need that for the risk calculation
.
So right now there's about a hundred ninety five pips in the stop loss.
Let's remember that number and move on to calculation calculating our lots.
All right so you get a lot.
We have to take the risk in dollar terms and divide by 10 tenth the number of pips and our stop loss
because this is quite a risky trade.
We're trying to break the zero point eight level.
I would rather go a bit more conservative here and that's why we would take about 5 percent of our balance
as opposed to the temps that we sometimes take 5 percent of six hundred nineteen point twenty years
dollars.
Thirty one years dollars.
Let's plug that into the formula.
And so the last thing that we have left to do is to type in our Stop-Loss and pips which is 195.
So let's calculate all of this
31 divided by ten times hundred ninety five.
This is a buzzer point 0 1 5 8.
So you can run this up either down or up.
I'll roll it up.
In this particular instance and that will give us zero point zero two points or two loss.
All right.
That means that we're ready to set our order now.
So now I'm going to click the new order button up the top here.
This will bring up the new order screen.
I'll just zoom out a bit so you can see everything at the same time.
All right so our lots are 0.02 Stop-Loss there a point 0.8 3 5 0.
Take profit is 0.7 9 5 0 comments.
Let's call this
fourth order.
We'll call this Gartley butterfly doesn't fit.
Just call it Gartley butterfly.
And at the start it's a number.
All right.
So now we're going to just quickly check that everything is correct and we're going to sell.
Perfect.
So there is also order over here and it's all in the market.
We just have to wait for the price to hopefully go in our direction.
All right so we'll leave this order alone for a couple of days and I look forward to seeing you on the
next tutorial.
Until then happy trading