Good morning and welcome back and congratulations as you can see the euro dollar shot through the top
border of the triangle triggered by start converting into a buy order and here out take profit at the
top.
So that's a fantastic result.
And I just love seeing these things in the morning when I wake up.
When you leave a trade overnight and even a pending order and you wake up and it's turned into profit
it's just a fantastic feeling.
OK so let's just drag this onto the chart and see how it went here.
You can even really see it because it happened all so quickly within the space of one hour so that's
where we entered into the market that's where I'll buy stop order was triggered and converted into a
buy order and then it the price kept going up and triggered our take profit and we got our revenue.
So that's a great result.
And if we look down here you'll see that the Buy Stop order was changed to buy order.
So this by stop order that has nothing to do with it.
That's the one where the lot size was incorrect and we deleted it.
So here all by stop order was triggered and changed into by order and then the profit was reached and
we got our profit of $13 and 64 cents.
Now that doesn't sound like a lot but let's put that into perspective.
Thirteen dollars and 64 cents represents approximately 2 percent of the balance that we had at the time
.
So we earn 2 percent in the space of several hours.
That's incredible when you think that banks will only offer you a couple of percent maybe four or five
percent maximum on your savings deposit for a year.
That's four or five percent in a year whereas here we were able to make 2 percent in just the space
of a few hours.
So I'll let you think about that.
What are we going to do now is an important bit.
And we have to close or delete our pending sell stop orders so as you can see the market is going upward
.
So this order has become obsolete.
The sell stop and we need to get rid of it because yes it will automatically expire sometime later today
.
However we don't want to risk just keeping it in the market because the price might still go down and
trigger it and that's not part of our strategy.
So let's go ahead and do that.
We'll go to the trade tab and we've got the sell stop order here.
All we have to do is double click the order this window pops up and all we have to do is simply click
delete and that's done.
Now if we go back to our account history you'll see that we've got the sell stop order here.
Now the orders are all ranked by their order number if you want to rank them by the time when you close
them just cook time and your cell stop order will be right at the bottom over here because we did close
at last.
All right so that's all for today.
Just to sum up in the Prius tutorial in this tutorial we saw how to use Buy Stop and sell stop orders
which was important we know we learn how to modify them how to delete them and just generally how to
use them in combination to create this kind of burst out strategy.
And also we worked with the triangle a very simple yet powerful feature on the forex market.
A good take away from yesterday's analysis was that if you see consistent behavior in the market that
the market is recognizing for instance triangle patterns and one triangled burst out and then another
burst out and now you see a third triangle forming then is a good chance that this triangle will work
too.
So a better chance than if it's just the first triangle you see on the chart.
And that applies across all types of figures or all types of indicators that you might be using a market
and that just means that the market is in that type of phase.
And all of the participants are also looking for those same patterns or figures or indicators.
I'll leave it at that.
We had a great trade and now it's time to move on with the day.
By the way if you haven't yet through review please do.
Adrea like to know what you think about the scores.
I look forward to seeing our next tutorial and until then happy trading