[Autogenerated] Hi, This is Greg Golightly,
and welcome to designing for Advanced Security within a W s
securing and managing your AWS account.
This course builds on concepts introduced in the
designing for complexity on AWS course.
So if you haven't watched that course yet and don't understand something,
you may want to pause.
Watch that course, then come back.
We're going to cover what makes the root user unique and how to
secure the root user in your AWS account will also discuss different
ways to secure access to your accounts,
including policies and other tools for limiting.
I am user access.
Additional ways to secure roles and how to use the permissions boundary
feature finally will discuss how to manage sandbox accounts in your AWS
organization and some benefits to using them.
When you create an AWS account, you start out with a single root user.
The root user has complete access to all AWS services,
and resource is in the account because it is so powerful you
need to take steps to lock down your route.
User.
Let's go through those recommended steps,
then talk about some things that only the root user can do do and how you
can actually limit the root user with service control policies instead of
using the root user for administrative tasks.
Create an I am username has administrative privileges.
It's recommended that you use I am groups To assign permissions.
Simply create an administrator's group with the appropriate permissions.
Then assign the I Am username group.
Next, delete your root access keys.
This goes back to using an I am user to administer your account.
Except for those things that only a root user can do do,
activate multi factor authentication on your route account.
This is a simple but important step to add a layer of security to your account.
You can use a virtual or physical MF a device Finally,
ensure that the root user has a strong, randomly generated password.
At least 20 characters in length.
You should also be using a secrets manager to generate and secure the
password and limit who has access to the root account.
There are a few account actions that can only be performed by the root username.
Any of these are one time actions or things you may not ever do,
but I wanted to give you an idea of when you would have to
use the root user to perform an action.
If in action isn't working as an I am administrator,
double check the documentation to see if what you
want to do requires the root user.
If you've enabled A W s organizations and service control policies,
it's possible that for a given member account in the organization,
the root user could have limited permissions.
Recall that actions that error not listed in an SCP are implicitly
denied and that S E P s can also explicitly deny actions which will
prevent them from happening under any circumstance.
If you're leveraging AWS organizations to manage several AWS accounts,
the root user of each account should still be locked down
following the recommended steps we discussed earlier.
But setting up guard rails with service control policies for each
account according to how you are going to use the account can further
limit the possible actions for any user,
including the root user.
So even if the root user was compromised,
any possible actions would be limited by the service control policy.
The other thing to be aware of when using A W s organizations
is that any I am users in the master account that have
permissions to change settings in AWS,
organizations need to be locked down as those users could attach and detach
S C P s from member accounts and organizational units or move member
accounts from one organizational unit to another,
thus affecting the permissions for that account.
Only a few trusted I am administrative users should have access
to the master account of the organization.
The rest of the I am users can be created and managed from a
member account in the organization to reduce the risk of compromise in the master account.