[Autogenerated] Hi.
This is Craig Google lightly,
and welcome to protecting your account and applications.
We're going to look into A W s web application,
firewall or Ralf and how you can use it to protect your web
applications from common web exploits.
A.
W s Shield managed distributed denial of service or DDOS protection,
including the differences between Standard and Advanced and AWS Guard Duty,
which provides intelligent threat detection and continuous monitoring
for malicious activity and unauthorized behavior.
AWS web application,
firewall or WAFT allows you to filter traffic with rules
based on any part of the web request.
You can use managed rules,
which are designed to protect against common threats and are
automatically updated as new issues emerge.
You can use waft with cloudfront application load balancers or API gateway.
There is no up front cost,
and you pay based on the number of rules you deploy and how
many requests your application receives.
So what types of properties can do AWS web application
firewall used to filter you can filter by i p address or
country and other values in the request.
Like HTTP headers and body, you are I strings and length of request.
You can also detect any included SQL code and filter on that
to avoid SQL injection attacks as well as any scripts that
error present in the request,
which may indicate a cross site scripting attack for each rule,
you will specify an action to take based on whether the
request matches the statements in the rule.
You can allow the request to go through, block the request or count the request.
Counting is a good way to test if your rules are behaving as expected
and can be leveraged for limiting or denying access.
After a certain number of matching requests over a period of time,
let's take a look at the building blocks of laugh.
First, you have a rule.
This will contain one or more of the conditions we discussed earlier.
Next,
you can add one or more rules to a rule group to more
easily manage and sequence related rules.
If you have certain rejects patterns or I P addresses you need to re use,
those can also be placed in sets and used in rules.
Finally, you'll create a web A C L and add rules and rule groups.
The web A C L is what will actually be attached to a
resource like a cloudfront distribution.
API, gateway, API or application load balancer.
A W S maintains several managed rule sets that error
available for use at no additional charge.
You can simply add these to your web.
A C L AWS Marketplace has additional managed rule sets that error
maintained by third parties and contained waft rules that have been
configured for certain applications or software systems to cover things
like a WASP Top 10 vulnerabilities list.
You can go to marketplace, browse rules,
then subscribe to those you want to use.
You'll be charged a monthly subscription,
plus a per request amount based on your volume.
You can cancel it any time in your subscription will be
pro rated to what you actually used.
We're not going to get into the details of AWS firewall manager in this course,
but I wanted to mention that you can use it to centrally configure and
manage waft rules across counts and resource is which can be very
helpful if you're using A W s organizations. For more details, check out the documentation for AWS firewall manager