[Autogenerated] Let's take a look at some I am policies in
action that use conditions to limit actions,
not action,
to limit the effects of a deny and black list and white list
approaches to policy writing Here is a policy that denies all
actions on all resource is without conditions.
This policy would effectively not allow anything at all.
However,
the condition checks the AWS requested region and compares string
not equals to us West to So what this policy is doing is denying all
actions where the requested region does not equal us west to Let's
take a look at this in action.
I've created a role that allows administrator access and
also has this deny policy attached as well.
Let's try looking at an E C two instance,
Notice that I can see the instances that error running
because I am in the US West to region.
If I change regions now, I get a permissions error.
All actions that error not in the US West to region are denied.
Let's take a look at adding a not action to limit these effects of the deny.
I'll go back to my administrator user and take a look at this policy.
This policy is similar to the last one in that it is denying all resource
is where the requested region does not equal us West to,
however, in this one instead of action.
SQL Star We have not action as e c.
Two star.
The not action excludes everything listed in the
not action element in this case, all to operations from the deny effect,
coupled with the other policy that allows all actions.
This will allow us to perform E C two actions in any region.
Again,
I've created a role with this policy and the administrative
policy now we can go to easy to and we no longer get an error
when we're in different regions.
Let's take a look at a blacklist and white list.
Example in this policy, instead of allowing all easy to actions,
were only allowing E.
C to describe actions.
This particular policy has no additional conditions.
Let's take a look at this one in action again.
I've created a role with only this policy,
since there isn't a region restriction,
I can perform describes in whatever region I choose.
However, if I were to try to launch an instance,
I don't have permissions to do that,
recall that only easy to describe actions were allowed.
So if I try to go to a different service like S3, I'll get a permission error.
Let's take a look at the blacklist example in this policy.
One statement allows all easy to actions on.
All resource is.
Then we have another statement that denies to specific actions E.
C.
To terminate instances and easy to delete tags.
This is a way to implement a blacklist.
You allow everything except a few select actions that
you don't want the user to take.
Let's take a look at a running instance.
If I try to delete a tag, I get a permission error.
The same thing will happen if I try to terminate an instance.
Those two specific actions have been denied from the permissions.
I could stop the instance or any other easy to action. Just not terminate instantiate or delete tags