[Autogenerated] a permissions boundary allows you to create a policy that
defines the maximum allowed access for a user or roll.
This enables you to grant certain users the ability to create other
users and roles while limiting the actual permissions.
They congrats to the users or roles they create.
One use case is allowing developers to create their own roles
for Lambda or Easy to without having to micromanage every
single role they need to create.
The I am administrator can create a permissions boundary that
limits what actions can be effectively granted by any user or
roll the developer creates.
Even if the developer creates a role with administrator access,
the role would be limited by the permissions boundary.
It wouldn't actually have administrator access because the permissions
boundary limit S3 effective permissions of the role.
Like a service control policy,
a permissions boundary does not grant any permissions by itself.
It only limits what can be granted to the user or role
that has the permissions boundary.
Let's go through a sample workflow for using a permissions
boundary as an I am administrator will create a policy that
will act as a permissions boundary.
This policy defines the maximum boundary.
You want to allow a particular user to be able to grant.
Next will allow on.
I am user to create an attached roles as long as they use the
permissions boundary as the I am username,
create a new role and see that we must set the permissions
boundary in order to attach the role.
Then we'll see how the permissions boundary restricts the effective actions.
No matter what the role may have granted,
Here's the policy that will use for the permissions boundary.
It only allows E C two and S3 actions in the US West to region.
We'll need the RN of this policy in order to create the policy
to require this as a permission boundary.
Next will create an I am policy for the user that we're going to allow to
create roles as long as they contain the permissions boundary.
We'll add the RN for the permissions boundary policy that we just created.
Remember this will restrict the allowed permissions to S3 and E C two actions.
The user will also need certain I am actions in order to create rolls in.
I am note that they will not be able to change policies for their own username.
Next, we're going to deny certain policies for the Dev Boundary policy.
This will prevent the user from changing the permissions.
Boundary policy that's being set up by the I am administrator
finally will deny the delete user permission.
Boundary action will save this policy and attach it to the user.
Let's go to our user.
Note that we've attached the permissions for Dev
one policy that we just created.
Let's log in with the Dev one User to create a role.
Now I'm logged in as the Dev one user.
Let's create a role.
It will be for this AWS account, so I'll put in the account number.
Suppose this user just selected administrator access because they
weren't sure which policy they needed to grant,
even though this violates the principle of least privilege.
Oftentimes it's what people use because it works normally.
This would give permissions to everything in the account.
Let's see how the permissions boundary helps us out with this.
Notice how we got an error when we tried to create the role.
It's because we did not attach the required permissions boundary.
If we go back,
we'll set the permissions boundary using the policy
that's required by our administrator.
Remember, the Dev Boundary policy only allows easy to and S3 actions.
Now the role has successfully been created.
We can see that the administrator access policy has been added.
Let's go assume this role as a user and see if we can
really do all of the administrator actions.
We'll assume the role that was just created.
We'll give it a display name.
Limited admin we can See that we've assumed the role of limited admin.
Let's check out S3.
Everything looks good here and we'll try Easy to if
we switch regions to us West one.
Notice how we get an error.
The permissions boundary only allows S3 and E C two in the US West to region.
If we try to access other services, even though we're in the US West to,
we'll get a permissions error.
Permissions.
Boundaries are an extremely good tool for allowing users to
administer certain things in I am while still making sure that
they don't grant too many permissions for services that they don't need or not authorized to use.