[Autogenerated] an AWS account is one of the strongest physical and
logical perimeters you can have around your resource is.
You may have felt hesitation creating sandbox accounts in the past,
because instead of creating a member account as part of an AWS
organization with a single payer account,
you were spinning up in entirely separate account,
complete with billing information and full access to everything as a root user.
Creating member accounts in your AWS organization is a much faster and more
secure way to create temporary disposable sandbox accounts.
Some advantages include isolation, innovation, accountability and oversight.
First isolation.
If a developer or other team member is in their own account,
they're not going to accidentally delete production or other resource is that
another person or team is working on second innovation.
When you don't have to worry about messing something up,
your more likely to experiment,
make mistakes and quickly iterate to solve a problem.
This type of exploration is highly effective because you can
actually observe things working or not working.
Third accountability.
If only one user has access to an account and they leave a bunch of
services running over the weekend that didn't need to run.
There's a pretty clear path to the responsible party.
There's no question about who is using the resource is or who to
ask if there are questions about account activity or adjustments
that need to be made regularly.
Deleting and creating sandbox accounts helps eliminate zombie resource is and
can encourage more thoughtful cloud spend when each user sees the breakdown of
costs associated with their sandbox accounts.
Fourth oversight.
When you create a sandbox account,
you can utilize service control policies to limit available actions in the
account to what the user will actually be working on and ensure any
security or compliance measures used in the account.
Stay in place.
You can set a budget to alert at a low threshold to make
sure there are no unexpected costs,
and you can create a role to give a user access to
their sandbox account and time box.
How long they have access to that role.
This can help you regularly delete sandbox accounts and create new ones to
ensure resource is allocated are relevant and necessary.
Just as Cloud computing has given us a much more fluid view
of resource is compared to buying and provisioning our own
hardware in a data center.
Cloud accounts could be just as fluid.
Now you can secure your root user and other users in your master account
and use a variety of items to manage your I am users,
including policies, multi factor authentication and permissions boundary.
You can also add an external IDE to further secure your roles,
and you can create sandbox accounts in your A.
W s organization for greater isolation, innovation,
accountability and oversight of your AWS resources.
Next,
we're going to talk about managing keys and
certificates using AWS Key management Service, Cloudhsm and Amazon Certificate manager.