Hello and welcome back to the course and party in this Tauriel we're starting off the first main section
where we will learn a lot about Parbat.
We're going to learn the foundations of this tool and we're going to lay the groundwork for the rest
of this course.
Answer.
Well we are going to learn a lot of theory and learn how the tool works how to navigate it and how to
use it.
At the same time it is going to be an exciting section because we're going to be solving a real world
business challenge.
So let's go ahead and find out more about the challenge that we're going to be tasked to do.
All right.
So here is the challenge.
His end of financial year and that means it's time for annual bonuses.
The store operates in three regions and only the top performing employees each region qualifies for
bonus.
Find out which three employees are eligible to get bonuses for this year.
Employees are measured on total sales in dollar terms and you can get the data set here.
So all of the data sets for this course are available at WDW super days designs that them slash power
be-I one word.
So let's go ahead and go to that page.
There is super data centers of course power be-I.
If you scroll down you'll see Section 2.
Your first bar chart in power be-I and this section will learn how to work with GSV files.
So go ahead and download this file.
And once the file has been downloaded this means the end for this tutorial because all we needed to
do is get familiar of the challenge and download the file and we're going to learn how to connect to
this file in the next tutorial.
And I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy Analise.