Hello and welcome back to the course and party.
Today we're going to explore custom visuals in a park and we're going to learn how to install them into
our software on our desktop as well.
So we've said that we need to go to is app daughter Parvi dot com slash visuals.
You can also find it quicker if you just go to Google and search for Barbie visuals or custom visuals.
And then this will be one of the top few links.
So here you can find all these amazing custom installations that are not by default present or prepackaged
in your power be-I So here is that here you can see a lot of his positions and they're very colorful
there.
Even the little thumbnail is very descriptive as well so you've got bubble charts here which are present
not by default Imparja But so you can get them here.
I got word clouds you've got Sancti diagrams you've got dial gauges Mukoko I've never actually used
to make a chart never got box and wiskers you got network navigations.
So just looking at most like the most popular ones I guess the bricks shard both Tyche are liquid filled
which is quite a fun way of demonstrating KPI as you got stars.
What else do we have here.
This is a critical one force directed graph.
That's that's good.
So like let's just have a look at a couple of them here once you click on the one you like.
You've got an option to download the visual or you can download a sample download the visual is like
a plug into your power be-I and it actually installs that Israel into your Parbat.
A sample is a sample Part B or workbook that already has a plug in installed and it also has some examples
of how to use it.
So go ahead and look this.
All right so as you can see it's it's loaded and it's it's like a dynamic type of his possession and
this position is called School Frenzel.
Assuming that it's showing who's friends with who at a school.
So you can see here some people are friends with them.
Which other nobody else.
And like that.
So yes the size represents the number of friends that person has.
And then you could just grab any one of these and you can drag it around and then just fall back into
place or somewhere nearby.
So this is pretty cool as fun to play around with.
And I think one of the kind of dominant places or visualization tools that creates these really well
is D-3 So the javascript language D-3 there a session package and so there they're done really well
but this is also a good implementation as well.
The Road We've got company communications right so i guess who's this probably who is who's boss or
something that's pretty cool.
Pretty fun to play around with.
And here they've got one which demonstrates all the features so they actually can have little icons
at the ends.
And so you can also put arrows you can change the width and so on.
And then they also give you some hints.
And so you can see here now you've got this force directed graph appeared in your Weasel's.
So that's kind of like how the plugin is installed.
And then you can also use it for your Alsatians if you prefer to do so.
All right.
So just as a normal visualizations we just click it it appears and then you drag some you drag some
like Jack some dimensions or measures into it and then you get the result they go.
So it's as simple as that.
We're not going to say this because we don't need a force directed graph.
There's just an example of how to download and look at a sample.
The one we're going to be using for all of Weasel's election purposes is a chord diagram and they are
very interesting and very powerful as well so we're going to learn how to use the core diagram.
Let's go ahead and download it.
And this time instead of downloading the sample download the visual writes a hearing to agree if you
agree to the terms and once you've downloaded the visual you just need to copy it into your folder where
you are performing or all of your analysis for this section and then so then bring up part B.
So this is the same work that we've loaded the data in.
So the euro debt crisis.
And now let's go ahead and just install.
So here click the import from file import a custom visual click Import and here select the file that
you just downloaded.
OK.
And there you go.
The file is ready or the insulation is ready.
So it's as simple as that.
We've installed the power vi chord chart into our software and we can now proceed to use it and we'll
continue with this in the next tutorial and until next I'm happy analyzing.