Hello and welcome back to the course and RBI appears to Tauriel We connected to our dataset.
And today we're going to visualize our time series data.
But before we proceed with that I would like to promise you to save your workbook.
And why is that.
Well because saving your work at the very start before you actually start creating your position is
a good habit to get into and working in tools such as power.
Because that way you can as you create it Zaleski you can simply press Kontrol s and it'll save your
progress and you won't lose any anything if your computer crashes or power be-I crashes for some reason.
So let's go ahead and do that.
We're going to select the dropdown here select Save As or just press control s on the keyboard and select
where you want to save it.
And the name and click save.
All right.
That's done.
So now we can proceed safely to creating of isolation and what are we visualizing.
Well we're visualizing unemployment or long term unemployment in the U.S. from 2005 to 2015 and we already
discussed this dataset.
We've got the period here so that's our time series then we've got the different categories of gender.
And we've got the different age groups and here we actually have unemployed.
So let's go ahead and see how we can visualize this.
First thing we're going to take period of dragons the charts and going to unemployed and drag it into
the chart as well as you can see part II has come up with a bar chart by default for us.
Now we're going to change this to a line chart.
So it's like chart over here and now we have a line chart for unemployed or long term unemployment in
the U.S. for years and how does it.
And as you can see for every year we've got a separate point on this chart.
And what's happened is all of the rows for that specific year have been aggregated or have been summed
up into this specific points of 2010.
That sum of all the unemployed values in the unemployed column for the roles that are for 2010.
And that's the same thing for 2008 and so on.
Now today we're going to discuss the two ways you can deal with time series in Parbat and we've actually
already talked about the previous year and this will be a good refresher but also really highlight the
differences between the two approaches and from UPSs Tauriel you will know exactly which approach you
need to use in which scenario.
All right.
So let's go ahead and Gossard the first approach is the show next level so we wanted basically what
do we want to achieve you want to drill into our data set and we want to understand if there are any
patterns and trends and so on.
So how do we drill it.
Well actually this three approaches there's three ways to drill it.
Got the drill down button but the drill down bottom just shows us individual drills into specifically
into individual records in our dataset.
That's not exactly what we want.
We still want to see more detail but we still want to see the bigger picture at the same time when we
have that bird's eye view.
So we're left with two options.
We've got the show next level and the expand next level.
Now we're going to start with the show next level.
When I click shown next level as you recall what happens is we were going to go down in our hierarchy
here so we've got your quarter month in day right now.
We're at the third level.
When you click Show next level we're going to go to the quarter level and we're going to disregard the
year level completely.
Let's have a look.
So when I click that as you can see we have gone down to the quarter level.
And bear in mind the excess here the waxes doesn't start at zero so that's why we're kind of like you
can see really how the charge is changing.
It actually starts 110 million.
So what's happened here.
Right now we only have four quarters.
And why is that.
Well because you'd expect that you'd have more right.
We have about 11 years or just over 10 years in our dataset and every year has four quarters so we should
have over 40 quarters over 40 points on this dataset right now.
But because we are disregarding the higher level and higher Harkee year level we're just going down
to the core level what we're doing is we're actually treating this access or this this variable quarter
not as a time series but rather as a categorical variable.
So in this case so we have these four buckets quarter one quarter to quarter three quarter four and
out of our data set.
What we're doing is we're picking out every single checking every so is this row quarter one or quarter
two or three or quarter for regardless of the year.
This was quarter 1 or I put in the quarter one bucket this was Koro on put in the quarter one bucket
quarter one then this one is already quarter to put on the court to bucket and so on.
So every roll goes into one of these buckets irrespective of the year.
And it's very similar approach to what you would have with gender right.
Of Gendry you'd also just basically bucket up your all your roles and tie them male or female and then
you would perform segregation on those buckets so that's exactly what's happening here.
So in this approach the best way to think about it is we're dealing when you select the show next level
you're dealing with your Times who is there or not is not really as a time series but more of as a categorical
variable.
That's important to remember.
So summing up the values of unemployed people across different quarters really makes no sense if you're
not taking a call into account years when it would make sense is if you instead of adding them up you
would take the averages right.
And then you could look for trends across corridors.
Unemployment is the average unemployment across different quarters change right.
Is there a pattern.
So let's have a look at the way to do it is in the values here.
Just like the dropdown and instead of some select the average And so there now you can see that the
average unemployment does.
There is a pattern across color.
So across all of the years that we've had those 10 years the average unemployment spikes in chorus 3
and then drops down.
And you can continue in that you can go to show next level again.
And so here you can see there is some seasonality.
Right.
So this is this is a chart that represents unemployment average unemployment in each month across all
of the years.
So we're not taking into account year or quarter here which is going at the month level and you can
see how unemployment changes and you can see that there's a drop in unemployment in June.
Maybe that has something to do with the school holidays.
There's a spike in employment in July maybe that has something to do.
School school holidays as well.
But basically we can see a pattern and that is one of those cases when you would actually use your show
next level option and deal with Vieuxtemps use that as a categorical verbal So hopefully that makes
sense.
That was our first approach to dealing with temperatures there.
Now we're going to go back up and we're going to look at the approach that we actually want to use in
our challenge.
Right.
So now we're going to change this back to some that's a sum of unemployment.
And here what we want to do is sort of show next level we want to expand next level.
And so when we click that information about the higher level in our hierarchy's preserved.
So here we've got year and quarter.
And so now for every year we actually have 4 or so there is 2006 quarter 1 2006 quarter 2 cells and
6 4 3 2006 4.
And as you can see we basically between this chart with each other Goodyears And this chart it's the
same chart it just.
We've increased the number of points on the x axis which is our times use and this approach is actually
dealing with the time series as a time series.
This is how you intuitively think of a time when you're dealing we don't think of time as a category
you know quarter one quarter to quarter three quarter four you think of it as a continuous variable
and we're just basically drilling into it or increasing the number of points on our timeline.
And that is done through this expand next.
And if we do it again now we have 12 points for every year so there's 2000 8 January February March
April May all the way to December and then goes 9 and so on.
So this approach allows us to visualize the actual sum of unemployment or the total unemployment in
a proper way.
So now we can really tell how the total unemployment has been changing all the way from 2005 to 2015
continuously through this level of detail of a month.
So we're looking at this whole chart at a monthly level of detail because that is the lowest level of
diesel in terms of time that we have in our vessels.
So there we go that's how we can deal with Times-News data.
Hope that now you're quite comfortable with the two different ways that you can a deal of time series
in part B.
They were shown next level which is dealing with taxes as a categorical variable and it can be used
when you're looking at averages and things like that or they expand next level when you just want to
increase the number of points on your timeline and actually deal over time series as you would intuitively
expect to deliver.
All right so that was quite a lot of knowledge to take in a level play around with that and let that
knowledge really sink in.
So you're comfortable with dealing with these two different approaches and also your next time.
Until then happy analyzing.