Hello and welcome back to the course on par be-I in today's tutorial we're going to create a distribution
for our age groups.
So let's go ahead and have a look at how that's done.
And the first thing we're going to do is we're going to create a new page Harrigan's called age and
then now if we just take simply age we can create a distribution because we need to first create bins
for this variable.
Right now it's just a numeric variable whereas we wants to create categories we want to create characters
for example from 20 to 25 years old 25 to 30 35 30 to 35 and so on.
So in order to do that you need to right click your numeric variable.
And so a group at the bottom and here instead of bin size select the BEEN size that you would want for
your variable.
So in our case we wanted to be five.
So five years apart and click OK.
And that creates these bins.
And now you can simply create two distribution using them so Jack pins into your workspace and then
select again custom ideas we did previously to understand how many people fall into each group how they
go that's your distribution for age.
It is as simple as that.
So maybe you might want to add a couple of things to this distribution.
Maybe you'd like to change some things for instance if go into color.
You might want to change color to a bluish color.
That's what I would do.
So that's that's a bit too dark something that maybe then we can also.
Yeah we don't want to do that because that will you can change the individual colors or every single
group we don't want to do that we want to maybe add the data labels like that may make some space so
that they can fit nicely if we can get them to fit.
Maybe we can adjust some things here so.
So just the size of all labels.
Oh that's actually.
Which one.
Everything here.
But then this text we can adjust the size here.
That's good.
So that way we know exactly how many fall in side each of those groups.
Then you can see you do fix up the formatting.
Hamid Hamid just point in this case we don't actually have decimal points.
Orientation and things like that.
So the usual things.
And that is pretty much it.
That's how we create bins in part b I was going to right click and select bins and then we create this
distribution chart by using the bins that we created and something that we can count which is customer
ID so you can confirm here that it is being counted.
And one final thing that we do want to fix here is we want to change these two percentages so it's easier
to comprehend it's easier to grasp because that way they're kind of like normalized so if you look at
two different regions the totals might be different but percentages will be comparable.
So let's go ahead and customer id click the dropdown.
It's like quick calc and so percentage of grand total.
And this is now where we might want to actually go back and fix up the formatting so we might want to
go to data labels and say zero decimal points.
And that way it looks nice and neat here so you can see that it's automatically adjusting the color
of the label even when it needs to be inside the bar as opposed to when it's outside the bar.
OK so that's how we create our age distribution.
And a quick heads up in the next tutorial we're going to do the same exact thing.
But for our balance.
So if you want to go ahead and try that on your own before we proceed to the next tutorial then you're
highly encouraged to do that so that you can practice the skills and then in the next interval you can
compare to the way I'm going to do it and see if your way is exactly the same.
And if the result also matches up and I Lipford see you on the next tutorial until then happy analyzing.