Hello welcome back to the course and party.
And here we can see where we left off last summer we can get our data set.
And today we're just going to explore.
Then invigoration of this tool so we're not going to create anything specific we just play around so
that we get more familiarized with how Paul VI is laid out so that we can navigate the controls easier
for the down in the course.
All right.
So here at the top we've got a navigation bar that stands out right away.
And let's go through it.
So here we've got to get data something we've already worked with recent sources.
We'll get to the recent data sources that you've explored in power be-I enter data.
We will be using this much.
But basically you can just add some data manually will be connected to our data sets instead.
So let's cancel that EDID queries brings up that same window that we saw before so this is the window
that actually connects to your data when you load it for the first time.
As you recall we there's another way we can adjust our data followed to calling that window we can go
in here and correct things through the modeling tap here if we want to.
So there's two ways of doing that.
And then we've got the refresh button which refreshes the data sets in case you've adjusted the data
set outside of power be-I in the original file and you just click this button and it will refresh the
data set and your visuals will be updated.
New page just creates a new page in your layout but it's much easier just to click and you page and
the left on the bottom here and you'll create new pages for you.
I think of them as new pages in a PowerPoint or something.
So basically like a new slide in a PowerPoint.
And that's that's the point.
So if you want to have several of the selections then you would just create several pages from Nuvigil
just as a resolution to your current page.
We also probably won't be using this button that much because it's easier to use the buttons over here
and we'll see how that works in a second.
Then we've got a text box you can just add a text box to your visualization you can add an image or
you can add some shapes if you like.
So those are pretty straightforward page view.
And basically adjusts your page how like how well it is fitted to your working space.
I prefer to leave it at a 52 page manager relationships.
We'll talk about this further down in the course it's about when you have several data sources and a
new measure so there's new measures.
You call them we'll talk about that as well and publish again we'll talk about this later.
So these are a bit more advanced features and will definitely cover them off for them.
Of course then you've got the modeling tab which contains even more advanced features again you've got
the Vange relationships and you measure and you call them new table salt.
BI So some of these we won't be using some of these will cover further down the course.
And for now we won't worry about this tab.
We will go to the modeling tab as we need it throughout the course.
So let's say on the hometime here on the left we can adjust that data as we discussed.
And this is one of the cases when we would use the modeling tab because we can change the categories
here and here we would.
We can adjust the relationships but that's a few sections away there's a bit of an advanced technique.
So we'll get back to it later on.
And finally so after all that on the right here we've got the controls of our vessels and this is where
we'll be spending most of our time when creating visualisations.
So here you can choose the results and you want to create.
These are different bar charts line charts area charts pie charts and so on.
And then you wrote this dot dot dot.
So we'll talk about this as well.
You can import customisations very powerful feature mix of power be-I is something that actually makes
this tool stand out in the marketplace that there's a lot of customers and will definitely cover that
off in this course.
It will be exciting to toile then we've got some controls here so these will do the change depending
on your visualizations.
But some controls and some filters and we'll explore those in just in a second than you was some formatting
which also changes based on your selection.
And finally you've got your data set.
You can put these like collapses if you want some more space or if you're not using one of them and
that's pretty much it for the controls.
But now to understand this better let's just play around let's track some columns onto bills the visualization
and we'll see what we can get.
So basically we're going to select out of our dataset wish called We want to use in isolation.
So let's select for example region right.
And then just drag it onto the whitespace.
It's that simple.
And then let's say units so the number of units sold and right away when we drag it into Bill or resolution
like that we get a table.
And as you can see here the table option has been hard for us so Microsoft RBI has dramatically selected
which option is going to show.
So what if we don't want to table.
What if we want a bar chart just like the bar chart over here.
The first option and as you can see we've got a bar chart and we've got central east and west.
And if you are over you'll see a tool to pop up so in the Central Region 1199 units were sold in total
than in the East Region 691 in the West 231.
And here you can see that these controls have adjusted.
So now you can go into Younus click this dropdown and you can see that it's the sum if you want to change
it you can change it to something else.
But we can all play around with this further down right now we just won't explode the visuals so you
can change to a different bar chart like that.
So what else have we got.
Let's try.
So that's just basically our Eric Arbor's not really the best option in this particular scenario.
Let's try a pie chart so you can see.
Now we've got a pie chart instead of our bar chart and again this is very telling.
This election further down the course we'll learn how to control these tool tips or these labels so
that they actually specify the percentages.
But even from here we can see that the central regions sold the most number of units.
What else can we do we can do in this case we can do donor charter right.
So this is already a powerful feature that in all these tools you have to jump through many hoops to
get a donor answer here just one click of a button you have a donor chart ready and so on just click
on see what you can get.
There's a tree map and here you even have waterfall chart so there's a beautiful beautiful wonderful
chart and you can see how the different regions add up into the total right there.
So I'm going to leave it at that.
Play around with this try dragging different columns onto the result zation you can remove a column
by just unchecking the box.
It's a very straightforward and intuitive control set that this still has it's just a matter of actually
practicing and playing around with food to get comfortable.
And once you've done that procedure the next tutorial and we will begin creating our Weasel's for the
section and of Accorsi next.
Until then happy analyzing.