Hello and welcome back to the course on par be-I in the various tutorial we were start solving our challenge.
But we were faced with the problem that we created this was Alsation and it's showing the total number
of units sold Bush represented.
Instead of the total toll or amounts in sales for a sense.
And so today we're going to fix that since then we're going to learn how to add a new column into a
data set which will contain the total sales value.
And in order to add and you call them all we have to do is go to the right Seto's Alsatian is actually
very straightforward very simple process or just the right click anywhere here on this dataset or even
on any one of these columns doesn't matter which one.
And here you've got two options and you measure and you call.
Now we will talk about new measure further down in the course we won't discuss right now.
Out of these two options we are just going to add and you call them and it does exactly what you think
it does.
It adds a new column physically into your dataset and we'll see that in a second.
So let's go ahead and click that and you call them.
And as you can see it's appeared here and over here you can specify the formula so we can say total
sales he calls and then just start typing.
What are the existing columns that you want involved in the calculation.
So we want to involve units.
If I start typing units you'll see that it comes up and just click enter or select this option over
here.
So office supplies union says specifies which data set to take that call from and multiply that by office.
We'll just say units and then it'll come up unit price.
That's what we want.
Because total sales for one for an existing transaction is the number of units sold in that transaction
times the unit price in that transaction.
And just go ahead and hit enter right away you can see that total sales has appeared here.
So before we continue with the position let's go let's go ahead and have a look at our dataset and see
how it change here.
So here you can see that we've got a new call them here total sales and the formulas up at the top.
And if I scroll down or just pick any one of these you'll see for instance on Sunday August 24th James
L. in the West region and James is sold dead desks he sold three units of desk's on that day at a price
of Taurus 35 so the total sales for this transaction are for this day for this day for this region for
this person for this item.
Total sales basically the total sales for this row is eight hundred twenty five dollars.
Let's pick another one that say Alex sold binder's he sold the Levan for 99 each.
So the total sales value for that eighty nine dollars.
And that's how we got this column is just multiplying these two.
And as you can see he's performed the calculations performed at the pro level and it's stored in our
data set and that's very important.
Right now it might seem like like an obvious thing.
But then when we talk about calculated measures it'll be an important distinction but let's not run
ahead of ourselves.
We've created this calculated column and that's great.
Now we can use it in our vessels.
And now let's create a new page.
So we'll just keep this as a position as it is but we'll create a new page soldiers actually sort of
clicking this button.
Right click here and we'll say duplicate page and here we just say it's sort of page three page four
actually renamed rename.
So if you just double click it let's name it something else and say total sales.
Right.
And this one we can rename to number of cells so we remember which one is which of sales total sales
and actually if you just double click a little name total sales in dollars and so here what we want
to do is click on his position and all you want to do is replace the units with total sales so let's
just track total sales and just place it over units in the values field.
And that's how that has changed changes that you can see that things have changed now.
So let's compare previously in the central region.
Alex was a top sales person he sold the most units now in the central region.
Matthew is a top salesperson.
He sold three thousand one hundred nine dollars in sales.
So even though he sold less units he made more revenue for the company in the East region.
It was Richard who sold the most units but now it's actually Susan who made the most sales in dollar
terms and here in the West region it was James.
And it is still a James who made the most sales and dozers.
So there we go.
That is how we create a calculated column or a new column in power B.A and that's how we use it in our
insulation.
So if I show this Challenger we just need to finalize this position so it looks fantastic and we'll
get to that in the next tutorial.
I look forward seeing them.
And until then happy analyzing.