Welcome to the Master Android 8
software development course with Kotlin.
So my name is Tim Buchalka, as you can see on
the screen there and my co-instructor is
Jean Paul Roberts. So we'd like to start
out by thanking you for investing in
this course and just to let you know,
that this is our goal to get you up to
speed as an Android developer in the
quickest possible time. Now this
course is a companion to our master
Android development course with Java and
covers pretty much the same topics but
it uses Kotlin rather than Java.
Now Google have made Kotlin the first-class
language for Android development it is
possible to use other languages such as
Python for example but at the moment
only Java and Kotlin and natively
supported by the Android runtime. Now I
know that you're probably itchy to get
started with the programming but there's
just a few things that we need to go
through first and I promise that I'll
keep this as brief as I possibly can.
Now there's over 25 hours of content in
the course right now and we plan to
continue adding in content until Google
releases the next version of Android
Android P whatever that was to add for
there are Java version of this course is
already over 50 hours of content and
this course is probably the largest and
most comprehensive Android course out
there and it's just gonna get bigger
and better so stay tuned for that
knowing that the course will continually
get updated. Now if you find a problem
with a video somewhere please let myself
or Jean Paul know and that's because we
really want to give you the best
possible Android training and even there
between us we've got a collective 60
plus years of software development
experience, we are here in and we do make
mistakes very occasionally, seriously
though let us know if you do find
something wrong with the video and we'll
endeavor to put it right as soon as
possible and finally I advise the best way
to use this course is just dive in and
get started. So what are you waiting for?
I'll see you in the next video.