Alright, so we're all ready to start
writing apps for Android but we should
probably start by answering the question
what is Android. Now Android is often
considered to be an operating system but
it's also a software stack that consists
of an operating system, Linux and a
framework for developing applications
and it also includes a number of key
applications such as contacts that
reflect its purpose as a mobile platform.
Android was originally written by a
company called Android Incorporated and
Google bought that company in 2005 now
its usual to think of Android as being
developed by Google and I tend to talk
about Google a lot in this course but
Android is an is in fact maintained by
the Open Handset Alliance so rather than
releasing Android as a proprietary
system or their board Android
Incorporated Google got together with a
number of other companies to create the
Open Handset Alliance the OHA there at
the time I'm recording this video the
OHA has 84 members who are all committed
to keeping Android open source so you
can actually download the complete
source code for Android and modified if
you wish there's actually a link to get
the source on the home page of the OHA
I'm just going to bring that link up on
the screen there again OHA Open Handset
Alliance you can see there's an option
there to get the source code there's
also a link there to get the SDK as well
now the home page is a little bit
misleading because the most recent entry
in the what's new section over here
actually has a date of July 18th 2011
and that would give the impression that
not much is happening with the OHA but
that couldn't be further from the truth
you're taking this course so you
probably know that version 8 of Android
code named Oh was released in 2017 a new
version of Android is actually released
every year
Android and the OHA are very much alive
now you can learn more about the OHA by
clicking on the Alliance menu item at
the top of the page you're clicking on
members as I've done there shows the
current members of the OHA and if you
scroll down if I scroll down you can
probably recognize some of the names of
these companies there
actually part of the OHA and there's
different categories here is what we
chose with the default is mobile
operators handset manufacturers some
household names here for sure
the SUSE Tech is one Dell is another for
Jitsu so I'm quite well-known companies
NEC LG and so on now I'm not going to
spend time this video going through it
but the Android menu also is well worth
a read to get an overview of the
thinking behind Android now I suggest
that it might be useful for you if
you're on this page to actually watch
this video it's quite a useful video and
I have a bit of a read there all right
so let's have a quick nail at Android to
see some of the things that we're going
to be looking at getting our apps to do
now for this demo we're going to be
using an Android emulator or virtual
device and we'll be looking at how to
create virtual devices a bit later in
the course but think of them as so
basically a way to run our apps on a
wide variety of phones without having to
buy loads of devices because it's all
actually done in under a virtual machine
which means it's running on your
computer now in fact when Google
released Android studio 3 they also
updated the emulators now there's also a
couple of emulators that include the
Google Play Store
and what that means is that you can
install just about any apps from the
Play Store onto your emulator and we're
going to be discussing that in more
detail when we come to create our own
emulators but it's something that
developers have been asking for for a
quite a few years now alright so going
to switch over now to an emulator you
can see that I've got it running but we
can see that it looks like a real
Android phone there at the bottom of
these three soft keys and that you
follow those on just about all Android
devices these days there some
manufacturers do replace the middle
button with a physical key rather than
having it on screen but the function is
the same now the triangular button on
the left over here that's the back
button and some devices that appears as
a curve to left pointing arrow and
rather confusingly can appear on the
right-hand side of the screen instead
the back button though is used to go
back to a previous app to Smith's
dialogues cancel menus basically it just
goes back to what you were doing before
and just to see what I mean there
HIDA click hard to get into our list of
apps I could choose Gmail then I can
click on the back button to go back to
the list of apps no the middle button
down here that's the home button and as
I said some manufacturers use a physical
button for that instead and this button
takes you back to the home screen so if
I run Gmail again and then press the
home button we end up back on the home
screen rather than the apps list that we
got when we clicked on back now it's got
another function - if your long tap so
hold it down basically it'll just a
Google app you can see that that's come
up there when I've done that now I don't
want to set up the Google assistant at
the moment so I'm going to click on back
there to get out of that and we're going
to need another app running for this
next bit so I'm gonna launch Google Maps
as well so I'm just going to go to the
home again click on maps here and open
up Google Maps as well then the square
button on the right over here has
various names so you'll find it referred
to as the recents button or the
multitasking button or even sometimes
the intense button now before I tap it
one thing that may not be obvious is
that pressing back or home doesn't close
an Android app in the same sense as
closing a program on your PC the app is
still running and you can bring it back
to the same state it was when you
dismissed it
now the recent button shows all the apps
that are still running and if I click on
that now so you can see here that I've
got maps going as well as Gmail and you
can actually close it up completely by
clicking on the X up here at the top
right but Android will actually tech
take care of closing the older steps for
you if it needs to use the memory for
something else so there's generally no
need to do that what I'm doing instead
is tap Google Maps
I want to do that that brings it to the
foreground then you can scroll through
the list of recent apps so well to
demonstrate that I need a few more apps
running so we've got a decent list to
scroll through so I'm going to go back
to the home screen using the middle
button and go into apps and we'll start
by launching calendar now back will take
me back to the list of apps and this
time we're going to select photos
that's a bit boring because I haven't
got any photos of this emulator so I'm
gonna go back one more time now this
time we're gonna start the YouTube app
okay so we've now got a few apps running
and I can view them all by tapping that
- recents button again they're all the
apps of just launched - stacked up with
the most recent on the top of the pile
you can see it on the bottom that's
YouTube now this is much easier to do on
a physical device using an emulator will
take a little bit of getting used to
because the mouse pointer doesn't quite
behave the same as a finger on a
touchscreen and hopefully I won't
accidentally touch on that Paul trying
to scroll through them but the way to
scroll through them used to hold the
mouse button down while moving the mouse
to simulate a finger dragging so if I do
that you can see here that I can
actually move down and change the list
of apps as I scroll down or scroll up
for that matter I'm getting the
different two apps as I do that so
basically it's simulating the finger
dragging of the phone's touchscreen now
you saw that when I was dragging the
recent apps to move off the bottom of
the screen to reveal the older ones like
so have a stop down there the less I
scroll up you can see father's is coming
up YouTube and and so on now the Linux
kernel allows multitasking in androids
built on top of the Linux kernel so an
Android phone is a multitasking computer
and you can have actually have several
apps running at the same time which
we're doing here and this can be very
useful if you need to do something like
checking your calendar while talking on
the phone for example and in fact we can
simulate that I select Gmail from the
list of apps so I was thrown out click
on Gmail and next I'm going to find my
emulator now at the bottom of the side
menu over here is this ellipsis three
dots if I click on that that brings up
an extended controls which I'll just
move over so you can see the screen as
well this the menu lets you play around
with things like location and text
messages now the phone option in the
left pane over here I click on that that
allows me to send SMS messages to the
phone and you can also simulate an
incoming
phone call using the call phone button
and you can even enter different phone
numbers to build up a phone log which
can be useful if you're testing an app
that works with the phone log now on
this nexus emulator that causes a
message to drop down so that I can
answer the calls let's just do that
call device you can see that's popped up
there I've come over here now onto the
device I click on answer
now you can't really have a phone
conversation with the emulator but the
emulator is now behaving like a real
phone that's in a phone call so without
hanging up the phone I could tap on the
recents button go back to my email and
view that now there isn't much in this
email because I'm using a test account
for this demo but it can be useful to
check some details in an email during a
phone call all right so now that I've
checked my email I can tap the recent
button again and go back to the phone
call and obviously if that was off the
list we could scroll up and down to find
it and just click it to actually bring
that back on screen again so that's
pretty neat the Android phone that fits
in your pockets more powerful than most
desktop computers from just twenty years
ago now there is a slight oddity
sometimes with simulating phone calls on
the emulators at the moment when I tap
the red floating action button down here
during the call the extended control
menu sometimes doesn't seem to update it
thinks there's still a call in progress
so tapping the button in there will end
the call but in this case that has
actually worked okay but if you get a
problem there just tap on the button
over here to end the chords it's not
really a big problem just something to
be aware of when you're testing how your
apps behave with something like a phone
call happens now at the phone app by the
way doesn't appear in the recess of the
staff they win a call so when I tap the
recent button again you can see that
it's actually disappeared there's only
in the apps I had running before the
phone call came in to get back to it we
need to contact the home button click on
the blue phone icon here though I
haven't got any favourites saved but the
middle tab this one here with the clock
icon shows the time and duration of the
you know quote-unquote call I just
received and I can even simulate an
outgoing call by tapping the phone icon
on the right over here and that
simulates as I said an outgoing phone
call of course they're not really going
to make a phone call but it's a great
feature again with testing your apps all
right so I'm going to hang up the phone
let's hang up there Cornell so let's
have a look at split screen mode now a
new feature that was introduced in
Android 7 new go is split screen mode
the also said don't worry if you haven't
got an Android 7 or later device all the
apps we're developing this course will
run on all devices on Android 4
- that's Android jellybean onwards they
would be able to use split screen mode
on earlier devices but it's still useful
to see what it is now something about
Samsung devices have had split screen
for a while but it's no part of Android
itself which means that all devices from
moving onwards will be able to use it no
you need to point out already running to
go into split screen mode and I've
already got the phone data on the screen
so we'll use that for this demo now with
that running which it is we got a long
tap over here on the recents button and
again a lot of phone you'd be holding
your finger on it in the emulator I'll
just hold the mouse button down until
that happened you know on phones they've
got soft buttons rather than physical
devices the icon changes to show you
that you're in split screen so instead
of just a square it shows two boxes
inside the square to represent the two
apps running and that's what you can see
down here now I can scroll through the
list of apps down the bottom now and tap
the one that I want to open in that the
other half of the screen again if it's
come down and select them like so now
some apps can support running in split
screen so you may see a message over
those apps informing you of that but I
can scroll down and select for example
the Gmail click on that and I can have
that and the dollar running together or
the device on screen at the same time so
yeah that's pretty neat and it's also
possible to copy and paste between the
two apps but not all apps actually
support that now the bar in the middle
here looks like it lets you resize the
apps but at the moment anyway it's just
used to close one or the other by
dragging it over the app you want to
remove from the screen so I'm going to
drag it to get rid of the dollar so
we're left with just Gmail so we're back
in single view mode so we're now got the
one app running and the recent button is
never changed back to the single square
again okay so let's have a look at some
of the things we're going to be learning
how to add you know apps now at the top
of the Gmail app is a toolbar with a
settings menu on the left and a search
button on the right so there's the
settings and there's the search the
settings menu as I click it it produces
a navigation drawer and in this course
we'll see how to create these as well as
implementing search in Oh apps now to
dismiss the navigation drawer to swipe
to the left
now some older phones have a physical
Settings button instead of the settings
3 button icon appearing on the toolbar
it works in the same way just be aware
that if you create an app in the
settings icon doesn't appear on the
toolbar now it's also possible to have a
more traditional menu on the toolbar and
we'll be learning how to create menus
before we get into navigation drawers
now the brief instructions at the top of
the lists on 30 may looks like a snack
bar this one here these were introduced
with lollipop a material designed but
are available now for all Android
versions dating right back to version
2.1 and they're similar to the toast
messages that pop up briefly on the
screen but you can also add actions to
them which makes them more interactive
than the old toast messages this one has
just a simple button to close the snack
bar but you can also swap them off the
screen like so now the emails appear in
a list and we can create lists like this
using either the ListView widget or a
more recent replacement quarter recycle
of you know the recycler view is more
flexible but you can't tell by looking
at the screen which one has been used
here so we're gonna learn how to use
both in our apps anyway and we'll also
see how to use this floating action
button this is the circular button at
the bottom right of the screen and that
should be reserved for the primary
function that users would perform from
for any from any particular screen and
here it allows a new email to be entered
now I can scroll through the list of
emails I'll just go back now unless I do
that the recyclerview is taking care of
things for us all the lists tree for
that matter because again we're not sure
which ones being used here now I can
also tap on an email to read it and
we're gonna learn how to respond to taps
and long taps you know apps we can also
add buttons to the list like the star
next to each of these emails under here
and that marks them as a favorite now by
the time you finish this course you'll
ever learn how to create all these
effects and a lot more it's just pretty
cool the Android devices can also
determine their location and they do
this in two ways the most accurate is by
using the built in GPS module if the
device has one then that allows a phone
to be used as a GPS device an app such
as copilot or as a good as dedicated GPS
devices for giving directories or
driving in Google Maps also
the advantage of being free and also
makes a pretty good pretty good GPS
navigator though not all the emulators
have things like Google Maps installed
and that's why I chose the API 26
emulator at the time I'm recording this
YouTube isn't installed on the API 25
emulators now the other way that Android
devices can check their location is
using the Wi-Fi or mobile phone location
but this is far less accurate Wi-Fi in
particular can be way out because it
only reliably knows the location of your
connection to the Internet
now the phone cabinet in the street in
other words which could be a mile or
more from your real location alright so
go back to the home screen down and
let's just launch some apps by clicking
it over here now the first time you
launch it whether on an emulator or a
real device you have to accept the terms
of conditions but I've done that already
and again that's pretty standard for a
lot of google apps so alright the
emulators got a default location we can
change that from the extended controls
menu that we just used to make a phone
call
so come over here and click on location
and I can tell the emulator that it's in
Adelaide
now the longitude let's talk that in
first let's choosing the longitude and
latitude for red light lager T is going
to be one thirty eight thirty eight
point six oh one and the latitude we
need to set that to minus thirty four
point nine two eight five tap on send
that sends the new location to the
device and it's important to make the
latitude negative it lays south of the
Equator and if we leave it positive we
end up in the sea
and as you can see when I did that it
automatically went to Adelaide when I
actually updated the latitude and
longitude now you can also simulate the
device moving either by typing in and
sending new coordinates or by loading a
set of cord and it's stored in a GPX
file so I'm going to load a file using
the load a GPX XML button down here I'm
going to select the father I've already
got here Adelaide dot GPX and open so
once I've done that I've come over here
and click on the play button and want to
do that the corner and it's a sent to
the device just as if we were coming
from a rural GPS module you can see the
Google updates Google Maps is updating
as we do that
and as you can see it also tracks time
as well as locations so the speed varies
just like it would if you got out of a
car and started walking all right so
that's the GPS demonstration and
basically that's a quick demonstration
of how Android apps work and interact
with the Android operating system
now in the next section so let's start
off with a simple app to get the hang of
using Android studio to develop apps and
then we going to build up to create more
complex apps involving databases Google
Maps rest services and more and there's
also a tutorial section coming up and if
you already know Java or Kotlin
depending on which course you're
watching this video in and feel free to
skip those videos but if you're new to
the language the tutorials will actually
give you the basics and you'll find the
tutorials in section 4 alright so in the
next video we're going to download it
install Android studio which is the tool
you'll need to start creating your
Android apps so we'll see you in that
next video