In this video, I want to show you how to
download install Android studio which is
the program we're going to be using to
write our Android applications in this
course. Now just to remind that this is
the windows video so if you're running a
Mac or a Linux machine there's actually
separate videos that you can follow
along with for those operating systems
but if you're using Microsoft Windows
you're in the right place so let's get
started now it's possible that you might
be running a 32-bit version of Windows
and if that's the case Android studio 1
HD run until you install the Java
development kit first now to check
whether you have a 32-bit or 64-bit
version the windows will come down here
to the Start menu and in search we're
going to type system information and
open up the system information you may
need to go into control panel depending
on what version of Windows you're
running and once we go in there and a
system summary there's system type you
can see here it says x64 based PC or
just assume that up so you can see that
now this says x64 based PC which it does
in my case then you've got a 64-bit
version of Windows otherwise its 32-bit
so because I've got a 64-bit version of
Windows I don't need to do anything else
I can proceed with the Android studio
installation and that's because Android
studio now includes its own installation
of Java but only ships with a 64-bit
Edition and that doesn't work on a
32-bit edition so if you found that by
doing this you've got a 32-bit system
showing up then stop the video here and
skip ahead to the next video and that's
going to show you how to install the
java jdk on your 32-bit Windows system
then once you follow the steps in that
video you can come back to this one and
continue now note that this applies even
if you intend programming in Kotlin
that's because Kotlin uses the Java
Virtual Machine or JVM so you still need
to have a working JDK installed on your
32-bit system alright so i'm gonna
presume that at this point you fix those
issues with 32 and 64-bit and what we
want to do now is go to the website and
download android studio so to do that
we're going to go to
developer.android.com then you can also
searched for android studio when you
search in an engine to find the link so
want to make sure that you are at the yet
Android comm site so you know that
you're installing the official Google
version you can see at the top that
we're on that now one thing to be aware
of is that the new version of Android
studio version 3.0 is very different to
the previous version and has a number of
new features that weren't available in
the earlier version things like the new
layout designer for example so you'll
need to be using Android studio 3.0 or
higher for this course now if you've
already got Android studio 2.3 installed
you'll still need to install the 3.0
version of this course in Android studio
2.3 will update itself in the normal way
so make sure if you're running that
version that you install the update when
it offers it all right so we're ready to
do a fresh install of Android studio 3.0
my windows so we're on the main page
we're gonna come over here click on get
Android studio we're going to click on
download Android studio I'm going to
click on the checkbox to agree with the
above terms and conditions and click on
download Android studio for Windows I'm
going to click on run here just so we
can see it downloading down here down
the bottom and we'll just pause the
video of what this actually downloads
and we'll come back continue after the
download is completed ok so you can see
the Downloads nearly finished to hell
once it finishes you should be able to
run the downloaded file from your
browser click it that way and it's just
a standard Windows installer Exe file
and you'll get the usual prompt asking
for confirmation that you're happy to
allow it to make changes so I'll give
that a moment to run the security scan
and we can minimize the browser now so
we can see what we're doing in Android
studio shadow you can see it's now come
up you may not see that on the video but
I'm selecting yes here to allow this app
to make changes to your device then we
should see the standard Android studio
setup start and you click Next to start
the installation and the components I'm
going to leave both of those on the
default options Android studio and the
Android virtual device next I'm going to
leave the default folder which is fine
for us Program Files Android Android
studio next click on install so that's
now extracting the various files so
we'll just fast forward this bit and
come back after the installation is completed
nobo that by the way yeah during this
process you may or may not get an option
an error coming up saying that needs to
retry and if that does happen just click
retry and that's because sometimes some
of these components fail installation
for no apparent reason and retrying it
should fix it
sometimes even retrying more than once
and personally I've got no idea why
possibly the networks a bit slower or
something along those lines but in our
case hopefully we won't get that to error.
Okay you can say the installation is
completed we're gonna click on next you
know we can leave this checkbox on to
start Android studio and click on finish
now we got this option as well to give
us the option to import Android studio
settings from another location if you've
got a previous installation but in our
case we haven't so we're going to leave
the default selected do not import
settings and click OK Android studio is
loading you can see now it's actually
finding some available SDK to components
and it's giving us an option now to
actually go ahead and install some more
of the Android studio setup and
specifically an emulator that we got next
then we can run it either a standard
install or a custom select standard that
should be right in most cases click on
next you can choose the theme which is
how the computer of the display will
look for you whether you would like a
darker background with different color
fonts or a white background I'm just
going to leave the default the choice is
up to you click on next we've now got a
list of the various application settings
and also the installation settings what
it's going to download because we've
only completed the first component of
the download we need to go through and
install the rest so click on finish and
we'll let it go here go through and
download and install and click on show
details they'll give you a bit of an
indication as to what it's doing and
this is the part where I said you may
come it may come up and ask you to retry
and potentially more than once if
there's a problem with Google servers do
that if it does come up and chances are
that it'll work ok but what we'll do is
we'll pause the video here and we'll
come back once this is pretty well
finished now the other thing I didn't
mention is if you have an installed
Android studio or any aspect of Android
these Android software development kit
it may actually prompt you for a folder
and SDK folder you can actually put that
wherever you like and the fault is
usually a good choice in my case because
I had another product that used the
Android SDK it didn't prompt us for that
if you don't get prompted the default
location is probably fine
the one thing to check once this
installation has completed is to make
sure that haxon was installed
successfully and that's it hexam is able
to be run on your computer now you may
see an error that it couldn't install
hack someone I just want to bring up a
slide and show you that so this might be
an error that you'll see and able to
install until hexam and if you see that
that means you won't be able to take
advantage of the hack some acceleration
features when you run your emulator and
in the next video when we configure the
SDK you'll need to install the a RM
emulators instead of the x86 ones you
know the a RM emulator will still work
but it'll be a lot slower than an x86
emulator using hexam now it may well be
worth checking that VTX is enabled in
your computer's bios so if that's the
case have a look at that in the videos
enable VTX in bios we've actually got a
video dedicated to that and one of the
main reasons that hexam won't work is if
you haven't got an intel cpu on Windows
the requirement for hexam to work is
that it has to be an Intel CPU
presumably because Intel have created
that application that made it mandatory
that only Intel CPUs will actually work
for now so if that's the only error you
get then Android studio and the SDK will
be installed and we can continue
so let's actually just go back now to
the live installation and see how that's
going all right you see that we're still
unzipping here we've been downloading
and we're unzipping so the Pring the
installation is still progressing so
we'll just fast-forward this and come
back once it's pretty much done
you see now it's running the Intel hexam
installer so this this is the part that
actually needs an Intel CPU so again if
we're getting any errors here we'll know
that there was a problem but in my case
you can see down the bottom it's got
Intel hexam installed successfully so
that means that we're good to go alright
so we've now installed android studio
successfully at this point in the next
video we're going to look at configuring
Android studio now the steps to
configure Android studio are largely the
same regardless of which operating
system you're using so you'll want to
skip over the next few videos now
because the next video is cover
installing Android studio on a Mac and
Linux and installing the java jdk on
32-bit systems but if you've managed to
install this successfully you don't need
to watch any of those so basically the
next video in that scenario that you
want will be the video entitled
configure Android SDK on all three
platforms so I'll see you in the next video.