In this video, I'm gonna show you how to
download and install Android studio
which is the program we're going to be
using to write our Android applications
in this course. Now just a reminder
though that this is the Linux video,
so if you're running a Windows machine or a
Mac there is a separate video you can
follow along with in this section of the
course for those operating systems but
if you're using Linux you're in the
right place, so let's get started.
Now it's possible that you might be running
a 32-bit version of Linux if that's the
case firstly consider installing a
64-bit version the next time you rebuild
your computer because there's lots of
advantages. Now to check whether you are
running a 32-bit we can open a terminal
session and we can type uname space
minus m, now if it reports x86
underscore 64 it does in my case that
means you're running a 64-bit version
but if it comes back with either a 386
or i6 86 then that means you're running
a 32-bit versions of Linux. Now Android
studio includes its own installation of
Java but that only ships with a 64-bit
version and won't work on a 32-bit
system, so that's why we're talking about
64 and 32 bit so the bottom line is if
you've got a 386 returned or i686 on
the screen by following that uname
minus m command and stop the video here and
watch the next video, that next video
will show you how to install Java on
your 32-bit Linux system, once you've
followed the steps in that video come
back here and continue with this one and
note that this applies even if you
intend programming in Kotlin. Kotlin uses
the Java Virtual Machine or JVM so you
still need to have a working JDK Java
development kit installed on your 32-bit
system to be able to do that. Now if
you're running a 64-bit version of
Ubuntu or one of its derivatives then
you need to install some 32-bit
libraries first and if you just go
quickly to Google's instructions on
their page and we're going to paste the
link in and this link is available in
the resources section of this video if
you need it you can see if
developer.android.com slash studio slash
install.html, once we get there we
need to select Linux
and by the instructions because we've
got instructions for three platforms or
select Linux and you can see there's a
commands there for 64-bit machines to
get Android studio to work now what goes
through what these are for but the
bottom line is that we need to install
all five to get Android studio working
to get emulators working and to avoid an
error that can pop up and with Ubuntu
versions right up to and including 16.04
all these packages have moved into multi
arch and it's likely that up that other
distros will do the same so what I'm
going to suggest is you to try these
commands first the ones I'm about to
show you but if you get an error with
any library use a corresponding command
that I'm going to show in a slide after
these commands, this will make the sense
as we go through. We're gonna open a
command window again we'll go back to
our command window and what we want to
do is start issuing some commands and
cause i'm on ubuntu 16.04 LTS, I'm going
to type sudo space apt to get apt - get
space update
I can type in my password then I'm going
to type pseudo space apt - get space
install space libc6:i386
we're going to go through and install
some of these and press enter to accept
the default of yes and we're going to go
through and do for other libraries as
well up arrow and we're going to delete
the one out the next one we want to do
is lib in cursors 5 : 5386 again you
should be checking to see with any of
these commands don't work if they don't
work we'll need to do an alternative
command and I'll show you a slide for
that once we've finished you can see
these both work so far our power our
pyro we've got three more to do so Lib
std c++ 6:3 8 6 press enter
this one takes a little bit longer so
we'll wait for that to finish
Alright, put that one up a little bit
two more to do now, so the next one is
lib z1:i386 and the last one lib
bz2-1.0:i386, I'll let that
one finish off as well. Alright so that's
all of they're all done there now
multi arch supports running 32-bit
programs on 64-bit systems so the 32
doesn't appear in those names so
Google's pages still showing lib 32 z1
now if you get an error for any of these
as I mentioned you need to use the
corresponding command I'm about to show
you to install just the packages that
error and the slide shows the
alternative commands but remember that
you only need to use these commands for
any that failed with the other commands
in my case I didn't get any that file so
I don't need to do any of these, well so
here's as long as you can see and that's
just the alternate and naming for those
files if for some reason you've got some
problems with them. Okay, so now that
we've got the required libraries we can
install Android studio let's go back to
the Android studio site so moany at
developer.android.com slash studio
special store I'm just going to delete
the install part just go to the main
page for Android studio and that should
allow us automatically to select or
should automatically select for us
Android studio and it should be the
Linux version so I'm going to select
download for that but if by chance it's
using it's not showing of a Linux
version make sure you select that and
I'm gonna click on I agree to the terms
and conditions and I'm going to download
android studio because that's a
relatively large file we're going to let
that download first and what I'm going
to do is click on save a little game
save it into our downloads folder now
one thing to be aware of this is
downloading is that the new version of
Android studio version 3.0 is very
different to the previous versions and
has a number of new features that
weren't available in that earlier
version or earlier versions things like
the layout designer for example are now
very different so you'll need to be
using Android studio 3.0 or higher for
this course.
Now if you've got an older version saved
version to version 2.3
you still need to install the 3.0
version for this course into a studio 2
and 2.3 will update itself to version 3,
so make sure you accept the update when
it's offered in that version if you are
using a previous version of Android
studio. Alright so I'm just gonna let
this finish it's just about to finish
downloading and then we're going to
begin, ok that's finished as you can see
so I'm going to close down the web
browser and I'm going to just open a
browser, a explorer window and I'm going
to go to my downloads folder because
that's where it was so you're going to
go to whichever folder you were
downloaded this hat or wherever I went
my case I went to my downloads folder
and I'm going to extract this by opening
it and once just to actually put this
somewhere so I'm going to just put this
in my home folder so I'm gonna click on
the Android studio right click extract
and I'm gonna come up here to home so
I'll depth that is installed in the home
location but you can actually install
that wherever you like but in my case
that makes sense to install to extract
it to there so let's go ahead and do it
let that finish
and by the way obviously you've probably
figured out now this is the ubuntus
installation instructions if you do have
another linux distro check
out the the installation page for
android studio that i've showed
previously because it's also got
instructions up for example for a 60 bit
64 bit fedoras setup so some options if
you need t. Alright so we finished
with our card manager we can close it
now, close down now the launcher
the file manager and we wouldn't go
now into the folder where we extracted
those files so I'm going to go in my
case and I have a look I'm should be in
my home location which I am and if I
have a look at the files there I can see
Android studio folder is there now so I
can type CD space and Android and that
will finish the autocomplete the path
and I have a look in the bin subfolder
you can see there's a file there called
studio SH I'm going to run that studio
dot SH and that's going to start the
installation process now what I'm going
to do is continue on and get this going
and I'm going to talk a little bit about
ibus if you happen to get a problem
with our bus then at this case because
it's a new installation we haven't got
any import any settings to import if you
have kind of old version of Android
studio you can use custom location to
grab your settings if you wish, give
android studio a moment to start
you can see it's finding the various SDK
which is software development kit
components that it needs because it'll
need to do that download in addition you
can see I clicked on next select
standard next you've got a choice of
themes here you can choose IntelliJ dark
color or gtk+ and that relates to how
the look and feel of Android studio oh
it's different now this one here with
the white background is great for
recording video so I'm going to do that
but dark the dark background is often
good on the eyes so you may want to
consider that in my case I'm going to
leave it on IntelliJ click on next I'm
at the stage now where you can see that
it's verifying settings and when you
need to get all this stuff installed
because Android studio is just the first
component we need to load download this
SDK on a software development kit which
is got all the stuff that helps us be
able to correct in Android applications
so I'm gonna click on next to that now
if you're using a bunt which I am or a
distro based on it then you should
already have KVM installed and this this
particular screen comes up if your
computer supports hardware
virtualization now if you're not sure
whether you have got it installed or
let's say you can actually click on this
link here - and perhaps book market
which could be a good idea if you need
to review the instructions later and
there's also a video later in this
section or making sure that VTX is
enabled in your computer's bios now
although this is used for intel hexam's
hardware accelerator which isn't needed
on linux kvam also uses VTX so it's a
good what's actually required to make
sure that that's enabled so if you're
running into issues later on with
emulators refer to that video there are
ad processors use a process called amd-v
an AMD v can't be disabled in the bios
so the bottom line there is you've got
an AMD processor this shouldn't be
anything more you need to do and i'm
going to show you in either case how to
check your virtualization is enabled at
the end of this video but now that what
we're going to do is click on finish so
we can leave that downloading and the
other thing i wanted to talk about very
briefly and i'm just going to get this
terminal window while that's downloading
going actually what we'll do is well
open another terminal window
over here, we'll just put that over the
top there to hide that one for now
now while Android studio was installing
you might have got an error appearing to
do with input problems with IBUs prior
to one point five point one one if you
didn't have any errors then you don't
need to follow this particular part of
the video you know the older version of
Ubuntu 14.04 LTS uses an older version
of ibus version one point five point
five but it's actually very rare to get
any problems the bottom line here is if
you find that the keyboard stops working
in the Android studio you may have to
restart and you should be okay if you
want to check your version of our bus
just add a new terminal window like I've
now then you can type in AI bus version
you see in my case I'm adding a bus one
point five point one one so basically
the input problem shouldn't exist if
you're running this version or higher,
in my case I am so I haven't got any errors
so just keeping in mind that you can
safely ignore the I bus warning in many
cases if it does come up don't click the
do not show again link if you do get
that warning in case you want to follow
up that link in the future you can hover
over it and click on the X icon at the
top to dismiss it for now and you can
always click on the do not show again in
the future if it gets too annoying but
again that's only if you're getting
problems you can see in my case I didn't
get those problems I'm going to close
down that terminal window all right so
you can see now that over to the right
told us that the Android SDK is up to
date and over here Android studio has
actually finished the process of
downloading the software development kit
so I can click on finish there and you
can see we're now running Android studio
and by the way during that installation
process if you do get a dialog asking
you to retry at some point just click
retry because sometimes the downloading
of some components fails for no apparent
reason perhaps around busy network and
then take Google's end and retrying it
should fix it in most cases and perhaps
sometimes you may even need to retry
more than once
certainly there has been an issue in the
past but obviously with my installation
I didn't have any problems today.
Alright now once the installation is
finished it's a good idea to set up a
desktop launcher so that you don't have
to keep running Android studio from the
terminal so to do this you just come
down here to configure and click on
create desktop entry and
I can click on ok you can optionally set
it up so the entry is applicable for all
users on this machine I'm just going to
click on ok to adjust this user and you
can see the Android studio icon appear
to the left there ok and we can now exit
Android studio then we can come back up
to here and we can type it into a studio
or I could have clicked on the like
there and I can click on the enter to do
and I can start it that way now without
using the command line. Alright so
that's Android studio installed now we
need there is a video coming up where we
need to actually configure the Safa
development kit and you'll see that also
in this section of this course but - one
other thing I promised to do was just
talk about this was just showing you how
to quickly check to see if hardware
virtualization supported so we're back
on this terminal session again and we
can type in KVM - ok now this case I've
actually got an error as you can see
here if you get that error it's telling
you how to fix it we need to install the
CPU checker so type in sudo space apt
space install space CPU - chicken well
then install and once we do that we
should be able to check and we can the
command to type K again KVM - ok you can
see here that we've actually got an
error I've got an error because I'm
running Linux and a Mac operating system
it's a virtual machine but you hopefully
will see an error message similar to
this on the screen and you can see on
the screen there it actually says k vm
acceleration can now be used
Dheeraj KVM exists so more than likely
that you'll actually get that on most
Linux installations and alternate to
that commands you're going to do a cat
space /proc /cp you info space of coal
or pipe rather space eat grep space
minus c double quotes vm x then the pipe
character again SVM that's an alternate
come on there if you're going to know
about other than 0 then hardware
virtualization is ok yeah I've got a 0
here again because I'm running Linux as
a virtual machine on Mac platform this
is what you should see something like
this you can see in that example there we've got
for showing which means that Harvard
virtualization is okay for that machine.
Alright now if you're not running a
virtual machine already like I am search
I'd like to see if your Intel processor
supports VTX and if it does watch the
later video in this section of the
course to enable that in your BIOS and
if you've got an AMD processor then that
doesn't apply if your AMD processor
doesn't support virtualization and the
previous commands would report of that
and there's nothing you can do in the
BIOS to enable it from it for an AMD
platform. Alright so in the next video
we're going to look at configuring
Android studio and the steps from now on
are largely the same regardless of which
operating system you're using so I'll
see you in the video titled configure
Android SDK on all three platforms and
by the way skip over the next video
because that was relating to installing
the Java development kit on a 32-bit
version of Linux which doesn't apply now
because you've either done that already
or won't need it, so go to the video
titled configure Android SDK on all
three platforms in this section of the
course and I'll see you in that video.