Alright, let's have a discussion about
variables and types. Now a variable is
just a name that we give to an area of
memory so that we can refer to the
contents by name, so I think of it like
the mailboxes in an in an apartment
block now there's a bank of mailboxes in
the lobby and each one is labeled with
the name of its owner
then when the post person delivers the
letters they'll put mine in a mailbox
labeled Tim that makes it easy for me to
get my mail I just open my mailbox
rather than having to check them all.
Once again there's a difference in the
way humans and computers behave now the
post person wouldn't try to force a
parcel into my mailbox because the
mailbox are slots only big enough to
take letters then things wouldn't go
well if I tried squeezing a large parcel
in but computers don't think like that
so we have to tell them what kind of
thing we can store in each of the
variables that we use so let's actually
see how that works with an example I'm
going to come up here to our Kotlin
tutorial project and I'm gonna put some
code in below the existing two lines of
code and put a space in there so I'm
gonna start on line five I'm gonna type
var ah space Tim :
space string equals double quotes or
speech marks Tim Buchalka then
I'm gonna type print line on the next
line parenthesis Tim. So what we've done
here is we've created a variable called
Tim and put the text Tim Buchalka in the
area of memory that's now labeled Tim so
we've told the computer that this area
of memory can hold string values so it's
fine to store text there. Now string by
the way is the name given two types of
variables that can store text and on the
next line on line six we're printing Tim
but instead of printing the three
characters Tim the computer is going to
go off to the area of memory that we've
labeled Tim and get the contents and
should then print those contents not the
name that we've given to that bit of
memory so let's just run the program to
confirm that but I right click it and
click on run main kt and you can see
down here down the bottom,
it's printing out my full name, so on line five
up here we declared the variable Tim.
Now when we declare a variable we tell the
computer what type of information it can
store so in this case it can store
string objects we then gave the variable
a name Tim and again when we run the
program it printed out my name at the
end as you can see that down the bottom
left-hand corner of the screen. Now often
you'll also give the variable a value at
the same time which we've done here by
using equals then the string that we
want to assign to the variable however
you can also assign the value later if
you want so to show you what I mean by
that I can leave this line here var Tim
stream and press enter art a string then
on the next line I could type Tim equals
let's move this over so it's indented
correctly and when I run that we should
get exactly the same result you can see
it still shows Tim Buchalka
the important thing here is that the
variable Tim must be declared before we
can assign a value to it until we
declare the variable the variable the
computer doesn't know what kind of
information it can store it also hasn't
allocated any memory for it, so it's a
bit like the poster you're trying to
deliver a letter but there's no mailbox
with my name on it being human they can
make decisions for themselves they might
for example ask the neighbors if anyone
called Tim has moved in recently the
computer however won't make any
decisions that you haven't programmed it
to make so you'll just get an error so
then let's actually see that what I'm
going to do is on line five I'm going to
delete the declaration or rather I went
to leader I'm going to turn it into a
comment instead and I'll explain
comments in a minute but I'm going to
put two slashes there slash slash
forward slashes yeah what's up done that
the first thing to notice is that we've
now got two errors the word Tim appears
in red in both places that it's used and
that's because Kotlin no longer knows
what it means now I can see what the
errors are by the way by hovering the
mouse over the red text unresolved
reference Tim and I can also hover over
the red marks
marjina sporting at the same thing
basically showing the same error which
is unresolved a reference Tim so that's
computer speak for I've got no idea what
you mean by Tim I can't run the program
now but I can try anyway so I'll run
that we actually get an error here it's
not allowing us to run and it's
basically saying that we need to fix
this error before we can run it now I
know that doesn't give a lot of
information about the type of error but
that's because Android studio is really
intended for creating and running
Android apps we'll be looking at other
error messages later on when we get them
because our code compiles more crashes
for now though there's no point trying
to run a program if Android Studios
highlighting errors on the screen as it
is he man our example so what's happened
here is that we haven't declared the
variable Tim, so Kotlin has no idea what
it's referring to so instead of deleting
the declaration I turned it into a comet
so any line that starts with these two
slashes like this one is ignored by
Kotlin it's a good way to put comments
in your code to explain what the codes
doing it's also a good way to
temporarily disable lines of code that
are executed like I did here now I'm
going to uncomment that line and I'm
using a useful shortcut key to do that
on a Mac its command and slash and on a
PC running Windows or Linux it's control
slash so hold down the command key or
control key depending on your operating
system and press slash when I do that
the lines uncommented again and if I
hold down and do it again it's then
coming to Dell again and so on I can
just go down the page there but I'll put
those back in so I've got all three
lines now and committed and by the way
that doesn't work too old too well with
some keyboards that are laid out
differently to the standard u.s.
keyboard so you can either use the code
menu up here to code menu comment with
line comment and choose that which will
do the same thing or you can just type
the two slashes which you saw me do
earlier in this video like so all right
so I put that line back in there so
let's have a look at the type of the
variable Tim. Now we've declared Tim on line 5,
to be of type string which means it can
only hold text values if I try to assign
a number to it it won't actually work so
I come down here and change this
declaration Tim equals I change that
instead to 32 we've got an error here
and if I hover the error the integer
literal does not conform to the expected
type string so we can assign a number to
a string variable Kotlin doesn't allow
that now you might be tempted to get
around that closing the number 32 in
speech marks or double quotes like so
and that will work there's no error now
and I can actually run the program
actually what I do is I'll just run it
up here and you can see the number 32 is
outputting occasionally you might
actually get an error which says could
not fall on a load main class Katy after
a failing when you've actually had an
error what you may need to do from time
to time has come up to a build menu and
click on rebuild project to get rid of
that particular error but in any case in
my case that actually worked ok and you
can see we've got those value 32 printed
but you might think that we have
actually fooled the computer but we
haven't really done that though Tim is
still storing a string it's just made up
of the two characters 3 & 2 now it could
be used to represent the number of my
mailbox but not my salary for example,
so we currently sums with it in other
words if it's a number in double quotes
now if we want to treat it as a number
then what we have to do is declare it to
be a numeric type now the most common
Kotlin type for storing whole numbers is
int which is short for integer all right
so let's try adding this code and was
hoping bar Tim salary colon int to the
capital I equals 32 on the next line of
our space monthly colon int equals Tim
star which is the multiplication
operator for then I'm going to type
print ln parentheses Tim salary, print ln
in monthly
so by declaring Tim's salary which we've
done on line nine to be an int it's now
treated as a number and we can do
arithmetic with it so I can multiply it
by four to get my monthly salary which
I've done on line 10 and int here is an
abbreviation or shortcut for integer the
second thing is that we can use the
value of a variable in calculations then
assign the result of that calculation to
another variable and we can see on line
10 we're doing just that
so the code the code is multiplying the
value Tim salary by 4 then assigning the
result to the variable monthly. So let's
just run this program to make sure it
works let's do a build rebuild project
run again now this error might be a bit
cryptic for you you might be wondering
what's going on here but if you hover
over here to the right we can actually
see none of the following candidates is
applicable because of receiver type
mismatch so actually getting this error
on line 10 and I guess looking at that
area you might think that's a bit
cryptic and I tend to agree what it
means is that you can't multiply a
string by an integer actually you can't
multiply a string by anything but the
computer doesn't do that kind of
semantic reasoning it just sees a string
in an int and that's what it reports so
I'm gonna put this back now to get rid
of the error then I'm also going to
change the Tim back to my name so the
outputs a bit clearer. So this thing this
code on line 10 should have been Tim
celery let's change that but also back
up here where it's not the 32, I'm gonna
change that back to my name again let's
try running that and see if it works and
this is that error that will pop up from
time to time could not fall in a load
main class main kt if that does come
up and it has been working just click on
build and click on rebuild project once
that's finished click on run again and
it should find that all then work, so in
this case now we've defined Tim salary
32 and you can see the calculation as
beep for monthly has been Tim's salary
times 4 which is 128 and the
lines 11 and 12 we're
printing out for value
of Tim's salary and monthly and my name
is also printing correctly as well.
Alright so let's in the video here now
that we've got some working code. In the
next one we'll continue on with our
discussion of variables and types I'll
see you in the next video.