The next concept that it's time to talk
about is classes. Now classes are a
fundamental part of object-oriented
programming now we've used some classes
in the previous videos and that's
because stringing int our classes so
think of a class as some sort of thing
in an application now effectively
they're nouns within an application like
for example a player or an enemy or a
train maybe now using computer game
analogies this could all be classes in a
game that we've written so we're going
to go through the process of creating a
class so that you can get a good handle
on why you'd want to use a class now the
android framework contains a load of
classes and a lot of the work in writing
android programs is already done for us
and all the widgets that we add to our
apps our classes the textview widget
that displays so want to displayed hello
world in the last section was an object
created from the textview class so we
didn't have to do a lot to display the
text because the android framework took
care of everything needed to Center the
widget and ultimately display the text
so once we've seen how to write a class
we'll look at how to use them now as an
example of some classes we're going to
create some basic ones that you can use
in an adventure game now we're not going
to be producing a full game but we'll
use some other classes that a game may
use just to look at the concept of
classes in order to create a class we
need to make sure that the project pane
is actually expanded as it is on the
right-hand side then we need to come
over here to the Java folder right click
that select new and then select Kotlin
file slash class now we're going to type
in player for the name of the class so
we're creating a class called player
which is going to have some basic
information about player in a game now
the convention is that class names start
with a capital P and you saw that I used
a capital P for the word player so make
sure to use that capital P now in the
kind of drop down here plus click on
that now you want to choose class here
now it's not that important you can
leave it set to file if you want but
doing it this way changing it and
selecting class
saves you a bit of typing so click on ok
and you can see that Android studio has
automatically created the basic
declaration for our new class now
there's not a lot of code in there so if
you chose and file a moment ago you
wouldn't have a lot of code to type in
you have to just type in what you can
see on the screen there so the good
thing with the class is it can be a
container for lots of variables and it
can also have program code that relates
just to a player now we're going to go
through and explore that a little bit
further what we'll start off doing is
sending up some variables that would be
appropriate if this was a player class
in a game all right so what are some
things that maybe a player in a game
would have well they're going to need a
name to start with we're not going to
have any players with that name so
whenever we create new plays we're going
to have to give them a name now in
Kotlin we can specify the name in what's
called the primary constructor you know
there are a couple of ways of doing that
but the most common is to add the
variable to the class declaration so I'm
gonna have a go at doing that so a line
fire we've got class player I'm gonna
come over here to the end of the word
player and at parentheses anything I'm
going to type Val space name colon in
the word string so what we've done there
is to tell Kotlin that a name must be
supplied whenever a new player objects
are created and we're gonna be seeing
how to create them shortly now we also
need to keep track of how many lives a
player has as well as their score and
the level they've reached in the game so
we need a few more variables so let's go
ahead and create those as well I'm going
to put those in the class starting on
line six as you can see here we're going
to type VAR space lives equals three var
level equals one and var score equals
zero alright so that's the basic class
created now it doesn't do a lot at the
moment but it'll have a name when we
create it as well as default values for
the number of lives the level and the
score now players start off with three
lives and they'll start at level one and
their score will actually be zero
no-no-no self-declared those three
variables using var rather than valve
now the name won't change after we
create the player so that's declared to
be vowel we expect the score and the
level to increase and the player may
also lose lives so consequently those
three variables have to be VARs now
another thing to notice is the way
Kotlin can infer the types of variables
a lot of the time that we have talked
about that before now with a signed
integer values to lives level and score
so we don't have to specify their type
now we have an aside any valley to name
yet so we have to tell Kotlin that's
going to hold a string and that's why
we've used this string type here on line 5
all right let's create some players and
see what we can do with our bass player
class so I'm going to switch back to
main Katy so you can go to clicking up
here in the tap and for some reason
that's not open you can double click
main dot Katie over here to open it up
and what we're going to do is delete all
this other code out completely right up
to but not including line 1 so we've
just got the first line fund main and
nothing in between the code block or the
block of code from lines to one numbers
alright so how do we actually create a
player called team well we can actually
type Val Tim equals player then double
quotes Tim and we can type prickling Tim
dot name print Lynn Tim got lives
ritalin Tim that level and ritalin Tim
got school and by the way ignore this
name column that's appeared before Tim
I'll come back to that soon and explain
what it is it's not part of the code so
you don't actually have to type that in
alright so on line two
we created a new instance of the player
class now that's an important concept to
understand the difference between the
class and instances of that class now
one way to look at it is to consider the
classification of life on this planet
now all life forms
fit into different classifications and
we're all members of the class called
humans now we were all created from a
template that defines a human and we're
all individual instances of human so my
name property has the valley Tim but
yours probably has a different value now
of course people can share the same name
but if there's another timber chart or
instance out there they'll have
different values for other properties
such as their heart or hair color or
whatever so the class is called human
and we're all instances of the human
class and that's really the difference
between the two things so the class is
just a template and the values for these
properties will be assigned when we
create instances of the player class so
let's actually run this program and see
what happens
okay so we can see the valleys of the
properties printed out over here no used
dot notation to refer to the various
properties that Tim has so on line three
Tim dot name refers to the name property
and then the other ones
Tim dot life's refers to the lives
property and so on now as well as
properties classes can also have
behavior and we're going to change some
of the properties it's going to get a
bit tedious typing all those print line
statements in and it'll be really handy
if plow instances were able to display
these values so one way to do this is to
add a show function to the player class
so let's go back to the player class
file and do that so I'm going to come
down here and I'm going to leave a gap
between the VAR score line and the start
of the function type fun show
parentheses the open a code block the
matching of this high print line' then
we're going to do parentheses they're
going to do three double quotes three
like that I'm gonna press ENTER and I'm
gonna make a space there and I'm gonna
type of name : dollar name lives dollar lives
the next line level : the level and then
the last line score : on a school then
for the ending parentheses I'm going to
do three double quotes again one two
three so the show function is quite
simple it just prints the values of the
properties now I've used triple speech
marks or double quotes to format the
values which we haven't seen before
they're using these triple double quotes
like this is a way to split of string
over several lines and you'll see the
effect that it has when we actually run
the program so we'll go back to main
katie and we can now remove all these
print lin method calls now because we
don't need them anymore
so let's now move these print line
statements there for them actually what
I'll do is I'll comment them out and I'm
gonna call the Tim show function instead
so I'm gonna tim dot show so let's
actually run this
and you see we've got named Tim lives
level and score so we used dot notation
to call functions on class instances as
well as to access the properties so here
Tim dot show that were using on line
seven that calls the show function on
the variable Tim and if you recall Tim's
an instance of the player class and all
player instances will have a show
function now we can see that by creating
another player instance so I'm going to
call this one of the ways I'm gonna type
Val Louise equals player capital P
parentheses Louise then I'm gonna type
Louise dot level equals 5 then on top of
the Wiis dot show so we provide the name
Louise when we create the new player
instance and I've also set Louise's
level to five so if we run the program
now we should give the details of Louise
printed out after my after Tim
and you can see we've got named Tim
laughs three level one score zero and
then Louise lives three level five this
time and score zero so each player will
have a different name and their scores
and these other values will also be
different now with during these valleys
as properties in the class and each
instance of the player class will have
its own values for those properties now
the codes slightly entirely because
Louise is about because Louise was
created with a default level of one that
we changed it on the next line to five
it actually been needed to specify her
level when we created that always
instance a player now in Java you can
have different constructors for a class
so you could do something like this you
can pick up to Louise you can put
something like comma five and then
delete this line now we've got an error
because our class isn't set up to accept
a level when we create it now as I said
in Java he'd create different
constructors that would accept different
arguments when creating the class now
that's also possible in Collin but
Kotlin allows two fault values for
arguments now you'll see Java classes
with different constructors when we
start using the android framework
classes so don't worry too much about
them at this stage they're just Java's
way of doing what we're about to do in
Collin so what we can do is change our
player class to allow the number of
likes and the level to be specified when
we create the class instances so let's
actually go back to player Katie and up
here on the line line five we're going
to put a comma after the string comma
space var level colon space int equals
one so because we've now declared the
level property in the constructor we can
delete its declaration inside the class
in fact we have to do that you can't to
clear the same thing twice and you can
see we've actually got an error here
because of that conflicting declarations
so let's go ahead and delete that
and the errors then disappear so now
that we've actually done that we can
provide a value for leather when we
create Louise
so the error in Maine should have been
fixed so if we go back to that now you
can see the error fixed itself
automatically and if we run the program
now we should see that level has been
set to fire which it has for Louise and
that's because we've set the level to be
five in the case of Tim never was set to
one because that's the default value so
in other words because we haven't
provided a valley for Tim on line two
the default value of one's used so in
other words Tim level stays at level one
and you may have noticed when I switched
back to the mains to the main function
that the line the line 9 changed and he
saw a level actually appear so the veldt
the value of farm now has the word level
in front of it and as I mentioned
previously and it's got part of the code
that's Android studio showing us what
the various arguments represent so
Louise is the valley we're providing for
the name and fives the valley for the
level now that's quite a neat feature
and it's very helpful to have a reminder
of what the arguments are it can be
confusing when you've watched the code
on a video though you don't have to type
the name : a level : here I'm actually
put on the screen automatically by
Android studio now if you're using the
default color scheme the argument names
hints appear in a light gray with a
light background as you can see here but
in the dark color scheme if you're
running that they're the same but the
backgrounds have been harder to see
against dark colors black background so
remember that they're displayed by
Android studio to remind you what the
arguments are they're not pile of the
code and you shouldn't be typing them in
alright before I show you another way to
specify the values for these arguments
it's actually time for a challenge so
your challenge is to modify the player
class so that its constructor allows
different values for the lofts and score
properties now the defaults for both
will be the defaults that the class
currently using when you've made the
changes create two new instances of the
player class and you can call them
anything you like so the first in
should have a level of 4l8 lives the
second one should have a level of two
five lives and a score of 1,000 use the
show function to print out the values
for your new instances and note that
when you add parameters that have
default values they must be listed after
any parameters that don't so they must
be the first parameter that's declared
in the player class and that's why I
added level after it so that's the
challenge pause the video now and see
how you go and I'll see you when you get
back and show you the solution pause the
video now
all right so to allow the number of
lives and the score to be set when we
create new player instances we need to
add two more parameters to the class
declaration now because that results in
duplicate declarations for the two
properties we also have to delete them
from inside the class so let's go have a
look at doing that let me go to the
player class we're going to start by
leaving Vout name string there and also
leave the level as it is after the in T
equals wonderful level we're going to
put a comma var lives colon int equals
three comma and var score colon int
equals zero
we no need to delete these two lines the
var lives equals three and score equals
zero because we've defined them now as
arguments in the class definition on
line five and that should fix the errors
but you can see that they have been
fixed so that's the change to our player
class now that we've done that we can
create two new player objects and
specify their lives and score now I use
the term objects there instead of
instances I'm actually the same thing
you'll hear people talk about instances
of a class or objects an object is just
an instance of a class so the two terms
are used interchangeably all right so
let's go back to the main dot Katie and
let's add this extra take two extra
instances so start with vowel space gr8
equals player parentheses gr8 comma
space comma 4 comma 8 and then Val
want to watch equals player and we
username ace comma 2 comma 5 comma 1000
then let's actually show this as well so
gr8 dot show and then want to watch dot
show so let's now run the code and you
can see we've got the output there for
the other two then Tim and the Louise
but also for the GRA
live says 18 levels for an ace life's 5
level to score 1000 and you may have
noticed when I was typing the arguments
that Android studio showed the name of
the argument that corresponds to the
position where I'm topping the numbers
now you may have wondered what use these
argument names hints were when I
mentioned them before but now that we've
got three numbers in the row for one to
watch you can see that they're useful
without those hints you'd have to
remember what order you define the
parameters in the player class but now
we can clearly see that 5 is the number
of lives and 1000 is the score this is
the code on line 13 and as I said we ran
the program when we got the correct
results now by the way setting the score
like this would be useful if we were
restoring a saved game for these two
players and having to create them with
the valley's they had when they saved
the game in case you're wondering now
I've used modern text speak style names
there just to show that you have you
can't have numbers in variable names so
variable names mustn't start with a
number but you can use numbers within
the names of variables all right so
that's been a quick overview of what
classes are. Now you'll find if you go
through the course that Android has a
lot of classes built into it a great
deal of our programming will be using
the functionality provided by those
built-in classes and we're going to be
exploring that a lot of that as we go
through but for now though let's move on
to the next video.