When we started looking at classes I
mentioned that there's less need to
overload functions in Kotlin and that's
because Kotlin allows default valleys to
be specified for function arguments.
Now I didn't say very much about overloading
at the time, so let's look at what that
is in a bit more detail now when you
were overload a function that just means
creating another copy of it with
different parameters so that could be
very useful here because we could use a
different version of drop loot and give
it the name of the loot so we could come
down here at the moment we've got our
loan 51 the definition for blue potion
but in terms of drop loot we could do
something like Tim dot drop loot and
actually enter the name so in visibility
potion now we've got an error at the
moment because we're passing a string to
the drop loot function and it expects a
loot object now if we could pass a
string to drop loot then we could drop
the invisibility potion even though we
don't have a reference to it so what we
need to do here is create a version of
drop loot that accepts a string argument
then get it to remove the corresponding
item from the list so let's go to our
player class we're going to add this
after the existing drop loot method all
right so we're gonna start and drop loot
parentheses name colon string :
brilliant then we create the function
with the left or right curly braces and
then we'll just do print then dollar
name will be dropped for now we're just
going to do a return true so when
overloading a function we create another
function with the same name but we give
it different parameters now the compiler
checks the parameters and calls the
version of the overloaded function that
has matching parameters so we've got two
versions of drop loot now as you can see
so this first one on line 32 takes an
argument of type loot because we've
defined the parameter to be loot then
the second drop loot on line 40
one takes a string argument now it
doesn't do anything useful yet we're
focusing on the overloading mechanism at
the moment we'll actually add more code
to the second version in a minute so go
back to main now notice that the error
disappeared and the first time we call
that drop loot this code here onload 45
well actually this is probably a better
one here so let's do this one rely on 52
so we're calling droplet then we're
giving it a loot instance blue potion
and by doing that the first droplet
functions called but down here when we
call it with a string argument
invisibility potion again line 58 then
that's the second drop blued functions
that's going to be called instead
because we passed the document of type string.
So let's actually try running this and
see what happens and you can see that
the other code is executed then right
down the bottom invisibility potion will
be dropped so that's working in our
second version of droplets obviously
being called at that point so that's
function overloading you create another
version of the function with different
parameters and Kotlin calls the one that
matches the argument types now there's
less need to overload functions in
Kotlin than there is in Java because
again we can use two fault values for
the parameters instead but it's still
necessary to overload functions
sometimes and this is one example all
right so we're going to finish this
video by making our overloaded droplet
function work
now the Kotlin collection classes have a
remove if function that we can use to
remove it an item from the list if a
certain condition is true so let's
actually try that we'll go back to
player the player class and a second
droplet function we're going to do in
return we're gonna delete true and
instead we're going to return in the
entry dot remove if we're going to
delete the parentheses then want to add
a code block instead and within there
I'm gonna put IT name equals name two
equal signs there so that checks each
item in the list and removes it if the
name is the same as the name we passed
into droplet now it here where the it dot well
- the item is currently being checked so
if the name of the current item matches
invisibility potion in our example then
the item gets removed from the list
remove if then moves on to the next item
in the list and repeat the check now if
any items are removed it returns true
otherwise it returns false which is what
we want the function to do so we can
return whatever remove if returns so
let's see it working what I'm going to
do is print out Tim's inventory at the
end of main so we can check that the
invisibility potion has been removed so
we'll go back to our main making sure
that I've actually spoken up the same
here that's been added as invisibility
potion and what is being removed as an
invisibility potion I'm gonna talk tim
dot showing the tree and let's see how
that goes if you run it and you can see
Tim's inventory down the end here the
invisibility potion which was there and
the previous call has now been removed
so we've only got the chest armor and
the ring of protection left so that's
working fine now just in case you're
wondering we don't have to use the
material values when calling a function
so we could have done the same thing as
we did before for the blue potion
so according on something like this if
and surround them in parentheses
add a code block and then put Tim show
into the tree and else you're printing
you don't have an invisibility potion so
could do that instead and I'll delete
that call to the show inventory method
so let's run that and you can see we get
the same result in this case with only
the two items left alright so I think we
got to the end of this video now that's
probably quite a bit to digest so go
back and watch the last few videos a few
more times if you need to and go through
step-by-step now it'll make more sense
the more times that you go through it if
you watch this and you aren't following
along I do suggest you go back and
actually type this in as I'm typing it
in what I found when I was learning to
program was that typing the code and
rather than just reading it really
helped to consolidate the
back then of course there wasn't really
much of the way of video tutorials what
we did have was a whole load of
computers released at around the same
time such as the Sinclair zx81 Commodore
pet BBC computer made by acorn and a
whole lot of other machines and there
was also monthly magazines and we learnt
a lot from reading the manuals but also
from typing in the code that was
published in those magazines now
obviously you'll make errors when typing
the coding and debugging the programs to
file the errors or make them work was
also a great way to learn so typing an N
seems to solidify the information and
make it a lot easier to understand so I
certainly recommend that you don't just
watch these videos but you also act and
be typing this in as the video
progresses and in addition also try
modifying the code to try different
things and start up with simple things
such as perhaps adding an extra field to
one of the classes then by making other
improvements you almost certainly get
errors but sorting out the errors is a
great way to increase your understanding
of how it all works now you can't do any
damage the worst that will happen is you
get an error message now that wasn't
always the case by the way it was
possible to speed up the screen on an
early computer called the Commodore pet
by writing certain values to specific
memory locations and if you got that
wrong the display would be permanently
damaged but that's no longer the case
and you keep you literally can't do that
these days with modern computers
basically you can't do any damage to
your computer with Kotlin, so have fun
and try things out all right so I've
hoped you enjoyed this and I'll see you
in the next video.