Alright so continuing on before we
actually get into the layout designer
you want to make sure that Android
studio is using the Android view for the
project pane. So to see whether your own
come over here to the left-hand
pane here and by the way if you've got a
screen that looks similar to that just
click on the project tab to open up the
pane there and you want to make sure
that Android is selected if you're in a
different view things may look a little
bit different so you want to make sure
that you're an Android view which is the
usually the best view to be in when
you're actually working with Android
code you can work in project view if you
prefer but some of the dialogues that
appear when creating layouts for example
actually are different in the two views
and I'm going to mainly be using Android
view for this course and we'll let me
switch to project view when it's
necessary to work with a few files that
don't appear in Android view alright so
now that everything's set up we need to
go to the res folder and expand layout
I'm gonna open it up
he's the res folder I could expand that
and there's our layout folder you
explained that as well
now this res folder by the way is where
all the apps resources things like
images and so forth live so it's the
files in here including all the
subfolders that can't have capital
letters in their names now I'm going to
start by opening this activity and it's
called main dot XML file by double
clicking it now I could have just click
this tab at the top here if I wanted to
instead but if you close it you may need
to know how to open it again and that's
how by double clicking it over here so
when you'll get the layout designer with
a design and a blueprint now on a small
screen you can toggle them on and off
using these two buttons up the top of
you your design and blueprint so I can
select just design or just blueprint or
design and blueprint so depending on how
much screen real estate you've got you
may or may not want to turn those off
now the icons on these buttons by the
way have changed from the previous
versions of Android studio and there's
nothing to say that they won't change
again now if you hover your mouse
pointer over any of the buttons though
you'll get a tooltip to briefly
describes what they do and that can be a
very good way to make sure that you're
clicking the button you want whatever
icon it happens to use so I can hover over that
select design surface as you can see and
I can either click on it there and that
brings up the little pop-up menu and
choose which one I want this click
somewhere else to actually get rid of
the New Year menu all right so that's
very useful if you want to experiment
with things but we're going to be
looking at most of the buttons on the
toolbar anyway so as well as toggling
off either the design or the blueprint
we can also make more room by closing
the project pane and that leaves a more
screen space for our layout so I
normally do close up when working on the
layout designer only come over here just
click on the project tab bear to the
left and that gives us the in this case
the designer and the blueprint showing
on screen at once again we can come up
here if we wanted to and toggle to have
either one of them or both of them I'm
gonna leave both of them on so make sure
now that tell you have got your screen
set up like mine with both the design
and the blueprints showing we're going
to talk about what they are so firstly
the designer then it looks like a real
phone because you're a preview of what
your design is going to look like when
you run the app so that's this one
obviously on the left hand side now the
one on the right hand side well that's
the blueprint so think of that as a sort
of schematic diagram so it shows the a
relative position of things in the
layout but doesn't attempt to show
exactly what they look like everything
is represented in the blueprint by an
outline now there's an important side
effect as a result of this the
computer's got much less work to do when
it renders the blueprint compared to
rendering the designer so that means
that you'll find things work smoother if
you use the blueprint to layout your design
especially on a slow computer or one
without much memory now in this version
of Android studio the blueprint also
shows the constraints all the time and
that's these little zipper things that
you can see here to the right hand side
where it's in the designer they only
appear when you move their mouse into
the design and you can see now that um
in the designer it's not showing them
soon as I move away they disappear now
for that reason if you have a problem
and want to provide a screen shot when
you post a question in the Q&A section
of this course it'll make our job much
easier if you include the blueprint in
the screenshot now personally I normally
work with just the blueprint and toggle
the designer on what I want to check
what it looks like
so I could sit quietly for this video
I'm actually going to leave them both
showing in these in this video and
future videos in this section of the
course okay so the other button that I
want to mention for now is the auto
connect button and that's the button in
the tool bar that looks a lot like a
magnet you can see this one over here
I'm just gonna hover my toolbar up my
mouse over the toolbar don't see the
toolbar tip you can see that if I hover
over it it says turn on auto connect now
this can be a nice feature but it can
sometimes be annoying at the moment you
can see that it was turned off because
I've got the option now to hover over to
turn on auto connect and you can see
that when I've clicked it the slash that
was through the magnet has now
disappeared and that's telling me that
that's no on if I hover my mouse over
there again to toggle I can turn off or
I connect there's a little slash
set-piece through them through the
picture of a magnet now but I'm actually
gonna leave it on for the moment though
by clicking on it again and we'll see
what it does in a minute but let's start
out by getting rid of the holo world
text view widget so I'm gonna select it
by clicking on either the images so
either the image is in the designer or
the blueprint or alternatively I could
also do that in the componentry then my
component tree is not showing at the
moment so I'm come down here and click
on this little option here and that will
show that the component tree which is a
list of views that are in our design so
to delete the hello world I can click
either of these or I could also click
over there but noting that that's now
highlighted in the component tree when
I've clicked that incidentally clicking
on the space outside the images and
deselects it so if you ever want to
deselect something just do that and you
can see that no matter which way I click
I can get it selected and it updates
either the component tree or the
designer and or blueprint depending what
you've got on the screen so making sure
that you've - you've selected the text
view widget I just want to talk about
briefly about this blueprint and how if
you look really carefully it almost
appears that the blueprint looks a bit
like a pair of punk-rock denim jeans and
the zippers also appear when I move my
mouse over the design we talked about
that term before but what we're going to
do now is delete this and to do that I'm
just going to press the del key on my
keyboard and you can see that's now
removed it from the designer the blueprint
and also from the componentry alright so
we're going to add an image view so what
we need to do is use your operating
systems File Manager to find the JPEG
files that we talked about previously
that you hopefully have downloaded by now
now I actually downloaded both of them
to my desktop so I'm just going to open
up finder on my Mac go to my desktop and
I'm actually created a subfolder called
images and if I just bring this over
into the window now you can see that
I've got my two images showing their
ball underscore 100 by 100 and ball
underscore 640 by 480 so what I'm going
to do now is select both of those files
I'm going to right click those and
select copy and obviously if you're on a
Windows or Linux machine you'll do
whatever it was similar in probably ctrl
C on Windows or Linux we want to copy
those and we want to paste them directly
into our project and to do that we go
back into Android studio now in my case
because I've closed the project pane I'm
going to open that and we're going to
make sure that I'm in the res folder and
then we're down here won't expand the
drawable folder because that's actually
where we want to paste them somewhere
right click on this drawable folder and
choose paste and it's asking whether
we're sure that I'm sure that I want to
copy those files into the folder that's
going to be going into you can see there
at the end
res drawable I want to click on OK
because I want to do that and noting now
that the two files have now appeared in
the drawable folder and obviously you
can confirm there that both those files
haven't got any capital letters in the
filenames and I knew that but if you
happen to be using uranium which is
again just to reminder not to use
capital letters if you're using your own
images alright and I've got the drawable
folder and expanded we can see that
those two files are there are they
showing there so what I'm going to do is
make some more space by shrinking the
project pane so let's go ahead and do
that again
clicking on project to close it down
leaving just a constraint layout to the
left and also our designer and blueprint
views now the image view widget is in
the images section in the widget palette
now the palettes not open for me at the
moment I'm going to click on this option
here little tab and you can see that
that brings the palette open and that
will also toggle so I can click on and
click on it again to actually hard if
you want to do that
and to harder the game just incidental
if you want to close up once you've
opened you can just click on that little
button there and that closes it down I'm
going to leave it open because what we
want to do is get access to the image
view widget as I mentioned it's in the
images section over here to the left and
click on images and you can see there's
our image view widget so once I've done
that I'm going to hold down my left
mouse oh I'm gonna drag it as I would
normally drag an item on a computer you
can just drag it and drop it either on
the design or the blueprint note that
Android studio cleverly shows its
position on both the design and the
blueprint so I'm gonna start by dropping
it in the top left-hand corner now
notice that line or notice the lines
that will appear once I get close to the
top of left edges and you can see now
that we've got a line a horizontal and a
vertical line just in the top left hand
corner of the image and I'm still
holding my down my mouse button at this
point and I'm gonna release the mouse
button now once I do that you'll get to
this pop-up this resources dialog now
what I can do I can either start typing
the name of the image in this case ball
and the box at the top or I can scroll
down and find the image that I'm looking
for and obviously in this case we've
only got a few images and though they're
appearing right at the top here but in a
complex project you might have to do
some scrolling to find it and father I
want to click it there's a neat preview
that will show up to the right-hand side
that actually shows you what the image
is going to look like and confirms the
picture itself so what I'm going to do
first is click on the ball 640 by 480
that's the one that were going to be
using at this point I'm going to click on ok,
we should find the image you know
appears which it has in the designer and
the blueprint now it's top left corner
will be roughly where we dropped the
image view when you first dragged it
onto the layout now one of the things
that has changed a few times is the
exact behavior when you drop an image
onto the layout the point here is that
you're learning how this layout designer
works and how to create layouts that
look like what you want so you might get
slightly different behavior on your
screen at first but that's fine we're
going to be looking at how you can
position things exactly where you want
them so don't worry if things do look a
little bit different at the moment so
over in the top right here is what used
to be called the inspector so I'll
continue calling it that
you can see that there's constraints set
to the left and to the top here got
these little lines that hover to the top
and then to the left but they were set
automatically and they reflect the lines
that appeared when I dropped the image
all right so what I'm gonna do is delete
that image for you and then I'm going to
go through it again to show how that
behavior changes depending on where you
initially drop the widget so I'm going
to select the image view I can select it
either with the either by clicking on
the image view in the component tree or
by selecting the image anywhere from the
designer or the blueprint and then I'm
going to press Delete on the del button
and that removes it from our screen as
you can see now this time what I'm going
to do is drop the image view widget at
the center of the screen I'm going to
grab it again I think I write down right
down to the center of the screen noting
that I've moved it around a little bit
until it if the lines at the top left
right and below we knew we got the four
lines showing on the screen there so
basically what that means is with those
lines showing both the vertical the
horizontal line sort of going through
the image that should mean that the
image is now centered vertically as well
as horizontally so I'm going to release
the mouse it's going to ask us for the
name again I'm gonna choose ball
underscore 640 by 480 and I'm gonna
click on OK now the difference is quite
subtle but this time is constraints in
all four edges you can see over here in
the inspector top left bottom right have
all got lines then notice I said don't
worry too much if your screen doesn't
much doesn't match mine exactly we're
going to see how to create these
constraints rather than relying on them
being created automatically and in fact
I'm also going to explain what
constraints are because I've used that
word a few times now and really haven't
explained what it means in fact it may
not even be apparent to you what I'm
referring to so let's delete them now
there's a couple of ways to delete
constraints we can either do it in the
layout or in the inspector so what I'm
going to do is delete the top constraint
by clicking on this circular constraint
handle as you can see this up here in
the middle of the image views top edge
you notice that when I hovered over
there with a mouse have turned to red
and after a few seconds the tooltip
appears saying delete connection now
that only happens if you selected the
widget so if you don't see those circles
click on the image of you first to
select the image view and then hover
your mouse over to the constraint and I
can press the del button to actually
delete that constraint or I can just
click on it again and by clicking on it
that actually deletes the constraint so
you can see that the image moved out a
little bit and the line that was
appearing here in the inspector has now
disappeared okay so it's deleted the
connection and we can see there's no
longer a constraint set in the inspector
it's in fact we've new only got three
constraints at the left right and bottom
of the widget so you can see them here
these lines here left over here right
and then bottom and obviously in the
inspector we can see an equivalent to
view of what's left but there is another
way to delete them and that's to use the
circles in the inspectors having come
over here let's go ahead and do that
let's delete the right and the bottom
one so I'm gonna come over here and just
click on that noticing how it turned
into an excess I click on delete and do
the right way and then to click on the X
there as well and that's now left only
the left constraint that's the only one
that's there now then I can go ahead if
I want to and I can just hover over the
left-hand constraint click on the button
to delete it and you can see we've now
got no constraints left for our images
and we can also see there's no lines in
the inspector showing that there are any
constraints so basically what this means
is that our image is now unconstrained
and that means there's nothing to keep
it in place on the screen now it is sort
of appearing in the center but and this
is important that's only because it has
to appear somewhere so imagine that
you're creating a collage by placing a
load of photographs maybe some magazine
articles things like that onto a large
piece of card you'll get everything
nicely positioned but you haven't used
any glue so as soon as you pick the card
up everything's going to fall off and
that's because there's nothing holding
all the photos and articles in place so
thinking about layout without
constraints as being just like that so
we've got an image on the screen but
there's no glue to fix that image in
place so what constraints are well
they're like glue because they fix the
widget in place without constraints to
which it will effectively fall off the
screen when you run the app now of
course it will really fall off the
screen it will be actually be positioned on
screen in fact in the top left-hand
corner of the screen but if you've got
several unconstrained widgets they'll
all appear at the top left so you what
you'll do is you'll get one on top of
the other all right so we're going to
finish the video in a moment but firstly
notice on either the designer or the
blueprint there's these little handles
on each of the four corners of the image
view these ones here and notice when I
move my mouse there they actually change
and day you can see if I hover over that
it says resize viewing and when I
actually click on into there the mouse
pointer changes to the normal resize
pointer for whatever operating system
you're running on so let's actually just
get into here to the bottom and
depending on what you can see on the
screen there you might find that the
entire image no longer fits the designer
because we've removed all the
constraints but just select one that you
can what I'm going to do is select the
bottom right one so they might take a
little bit of fine-tuning to get to
exactly where you want I'm going to move
this and I'm just kind of drag it so
occupies you know right about a quarter
of the screen like so then release the
mouse button.
So just what you do now before you start
the next video is just practice resizing
the image using the for handles you can
see now it's a little bit easy to get
access to all for now just say familiar
with the concept of ream resizing images
and you'll be ready to go for the next
video. Alright so this video has become
quite a long one I'm gonna finish the
video here now in the next video we're
gonna talk more about constraints and
resizing widgets so see you in the next video.