So I mentioned towards the end of the
last video that the Android studio
layout designer makes it easier to see
how things look on different devices so
we're going to add a button to our
layout to demonstrate this. So I'm going
to start off with an image view set to
wrap content both vertically and
horizontally and we did that in the last
video you can see layout width and
height is wrapped content you can see
the Chevron's which indicate that we
also want to make sure that our
constraints are at the top left right
and bottom of the image view to the
screen and that's obviously a set as
well as you can see here next we want to
make sure that auto connect is off
there's this little button over here
what I connect which are talked about
briefly before we want to make sure that
that's actually off we can sell when
it's actually off because there's a
slash that's appearing through the
little magnet icon so I'm going to do
that to make sure that that's turned off
next what we're going to do is drag a
button to the top left of the screen
slightly in from both edges I'm going to
do that just in slightly and from both
headers like so and release the button
and once I've done that you can see over
here that oh we've got some warnings new
that's because there aren't any
constraints there so I can click on show
warnings missing constraints in
constraint layout so to fix it up I'm
just going to add a constraint from the
button to the top of the screen and also
add a constraint from the button to the
left of the screen that fixes up that
error you won't worry about these other
errors for now we'll talk about those
later and I'll close it down and what
we're going to do now is change the left
constraint on the image so that it's no
longer constrained to the edge of the
screen but to the right-hand edge of the
button instead so I click on the image
view you can see that clearly we've got
two constraint to the left of the screen
so we're going to remove that and
constrain it to the right of the button
so I want to click on the image views
left button left circle if flash is red
and I click on delete connection and it
removes the left constraint and what I
can do now I'm gonna drag the circle to
the right-hand edge of the button so I'm
gonna click on it and then drag it over
and in earlier versions of Android
studio by the way you could drag the
constraint handle to anywhere along the
edge of the button or
widget you were constraining to that's
now change and you have to drag to the
constraint handle on the other widget so
that's the constraint handle on the
button in this case now notice since I'm
holding the mouse button down that the
constraint handle for the button is
flashing green and that's a visual
indication that we should be aiming for
that or not anywhere else on the buttons
right edge I'm just gonna move over here
now and constrain it release the mouse
button and we've now got a constraint
from the left of the image view to the
right of the button so basically the
left-hand edge of the image view is now
constrained by the right hand into the
button so that the image view itself can
occupy all the space from the right of
the button up to the screens right edge
now if new look up the image centered in
the space between the button to the
right-hand edge of the layout now
depending on what version of Android
studio you're running you may actually
have to click on the image view and make
sure that your margins are set correctly
in my case is set correctly to 16 to the
right and 16 to the left of the image
view to make sure that you truly are
centered in the middle and by the way
because we're using the wrap we're using
wrap underscore content the image view
is 100 by 100 but we want to play with
the unit so what I'm going to do is
change it to fixed by clicking on the
inner lines again because this is the
image view so click on the image
uihlein's so doing that changes the
layout width to layout height to reflect
the last sizes that we've specified so
if by some reason yours aren't set to
100 DP by 100 DPS mine are here then
just type them in manually there to see
what's wrong with using pixel
measurements what I'm going to do now
has changed both the DP sizes to 200 px
px standing for pixels so I'll go ahead
and do that so I'm topping 200px I'm
just going to tab over 200 px again and
press Enter now the image is still
centered where it should be
notice that it hasn't changed size so on
this device the nexus 4 200 PX is equal
to 100 DP then that's fine on this
screen so let's see how it looks on
other devices now
by the way I can choose different
devices using this drop-down over here
from the designers button bar now the
next is one is quite old so let's choose
that first and see what happens and you
can see that everything still looks
pretty good but the image is bigger than
it was relative to the size of the
screen but even worse there is something
like one of the Android wear devices so
let's go ahead and click that again
you'll come down here and choose is 320
by 2 90 round chin now looking at the
blueprint rather than the design because
the design now renders as a circle
that's because we're devices are like
watches and this one has a circular
screen the things I think you would
agree are getting a little bit hideous
now with the image overlapping the
button and extending beyond the
right-hand edge of the screen and the
buttons also messed up in the design
because we created a layout for a tip
for a rectangular screen but don't worry
about that because we're looking at how
things size at the moment now to get
around this and make images display
reasonably on all devices Android uses a
concept of device independent pixels or
DP now one DP is equal to one pixel at a
resolution of 160 pixels per inch but
scours to use more or less pixels as the
pixel density of the screen changes so
I'm going to go back to our original
Nexus 4 device and what we going to do
is change the sizes back to 100 DP and
this rate and 100 DP is about the same
as 200px so everything should still look
the same now let's switch back to the
Android wear device again and see what
it looks like you can see now that we've
done that everything still looks ok
ignoring the circular display of course
now these are pretty extreme differences
from a 768 by 1280 Nexus to a 320 by 2
90 watch but using density-independent
pixels DP instead of pixels allows the
widgets to be resized to still look ok
and remain usable now of course you'll
eventually run into the physical limitation
of a small screen if you have more in
your layout than will fit now if I
choose the 280 by to have you watch just
to show you down here the things just
physically won't fit so using DPS can
only achieve so much you know if you
were creating an app to run on a
wearable device then you design the
layouts using one and Android studio
does fully support wearables but we're
not going to be covering that in this
course but using the watch made it
really obvious how using DPS they'd be
preferred have over pixels when sizing
images and other widgets I'm going to
switch back to the Nexus 4 because that
watch is a little bit small on the video
to show a similar device independent way
of specifying text size then when I come
over here and click on the button to
select it the attributes window change
to the right and I can come down here to
text appearance and you might find that
that is sized up like that if it is just
click on the little check the little
arrow to expand it out and what we can
do is set the or see the font size and
that's the text size here so here the
units are SP which stands for scale
independent pixel the concept is the
same but SP also considers the users
preferred text size now what I'm going
to do is change this text size to 32 px
and although that's a little large it
still displays okay here now if we
switch back to our device our watch that
we're using before the 320 by 2 90 you
can see that we've got to be of a
problem now the button L overlaps the
area where the image is constrained to
appear now 32px on our original device
for 16 SP so I can change the size here
to 16 SP by typing that in the text size
let's build it looks okay well okay
because it's still a bit large for the
screen but so what is clear is that the
buttons now moved or clear of the image
and if we go back to the Nexus 4 device
everything still looks fine now there's
a useful
scription of DP and SP on androids
developer website I'm gonna just uh
putting that up on the screen and was
going to paste in this link the good
reading just to read up a little bit
more on what density independent pixels
are the bottom line here is to use
density independent pixels when sizing
graphical elements and scale independent
pixels when sizing text alright so I'm
going to finish this video by mentioning
that this isn't quite the full story
it's possible to provide images at
different resolutions and Android will
choose the one that's most appropriate
for the device that the apps are running
on now we're going to be looking at
doing that later in the course but I'll
mention it briefly because I promised to
explain how come our 640 wide image was
wider than a 768 screen we're scrolling
down on this page about halfway down you
can see here we've got this provide
alternative bitmap section they were
going to be providing alternative images
later in the course
for now though what's interesting in
this section is the scaling factors for
the different densities so notice here
on the screen that X hate DPI has a
scaling factor of two so we go back to
Android studio and drop down the list of
devices and we can see that our nexus 4
is an xhdpi device so a 640 by 480 px
image was scoured by two to become 1280
by 960 pixels which is wider than the
screen so as an exercise use the source
compat attribute to load the ball
underscore 640 by 480 image back into
the image view and specify its width and
height to be 640 PX by 480 px that'll
confirm that it does fit and was scaled
up when the DP units were used and just
as a hint delete the left constraint
this is not enough space to the right of
the button but I'll leave that with us
and exercise and see you in the next video.