Alright so let's go ahead now and add
these two buttons to the bottom right of
the layout. Now the buttons will appear
under the widgets category click on
widgets now I'm going to select button
I'm going to drag it right down to the
bottom right hand corner now notice that
when I do that and the guidelines appear
both horizontally and vertically when I
release my button the mouse button
we've surprisingly got constraints on
the right hand side and on the bottom
side so it's no constraint to the bottom
right of the layout and in this case
it's exactly what I wanted to happen now
it's pretty cool but only works if you
get those guidelines before dropping the
widget so let's see if it works out what
to do though with the second button now
this second button is going to be the
okay button and we'll go to the left of
the first one so the only aim here is to
drop it about 16 DP to the left of the
first button I'm gonna select that drag
it over around about 16 DP to the left
of the first button and release now in
this case we've only got one constraint
and that's what I'll do is I'll delete
that again as I try and move it so it's
around about in that area release it you
can see it hasn't quite got it right
here we've got a constraint just at the
bottom at the moment and if you don't
get the left-hand button constrain to
the right one you can just create the
constraint manually and I'm going to go
ahead and do that it's gonna see at the
moment we've only got a constraint from
the button to the bottom of the layout
so we're going to constrain it to the
left constrain the right of the second
button to the left of the first one and
you can see we've now got two
constraints now even though that's
happened that's not quite what we want
the two buttons should be aligned to
each other vertically and a lot of this
sort of does that they asked sealed
independent now let's put some text in
the buttons so that we can refer to them
as okay and cancel and that'll make it a
little bit clearer on what I'm talking
about I'm going to make sure that the
left button is clicked which it is and I
come up over here into text they're
going to type in okay I just press ENTER
and you can see that the text has updated
that button. Now be careful when doing
that and use the text attribute and not
the one below that with the wrench or
spanner before it now any attribute you
see an inspector marked with the wrench
is a tool attribute and that means that
it only affects the display in the
layout designer tool attributes are
ignored when the app runs on a device
all right so now if I drag the okay
button up the screen you can see that
it's no longer aligned with the cancel
button now there's a number of ways that
we can get the effect we want I could
constrain the bottom of the okay button
to the bottom of the cancel button or
perhaps constrain its top to the top of
the cancel button now either of those
would work fine but when you're dealing
with widgets containing text it's also
useful to be able to line up the
baseline of the text rather than the
edges of the widget now both our buttons
rather are the same size and only
contain a single line of text so
constraining the tops or bottoms would
work but I want to show you how to
create a baseline constraint especially
because it can be a little bit fiddly
what I'll do first so as I just changed
the text on the other button to cancel
making sure that I'm not using the
attribute with the wrench cancel press
ENTER there to update it
and go back to the okay button by
selecting it again all right so Beth
both our buttons are the same size and
only contain a single line of text as I
said so we could constrain the tops or
bottoms and that would work but what I
really want to do is show you how to
create a baseline constraint again
because it can be quite fiddly now I
said previously that there were four
constraint handles one on each edge of
the widget but there's actually a fifth
on widgets that contain text and it's an
oval right in the middle of the button
but it doesn't actually appear until you
ask for it so making sure that you've
selected the okay button which I've done
and it's got this other little button
down here now called a B and I'll just
move the cursor away there briefly so
that disappears and if you come over
here you see the a B an init baseline
and I click on that that because that
causes the baseline constraint handle to
become available
and you can see that's no appeared in
the middle of the okay button now when I
click that and start to drag every
widget that supports baseline
constraints gets an oval head or in the
middle and I'm just going to start that
by just selecting it and notice now that
in the cancel button we've also got that
baseline and also in the text view at
the top left hand corner you can see one
there as well so I'm just going to
release the mouse button and you can see
that they disappear again I've got a
whole were at the end now and also the
text edit as well has also got that
baseline the oval so what we want to do
is hover over the eye of the oval until
the handle flashes I'll just do that
again just to make it clear so hover
over it until it flashes then you can
hold down or click your left mouse
button that then enables that for
dragging and what we want to do at this
point now is to drag the oval into the
cancel button and just before I do that
though it is important to wait for that
that flash before you create a baseline
constraint more so than with the other
four constraints and you'll discover the
problem for yourself when you start
inadvertently dragging widgets around
the screen so now you know the solution
alright so I'm still will still have the
button selected and I'm gonna drag the
oval from the okay button into the
cancel button and then release the mouse
button to create the constraint so ever
do that release it and you can see we've
now got a constraint from the okay
button to the cancel button now by the
way if there was a constraint from the
top or bottom of the okay button that
will have been deleted and that's
because you can't have top and bottom
constraints as well as a baseline
constraint so in other words you can
constrain the top and bottom of the
button or you can constrain its baseline
you can't do both so notice if the top
and bottom constraint handles have now
disappeared from the okay button so the
okay button is now constrained
vertically to remain lined up with the
baseline of the cancel button now a
baseline constraint like this is
different to constraining the top or
bottom of the button in this case it's
the actual text that lines up so if the
buttons are different heights the layout
looks better
and that's because the text itself is
aligned now when it was constrained to
the bottom edge of the layout that
allowed me to drag it up and down the
screen the only thing that changed was
the distance from the bottom of the
layout so now though it's constrained to
the center button so if I try to drag
the okay button up and down you'll find
that nothing happens I can drag it left
or right but I physically can't now drag
it up to any higher than the cancel
button but even cooler though watch what
happens when I drag the cancel button up
or down when the cancel button moves up
and down the OK button
follows it and that's because of the
vertical constraint I can put that back
to where it was now I might just tidy
this up a little bit by changing the
margins to 16 for both
now whether i'd constrain the top bottom
or baseline that would still be the case
the ok button can't be moved vertically
and that's because it's constrained to
the cancel button and when the kids our
button moves vertically the ok button
follows no notice also that when the ok
button selected up in the inspector
it shows the death sort of like a
downwards arrow to indicate that there
is a constraint but we can't change the
margin value like you can with the
constraint to the right so you can see
that there's no facility for me to
change that margin and that's because
baseline constraints in fact don't have
margins all right so let's select the
edit text widget again you can see at
the moment that it's constrained to the
right-hand edge of the screen so what
this constraint to the right-hand side
now ideally it should grow as text is
entered and if you remember from earlier
that means that we should set the height
to wrap content by clicking the inner
lines in the inspector I'm going to do
that in a minute but first what I'm
going to do is put some text into it so
you can see what's happening now
normally you'd allow the user to enter
text in there while the app is running
but to save having to type in a load of
text in the emulator I'm going to pay
some text into the text property here
instead and press Enter
and that text is available in the
resources section of
so that so you can do that yourself as
well if you're following along so I'm
going to come over here to the text
again I'm making sure that I'm not
clicking on the text with the wrench and
I'm going to paste in the text and press enter
now it doesn't expand until the layout
height property is set to wrap content
so if you add a text widget isn't set to
wrap content then you'll want to change
it now in my case you can see that it is
set at the moment to wrap content all
right it so that wasn't really quite
what I had in mind now I wanted the
widget to expand to fill its text but I
definitely don't want it extending that
far down the screen so the mini
challenge is to work out why it's done
that and what we should do to prevent
that from happening so I'm going to end
the video here now I'm going to leave
you to see if you can come up with a
solution to that problem and in the next
video we'll start by going through how
to resolve it, so I'll see you in the
next video.