Alright so we've still got the image
to add but before doing that let's run
the program and see how it behaves and
that'll also give us a chance to see how
the layout and the code work together.
Now what we need to do though is make a
change to the code so expand the project
pane if it's not open we want to come
down here and make sure that we're in
the Java folder because if you recall
the Java folder contain the source files
which ultimately contain our code we're
going to open up the package in this
case Academy don't learn programming
directivity and there's this main
activity you know there's only the one
class here at this time but in more
complicated apps you'd see that there
would be a lot more classes so I'm going
to double click that now to open loop
and in main activity the layer is used
by this setcontentview statement on line
10 and that tells the app which layout
to use when it runs now I guess that's a
slight oversimplification but so with
any one class that's totally accurate so
instead of using our layout dot activity
underscore main we need to change that
to our dot layout got note under School
layout to use the layout until we've
been working on and just created in the
previous video so I'm going to delete
that and I'll just tap press the period
or dot and notice when I've done that
we've automatically got an option here
Android studio knows which layouts are
available in your project and it's
suggesting the note layout literally
silicide entered that period or type
that period and sometimes it doesn't do
it that quickly if you type the first
few letters of the layout you're looking
for it'll find it in the drop-down and
obviously using a drop-down is more
convenient because it saves typing but
also help you to guard against hopping
errors so instead of typing but allow
them just going to press into there all
right so that's really the only change
we need to make it this time to the code
so we've told the app now which layout
to use when it runs so I'm going to
close down the Kotlin class and I'm
going to close the project pane again
I'm going to make sure that no times
called layout select it again which it
is and let's just run that to see what
it looks like.
Alright so there's the app running.
Now it doesn't look too bad at all although
I still need to change the text in the
text view in the top right hand corner
but there is a problem though and it'll
become a parent as soon as I'll start
trying to type something into the other
text but firstly when I click in the
edit text you can see the on-screen
keyboard appears and things gonna be
wrong then the keyboard is partially
obscuring the edit text so I can't
actually get to the end I can try
scrolling so I'm trying to scroll
simulating like a scroll but I can
actually get to the end of the text you
can see it's sort of just jumping around
and just generally not quite working correctly
no no not I really allowing us to get to
the end now this might appear to be two
problems but the cause is the same so I
can't scroll the text right to the end
and I can also can't add any more text
to the end for that reasons I can't get
down there to do that but as it happens
fixing that issue also prevents the
keyboard from obscuring the edit text
widget and that's really the real cause
here now one thing I want to point out
though is that I can't give you all the
answers I can show you a good variety of
layouts in this course but I can't
predict every layout that you want to
create in your own apps nor how they'll
have to interact with things like the
keyboard what I will do is try and show
you as many potential problems as I can
such as this one here and I will also
look at different ways to get the same
effect by changing the constraints we
use but it's important that you really
get the hang of the layout design
yourself and also important what is
important to think about your layouts
not us fix things but more as fluid
designs that move around if the user
does things on the phone or tablet now
this layout is a great example of one
that looks good in theory but falls over
slightly in practice
so let's actually see what we can do
about it so I'm just going to go back
into Android studio now now I've clicked
on edit text all was already selected
anyway one thing to notice here is that
it's set to be centered vertically in
the available space now that doesn't
really make sense here it should really
always be positioned at the top just
below the title and then grow downwards
as it needs to so I need to set the
vertical bias to zero
and that's the same is true for the
horizontal bias now it's visually
obvious which way you need to go so I'm
going to drag the vertical bias to the
top as I mentioned and set that to zero
and also I'm going to drag the
horizontal slider to the left as well to
make that zero so now we've got both the
vertical and horizontal biases set to
zero now we do get questions about what
difference this makes and often it
doesn't make any difference with less
text and the layout underscore height or
layer and let's go a width set to wrap
content it will however make a
difference but that's actually got
nothing to do with our problem so what
we need to do is to make the edit text
scrollable vertically now the edit text
could already be scrolled but without
the scroll bars actually being set the
layout doesn't collapse it out of the
way of the keyboard so to turn on the
vertical scroll bar what we need to do
is expand the full set of properties and
we do this by clicking on these two
little arrows up here in the inspector
and then we're going to search through
the large the alphabetical list until we
find the scrollbar setting now remember
that your might need to use this cog
over here to select all that jeebies so
if I click on that and you might be in
that mode there so if you see that a
mode that looks similar to that just
come back here and click on all
attributes table and you'll get to the
right view all right so let's scroll
down now, so we can see this scrollable attribute
there's scrollbars you know spared that
as you can see and we want to set that
to vertical so I'm going to click on
vertical you can see it updates over
here now now we're also going to set the
scroll indicators that stays a little
bit further up which I'll expand and
we're doing that to provide a visual cue
that the contents are scrollable now we
want to click over here come over here
and click on right select that and also
end and you can see that though we've
got both selected now now start and end
properties were introduced in API 17 and
they're designed to provide the expected
behavior with the languages that are
written from right to left Arabia can
person for example so but you think
start instead of left and end instead of
right you're allowing your app to cope
with right-to-left languages now if
you're targeting Android versions prior
to API 17 as we are then you should also
set a left or right as well so that
those earlier versions also work now the
scroll indicators provide a visual
indication that a widget can be scrolled
and also indicate how far through the
contents you've already scrolled so note
that they were introduced in API 23 sets
wouldn't have any effect on early
versions of Android all right so now
that we've enabled scrolling the enter
text widget should be scrollable so
let's run the app again to test that but
first I'm going to change the text in
the text view to constraint layout so
I'm just going to click over here and
we're going to close down this mode and
go back to our normal mode and let's
change the text there and we'll call it
two constraint layout so notice how the
width of the edit text changes and
that's because it's constrained to the
right-hand edge of the textview and keep
in mind also that sometimes it takes a
little while for the blueprint to update
after a change like this so that causes
the other text to become narrower
because it's constrained to the
right-hand edge of the textview.
Alright so let's try running the program again
so now that I've run it again Android
Studios instant run will install the
changes and restart the application and
that's actually quite a nice feature
that first appeared in Android studio
1.5 now it could cause a few problems
with apps not restarting but the bugs
seem to have been ironed out now and it
makes the whole process of testing
changes a lot faster than it used to be
so you can see here now we've got a
different layout there well it looks
different now because we've added the
scroll the scrolling capability you can
see that the app is now functioning
different to what differently to what it
was before firstly we know automatically
at the bottom you can see the bottom of
the edit text and also the keyboard is
now not obscuring the text and I should
be able to scroll up and down now you
can also see over here if you look
carefully the visual representation of
us scrolling up and also where we are in
the text so that's all working nicely now
against you sir I can get right down to
the bottom as well now keep in mind as I
mentioned it's scrollable and you saw
that it was scrollable and the scroll
indicators are appearing on the right
but those scrolling indicators only will
appear on devices running Android
marshmallow or later now it still can be
scrolled in all versions but it's only
the indicators that don't appear and
again scrolling the text of the edit
text also fixed the other problem we had
and you can see now that so we can
scroll right to the end of the text and
I can actually add more timwas here if I
so desire alright so there's just the
image to add now so what we want to do
is go back to Android studio and we want
to drag an image view onto the left of
the design just below the title so we
come over here and click on images image
view and we're just going to put that
just below the title don't put it about
there and what we want to do is because
that's come up automatically is you want
to select the ball underscore 100 by 100
so like that okay then we want to
constrain the top of the image view to
the bottom of the text view so let's do
that first
there the left edge of the image view
should be constrained to the left edge
of the screen and the right edge of the
image view should be constrained to the
left edge of the init text widget so
let's go ahead and do that so I'm gonna
we can see that in this case the left
constraint has already been added so if
yours hasn't been added didn't do that
but we also want to constrain as I
mentioned the right edge of the image
view to the left edge of the editing so
I can go ahead and do that now the other
thing to do is also make sure that the
layout width is set to match underscore
con constraint otherwise the image may
run off their left edge of the screen
and you can see at the moment I've got
that set to wrap content so I'm gonna
change layout width for set to match
constraint all right so let's actually
run the app again and see how it behaves
you can see that it's gonna move that
over a little bit that looks pretty good
and you can see that we've got our text
there we can still scroll that up and
down I can hide the keyboard
and see more of the edit text now and
that's still looking good so let's just
move that over to landscape and have a
look so any landscape and by the way you
should always test your layouts in both
portrait or landscape as well as on a
range of different devices such as a
phone and a tablet so you can see that
it looks pretty good in portrait and
landscape now the two buttons on the
side of the emulator by the way lets you
rotate the device as you saw me click so
I can go back and click it the other way
go back to portrait again it really
makes a great way to easily test layouts
without having to run it on a physical
Android device all right so that's the
end of our introduction to the layout
designer that Google have produced for
Android studio now we've actually
covered quite a lot including some of
the widgets available and how to place
them on the design now we also saw how
to use constraints to make sure that the
widgets appear where we want them even
when screen size and orientation change
now we've covered the different types of
constraint and how they affect the
behavior of widgets that are constrained
to each other now the inspector is very
useful and we've seen how to use that to
change the sizing of widgets as well as
their position within the constraints
the margins and the vertical and
horizontal sliders can also be used to
set the bias from the inspector Google's
aim with this new layout designer was to
make it possible to do everything you
need to do without having to edit xml
and i'd say they've largely succeeded
there is one time when you definitely
need to view their xml though now you've
noticed that just put this back on the
screen neither the blueprint norther
design make it easy to check all the
constraints at once and there's no way
to display all the properties on the
screen at once not unless you cut out
three meter higher screen so if you have
problems with a layout and want to post
a question about it a screenshot alone
will probably not help us to work out
what's going on in that case if you do
want help with a layout that's not doing
what you want
please select all the XML and paste it
into your question that way we can see
everything that's said in it and they're
gonna be coming back to that later and
give you some tips to make you know and
make it easy to compare your XML with
mine all right so that's the end of this
video in the next one what we're going
to do is create an app that does more
than just display things on the school
we'll get it so that clicking a button
actually does something. I'm gonna stop
that up with a challenge though just to
warn you the next video will start with
a challenge to design the layout that
we're going to be using in the app.
So I'll see you in that next video.