in the previous video we added some
debug logging to our app now in this
video we're gonna have a look at what it
does and how it can be useful now at the
bottom of the Android studio screen or a
couple of panes that can be really
useful when you get around to running
your apps now the first one down here is
the run window so run the what I'm going
to do is run the app now just confirm
that we can see that running let's see
that running now they're going to click
on the run tab over here to actually see
some information about it and it starts
off showing the adb commands that
Android studio uses to install and run
the device now we're going to be looking
at adb which is the Android debug bridge
a lot later in the course
but if you get problems running your
apps then we may ask you to have a look
in here and paste any error messages
into the discussion and Q&A area
now hopefully Android studio will
connect your emulator or device if
you've got a slow system with less than
say 8 gigabytes of RAM then it's a good
idea to start your emulator manually and
you can see that in videos that I've
been doing in some cases I've been
running the emulator having the emulator
already running and by the way you can
do that from the AVD manager that we saw
in section 3 now starting the emulator
before you start coding we'll give it
time to start up and saves you having to
wait when you run your app ok so that's
the run tap the second tab is used for
once your app actually runs and I'm
ignoring the to do at this stage and it
used to be called the Android monitor
pane but in Android studio 3 is now been
renamed to logcat and this is one here
and possibly they renamed it because
that's what most people called it anyway
now the lock kansai click that that
shows all sorts of things that are
happening on any connected device or
emulator and with a real device you'd
see loads of entries appearing in him
and you probably also see some warnings
and probably some errors as well and
most of these will have nothing to do
with your app so the trick here is to
work out what's what because there can
be a lot of output in here but
fortunately we can filter that now over
to the far right here is a drop down and
at the moment you can see that it's been
set to show
any selected application now you might
think that that's enough and we don't
need to provide a filter as well but it
also shows all sorts of system events
now if we want a full picture of what's
being locked we can change this drop
down to no filters sub done there now
now we get a ton about put aside scroll
up you can see there's a lot lot of
information there and that's with the
emulator just sitting there not really
doing much and all of that might be
useful to Google engineers but I think
at this point it's fairly confusing to
us so what I'm going to do is put that
back to show only the selected
application again show any selected
application now if you're debugging more
than one app at once
maybe you've created a GUI app and a
service for example then you select
which one to display in the second
drop-down over here so the second from
the left
and you could choose which particular
app that you're wanting to get the
output for you can see that there's
quite a few what Android apps that are
actually running right now on this
emulator but you can see that's ours
they obviously by the name alright so
I'm going to leave that on but encounter
apps tool which is our app and we can
look at what happened when we launch the
app now if we scroll back to the top of
the entries and if you scroll I don't
have a look we should be able to see the
oncreate method message that we actually
put into our code and there's the own
create called message so that's the text
we used in the log d call or at least
the last part is the uncreate called
the rest has been added automatically by
Android to the left-hand side alright so
there's still a lot of other stuff there
you can see here that we're not really
interested in at this stage so we can
tidy up this log a little bit more so
there's a search box towards the
right-hand side over here so what we can
do is we can further filter what's being
displayed and that's one of the reasons
for providing the tag that we did in the
previous video in our login call our tag
was main activity so I'm going to type
main activity into the Box main activity
and you can see that toe we've got one
create corner which was the message now
I suggest always typing in lowercase
here by all means experiment but
generally you'll get
better results with lower case basically
lower case will always work but if you
try to match the case of the tag and
make a mistake and it doesn't work so
I'm going to quickly demonstrate that by
deleting the contents of the box and
typing main this time with a capital M
and that's obviously working fine but if
I then start to add activity but using a
lowercase a I see you can see that the
log out port has disappeared in other
words nothing matches so all the log
entry is disappear and once again
experiment after you watch this in the
next video alright so I'm going to put
that main activity back in lower case
again and we only get the log entry
entries from our main activity class you
know at the moment there's only one
entry on create court and we'll be
adding some more but at the moment I
just want to get you familiar with
filtering the logcat now if you recall
we also added login to the buttons
onclicklistener so i'm going to switch
over to the emulator now type in some
text click on the button and you can see
what happe r in the log captor pane
basically every time the buttons tapped
we're going to get that second message
if you just go back and just click it a
few more times
you can see it's being outputted into
the vodka pain every time that button is
actually tapped so that's pretty cool
and it's a very useful way to see when
you miss it when your methods get called
now I've been telling you that the
activity will be destroyed and recreated
when the device is rotated if that's the
case we should see uncreate being called
again when we switch to landscape now
before I do that there's something else
I want to show you and it's not obvious
since also not documented at least as
far as we've been able to find now we
can quickly end up with a lot of log
entries even with the filters that we've
set up and that can make working out
what's just happened quite difficult now
fortunately we can break up these log
entries a bit what we're about to do is
rotate the device into landscape so we
can add a comment to that effect in the
log cap now if we move further I'll
click the mouse after the last entry in
the log cat we actually get a line break
as you can see there the cursor moved
out and if we type in that something
here's our rotating intern landscape
press ENTER again and now we're going to
go back and rotate the device into
landscape and if I do that
you can see what's happened that
obviously the device has been rotated
into landscape mode and that's expected
we can see the uncreate being caught
again and now that we've actually topped
in that message it's very easy to see
which methods were called after we did
that so if we then had come back here
and then add another message back to
portrait then go back to the device your
emulator then go back to portrait we can
see that our log cat is telling us that
oncreate scored again and also now the
layout of the log is probably a lot more
intuitive now this is going to be far
more informative when we log the rest of
the lifecycle methods but already you
can see there's a great way to see
what's going on with our apps and which
of our methods the android framework is
calling now I said that this ability to
type comments into the lock head is
undocumented it's been working for the
last few releases of Android studio but
that doesn't mean it's kind of going to
continue to work and the reason for that
is Google changes things all the time so
make use of it while long while as long
as it lasts or as long as it lasts and
if you find that you can no longer type
into the logcat you just have to accept
that the facilities been removed for
whatever reason now the last time I
mentioned in an undocumented feature in
a video Google removed it two weeks
later so I'm just one so that's why I'm
telling you now that it might stop
working all right so that's the logcat
and how to use it
now I haven't mentioned this first
drop-down box and if you've got several
emulators of devices connected and lets
you select which one you want to view
the logs for keep an eye on that because
if you closed down the emulator and
restart it you might end up with one
marked as dead now obviously it won't
log anything if it's not running so use
that drop box if that's the case to
choose the one that is running all right
I'm gonna stop the video here in the
next video we'll add looking to the
other life cycle methods and see exactly
what happens to our app while it's
running so I'll see you in the next
video