in this section we're going to create a
basic calculator as you can see on the
screen and it's going to give us a
chance to practice what we've learnt
about layouts with a more complex
example and we'll also be connecting
code to a lot more buttons than in our
previous button click app in this
section we're going to look at working
with groups of widgets to see how we can
do things like constraining them to be
positioned as a group as well as setting
common properties for multiple widgets
at the same time and we'll also show a
slightly different approach to creating
an onclicklistener
so that the same method can be used by
multiple buttons now this happens you
can see is a basic calculator and in
order to enter numbers using the apps
buttons then perform the calculation
when any of the operation keys are
pressed the plus minus multiply and
divide now the stock Android calculator
builds up the calculation on the screen
and doesn't actually evaluate it until
you press the equal sign but else is
going to evaluate each sum as soon as
you press the next operator just like
early calculators did and we'll have two
lines for display as you can see though
so you will now be able to see both
numbers at once and won't have to
remember the previous one like you did
with those early calculators and also
unlike the early calculators it'll show
you which operation it will perform next
so you don't lose track pressing equals
will update the display with the result
and can also be used to start a new
calculation by transferring the entered
number up into the result ready to use
in the next calculation well let's have
a quick demonstration here of this
calculator app to see how it actually
works so I can enter a number like by
clicking on it 9 and multiply 3 equals
27 then I can also continue with that by
putting 10 multiplied you can see the
values getting updated there and we can
clear it by just pressing equals and I
can type in something like 20 plus to
add 20 to it so I've got the value of
290 and the other thing that we're going
to be doing in this section of the
course is working with both portrait and
landscape versions so if I move this
over to landscape now
you can see we've got a slightly
different result there we've got the
layout looking a little bit different to
take advantage of landscape mode so be
learning how to do that as well I'll
just move that back to portrait note
also that the value that we've been
using stayed there when we moved from
landscape to back to portrait and then
from portrait to landscape and we'll
also be showing you how to do that in
the section for the course as well and
later in this section we're going to
have a look at guidelines which can be
used in a constraint layout to a link
widgets either vertically or
horizontally so that you can anchor
widgets to them all right so let's move
back near to Android studio and we can
start work on this project so let's get
started now creating a new project and
then in the next video we're going to
look at the actual layout of our
calculator so start Android studio and
we're going to click on start a new
Android studio project and I'm gonna
call this calculator I'm going to leave
the company domain name the same learn
programming down Academy now Android
studio is suggesting a suitable location
project location ending with a
calculator directory and you can store
the project somewhere else if you want
but the Android studio normally
remembers where you've told it to create
projects so only the final directory
name changes so I'm going to leave it as
the default on screen there and there's
another important option we have to
select on the screen and that's this
option down here to include Coughlin's
support now remember to tick that box if
you want to generate Kotlin code and
make sure it's unpicked
if you want Java code in my case I'm
going to leave it ticked and click on
next then we're going to continue to use
the minimum SDK of 17 and you can see
this API 17 is already selected here so
you want to make sure that that is
checked and leave everything else
unchecked and then click on next again
now we're not going to have a menu in
this application so empty activity which
is selected here for me automatically is
our best choice for the template to you
so make sure you select that and I click
on Next again and once again we're just
kind of accept the names that Android
studio has suggested for both the
activity name and the layer
and just make sure that both both the
generate layout file and backwards
compatibility app compat check boxes are
checked and then click on finish so
that's the project created I'm going to
leave it just building and in the next
video we'll actually start producing the
layout for our calculator app so I'll
see you in the next video