all right so let's start with the layout
for the calculator app now we already
know exactly what it should look like
because we've seen it running but you
wouldn't normally get to see a program
running before you'd written it now the
obvious thing to do would be to add the
widgets in the order they'll appear on
the screen but you'll often want to add
a widget that you hadn't originally
decided you'd need now to show you how
the layout designer can handle that what
I'm going to do is forget that I need to
enter text widgets and then add the
second one afterwards so as you can see
on screen I'm in the layout designer and
if you've got the project pane open
shrink that to make a bit more room and
you can see that I've already done that
so we want an inner text widget at the
top of the screen and the data entry
widgets are in the section titled text
over here which I can click and open and
connect this a little bit just to see a
bit more now Android actually provides
quite a few widgets for entering data
including three per entering numbers so
we've got number number signed as well
as number decimal now our calculator is
going to allow signed decimal numbers so
we have to choose one of the available
ones and modify it slightly so we're
going to go with the number signed so
we're going to delete near the halliwell
textview so let's do that of course that
was created automatically by Android
studio when the project was created and
what we're going to do is drag one of
these widgets that number saw into the
top of the screen now it's going to be
centered eventually so I'm not worried
about where it's going anywhere at the
top will do for now I'm just going to
put it up the top there you know this is
actually going to store the results of
our calculations so I'm going to change
its ID up here making sure that it's
selected which it is change the ID to
result press into there and you can see
the name is also reflected in the left
under the component tree next we want to
set a top constraint to the top of the
layout and left and right constraints to
the edges before doing that though make
sure that the default margins setting is
set to 8 DP you can see over here that
it is set to 8 DP for me if for some
reason that's not change it back to ATP
and if auto-connect
has
already created some of the constraints
you can just change the merchants
yourself manually to eight so I'm gonna
go ahead and create the constraint from
the result to the top and also to the
left and also to the right and we can
see hip here in the top right hand
corner in the inspector that we've got
two other correct margins of eight for
top left and right you know the other
thing you want to do is make sure that
the widgets set to wrap content both
horizontally and vertically and you can
see that's the case over here all right
no mass I mentioned I'm gonna skip the
second edit text widget we're gonna
start dragging buttons now onto the
design in a rough four by four grid now
there's no point here worrying about
placing them exactly just yet and that's
because all the positioning is
ultimately going to be done using
constraints now if what I connect is on
for you make sure you turn it off at
this point and you can see over here
that to my auto connect is off because
I've got the slash showing through or
over the top of the magnet item icon
which of course is the icon for auto
connect so making sure that that's
turned off and I'm doing that because it
doesn't really do the same thing for
each button and I want them to follow a
pattern in the way that they couldn't
their constraints are actually organized
so I'm gonna drag 16 buttons now so
we're gonna click on all either here in
the pallet and then move over and just
start dragging some buttons again it
doesn't matter too much where these
buttons are because we're going to be
using constraints to actually position
them exactly so a 4 by 4 green as I've
mentioned
okay we're halfway there
okay three to go
unless you can see now I've got all of
them on there and a little bit of a
squeeze but again don't worry if they
overlap or don't line up properly
because we are going to be fixing that
and you saw they turned off or don't
connect for that and I really do suggest
that you do that it really doesn't seem
to cope well with a lot of widgets all
right now we want the buttons for the
numbers to be called button 0 to button
9 and if you'd look at the componentry
to the left over here we can see two
things firstly there's this little error
bar peering and it's complaining that
the view isn't constrained and that's
because we haven't got any constraints
because we had auto-connect turned off
as you can see that it has actually
named this button 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11
through 216 and that's because the
Android studio automatically appends a
number to the ID when you put more than
one of the same widget on the screen now
you might be tempted at this point to
work systematically up or down the
screen changing the IDs
but you can't set a widget to have an ID
that's already in use now you can of
course do this any time any way you want
but what I'm gonna do is try and change
as few IDs as possible we're gonna make
the button text match the IDS in Android
studio has a side for us so I'm gonna go
ahead and change the first indeed the ID
of the first button button click on that
and I'm going to change the ID that to
button 0 and I'm also going to change
its text to 0 and the componentry is
very useful for work like this
you know when selecting the buttons at
this stage because at the moment they
all look the same in the layer all right
so you can see I've changed button zeros
text and ID button 0 and 0 respectively
I'm going to work my way through buttons
2 through 9 in the componentry
giving them the correct text so I'm
going to click on button to change the
text to 2 1 3 3 4 4 5 5 6
okay seven eight I have no idea so you
can see we've got the buttons 0 2 3 4 5
6 7 8 9 at the moment now we're missing
buttons 1 at the moment Android studio
calls the second button button - but
didn't create a button 1 because when we
added the first button it didn't
actually know there'd be more so what
I'm going to do is change the ID of
button 10 by clicking it you changed
that to button 1 then we now change the
text to 1 as well okay alright so we've
now got that 10 digit buttons so it's
time to start raising them correctly
now I could do with a bit more room at
the top because 7 is going to go at the
top left of the button grid but there's
not enough room to really place it
without overlapping it's a little bit
tightly now there's no reason you can't
overlap buttons when you're creating the
land but it does make getting to the
constraint handle is difficult so rather
than moving the buttons down
individually though what I can do is
just click just below the book the
bottom right button down here and I can
drag a rectangle out so that it extends
over all the buttons so I'm gonna do
that and there's actually no need to
just to fully enclose a button just any
part of it will select it and if the
rectory at the rectangle includes any
part of one that's going to be selected
so when all the buttons are selected
which you can see that the rectangle is
touching all of them now I'm going to
release the mouse and you can see there
that we've selected all the buttons you
can see that clearly in the blueprint
but also in the component tree so I'm
going to drag them down there just to
make a bit more room for what we're
doing right down towards the bottom and
you can click anywhere in a blank area
of the designer blueprint if you do that
that and selects them or deselect them
you can see that's happened there all
right now to layout the grid
one of the buttons is going to be the
key button no it's that one that's going
to be used to constrain the entire array
of buttons and I'm going to choose
button 7 which is the one that will be
at the top left now you could use either
the button 7 or the slash button the
forward slash which will
at the top right the one that we're
gonna be using for division but we
haven't named that one yet so what I'm
going to do is constrain the top of
button seven to the bottom of the Edit
text widget and then constrain its left
edge to the left edge of the screen so I
do that I'm going to click on this seven
and their submission are going to
constrain it to the bottom of the edit
text widget so I'll do that first and
then I'm going to constrain its left
edge to the left edge of the screen like
so and you can see that it's been placed
automatically once the constraints are
set and that's why I haven't been too
worried about trying to place the
buttons accurately
all right the next thing I'm going to do
is constrain the baseline of but Nate to
the baseline of button seven and the
left edge of button 8 to the right edge
of button seven now when you're doing
things like that I suggest leaving the
baseline till last if the buttons get
too close together then setting the
constraint or the edge can be very
fiddly now because the baseline
constraint handles are in the middle of
the widgets they're actually much easy
to work with when widgets are close
together so let's do but Nate first I'm
going to do the backlight constraint
from its left edge to the right of
button seven you come button that eight
constrain it to the right of seven as
you can see there now if the display
gets a bit messy which you can see it's
getting a little bit messy from my point
of view now we've got the eight button
overlaying another number
don't worry too much about that that's
okay as long as button eight is selected
which it still is and if for some reason
it isn't remembering you can still
select it from the component tree to the
left I can set a baseline constraint to
button 7 if it gets hard to click on the
constraint handles and you may have to
drag buttons around but it doesn't
really matter how chaotic the display
starts to appear because you'll get more
and more organized as the constraints
are actually created so what I'm going
to do now is come down here and click on
the a B button which opens up the
baseline from straight and then I'm
going to constrain this button eight
baseline from straighten to button seven
so when they click on hold come up and
straight to button seven you can see
it's been moved up for us automatically
and by the way as you finished setting
up the constraints for each but
make sure you do check the margin just
to make sure that they're set to wait
it's easier to do that when the while
the buttons been selected rather than
going back in going through all them
individually later alright so button
know it has a constraint from its left
edge to the right of button late so go
ahead and do this I'm going to click on
button 9 and the left edge of button I'm
really constrained to the right edge of
but night you can see that's moved over
for us so you can see that it did move
but it's still selected and again it's
the longest I don't click on anything
else I can turn on the baseline
constraint handle then drag it to the
baseline of bottom right I'm gonna go
ahead and do that
turn on the baseline then we constrain
it tight you can see that moves up and
lastly for us now button for needs a top
constraint to the bottom of button 7 now
it might be tempting Nero to constrain
the left edge button for to the left
edge of the layout really though we want
the entire array of buttons to work like
a single group so if we go constraining
each rotor layout then it would behave
as a single entry so instead what I'm
going to do is constrain the left edge
of button 4 to the left edge of button 7
then set the margin to 0 so it lines up
but let's start firstly with button 4
let me click on that and we want to set
the top constraint to the bottom of
button 7 do that initially then as I
mentioned we're going to constrain the
left edge of button to 4 to the left
edge of button 7 so I'm going to go
ahead and do that and you can see at the
moment looking at this it's got a margin
of 8 but we want to change that margin
to zero so then it lines up directly
under set and of about 97 so I'm gonna
turn it to zero and you can see they're
lining up and looks quite nice
particularly in the design you can see
over here that it's so long that one
looks nice and just to show that the
reason that I've done that if I don't
start dragging button 7 around the
screen so I just click on just button 7
you can see that that's I drag that
around all four buttons are moving now
and that's exactly what I wanted to
happen all right I can just hit that
back to eight now I could have just
changed the margins back to eight
instead of just dragging it back but I
did a combination of both theories you
can see all right now button five needs
a lift constraint to the right of button
four and a baseline constraint to it as
well so let's go ahead and do that so
button five constrain the left first to
the right of 4 and then we're going to
do the same thing we've done before with
other buttons set the baseline before
there it's not lines up there making
sure the margin of eight is still
correct and button six is constrained to
button five in the same way so click
click on six constrain the left edge
first and then we do the baseline
selected at five to put it over to five
as well they were checking that the
margin still eight as well
all right so button one well that's a
repeat of button 4 so it's top is
constrained to the bottom of button 4
and it's left edge to the left edge of
button for with a merchant of zero so
let's do that
so button one constrain the top first
and then as we've done previously for
that for our button for constrain it to
the left edge of that comes off that's
our button and then change the margin
the left margin for button 1 to zero
something that lines up nicely and we
can confirm that things are still
looking ok we can move seven around
click on button 7 we can move it you can
see that everything's moving over moving
nicely and then I can just quickly
change these margins if I want to to put
seven back to cow where it wasn't
consequently all the other buttons mean
as well all right so back to is
constrained to button 1 and button 3 to
button tooth so we need the lifts
constrain to the right of the
destination button in a baseline
constrain as well so let's do that for
buttons 2 and 3 so button to constrain
to the left of button 1 in the baseline
let's try it they're making sure the
margin is set to eight which it is and
then lastly button three constrain that
to the right of button of two and set
our baseline constraint as well okay and
the margin you can see in the inspector
is also set to eight so at this point
now we've got a nice group of buttons
that I can drag around it's a single
object again I can just drag them around
you can see that all annoying buttons
are now moving around nicely so again
I'll just change the margins back to
wait so that's sitting in the right
position all right so let's finish the
video here in the next video we've still
got some remaining buttons that need to
be changed and also their text change so
we'll start working on that
in the next video