since we talked about at the end of the
last video in landscape mode the buttons
are far too close to the bottom of the
screen and there was a fair bit of space
between the widgets vertically so we
could start shuffling them up by
reducing their top margins and sometimes
you may have to do that but androids
they actually got another solution it's
possible to create separate layouts for
different screen sizes and landscape
counts as a different screen size to
portrait you know this particular layout
doesn't look the best in landscape so
let's have a look at how to use it as
the basis for a separate landscape
layout now this is quite a complex
layout and you may not feel too
confident about playing around with it
in case you mess it up but fortunately
there's an easy way to save everything
so you can put the layout back if things
go horribly wrong while you're
experimenting so we come over here and
click on text to go back into text mode
then we're going to copy all the text
control a on a PC or Linux or command a
on a Mac and I'm doing a command C but
it would be a ctrl C on Windows or a Mac
or of course you can go to the edit mode
and do a copy that way you could have
done a select or than a copy cetera but
anyway get a copy of the text as you can
see there and you can paste it into your
favorite editor and you couldn't even
create a new layout in Android studio
and paste it in there or although I
prefer to use a separate editors editor
so that I don't mess up and leave unused
our layout layouts in my app one word of
warning though be careful if you're
using TextEdit on a Mac and don't use
WordPad on Windows use notepad instead
the reason is that they can mess around
with text and do strange things like
trying to match up speech marks with 66
/ 99 characters instead on my Mac I'll
make sure text and edit is set in text
mode by going into the format menu so
I'm going to click on go into text edit
new document and they're gonna go into
format and I can select here make which
text as an option comes up and then it's
plain text mode so I'm clicking to
they're basically make plain text again
as you can see and you can see what the
control has changed there as well
I'm going to paste that T in there so
you'll do that in notepad if you're on
Windows or some other editor to take a
copy of what we've done so that we can
restore it if need be
so basically anytime you want to go back
to the layout as it is at the moment you
can just copy this text back into the
Android studio into the text tab and go
back to exactly what it was before all
right so back to Android studio I'm
gonna click on design again so to
actually create a separate layout for
landscape we just have to place a copy
of this layout in a special landscape
directory then modify it to work with
landscape but Android studio makes it
very easy to create layouts for
different orientations and screen sizes
so the button that switched from
portrait to landscape is another option
so I'll come over to here and you can
see that time on this option here
creates landscape variation and that
creates a new layout from the current
layout so I click on that now I'll open
up the project pane we just go and have
a look look at the layouts you can see
we've now got two files there and even
though they've got the same name you can
tell which one you're working with
because the editor tab prefix is the
name of lead so we've got the landscape
when I here land slash activity in the
school main we've got layout slash
activity underscore main so you'll
easily know which one is which and also
down here in the pre in the project pane
you can see the word land is in
parentheses to the right so you know
which one is the landscape version now
when you're working in landscape it's
very useful to be able to show either
design or the blueprint on their own
we're moving things around I prefer to
work in the blueprint so I'm just going
to use the button on the toolbar to
display it by itself and it close a
project page just give us a bit more
space
so how are we going to sort out the
layout for landscape now in landscape
we're actually short of screen depth but
we've got plenty of width now you may
come up with other ways to layout the
widgets for landscape but I'm just going
to place the two edit text widgets
side-by-side on the same line they're
gonna start by changing the base
constraint of the operation takes you so
let's click on here the operation we
want to lied that to the button seven
widget instead you know it's still going
to be a baseline constraint but we're
gonna move it down the screen now this
is the widget that we had trouble with
in the previous video because it's so
small I'm just going to expand the
properties of these pane over here the
inspector and we're gonna have a look at
our constraints again and we're gonna
come down here where we've got baseline
to baseline of which is currently set to
a new number you used to drop down we're
going to change that to button seven
instead and you can see it move down the
screen when I did that now it would be
confusing to have a constraint to two
different widgets so I'm going to change
both constraints
although the constraint names can't be
read properly without making the pane
wider we can see which one was set to
number two new number so I'm just going
to change the both it'll change that one
now instead of a new number you know if
you find in this particular case that it
doesn't give you the full list of
buttons you come over here and click on
the ellipsis and select button seven
that way click on OK then it result is
we've now got it changed both
constraints new constraint a button
seven alright so the next step is to
delete the top and right edge
constraints on new number and the left
edge constraint and result so I'm gonna
go back to our normal properties instead
of the extended ones so selecting new
number so we're going to delete the top
and right edge constraints on new number
and the left edge constraint and result
and to delete the top first at the right
edge on your number delete them as well
the constraint that is then the left
left edge constraint and result and
result was this previous one so I'm
going to delete that as well now the
right edge of new number two
didn't be constrained to the left edge
of result let's do that first let's
drain it to the left edge of result and
then we also want a baseline constraint
crate created for the two so we'll come
over here click on the blue button to
enable the baseline constraint they're
going to constrain it like so
oops I didn't quite click it then try it
again that's better now we have to put
the baseline constraint from new number
to result rather than the other way
around because it's result that has the
vertical constraint to the top of the
screen of course you could change that
but it doesn't actually matter which way
we ended or goes now you could also
constrain new number to the top of the
layout instead but by anchoring the to
edit text widgets together we only have
to move one on the other will follow
now the buns aren't sentient but we'll
come back to that in fact there are a
few things wrong with the landscape
layout and we're going to be looking at
them all a little bit later but that's
the layout for the calculator app
completed for now so let's actually run
it to see how it all looks so I'm just
got a runner and we'll just check it out
then the emulator just to see what it
does look like
okay so there it is in portrait mode so
that's looking okay and we go over to
landscape and you can see it's looking
okay so we're not perfect but we need to
make a few changes to that but you can
see that it's looking much better
because of the additional layout that we
created in landscape mode so at this
point now we're ready to start writing
the code to make it calculate the last
thing I'm going to do is I'm just going
to go back to portrait and go back into
the code and for both the layout files
what I'm going to do is let's go into
the text view and if you click on the
code menu and rearrange code I'm going
to do that for that one and also for the
other layout as well do the same thing
code rearranged
just so everything's in a standard order
I'm just gonna go back to design on both
of those and I'm doing that to the
reason I did the reformat code from the
code menu just so everything is in a
standard order if you need to compare
your code with mine and in the next
video I'm going to actually going to
show you how to use Antoine junior to
compare files so that you can compare
your code to mine if you get any
problems and are struggling to work out
what's different so let's get started
with that in the next video