in the previous videos we created the
lay up for the calculator app and we saw
it running on an emulator now it looks
fine on my screen when I run it but if
you're having problems you might be
struggling to work out exactly what's
wrong
if you missed a step while we were
creating the layout it can be difficult
to tell from the screen what bit may be
missing and if it's a whole widget then
you probably spun it quite easily but
trying to work out all the constraints
by comparing the image on my screen if
yours isn't very easy and intuitive
there is a better way and that's to
compare the XML files produced for the
layout now Android studio has a built in
diff tool and that's a tool that allows
you to compare files with the computer
doing most of the work
now these tend to work best when the
contents of the files you're comparing
are in roughly the right order so after
completing layouts in the course make
sure the order of your widgets in the
component tree matches mine and you can
see that on the screen there now it
didn't add another couple of widgets to
the top of the layout since our last
reorder the component tree so check the
order of the tree and move them back
near the top if necessary and you can
see we've got the result operation new
number the buttons 0 through 9
then we've got divide multiply minus
plus dot and the equals buttons now it's
also a good idea to reformat your code
this applies whether it's XML or program
code that you want to compare formatting
the code in a standard way makes it much
easier to use differencing tools to spot
differences so to do that and I did show
you this in the last video but click on
text and come up here to code to the
code menu and select reformat code
that's how you'd go about actually doing
it but you can see I've got a little pop
up here saying my code or content rather
is already properly formatted all right
so I've already got a copy of this
layout file on my computer and we're
going to do I want to close down the
landscape while I'm gonna be dealing
with the portrait so we're going to be
testing and comparing that one so I've
really got a copy like I said
so to start the comparison tool you want
to expand the project pane and follow
the file that you want to check so I'm
using the portrait activity underscore
main dot XML subset so I can come down
here and open up the layout and here the
activity underscore main dot XML is the
one we want then will it select the file
in the project pane you can actually see
the path up here displayed just above
the pain so within the calculator
project this activity underscore main
dot XML can be found in app source main
res layout that's the folder and
obviously the name is activity
underscore main dot XML now you'll need
to know that path within the project
when you come to compare files and
different projects such as your copy
with the file with the files in my
source code for now though I'm going to
compare this layout with another copy
that I've already stored or this
computer's hard drive so with a select
activity del XML in the project pane
over here which is selected and I'm
going to then come up to the View menu
and click on compare with I want to do
that I get a pop-up appear and by the
way the shortcut key for that is ctrl D
on a PC or Linux or command D on a Mac
so this is the file picker dialog and I
can use that to navigate to the other
file so one that I want to compare to
this projects activity main.xml so in my
case I've actually stored it on my
desktop so I'm going to click on their
activity in the school main and let's go
up here and let's go one and click on
open you know once I've done that I've
chosen the second floor you can see that
the diff tool is started up with the two
files displayed side by side near the
top right of the window shows me how
many differences there are between the
two files and you can see in this
particular case it says no differences
and over here it says contents are
identical now most of the window is
taken up with the two files side by side
with matching lives aligned as far as
possible
now because there are no differences in
these two files everything lines up
perfectly and I can actually scroll the
text up and down to check that all out
and you can see as I do that we're
getting your
tation of both files now on the toolbar
at the top is a button that collapses
identical sections so that you can focus
on just the bits that are different and
that's this tool over here now because
these files are the same it collapses
them both completely but CC it again
only when there are differences I'm
gonna click it again there anyway and
you can see by doing that there's no
text there's no where XML showing
anymore
again because it's only showing one it's
different in this case the two files are
identical no next to that is another
button then this button synchronizes the
scrolling of the two files you can turn
that off if you want to scroll one file
without the other one following it and
that can be useful if you're comparing
blocks that are in that are in different
places in the file you know with this
diff tool we have to do that manually
and differences in methods that appear
in a different place in each file and
highlighted for you next to that so we
go over there's the COG which is the
Settings button which you can turn on
line numbering if it isn't already on
and it's also useful just to word
disable code inspections from the
highlight to level submenu I can click
on that and you can see the various
options we've got in there now code
inspections are the warning and error
messages that appear in the margins and
with these files lines two three and
four and if I just open it up again so
with these lines with these files
launched two three and four is showing
in red in the right-hand pane and I can
actually come over here and click on
that the three errors found so that can
be distracting when you're trying to
look for differences in the file so I
tend to disable the inspections by
choosing syntax from that menu by coming
over to here highlighting level and
choosing syntax which was already
selected but we go back and click on
highlighting level two inspections you
see there's three lines that I'm
referring to in red so again I'm going
to just come over here highlighting
level syntax all right so that's about
all we can see with these files and it
is a bit boring with the flowers are
identical after all but I have got
another file that I didn't reformat and
also that the widgets are in a different
order in the componentry
so let's have a look at comparing files
that differ markedly so I'm going to
close this down
I'm going to make sure that activity
underscore main is selected view menu
compare with this time I'm going to
select the activity underscore main
underscore compared to dot XML click on
open so we've got a completely different
setup here and then in fact is showing
39 differences so this is one reason why
I recommend that you use the code
reformat code option and make sure that
you widgets are in the same order of
mine before using this tool to compare
your code to the source you can download
from the resources now what are the
things that reformatting the code does
is order the XML attributes in a
consistent way
so the first attribute is always the ID
for example and you can see in the left
hand pane that the IDS here for every
widget starts with an ID we've got the
inner text and the textview there but in
the right hand side file that's not
really the case there's no such a patent
in other words and as I scroll through
the document it's really hard to see
what's happening and what the important
differences are and in fact this
probably isn't going to help power as
much at all now if I'd reformatted the
code in that second file and make sure
that the widgets were in the same order
as my code then the differences would
actually be much easier to spot so I'm
going to close this window down and do a
comparison with a formatted file and the
same thing I'm going to select activity
main in the in the project pane view
compared with this time I'm going to
select another file this is activity
underscore main underscore compare three
dot XML open that and initially it looks
worse it says that there's actually 55
differences but now the ordering of the
widgets and the XML attributes have been
sorted out it's going to be much easy to
spot the differences now firstly we can
see that the edit text in the second
file has a different ID there the input
type on line 22 you can see that's
slightly different as well we've got
number decimal pipe number signed
compared to number signed pipe number
decimal so that's fine and we can ignore
that one but the operation takes view if
we just scroll down a little bit more
well that's cool so I've got a few
differences you can see
that for the operation on the right hand
side we're using 16 DP for the various
margins and the textview for operation
on the left is using 8 DP and in
addition it's going to text properly set
to a plus symbol and we haven't got that
text attribute used at all on the left
hand side and it's constraints are also
slightly different now remember that end
underscore to end of is the same as
right underscore to write off when
dealing with constraints so it turns out
those differences aren't important but
two older versions of Android studio
uses left and right while Android studio
3 currently uses start and end of course
that could still change in the future
now these older versions also use the
layouts ID which is the app plus ID for
word social activity underscore main and
that's actually the same as parent
you've got parrot down here you can see
compared this is on line 37 on the Left
compared to the use of the actual
epicenter the app plus ID slash activity
main on line 39 on the right hand side
and again that's the same as parent
because the laird is the parent of our
widgets so we can ignore those
differences as well so let's move on a
little bit now look at the next one I'm
going to come over here and click that
it says I can actually scroll both of
them at the same time so we have a look
at this next and it takes now the one
that's showing here on the left
now this next say edit text widget is
just about the same the only differences
are those input types that we talked
about this is on line 48 on the left
hand side in Lion 52 on the right hand
side there's also a top margin in the
left hand file so this is the sort of
thing you could easily miss if you
compare the files manually now the 10
buttons that follow have some
differences there I can scroll down and
we can start looking at some of those
the ones on the right if you have a look
you see that they've all got their
minimum height set as well as a minimum
width and we haven't got a minimum
height showing on the left hand side
only minimum width so using a tool like
this makes it much easier to spot
problems in code when you've got a
working version to compare your code to
now as long as you're careful
and watch carefully what you're doing
it's possible to edit these files from
actually inside this difference tool to
make it easier the tool provides buttons
that will automatically synchronize
lines then you can either transfer the
left hand code to the right or the right
hand code to the left
now normally you'd probably go from
right to left because the left hand side
is the file in your project and you
probably wouldn't be checking for
differences unless you've got a problem
in your code so in other words you
probably wouldn't want to be wanting to
update anything but the file that's in
your project you know I'm only doing
going to do this to show you how it
works and I don't want to mess up my
project file so I'm going to send the
code from the left over to the right but
bear in mind that you'd normally
probably send in code on the right which
would be the file that you've downloaded
to compare the one on the left hand side
so I'm going to synchronize all the
constraints settings for the ten buttons
on the right by copying the settings
from the left now in the center margin
where the line numbers are there's
actually a little button you can see
this little greater to greater than
signs and that synchronizes the section
to the right and there's another one
this size which will go the other way so
when I click over here on button 0 this
little button we get this warning about
the phone up being part of the project
but that's normal in US I said you'd
normally be going the other way and you
wouldn't be getting that so once I click
click okay for that we can see the
change is now being a plow being applied
and moved over to the right hand side
now I did the minimum heart I could also
do the streets as well the same way and
if I changed my mind and decided that I
didn't want that I could come over here
and put the change back onto the left
hand side but I'm not going to be doing
that here so I'm I'm really just gonna
focus on the constraint settings rather
than the minimum height adjust to show
you how it works so as we scroll down
now have a look a little bit more we can
see for button 1 I'm just going to
change the constraint button to
constraint again we can just go in a
little bit more
next one for the constraint the
constraint with the button for now
button five will just come down and do
the constraint and you can see it's
applying those changes over to the
right-hand side as I'm doing that
okay scrolling down a little bit now
next one
and obviously these are very minor
little changes that have been picked up
but you can see the concept of changing
it to is being is being applied here as
I go through in door eight and nine and
if I want to talk a go back and do the
same for margins as well and probably it
would be a good idea to actually do it
all I said I wasn't going to do that but
if you think about it it probably does
make sense because it's clearing up the
code and making it much easier to see
any other differences so I'll just go
ahead and quickly do that
and you can see that that's where making
all those changes things are now lining
up a lot better as a result of that so
it did write down they'll write back up
to button zero and you can see that code
now is effectively identical we can move
down now to the rest of the buttons I
just finish those off as well so still
at the button multiply and we can do the
same thing there's a change there
constraint there and also the margin
this has got a margin and a minimum
width we can change that as well for
button miners that's one of the minor
change to the constraint to line and
let's do the same for that one for
button plus same for button dot and the
only way now is we're right down to the
last section now and button equals we do
have to be a little bit careful with
this one and you should have noticed by
now that the difficult replacing all the
text that's highlighted in blue now if
we use the button to update the
constraint to the right-hand file it's
also going to remove the guideline
widget that's this one that's on this
side that doesn't exist on the left-hand
side I'm going to do it anyway because
we're not actually updating the project
but it is important you don't just click
without actually paying a bit of
attention to what's actually being
changed all right and there's the
guideline gone and by the way if you
clicked on one of these Chevron buttons
to copy code across or something doing
but then change your mind you can do a
control Z or commands it on a mac to
undo the last change made and each time
we do a command or control Z and does
the change before that so I can do one
on here now on okay you can see the last
change I can do one more and I could go
back and do it a few more times if I
wanted to and then I going to put them
back if I so desire so you have got the
ability to undo if for some reason you
want to do that if we just don't do one
more again keep in mind that you can
also edit the text directly in this div
tool instead of using the copy so we
could come over here for argument sake
for one or two and just delete that
little bit or you can look quite still
do that if you want to so either way
will actually work all right at this
point now all the buttons have their
constraints corrected and I've got to
the end of both files
now you probably saw that the right hand
file had an extra widget a guideline
which has now been removed we're going
to be actually adding a guideline later
on it's because of the guideline that
some of the constraints were different
so I've probably broken that right hand
file now but you can see how useful this
difference tool is and how you can copy
code across from one file to the other
now it's not the best differencing tool
in the world and if you already use one
and are happy with it
you can continue to use that instead in
fact you can integrate another diff tool
into Android studio and show the current
files in that tool instead the ice I've
said there are better tools available
but this one comes with Android studio
and certainly beats comparing files
manually and get it gets better in fact
because it also allows you to compare
entire directories and let's have a
brief look at that in the next video