in the previous few videos we produced
the main part of our app that responded
to the different button clicks now the
operations buttons need a method called
perform operation to do the arithmetic
and we created a dummy method to allow
us to test the program up to that point
so it's no time to look at what the
perform operation
will do
now the program stores the two numbers
that are involved in the calculation in
variables operand 1 and operand 2 now
when the program starts operand 1 will
be null and up around 2 will be 0 now
the perform operation method is called
with two parameters the first is a
string holding the value from the edit
text
and we've already checked that that
isn't an empty string now the second
parameter is the operation again as a
string holding the symbol that
represents the operation so the first
thing that this method will do is check
up around one if it's no then there
isn't any calculation to perform but we
do have to store the value in the
operand and as well as that we need to
update the result on the screen the
input to edit text widget is also
cleared then we're done and the program
goes back to waiting for a button to be
clicked
now if operand one isn't null then the
very passed in must be operand two after
the initial call of this method operand
one is only ever updated with the result
of a calculation as long as you count
equals as a calculation but you'll see
that in a minute now the next step is to
decide which operation is pending there
will always be an operation pending
because we've initialized pending
operation to be equal to be a string in
other words the equal sign
now if the pending operation is equals
we set it to the operation that caused
this method to be called the one passed
in as the second parameter we then check
to see if that was also equals if it was
then there's no arithmetic operation to
be performed instead we just transfer
the value to operand 1 and display that
as the result so the result of an equals
operation when there's no other
operation pending is just to update the
result with the new value and put the
new value into operand 1 ready for the
next calculation so there's no need to
clear the value in operand 2 because
that will get a new value the next time
this method is called now if the pending
operation wasn't equals the operation is
performed on operand 1 and operand 2
then the result is set to operand
which Neal holds the answer to the
calculation and the method ends clearing
the input field on its way out
now it may actually help to see both
flowcharts together so here you can see
the design of the complete program all
right so it's time now to write the code
for the perform operation function
alright so here we are again in Android
studio so what I'm going to do is create
this function this is a perform
operation so we're going to change this
and we're gonna start at the top and our
first bit of code if parenthesis is the
operated one if that's equal to no we
open a code block and it's going to be
operand 1 is equal to value dot 2 double
and otherwise you put an else outside of
the code block and open another code
block otherwise operand 2 is equal to
value dr double then we're going to type
after that if parentheses pending
operation is equal to the equal sign in
pending operation equals operation and
next what I should have done there is
open a code block then have a code block
closed there next we're going to type
win parentheses pending operation and
open a code block then we're going to
type double quote equal then the desk
greater than sign operand 1 equals up
around 2 then we're going to that's the
equal sign then the test for the divide
button so the / - greater than sign if
then parentheses operand 2 if that's
equal equals to 0 dot 0 then we're going
to top operand 1 equals double dot n/a
end
and here we're going to hear no attempt
to divide by zero to divide by zero so
we're specifically testing for zero
there otherwise else then operand one
away from the code block again equals
operand one and two exclamation marks
here and divide it by up around to
closing code block as you can see there
next we want to handle the next line the
and I shouldn't really indent this so
it's a little bit more readable because
it's not really readable the way I've
done it so I'm gonna do it like that
which is how we should really have had
it anyway so if operand equals 0 dot 0
well this is the code that's executed on
that line then we've got the else there
this is all to deal with the deal with
the division and then we're going to
come back here and we're going to handle
the next one which is multiplication
yes Tariq's so we do a dash greater than
sign operand 1 equals operand one
operand 1 to exclamation marks times
operand
- okay next line we want to do hand with
the minors so double quotes minors -
greater than sign it's going to be
operand 1 again is equal to operand 1 -
exclamation marks take up around 2 and
the last one will be + as obviously on
the next line in double quotes
- greater than sign operand 1 equals
operand 1 - exclamation marks + operand
2 alright we close off that code block
so we delete the rest here for the wind
that is and the next one which closes
off the if for the original test online
83 and the else for checking where the
operand 1 is 0 then on the last line
down here we've got
we're going to delete the display
operation text equals in this tab what
we're going to do is put down their
result dot set text the operand 1 dot 2
string and then we want to type new
number dot set text double quotes and
two empty or two double quotes within
the parentheses I should say all right
so what does this function doing now
well the first thing it does is check
see if operand 1 is no and assigns it to
the numeric value of the value string
that was passed as the first parameter
now if that was the case the rest of the
code is skipped until the result is
displayed way down here on line 104
basically at the end of the function you
know the input widgets cleared on the
next line ready for a new number to be
entered now if operand 1 wasn't no the
value gets assigned to operand 2 then
the rest of the code the main part of
the function it's code is executed now
if the pending operations is equals so
we're down to this line here now
193 then the current operation should be
performed and so therefore pending
operation is assigned the new operation
so in other words operand 1 equals
operand 2 now if you used to Java you
may actually will be horrified by the
code here on a line 88 because in Java
should never compare strings using
equals equals it almost always fails so
the comparison will be false
now that's such a common source of bugs
that Kotlin has changed the way that
equals equals works when dealing with
objects so it now does the comparison
that you'd expect if you want the Java
behavior in Kotlin you need to use 3
equal signs and as it's rare that you do
want that behavior the extra typing is
in a problem alright so the code that
uses a win statement to decide when to
add an extracting subtract etc and I
think I pointed down here before when
were talking about pending operation but
of course I was
to the code that was being executed up
here but we now at the stage where we
actually are now talking about the
pending operation all right so the code
at that point is using a win operation
to decide whether to add subtract etc
now if the operation is still equals
after the previous test operand one gets
the new value which has already been
converted to a number and is stored in
operand 2 otherwise the appropriate
calculation is performed and the results
stored in operand 1 now there's a check
for division by 0 you can see that here
on line 94 and the calculator will
display in a n for not a number
rather than crash in a n by the way is a
special value to cater for cases like
this where a calculation results in
something that can't be represented as a
number which you get when you try to
divide by 0 all right then finally the
method displays the result in the result
edit excellent clears the input field
before returning now one other thing to
look at is why have we got these two
exclamation marks after the operand one
whenever we use it in the calculation
you actually use that as you can see a
total of four times in this method in
this function for each of the operations
the divide multiply subtract and add
well the exclamation mark is sometimes
called bang which would make exclamation
mark exclamation mark the bang bang
operator and that's not a bad name for
it because if you've used it incorrectly
your codes dead now the Kotlin
documentation describes it as being for
null pointer exception lovers and if you
use it on a null object you will get a
null pointer exception so let's actually
have a look at what it does and why I
considered it's safe to use it here so
we're going to look at the divide
operation and specifically this is our
code here on line 97 so if I remove the
being being operator so delete the two
exclamation marks you can see that we
actually get an error then if we just
hover over it smart cast a double is
impossible because operand 1 is a
mutable property that could have been
changed by this time you know the error
previous to that before the Kotlin was
updated is that none other follow
functions can be called with the
arguments applied so the point here is
that the error message is implying that
one of the operands is of the wrong type
which can be confusing at first because
after all they're both doubles aren't
they
well actually no they're not operand two
is a double but operand one is a double
question mark the nullable version of
double and if you come up and just check
the declaration of these two properties
we have to code there we've got a double
on line 16 double question mark for
operand 1 and just double which is set
to a value of zero point zero on line 17
so double question mark which is the
nullable double class isn't the same as
the non nullable double Kotlin treats
them as different types which is how it
prevents us from accidentally assigning
nil to an object now going back to our
divide operation again here on line 19 7
and we're going to put back the bangbang
operator the two exclamation marks after
operator one to remove that error so
what the bangbang operator does is
return a non nullable value of operand 1
so that'll only work if operand 1 isn't
know if it is no we'll get a
nullpointerexception
okay so that's what it does and why we
need to use it now the reason by the way
that it's safe to use it is because all
this code is inside a null check so
right at the start of this function
right at the very top we've got two
tests here on line 83 if operand 1 is
equal to null so right at the start of
this function we test to see if operand
1 is no up here on line 83 and we're
only actually be executing this code if
it isn't so therefore it's a safe place
to use bang bang
now colon provides the bang bang
operated for when you need it but
remember that it's your responsibility
to ensure you don't use it on an object
that could possibly be no all right so
the method exactly follows the flowchart
now and should work so let's actually
run it and see if it does work you're
going to run the code and switch over to
the emulator so let's now try some
operations to see whether they work so
let's try the first one
seventy then we'll do a plus five and
then we top the or click on the Eagles
and you can see we've got 75 at the top
so that's working now we can try
multiplying by ten so if we type down at
this point the multiply will click on
the multiply but 'n ten then equals we
should get the answer hopefully 750 you
can see we've got 750 at the top there
so let's divide now by 375 so I'm going
to type three seven five three seven
five then divide click on divide we get
the answer a tube which is correct now
if I do a divider by two here again so
if I'd actually click on divide two
equals we get the answer of one and if I
try to divide by zero by entering the de
vial kicking on the divide button zero
in Percy call click on equals we get the
n/a in not a number
now that would normally crash but we're
getting the result in a in instead and
the reason for that we're handling this
here is the code on line 94 95 so
basically sending operands to n a n
rather than the app crashing because of
course dividing by zero isn't allowed
all right so I don't think we've done a
minus yet so try typing 65 - 65
we will type 65 equals to get rid of the
LAN so I can done that now now we'll try
a subtraction so I'll put minus 80 then
minus 50 equals minus 65 which is
correct and then we'll type 150 plus 150
plus and we get the answer of 85 which
is correct so I think things are working
fine I'll try typing a few decimals now
so for try typing 10.25 plus we get the
answer of ninety five point two five
and let's just try another one plus
sixty four sixty four point nine eight
seven equals 160 point two three seven
so that seems to be working well so
we've got our basic calculator working
well at this point in time so it does
work fairly well and one nice touch is
that there's no need for a Clear button
to start in your calculation so when you
want to start a new calculation press
equals to finish the current one then
top the new number and press equals
again the new number is then transferred
up and up into the result ready to add
to it or multiply it or whatever you
want to do next however that's not
necessarily very intuitive so we're
going to look at that more in the next
video so I'll see you in the next video