a few videos ago we looked at different
ways to get references to our widgets
from Kotlin code so let's review the
code again and quickly go over what we
did now for the first two widgets the
edit text widgets for the result and the
users input we used the approach that
would be familiar to Java programmers so
we declared the properties first on
lines 15 and 16 as you can see here then
called find view by ID in the oncreate
method to get the references to the
widgets in the layout and we had to
declare the two properties as late in it
but otherwise that's pretty standard
code now for the display operation
textview we used a lazy delegate this is
the code on line 17 now the find view by
ID function isn't called
until we first access the display
operation property and is then cached so
that find V by ID doesn't get called
repeatedly now we had to give a Kotlin a
hint
so that it knows what type to cast the
view to and we did that by using the
Dimond operator to specify textview when
calling finally by ID over here again on
line 17 now Kotlin has a number of
extensions for Android they can simplify
this even further and one of these lets
us effectively import the resources and
then refer to them as normal properties
in our code first we have to import what
are called synthetic properties and for
our activity underscore main layout
that's going to look like the following
so it's basically below the other
imports up here we type import so it's
hot links dot Android not columns I've
got links that Android dot synthetic dot
main dot TV underscore main dot star so
after adding that import all the widgets
in our layout can be accessed just like
any other properties that we imported
into our code now it's easier to fully
appreciate that by seeing it in action
so
going to modify our existing code to
make use of these extension properties
and S&T notice that the only thing I'm
doing is deleting code and in fact what
I'm going to do is I'm going to start by
commenting it out just so you can see
how much code we can remove so I'm going
to start by commenting out the three
lines up here there are definitions in
line 17 through 19 and next I'm going to
come down here to the definitions in the
oncreate function and I'm effectively
going to comment all those out right
down to the button plus definitions just
right down here to the button plus I'm
going to come up here including result
and comment all of those out right down
to bump to button plus so we've removed
all the properties and local variables
in all the boilerplate code that just
calls find V by ID
unless you can see in this particular
program that's a fair bit of code now we
do have two errors that's because we
called the text view property display
operation but the ID of the text view is
operation so you just have to change the
old property name into the to the
correct ID and the two lines that we've
got an error so firstly I click on the
first one you can see we've got this
display operation they're going to
mention that the text view name is
operation so let's change that operation
and then look at the second error
display operation again and make that
operation now there's two of the lines
we can remove this well because if you
go back up to the top and have a look
we've actually got two unused imports
although android studio may have deleted
them for you if you told to remove
unused imports in the settings and in my
case i have done that and the two one
two were imports that have been removed
our Android widgets X View and Android
that widget donnetta ticks in my face
you can see they have both been removed
because I've got that setting to room to
basically remove unused imports
automatically and what I'll do is start
my emulator because we're going to test
the app again just to make sure that
still works
and it's obviously a good idea in this
scenario given the changes we've made to
do test run just to make sure that
things still work is there working
before so I'll just uh fast-forward this
run our app to make sure it still works
all right so let's try a calculation so
25 x 4 equals and x 3 equals that's 300
that's correct
let's now divide it by 9 x 3 equals 100
so that's working fine without all the
code that we've now removed well so
let's just go back to the code and don't
love it too how this all works so what
we add at that line which was on line 10
which is now on line 7 this import this
cotton links non-android not synthetic
domain done activity underscore main dot
star the Kotlin extension plugin creates
properties corresponding to each of the
views in the layout now in this case it
would import them from activity
underscore main because that's the name
that we provided to the import again on
line 7 now behind the scenes Kotlin adds
a caching function to our class now the
first time we access one of the
properties by using the viewers ID the
caching function calls find V by ID to
get a reference to the view it then
stores that so subsequent accesses don't
result in further calls to find V by ID
I think you can agree that's pretty neat
because we can refer to the views in our
layout without all that boilerplate code
that we had before all that code that
I've now commented out in this so class
now I'm going to leave the comments for
now so that they'll appear in the source
code for this video in the resources
section what I will do is delete the
comments at the start of a future video
before we make any more changes to the
code now one thing that we couldn't see
is that Android studio will add the
import for us we couldn't see it because
we'd already added code that used the
properties but you'll see the import
being added to our next step I'm going
to be using this approach in most places
from now on there's at least one bit of
code where I won't but I'll explain why
at the time so there are several ways of
getting references to the views or
widgets in a layout from our Kotlin code
you'll find always being used in code
that you'll come across and there's
nothing right or wrong about any of the
approaches I think this last way results
in the simplest code which is why I'm
going to be using it going forward now
if this method wasn't available I'd
prefer the lazy delegate method wherever
possible if the widget reference has to
be read right then later nits is the
next choice and you can only use lazy
with vowel properties not with VARs in
the next few videos we're going to go
back to layouts now calculator doesn't
look too good in landscape and that's
because the buttons aren't centered and
we're a bit pushed for space vertically
so we're going to look at ways to tidy
that up so let's work on that in the
next video