at the end of the previous video I left
you with a challenge to add a new button
to the calculator to allow negative
numbers to be used in calculations no
I'm not going to show you the slide
again because you can refer to the end
of the last video but essentially the
thing missing from the calculator app is
the ability to enter to enter negative
numbers for calculations and we talked
about adding a button to negate the
current value of what is actually in the
edit text so for the solution I'm going
to work in the landscape layout because
it's got a bit more room horizontally
and will look better in the video now
adding the button itself is easy but it
does mess up the centering of the button
array that's because there are now five
or will be five buttons across so the
guideline would run through the middle
of the button but nine now I could add
the new button by dragging one onto the
blueprint which would work falling and
we've seen a few attributes of these
tops though so it would be handy if we
could somehow create a new button with
all the same attributes already set so
it turns out we can actually do that so
if we right click one of these buttons
I'm going to use button divided here so
right-click it and choose copy from the
menu next we're going to come over here
and right click on the layout and choose
paste
you know I consistently had problems
doing that in Windows if they're doesn't
the button doesn't paste right click on
the constraint layout in the componentry
and paste there because that worked
every time but if I opened the
componentry all the componentry is open
i'll just open the palette so that we
can see down the bottom here we have got
button divided to here so it did
actually copy but because we've copied
the button all the details relating to
that button have been copied as well so
in other words nothing seemed to happen
but that's because the new button was
pasted on top of the one that we copied
now we can drag it out of the way to
make it visible and I like to select it
in the componentry first just to make
sure you've got the right one but I want
to do that
so first thing I'm going to do first is
now come over here I'm going to delete
all the constraints using the delete
straights button for this particular
button they're gonna set its ID to
button neg at the moment it's done it's
called button divided to sew button nig
I'm also going to change the text size
property to 12s pages so it better
matches the size of the other button so
text size over here 12 SP and we're
going to change the actual text itself
instead of the slash it's going to be
negative sides because we've got
multiple letters here changing it to a
smaller size makes it just sort of blend
in with the other buttons a little bit
better in terms of text size so to make
it part of the grid we're going to set
its baseline constraint to the divide
button then also constrain its left edge
to the right edge of the divide button
so I'm just going to move this out of
the way a little bit first so again
we're going to constrain the baseline
constraint to the divide button so I
think I would do what we've done always
for constraining things about baseline
and did it under divide and then also
constrain the right of the neg button to
the sorry the left to the dig button to
the right of the divide button like so
now the buttons are 48 DP wide so we
could try to Center the grid by using a
margin of minus 24 DP for the left
constraint of button 9 but unfortunately
that doesn't work and that's because
negative margins aren't allowed for
constraints so let's actually have a
look at another way to Center the grid
and it turns out it's actually quite
easy because we've already got an array
of widgets that are all constrained to
the central button 9 so instead of
trying to center button 9 to the
guideline I'm just going to Center it in
the layout but I'm not going to delete
the guideline because it's so used to
Center the to edit text widgets I'm just
going to delete the left-hand constraint
from button 9 to the guideline though so
I'm gonna start by coming out to button
9 delete the left-sided constraint which
is currently constrained to the
guideline and even though it's closed
you can see when I hover over that the
little lion is hovering and moving up
he's showing in red linking up to the
god
telling me that the constraint is on the
guideline I'm going to delete that and
to delete that you may have to move it
slightly over to the right just delete
it like so and then move it back again
but actually we don't need to move it
back again because we're about to
constrain it again anyway to Center it
so I've deleted the left-hand constraint
from button 9 to the guideline and I'm
going to constrain the left edge of
button 9 to the left edge of the layout
and it's a right edge to the right edge
of the layout so let's go ahead and do
that it's the left edge of button iron
to the left of the layout then the right
edge of button 9 to the right edge of
the layout and you saw that everything
went a little bit weird when I set the
left constraint the entire block jumped
to the left and we seem to have lost
half the buttons but everything became
or came right when the right-hand
constraint was set so it's actually fine
now as you can see and we can see that
the 963 and equal signs are perfectly in
the middle of the layout so setting the
right-hand constraint first gives the
same behavior by the way the buttons to
the right seem to disappear off to the
right edge of the screen in some cases
but now that you've seen it and know
that you needn't worry about it now that
may or may not happen for you you might
find that some of your buttons do
disappear on the left or right hand edge
of the screen just depending on which
side of the constraints you're sitting
first but if that does happen just
continue by setting the other constraint
on the other side of the widget and the
things will come right as they are for
me now all right so now that's caused
the entire grid to be centered as long
as the horizontal slider is at 50% and
obviously we set that to that previously
so these aren't 50% as you can't easily
see whether it's 50% by the way we'll
click it back so it's on the percentage
that'll come back again now and you can
see that we're sitting on that's 50% so
that's good to go and again all the
other buttons follow what we did because
they're constrained to button 9 the last
thing I'm going to do here is now drag
button neg just to be consistent to look
at that to be below button divided it's
gonna come down here and just put that
below button divide that's really where
it is in our layout all right so that's
the layout
I'm gonna reformat the coat before in
the video often it won't need anything
changes but just to be consistent I'm
going to do that you can see no lines
were needed to be changed there and go
back to the design tap so the XML is now
nicely laid out and again the reason I'm
doing that even though in most cases
Android studio is doing a good job of
keeping it reformatted is just in case
you want to compare your code to mine
alright so in the next lecture what
we're going to do is create the code to
make the neg button work see you in the
next video