all right so it's time to start creating
our app to download that RSS feed and
display the data onto the screen now the
app itself is going to be pretty basic
but it will demonstrate some very
important concepts including performing
operations on a separate thread so that
the app doesn't appear to freeze while
it's performing a long-running task now
although it's getting rarer these days
you may have actually seen android pop
up
ANR dialogues an hour by the way stands
for application not responding although
Google have changed the way that the
dialogues appear in fact I can make one
appear quite easily by doing something
incredibly foolish with a few lines of
code I'm actually going to add a loop to
the only create method what I'll do
first though is I'm going to start my
emulator so that's ready then we're
going to type in some code well that's
actually yeah starting so again we're
going to add this loop we're going to
add this after the set content view line
and the loop is just going to say while
parentheses true open the code block and
then we're going to put foul X or case
about x equals 1 and that's actually yet
now in case it's not obvious don't ever
do anything like this what I've done is
created a loop that just goes round and
round forever but doesn't do anything
other than give X the value of 1 so it's
a really pointless thing to do but it
will prevent the oncreate method from
finishing and will make the app freeze
so when I go ahead now and run this on
my emulator
we'll get that I'm able to compile
now we don't even get to see the usual
hallo world that Android studio includes
in the default layout and that's because
the display doesn't appear until after
oncreate terminates so if I come over to
the app now if I click on the back
button to stop the app there's a short
pause so what should happen is the
android framework will no detect that
the apps frozen and you can see that
that's popped up on the screen now and
at this point here I can either wait or
close the app and sometimes the app
really is doing something and you might
decide to wait but I'm going to close
this one because it's never going to be
doing anything useful so I'm gonna click
on close out so that was an extreme
example but you can see that Android
doesn't like it when an app takes over
the device and doesn't finish its job in
a reasonable amount of time and there's
a very good reason for that
which is that the user interface is
shared by all apps so there's only one
screen on the device so if one app is
taking it over and if it refuses to
release it then the device effectively
can't be used for anything else
you know if you remember from the
discussion of the activity lifecycle
when another activity is started it
doesn't become visible until the on
pause method of the current activity
finishes now this activity with the
infinite loop will never finish
so if Android doesn't provide that
dialog as a way to kill the app then the
device effectively couldn't do anything
else now remember that activities are
being interrupted all the time one thing
that often interrupts what you're doing
on a phone is an incoming phone call if
your app prevents users from answering
the phone well frankly they're not going
to be very impressed in fact that won't
actually happened Android is now
cleverer than that and will let things
like an incoming phone call take over
but the point still holds if the user
wanted to make a phone call that have to
close our rogue at first and we've just
seen that it doesn't close until we tell
Android to kill it so all of this is
really really you should hopefully
emphasize the point that it's important
that we think about what our apps are
actually doing and we don't perform long
running tasks on the main thread doing
so will block the user interface now
you'll find the documentation referring
to the UI sorry
which means the thread that the user
interface is running on so when we do
something like downloading data over the
Internet we don't really have any
control over how long the process will
take sometimes the Internet can be very
slow and sometimes even sites such as
apples can go down and become
unavailable now that would obviously
cause our download to take a long time
and could cause our app to freeze while
it's waiting for that download to
complete so the way to cope with this is
to run the download on a separate thread
now think of a thread as a way of
running code at the same time this other
code is also running in fact with modern
multiprocessor or multi-core devices
that's exactly what does happen the
thread will run on another processor or
core or the user interface continues to
execute now writing multi-threaded
applications is notoriously difficult
and even experienced programmers
struggle to get it right but fortunately
Android provides a class that takes care
of all of the complexity for us so we
can use an async task to perform the
download on a separate thread and then
get notified when the download is
finished so the download will happen in
the background and the user interface
throughout the UI thread will receive
the results of the download so the
download will happen asynchronously
which just means in the background on a
separate thread and our app can get on
with other things while that's going on
now we can even switch to another app
and do something else while an async
task is running this app won't allow
that but we'll see ways to make that
possible later in the course so
basically we tell the android framework
to get on with the task then forget
about it until that task finishes so
that's the theory at least unfortunately
though using an async task to
communicate with the UI thread in Kotlin
isn't quite as easy as it sounds now I'm
going to go ahead and use one anyway but
in subsequent videos we're going to
delete all this code and do it a bit
differently now there are a couple of
reasons for doing this one is that most
of the google examples are still written
in java and probably will be for a while
yet so that means that you're going to
be seeing the the java way of doing
things and the cotton ways often
very different so this example will show
just how different it can be now the
other reason is that Android studio will
actually convert Java code to Kotlin for
us in fact that's how I produced his
first lot of code that we're going to
see I had to do a bit of tweaking but
ultimately that didn't work however what
it produces is basically Java code
written with a Kotlin syntax now you
will find Kotlin code that's been
produced in this way and you may even
end up having to maintain some but
hopefully by the time you've worked
through these next few videos you'll be
better position to spot code like that
and more importantly you won't write any
more yourself alright so let's start
first thing I'm going to do is delete
that rogue while loops that we don't
want so I'm going to come over here and
delete those three lines now most of the
time new classes go into their own
Kotlin file but this class is going to
access properties of our main activity
so therefore I'm going to create it as
an inner class so normally I'd
right-click on the package and choose
new then Kotlin class and that would
create a new class but here we don't
want to do that because we're going to
create the class inside the main
activity class so I'm going to call this
one
download data and it's just the same as
any other Kotlin class except that it
can only be used by main activity so in
other words it's not visible to any
other class in the program so I come
down here and add this code I'm going to
clean that space up and then below the
oncreate function I'm going to type
private in a class download data : then
we'll top async task press enter there
and I'll go to add the Diamonds and then
put string where the diamond operator
should say the string comma void comma
street then at the right of the diode
operator I'm going to add parentheses
then add the left or right curly braces
now at the moment we've got an error
there but what I've done is I've created
a new class that extends the async task
class
now extending an existing class which is
also known as sub classing lets you take
advantage of all the processing in the
existing class so here what we're doing
is taking advantage of the asynchronous
processing that the android framework
provides and all we have to do is
provide the code for the task that we
want to perform and then let Android
take care of all the multi-threading
complexity for us now we need to set up
three parameters when we create an async
task so that the Android knows what type
of task we're dealing with now here was
saying that the information that we'll
provide to the task will be of type
string so we're going to pass in the URL
in the RSS feed we're going to store
that as a string this is that first
parameter here first argument string now
the second parameter is used if we want
to display a progress bar that's this
one
now our download is quite small so there
won't be time for a progress bar to be
displayed now if we were downloading
large amounts of data that could perhaps
take a few minutes or more to download
then it might be a good idea to give the
user some idea of how long it'll take
and also how far through we were but
that's we're not going to do that I'm
making the second type here void to show
that we're not actually using that and I
went to the third parameter this is the
type of the result that we want to get
back so all our XML will be a string so
we're using string again for the third
parameter type now you can find out more
information on the async task class in
google with documentation let's just
open it up briefly I'm just going to
paste this over the top of our RSS feed
now at the moment as I mentioned a lot
of Fogle's examples and including this
one as at the time of recording this
video is still in Java and not Kotlin
unfortunately and that's one reason why
Kotlin programmers need to have some
familiarity with the java language now
we will look at how android studio can
make life a lot easier for us so don't
think by any means that you need to be
an expert Java programmer to work
through this course alright so that's
the three parameters that I've talked
about here that we need to define when
we setup an async tar
so that Android knows what type of task
we're dealing with the first permit
again will be a string containing or
holding the address of the RSS feed
we're not using the second parameter at
all and the third will be the string
containing or the XML that we've
downloaded now Android studio is
actually showing an error here
and that's because if we're going to be
using an async task then there are some
functions that we need to implement well
actually there's only one function that
we must implement and that's the doing
background function we're gonna hover
over there you can see that it's telling
us that it's really looking for this
doing background it's basically saying
that the class download data is not
abstract and does not implement an
abstract based class member but as it
turns out we're also going to implement
another function though because we want
to get data back when the task can
please we need to implement the on post
execute function Android will call that
function when the job's done without
that there wouldn't be a way for us to
know that the task had finished and
therefore we wouldn't get the result now
we can get Android studio to create the
base stubs for the methods by using ctrl
o to get a list of the methods that are
available to override or implement you
do want to make sure that your cursor is
in the inner class for that to happen
and once you do that you can just do a
ctrl o and that brings up a list of
potential functions that can be
overridden and of course we saw that in
an earlier video when we overrode the
methods in the activity lifecycle so as
you can see there are a few methods
available when if we're updating a
progress bar then we want to do that in
the on we want to use rather the on
progress update function and the on
pre-excitation would be used to set up
the progress bar for example but can
also be used with setting up anything
else that's needed for our task to run
now both of those methods are called on
the main UI thread otherwise they
wouldn't be able to display anything so
it's important not to do anything like
trying to start the download in on pre
execute now the other method we want
though is onpostexecute which also runs
on the main UI thread once the
background process has completed so
therefore we're going to choose both our
doing
crowd and we're gonna choose
onpostexecute which was already selected
and then we're going to click on ok and
you can see that those two functions
have there been created and the error
message has disappeared all right so I'm
going to start the code to do the
downloading in the next video but what
I'm going to do for now is just put some
logging into these functions so that we
can see what's going on and get a feel
for how the async task works so we're
going to need a log tag for each of our
classes so I'm going to come up firstly
to our main activity and the first line
after the definition for our main
activity are going to type private Val
tagging uppercase equals double quotes
main activity in double quotes so we can
now use that tag when logging in main
activities on create function we can go
ahead and do that let's go top log dot d
put our parentheses and tag comer
if we just type on create called let's
do the same for the download data in a
class so I'm going to come down into the
first on first line after the definition
we're going to type private Val tag
equals download data alright so now that
I've added those tags we'll finish the
video here in the next video we'll start
continuing on with this program and
we're going to start in that next video
by looking at the warnings that Android
studio are popping up so I'll see you in
the next video