That's the end of the previous video we run the app and we got a security exception because the app
didn't have permissions to access the Internet.
Now we had a look at the stack trace and how it's a useful way to work out what went wrong and just
kind of run them up again.
Now just to get the same error and we can see the links in there I incurred appeared blue when I do.
That's the stuff that up
case they say we've got to crush them and if we haven't looked at look that we can come over here and
scroll over and we can see Ellingsen blue.
Click on that first thing that takes us to law in 51 and you can see that the error happened when we
tried to do anything with the connection.
In this case even just reading the response card.
So the problem was with the internet connection and the fact that it's a security exception really provides
all the remaining information we need just to confirm that it's a security exception again swap and
have a look Javid land security exception permission to drive and to get a suggestion if a missing Internet
permissions perhaps.
Now before we look at fixing the problem which is obviously something we need to do let's catch that
exception and make all those error messages a bit tortilla instead of showing the full stack trace.
So we're going to close down the camp for now.
We're going to add another catch here and we're going to put the original exception back again now.
But above that I'm going to do is add another catch.
For our security it's a catch we call calling security exception and a code block and we're going to
lock a log today I should say Prentice's Tecoma that's going to be download
ex-MIL colon security exception
these permissions that will put a saw and left or right could be Bryce's a message try running them
again.
Now that should prevent us from getting that big exception.
Big stack trace Rala publish is to say oh lord.
So now it's no longer crushing that if are going to go cap.
You can say you've got a security exception these permission and then you've got the message that's
coming back from the actual exception itself.
Permission denied not missing Internet permission.
And then of course with an error downloading as a result.
Yeah well we've got some good errors in the law.
We're going to talk less briefly and show you a bit more about the LOLcat and how you can make it easier
to find information you know to start by clearing the future by clicking on XIV and then you can just
see how busy to look at Kits there's lots of other information there that we've been filtering out.
But we can feel that using the box in the top right of the Android monitor.
And again you've seen this before but if I type in download data there were see messages.
Boy had dandified data class but curiously This is sort of case sensitive.
So if I delete this and I stop the word download with a capital D download
to match the tag the page in the log then you have to continue matching the case exactly.
So deadline data will display the entries log for the class patellar day.
So you can say hey I don't need to talk anymore because you can see right away it's not matching anything.
So the best thing to do here is to top all your filters in lower case or download data which then works
to the other.
After that it topped download data into the the box where we can see the background starting starts
with and then the link and then you were that received obviously and it also logged in error after the
error from Deadline ex-MIL catching the security exception and finally post execute its logging its
parameter as an empty string which is what I would ask which is what we'd expect if doing background
I gave an error.
And again when I delete the contents are cleared by clicking on the x we get heaps of messages again.
Now this would contain far more of a physical device but even an emulator is continually logging all
sorts of stuff.
In fact if a change is dropped and here to the right to know filters and scroll up you can see that
there's an absolute load of things that have made Lotti heaps of things.
And you can see there's just pages and pages and pages of stuff they are going to turn up to show only
selected applications again.
So application I should say.
So we're just getting stuff that's relevant for us.
There's a selective application it's referred to by the way.
He's the one in the second dropdown from the left this one here which is obviously our our academy Donlin
programming up top 10 dead letter.
Now Edward device has had quite a few things going on at once so you can actually look at logs for other
applications if you want but it lets you get involved in Android system programming you generally just
want to leave it to display just the entries for your app.
Now if you do want to force tech tries to predict when you've caught an exception you could do that.
And I just took it back here back to occurred there close to the location so they could do that by calling
the print stack trace method of the exception.
So I got to add that to the catch block for the security exception just to show you.
So we can actually do that before the log.
Does it really matter where we do.
But we do it before we'll do a dot print stack trace to locate and make sure that I have cleared the
filter so it doesn't throw it out most of the spectra.
So basically I'm going to get more data about doing that.
And another by that time to start running it again.
So one of the first is I'll actually clear the filter as well.
OK.
And we'll run them again.
And you can say now that we've done that we've printed out quite a bit of stuff there.
Basically that's the price that we had before I caught the exception and you can see scrolling up and
it's actually done that now we're into it.
Today it doesn't color the message is red.
That's because they're created deliberately by by our act now rather than by the Java runtime.
But the links in the code rescored have a look to the wrought there's still a different color.
So it has to click on my activity Katie and get to learn 51 and see where the error actually is.
Basically it's the same lot of card the response equals connection response card.
Now something else we can do as I mentioned earlier is future are more than want to and be useful to
get some idea of what's happening through main activity and we can do that by filtering for main activity
or download data.
I we have say this before but we'll just briefly share that again.
So that's main activity.
You say the use of this pop pool bar character before vertical bar which actually means or can talk
Danila dicer and now we're getting information about main activity or download data so the vertical
bombings all basically.
All right so that cleans everything up and we can see uncreate pings started in my activity.
I mean he does want us to log entries for the download data class.
OK.
So I'm going to close the account for now and let's talk about permissions.
They are but a photo that has no permissions to anything at all.
And that has to get permission from the user to access resources it needs.
And this was usually done with the apps installed.
Now I say was as you can see on the screen there because with Android 6.0 marshmallow Google changed
the way that I that obtained permissions for the resources it needs.
No Prato Android marshmallow user grouted the requested permissions when they install the app.
If I didn't grant all the permissions that the app couldn't be installed once granted the app had all
the requested permissions for its entire lifetime of the device and the only way to revoke any of the
permissions was effectively to install the app.
Now with the above spell the one above and that requests the permissions it needs when it runs and it
has to do so each time it does run.
Notice the Google documentation states even if the app used the camera yesterday it kind of a shame
it still has that permission to live.
Now the documentation isn't as clear as it could be and if you read it in a certain way it could be
implying that Europe has to request the permission from the user.
Each time it runs.
But that isn't the case.
Fortunately once the user has granted permission then your app continues to have that permission and
unless the user specifically revokes it the app still has to request the permission each time.
But the Edwyn system doesn't ask the user every time.
All right so let's have a look at the documentation because apart from that one source of confusion
that's pretty good.
Now Google is separate the documentation into reference guides and Torrijos and the tutorial pages for
permissions explains it all.
I'm going to just put that in a browser.
Post the link for it.
Now this first page explains that each app runs in its own sandbox elsewhere the documentation explains
how this is achieved which is by creating a new Linux user ID for each app but we don't need to understand
that level of data to work with permissions.
No the killing StarLink down here at the bottom goes into a bit more detail so I that it starts by saying
that the app has to declare the permissions it needs in the app manifest.
We're going to be doing that for the Internet permission in a minute.
When the second paragraph is this description of the different behavior for Android versions up to 4.1
and for version 6.0 and whole.
Now up to four point one they use it grants permission when they install the app.
If they don't grant the permissions then the app doesn't install.
But from 18:26 point zero and above the HUSIC grants permission when they run the app then it's worth
going through this Google tutorial when you come to create your own apps.
Here's the recommendations of weight and how you should request permissions when your apps running.
No good we suggest that you don't read.
You don't request all the permissions at once but instead you wait until the user does something that
needs the permission before asking them for it and it makes more sense to the user.
If your app asks them to give them my full permission to access the contacts when I've just tried to
use your app to share file with someone for example.
But if you request that permission to suicide first run your app then they might be left wondering why
the app needs to access their contacts at all and that is a very useful link.
At the end of the third paragraph down here which is to take it to the definition of normal and dangerous
permissions no permission to access the internet cancels honorable permission and the system will automatically
grant that permission.
As long as we declare it in the benefits.
But scrolling down slightly.
You can say that Tony list here dangerous permissions and permission groups can talk.
Hear about mission groups and yes guys it's a bit more detail about the various types of permissions.
This is dangerous permissions as well.
It's a bit of an overview of what it is and again looking at the table section listing what I've enjoyed
talking all of what you suggest are dangerous permissions are going to be looking at had to do with
requesting permissions with no apps running later in the course when we need access to the context and
the microphone.
But in this quote up a bit and to the best basically up to the normal permissions script.
Noble and dangerous permissions.
There's a link that's a noble permissions so when I click on that if we have it all we can save is code
and internet is defined as a normal permission.
So the good news for this is that we only have to declare that we needed to get permission in the manifest.
They will then work on all Edward versions that were actually targeting suffocate back.
Back now to get George to go to open the Edwardo manifests.
Now if you're working an interview on a suggestion early to do that for the benefit in the manifests
folder under wraps.
I put that up.
You can say that I mean android.
You hear what manifests.
I'm going to click on that and there's no header manifest and ex-American double click on that.
Now don't worry too much about all this stuff in here.
We're going to be looking at the application tag later on and explaining what it means.
For now that we need to add an entry to declare that the app uses the Internet.
Now I'm going to make some space at the top here.
Just after the package before the start of the application tag I'm going to stop Torpey the user's text
or less sense on users.
Now I definitely recommend using the code completion chahiye to make sure you don't make any errors
when talking.
If you get the case wrong you won't see an error in here but the app won't work because the permission
must be granted.
Now one uses Desch permission to go into TEB to my Arrakis to get into that.
Then I'm going to present terracotta clicked on it to select it and notice that when I've done that
we automatically got this pop up.
I prefer to use the Cherokee Eric is to select the one I want and that's because I don't like switching
from the cable to best but it's your choice as to which one you want and all the available permissions
are showing and you can say here I can select the one I want.
And again these publishers are case sensitive.
So once again I recommend that you select them from the list rather than tossing them in and you can
filter the list as well so a topping cam for example say you could see the Android permission doc Kemmerer
is showing in the list but I don't want that once I want to delete cab top.
I Argentine's did and you could say we've got some the other ones that have got the letters.
I them them can see that there's the Internet permission there.
Once again he's dead.
OK I get Precentor and he can say that's it for us.
And I just need to close the tag with the forged Slessor and click on the fourth slash that closes and
adds the last bit of the tag and that's the Internet permission declared in the manifest.
Now this time the app should run without any errors so let's run it and have a look at the look at what
we're doing.
Well I put up the log at first it will run it will just clear the log log cat which I've mentioned before
is a good habit to get into.
Even though I had George Judaea tends to do that for us at the moment.
Right I can say this to.
We have got an era anymore.
If you scroll back up to the top you can see the run at the top.
We've got to download ex-Beatle the response card was hundred.
So that's looking good.
And that means that it responds better to her is OK.
If your internet connection goes through a proxy then you might get two or three response instead.
But that's also fine.
And we can see the example you probably saw that scrolling up and that's the Exham are printed by the
umpires to execute method.
So at the definitely working fine.
One thing to be aware of is that there's a limit to how much a log entry can be so you won't necessarily
see all the examples in the locker.
If it hadn't all downloaded had been an error so it looks it looks like everything is falling apart.
Have a look.
You say it seems you just chop it off.
But again that's due to the limit of luck kat.
And if we saw the error there was an error downloading we would have got some form of error and we haven't
in this case.
And we all had logged in number of Bauch was safe to say here is say 6 1 6 0 1 box which is about 6
6 came close to 7 quyte showing in the log so that's good.
So obviously it's not all been logged but it has been downloaded.
Yep otherwise we can see what happens when things don't work properly.
It's very simple to do we just change the U around to something invalid so we close the benefits for
now and don't just get back up to the top of that fall just.
Perhaps have another letter.
So this makes this add a very this to make them invalid so if we run that again they'll
And you can say we get a completely different era here and I will resolve.
I very extraordinary is that people will come and we get a traditional IRA.
So basically it's an exception that's being LUGG then we know that because it's no exception reading
data which was the message that we talked in when we specified the catch block for the IO exception
you could say here it's reading data.
Now the extra bit of the error message self-describe and have a look and able to resolve Hirst's obviously
that's not something that's come from us that's come from this 8. message property either here to the
right hand side and that's been printed out and basically we're updating that to the log tree no exceptions
include various bits of information and the message is a useful thing to log because it provides more
information on what may have caused the error or what sort of tested that old street exceptions are
caught.
But there's one thing more to do.
First they were put fixed line 23 could do that.
So we're left with now a valid yourself again.
They're going to do is turn off the internet connection in the simulator.
So we're going to just print the image on the screen.
Or that's what I'm going to do now is turn off the internet connection in the light to now unlock a
root of all.
Well you could just stop the watch fired by both data.
You can't actually do that on some emulators.
What we can do is turn on airplane mode which prevents the simulator from accessing the network you
know just like a physical device.
You can drag the top of the screen down.
Let's do that here to see the couple of options but we can also go into settings if we want and turn
on airplane mode there.
So click on that if you want to we could do a search for a plane select that I'm going to turn airplane
mode on and so you get the oxygen at the top of the screen here.
There will be another step.
Wasfi is off.
That's because the is using the computer's network connection.
Instead what it does it sees it as a mobile data connection.
Now what about data has an orchid on the Follette.
We go back to where we were there was I just closed it down because it abdicated.
And we can see over here this is the option for my Botella collection.
You click on that or click it up already applied by another click it off in any event and want to leave
it on for now and come back here and run again I going to kill the cat just to get into the habit of
doing that.
Let's see what happens with a mode on my boat.
I have turned off
and you can see what the IRA are no exception.
Reading tatter and able to resolve for highest.
So what that system do with the heisted cup he resolved even with a valid euro.
Now strangely Occasionally you will find this emulate Aboo work when you sit a plane might that happened
to just stop the EP and rerun it.
I presume it's some sort of bug perhaps with we'll see you later.
But in that case you can say that it worked here.
OK.
So that's how tantalizing the example for the RSS feed Doubleday's before we change anything.
It's just turn a planned mode off and click on to make sure that my boat out of condition is activated
and we just cut back and just run the one more time just to make sure that it's not working again.
And he can say we know we're getting data in the lock at the bottom so we could to go.
All right so that's the app but downloading the ex-MIL for the RSS feed in the next video we can change
oldest kind of brought it into much more content in like manner.
So see you in the next video.