all right so let's now run the app and
see if it works and I'm going to open
logcat I'm gonna make sure that I've
still got my filter set main activity
pipe to load data which I have and I've
also got red Jack's checked as well
which would be the default now as long
as I haven't left the emulator in
airplane mode it should all work I'm
going to clear what I don't need to
clear the lock at first because it is
clear if not do so and we'll run it and
see what happens and we'll tab over to
our app and that doesn't look good
there's no XML being logged and also no
stack trace to give us any indication of
what's going wrong you know there are
two errors as we can see here showing up
from main activity and if we click on
the top one the top error here that
takes us to as you can see our on post
execute function and to the call to the
pars applications dot pars function call
so with just that information in the
logcat things like this can be really
hard to debug but fortunately that isn't
all that's available the problem is and
I alluded to that is that we're
filtering the logcat and that means that
we don't see any entries being logged
unless they come from main activity or
from download data so I'm going to click
on this little X here to clear the
filter window and once I do that well to
clear the filter rather and once I do
that you can see that we've got the
complete log now that's actually gonna
give us far more to go on so remember
that if you filter the logcat make sure
you clear the filters when your app
crashes
otherwise you'll be trying to find the
cause of the crash with very little
information to go on
now before we cleared the filter there
was nothing to indicate that pars was
even being called now that could have
caused a lot of confusion when trying to
debug this so now that we've cleared the
filter we can see if we swap and have a
bit of a look here or we can actually
see anyway we can see that pars clearly
has logged the XML because that was
showing as soon as I cleared the filter
a
you can also see if we scroll down and
have a bit of a look here that the
actual error is here on line 29 no
cannot be cast Hunan no type Java dot
language strings I'm gonna click on that
and that takes us to the line that's got
the to do that I talked about in the
previous video so the error in the
locale was Kotlin dot typecast exception
and you can see this on screen no cannot
be cast to non no type Java dot length
string so what that essentially means is
that we try to call the to lowercase
method on a value that's null now xpp
dot name starts off no until something's
being read and no doesn't have any
properties or methods so to fix the
problem we're going to use the safe call
operator that we've used before and it
makes sure that we don't attempt to call
methods on things that are null so all
we really need to do here is actually
after the xvp dot name we're going to
put a question mark after that and then
going to remove the to do because we've
effectively fixed that now if we run
this again this time we're actually
getting our formatted data showing in
the logcat so clearly that was the issue
that we've managed to fix so if we
scroll back now up to the start of the
log we can see this uncreate starting
and then there's doing background starts
you're going to spots code of two
hundred and we screw it in a bit further
then you can see that the parser is
logging the XML that it receives and
that's working just like it did before
but after that if we keep scrolling down
again now past the XML we can see that
the log entries from our parse method
showing here studying tag for feed
studying tag for ID ending tag for ID
and so on so every time there was a
start underscore tag or end of the
school day event it got locked so the
lock caps showing the name of each tag
in the XML as the pull parser sets event
type to start underscore tag and end
underscore tag now if we scroll down and
read about 20 or so lines down we can
overhear the starting tag for entry so
from there to the end of the entry tag
the codes looking for the tags were
interested in and storing their values
in the feed entry object now we can make
life a little bit easier by using
control F or command F on a Mac to
search the logcat for entry so we'll do
that entry when I press ENTER it jumps
to the first account will actually jump
to the first occurrence automatically if
I press ENTER it should jump to an
occurrence of entry that's in the XML at
the top and I can use the down arrow on
the toolbar to jump to the next one I
come over here and get into the next one
and I can also use this little plus
button over here to highlight all the
places where entry appears and then they
will stay highlighted as long as I don't
close the search pane and that's great
for scrolling up and down the logcat
seeing where the entries starting in
click on that let's scroll up and down
and you can see entries highlighted
there for us automatically it's pretty
cool so the pass is going is going
through the entire XML stream responding
to the information it finds in there
there are codes checking to see when our
new tags found and when it ends and
pulling out the values we need now most
of the tags start and end straightaway
but when we get an entry tag starting we
stay in the entry because all the other
tags are nested inside it and once it's
gone through updated ID title and so on
processing all those tag
it eventually gets the closing tag for
entry there's release date and content
and then we get the in tag for entry so
you can see that as we're going down
here the starting tag all the various
tags there
release date Azhar said there and
eventually the tag ending tag for
content and then ending tag for entry
and then we've got another one starting
so once we get the end tag for an entry
we know that all its fields have been
processed and we can add the object to
the list and that's why most of the code
does its processing where we get to the
end underscore tag events in other words
that's why we added a lot of coding in
this particular areas the the end and
the score tag tag if that makes sense
so what I can also do is come over here
to the file and instead of just leaving
entry in there I can actually put a pipe
and the name as well I still want to
make sure that the regex
checkbox is checked but this time it's
the regex that are appropriate for the
search not the regex for our filter you
can see now that it highlights just
scroll down the file a little bit more
so we can see the bit better it's
highlighting both name and entry because
we've used the pipe to be able to search
for either of those now I've done that
to show why we keep track of when we're
inside an entry tag so I'm scrolling
back up it's go right back until we get
to the first entry
so there's the first entry so if keep
scrolling it back up to the top to our
very first entry
all right so our first entry is here but
you see above that there's a nametag
that's not part of that first entry
there but we don't want to use that name
it's the name of the whole feed not one
of the individual applications so
because we only use the tag valleys if
in entry is true the code will ignore
this one alright now if we scroll down
to the bottom here we can see the
summary of the application records that
we've created as well so there should be
ten applications there because we chose
the top ten feed and we can see the data
nicely formatted into the individual
feeds now one thing I want to mention is
the image URL there are actually three
image tags in each entry in our code
picks up the value of each one then
overrides it when the next one comes
around because the image tags appear in
size order in the XML we end up with the
URLs for the 100 by 100 image but you
shouldn't really rely on the ordering of
tags in an XML feed the XML would have
been invalid whether whatever order the
image URLs have appeared so go back to
Chrome and if we look for those images
so look for image you'll notice here
that the image has got a height
attribute so if we were interested in a
particular image size we could check
that attribute and only store the URL
for the height we wanted but I'm not
going to check the attributes in this
code because it will make it too
specific to these Apple feeds and you
may want to experiment with different
feeds but if you really want to test the
attributes you'd usually get attribute
value function of the pool passer and
you can search online for ways to do
that I'm going to pop up a slide for a
few seconds showing the changes I made
to test the height attribute and load
the small image URL or width the height
of 53 so if you want to choose a
specific image and get stuck you can
refer to this slide for one way to do it
all right so that's our application
downloading the feed and parsing out the
information we're interested in the next
step now is to display it on the screen
now we could add ten text few widgets to
the screen and put the details of each
application in them
but then the app wouldn't work for the
top-25 feed or for other fees that could
return perhaps hundreds of records so in
the next few videos we're gonna look at
one way of dealing with displaying data
when you don't know in advance how many
records is going to be so as always I'll
see you in the next video