In this video, we're going to download the YouTube Player library and add it to a project that we're also going to create.
So with Android Studio loaded, we're going to create this new project by clicking on 'Start a new Android Studio
project', and we'll call this one Youtube Player.
Now notice that I've used a lower case t in the word Youtube.
The library that we're going to be using now has capital T throughout.
And what I suggest you do for the company domain is do something a little bit different. Now in
my case I'm going to use learnprogramming.academy for the company domain.
But the reason we want to do something different is because we need to get an API key from Google,
and it's tied to the package name for the app.
Now I'm going to show you how to get the API key in another video, and that key is used by Google to track
usage of your app, and that allows them to charge you,
but don't worry you get plenty of free use.
So that won't be a problem for this app, but if every student used the same key, then with over 40000 students
that signed up to my previous version of this course, it may well be a problem.
So don't worry about being charged though, you have to enable billing in the developer console before Google
will charge you, and you'd have to use the app continually on loads of devices all day, to exceed the generous
daily limit that they actually give you anyway.
And again if you haven't enabled billing, you won't get charged and it'll actually stop working until
the next day.
So no matter what if you don't enable billing, you won't get charged anything if you do happen to manage
to go over the usage allowance.
So for this company domain I'm going to stick to using learnprogramming.academy,
but if you've got your own domain name I suggest you use that.
Otherwise use something like yourname.example.org, something that will be unique to you, and
probably a good idea to run your first and last name together, you know like
Tim Buchalka.example.org for example, or the other way round. Just try and make sure you enter something
unique there.
Alright so you know the drill with the Kotlin support box by now, so tick it if you want Kotlin code, or
untick it for java and I'm gonna click on next now.
And in fact you know the whole process pretty much now,
so in future videos we're going to be starting with the project already created and opened,
and I'll just give you the project name and the template to choose.
Alright so I'm going to choose API 17 here as before, go on
next. I'm going to select empty project, empty activity, click on next.
I'm going to leave the default for the activity name and the layout name, so that Android studio creates the
activity for us, and also creates the layout, and I'm going to click on the generate layout of file checkbox
as well as the backwards compatibility one, and click on finish.
Alright now, while that's getting set up what we need to do is go ahead and download the library that we
are going to be using for this project.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So I'm going to open a browser. I'm going to paste in the url,
and again what we're doing here is, or what we need to do, is integrate the YouTube API into our app,
and we have to download the library file from the Google YouTube site which I've gone to now.
And in case you wondering, API stands for Application Program Interface, and API provides functions or
classes for performing a certain task, or one task or another,
in this case playing YouTube videos. Alright so the page as you can see here contains a lot of information on using
the Android YouTube API.
There's also this reference tab up here which you can check with all the documentation for the various
classes, and as an exercise, perhaps once you've finished this app in this section of the course, you might
well want to come back and experiment with various other things.
Now one example might be checking out this YouTube.ThumbnailLoader
So have a play once you've finished the app in this section of the course, and maybe modify it to add some more
functionality. Now by the time we've finished this app, you'll have seen how to do things like launch a new activity
when the user clicks a button, so that you can add more screens to the app if you want.
So there's all this information available which makes using the API a lot easier,
but we need to download the libraries, so I'm going to click on guides up here, the guides tab to go back.
Now just down the page here is a link to the download page, this one here.
There's also a link over here in the left hand side, but I'm showing you this one for a reason, and it's saying
you need to have version 4.2.16 or higher of the YouTube app installed on your device
to be able to use this API.
Now previously I had to suggest that you use a physical device to test this app on.
However when Android Oreo was released, Google used or also released, emulators that can install apps
from the Google Play store so that limitation's been removed.
And there's actually now two different types of emulators, but we'll be discussing the differences
when we come to running this app.
So for now I'm going to click on the download link that takes us to the download page.
Now the version number when I'm recording this video as you can see on the screen is 1.2.2,
and it doesn't seem to change very often, but if there happens to be a new version when you come to watch this
then that's fine.
Just grab that current version and download it.
So I'm going to click on download and I'm going to save it to my downloads folder.
Now we're going to follow that downloaded file, and I'm going to double click it in my case to extract it.
But if you run Linux you can right click and choose extract,
and if you're on Windows you can do a similar thing, you can click on and extract all.
So basically unzip the file then go into the unzipped folder.
There's a libs subfolder: you want to click on that, then
there's this YouTubeAndroidPlayerApi.jar
so we want to select that. In my case I'm going select copy.
So you'll do the equivalent if you're on Windows or on Linux, and then we want to swing back to our project in Android Studio.
Now generally speaking, keeping the project pane in Android view is more convenient, but there are a
few things that you can't do in Android view.
Now one of these is copying external libraries into the project,
and that's because the libs folder that we need isn't available in Android view.
So you can see up here there's no mechanism to get to the libs folder,
so what I'm going to do is switch into Project view briefly,
using this drop down up here, select project.
Once I do that I can then click to open the project folders, click on app and we've now got this libs folder,
and you can see at the moment that's empty, so I can right click the libs folder
and I can select paste. And you can see that we've got a dialog asking for confirmation of the copy,
so make sure the directory it's copying the file into does say libs at the end, and you can see clearly here
on my screen that it does say libs, so we're in the right place.
Click OK, and now if we expand by clicking on this little triangle, we can see that the YouTube
AndroidPlayerApi.jar is now in the libs folder.
Alright so with that done, I'm going to go back now and switch it back to Android view.
So now that we have copied the file into the libs folder, we need to tell Android Studio to use it in our project.
Now one way to do that is to add a reference to it in the build.gradle file.
Now things are changing at the moment and you might still be working on the older version of Android
Studio as well as this one,
so I'm going to show you another way. So you can go into the file menu and you can click on project
structure. Once you do that, in the left hand side list here select app from the module section down here. Then you want to
come over here to the right and click on the dependencies tab, and that lists all the dependencies
for this project.
Now as you can see we're using the appcompat library, and we're also using the constraint layout etc. Now if you're
producing Kotlin code, you'll also see the standard Kotlin library in the list. You can see down here I've got that
showing as well.
Now right at the top, usually it's at the top, is a reference to *.jar files in the libs directory. Now
that would automatically include any jar files that we place in the libs directory,
and of course we've actually done that at the moment.
So there's really no need to do what we're about to do,
and that's because our YouTube library will be automatically included in the project because we put it into
the libs folder.
But I think it's useful to know how to add libraries, especially if you decide to keep the jar files
in a different directory.
So we're going to go through that process anyway.
So to add a jar file explicitly, rather than relying on that catch-all include, you click on the green plus.
In my case it's down here, but it may be at the top right,
depending on what operating system you're running on,
but click on the add anyway,
in any event. Once you do that you get this little pop up menu,
and you want to click on and choose Jar dependency.
Now once you do that, that pops up a file browser which lets us browse the directories in the project.
Now the jar file has to be in the project somewhere.
So on Linux though unfortunately there's no ability to move back up to browse the entire hard disk. On my Mac though,
I have to actually browse into the project directory and find libs, and you'll need to do a similar
thing for Windows, so in my case I'm actually already there.
I've already got the YouTubePlayer app libs folder, and you can see the YouTubePlayerApi.jar,
sorry the YouTubeAndroidPlayerApi.jar, is actually there.
I can just expand that out, we can see the full file name.
So do whatever you need to do to get that open.
Select the file then, and click on OK or open, depending on what your operating system shows,
and you can see that that entry has been added now to the screen.
Now if you want you can remove this catch-all include entry up here,
at this point. You just click on it and use the red minus button, or in my case it's not red, but it will
be, depending on your operating system,
it may be a different color, and it may also be over here to the right,
but in my case on the mac it's down the bottom. So if I clicked on that now that would actually remove
that entry, but there's no need to remove it because the library won't be included twice if you leave it in.
Now if you're experimenting with different libraries or trying different versions, then you don't want
everything included automatically,
and this is how you prevent everything in libs from being added.
So only the libraries you add explicitly will appear in the project if you actually remove this line.
But I'm going to leave it so you can see it in the build.gradle file.
So, for that reason I'm just going to click OK because we're actually finished here now.
And you can see it's got a gradle projects sequence in process, so Android Studio quickly realised there
was a change and synced the project for us.
Now in earlier versions of this course we added the library by modifying the build.gradle file, but
the way we've just done it's safer, because there's no chance of typing the filename incorrectly.
It's useful though to be familiar with build.gradle though, so
let's have a look in there to see what we've just done.
Now confusingly with Android Studio projects, there's two build gradle files: one you should edit, and one that
you very rarely change.
Now the one we what, and I'm going to click on it and expand this, down here,
the one we want is in the app's directory.
This one up here is lower in the tree as you can see, below
the Project:YoutubePlayer, this one here, build.gradle module app. Now because we'll not only be looking at
Android view though,
I'm not going to change the file name here.
And if we go back now and have a look in Project view again, you can see we've got this build
dot gradle and
it's actually in the app path, and there's also not a build gradle there. But if we go back now again
just to have a look in Android view, we've got, all the gradle scripts are in the same place.
But it still shows just the module up here and this is the one that ultimately we want to have look at.
So I'm going to double click on that
to open it, and just out of interest if you accidentally opened the wrong one,
have a look at this other one,
it actually makes a point of saying 'Don't place your application dependencies here;
they belong in the individual module build.gradle file'. So it's really just a warning to let you know that,
or to remind you that perhaps you're looking at the wrong build gradle file.
So I'm to close that one down and leave our app one open.
Now eventually you'll get used to which one's which
but till then, just open one and if you see that warning then close it and then open the other one.
So in this case we've now got the right one open.
So this module build.gradle file has all sorts of information telling Android Studio, or really the gradle
build system, how to build the file that's deployed to our devices or emulators.
So down at the bottom here,
inside the dependency section, we can see the jar file that we added right on the last line, sitting there
now. Now we could have just typed that line in, instead of going through the menu that we did earlier in the video,
and if you do type these entries in, it's really important that you get the case right.
Now I mentioned at the start of the videos about the upper and the lower case t, and you can see here that
on the libs/YouTube we've got a capital T there.
If you use a lower case t in YouTube for example, it won't work.
Now if you're used to Windows, remember to put the slash rather than the backslash between libs and the jar
filename, so don't use backslashes in other words. So at the top of this dependency section is that catchall
entry I talked about, to include all jar files from the libs directory.
Now I didn't delete it then so you could see it in here,
but I'm going to delete that entire line now, and move that up.
Now it's usually a good idea to be explicit about what you want to do when programming,
rather than relying on default behavior, and this is why I've specifically listed the YouTube Android
Player API jar file. So I've deleted that implementation file tree line.
Now it wouldn't hurt to leave it in. The library wouldn't be included twice, but we're being explicit here,
and we're listing the jar file in it's own implementation statement anyway on line 34.
Now with that said there's no guarantee that Google won't remove that default inclusion of all jars
in the lib folder, so it's really useful to know what's going on here.
Now whenever you make a change to the build gradle file, you'll get a message at the top as you can see now
telling you that the file's changed, and you need to click the Sync Now link.
But if you're making several changes you can actually do all the changes first.
Just make sure that you do the Sync Now, or
click the Sync Now, by clicking the link once you finish the changes, or you'll find things won't work
properly. So I'm going to click on Sync Now.
Now there are a few more things to look at in this file.
The first are that these dependencies over here start with the word implementation. Now in previous versions
of Android Studio, that used to say compile instead.
And if you're working on an old version as well, or more accurately if you're using an older version of gradle,
then that'll be compile instead of implementation.
So watch out for that and use compile if you're working with the older versions.
Now if you go through Android Studio's menu like we did first, it'll use the correct keyword.
Now the other thing that you may want to change in here are the minSdk up here, and the targetSdkVersion here at the top.
Now these are the values we provided in the wizard, when we originally created the project earlier in this video.
Now if you change your minds then this is the place to change them. So more importantly, if you open an old
project and you want to convert it to target the latest version of Android, or maybe drop support for
an old version,
then you can change these settings in here.
Remember that the minimum version now supported is API 14, Ice cream sandwich.
Now if you're converting an old Marshmallow or Nougat project to Orio, then you'll also want to change the compile STK
version to 26, and the build tools version to the latest version of Orio. So as I record this
it's 26.0.2 but have a look at any new project you've created to get the
correct version numbers.
assuming you've installed all the latest updates of course.
Now the last thing here is that it's possible that this app compat line is actually highlighted, so what
I'm going to do is change this back just to show you what I mean here.
I'm going to change this back to an older version,
26.0.2
and I'm going to show you what happens when there's a newer version available. I'll give that a moment to sync. Then you'll notice
now that we've got an older version here, that this is actually highlighted,
and if I hover over that, it actually says a newer version of the app compact library is available. And if I actually
click on that, we get the lightbulb
over here. And I can come down here, and I can click on change to 26.1.0 and that number
will be whatever the latest version is, and that will update it, then I need to come over here and click
on Sync Now.
So if you see any entries highlighted like that in yellow, that's the way to actually update them to
make sure that you're running the latest version.
And keep in mind that when you click on the Sync Now button, that will actually do any necessary downloads
to get that latest version for you. Pretty cool.
Now I've already gone ahead and actually clicked on that and actually updated it.
But generally before you update there are implications,
and that's why Android Studio didn't just go ahead and upgrade it anyway.
Now you'll find it does that for certain things like the gradle build system.
It'll prompt you but can update gradle automatically.
The reason for that is, that only affects the build process -
it doesn't change what's compiled into your final app - but changing those library versions does change your app.
So if you're app's gone through final testing for example, and it's ready for release, you can't suddenly
go changing the library versions. If you do, the app will need full testing again.
And the other thing to keep in mind is that sometimes new libraries do introduce bugs. They can also change
the way your app works in subtle ways.
So bear that in mind - if you change any of these library versions, your app will need testing again before
you release it.
Now while you're working through the examples in this course, I recommended that you do use the latest version
of all the libraries though.
And that's why I went ahead and clicked on the light bulb and I changed the app compat vision to
26.1.0 which is the latest version currently existing.
And then obviously I went through and clicked on the Sync Now. Aright we're going to be coming
back to this file later to look at some of the other things in here, but for now though
that's the project set up so that we can use the YouTube API.
So I'm going to go ahead and close the API, the build.gradle file here, and we'll finish off the
video. In the next one,
we're going to start work creating a new activity to show those YouTube videos.
So see you in the next video.