Alright, so there's one other thing that I want to quickly show you before we start experimenting further,
and that's the Theme Editor. Now at the top right of the window, when you're editing a file containing style
tags,
is this link to Open editor.
So I'm going to click on that.
Now the reason I'm not going to spend long on this is because frankly, it's rubbish.
You'd be much better off, or are much better off editing the small amount of xml that you have to
deal with, to create styles rather than using this editor.
But with that said let's have a look anyway.
So it starts off by displaying the AppTheme style, and you can see that in the Theme dropdown at top right over here.
Now we haven't changed AppTheme for the various API levels, but we have changed the AppTheme dot NoAction
Bar.
So I'm going to select that style, using that dropdown over here, AppTheme.NoActionBar.
Now we can see the various parts of the display and how they've been styled.
That's pretty cool,
and that may be the best use for this theme editor.
In fact, the term theme viewer might be a better use for it.
Now over at the top left, we can see how the toolbar's been styled, and you see that it's in
teal at the moment.
And it also shows how buttons will appear as well. Now as of the time I'm recording this video, it's not
doing a great job of rendering the fab button, down here, very well.
You can see that it's showing a grey square and we know, of course, that the fab appears in deep orange.
So there are a few little bugs with this.
And another thing that you'll probably notice is that the main display doesn't always update straight
away. Once you scroll the main screen, though,
generally, everything does fix itself up and gets updated. OK so we've got API 27 showing up here in the drop
down at the top.
So as of the time I'm recording, API 27 is the latest version, but Google are yet to release all the information
about that, including the source code etcetera.
Alright, so over here we've got API 27 showing in the dropdown at the top, and over on the right hand side, you can
see down here in various places, it shows API 26 for many of the attributes.
Now normally that will be the same number,
so if it's 27 here, it'll be API 27 here,
but because API 27 is in transition as of the time of I'm recording this video, that's why we're seeing a
discrepancy there.
But note that it's also showing API 23 for some of these attributes.
And those are the attributes that we've specified in the v23 style sheet, so navigation bar color
being one example of that.
You see that it's sharing API 23 over here to the right.
Now we can change, either using the dropdown at the top over here, or the one next to each particular attribute.
So what I'm going to do is start with the top one up here, and change this to API 17, and you will notice that it
seems to take a while to update the screen sometimes, and if I come back up here to my mouse,
notice how just doing that changed it to 17.
So it seems to be a bit buggy at the moment, but note that when I did do that, now that the navigation bar
down here is now showing in black rather than dark teal.
So it knows that our theme doesn't style the navigation bar on API levels below 21, then the display obviously
reflects that.
Now the API levels on the right
may well go up to, may be a bit strange as well.
So color primary, if we have a look at that up here,
may be showing API 23 and it is in my particular case.
So it's quite good,
this Theme Editor, for showing you which parts of the display you've set to various colours, and you can
drop down different API levels to the right hand side over here, to see which value you've specified or defined
at the various API Android levels.
Now I say quite good.
When I first did this it was showing a switch colour as a light hue, up here.
So it was showing that, rather than the orange accent color we're actually using.
So it's certainly not perfect.
Now if you want to change a colour, click on the image of the colour
with the folded up corner.
This is these ones over here,
and we'll get a resource dialogue.
So if I go on to change color primary dark for some reason, I click on that there, and that can
take a while to pop up
occasionally. So I can scroll down and choose something else. I could try choosing, perhaps, holo blue dark and
click OK, and you can see the change is being reflected over here to the right. And if you go back
to our styles files now and have a look.
Firstly in our regular styles dot xml, and look at color primary dark, and specifically down here under the AppTheme dot No
ActionBar, because remembering that's what we're editing, and you an see the item name equals color
PrimaryDark, and we've got the new definition that we've just specified.
And if we have a look in our v21, we've got a similar thing appearing there for colorPrimaryDark, down there on line 7.
and v23,
we've again got the same feature there.
So basically it's updated that style in all three files, and it,
in other words, it knew that this NoActionBar style was defined for
each of the three API levels, and made that change. So that's good.
Now one thing that it is really useful for, is defining your own colors.
Now with that said, I'm not suggesting you do that. Google's material design colours have been carefully chosen
to work well together.
But if you're an expert designer or you're matching a corporate style or something, then you may need
to use different colours.
So I'm going to use color primary for this, and click on the color image to get that resource
dialogue back. Then I'm going back into Theme Editor first, then color primary, I'm going to click on over here.
Now over to the right here,
there's two links.
You can see we've got Reference and Color.
So the Color link gives you a color picker and lets you define a new colour. So click over here,
and you want to make sure if you do that, that you give it a name at the top up here,
otherwise it's going to overwrite one of your existing colors.
Now it's just a standard color picker, and it shows the custom colour that you've chosen, as well as how text
will look using the primary and secondary text colours. And you can use a little dropper to the left of it
here, to to click on a color anywhere on the screen and it'll actually match it for you.
Now I certainly wouldn't recommend trying to create styles using this.
It's much more reliable to modify the xml, but it's there if you want to use it,
and by all means have a play with it.
But I do suggest you back up your xml files first, because if for example, if you change the theme
parent using the dropdown list, you can't always get the original ones back again.
Alright that's all I really wanted to say about it.
I've shown it to you, and if you decide to create styles using it,
then don't say I didn't warn you if something goes amiss. Now before I finish this video though, I'd better
put everything back.
So I'm going to close down or cancel out of this pop-up. I'm going to close down the Theme Editor, and in each of the style
files I'm going to go back and just remove that
extra line, the colorPrimaryDark that was added. So we're back on what we were before this video.
So v21 and v23 are back to our regular styles, and I'm going to remove that one down here as well, in the
AppTheme.NoActionBar.
So we've now got just those two entries in AppTheme.NoActionBar.
That was for the regular styles v23.
We've still got the extra two that were there prior to this video,
the v21, and we've just got those three.
And also check for additional styles files that may have been created.
It's easier to do that in the project view,
just make sure you've only got three styles files. So I can come back here and click on project and I can come down to
our values folders.
So you can see we've got styles which is in the original values folder, and we've got values v21 in styles and values v23
has only got a styles, so it hasn't created any more files in this case.
But if there are any others that the Theme Editor created, now is a good point to actually delete them and
I suggest you do that.
Alright so we're going to go back to Android view, and I'll end the video here, and in the next one
what we're going to do is experiment with the image that we show, when displaying the full photo.
So I'll see you in the next video.