so let's go through some common database
terminology that should be useful for
you when we're working with the
databases in this section of the course
and the idea here is that it will
make it a lot easier to understand the
app when you understand what the
fundamentals are and what all the
actual various terms mean now the very basic level the databases the
container for all the data that you store
or that resides inside now when you
use the term database you're referring
to the entire data as well as the
structure its actually stored in
and in addition any queries and views on
that data now in sql lite which is
the database used for android apps
the entire database contents are stored
in one single file but that isn't true
of most large database systems now the
database dictionary provides a
comprehensive list of the structures and
types of data that are used in recording
the data so basically describes all the
tables and fields within the database now
more on the specifics later but in
sql lite there is a table in each
database called SQL_lite_master that has this information
in it you can query that table but there
are commands that do it for you so you
don't have to understand the structure
of the master table but it's there for
you anyway and as we go through the
app you'll see how these commands
actually work
now a table is a collection of related
data hold in the database so i think of
a contact database for example that
stores the name and the address and the
phone number or perhaps your customers
or what about an invoice table that
records the invoice number in details of
the invoice so in this slide there are
two tables contacts and invoices that are
used to store information about contacts
and invoice details now its SQL lite
databases such a sql lite again used
in android app development or another
database like Microsoft sql server
there are ideal for storing structured
data that can be organized neatly into
rows and columns like you can see in
these examples now with all the interest
in Big Data their databases such as no
sql or hadu that can cope with data
that doesn't have such an obvious
structure but we're going to be
restricting our use of database to
structured data
so field is the basic unit of data in
the table so a field in a database can be
thought of probably in a similar way to
what an instance variable in Java is and
you've seen those obviously in different
apps and just like a class variable a
database field has a name and a type
now the type restricts what kind of
data can be stored in the field for
example it could be a string or it could
accept numbers so many databases also
allowed date fields large text fields
and also fields where you can store
things like photographs or audio and
these field types can
often are often called blobs which is
supposed to stand for binary large
object it's a great name and I can't
help thinking that the original acronym
was something like LBO for large binary
object and they came up with a cooler name afterwards
now fields are often referred to as
columns in databases I know this can be
technically confusing sometimes because
if you come from an Excel background
you'll find that the definition is
probably a bit different to what you
think of as a column in the spreadsheet
the term column refers to an entire set
of data extending across many rows but
in a relational database column
generally refers to a single entry
although when talking about the
structure of a table rather than the
actual data then you could talk about a
column to hold the invoice number which
is probably closer to the spreadsheet
use of the term now when referring to
the data in the database though we're
talking about an individual item like a
base unit of data the relational
databases existed nearly 10 years before
the first spreadsheet program and we
just have to accept that column means
slightly different things in each case
but more on that shortly
now a row or record is a single set of
data for all fields that are in that
table so if you've got four columns like
the example on the screen and if your
table has an invoice number or a date
a description and an amount then a row
represents those four values for a
single invoice so it's really a
collection of all the columns that
comprise the details of one entry in
that table so the highlighted record
holds the details for invoice number two
which was a laptop costing just a
thousand dollars sold on the
twenty-fourth of may 2016 and you can use
either the terms row or records to
identify it but the correct relational
database terminology is actually row
....
now a flat file database stores all
the data in a single file which can
result in a lot of duplication of data
over here
ISPs credit limit needs to be increased
so that they can purchase the monitor as
otherwise that can actually go over the
limit
so in order to increase the limit the
data in three rows would have to be
modified
now as you can see every row in the
table that contains a record for isp
must be changed in order to increase the
credit limit so flat file databases are
not used very often anymore but they
were fairly popular in the early days as
they directly mapped to those card index
records that companies sometimes used
now if we were storing names addresses
and phone number type information than a
flat file database is fine for the job
and even today people still use address
books and rolex style contact systems
with each person's details on a
different card but there isn't really
much need to relate the individual cards
to each other
this works perfectly well as you can see
from this invoice example though trying
to store all the data in a single table
results in duplicate data you're using a
relational database tables can be
related to other tables which is very
useful
so continuing on with the invoice
example we can split the data out into
a customer table which contains standard
company data such as their name address
and a credit limit and another table
called invoices containing all that
customers purchases the name column in
the customer table is related to the
name column in the invoices table now in
relational database terms this is called
a join in fact in this example we have a
one-to-many join because they can and
probably will be many invoice rows for
each customer using a relational model
updating a customer's credit limit
involves changing the data in just a
single row so there is a mechanism to
join these two tables to link the
individual records in each table to each
other and you'll often see designs were
third table is used to provide the link
that's in this next slide
and it's also very common to use a
linking table to relate the data to two
other tables now here when an invoice
record is stored a new record is created
in the customer_invoices table
to link for example invoice triple 0 4
with customer isp now one advantage of
this is that the invoice table only
contains data relating to invoices the
rows are not cluttered up with
customer information of any kind not
even the customer name splitting the
data up like this is known as
normalization now database
normalization is basically the process
of removing redundant duplicated and
irrelevant data from the
tables and the more that this is done
the higher the level of normalization if
you look into a normalization you'll
find that you can go up to level 6
normal form but in most practical
applications it's ready to go beyond the
third level that's an interesting
subject but the math can get a bit
horrible at the higher levels our
example on the slide isn't quite as
normal as we should be because we've
used the customer name as the link
between the customer and invoice tables
and if one of our customers change its
name which is quite common thing happen
then we'll have to update each of the
relevant entries in the customer
_invoices table as well the
usual way to do with this is to use a
unique ID field that stays the same for
each customer once its allocated we
shouldn't store the customer balances in
the table has that's best calculated
when needed
so a view is a way of looking at the
data in a format similar to a table but
bringing data together for more than one
joint table so in this example the view
contains columns from the customer table
and the invoices table so a view can
just contain just some columns from a
single table for example just the
description column from the invoice table to produce a list of items that
have been sold now in SQL lite the data
in a view can't be updated so that means
that you can't add a new row to a view and have it place to new data into the
relevant tables some databases
such as Microsoft sql server do allow
this but in that case you do have
restrictions on the columns that can and
must contain if they're used in this way
that's not something we need to worry
about because we can't do that in sql lite
alright so that's enough to get started
and we're going to explore these terms
more as we go through sql lite so
coming up in the next videos we're going
to discuss a a few more database concepts
and i'll be going into more detail will
be using practical examples and actually
using the sql lite database now
sql lite is designed to be embedded
applications and is actually a library
that's called from our application code
it does ship with the shell program that
you can use to create databases in
integrate them though and we'll start by
using that to explore the commands
available in sql lite now before we
can use that shell program we need to
make sure that it's available on your
systems path so the next three videos
are going to show you how to do that for
windows mac and linux so there's one
video for each operating system so
follow the instructions in the relevant
video for your operating system and you
can skip over the videos that aren't
relevant so i'll see you in one of those
videos