in this video we're going to set up the
command line so that we can use to sql
lite command-line interface now this is
actually for windows so if you're running
windows do watch this video as we go
through and show you how to set up the
path but if you're on a Mac or running
linux there's a separate video for you
in this section so go and watch that
one instead of this one because that's
going to have everything that's needed
to get to the sql lite command line
interface working on your operating
system but for windows you're in
the right place so we actually are going
to digress and set up your
computer to access things as i mentioned
the like the sql lite Command
line interface and we're doing that so that
we can enter sql lite commands on
your computer
alright and you may have noticed that
when you run your apps from android
studio sometimes a brief message pop up
saying waiting for ADB and this comes
up as Android studio starts the adb
server on your machine and check that
there's a physical device or emulator
that can connect to now ADB
extremely useful for managing android
devices and is the way that Android
studio installed and runs your app now
because android studio knows where the
sdk is installed on your machine this is
the Android SDK it can use tools like
the sql lite command-line interface
and adb with no problems but for us to
use them directly what we have to do is
add the Android SDKs platform tools
directory to our computers path
let's see how we go about doing that so
the first step is to see if the paths
already setup so make sure android
studio is started as you can see it's
opened up here now and you can open the
project from the previous section
just fine
we're not actually going to use the
project we just need to get android
studio running
alternatively you can just started as
I've got it here and just beyond the
main screen without opening a project
and once that starter want to actually
click on the terminal tab to start a
terminal session we can do that in a
few ways you can just come down here to
the windows button and we can if you've
got windows 10 you can just type in
command we get the command prompt come
up like that and i can press enter we
get a command prompt
alternatively on an older version
windows you just click on here will be a
run window and you type in CMD in there
and press ENTER and you'll get a screen
similar to this one so now if we type in
the command adb press enter and that's
checking to see whether the paths
already been set up as you can see in my
particular case i've got a message
saying adb is not recognized as an
internal or external command operable
program or batch file that's telling us
that we do need to continue on with the
steps in the rest of this video if you
did get another message of something
about adb running that would mean that it's already been configured and
you don't need to do it again
alright so what we need to do now is
check where the Android SDK installed on
your computer so go back to android
studio now if you've got a project open
you can go to the file menu and select
project structure and that will get you
to the same place i'm about to do here
and the welcome screen I can just click
on configure and go to SDK manager
and what we're looking for is this
android sdk location and you can see on
the screen there it's in my case c colon
backslash users backslash tim backslash / app
data backslash local backslash android
backslash sdk quite a mouthful but
that's basically where the android sdk
is installed on this computer and it may
well be different for your computer and
most likely it will be different
we're going to select the full path i'm
just going to copy it like so I'm doing
command C and and going to just
open notepad and again in that you can
either in the run window you can type in
notepad or in the case of Windows 10 i
can just type notepad or type
enough letters and it pops up the match
and open Notepad i'm going to paste in
that path so you can see the path that I
got from Android studio is now in the
notepad and again don't worry if yours
is different if you copied it from
Android studio then it will be the
correct path to wherever your SDK is
installed now ADB and sql lite are
actually stored in a folder called
platform tools within the Android SDK
folder so what we need to do is on the
end of this path that we've
copied from Android studio we gonna put
another backslash and type platform-
tools like so and you can see
we've got the entire path showing on the
screen there once we've done that we
need to copy this again i'm selecting
and i'm doing a command c or
right click and select copy
either way and we need to then put
this path into the system android studio
won't actually detect the path change
until it restarts i'm going to exit
android studio anyway now that we're
done with that we don't need it anymore
we're going to go into the windows
control panel or settings to make this
change now if your computer's got a
Windows key then the quick way for all
versions is to use the windows and pause
button and sometimes pause and breake
are on the same key normally at the top right of
the keyboard
however some laptops can be different
but that's the quickest way to get into
the options the options where we want to
go and in my case what I'm going to do
is I'm going to click on the windows
button click on settings and you might
need to click on that and select control
panel depending on your version of
windows alright now what I'm going to
do their will be a couple of ways for you to get to
the area in control panel with the settings that
we need to get into on Windows 10 I
can type advanced click on
View advanced system settings
that's going to get me there but you may
actually have an option to go into
system on an older version of windows to
get to the same screen and if you click
on the windows key and pause a windows
option pop up and a
little link you can click on to select
advanced system settings bottom line is
you want to get into this little screen
as we can see now and the other way
you can do it just in case you having
trouble finding it on windows we have
versions before Windows 10 just right
click the my computer icon on your
desktop and choose properties and you
there
Windows 10 doesn't have an easily
accessible my computer so press the
start button and type environment would
be another way of doing it so you get
two options in that case but the first
one does nothing so click the second
one
alright so we're going to be now
changing something here in the system
properties under advanced so from the
system properties want to click on the
environment variables down here now unless your already really comfortable with
doing this leave the system variables
alone
if you mess up the system path variable
it can actually be quite difficult to
recover from but under the user
variables at the top here there may or
may not already be a path variable defined if their is you want to click on
it and click Edit but if their isn't just click new so assuming that
the said path over here to the
left click on edit but in my case I
haven't got a path variable so i'm going
to click on new and because it's new i'm
going to type path but if you were
editing at that point in time you
wouldn't touch the variable name because
that would already be set to path you've
been working only in this variable value section
now if there was something already
in this path lets just say that you got
there and their is already something like that
showing leave that in there you don't
want to delete what's already in there
but you want to put a semicolon at the
end of it and then paste in what you've
copied out of notepad so that they are
actually both their but in my case I'm
going to delete that because of course
we didn't have a path user variable so
I'm just going to paste in  that
link that we've got from notepad and click
on ok so once that's done we can click
on OK and click on OK again and the
changes will be made now what we're
going to do now is closed that down and
we'll leave that notepad for now but we can
probably close that and not save
it in a minute
so now we're here what we're going to do
is we're going to type in a command like
we type before adb to see whether it
works if you do get an error like that
what you need to do is click type exit
and close it down then we need to do the
same process to actually open the
command window again in my case i'm
going to type command and i'm going to
type adb again you can see now that
we've got a whole heap of mumbo-jumbo
there but the bottom line is that
this time it didn't come up and say it
wasn't able to be found
so what that's actually telling us is
that we now configured the path
successfully and in the next video
when we start actually looking at how to
use this sql lite will be able to
access that that's because the sql
lite is in the same path as ADB if you
really wanted to at this point we could
now type sql lite 3 and press enter and
you can see now that we've got an option
coming and says sql lite version
3.9.2 again
this is our way of accessing databases
and we've confirmed we can use both the ADB
and sequel lights so we good to go so
we can quit out of here and the way to
quit out of there is just to type .quit
that's it so that's the end of this
video we've tested that adb is working
but more importantly would also tested
that sql lite is working and now
that means that we're ready to go and
start working on this in the next video
so because this is the windows video you
want to skip the mac and linux videos
now that are following this one and move
on to the video after that we can start
using sql lite i'll see you in the
next video