All right so that's the database file created at that moment.
There's nothing in it.
So I need to execute some sequel statements to create a table and put some data in it.
Let's go ahead and add the code for that.
So I'm going to do a sequel.
He calls in double quotes create table space contacts in parentheses or left parentheses underscore
ID spice integer spice pro-McCain common spice K spice not spice.
No comma spice text comma find spice integer comma team spice text the raw parentheses and close the
double quite.
Two cards is the string of what we what we can do is to a database dot exec Saeco and in parentheses
pass Sakal playing the string.
So I want to execute and then what we'll do is on the next line would you say call equals Betancourt's
insert spice into any spice contex parentheses nine common spice wine common spice female parentheses
spice and valleys and left parentheses single quite timid single quote comma and put six four five six
seven eight nine come on then a single quites to that same outcome single quite there in parentheses.
Not quite.
Now I'm going to do the same thing there database dot exec Sakal and pass sequence the argument again.
So the method we call to execute sequence statements in our database as we can say is the exec siecle
method and all we're doing there is passing a string containing the Siku statement when executed.
So we start off by creating a table called contex that contains the three columns name phone and email.
And we also including an ide column.
And we've discussed the already column before and we'll see how Android uses it.
When we come to populate a list view from our data.
So an expert inserted some data into the table.
I'm going to insert some data in the type of guy using the second insert statement alone 23.
We've used that in previous videos.
The the white cotton strings are enclosed in speech marks or quites so therefore it makes sense to use
single quites in so it has Saeco instead insert statements and I've done that as you can see launced
when he's right there we could use double quotes or speechmatics inside a string.
But then we'd have to skate escaped with a backslash.
So that Cutler knows we're putting a space Mago quite inside the string rather than terminating the
string at that point they can get confusing having all these backslash characters.
So I think it makes a lot more sense to use single quites for the values inside a second string rocksand
it's part that's how first insert statement and it should create a new row in the context table with
those values.
And these are the same siecle commands that we've used in previous videos when we entered siecle into
the C Kalat three command line interface.
So we're literally just passing them as arguments to the exec siecle method.
Now the exec sequel method isn't really intended to be used for data manipulation statements.
It works and we will verify that shortly.
Let's see what the documentation has to say about it.
We're going to come up here and click on the exact siku.
I'm going to pick up that pipe in the documentation.
You could say he executes a single sequence type that is not a select or any other.
Is your statement that returns data.
So in other words if you try to execute a select statement you'll get an error.
Now the documentation is quite a little bit further.
Also it mentions the uncertain update method and we're encouraged to use them instead of exec siecle.
We want to change data in the database.
Now one reason for using Insert an update is that we've got no record of the ID that was generated for
any right.
So that's often important.
We may want to store it in the news tag for example so that we can quickly retrieve the record that's
being displayed.
One example.
Now I would change the way we're adding that record but I will add another one this time using the insert
method instead.
And to do that can come down here after the insert into context long after the second call to the exact
same call method that values equals and kind of code content values happen in closing a print.
It's not a ploy.
Kenny Brice and right which you can say has been added automatically and then the next one I'm going
to put put parentheses.
That's really Niven type of quartz comma and Fred and double quites like slobbing the report parentheses
again.
Finally double quotes and then this time I can put one two three four five with out double quotes and
on the third line put parentheses around double quotes come up and double quotes Fred at Newark dot
com quite the raw parentheses.
They got the closing right.
Kelly Bryce there's you can say that after that what we're going to do is put Vau generated on D is
equal to database don't insert parentheses contex and double quotes come up the values and I missed
one argument there because if I have a look at the insert again just about here and have a look and
this to have the now column hack as well as policy values hard to do is come back there and add now
as the second argument and that should fix it up.
Right.
So tally can obviously say now that the insert method is taking three arguments the name of the table
to insert into context in this case.
We've also got this now column hack and also that and then the values that we're actually adding are
wanting added to the table to that particular table.
Now I'm going to talk about the number column hack argument.
A bit later.
For now that I see you can say I'm just using or passing.
Now for that.
Now the values are provided in something called a content values object.
And really all that is is just a wrapper class around a hash map which lets it store a set of key value
pairs and you can see overstand where assigning the key value pairs alone 29 3:31 basically got one
for each field in that table each column in that table.
Basically the case of the column names and the type which you probably figured out with it passing the
table type values to that insert method.
Now also I saw into the valley return by insert a lot 34 to a variable called generated ID so that we
can look at and check that it's what we expected it to be.
Now you may not come across apply before talking about the card up here.
20.
It's a Cartland extension function that takes a function block and executes it with an object it's called
on as its receiver.
So effectively that means that the function block runs just as if it was a function of the class the
content values class.
In this case so apply returns the object it was code on which is extremely useful because he were responding
that to the values variable which means that the values get the new content vallies object.
Now the equivalent code we could have done was going to post.
And just to give you an alternative
precedent except formatting.
We could have done it that way and I can say that's a similar way of doing it but to block the way that
apply returns the object that it was called and I think it makes for better looking code.
But the that the example that I pasted in here would be how you would write it in in Java or non idiomatic.
It's huge.
It's more usual to use apply when doing things like this.
Right so the code that we've written that should create a database and the context table and insert
some data into it before we run this and check it.
Let's add some logging.
We're going to start with a usual tech constant.
Let's go up into that product constant flle tag because it's main activity.
Obviously that should have been above the class let me put that in the right place.
Cuyp is a consummate and let's add a bit of logging just to make sure it's working.
I'm going to come down here and just before the exec I'm going to put logged up the parentheses tech
come up and double quotes we're going to put on Create call on siecle is ta'ala secret.
You take a copy of that line.
So that's Firaaq creation table down here from the sequel for the insert.
We're going to do the same thing for the exact exact is called On create a sequence call again that's
our second line.
And for the third one after the Vau generated Ardalan it's come down to the end of that I'm going to
do some logging there we're going to change that a little bit.
We're going to look at it with a dollar generated ID at this point.
Now we should be able to run the app and see the entries in the look at let's actually run this now.
So what I'm going to do is select an emulator that have to find.
That's not a Google Play emulator.
And the reason that is that we're going to be using IDB to connect to the device and end the database
later so I'll go on the Rabboni credit he codexes for this IPO 26 Texas.
And that tells me right away that it's not a Google Play and that's because the Google Play emulator
doesn't give you the ability to get read access.
I'm going to select that one.
OK let's give them a moment to stop
the comics that we think about we really want to see the logs.
Let's have a look at and log.
We've got a lot of stuff here so what we can do are just to make it a bit easier to see what we've done
here.
We can remove some unnecessary noise from the theater party or torturing on minor activities.
Let's say that forward slash main activity you can say to me that we can see really much more clearly
what's actually happened here with that the slash part of why the force that you might still get an
interesting log entries from the system that's expected that we have a look at the log entries.
The new ID for that second row is number two which we would have expected.
All right so that's execute sequence statements from our cutline card.
We use the the exec sequel method of the sequel like database class to execute Siku statements.
We've also got insert update into late methods we can use as well.
And these are more appropriate when inserting or updating data in the database.
Now by the way that the exact sequence will work for insert update and delete statements but you will
see later why it can be useful to get an idea that was generated or a count of the number of rows affected.
In the case of the update and delete methods or about to finish the video here.
The next step is to write some code to retrieve the data and we'll work on that in the next few.