In the previous videos we write a very simple app that created a database that inserted some data into
a Contacts table.
In this video I'm going to show you a little bit about the Android file system.
This can be useful so that we can check where that database file is.
That will open it and have a look at the data in there.
So Android is built on Linux Android and Linux uses for its caches rather than backslashes in parts.
Folland directory names are case sensitive.
So in other words size data is not the same as for such data or with a capital date that went toward
creates a new user account for each app to keep each app secure that data is stored under the package
name in for its fresh data for its last data and Android emulators are rooted.
And I'll talk more about roots and shortly the Android operating system is based on Linux.
That's right.
Essentially an Android device is really a Linux system.
So if you've already been using Linux or used to Linux then you'll be you're already very familiar with
the file system and the basic commands we can look at 0 6 on a Mac OS side shares a lot in common with
Linux as both operating systems evolved from Unix.
You know if you're used to Windows on the other hand remember that Linux users slash character in file
past the forward slash rather than the backslash used by Windows.
And again as I mentioned Android installs are Mumsie CHEP under a separate user account and it creates
a new account for every app that's installed by the folk.
Linux doesn't allow users to access each other's data.
So this results in a great deal of security.
One app can access the data belonging to another app and that includes outside database.
Now there are ways to share data and we will be looking at that later in the section.
Now that data is stored in a sub directory inside fortnights type the forest has data and each app has
its own directory in there.
The directory name is just the package name and we'll look at that shortly.
Now finally some of the emulators are rooted and what that means is it doesn't mean that they're not
working means that you've got root access or administrator access.
If you prefer the windows Tib's they can access everything on the device but unless you've routed you
physical fire in much of what we're about to do here won't work on a physical Android device.
And the other thing to note is that it won't work on the Google Play emulators I mentioned way back
in Section 3 that the Google Play emulators don't allow root access.
You can either have the ability to install apps from the place or with regulators or you can have read
access to the emulator.
You can have both at least not at the time of recording this video anyway.
So what that means is that it's important not to use a Google Play emulator if you want to examine your
apps database on the emulator navigational API.
I mean it is a fine.
Make sure you choose an image that doesn't have an entry in the placed or column in the DVD manager.
And what I mean by that is the city manager up and it can say hey we've got a nexus 5 x IPO or 26 and
we can update that in a few videos Tom.
But there's no place to walk on.
So that's an example of a device that isn't rooted.
So in other words we wouldn't be able to access the database.
This one down here and actually made it clear that it has got real access nothing that it hasn't got
the Google Play on there.
And you can see over here it says Google IPO is where I grew up.
We've got full access to that read access to that.
And in fact that's the I mean I've got running at the moment.
And you can see up here the difference there is it's cooking.
So bottom line here is see want just follow along.
In this video you get access to the database from the command line.
You need to make sure you're not running an emulator that has been set up with Google Play.
OK.
So I'm back in the studio with the sequel project loaded and I'm stunned at the idea that I was testing
and I can say I behave like Tebb I've been taught there's a C code that tests running.
So what I'll do is let's run it one more time just to make sure we're all on the same page and it's
still working life in the lockout and just a shadow on the screen and you can say we've got it right.
There are two records coming back and we've now got it showing with the record ideas.
Number two as well as already too.
And by the way when you run an app on your emulator Android studio installs it just like any that you
download and you're fired.
So what we're about to say applies to all Android apps.
We're going to open the terminal window cause this one first.
The can't open the terminal window.
Then by clicking on Terminal One of them to put it into flighting mode to of maybe this up here out
of the way it resized a little bit so that won't affect the subtopics if you happen to be running that
can say that you've got a fair bit of flexibility in how you organize these pains when you're working
with them outside the command line to check that there's a device available we use the command IDB devices.
How deep a device is center and you can say it's his list of devices attached so that command returns
a list of devices attached.
He can say he had an and emulator connected nothing that nebuliser just a piece.
Just as a physical device.
As far as the IDB commands are concerned now because of adding up to one device connected I can top
ITP show and we get a prompt on the device now.
So I've gone into the I mean lighter like to know what Linux the command to show a directory listing
is LS which is the equivalent of D.O.A. our windows.
It give us a bit more information on these problems but them two Ls spice more l lower case there's
a list of favs.
This is on the actual image right now.
So even though we're effectively running with root access of the emulator we still don't have permission
to the files in the root directory.
We set up full access to everything and we're not saying permission denied area but basically there'll
be some Fahrzeug it won't be able to access until we give ourselves that full access.
Now some nebulizers such as the Marcus of one will give you more permissions so you might not get a
pension or permission denied message that we never gave or changes things a bit.
So you might not say it with me.
It is the PC at the bottom line is I haven't got that permission denied.
But it's not a problem because on an emulator what we can do is request super user access.
So I'm going to do that.
Topis you disappears Rexus and Donelly spice for elegant and it's very unlikely that you'd be able to
use the command on a physical device even if you've routed the device still to get the program that
actually runs the su command onto itself.
So now that we can see the following directory names to what we're interested in is the directory called
data analytics a D in the first position of that sequence of characters which is to have a look at that.
Do you ever hear this first sequence of characters that indicate that it's a directory.
If there's an L there that means we're looking at a symlink.
Sort of like a shortcut to another directory.
So lucky exit etc for example.
Notice that that's got an L and it's actually redirected to slash system slushed.
Easy as you can see I have the right hand side.
So basically ATC here.
The authorities say is a shortcut to the forward or forward slash system for ATC.
Now we don't really interested in most of the files and directories.
So let's have a look into that data directory.
I'm going to hop CD spice data and I'm going to help spice models though about the way I noticed on
the bottom that the prompt is changing to show the current directory so we can see now that we've changed
to the data the reference is the prompt and once again most of the stuff isn't relevant to what we're
doing at the moment.
But you can see how he can use change directory command say to change into different directories.
So let's change into that data directory again.
So this will effectively be the data slash data directory.
And on top say they spice d'Artois again and that is now that the prompters Shankar's data slush data.
So again the prompts changing to reflect the directory we're County in.
And that's very useful as a check so that is something in the wrong directory don't LS Spice models
that they know.
So now that we're in data data and now things are starting to get more interesting we can see the storage
directories now for all the apps listed on stold Rather on this emulator.
Now there's quite a few that came with the emulator and we can also see some of the eps that I tested
if we scroll up.
So I'm going to scroll up and have a look there.
You keep scrolling up and notice that we've got the Academy Donlin programming ones with a calculator
flicker.
The sequel I test our current app and it was our top 10 downloaded showing there as well.
But basically every app that installed it's got its own folder for databases.
So at this point we were interested in a sequel like this step.
So referring back to Judge Trudy I briefly scrolling up notice that you probably recall that that page
is academy LOONE sequel light test.
So therefore we need to use that for what we need to go into that directory and see what's in there.
So I'm going to say the spice now could top Academy taught in programming sequel at Test don't have
anything to do is topping the first few letters.
ISCI in this case impis tap.
And that gives me a list of all the directories that match what I've talked inside files are Calamy
don't let me dot what I can do now is just Toppan s press time again.
Or do you get the full path I into there.
Now you can say it by the prompt in academy and in programming but sequela test LS Spice models elegant.
Now at this point we're really interested in the databases directory.
So it's changed into that directory and have a look at our database Saidy spice and top tier again for
and spice Fonzo.
And finally you've got to this place now where our database resides and you probably remember that fault
line that we chose seek a lot of test dash 1 TB.
It's basically we've found a database.
Now noticed that in addition to the database file there's a fall with the site name and Desch Journal
on the end.
Sometimes it's usually there but it may not be there in your case this Deskjet will follow the second
one here.
That's a transaction log.
That's sequela uses to handle database transactions.
So it's used if something goes wrong.
And an update can't be completed for any reason.
So using the transaction log siecle lot can undo all the changes and put the database back into the
site.
It was then if all goes well it uses the journal file to commit the transaction.
So at this point anyway we found out about as fall as we can say that I'm looking at the prompt that's
in the data slash data Sledge's Academy taught learn programming a lot.
Test slash databases directory.
So once you know your project's package name you can find the database easily.
It'll always be in the same path.
It's just the package name pop that varies.
Right now we get to this stage because I open the database and check that it's as we expect it will
be.
We're going to talk talk about a lot.
Three spice and then a lot with the same ups and then on the top bar select the DeBerry which is selected
for us by the Foxtons presenter.
Now when I press tab I mean going into the database so I could have also I just talked in the whole
file line but our top secret a lot.
Q On press tab and we matched part of the name enough for it to open up any wife right so that gives
us the familiar sequel up prompt that we've used earlier in this section of the course and we can use
all the commands that we've seen in those early videos in this section.
So first let's check the structure of our database schema.
Now that's interesting.
We've got the context table that we expected.
But there's another table in there called Android underscore meta data.
Now that type was created automatically by the sequel like database class and it's used for localization.
Till now searching for words that contain accented characters for example it contains a single field
code locale with a locale to be used.
But we don't normally have to worry about that typo because Android creates it for us.
So we're going to ignore that table.
Instead we're going to have a look at our context data.
We're going to top select spy stuff from spy stuff from in context then add a semicolon and then there's
two records.
So let's add another one here to check this is are working properly.
And Bob the wife unable to run an emulator on your system and you're using a physical device instead.
Don't worry about not being able to perform this next step.
Your database will have one less row than mine but you can always modify the have to add the extra row
if you want.
So what I want to do is add a new record.
You see the sequel like command line interface and then we should be able to see it when we get back
into our app.
I'm going to insert spice into Spice contex spice Thalys parentheses.
I going the top three Khama spice and single quite pop single quite common five six seven eight comma
and a single quite Bob at his home.
How come single quite wrought parentheses in a semi-colon Precentor and nowhere put use is a good sign
that to come on top is worked we can confirm that potong select spice style spice from spice contex
semicolon and now we've got an extra requit showing that it's very good to go.
And by the way you used to recalling previous commands by pressing the apere K..
I'll try that.
Now this doesn't work in sequence not from the command line in the Unix shell on the emulators and that's
fair enough because there's not much point Google including all the bells and whistles.
When we don't spend much time using the shelves just to whites to the device storage.
So you just you have to top the commands and it's time to get them to work.
All right so let's swing back to androids Judaea now that we've added that record to the database more
specifically back to our code.
Now we've got a problem here at the moment a slight problem if we run the epic in it's going to drop
the table.
And what added data that would just add to that new record.
So what I'm going to do is coming out to this code and basically going to commit to the card all the
way all the way after the Vout database definitional 1:23 all right down to the query.
Right down here.
Write down to them it's going to come out
and i'm are going to kind of this last long down here because obviously now that it isn't going to work
given that we've already commented that the other card that created the generated ID variable now that
I've done that we should be able to run our application and see those entries from the database.
And I really liked it when I read the blog as well.
You get a moment to stop and this time you can say that word successfully.
And we are successfully saying three entries there but one two three.
The third one was obviously Bob was the entry that we just added from the sequel three command line
on our emulator.
All right so that's a basic introduction to the Android file system and accessing the sequel like database
that your Android app creates on an emulator.
It's very useful to be able to do that so that you can check the data that your apps writing to the
database being able to check what's been written to the database can make debugging a lot easier.
Now this Hepton put very much in the database and Desam said it's certainly not the way you should write
a database app.
But if you're trying to debug a database app then this technique is very useful.
Just before I finish what we're going to do is a close look at when we got back to our terminal and
one exit out of there is going to top down exit to exit circle at 3 going to exit exits from simple
user mode exit again which exits from the show.
The next one more time which closes the terminal pain in a studio.
All right so in the next few years we're going to start to see how to do this all properly using a content
provider for working with databases in Android apps.
See you in the next video.