In the previous video we created the layouts to display the contact records using Ellis view.
Now it's time to write the code to retrieve the contact details.
Now before we get into the coding there's been a change in the way the private access modifier works
in cotland when used on a top level object.
It used to mean package private.
So that meant that any private constants we declared would be visible throughout the package.
Now that would obviously cause problems with dialog tags because much to the column falls we've created
or create have a tag but that's no longer the case.
And when we're not private is used for a top level object it means private within the fall into sin.
But just to demonstrate what I made I'm going to create the usual tax train that we're using so I've
had throughout the course now of course in the yeah within the class with little private felle taking
up a case equals type of quites mine activity that results in a warning from Major.
Because the name tag doesn't conform to the naming conventions.
What's come over here.
You can see you've got two warnings the first one is if the tag is being used will rectify shortly the
second and you can see there not matching a particular following at the convention or the regular expression
says a change in the way that cotland treats profit for toplevel objects means that we can move our
tag outside the class and make it a contest as to that
real progress we need to make it at a cost now.
When you say you have a hover over the warning we've got the warning about the property tax not being
used at this point in our application it's basically this is now exactly what we want.
Tag is no private to this fall and it won't conflict with any private tag Constance in other files.
Right so I'm with the code.
So we're going to put the code to access the contacts inside the on click method of the final action
button that is Codys I'm going to delete that code first.
Can add some logging I looked the indices.
Let me have Tom Toppin did I come up quite small just put tough happened on click call and starts.
OK.
So there's a log now going to stop cheating kind of replace some code with a declaration of a string
array.
After this logging method so going to be about projection equals the array of parentheses.
And that's going to be contex contract start contacts start to supply and his call name analytical problem.
In closing parentheses.
Now that's cheating because I already knew which column stores the context name but how would I found
this out if I didn't already know that no say had to call up the documentation so that line before.
So I'll go ahead and do that by selecting the contacts in contact contract that contacts those part.
He then opened the door to the quick documentation.
So that's useful if you scroll down and have a bit of a look and say in the columns you eventually get
to display the name on a school prom or the display name for the contact but that only works if you
already have the object name on the screen to click on unfortunately.
You know if you want to find the documentation for something like accessing context data you best friend
is probably the Google search engine.
So think of the key things about what you're trying to do.
Then google these words that's going to put up a browser.
So this case probably would be appropriate to something along the lines of Android contacts content
providers.
So they're looking for the content provider for the Android contex Nick.
Obviously you could phrase that in a number of different ways and it lets you manage to come up with
something really obscure You should probably get some useful results.
You say in my case it's return some interesting looking links.
They all think you can see here to develop a dot Android dot com so they are the official source of
documentation from Google for Android development.
So I'm going to go to this first copy the one that links to content provider and the topics it it's
definitely worth getting into the habit of checking out the Google documentation type provide reference
docs which can be a bit Troyan hard to read as well as guides and trendy docs that are more tutorial
style in nature.
This one's a god document and that will show you more on how to access to context database for the content
provider.
Now by the way we're going to be looking at a lot of this stuff covered here in our next app.
Things like retrieving a single row for example but do take advantage of the Google documentation to
learn more about how Android works in general.
Right.
I'm certainly not going to read all of this scrolling down a bit so we can see this diagram here showing
how the contact details are organized in the description below and you can see that you've got contacts
contract contacts and it mentions here that it's a row or rows representing different people based on
the aggregations for contact rows for that purpose I'd probably say adios.
I going to click on that link now
that brings up the contact contract.
Talk contex a class here.
You can say there's obviously a lot of information on the class but all we're really after here at the
moment in the column is we can use it if we scroll down a little bit.
You say we do get a list of the various columns and there's our trusty display and called name and the
scope problem Me field column 9 because not so much the names are what's really to be technically correct
it's the constants that we should use when referring to the columns column names in the database aren't
really of interest when using a content provider.
In fact when you use a content provider you're not interested in anything about the database.
Now we know that Android users sequel lot to store the contact details.
But Google might decide to change that in the future as long were used to constants defined in this
class.
It won't matter if they use a completely different database with totally different names for the fields.
If I do that they'll update this class.
And because of that I is constant as a static KAC holograms being the same everything.
We'll continue that code will continue to work.
So this fourth entry in the time always display underscore name on a SQL primary and that sounds like
the cube we want right so back to a hard name and we now know where that display name Pommery came from.
Now this is where it gets fun.
If dealing with multiple levels of abstraction is your idea of fun.
So what I'm going to do is talk to comedian and explain what's going on.
So after that valproate bijection lawn and reval spice cursus equals.
Just be content with all the dot queery in print parentheses is going to be contact's contract dot contex
dot content on Wisco you're right.
He he's not going to come on the move to the next line.
We're going to a projection Halma there was no clamor no comma.
Then we're going to end up with contact's contract dot com tax dot net We get into and despite the scorn
I will select just plain call name on school property then we'll just end this for the entry looked
like a parentheses take home a couple of quotes.
If I be on clicking
so we get a content resolver in case you're wondering how this was accessed we get that from the activity
using the Get content resolver method but because this is Katlin we can use the property directly instead
of going through the counter.
So that's how I've been able to use this content resolver here.
So the content result was queery function returns a cursor containing the data we want.
Let's start by looking at those parameters we passed to the query function.
Know we've got something we can query for data.
The content resolver that returns a cursor.
The parameters were passing to the query method of first of the year.
That's this first entry here now.
So this somehow identifies the data source that we want to get data from.
This could be a database and a table for example but this code doesn't need to know where the data is
coming from at the moment.
We don't care about that either.
Now we'll find out soon enough but for now we're just kind of accept that this year-I identifies the
source of our data.
Next we've got projection.
This is just a string array holding the names of the columns that we want to retrieve.
Now we're just asking for the display name primary or display.
I was going to school probably call them here but we could put more fields into the rife with more.
Next you've got selection that's a string containing a filter to determine which rows are returned and
pick if this has the where clause in a sequel statement.
In fact that's exactly what it is without the key word when and in this scenario because we're passing.
No.
We could all rise returned selection items as the next one.
This is an array of values that will be used to replace placeholders in the selection string.
So there are a number of advantages to using the Selection parameter to specify the values we want and
we will look at size.
But basically your selection moppy name equals questionmark and the selection Ogg's could contain a
single variable.
The query would then use the filter the where clause.
If you like name equals Bob because we're not doing any filtering again we're just parsing now.
For this as well.
The last entry is the sort order.
This is just a string containing the names of the fields you want the data sorted by.
So it's just sequel.
Order by clause without the actual keywords siecle K was autobio content resolving with an executed
query against its data source and give us back Kisa.
We can then use the cursor just like we did earlier.
We'll just use a loop to loop through all the rows in the cursor and display the contact names so that
it's easy.
But what's the content resolver all about.
Well I said that there were several levels of redirection here and we'll look at that in the next video.