All right.
So we're now ready to run the app again to see how it behaves.
We're going to do that and talk about what's wrong with the code.
So we need to say firstly have the app behaves from scratch.
So I'm going to get back to me later and I'm going to delete this app so I was starting from a clean
slate.
And when I installed that
and I'll run it again.
And open a locket so that we can see what's going on.
So the first test that we want to do here is to see how it behaves when we deny access and it's going
to be the size of a little bit more so I can say a bit more than look
what I said the first test is going to be to see how it behaves when you deny access.
So I'm going to click on tonight and now when I click on the FAP it should display a snack bar and the
link there to grant access which it is.
And that should continue to appear whenever we click the FAP.
So if I spot that on screen the snack bar click it again comes back again which is good which is the
expected behavior.
And then the look that you can see I'm doing that the Fab's on click method starting and ending.
All right so let's see now what happens when the grant access link is clicked.
So the LOLcat Now you can see has the on click method starting again this time a call to request permissions
and then the on click method ending.
And as a result we've got the Android door locked asking for permission to access the contacts want
to come out of the human click on denie can we say permission refused either here in the log.
We now request permissions result.
Callback is code.
So let's do that again.
But this time I click on grant access I'm going to check the don't ask again check box and click on
tonight.
Now effectively what I've done is told and tried not to ask again.
So in terms of our code the to should show request permission or rationale should now return false.
So in other words this bit of codein he should never be executed.
So let's actually check that I going to click on the fabric button again come from Texas and you can
see what's happened in this case.
That card was executed and the settings for the application is now showing on the screen again so that
it's working well and looking up to look at it.
And here is what you can say that you're showing on the screen the package academy to learn programming
to our content provider example so that you are all together with the action on the school application
on the school.
Details on the school setting family that were used in seduction that sits well lets rather Android
open the settings for this app rather than just going into the mind settings screen.
And that is tiny here also in the alog that the snack bars on click method has finished.
So they can say the snack bar on click and entry after the launching of the settings and you'll see
why that's important in the moment.
Back in my lap I'm going to click on permissions and then I'm going to grant access to our contacts
are turning that on what's that and that tapping back a few times to take us back to our app which is
done here now but not a set up when doing that.
Nothing's appeared over here in the log.
The app now has the permission it needs but it doesn't know that it has got that permission.
So I could say basically at this point when I've tapped the fabric in the snack bar still appearing
instead of a contact details and if I quit the app closes down and run it again.
And click on a button.
It is actually working correctly and you can say in fact that permission is granted now showing in our
location.
But really that's not the best user experience requiring the user to shut down the app and started up
again in order to proceed.
So let's actually have a look at the code to see what's going wrong here.
So the actual problem is caused by the test in the Fab's unclick method.
This is the card here.
Basically the line 46.
So if you used read granted here to still whether we have access or not but we haven't updated it after
going into the settings.
So consequently it actually filed there had returned false and we were able to get access to our contacts
until we closed down the up and started it again.
Now what kind of site never store state in a variable like we've done here.
But what I will say is I think long and hard before doing so.
Sometimes it can be necessary but generally it's much harder to check the site when you need it rather
than storing it in a field as we've done here.
And the problem we've got here is that we check to see if we had access in the uncreate method and set
rate granted to True or false to reflect the state of our access.
But dead in the request permission was so Kolpak method.
We also set it to true squint and have a look at that.
This one he got starting on law 91.
So he also said that if access is granted after calling request permissions so that means that the would
work after tapping allowed in the.
But our code that launches the app settings has no way of knowing whether the user granted access or
not.
Now of course we know that they went into the settings because we sent them there.
But we've got no control over what they did when they got into the settings.
So it's very tempting to store things like whether you have a particular permission and it's also very
common.
But once you start doing that you'll find yourself adding more code to keep the variable up to digest
changes we saw earlier that the snack bars on click method ends where the user is still in the settings.
So we don't really have a convenient way to check the permissions again.
So good rule is if you want to know the state of your environment then chicken each time you need to
know rather than storing that state in a field.
So don't store the stype because you'll end up struggling to keep your stored value up to date.
Or what's ahead.
Got about fixing that.
Well let's work on that in the next video.