in this section we're going to create an
app that stores data in a sequel light
database know the apps going to be a
task timer that we can use to record how
long to spend on different tasks it's
useful if you have to complete
timesheets for billing customers for
your work for example and it introduces
some very important techniques for
Android programming including all the
operations you'll need to perform on a
database the databases will have
separate tables to store the tasks that
we'll be timing and the timings
themselves so that you'll be seeing how
to add data to a database when tables
are joined now more importantly perhaps
you'll also see how to delete associated
records in a joined table in this case
if you delete a task then all the
timings associated with that task will
also need to be deleted of course it's
good practice to warn users that this
will happen and the app will also use
dialogues to warn the user and allow
them to cancel the operation although
the focus of Android apps tends to be
phones it's well worth considering
tablet users when producing your apps in
this app editing a task record on a
phone will show a different screen
because there just isn't enough room on
a phone's display but on a tablet users
will be able to win up the task details
alongside the list of tasks
now we achieve that by using fragments
and we'll also be seeing how to
implement those fragments
you know apps now another thing that
this app will need to do is record and
display dates and we'll be using the
Java calendar classes to do that now it
may seem like an easy thing to do but
you have to be really very careful when
dealing with time users can download
your app from almost anywhere in the
world and it's very easy to mess up when
dealing with different time zones so I'm
going to be looking at how to safely
deal with time across the world in your
apps we'll also see another way to
respond to events from a recycle of you
knew our list of tasks will include
buttons to edit or delete the tasks and
will need to respond to taps on the task
itself to start and stop timing so let's
have a look at the app running on an
emulator so
first thing we do is provide the user
with basic information on how to use the
app when they first run them so this
screen will show a list of tasks that
the users set up but until they create
some tasks the display would be empty
and we've taken advantage of all that
space to give them some basic
instructions so tapping on the plus icon
up here in the toolbar allows new
details to be entered
now we've seen edit text hints before
and they were very useful way of letting
the user know when they should answer on
what they should enter into each field
and they cancel that and go back home
and then select abandoned changes you'll
rotate the phone into landscape now I'm
going to tap on the plus sign in the
toolbar again now the apps using
fragments here and you can take
advantage of the extra screen width to
perform the editing on the right-hand
side of the screen
all right so I'm going to into some
details here now I'm going to top task
timer for the name click on next
I'm gonna top Android database app for
the description and notice when I
started typing that the android keyboard
took over and in landscape each field is
presented for editing and androids also
adding this next button to move on to
the next field so I'm going to add to
zero here for sort order and that's so
this app should appear at the start of
this list and then I'm going to click on
done now when I click on save over here
the data is saved to the database and
we've now got one task in our list so
let's add another task now in landscape
mode and then we'll swing over to
portrait for the one after that so this
is my Java course entry so I'm going to
type in Java course and click on next
description I'm going to leave blank and
that's because the task name says enough
so next and for sort order I'm going to
enter 10 number 10 click on done and
they click on save now the Java course
task is sorting below the task timer
task and that's because Taft's time i
have a sort order of zero right so I
switch back to portrait of
we're going to tap on the plus icon in
the toolbar to enter one more task now
because the screen isn't wide enough to
show the list and allowed data entry the
fragments displayed by itself here in
portrait mode using fragments lets us
write apps that automatically adapt to
extra screen space to give the user a
better experience rights or the name for
this is our task it's going to be
cycling now it's good to take a break
from the computer now and then so I'm
going to record how much time I spend in
cycling but that is a slightly vague
name so I'm going to make the
description ride my bicycle in day in
portrait mode there's enough space to
display the end of text and the keyboard
as you can see so Android doesn't have
to present their fields one by one now
the data is not saved which means it'll
be lost if we use the home or back
buttons to return to the previous screen
so I click on that back so what I'll do
is come up here and just fix that typo
there so what we come back so to prevent
the loss of data we're showing a dialog
here so that the user knows they're
about to lose data if they continue in
my case I want to save those changes so
we're going to choose continue editing
so I'm going to leave the sort or a
blank and it should default to zero that
means that this task will sort to the
top of the list and if two tasks have
the same sort order then they'll appear
alphabetically so when I click on save
we can see that cycling is at the top in
order to start timeing a task we just
long tap it so I'm going to do that now
the heading change is to show which task
is currently being timed now if we were
billing a customer for this task or any
of the tasks we probably wouldn't be
interested in charging for every second
so I'll stop timing that now and if you
go into settings and we've got options
here to ignore timings for tasks that
last less than a certain amount of time
now you've probably seen sliders like
this before but what's not obvious is
just how much control you can provide by
using them in most applications dragging
the slider would increase some value in
a linear fashion but that wouldn't
really make a lot of sense
if you wanted to ignore timings less
than five minutes that's 300 seconds and
you'd have to drag the slider a long way
to get that high but the slide is a
little bit different though I'm just
going to tap to it now
nobody is my keyboard just to show you
the increments so as we start off you
can see the increments of five seconds
and that is true until we get to 55
seconds after that though if I do
another one notice how to now jump to
one minute then it counts in 5-minute
increments until it gets to 15 minutes
then the next time it goes to 30 minutes
then to 45 minutes and then it jumps to
one hour then the next minute convinced
to two hours so you can see that we can
provide a lot of flexibility without
having to clutter the screen up with all
sorts of different sliders and we'll be
seeing how to create a slider like this
in this app as well so move that slider
back to zero now otherwise we have to
wait a long time to get any real timing
data to display in the reports that
we're about to look at now this settings
menu also lets us choose which day a
week starts on some companies start on a
Sunday when they're doing accounting
other start on a Monday so tapping up
the tapping the day here brings up by
this list of days which is a dialog
where you can choose the day of the week
and it's probably a bit pointless
including the other weekdays in this app
but this is a good example of how to
choose one of a range of options and for
that reason all the weekdays are
included so I'm going to make my weekday
start on a Monday alright so we click on
back now to go back to our list of tasks
alright so let's start another timing
for my Java course you can see that's
showing on the screen there now I could
just long tap that again just top it but
if I want to actually switch over to
another task I could long tap that task
and it ends the timing for the Java
course and starts the timing for the but
the year cycling all right so that's
enough sorry I'm going to long tap that
to stop it it's time to get back to work
so the second icon in the toolbar up
here that's used to display reports of
how long we spent on each task
so this durations reports I'll open it
now there's got two different layouts
for portrait and landscape
portrait mode we can see the task name
the date and how long was spent on each
task in other words the duration but
whenever I take the device back into
landscaping in there now we also get the
description showing as well now you can
sort the list by clicking on the column
headings we can see the timers in task
order or by clicking on the description
column here description heading rather
you can see that it's now sorted by
description we can also display four
weeks or just single days but with only
two timing records that's not easy to
demonstrate this is a good time though
to show a bug in the program though now
at the moment we're viewing a full
week's data there's only data for today
and because I've only just done some
timing the button on the toolbar up here
shows a one to indicate that it'll
switch to just showing a single day so
when I tap that it changes to a seven as
you can see in the screen there now to
indicate that tapping it again would
display a full week but what's actually
happened to the data it was there in the
week view and should be appearing for
today well it's very easy to get things
messed up when you're dealing with dates
and times across the world I can see the
timings that were there by using the
calendar icon or clicking on that and
choosing the previous day using
yesterday in my case it's the 12th click
on OK and the entries actually appear
again and there's the timing data back
now I selected yesterday in the calendar
but the date column over here is still
showing today's date so the reason for
that is that I'm recording this in
Australia which is currently nine and a
half hours ahead of Greenwich Mean Time
GMT because I'm recording this early in
the morning it's still yesterday
effectively at Greenwich unless you
specify otherwise times are in GMT
Greenwich Mean Time that's going to have
serious implications for most parts of
the world including places like the UK
and Portugal that use GMT in summer both
those places change their clock to
summer time so we've got an app here
that works sometimes in some parts of
the world but won't work all the time
anywhere well that's not quite true
it'll work all the time in Casablanca in
the Azores where they stay on Jim
all year round but overall that's not
good and you'll get a chance to fix this
towards the end of the section and yes I
did say you but don't worry though we'll
be covering the problem and solution
before the challenge alright so I'm
going to go back to the main tasks
screen now and the menu up here has also
got a generate option that we can use to
generate test data so I'm going to click
on that and it'll make our report a bit
more interesting and you can see that
it's completed already depending on the
speed of your computer it may take a
while this menu option won't appear
though in the release version of the app
there's some code that checks to see if
we're running in debug mode which you
are when you're running directly from
Android studio as I am that makes this
option visible the code though hasn't
got any frills it's really only there to
generate data for use while we're
testing so that we don't have to wait
while we create hundreds of timings and
if we were going to do something like
this for users then you should run it as
a background thread because in my case
even though it was relatively fast the
emulator appeared to hang you may find
that the displays called blank for
example on earlier versions of Android
the point is that the app was very
definitely blocking the user interface
which is not a good thing so this
generate data option generates between
100 and 500 random timing records for
each of the tasks that exists in the
database so it will take a little while
but it's much quicker than us having to
create the data ourselves and actually
it's a bit slower than it should be
because the method that generates the
random data also logs what's doing in
the logcat
so although the emulator screen looked
like there was nothing happening if I
quickly bring up in Android studio you
can see that there's quite a few min
trees there showing details about the
actual wah timings that were actually
generated all right so I'm gonna close
it down here back to our emulator
alright so now that that's finished
we're going to go back to our reports
again by clicking on the icon now the
report is sorted by name then date but
we can group all the cycling tasks
together by clicking on the task name
heading look so now the first button on
the toolbar that's a switch between
displaying a whole week or just the
current day now at the moment it's
showing a whole week's worth of data by
clicking on the one button
that's what's there just showing tonight
and if you're doing this in America
within five to eight hours at midnight
you'll be seeing tomorrow's timings and
that's because the USA is behind GMT and
as we saw earlier that the Year button
icon also changes to reflect the fact
that clicking it again will show a week
and again they've got that same
situation there with the bug they talked
about if the GMT bug so I have to go
back and click on the previous day to
actually get more data to display on the
screen all right now we have seen that
calendar so I click that calendar again
there now this time we're going to go
back about a month now so I'm gonna go
back to my chooses a May the 16th click
on OK there and if I cross here now and
click on the icon the 7 button now the
app should work out which seven days
will be displayed based on the data I
just chose and which day we've set for
the first day of the week in the
settings and that's easy to see there
now if I click the date heading first
season sort that you can see you've got
entries from the 14th 16th 17th and 19th
of May and just to confirm if we go back
to click on the calendar that is correct
because I chose Monday as my start of
the week and that's the 14th and we can
see Sunday was a 13th fair and we've got
no entries showing for the 13th I cancel
out of that
so basically same data here from the
14th through to the 19th which is
correct and that's obviously assuming
there's data for each day of course and
if we didn't have that bug that I've
talked about now the version of the app
is currently displaying dates in the
American format month day year that can
be confusing for people in other
countries so we'll also be seeing how we
can display the dates in the users
preferred format based on their country
all right so finally now there's an
option to delete old data so we get to
choose a date and everything before that
date will be deleted so I'm going to
choose the 16th year so I'm going to
click on the menu option select it
delete old timings I'm going to choose
the 16th click on OK
asks us for confirmation so we got a
prompt here making sure that we really
do want to delete all that data and if I
cancel it the data will still show but
if I go back to the option select delete
old timings select the 16th of May click
on OK click on OK again and you can see
now that the data prior to the date that
I've selected has now been deleted well
that's the theory at least it was
actually a bug in the program but fixing
that is also going to be challenged
towards the end of the section all right
so we'll go back to Nell to our main
list again so there's two buttons we can
use to editor task details and delete
the tasks so when I click the button the
delete button over here the trash icon
next to the Java course there's a
dialogue option that pops up here
warning that the timers will also be
deleted so our timings data is stored in
a separate table that links to the tasks
table and there's no point keeping all
the timings around if you no longer know
which task it relates to so the database
has been set up with a trigger when a
task has deleted all the timings records
with the same task ID are automatically
deleted for us and we'll be seeing how
to do that as we write the up as well so
I'm going to click on delete here now
which deletes that and now if we go back
to our reports we should see any other
entries relating to the Java tasks
because it's been deleted back a
previous week and again there's nothing
related to what Java are actually
showing them in the list anymore alright
so go back to the main task list again
now the up source I've got an about
dialog in the menu in the main screen so
I'll click on the button there so an
about screen is a good place to provide
additional information about the app and
we'll see how to include clickable links
in our screens so here I can click on
the link here to launch the Android
browser I can choose one I need to go
through the initial defaults and then it
will then load that web page
automatically and when I close the
browser notice that we get back to our
application again and we'll be seeing
how to do that as well now I can't demos
the email link we just go back again and
have a look there's also an email link
there I can't demonstrate that because I
don't have the email setup on this our
Android emulator but on a physical
device tapping the email address will
launch your email program with the to
address already filled in ready for you
to type an email so our previous
dialogues had ok and cancel buttons but
this one's just got an OK button so I
can click on that to close that down so
that's our app it's basic functionality
may be quite simple but we're going to
be learning a lot of useful techniques
when we write this app and we'll start
by looking at the underlying database
which we'll do in the next video