Welcome to Python for data structures algorithms interviews I'm Jose Portsea and I've taught thousands
of students are new to me about Python programming and data science and now I've created a course to
help students of the interview process.
This course will help you ace the type of coding interviews done at the top technology companies.
So what do you get off this course.
This is a three in one course it includes lectures on data structures and algorithms.
It's a cover computer science theory plus coding questions asked in real interviews and answers to them
as well as non-technical interview preparation such as Resume reviews and doing well and in person interviews
.
This course is packed with tons of content.
You'll get lifetime access to over 200 lectures for every lecture consist of a video with clear explanation
of a topic along with a notebook of written code and explanations for reference so you can learn in
whatever way works best for you.
We cover everything you need to know to interview overall.
The course consists of non-technical interview preparation reviews of all major data structures and
algorithms practice interview problems and mock tech company interviews.
So who's this course for this course is designed for a variety of audiences including self-taught programmers
who already know Python and want to learn about data structures and algorithms and begin interviewing
for tech positions as well as students currently studying computer science.
And want supplementary material and data structures and algorithms and interview preparation for after
graduation as well as professional programmers who need practice for upcoming coding interviews.
And finally anyone interested in learning more about data structures and algorithms or the technical
interview process choose this course.
Don't just get high quality videos and lecture materials.
You also get a program designed to effectively teach you what you need to know efficiently as possible
.
It's like having private tutors design an interview study curriculum just for you.
You'll also get to join our community of students who are quick to help with their feedback and share
their thoughts as well as access to the discussion forums where I'm always around to personally help
you.
This course comes of a 30 day money back guarantee if you're unsatisfied in any way you get your money
back no questions asked.
Plus you can keep all the lecture notes as a thank you for trying out the course.
This course will help you achieve your career goals in software and technology.
A career in this field is rewarding because of that interesting problem to solve.
The financial benefits and the freedom it offers.
Check out the next preview lecture for a full overview of the extensive curriculum of this course.
All right.
So what are you waiting for.
Start the next chapter in your career and enroll today