Hello everyone and welcome to the Riddell's section of this course and this section of the course we're
going to discuss riddles and brainteasers in general and in this particular lecture we're going to discuss
how to approach riddles.
So a lot of companies actually have policies now banning brainteasers and riddle type questions.
This includes Google and Microsoft and Google became famous back in the day for asking these sort of
brainteasers.
But then they realized they had really little to correlate with solving and being good at brainteasers
with actual performance on the job.
So now they have policies to bend them over some interviewers are still going to ask these type of tricky
questions.
So there's a few types of riddles and brainteaser.
The three main categories are trick questions estimation problems and math puzzles trick questions usually
rely on you having some sort of weird prior knowledge and are really the worst type of Riddle and brainteasers
can be asked and hopefully you're never asked the trick question in an interview.
These are really unfair problems to be asked.
We do have a sort of trick question in this riddle section but I will make you aware that it's a sort
of trick question.
So you don't spend too much time trying to solve it.
The next type of Riddle and brainteaser is an estimation problem estimation type problems are also being
banned at some companies but you should be aware of them.
So for instance common estimation problems are how to estimate how many McDonalds there are in the United
States or estimate how many happy birthday posts are there on Facebook in a given day.
Things of that nature.
And keep in mind for estimation problems you may be required to estimate things that are relevant to
your position.
So if you're interviewing for the G-mail team at Google you may be asked to estimate how much time is
spent on Gmail in a given day for an average person or how many people log in to G-mail every day.
Things of that nature.
Finally you have math puzzles.
These are puzzles whose background is rooted in some sort of logic or computer science and you should
be able to solve these.
And that's what the main focus of the riddle section is the sort of algorithmic and math puzzle type
riddles and brainteasers.
So how can we approach these problems.
Let's find out.
First off don't panic when you get a brainteaser.
Interviewers want to see how you tackle a problem.
They also don't expect you to immediately know the answer.
Just start talking and show the interviewer how you approach a problem.
In many cases you're also going to find that the brainteasers have some sort of connection back to the
fundamental laws or theories of computer science.
The data structures and algorithms that we've been discussing throughout this course if you're stuck
.
It's recommended to try simplifying the problem solve it for a small number of items or a special case
and then see if you can generalize it.
Remember to check if you can relate the problem to some sort of fundamental data structure algorithm
.
Remember to break down the problems.
OK that being said.
Best of luck on these riddles.
They're presented as Jupiter notebooks.
So the first Jupiter note book will present the problem and then the second one will present the solution
.
We'll walk through the solution for all of them after we present the problem statement to you.
OK.
Best of luck on the Riddell's