Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on linked in this lecture we're going to discuss what Linked-In
is and how best to taken advantage of it in your job search.
So that is one of the most important social media platforms for job searching and networking and it's
imperative to have one as you begin your job search.
So in case you're not familiar if Linked-In Linked-In is a business oriented social networking service
something to know is that most of the site's revenue comes from selling access to information about
its users to recruiters and sales professionals meaning a lot of recruiters at large corporations actually
have their company pay LinkedIn so that the recruiters can use it to find people looking for jobs.
People like you so if you don't have a link and profile yet you should go make one right now before
continuing on with the rest of the lecture.
Something I want you to note though is you can actually use your email contacts to get connections.
So keep that in mind as you create your profile.
LinkedIn should automatically ask you this and get a pop up as the image shows here on the slide.
So again go to Linked-In and create a profile explore the Web site a bit and then come back and complete
this lecture.
All right.
So you may already have Illington profile.
You should have created one looked around the bit.
Let's discuss some of the features of Linked-In.
First off Linked-In recommendations Linked-In recommendations are bit almost like a letter of recommendation
on yearly than profile if you want a recommendation.
You start off by asking people you've worked under or with to give you recommendations.
Always remember to thank them and if possible return the favor by recommending them back if it's appropriate
.
You can also ask professors and teachers to leave recommendations on your profile.
Under education section again you should really only ask people you personally know for a recommendation
next.
Arlington skil endorsements.
When you're creating a LinkedIn profile there's a skills section and you may have skills such as programming
or python that you'll put on your user profile.
Other users can endorse you for these skills.
Having scores on these skills might give your profile an edge.
Some recruiters keep an eye out for these.
Others don't really care.
Their actual usefulness is kind of debatable.
Different people vary the perception of them.
Some people think they're worthless.
Some people take them really seriously but you should at least know that they exist and keep an eye
out for skill endorsements and if someone endorses you for a skill.
Ok next following in link then you can actually follow people on LinkedIn and if you produce content
let's say you have blog posts articles or you produce new code and get her.
You can post it on Linked-In to your followers and they're going to see it in their feed and get notified
and you can also add a follow me button.
If you have a personal web site next linked in as a job search tool.
So Linked-In has its own job hunting platform.
You can check it out at WDW that link then that com slash jobs.
So if we hop over to that real quick it will look something like this.
So I'll say start your job search here.
You put in job titles keywords or company names the location and then search.
So it's a pretty good job search tool.
I definitely recommend trying it out especially if you have a pretty complete LinkedIn profile.
They'll try to match you have jobs that makes sense to you.
So check it out.
We'll discuss other job sites search tools and job boards later on in this course.
But as far as Linked-In you should be aware of this one and will come back to it later on the course
we did when we discuss job searching tips in general.
So let's go ahead and go back to the presentation.
All right.
So after checking out Linked-In dot com slash jobs I want to discuss a few Linked-In premium so Linked-In
premium is actually a premium service and we discussed earlier that some people pay Linked-In to get
a premium version of the web of their web site.
So Linked-In premium gives you a few things.
It allows you to mail people such as recruiters and email is basically linked end's own internal messaging
system.
It also allows you to connect with and contact recruiters more directly and that gives you improved
information on lengthens job search tools.
So if you're looking for jobs on lengthens job search having a Linked-In premium profile will actually
give you information such as how many people have applied that job through LinkedIn.
What's the average education background.
Years of experience cetera.
There's a 1 month free trial.
And what I would recommend you do is after you're done studying and you're ready to actually begin applying
for jobs try the one month of Linked-In premium.
Use it to contact recruiters and take advantage of that one month.
Really milk it.
And then if you decide you need it more pay for it.
If not end your 1 month free trial.
No problem.
It took advantage of it.
OK.
A quick now on discussion etiquette.
Please be polite and thoughtful when posting your linked in profile to discussion boards.
I want you to feel free to post if you generally need help and try to give honest feedback to other
people who have posted their Linked-In profiles.
However don't just spam the discussion boards on this course with your profile for no reason.
All right.
With that being said here's your Linked-In homework.
You should create Illington profile update your picture to a professional looking picture.
Make sure your face is fully seen in the photo complete your profile information.
You should get at least 10 connections.
People you know people you work with and your final homework assignment is to get a connection to recruiter
hopefully at a company that you're interested in.
All right that's it.
Make sure to complete that task list and I will see you at the next lecture.
Thank you everyone