Hello everyone and welcome to the large search engine company mock interview for this mock interview
.
You'll have a phone screen and then for onsite questions presented in the form of chip or notebooks
just short snippets of the question make any reasonable assumptions you have to make are the first two
questions.
It's almost a one part or one question with two parts to it says the first two on site questions are
pretty related to each other.
When you get all the questions the solutions are presented to you afterwards.
Again go through all the questions first and then review the solutions the ones you missed.
Go back and try him again.
At the end of this lecture or this section excuse me you can check out a resource with an interview
of Google's director of Global staffing programs for answers come questions about Google's hiring process
.
But that being said good luck with the mock interview.