Hello everyone and welcome to your next interview problem.
So for this interview a task you've been asked to implement a Q It's a pretty common interview problem
.
Just like implementing a stack or implementing a deck.
So in this case implement a queue class a class be able to do the following check if the queue is empty
.
Do it on cue or in queue do a queue and then return the size of the queue.
We review the theory lecture.
If you don't remember what these two terms mean.
But don't take a look at the implementation of a q lecture until you've tried doing this on your own
from memory.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.