Hello everyone and welcome to the solution for the great pear some problem just to get over the problem
statement again.
It was given an integer array output all the unique pairs that sum up to a specific value k.
So in this case the array is a list of Pi finalists and then the second argument is just an integer
that specific value k and you to return pairs.
So let's go ahead and go with the solution.
The solution we're going to go over is order n.
So it's going to use the set data structure.
We're going to do is perform a linear pass from the beginning and for each element we check whether
K element is in the set of scene numbers.
If it is then we found the pair of some k and add it to the output.
If not this element doesn't belong to a period.
And we added to the set of scene elements.
The algorithm is really simple to figure out using a set.
So the complexity is order and because we do a single linear scan of the array and for each element
we check we check whether the corresponding number to form a pair is in the set or add the current element
to the set.
Incertain find operations of a set are both average order one constant and we'll look at that later
and why it's Order 1.
But the algorithm and totals since we're just doing and passes is order n.
So here's the solution.
Let's go ahead and go over it and explain all of this as we code along.
So go ahead and jump over.
So first thing we're going to do is create a function and have it take that array in that specific integer
k we can do an edge case check in case there's less than two elements in the array by just saying if
the length of array is less than 2 we can even just say return.
That means it's just not going to return anything.
But you can have it return a string or print the statement.
No error less than two in the array.
That kind of thing.
It's up to you.
Then let's go ahead to make or sets for tracking.
So we'll make a scene equal to a sets and make output equal to an empty sets.
So this sort of scene equals set using a set for tracking.
It's something that you're going to see over and over again as a strategy for interview problems.
This is the first time we've seen it so far.
But keep this in mind it's a really great strategy at converting things that might seem like take order
and squared and reducing it down to a linear order.
OK.
Continuing on.
Let's go ahead and get to the meat of our solution.
I'm going to say for every number in our array.
So for now I'm in OUR I'm going to set the target difference.
And what I mean by that isn't going to create a variable called target and an equal to the difference
between k and that number.
So remember K is the integer we're trying to find the two numbers that sum up to it.
And right now k minus numb is the target we're reaching for.
So if that target is not in the numbers we've already seen we're going to add it
the number that is.
Otherwise if it isn't seen we can add the tuple with the minimum corresponding pair.
So remember I asked you to actually keep track of those pairs will return the length of the output.
But in this case I actually want you to output the pairs themselves as well just so we know we're able
to do it.
So we're not going to add a tuple.
So we're going to do that is by saying take the minimum between the number and the target
and then take the max between the name and the target.
And that's going to be the tuple we add to the output and then engineers say return length of the output
.
In this case let's go ahead and check it out.
So we have our solution let's make sure it works.
I'm going to say here some let's go 1 3 2 2 to put in four.
We should get AUPs looks like we have an error.
Takes exactly one argument.
Let's go ahead and make sure that we have enough to make this a tuple which we forgot.
Now I'll go over this line in just a second.
OK.
So that's correct.
Now we are missing a set of parentheses here.
OK.
Now let's go ahead and add a one liner to print out the actual tuple.
So I cannot comment this out and say return.
This is a little trick to print a new line.
England join and then lets you map a string to the list of the output.
So this is kind of a bit of a python trick just for printing stuff out.
So it looks nice and it's legible.
So for run this WIPs we don't want to return this we actually want to print this.
There we go.
OK.
So here we have the two pairs as a tuple.
Let's go ahead and go over a solution again so we can really break down this line.
And the logic here as far as what's this line is doing is just taking the output converting into a list
making sure all those tuples are strings.
By mapping the SDR function which converts to a string to every element in that list and then joining
them with new lines in between.
So if you print it you get these strings of tuples which have been converted in to just a print sees
one comma the integer and another prints.
OK so let's break down the important stuff.
So we have an edge case check in case there is less than two elements.
And then we have our sets for tracking the numbers we've seen in our output.
So we're going along the array and we're saying for that number in the array the target number we're
looking for will be k minus numb.
So that makes sense right.
So for instance if we have four.
Now we're at the first digit which will be one that we're looking for for minus one is three on the
first number we haven't seen it.
You'll see on the second pass we'll add that scene and be able to find it.
So then we say if Target is not seen we haven't seen that number yet we go ahead and add it to that
set and then else what we do is we add it to the output.
So we say output the ad and we take the minimum between the current number and the target.
As one of the pairs.
And then we take the maxim between the number and the target.
So we want to find out which was the minimum.
So whichever was less between that number we're currently on the target we're seeking.
As one of the items in the pair and the other integer in the pair will just be the one that's greater
between the number and the target.
OK.
That's it for the solution.
Again just remember in order to test your solution on the test cell you had to return the number like
this format.
So you got something like this.
All right.
That's it for the solution to the pair some problem.
Go ahead and read the entire solution note book in case you want explanation of the logic even further
.
But that's it for the solution.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture