Hello everyone and welcome to this lecturer we're going to be implementing FS or breadth first search
.
So this algorithm provides us with the ability to return the same results as DFS but with the added
guarantee to return the shortest path.
First remember this has to do more of that word ladder puzzle.
So this rhythm's a little more tricky to implement in a recursive manner.
Instead of using a Q data structure so what we're going to be documenting just the iterative approach
which is most likely what they're going to be expecting in a interview setting.
So we're going to be coding out this all right.
So we'll simmer graph is in the form of the dictionary we have your vertex and then the vertices is
connect to.
So let's go ahead and implement this out.
So what do we do if Libya.
FS Well our function is going to take in that graph and that starting vertex will have an object visited
and that's going to be equal to an antisense.
And then we'll have a Q
and we'll will treat this as just a list start and you can actually use a queue from the collections
module if you want to.
We're just going to be popping it off with a specified index 0 to treat it as a queue.
So basically I'm going to say is vertex is equal to q.
The pop at 0.
So you could just if you wanted to from the collections module you could import here as we've discussed
back in the Q section or bill that you're on.
Q Maybe you're asked in an interview setting.
Anyways so while the Q Still there pop it off at zero.
So that's going to be that first one.
Remember the first in line going to review the Q lectures and if you say if Virtex is not in visited
Well we're going to do is take visited add that vertex to it and there we're going to use a Q to extend
.
We'll say.
Q That extends and that going to graph that vertex minus the visited and then just return visited.
So it's extremely similar to DFS except you notice we treating it as a queue.
So we pop off at the beginning.
So what's actually going on here.
Well the main thing you should notice is that the actions performed per each explored vertex are basically
the same as the first implementation.
However what we're doing is replacing the stack with a queue and with the queue what's going to happen
as well as that explore the breadth of a vertex that before moving on.
And this behavior basically guarantees that that first path located is the shortest path present based
on the number of edges being the cost factor.
Right.
So if you want to check out more explanation notes you can always reference a Jupiter note book here
.
So this is where we just code it out.
But there's again code that will actually also tell you how to print out the possible paths so that's
also helpful to know as well as just printing out the shortest path that's there not.
And again some really great resource for free to check out.
That's all there is to it.
Again it's really quick if you already know how to DFS you're simply just switching a stack for a Q
here.
That way you guarantee the shortest path is the one you hit upon first.
All right I definitely encourage you to really read about graphs and DFS and be EF-S on your own in
the pendant early.
Don't just take everything you've learned from this course but really you should explore more and use
the resources provided for you to really build out your understanding.
It really helped complete your computer science knowledge as far as graph theory.
But as far as interview questions definitely the most important wants to know is how to implement a
graph how to implement both FS and DFS and then another common interview question is basically filling
out this function which is to return all possible paths.
Sometimes I ask sometimes no they don't.
Sometimes they don't even ask Raphe questions that also keep that in mind.
But basically the ones that we ask in this course are the definitely the ones that you should really
really know.
OK well thanks everyone and I will see you at the next lecture