Hello everyone and welcome to your next interview.
Problem for the stacks.
Q Is index section of the Course.
This interview problem is to simply implement a deck class your tech class should be able to do the
following check if it's empty.
Add to both the front and the rear of the deck.
Remove from the front and the rear of the deck and check the size of the deck.
OK with that being said there is no solution inch lecture associated with this particular problem because
we already have an implementation of DEC lecture.
So after trying this out on your own you can go ahead and review the implementation of a DEC notebook
and lecture to get your solution to this problem.
With that being said Make sure you try out this your own solution beforehand.
Don't take a peek at the solution before trying it on your own from memory.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture