Hello everyone and welcome to the solution to the binary search tree check interview problem.
To reiterate the problem statement given a binary tree you have to check whether it was a binary search
tree or not.
So if we just zoom in here.
So too much so we can take a look at the solution.
I'll just be walking through the solution note book.
I won't actually code anything out live because there's quite a bit of code but actually one of the
solutions is really simple.
So the simple solution is to know that if a tree is a binary search tree then traversing the tree in
order should lead to the sorted order of the values in the tree so we can actually perform and in order
traversal traversal and then check whether the node values are sorted or not.
So if you go back to treat traversal lecture you should be able to check out the function we had for
that in order traversal of a tree.
So here that is just straight from that lecture.
In this case what I did was create a list called Tree values and I appended the values of the tree as
we traversed in order and then went ahead and did a sort check.
And what this sort check function does.
It takes that list of tree values and then just checks if the tree values list is the same as the sorted
version of the tree values list.
And so with that function here I can check if the in order traversal of the tree actually was the sorted
values and then I know it's a binary search tree.
In other classic solution is to keep track of the minimum maximum values a node can take as you go through
the tree in each node.
You're going to check whether it's values between the min and max values it's allowed to take the Ruken
take any value between negative infinity and positive infinity.
ANY node its left child should be smaller than or equal to its own value.
And similarly the right child should be larger than or equal to that own value.
So remember this was the BSEE property.
You can go to review the binary search tree lectures but this is essentially just checking each node
for that BSD property and the so doing recursion.
What are you going to do send the current value as the new max to the left child and send the men as
it is without changing it.
And to the right child what you're going to do is send the current value as the new men and send the
max that change.
So here's an example of that sort of logic.
Code it out so you have this class note here.
In this case we have key value and then left and right as none.
As I mentioned before you can use basically any node class you want something that just makes sense
to you because an interview setting.
You're probably just going to expect you to write out your own methods here.
In this case I just said the function tree Max tree men and then I have this verify function which if
I zoom out a bit and see it in its full scope and I just have some examples here.
We go ahead and just go back up here.
What's happening here on tree Max is if we're saying if not node just return a flow of negative infinity
.
And what this allows us to do if I just copy this and go to a try that Jupiter empty cell.
This just allows you to have negative infinity in a notebook.
Or excuse me in Python.
The coming back to this.
If it's not a node that does not end up being true you just return negative infinity and then Otherwise
you have Max left and max rate variables and that sequel to the recursive call on the left and right
nodes and you just return again key.
Max left Max right in you doing a similar recursive call here except the minimum now on the left and
right of that node and basically throughout this varify function.
All we're doing is just making sure that BSEE property is true.
So we're making sure that that node laughs into the tree max function is Lessner equal to the node key
and that at the right it's greater than or equal to.
And you also verify the node left and node right through recursive calls.
Basically you just keep recursively verifying each note in that fashion.
So he gave an example of what this would look like.
We have 10 5 and 30.
So 5 is less than 10 and 30 is greater than 10 to the left and right nodes respectively.
So that will print true since that's correct.
Here we have 10 as are roots the right of that is 20 so that's still good left of that IF is 5 so that's
still good but what happens is we have left right equal to 15 and since 15 isn't in the correct position
it's going to print false since 15 is to the left 10 and it shouldn't have been on the right there.
OK so I'm going to check out this code yourself and go ahead and put in an example Sirian to this note
code so you can understand what varify is doing.
And these recursive calls on the min and max checks but really the key to understanding this problem
in the second portion is going to be the BSEE check and really in an interview setting.
You're most likely probably going to be asked to implement this solution instead of the sorting trick
here about the in order traversal.
Ok if that being said definitely review this one.
It's a classic interview problem.
Feel free to just google search validate BSD in case you want more information on this problem as well
.
OK thanks and I'll see at the next lecture.