Hello everyone and welcome to your next interview.
Question for the tree section of the Course.
This one's called tree level order prints.
So you're given a binary tree of integers.
And what we want to do is print it in level order.
The output will contain space between the numbers and the same level.
And the new line between different levels.
So for example imagine that given this tree where the is one left to the right of the root is three
and then you have four or five six so you have three levels to this tree your output given a tree that
looks like this should look like this.
One two three four five six.
So your function if you were given something that looked like this for a node class let's say left or
right now should be able to take in a tree just take in whatever tree and then you can go ahead and
be creative.
As I mentioned in the previous interview problem go ahead and call right left vowel or whatever node
properties you want off that tree.
So we want you to do is print out the levels of the tree as such.
OK.
So this is more of a traversal problem and again you might want to take your time with it.
Think about what we learned about tree traversals and how you would print this out and go through this
tree essentially in all levels as you're printing it out.
OK with that being said again just given a binary tree of integers prints it in level order.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.