Hello everyone and welcome to the shelf sort lecture so this lecture will have an explanation and visualization
or shell soar.
And in the next lecture will have an implementation Python of shells.
So let's discuss what the shelf sort algorithm actually does.
It's pretty similar to the insertion sort's algorithm but it improves on it by breaking up that original
list into a number of smaller sublists instead of just that one singular sublist and the unique way
that these sublists are chosen is the real key to shell swords.
So instead of breaking the list into sublists of continuous items the shell sort uses in increments
that will call I.
It's sometimes called the gap and it uses the increments to create a sublist by choosing all items that
are eye items or parts.
So let me go to show you a figure of what I mean by that.
So if you look at this figure this list has nine items.
If we use an increment of three then there are three sublists and each of which can be sorted by an
insertion sort and after completing these sorts we get the list shown here which I'll show you in the
next figure right here.
So although this list isn't completely sorted.
Something really interesting happens by sorting these sublists.
We've moved the items closer to where they actually belong.
So let me go in and show you what a final insertion sort.
Using in increments of one looks like.
So here and this figure right now we have the sublease 1 2 and 3 sorted.
So notice how there's these nine items we have.
I equals three so little sublists.
Three of them three items each.
And if we sort the sublists at an increment of three and go to the final insertion sort gear and this
one is just going to be using in increments of 1.
So in other words just a standard insertion sort.
And then you can note that by performing those earlier sublease sorts we've actually reduced the total
number of shifting operations necessary to put the list in its final order.
So for this case we actually need four more shifts to complete the process one shift for twenty two
shifts for that 31 elements and one more shift for 54.
And then your entire list has finally been sorted.
Now I want to show you one more figure here and we'll actually get to what disfigures actually doing
later on in the implementation.
But I mentioned earlier that the way in which the increments are chosen is one of the unique features
of shell sort.
So we'll show this later in our implementation but which you can actually do is start a first case with
an over two sublists with and being the number of items in your list or array and then on the next pass
perform and over for an X center and then eventually a single list is sorted with that basic insertion
sort.
So right now this shows what the first sublists of the example of implementation are going to do in
the next lecture looks like.
So don't worry about this too much.
Now we'll actually cover this later on when we actually implements our shell swords.
So now let's go ahead and take a quick look at some visualizations that you can check out.
So we're here at the Jupiter notebook for the implementation of shelfs or they'll see some resources
for review.
Go ahead and click the last one.
The sorting algorithms sorting Dasch algorithms dot com and you'll see some shells soar visualisations
free to check out and then keep in mind remember here that the gray values are unsorted.
Black players have been sorted OK.
And then here's a pseudo code for the algorithm and then it shows you the properties as well.
So if we just check how this shell sort looks on a random you'll see they have multiple sublists occurring
here due to the implementation.
And eventually at the end they do one final pass as an insertion sort.
All right.
So when we talk about implementing this we will talk about the properties a little more and why Shell
sort is a little better than just a normal first pass of an insertion sort.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture