Hello everyone and welcome to the implementation of the shell sort's lecture.
So just as we review the shell sort improves on the insertion sort by breaking that original list into
a number of smaller sublists and then each of those sublists is using an insertion sort.
So the unique way that these sublists are chosen is the key to the shell sort is sort of breaking up
that list into sub lists of continuous items.
But the shell sort is going to do is use in increments I which is sometimes called the gap to create
a sublist by choosing all the items or items that are eye items apart.
OK so we've seen those figures that show that idea in the previous lecture in go to review them or you
can go ahead and check out the resource for review here in the Jupiter note book.
But we're going to do is go ahead and implement our shell sort and we're going to use two functions
here.
We're going to have her main show sort function and then we're going to create another function to do
that gap insertion.
So that will be this function here.
So let's go ahead and get started with our basic shell sort.
So I jumped over to a new tab here in the Jupiter notebook and I'm going to say let's say shell underscore
sort's and passen some array.
OK.
First thing I'm going to do is go ahead and say sublist counts as equal to length of array divided by
two and then all we're going to do is say well we still have sublists so well sublist counts is greater
than 0 4 and I'll say for starts in range all the way up to the sublist counts.
This is weren't going to do that gap insertions are going to say Gap underscore insertion underscores
sort.
And that's going to take three arguments and this is a new function we're going to develop in just a
bit.
It's going to take in that array.
It's going to take in a starts and then it's going to take that sublease counts and then once we've
done that after you do that for Luper we're going to just go ahead and do is say sublease count is equal
to sublease counts divided by two.
OK so now let's go ahead and focus on this gap insertion sorts.
So we're going to say the if gap underscore insertion underscores sorts and again it's going to take
in an array that starts.
But instead of saying sublease counts what we're going to do is go ahead and treat the says is that
gap that we discussed earlier.
I'm going to say for I in range.
And in this case we're going to have our starting be our start points plus that gap all the way to the
length of the array.
Now we're going to go in steps of the gap OK and then let's go ahead and make a variable called current
value
and set it equal to whatever that value is at this index of the array.
And then let's go ahead and say position
equals.
So we're basically doing the same thing as we then and a few other algorithms at a current value in
a current position and then using that gap we're going to do is say while position is greater than or
equal to gap and the array value at the position minus the gap is greater than that current value.
Here's where we're going to do sexually that exchanging we're going to see position or that shifting
position minus gap and then say position then equals position minus gap.
So we're switching both those values and those index positions themselves.
So we're using the gap there.
And then at the end all we have to do is after this while loop just go ahead and set that current values
to just say there re at that position it's just equal to the current value.
All right so we've there are two functions before you go ahead and break them down more let's just make
sure that they work out.
So going to go ahead and copy from the other notebook this test array and this test call.
Run them and it looks like in fact we're good.
It actually did sort.
So let's go ahead and zoom out and then see if we can break down what's going on here.
So first thing you want to notice is how we're actually choosing the increments or those gaps those
sublists here.
So in this particular method or implementation all we're doing here is we're beginning with and over
two sublists So this array has elements that are first sublist is going to be and divided by two.
And then on the next pass we end up having is and divided by four right because we're dividing that
thing again by two.
So what halftimes 1 1/2 is 1 to 4.
And then we're taking that length's the array which is going to be an item to the array and then the
writing by four.
So on the first pass you start with over two sublist.
Next pass.
And a before and eventually a single list is sorted.
Just that basic insertion sort.
So what you can do if you want to visualize this a little more is actually create a print statements
so you can go ahead and put a print statements after this for a loop and you can go ahead and say Prince
this case let's say after increments of size and then let's go ahead and just say sublist counts here
and then we'll print another 9 line here.
The list is and then what we're going to do is just put that array value there.
So let's make sure that worked out
OK.
So here we have our increments so let's just go in and check the length of that array so we can get
an idea of what's going on here.
So we have 11.
So close is 11 divided by two rounds off to five.
So after the increment size 5 we essentially have this list increment size to have this list Ingrid's
size one we end up getting this list.
So you can go ahead and review the previous lecture on the actual Celso shell sort's excuse me and how
we had those sublists and the insertions and then those final insertion sorts when we had the increments
of 1 go ahead and check them out.
Those figures are really helpful.
But essentially Remember that with the shell sort we're just improving on that insertion sort.
By breaking the original list into a number of smaller sublists each of which are then sorted using
an insertion sort.
And the key to this is that unique way that these sublists are chosen in the shell sort.
So instead of breaking that list into a bunch of sublists continuous items the shell sort uses that
increments.
I sometimes call that gap and that creates a sublist by choosing all the items that are eye items apart
.
OK.
So go ahead.
Write this up yourself.
Make sure you understand it.
I really suggest using print functions to help you keep track of what's going on throughout the functions
and your function calls.
That's super helpful.
So if you're ever not understanding one or two lines of code try putting a print statement there and
seeing what's actually happening.
Go ahead and print out different variables so you can get an idea of what's actually being sorted where
you sublists where your gaps etc..
OK.
But that being said that's the implementation of the shell sort.
And I will see the next lecture.
Thanks