Hello everyone and welcome to your first riddle slash puzzle problem for this section of the course
.
Here's the problem statement.
There's a group of four travelers that's coming across a bridge at night.
So it's dark.
The bridge can only hold the way that most two travelers at a time and it cannot be crossed without
using a flashlight.
However for travelers only have one flashlight among them each traveler also walks at a different speed
.
The first traveler can cross the bridge in one minute.
The second in two minutes the third and five minutes and the fourth person takes ten minutes across
a bridge.
Here's the challenge if two travelers cross together at the bridge at the same time they have to both
walk at the speed of the slower traveler.
So for instance if the person that can cross a bridge in one minute walks along the bridge with a 10
minute traveler then they both have to walk at ten minute pace and they both take 10 minutes to cross
the bridge.
All right.
So your question is What does the least amount of time in which all the travelers can cross from one
side of the bridge to the other.
Remember the bridge can only hold two people at once and one person has to be carrying that flashlight
and if two travelers cross together they walk at the speed of the slower traveler.
All right.
Best of luck.
You definitely want to draw this out.
So practice using a pen and paper or a white board to try to draw out your logic of how you would have
people cross the bridge for the slowest or excuse me for the least amount of time possible.
OK everyone.
Best of luck.