Hello everyone and welcome to networking events and this lecture we're going to discuss how networking
events and Web sites can help bring you into contact with people directly involved in the industries
you're interested in.
Let's go ahead and discuss some popular tools.
First off just general conferences you could consider going to a conference to meet people in your industry
.
Many conferences also have hiring fairs.
Best way to find relevant conferences is by googling either the topic or programming language you're
interested in.
Plus conference most official and large programming languages have some sort of conference related to
them.
So for example if you google Python plus conference it should lead you to pikemen which also has a hiring
pair attached to it.
You Google something like Python plus data science post.com Prince you'll get to PI data which is another
python data science related conference.
There's also meet ups.
So it's one of the original source for networking and it's stody though that meet up dotcom what it
is that allows you to meet up with people in your local area who are interested in the same topics you
are.
So go to meet up dotcom and look up programming languages and topics you're interested in.
Also want you to be aware of eventful and events brights the meet ups or excuse me the events uneventful
and events brights you won't get a gathering of like minded individuals meeting up to discuss stuff
.
You'll get more of a professional on officially event field there and you'll need to buy tickets for
those events.
So just keep that in mind as you explore those websites.
Finally as far as your assignments you should at least create a meet up profile so you can get notified
of relevant meet ups in your area.
All right that's it for this lecture in this section.
Hopefully you have a good idea now of the basics of networking and I'll see at the next lecture.
Thanks everyone