Hello and welcome to the phone screen problem for the social network company mock interview questions
.
So the problem statement is this remove duplicate characters in a given string keeping only the first
occurrences.
So for example if the input is a string tree traversal the output will be t r e space a v s l.
So I notice that since you haven't already occurring the second Ian tree gets removed as well as the
E and traversal and then the t r get removed because they're already in tree.
OK.
So write a function again that removes duplicate characters in a given string keeping only the first
occurrences.
So your requirements for this problem is to complete the problem in a text editor that does not have
syntax highlighting such as a Google doc or any word processor a text editor.
Again as we've stated before a lot of phone screens will just have you screen sharing on a normal text
editor that doesn't have syntax highlighting.
So it's important to practice writing out code without syntax highlighting or automatic indentation
.
Now again don't worry if it's perfect it doesn't have to run but at least get the general concept of
what you're trying to do and then you can go to either Jupiter or notebook or any other ideas and test
out your code.
All right.
With that being said.
Best of luck and I'll see you at the next lecture.