Hello everyone and welcome to lecture on salary questions and answers.
So in this lecture we're going to go over a few SALIR related questions and some appropriate answer
strategies for them.
There's really no need to pause and practice these sort of questions until you're actually getting interviews
and offers.
So the first question is what kind of salary are you looking for.
So attempt to get the company to make the first offer.
Most negotiating professionals believe that whoever brings up salary first loses in the negotiating
game.
So if possible try to deflect the question so you don't disclose an exact number.
First another question is what is your current salary.
So bear in mind that what you earn has no direct bearing on what your work and what you want to make
though it can be difficult to support this in an interview without seeming defensive or awkward.
So although the interviewer is looking for specifics here you can be somewhat elusive in general without
compromising the quality of your response.
You know the question is What would you like to be earning five years from now.
Here the interviewer is most likely just trying to gauge your ambitions.
So this is a good time to be honest of your aspirations to try to assess what the interviewer is looking
for with this question.
It's a pretty uncommon question.
You're more likely just to be asked Where do you see yourself in five years not what you're going to
be exactly earning.
All right that's it for this specific salary questions.
Up next we're going to cover how to prepare references.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.