Hello everyone and welcome to the implementation of quicksort lecture.
So as a reminder the quicksort algorithm first selects a value which is called the pivot value although
there are many different ways to choose the pivot value.
What we do simply is the first item in the list the role of the pivot value is to assist with the splitting
of that list.
The actual position or the value belongs in the final sorted list commonly called that split point is
then use the Vitalist for subsequent calls of the quicksort.
So again you have resources for review and you can check out the previous lecture if you want more coverage
on the theory of quicksort where we're going to go ahead and implement our own quick sort algorithm
.
So this probably would be one of the most involved out of the all the coding of the algorithms so just
keep that in mind.
We're going to have three separate functions in order to make this happen.
So let's go ahead and just dive right into the code before we break it down line by line and explain
what's actually going on.
All right.
So first thing we're going to do is just go ahead and start functions.
We're going to say DCF and say quick underscore sort's And let's go ahead and pass an energy.
You know what I want to say right now is just pass and I want to make this skeleton of all the functions
we're gonna use next and we're going to use is called Quick sorts helper.
So this original quicksort function is going to do in it's going to invoke a recursive function called
quicksort helper which Let's go ahead and do it.
We'll just take a quick underscore sort's help and that will take in an array and then a first and last
marker and we'll say pass right now.
And then finally the last one we're going to say is partition.
This also take the array first and last books and little say pass.
All right.
So we have the quicksort function and then it's going to invoke a recursive function.
Quicksort help which begins at the same base case as that merge sort.
So if the length of the list is less than or equal to one that's already sorted.
If it's greater then we can be partitioning and recursively sorting that array.
So that's what the partition function is going to do.
And it's going to implement that process described in the previous lecture.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So we have quicksort and all it's going to do is like I mention just going to call quick sorts hell
and it's going to take in that array will start off at 0 and then go to lengths of the array minus one
.
And the reason for that being is the way we set up our end of values when we do partition.
So quicksort help we're just going to say if first is lost than last we're going to split up set up
a variable called split point
and then that's going to be returned from the partition call and again partition is just going to take
in the array first and last and then similar to the merge sort.
Here we're going to call a quick help twice on the array first and then all the way to the split points
minus one and then we're going to call it again quick underscore sort.
Underscore help on the array and then from the split points plus 1 all the way to the last element.
So this should look really familiar from the merge sort's implementation where we had that recursive
call one on that first left half than the other one and that right half.
So now let's take advantage of this and use filter partition function to really start doing the merging
in that quick sorting.
So let's go ahead and create a pivot value will say pivot value as a variable and just have it be that
first element.
As I mentioned there's different ways of choosing the pivot value for the simpler implementation we're
just going to use that first element.
So then let's go ahead and make those marks so hopefully remember from those figures we had that left
Mark and that right Mark.
And just like we did in the last lecture theoretically at least I'll say it last Mark equal to that
first plus 1 and then right Mark just equal to last.
And then what I'm going to do is set up a while loop and in order to make this a little more readable
I'll set a variable called done and have it be equal to false.
That way all my while loop can read something like this.
While not done so that allows us to have a really nice readable while loop and then I'll say while that
left Mark is less than or equal to the right mark and the array value at the left Mark is less than
or equal to the pivot value.
Then I'll just say left Mark
is equal to left Mark plus one which I can just write like this
and then I'll say another while loop.
While the value at the right mark in our original array is greater than or equal to the pivot value
and the right mark is greater than or equal to the left Mark and the right mark is going to be subtracted
of one subtract from the right mark.
So remember from that last lecture how we move them closer to each other so left Mark starts moving
to the right and then that right Mark starts moving to the left.
As long as it's two conditions end up being true.
And then finally if we say if right Mark is less than the left marks or remember that was that crossing
point.
And then they're done.
So I will say Dunn equals true otherwise you're not done yet so I'll say else.
And this is where we basically do that.
That switching will say create a temporary variable
of the left Mark value and then set left to mark equal to the right mark and then set the right mark
equal to the temp.
So that's basically just the way we're switching those values once they cross over.
All right.
And then all we're gonna do is outside of these wild loops are essentially outside of this wild done
.
We have to do one last switch here I'll say 10 Zucco to the value at first and then that value at first
is then going to be equal to the right mark or the value at the right mark and then the right mark value
is just equal to scuse me simp here.
And then we can just return the right mark since we're be calling partition here which basically just
returning in a split point.
So partition is just going to be returning that split point after doing these operations.
All right.
I know that was a lot of code.
So let's go ahead and check it out.
Make sure it all worked and then we'll break it down further.
So going to say an array.
Let's go ahead and just copy and paste this from that Jupiter notebook we already have.
Make sure this all worked out OK.
It looks like it's sorted and looks like we're good to go.
So let's go ahead and break down what's going on here in our implementation of quicksort server.
The first thing we had to do in quicksort was select the value which is called that pivot value which
is what we have here.
While we're making the partition we're selecting that pivot value and in this case we're selecting the
first item in this list and the role of the pivot value is to assist with splitting the list.
So the actual position where that pivot value belongs in the sorted list commonly call that split point
which is what you end up returning from a partition function.
That's going to be used to divide the list for subsequent calls of quicksort which is what we're doing
here.
OK.
So we have our first pivot value which is going to be that first elements.
So then this partition process is what's going to happen next.
We have left markers in our right markers and with this partition process is going to do.
It's going to find that split point and at the same time move other items to be on the appropriate side
of the list either less than or greater than that pivot value which is what we're doing with these checks
here and here.
So as I mentioned that partitioning begins by locating those two position markers that left Mark and
the right mark at the beginning and end of the remaining items in the list.
And the goal of this partition process is to move items that are on the wrong side with respect that
pivot value are also converging to that split point which is why we slowly start to move the left Mark
to the right and that right Mark to the left.
And then when specifically we begin this process by just incrementing left Mark here.
Incrementation until we locate a value that is greater than the pivot value which is what we're doing
here.
OK.
So then we decrease the right mark until we find the value that is less than the value which is what
we're doing here.
So basically once it breaks.
So isn't that what we're doing here.
Once it breaks and is greater than the value.
So at this point then we've discovered two items that are out of place of respect to that eventual split
point and then we just exchange those two items which is what we're doing here and repeat the process
again.
So at the point where the right mark becomes less than the left Mark that's when we stop which is our
Done statement here and then we know that the position of the right mark is not split point and that
pivot value can be exchanged with the contents of that split point and the pivot value is now in place
.
And in addition to all this all the items to the left of the split point are now less than the value
And the only items to the right of the split point are greater than the pivot value.
So the list can now be divided up to split point and the quicksort can be invoked recursively on the
two halves.
In this case we used Quick's or help on those two halfs here.
OK.
So that's the basics of matching up what we theoretically talked about in the previous lecture to an
actual implementation of the algorithm.
I would really suggest that you use print statements wherever you feel uncomfortable or confused about
our implementation here.
To print out what's actually going on and when you're doing that.
Go ahead and switch this array to the same numbers that we used in the previous lecture.
So you can actually see your Oraibi printed out in the same way that we have the figure in the previous
lecture on those slides.
And that's going to be a really useful way for you to build out your understanding of the algorithm
printout.
Follow along and really understand how the partition and quicksort process is actually working.
And if you still need more help again if you go to the Jupiter notebook there's resources for reviews
such as the Wikipedia page visual algorithm etc..
All right.
So that's the implementation of quicksort.
Thank you everyone and I will see you at the next lecture