Hello everyone and welcome to the sorting and searching interview problems.
So we've gone over the theory now let's talk about interview problems themselves.
So in this section most common interview questions are related to sorting are just implementation questions
in this section you're actually just going to be asked to implement each of the sorting algorithms.
We've already gone over then check the relevant implementation lecture for the solution.
So this section is going to be a little bit different than the other and to be a problem sections we've
done where there is no direct solution video after the interview problem.
Just go ahead and check the relevant implementation lecture for that algorithm.
We'll go over this again individually for each of the interview problems the reminder that is a special
no on the binary search algorithm.
This section's interview problems are just going to ask you to implement it.
But keep in mind that future mock interview questions or it's the end of the Course will ask you questions
we're using a binary search is critical to finding the answer.
So really no binary search.
Well but that being said.
Best of luck on all the questions.
Remember we're just going to be implementing the sorting algorithms the interview problems for this
section of the course.
OK.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture