Hello everyone and welcome to the Big O notation lecture in this section of the course in this lecture
what we're going to be doing is just going over the corresponding Jupiter notebook that accompanies
this lecture.
We won't be doing that much or really any live coding we'll just be discussing the functions that we
previously looked that okay with that being said let's go ahead and jump to the Jupiter notebook.
All right.
This is the Big O notation notebook and I recommend that you actually read through this notebook and
then if anything does it make sense to come back to this video lecture where we're all going to be going
over it.
All right.
So we previously discussed these two functions And now remember these functions take in an end and then
they return the sum of the numbers from 0 to end.
The first one that it really and the second one took this algorithm the end times and plus one divided
by two.
So what we want to do is develop some sort of notation to objectively compare the efficiency of these
two algorithms.
And a good place to start would be to compare the number of assignments or operations each algorithm
makes.
So let's start with just assignments in general.
So if we look here the original Some one function will create in assignments n plus one times and we
can see this from that x range or range based functions.
Just a quick note.
This is since this is in Python 2 we're using x range which is just a generator but range in Python
3 is the same.
So don't worry about that detail or really just discussing Big-O notation here.
So continuing on this original function will create that assignment.
And plus one times.
So this means we will assign that final underscore some variable.
This one right here is going to sign it and plus one times.
So here is the 0 and then it assigns it and plus 1 times.
So we can say that for a problem of any size here it's input.
This function will take that one plus and steps for that.
And plus 1 steps and this n notation right here allows us to compare solutions and algorithms relative
to the size of the problem.
So since someone this first function of 10 will be different than someone of let's say a million.
If an equals 10 or nickels a million they could take very different run times.
But if we get some sort of Big O notation that's relative or in terms of the input we can objectively
measure it across any sort of input as long as the Big O notation is relative to the input.
So that's where this end is going to come into play and we'll see that when we actually formalized the
notation.
OK so let's go ahead and scroll down here and zoom in a bit so we can discuss the formality of BIG N
or Big O notation.
Scuse me.
So Big O notation.
Formally we can say it's describes how quickly runtime will grow relative to the inputs as the input
gets arbitrarily large.
So there's three points there.
Let's go ahead and examine them more closely.
So first point this first bullet we want to compare how quickly runtime will grow not compare exact
run times since those can vary depending on the hardware.
So as you mentioned before we want to compare objectively these two algorithms not based on runtime
.
And what I mean by not based on runtime is not based on exact runtime.
We just want to compare how quickly runtime will grow.
So I don't want to compare let's say 10 seconds versus 12 seconds.
I want to compare something objectively and that can be how quickly runtime will grow.
Second point we want to make is since we want to compare the variety of input sizes we're only concerned
with runtime growth relative to input and that's going to be where this and notation comes into play
.
And then the third point is as it gets arbitrarily large we only worry about terms that will grow the
fastest and it gets large and to this point we can think of Big O analysis as sometimes also known as
asymptotic analysis.
OK.
So let's go ahead and scroll down to the table where you can see how this syntax works.
So the syntax for that first function can be said to be big O N since it's runtime grows linearly with
the input size.
In this next lecture we'll go over more specific examples of these big O types and types.
But just to note this is what the format of the Big O notation is going to look like it's going to have
a big O.
And then the Big-O notation or performance inside the print Decies.
So here's some common run times of big functions.
So the common ones are constants logarithmic linear log linear quadratic cubic and exponential.
So what I'm going to do now is use a library called Map plot live to plot out the differences between
these big O's.
So you can go ahead and check out that code yourself but don't worry about it we're just discussing
Big O notation here.
Not that lib but I use that code to create this plot here.
So here we can compare the growth of relative runtime versus the size of the input.
So you can see here in constant time you'd have a straight line and then you'd also have logarithmic
log linear quadratic and cubic and exponential.
So let's go in and zoom out a bit so we can see him all.
Here we go.
So you can see that there's a big impact.
If you don't have a good big 0 for your algorithm.
So there's a huge difference a big O efficiency can make for the same end value against some sort of
project at runtime.
And clearly you want to choose algorithms that stay away from any exponential quadratic or Cubitt behavior
these guys seem to grow so fast you can note that for small input sizes so very low values of n they're
all very similar and to each other.
So if you only expect the deal flow n for maybe for certain cases the Big O doesn't actually matter
to you.
But as you can see as and grows larger you'll get huge differences the pending on the efficiency of
your algorithm.
So in the next lecture we're going to do our how to properly denote this big O.
And then we'll look at examples of various problems and calculate the big O of them.
So what we see in this lecture we just saw a quick kind of almost a preview of the various big-O types
why it's so important to choose or try to create an algorithm that has a inefficient Big O relative
to its performance and runtime.
OK.
So in the next lecture we're going to see a bunch of examples and break down.
Big.
All right.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture