Hello everyone and welcome to the tough interview questions lecture.
So some non technical questions can actually be pretty tricky to answer.
But we're going to do is prepare for a rundown of them and talk about general response strategies.
So overall strategy should be demonstrate your ability to create.
Use real examples from the past and show how you'll fit into the company's culture.
So we're going to do just get some general practice what you'll see is a bunch of slides of questions
on them and for each question after we ask it.
Go ahead and pause the video and then attempt to answer it afterwards.
Play the video and then listen to some general response strategies.
So your first question is tell me about yourself.
Go ahead and post the video now and try to answer the question.
OK.
So hopefully you're tempted to answer.
Tell me about yourself some general strategies.
First off this is one of the first questions you're going to encounter.
It tests for composure communication skills and ability to develop some sort of rapport with the interviewer
.
Prepare a 60 second script which breaks the ice in the first 30 seconds of an overview of your achievements
and then the second half should include mention of your recent professional or academic accomplishments
to enhance how good of a candidate you are.
So again just a brief personal background overview include your academic background if you're a recent
student or some key accomplishments or credentials depending on the type position and your experience
and then you also want to include the most impressive or at differentiating strengths that will resonate
with the interviewer.
Next question why are you leaving your current position.
Go ahead and pause the video and come back to it once you're done answering.
All right.
So this question the interviewers probing for some sort of dissatisfaction or this content he or she
wants to see if you will speak negatively about your employer or supervisor and this question really
tests your character and ambition.
So point is regardless of the reasons you're seeking the new position.
Always remain positive and don't complain.
Demonstrate that you have the vision of your future.
Emphasize that your departure will be professional in any setting.
So the key message you want to convey here is that you're sitting in front of the interviewer and considering
leaving because you want to grow.
You want more responsibility and growth opportunities and that's why you're leaving your current position
.
OK.
Let's go ahead and go to the next question.
Why do you want this position.
Go ahead and pass a video now in answer the question.
All right.
Why do you want this position.
It's going to be another common but tough interview question.
The answer here will vary depending on the position and the company.
But what you really want to come across as someone with desire commitment passion toward your career
goals that's going to be really important to the hiring manager.
So your confidence in answering this question should come from knowing capabilities desires and goals
.
The sort of self-assurance comes across in an interview in your voice and body language in addition
to the actual content of your answers.
Confidence is everything.
With this question.
So remember that.
OK let's move on to the next question.
Where do you see yourself in five years.
Has the video now.
And answer the question OK.
So was this sort of question the interviewer wants to see how you envision your future evidence that
supports the fact that high achievers are also people who have defined goals for themselves.
So the interviewer also wants to see how realistic your objectives are and how well they mesh with the
company's goal.
So just keep that in mind.
Let's go ahead and go to the next question.
Here's a tough one.
What's your greatest weakness.
Go ahead and post a video now.
In answer to a question.
All right.
So this is one of the weirder and tougher questions and actually personally think it's a pretty poor
indicator of how well someone will do in your company's culture but you should be prepared to answer
it because it's a common interview question.
The general strategy for this question is to turn this question around and discuss an area that needs
improvement.
That's not just an outright weakness.
Then you're going to want to demonstrate that you're doing something to improve in that area.
You should definitely avoid overused and cliched answers such as I work too hard or I expect too much
of others.
What you should do instead is give one or two examples of something that won't affect your ability to
do the job and that you're improving it.
It's not just an outright weakness it's an area that you're working on improving.
Let's go ahead to go to the next question.
So what do you know about our company.
Go ahead and pause a video now and answer the question.
So granted the answer to this question will very wired wildly the pending on what the company actually
is and who you're talking to.
But after all the work you did prior to this and preparing for the interview there should be a no brainer
.
The answer to this question demonstrates the interviewer that you've taken the time to research the
company and have identified where and how you can contribute.
So keep that in mind.
The answer to this question is going to change a lot depending on what the company is but you should
be prepared to answer it.
Next question is what's the most difficult situation you had to face at a job.
Go ahead and pause a video now and answer the question.
All right.
With this question the interviewer is looking to discover what you consider a difficult situation and
how you resolved that situation.
Again this answer should roll right out when you're asked.
Prepare a good script for this question and spend about 80 percent of the time on the solution.
Only just mentioning the problem itself.
Again you want to focus on the solution to the situation not the situation itself.
Let's go ahead and go to the next question.
Next question is What do you think makes a successful manager.
Go ahead and pause the video and answer the question.
All right.
With this question the interviewer is trying to determine your management style and philosophy here
the emphasis should be on teamwork training and development coaching and leading by example a mention
of attaining corporate objectives would also be appropriate.
If you're interviewing at a larger company.
So those are all the questions.
Make sure you have answers are general ideas prepared for these sort of questions.
Good job.
And in the next lecture we're going to focus on questions designed for students.
Are people just getting out of school.
I don't have a lot of experience yet.
Thanks everyone.
Again go through this lecture right before your interview Seacom prep for the tough non-technical interview
questions.
Thanks.
I'll see you at the next lecture.