Hello everyone and welcome to the dynamic array exercise lecture in this lecture we're going to be implementing
our own dynamic array class.
So as always there's a notebook associate of this since it's a live coding lecture.
If you go to do if you go to the array sequences folder under dynamic array exercise.
I on a book here.
If you click on that you'll get this dynamic array exercise notebook and it has all the code as well
as some notes and lots of comments for you to fully understand what we're going to go through this lecture
.
So we're going to basically basically be implementing this class dynamic array.
It's going to act similarly to a python list.
So let's go ahead and get started really quickly before we begin.
We're going to be taking advantage of two features of Python.
One is a built in library called C types.
You can check out the documentation link here for more information but it's basically just going to
be used here as a raw array holder.
If you scroll down to the very bottom of the eye of the dynamic array class that we're going to be building
.
That's the only part where we use it where we actually make a new array.
OK.
And then the second note that I want you to be aware of is we used an underscore before method's name
to keep it non-public.
So we'll show a quick example of that by copying and pasting this code into the notebook.
So for instance now if by say lowercase them is equal to an instance of that class.
If I do that tab I will get public help but notice I won't get a list containing private because it
has that underscore I would have to specify underscore in order to see all the special methods available
to me and at the very end one of them will be private.
So we're going to make use of that just because certain methods don't make sense for the users to be
able to call them.
All right.
With that all being said let's go ahead and get started on implementing our own array class.
So we've cleared all the cells and we're going to go in and start our implementation.
First thing imma do is just import that C types and we'll get into that later on why we actually need
to do that.
So let's start building out our class color class dynamic array every number it's PEP 8 to have this
capitalized pass an object.
And let's go ahead and get started.
First we want to initialize.
So underscore underscore in it underscore underscore and we're just going to pass and self.
And there's essentially three attributes that we're going to have here.
We're going to have an We're going to start at zero.
So this is going to be the actual count of the actual elements.
By default it's zero.
We're going to have capacity be another attribute by default.
I'll just be one so can accept only one element by default.
Remember we're going to be using a dynamic array style in order to implement larger capacities and show
methods to do that later on.
And then finally I'm going to say self-taught A.
And that's going to be equal to self.
That's another method which we'll call make array and we'll build that out later.
And it's going to pasan capacity.
OK.
So we have these three attributes that count actual elements with and the capacity default is 1 and
the self-taught A which would call make array which we're going to build out later on.
The next one we want to do is a special method length it's going to pass and just self.
And this is going to return a number of elements stored in the array.
So it's going to do is return self-taught.
Em All right.
And then one more special method we want to do is get item.
This is going to take in self of course and it's also going to take in a k parameter.
And what this is going to do is it's going to return the elements at index k.
So after creating a dynamic array you can use indexing to return the element to index.
So I'm going to say if not
zero Lessner equal to K less than or equal to self-taught.
And remember this the count of the actual elements.
Basically this is saying if that K that index you pass isn't actually in between zero and the count
of the actual elements will have to return some sort of error.
In this case there's a specific error for this index error.
So make sure you go ahead and review errors and exceptions.
If you don't understand what this sort of syntaxes But what this is just going to do it's going to out
KS out of bounds if you happen to ask for a K that's out of bounds of the array.
So if that clears then we're just going to say return self that a.
OK so we're going to retrieve from our labeled a array index k.
And the reason we're using that self-taught a notation is to reflect back on the diagrams from the previous
lecture where we had two arrays a and b array.
So we'll also keep the Beary notation later on as we implement this further.
All right.
Next method we're going to create is the append method.
So this is going to add an element to the end of the array.
So I'm going to say a pen.
We can zoom in here a little bit.
I'm going to say a pen.
It's going to take self argument since we're acting on that instance of the object.
And it's also going to take elete which stands for elements.
So it's going to add the elements that L.E. to the end of the array.
And this is where we're going to have to check our capacity.
So as we mentioned in the previous lecture I'm going to say if self-taught.
So the count of the actual elements if that's equal to the capacity
self-taught capacity was colon then I'm going to say self that and what I'm going to have to do is if
my current count is equal to my capacity I'm going to double the capacity if there isn't enough room
.
So later on when I'm going to do is creates a private method called resize.
So in this case I'll say underscore resize to times self capacity and just keep a note here to X if
capacity isn't enough.
All right.
So what we're going to append an element we check to see if our current count is equal to our capacity
.
If it is we're going to resize and double it after we do that we can say self of our aere
person and set it equal to Ellie.
So we set self-doubt an index to the elements and then since that's equal to the elements I'm going
to have to do is add one to that counts.
All right.
So we double the capacity and then we take that last one.
And that last count said equal to that new element that we're appending here and then add one to n to
our count.
All right so since we mentioned this underscore resize special method here let's go ahead and build
that out.
So when I say the underscore resize it's going to take itself and then it's also going to take in arguments
new cap which is the new capacity which is what we were passing in here that I'm highlighting right
now two times the current capacity self-talk capacity and this is going to resize the internal array
to the capacity of that new underscore cap.
So we're going to use the same sort of notation we use in the last lecture B.
So I'm going to say this betray is equal to self that
make array.
And we're going to be using that C types library that we mentioned earlier to use that Maskerade method
we haven't developed that yet but we'll do it after we finish out this resize method.
So we're going to make array.
And it's going to accept new cap as an arguments.
So we make a new bigger array and call it B and then we say for k in range self-taught.
And so we reference all the existing values on the set B of K equal to self-taught a k.
So here I'm just referencing as we saw in that previous diagram in the previous lecture I'm basically
referencing all these existing values from a into B.
Once we're done with that and I say self that a is now equal to B.
So I call a.
Now that new.
And then I say self that capacity is equal to new cap.
So I reset that capacity.
All right.
And then lastly we're just going to make a method that actually makes arrays.
And this is going to make the raw array that we're actually creating.
And this is going to take itself and new cap and this returns a new array with the new cap capacity
.
And so we're going to be using that C types library here.
It's just going to be a one liner don't worry too much about what we're actually typing and how this
is working.
You can essentially just think about it as grabbing those raw bytes and creating that array.
So it's going to be new cap times see types of pie underscore objects in close parentheses afterwards
.
So just go ahead feel free to copy this line from the Jupiter notebook that's available to you.
So that's it.
That's our entire dynamic array class.
Let's go ahead and run it this cell and make sure we haven't missed anything up.
All right let's make a variable called a r r and instantiate it as a dynamic array.
Run it.
All right.
Looks like it's working so far.
So let's go ahead and do some things to it.
Let's go ahead and say are the pens the pen the integer 1 to it.
All right.
Now let's check the length of our array and it's 1.
So let's go ahead and appends in other array.
Excuse me another integer.
And Alice checked the length of the array.
It looks like the length is not 2.
And now let's see if we can actually access it using indexing methods.
And it looks like we can.
So index 0 we have one and an index one we have two.
All right.
So that was it.
We actually made our own dynamic array.
Let's go ahead and do a quick rundown of all the methods since we created them all.
So we're going to zoom out a bit here.
So starting off with the class dynamic array object we started with some attributes here.
Self-taught and which was the actual count of the elements in the array.
We started off with 0 elements in the array.
Then we have the capacity of the array.
We start off with just bam to hold one element and then we have self-taught a equal to.
Self-taught make array of self-taught capacity.
So in this case when we start out we set a equal to an array of capacity 1.
So we come down here and using that C types library actually make that raw array.
Then we start for some special methods length just to return that counts get item that allows us to
index.
But first we do a check to see if it's actually in bounds for that k if it is we just return a index
k and then we have this appends.
And this is really the key to understanding all of this is that we check our actual counts against the
capacity.
And if it's equal to it then we resize to double the capacity and that's really the main point of this
dynamic array that instead of having this huge array since the beginning we just check as we add elements
if our count is equal to the capacity and we double if the capacity isn't enough.
That's really what makes this array a dynamic array and we can keep adding to it.
And the space that we have will keep growing as we go along.
Then once we do that we just say a softer end is equal to elements and we add a count at that.
And then we created a method called the resize which sets the Sarabi almost like a temporary array equal
to make array at that capacity.
Then it says for K range self-taught.
And we basically re reference everything and a to b and then we set self-taught a equal to be again
and we set the capacity equal to the new cap.
And then finally this make array uses the c types library to make that raw array that we're referencing
throughout the entire class of this dynamic array object.
OK.
So that's it.
What I want you to do now as a little homework assignment is play around with it.
And I want you to see how it all resizes.
So try using the same system get size of.
So if I jump over to the Jupiter note book try using this right here let me zoom in on it for you guys
.
This s y s that get size of as remember if in some previous lectures we use that to see how many bytes
were actually being held.
So go ahead and check the length of the array and then check the size of it and see how it changes and
doubles as you add more elements and reach certain capacities.
All right that's it for the lecture.
I hope it was interesting for you to see our own implementation of a dynamic array.
And remember the key takeaway is really this append the method here where we're checking the capacity
and doubling if there isn't enough room and how are resizing the array by referencing a new array to
all the existing values and then resetting a new array B.
OK thanks everyone so much and I will see you at the next lecture.