Hello and welcome to the second onsight question for the social network company mock interview here's
your problem statement given a list consisting of a count ID numbers in the form of integers which contains
duplicates find the one unique integer.
The list will be guaranteed to only have one unique non duplicated integer.
Some requirements do not use built in Python functions or methods.
However you can go ahead and feel free to code this out in a group or a notebook or an ID of your choice
.
So to give you an example you may have a list that goes 1 1 2 to 3 so you have duplicates of the integer
1 and the integer 2 but the integer 3 is unique.
So your function should be able to take in that list and find that one unique integer.
Sorry keep in time you want to do or keep in mind you want to do this efficiently.
So keep in mind Big O and how that can affect your function.
All right with that being said.
Best of luck and I'll see you at the next lecture