Hello everyone and welcome to the Q overview lecture.
So we've learned about stacks and implemented our own stack class.
Let's go ahead and now learn about queues.
So as I mentioned we'll get an overview of what is in this lecture and in the next lecture we're going
to implement her own Q class.
So AQ is an ordered collection of items where the addition of new items happens at one end called the
rear and the removal of existing items occurs at the other end which is called the Front as an element
enters a queue.
It starts at the rear and makes its way towards the front.
Waiting until that time when it is the next element to be removed.
So the most recently added item in the queue must wait at the end of the collection the item that has
been in the collection the longest is at the front.
So this ordering principle is sometimes called First in first out or F I O by for FIFO.
Anyhow you want to pronounce it.
It's also known sometimes as first come first serve.
So the simplest example of a Q is a typical line that we all participate from time to time so we can
wait in line for a movie or a checkout line at a grocery store or a cafeteria.
The first person in that line is also the first person to get serviced or helped.
So that's the parallel and why the naming scheme is.
Q In this case.
So first in first out.
So for example in this figure we have two new terms here and q or on Q and then dequeue are they.
Q pending how you pronounce it.
So we had the back front of the queue.
So NQ term describes when we add a new item to that rear of the queue and a cute term describes removing
the front item from the queue.
So when we're thinking about how this relates to the push and pop methods that we saw in that stack
implementation in this case as we push items into the queue they're the first in.
But as we pop them out those first in items are also the first to come out.
So you can see how this is different than a stack.
So remember stack was last in first out in this case we're first in first out.
So keep that in mind.
So you should now have a basic understanding of what a queue is.
And that first in first out principle for them in the next lecture we can actually implement our own
Q class.
OK.
So go ahead and review this lecture in case anything was unclear to you.
There's also a Jupiter note book that goes along with the lectures.
You can check it out as well.
You can check out the resource for the PowerPoint that we went over in this lecture.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture where we're going to implement our own
cute class