Hello everyone and welcome to lecture on a more time zation.
So we've already discussed dynamic arrays.
We've implemented a dynamic array and we learn that when dynamic areas get full they double in size
.
So in this lecture we're going to do in amortized analysis of dynamic arrays.
So the strategy of replacing an array with a new larger array might at first seem slow since a single
append operation may require order and time to perform our new array allows us to add new elements before
the array must be replaced again.
So what we're going to do is use an algorithmic design pattern called the Morto ization.
We can show that performing a sequence of such append operations on a dynamic range is actually quite
efficient.
So again just to reiterate remember if we have a current number of elements now we're going to overflow
that is fill up the array we're going to double it to get more room.
But on that doubling that means that primitive operations for and a pen is going to be Order end.
So here we have one on two.
We have to double on four it put it a pen.
So it's going to be order m on eights again in a penalty order 8 on 16 order 16 Everything else is just
going to be order one for constant.
So again what we're going to do is allocate memory for a larger array of size typically twice the older
a copy the contents of the older read to the jury and then free the old array.
So go ahead and see a diagram of this process.
So here we have a dynamic array.
Initially we'll call it the table it's just empty and the size is zero or item 1.
We're having an overflow since our array is full.
So we have to double it when we enter item 2.
Again we're having an overflow arrays full.
So we have to double it on inserting item 3.
You're fine but inserting item 4.
You have to double it because you're having an overflow then on 5 6 and 7.
You're all right.
So let's do an analysis on this process here on the left.
We have that same figure showing the insertions and here on the right we're actually going to do the
analysis.
So for item number one for instance or table sizes 1.
So our cost of putting in that append or inserting it into that table or array is just one item number
two table sizes too.
So our cost was to order end and here's where the basically the magic of the more times analysis happens
on Item number three the table size has become four since we doubled it.
Meaning are costs three.
And then an item number four.
So you've already doubled the table size to for our cost is now just one for that insertion then on
item 5 and table size 8 Our cost is 5 but for six seven 8 since the table sizes 8 our cost of insertion
is actually just one.
So the more ties cost we can actually sum this all up and divide it by n the number of items in that
array and we can actually simplify that above series by breaking the terms 2 3 5 9 into 2 as one plus
one one to close to 1 plus for 1 plus 8.
So are those end terms that one plus one plus one and then using a bit of a math trick we can have the
other ones go one plus two plus four etc. divided by end meaning we have N plus 2 end over end.
And when you divide and out that will be just one plus two which is three.
So the more time cost is actually constant order one.
So go ahead and check out the resource section of the lecture for a PDA of a more detailed explanation
thats going to be your homework assignment.
So make sure you read that fool PDAF explanation just a few pages long but again it's a nice amortized
analysis.
This isn't really necessary for you to know given what the array interview questions are going to look
like but you should know if you're interested in how a dynamic array works.
So up next we're going to have a lecture over viewing the interview problems in this section of the
course and after that we'll get started with the interview problems.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture