Hello everyone and welcome to the next riddle.
This one's called eggdrop and it's probably the most common brainteaser slash riddle slash puzzle out
of the entire group.
So really try to think using the algorithms we've learned about when trying to find a solution for this
problem.
Here's the problem statement.
There's a tower with 100 floors on it and you've been given two eggs.
The eggs are strong enough that they can be dropped from a particular floor in the tower without breaking
.
You've been tasked to find the highest floor in a Can we drop that without breaking in a few drops as
possible.
This means if an egg is dropped from above its target floor that will break if it is dropped from that
floor or below it will be intact and you can test drop the egg again on another floor.
So show algorithmically how you would go about doing this in a few drops possible.
So your answer should be the number of the fewest drops needed for testing two eggs on 100 floors and
finding the highest floor you can drop it at without the egg breaking.
OK.
Best of luck and I'll see you at the next lecture.