Hello everyone and welcome to onsight question for for the large search engine company mock interview
.
The question problem statement is as follows.
Find the square root of a given number rounded down to the nearest integer without using a builtin square
root function in Python.
That's the s q r t function.
So for example.
Square root of a number between 9 15 should return 3 and 16 and 24 should be 4.
So you're going to be given a number.
Just a single integer and then you have to give the square root nearest to it rounded down.
So your function should be able to take any number between 9 and 15 and the output 3.
Any integer that is between 9 and 15.
It should output 3 and then any integer between 6 and 24 will output 4.
Since you're going to be rounded down to the nearest integer member you have to do this without using
the square root function.
As far as requirements go.
Feel free to code this out either in Jupiter notebook or an idea of your choice.
But as always it's recommended that use paper and pencil or white board to simulate a real interview
setting.
All right.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture