Hello everyone and welcome to lecture on the Knights tour problem.
So in this section in this lecture we're going to explain the Knight's Tour problem with that puzzle
is we're going to see if we can use graphs to set up the solution.
We'll view a solution in Python and then continue on to get a more general of the depth first search
.
Now just keep in mind as far as the breadth first search and depth first search so be EF-S and DFS in
the previous lectures we saw some basic puzzle that word ladder puzzle as just an introduction to an
idea.
Why would you want to have FS in this lecture going to see the Knight's Tour graph problem as an idea
of why we need DFS after this lecture and the next one we're actually going to do is have three lectures
in a row where we fully code out and do a live code walk through explanation again of a graph implementation
in implementation of FS and an implementation of DFS.
So while you will see code as just an image throughout these slides.
Keep in mind that we're actually going to live code all the algorithms in the graph overview again later
on in the section of the Course here.
So don't worry about having to code everything that you see right now.
This is just basically to give you some ideas of why we need the FS.
So let's go ahead and continue on.
So what is the Knight's Tour puzzle.
Well the nice tour puzzle is played on a chessboard of a single chess piece the night and the object
of the puzzle is to find the sequence of moves that allow the night to visit every square in the board
exactly once.
Now you don't need to know too much about chess to get this puzzle but what we're going to do is solve
the problem using two main steps.
One is to represent the legal moves of a knight on a chess board as a graph and then we can use a graph
algorithm to find the path of length rows Times columns just minus one where every vertex on that graph
is visited exactly once.
So let's go ahead and check this out.
So in case you're not super familiar of chess a chess again is an 8 by 8 board.
This is just a subsection of that board.
And you have this night and the night piece can move in an L fashion.
So all the dots here are legal moves for the night so you'll see has here is an L.
So three and then 1 3 than 1 3 1 and that's how the night can move.
So those are all the legal moves for the night.
In this particular subsection of the board and you can see that we can represent this as a corresponding
graph.
So now we want to know really how we can build out this photograph and we can actually use that using
this function here the night graph function.
So this is going to do is the function makes one pass over the entire board and each square on the board
the night graph is going to call a helper function called generate legal moves or general legal moves
which is actually on the next slide if you want check that out same time.
But basically what it does it just creates a list of legal moves for that position on the board.
Then all the legal moves are then converted into edges in the grass.
Another helper function which is called position to note Dear POS to note Id converts a location on
the board in terms of a row and column into a linear vertex number similar to the vertex numbers shown
earlier in this slide.
And then if we just take a quick look at that generate legal moves function.
Basically what this does is it just takes the position of a knight on the board and generates each of
the eight possible moves.
And then it has another helper function.
Legal court her legal coordinate.
And it just makes sure that particular move that is generated is actually still on the board.
So you have board size here.
So eight buy or whatever you just want to make sure that the legal move doesn't bounce that night off
the actual chess board.
So again these are in the Jupiter note book that goes along with this lecture.
But don't worry too much about them.
It's just for this specific puzzle and we're going to do later on is actually generate or implement
I should say in Python a very specific DFS and b fs after these next two lectures.
So continuing on what you want to know all the possible board moves look like after you built the graph
it looks something like this.
And this is something we'll revisit later.
But this just shows a complete graph of all possible moves on an 8 by 8 board.
So there's exactly three hundred and thirty six edges in this graph.
And what you should notice is that the vertices corresponding to the edges of the board have fewer connections
.
Right.
Which are legal moves.
So for example these are the vertices of the edge of the bore that have less legal moves which makes
sense because your knight would then bounce off the board so you can only really do two legal moves
from the corner which makes sense and once again you can see how sparse the graphics of the graph is
fully connected.
Excuse me if the graph was fully connected meaning every node was fully connected to every other node
.
Thirty four thousand ninety six edges.
Well there's actually only three six edges.
That means if we were to try to use an adjacency matrix to fill out this graph or represent the scrap
it only be about 8 percent for.
So definitely for larger graphs the adjacency list is a way to go.
So it's just a little reminder and throwback to that old lesson we had so continue here.
We're going to do the search algorithm.
We're going to use to solve the Knight's Tour problem is called depth first search or DFS and whereas
DFS algorithm discussed in the previous section builds a search tree one level at a time.
The DFS algorithm will create a search tree by exploring one branch of the tree as deeply as possible
.
So in this section again we're going to look at two algorithms that implement that that first search
the first group we're really like is directed really particularly to this specific puzzle the night
store problem and it explicitly forbids a note to be visited more than once which is exactly what the
Knights for a puzzle was right.
We wanted to visit every board exactly every position on the board exactly once as a night.
Later on we're going to discuss a more general DFS which will do in the next lecture.
So the first exploration of the graph is exactly what we need in order to find that path that has exactly
63 edges.
We're going to need to we will see that when the first search algorithm finds a dead end which is a
place in the graph where there are no more moves possible.
It's going to go back up the treats.
Next step is vertex that allows it to make a legal move.
And this is for that particular algorithm for solving the Knights top puzzle.
So the tour function is actually here on the next slide.
But it's going to take four parameters and which is the current depth in the search tree takes some
path a list of vertices visited up to this point you which is the vertex and the graph which to wish
to explore and then limit which is the number of nodes in the path and that we should note that the
night tour function in this case is recursive.
So let's go ahead and explore it here a little further and that.
So you'll notice what happens is that our function again is using colors to keep track of which vertices
in the graph have been visited.
So unvisited overseas are colored whites and visited vertices are colored gray.
And again if all the neighbors of a particular vertex have been explored We have not yet reached our
goal length of 64 vertices and we've reached the dead end.
And when we reach that end we have to actually backtrack.
So backtracking happens when we returned from night tour that night tour a function of a status of falls
.
So if you return office that is a false from the nightwear function meaning done was never set equal
to true.
It means you have to backtrack and so in the first breath first search we use a Q to keep track of which
vertex to visit next.
And since that first search is recursive we're implicitly using a stack to help us for backtracking
.
So when we return from a call to the night tour have a status of false which happens in this line.
Right here we say Dunn is equal to that recursive call of night tour.
So when you return from a call tonight Torfi set us a false you're going to remain inside this wild
loop because you're saying and not done right and you're going to then look at the next vertex in that
neighbor list object which is right here.
And B our list more or less just a list of getting the connections.
So let's go ahead and look at a simple example of the night tour in action and I'm going to show you
some figures of what you can check out.
So let's go ahead and go jump to the figures and if you're in the if you downloaded this resource PowerPoint
presentation everything I just said is in the next couple of slides.
So we're going to go ahead and jump for it right here.
This snakes for example.
So we're going to do a start at node A and the nodes adjacent to A R B and D so we can see this is a
directed graph already and since B is before the alphabetically The first is going to select B to expand
next.
So let's go ahead and show that.
So we've selected B to expand next to and then exploring B happens when that night tour is called recursively
B is adjacent to C and D.
So the nightwear will elect to explore C next she'll be the next one.
So now we're exploring c.
However as you can see node C is a dead ends with no adjacent notes.
If you look at where the edges are pointing it doesn't point outwards from C.
So we've reached that end here.
So now that we've reached that and what we have to do is backtrack.
So we then do is set C back to white and the called The Night tour function will return a value of false
return from the recursive call.
Effectively backtracks the search to vertex B and the next for a Texan to the list to explore since
we read that C is going to be D.
So then we go ahead and explore D.
And we do that with the recursive call to know the name from vertex D on what the night function is
going to do is continue to make recursive calls until we get to nodes C again.
So make a call here e f hasn't been explored so we go to F and then finally we reached C..
And by this time the last time that we reached C but will notice is that and the marker is going to
be less than the limit meaning we've already exhausted all the nodes in the graph and that at this point
we can return true.
In the case that we've made a successful tour of the graph and we return the list the path it's going
to have the values A B D E F C which is the order we need to traverse the graph to visit each each node
exactly one time.
So what does that actually look like.
If you were to try to try it on a pipe it well it would look something like this so this is the path
that a knight would have to take in order to visit each part of the board exactly one time.
So there's actually many possible tours and some are actually symmetric and with some modification you
can actually make a circular towards that star and that the same square.
So there's many solutions to this problem but you can see that using a graph especially a recursive
searching algorithm to the graph is a great choice for trying to solve this puzzle.
So that's the basic idea.
Up next what we're going to do we've gotten this overview of that special use case.
We're going to try to discover what General that first search looks like and afterwards we're going
to do a full life code walkthrough of all the implementations of a graph breadth first search DFS and
then depth first search DFS.
OK.
Thanks everyone.
Go ahead and review this lecture.
But this is basically just to get you a general idea of what you can use this for.
All right.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.