Hello everyone and welcome to the implementation of a graph overview lecture.
So this sucks we're going to implement just a simple graph by focusing on the Node class and you can
refer to this lecture for the solution for the future interview problem where you're asked to implement
Siggraph.
Now keep in mind we've actually already implemented a graph earlier in the section of the course.
So if we really understood that and you felt comfortable with it we can go ahead and feel free to skip
this lecture.
But at this lecture it's going to implement the code and this Jupiter notebook and explain it along
the way where we have a graph that's directed and the edges can hold weights.
We have three classes a state class a node class and a graph class and we build it this way just because
sometimes in interviews they want you to fill out some code.
They saw a node instead of an edge.
So this will we're going to build out.
You'll notice that it's going to look really similar to what we did previously and we're going to take
advantage of two built in tools.
The order dictionary and enough for enumerate and they're basically going allow us to as far as to order
dictionary.
If we go ahead and zoom in here there's links to documentation at Jupiter notebook for you but the order
dictionary what it does.
Go ahead and look for it here.
Ordered Dick.
So in order dictionary does is basically allows you to run a dictionary but it also remembers the orders
that the keys were inserted in.
So you can imagine that's a pretty useful tool for building out your graph.
So it operates just like a dictionary.
Except that it also remembers the order that the keys were first inserted them.
OK.
And the other thing we're going to be taking advantage of is in room which is support for enumerations
and it's going to be a very basic class syntax so we're going to say enumerations created use that class
syntax and allows us to create really basic enumerations or we're going to use that for this state class
where we have visited visited and visiting one to three so we can call those instead of white black
and gray like we did in the lectures and you can see you can read more on the documentation how you
would actually grab this.
Basically you just say print a representation of color red and it would give you one for the enumeration
.
OK.
So let's go ahead and jump to implementing this.
So the first thing we're going to have to do is begin by starting up that state class.
So let's go in and say from each noom imports income and you notice you make it an area where you have
no module named in them.
If you do have that it means you're using Python 2 and you need to go ahead and install it.
So if you need to install it you can do that by running.
Exclamation mark Pip.
Install the NUM three four.
And if you done of Anaconda installation you should be able to run this.
So they just click shift enter and then wait for that finished to install.
So I'm going to go ahead and let them install so we can use the numerate for using Python 3.
You don't have to worry about this step.
This will work without the installation.
So looks like we've just finished installing it looks all good.
Then to go ahead and delete that before I do I want to make something clear.
I have an exclamation mark here so I can run this as a basically a command line prompt.
So you could also put this into your command line or your terminal.
So I'm going to put shift center here.
Run this again and I can see it works great.
So that's going to allow us to create this really basic enumeration or inherit from it and then say
other visitors will one visit is equal to and the teen is equal to three.
Now it really depends on your interview situation whether or not something of this detail is necessary
.
You have to fill out and ask your interviewer if they really want that level of detail.
But let's go ahead and then begin the Node class.
So we're going to initialize the node
we have self and then it's also going to take in.
We'll say and you am for.
And that's just going to be the number of that note.
Some people also like to call this like the ID so say selfness is equal to none.
So and they'll say self-taught visit States is equal to states thoughts unvisited and that's really
where we're making use of this.
So it starts off unvisited and now we can actually keep track whether it's been visited visiting or
visited.
So that's really actually really useful.
Again the really depends on your interview situation whether they want you to take that into account
that children gain extra points for thinking about it and they will say self-taught adjacent as the
adjacent nodes and also that equal to an order dictionary.
Now last time we were doing this we just set this equal to a normal dictionary.
Here we're going to take advantage of order dictionaries which you may find useful for the first DFS
search algorithms.
But in this case for order dictionary will set.
The key is going to be the node it will have that value be the weights of that Vertex that connects
and then one more thing I'm going to do is add a special Messen underscore underscore SDR underscore
underscore.
So if I want to print the note or return something in this case and it is going to return self-taught
numb basically the number of that node.
OK so there is or node class and now we just have to build out the graph.
So going to say class graph I'm going to say initialize it and Im going to initialize it with just self
and I say self-taught nodes is equal to an ordered dictionary and I should have pointed out earlier
that we need actually import this first for we run this.
So let's make sure we actually say.
From collections import ordered.
So make sure this all runs.
So we have that will continue on the node and going to make a method to add a node.
So basically adding a vertex excuse me a node to this graph
and I will say node is equal to
node so making a little temporary variable there and then I'm sitting self-taught knows that or a dictionary
at that no call to node then is going to return node that temporary variable there.
So notice how I'm not saying self-taught node here I call self-taught notes here so I can set that key
which is the node ID and the value.
So then I can just add an edge by saying self source destination and weights will set it equal to zero
.
So this should look extremely familiar.
If it doesnt make your review the first time we implemented the adjacency list but it should look extremely
familiar because last time we did this we had from two and then weight was also at zero.
Now this case will say if source not in self-taught nodes we will add that node
or that source and will say if the destination is not in self-taught nodes meaning its not in the graph
right now will say cells at a node destination.
So we did this exact same thing earlier when we were doing the adjacency list but basically what I was
saying is we're going to add an edge give it source notice destination note and the weight of the connection
between them have that edge and what's going to happen is if it's if the source isn't in there as it
is the destination is in there I add it once I have added them I'm just going to say self-taught notes
source adjacent.
And then this is where it gets a little tricky but what I'm going to say is that adjacent method so
if we scroll back up member we have dot adjacent which is that or a dictionary.
So I called that adjacent and I also then want to call self-taught nodes destination on it.
And so that equal to the weight.
OK.
And that should be it.
So let's make sure it works.
So called G is an instance of our graph.
And then we can add an edge to it.
So I go from 0 to 1 to 5.
Notice they didn't have to actually say add node because remember our add edge takes into account if
the source and destination nodes aren't already in there.
So we have that and then we can actually say go ahead and well just say that nodes get all the nodes
and there we have our ordered dictionary with zero and 1 nodes.
And if we go ahead and say add another edge if we wanted to we could say gee the add edge and we'll
go let's say from 1 to 2 for weight of 3 and that's fine too.
We look at our notes now.
Now we have 0 1 2.
OK.
So that's really all there is to it.
Again hopefully this felt a little familiar to you should have been some things that are really familiar
especially in those adding the edges adding nodes instead of the verdicts vertices et cetera.
So hopefully they all felt pretty familiar but that's just another way to implement a graph in Python
.
And it's a super common interview question and it is going to be one of your practice interview questions
So I really suggest that you review this lecture as well as the lecture.
We implemented the adjacency list.
All right.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.