Hello and welcome to the second on site question solution for the large search engine company a mock
interview.
So this question you had the reverse of your first one which was given a dice which rolls from 1 to
7.
Simulate 4:59.
In that case we just threw out anything above 5.
Here it's a little harder because you're never given a dice which throws 1 to 5.
Simulate a uniform seven sided dice.
All right.
Let's go ahead and think about this and walk through the solution here.
We're not going to be coding anything out live because it's actually a pretty simple idea.
Well let's go ahead and explain it.
So because the five sided dice can't produce seven possible outcomes on a single roll immediately we
know we have to roll the dice at least twice.
If we roll the dice twice then we have 25 possible combinations.
Five times five.
While 25 is not divisible by seven we know that 21 is.
So that means we can implement our previous strategy of throwing out rolls.
Not an intended range but it's also important to know that we can expand the solution to implement more
rules in order to not throw any out.
So for instance there's no number times 5 where excuse me no exponent of 5.
That will be divisible by seven.
No matter how high you go because they're both primes run right after the other.
So we'll needed to find a range of the section of the 25 possible combination of rolls.
So a good way to do this is by converting the two rolls into a unique outcome number in the range 1
through 25.
Then we can create this number by taking the rolls.
Then we take the first roll and after subtracting 1 from it we multiply it by 4.
Now the first roll corresponds with values between 1 and 20.
Then we take the second roll added to the result the first manipulation giving us a range from 1 to
25.
So let's go over that one more time.
Our main strategy is this.
We're going to roll the dice twice on the first roll.
We're going to multiply it.
Whatever value we get by 4.
So since the dice can roll between 1 and 5 1 5 1 to 5 times 4 gives us a corresponding range from 1
to 20.
Then we take that second dice roll it or roll the same dice again and add it to the result of the first
manipulation which would be 1 through 20 plus something 1 to 5.
And now we have a range from 1 to 25.
So our final solution is to roll the dice twice checked the manipulator range from 1 to 25.
And if it's greater than 21 just like within the last problem do it reroll.
So let's see how this would look like coded out.
We have a function which produces that random integer between 1 and 5.
So dice 5 returns a random integer between 1 and 5.
Now we have a conversion function.
So we have a while true and this is so we constantly keep rerolling.
If we roll out of range then we roll the dice twice.
We'll call roll one our first roll roll to our second rule.
All right.
I have a print statement here that you can check out yourself.
It's commented out but this may help you understand what we're actually doing.
Then we're going to convert these two rolls into something on the range of 1 to 25.
So how do we do that.
We can take our first roll value so Track 1 from it and then multiply that by five.
That gives us a range from 1 to 20.
Then we're going to roll the second dice once and that automatically gives you range from 1 to 5.
And then you can print that converted range by summing them together 1 to 25.
So here you have 1 through 5 and here you actually have zero through 20 excuse me because if you're
all a one you can subtract one from it in zero times five at zero.
So this portion on your first roll is converted to a number that falls between 0 and 20.
And this one it gets converted to a number that falls between 1 and 5.
Summing those together you have a range of 1 to 25.
Since we're only considering 6:59 simulation will say if the number is greater than 21 reroll just like
we did in the last one and then we can finally just use mod 7 plus 1 to get that conversion since 1
321 is evenly divisible.
Or excuse me since 21 is evenly divisible by 7.
Can just made by 7 and add 1.
So basically break up 1 through 21 into chunks.
OK.
So make sure you check out this solution.
It helps if you write it out by hand or add a print statements in here.
But that's really all there is to it.
All right.
Make sure you review it and understand it and I'll see what the next solution.
Thanks everyone.