In this section,
we're going to review how to create a custom inbound channel adapter.
As I mentioned in the previous section,
inbound channel adapters use a MessageSource,
and we have three options for creating our own custom MessageSource.
We can implement one using a Lambda expression in our configuration class,
we can directly implement the MessageSource interface,
or we can extend the AbstractMessageSource class.
To build a MessageSource using a Lambda expression,
we first define a MessageSource Bean with an
InboundChannelAdaptor annotation that includes a poller.
For the method body,
we create a new Lambda expression that accepts no
arguments and returns a message.
In this example, you can see that we create a list of reservations,
add two reservations to the list,
and return the list as the payload of a message.
This is the simplest way of building a MessageSource,
but it isn't very reusable.
The more robust way of building a MessageSource is to
extend the AbstractMessageSource class,
especially if we want to build a reusable component.
The reason is that it provides support out of the box
for Spring's lifecycle management, so classes that extend it,
such as the AmqpMessageSource, JDBC polling channel adaptor,
and MongoDbMessageSource that we've seen in previous modules become
first‑class citizens in the Spring Integration ecosystem.
To create a custom MessageSource,
we create a class that extends the AbstractMessageSource class and
provide an implementation of the doReceive() method.
In this case,
the DirectoryMonitorMessageSource extends the AbstractMessageSource class,
specifying that it can manage any object.
We specify that it reads an object rather than a reservation,
because we're going to make it generic.
When we create it, we'll specify the directory to read from
and the entity class to which we want the files in that
directory to be deserialized.
In the doReceive() method, we list all files in the specified directory,
use Jackson to deserialize them into a specific entity class,
and then add them to a list of results.
We then package that list of results into the payload of a message and return
it back to the inbound channel adapter that invoked it.
As I mentioned in the previous section,
outbound channel adapters use a MessageHandler annotated with a
service activator that invokes the handler whenever a message
arrives on the specified channel.
Again, we can implement our functionality by using a Lambda expression,
by implementing the MessageHandler interface,
or by extending the AbstractMessageHandler class.
To build a MessageHandler using a Lambda expression,
we define a MessageHandler Bean annotated with a
ServiceActivator that listens on a specific channel.
For the message body,
we define a Lambda expression that accepts a message and
performs some business logic with that message.
Because it provides more robust support and is more reusable,
we're going to opt to extend the AbstractMessageHandler class for our example.
The DirectoryMonitorMessageHandler extends the AbstractMessageHandler
class and overrides the handleMessageInternal method.
The implementation is pretty simple.
It generates a random UUID for a file name and serializes the message
payload to that file using a Jackson objectMapper.
So let's dive into the code and see this in action.
We'll begin by building our application.
First, we'll build our DirectoryMonitorMessageSource that will scan a directory,
read files from that directory, and publish them to a channel.
Then we'll build our DirectoryMonitorMessageHandler that will
receive a message and write its payload to a file.
We'll set up our configuration classes to use the new
MessageSource and MessageHandler.
And finally, we'll build our reservation listener and reservation service. Then we'll run the application and validate the results.