In this module, we reviewed how Spring integration works with Apache Kafka.
First,
we saw that Apache Kafka is a publish‑subscribe based
durable distributed streaming platform.
It was designed to support massive scale streaming to be able to
handle things like page clicks on massive websites,
and it makes a wonderful message broker.
We saw how the KafkaMessageSource was used in the
role of an inbound channel adapter,
and the KafkaProducerMessageHandler served the role
of an outbound channel adapter.
We saw that the KafkaInboundGateway provided inbound gateway support,
and the KafkaProducerMessageHandler served the role of the outbound gateway.
The KafkaProducerMessageHandler supports outbound
channel adapters and outbound gateways,
with the difference being the type of Kafka template that's
used, a standard Kafka template in the case of an outbound
channel adapter and a replying Kafka template in the case of an
outbound gateway. At this point,
you should understand what Apache Kafka is and what it does.
You should understand how to integrate Apache Kafka was Spring integration
applications using both inbound and outbound channel adapters and inbound
and outbound gateways. And most importantly,
you should feel comfortable integrating Apache Kafka into
your own Spring integration applications.
Next up,
we're going to review how to integrate databases into our Spring integration applications.