Hi.
My name is Danny Jesse, and I would like to welcome you to this
module, data protection with Amazon Macie.
Let's learn a little more about this unique service that
uses machine learning to classify,
secure, and protect sensitive data stored in S3. Amazon Macie is a
security service that protects your data by analyzing S3 buckets and
their contents for sensitive information.
And this sensitive data can take the form of personally
identifiable information, or PII, which includes things like
credit card numbers and social security numbers,
which might be found in the contents of an S3 bucket, and of course,
you may have a perfectly valid reason for storing this data in S3,
but Macie will make sure you know about it.
Macie will also ensure you are implementing S3 security best practices,
such as having default,
encryption enabled and public access turned off at the bucket level.
You can also configure and schedule jobs in Macie to scan
the contents of objects stored in S3, including text files,
code and script files,
Microsoft Office products, and even RDS snapshots stored in
Apache Parquet format. Macie can further be customized to use
any kind of regular expression to match sensitive content that
might exist within your data.
And if you aren't familiar with regular expressions,
think of them as a way to specify a particular string of text or pattern that
can be matched within a document or larger text string.
So there are the obvious regular expressions for things like phone numbers,
social security numbers,
credit card numbers, and even things like AWS secret keys, but if
you can define your own custom text patterns for sensitive data
that are valuable to your organization,
such as employee numbers or user IDs, you can configure Macie to scan for it.
Macie will then generate alerts based on what it
discovers using CloudWatch events.
And later in this module,
I'll show you how we can automatically notify administrators about Macie's
data security findings or even execute a lambda function to quickly automate
the remediation of any issues Macie discovers.
So let's see this whole process in action starting with setting up Macie in the AWS console.