In this demo,
we will enable Cross‑Region Replication between S3 buckets in different regions.
We will also examine the JSON policy for the IAM role
permissions that are required to support replication.
So here we are in S3, and you see the bucket we created earlier in
this course, and it's in the us‑east‑1 region.
Remember that we enabled default encryption on this bucket with SSE S3 as well.
But first I'm going to create another bucket in a different region
so we can demonstrate Cross‑Region Replication.
So I'll come over here to Create bucket, and we'll call this bucket
awscoursereplicationbucket, and we'll put this bucket in the us‑west‑1
region, and now that we've created that,
I'll choose the bucket I created earlier in this course, and up here,
I'll go to Management, and on this screen,
I'll select Replication, and now I'll click Get started.
So you'll see the first thing it's telling me here is that I
need to enable versioning on the bucket,
which fortunately I can do just by clicking this button here, and now I
can choose to replicate the entire bucket, so that's anything added or
updated in the bucket from this point forward, but it won't replicate any
existing items that are already in the bucket, and here you see I have
the option of also replicating objects encrypted with KMS. So when I
check this here,
you'll see it selects the keys from my account in this bucket's region.
So anything encrypted with either mycmk or the default S3 key can first be
decrypted using those keys in the source region before it gets replicated to
the destination region and re‑encrypted there with a key stored in that
region, and I'll go ahead and click next,
and you see here that my destination bucket could be in
this account or another AWS account.
But I'll go ahead and choose my replication bucket here, and you'll see
I also need to enable versioning on that bucket, and here now I can
choose my KMS key from the destination region.
So I don't have any of my own CMKs in us‑west‑1,
but I can choose the aws/s3 key here,
and that will be the key that is used to encrypt any
objects replicated to this bucket, and I'll go ahead and click Next.
Now if I already had an IAM role with the appropriate
permissions as we discussed earlier,
I could choose that here or just have a new one created, so I'll go
ahead and choose Create new role, and I'll give the rule a name and
make sure it's enabled, and click Save.
So here you'll see the name of the IAM role that was created for us, but
what I really want to do here is go through the JSON policy for this IAM
role, and walk through what it's doing. So I could drill in through the
console to IAM, and find this new role and look at the associated policy
document for it, but just like the sample key policy we looked at earlier
in this course,
the policy consists of a long series of statements, so I think
it's easier to break it down statement by statement here and show
you what it's doing; and if we follow the effect action resource
pattern like we did before,
we see this role is allowing S3 to call the list bucket operation, as
well as a bunch of get operations on my source bucket.
So this allows us to get the version of the object that needs to be
replicated, along with its ACL and any tags, retention properties,
etc. Then jumping over to the next statement, we see we're
going to allow these replicate actions on our destination
bucket, and here we have a condition.
So where the object is encrypted using kms or AES256, which is
SSES3, and where the key ID we specify here exists in the
destination region, and then this next statement allows S3 to
perform the decrypt operation on items from our source bucket; and
here you see a ViaService condition.
So when the request is coming from S3 in the us‑east‑1 region,
which in this case is our source region, we can decrypt the items from our
source bucket using these keys from us‑east‑1, and finally,
this last statement allows S3 to perform the encrypt operation on
items in our destination bucket, and again with the ViaService
condition to say when the request is coming from S3 in our destination
region, us‑west‑1, for our destination bucket using the key we
specified in us‑west‑1. So again,
I encourage you to go through the JSON policy documents for your IAM
roles in detail, because it will be very helpful as you prepare to
take the exam to see exactly what kinds of policies AWS generates to
support these kinds of operations.
Now that we've enabled replication, let's go ahead and see it in action.
So I'll go back to my source bucket here and click Upload,
and I'll pick a random text file here and click Upload, and remember,
we have default encryption enabled on this bucket.
So you'll see if I go over here, and here you'll see the
file's replication status is already completed,
so this file has already been replicated.
But down here, you see we have the AES256 encryption on this file.
So now let's go into our destination bucket, and here's the file we just
uploaded to us‑east‑1 sitting in our destination bucket replicated in
us‑west‑1, and here you see its replication status is replica, and there's
the AES256 encryption on this file as well.
So remember, to get this object replicated, our IAM role
permissions allowed S3 to decrypt it in the source bucket
using the S3 key in the source region.
Then the data was encrypted in transit as it was sent to the
destination region, and then it was finally re‑encrypted in the
destination bucket using the S3 key from the destination region; and
all of that happened in the blink of an eye. So that's Cross‑Region Replication with S3.