Let's wrap up this module with a brief discussion about CloudHSM.
CloudHSM might appear on your exam,
but there probably won't be any in‑depth questions about it.
Now as you saw in the demo, when we created our CMK,
we were given the option to use CloudHSM as the source of our key material.
So CloudHSM is a cloud‑based hardware security module.
Now keep in mind that KMS is also backed by hardware security modules,
but those HSMs are multitenant, which means,
of course, that they are shared by many different users.
So let's say you have a compliance requirement that says
you must use your own dedicated HSM.
In that case, you're going to want to use CloudHSM.
CloudHSM is single tenant,
which means it belongs exclusively to you and it sits in your VPC
along with your EC2 instances and anything else you put there. So
you can configure a CloudHSM cluster that spans multiple
availability zones within your VPC to get high availability and you
pay an hourly price for it.
Let's take a quick look in the console, and I'll show you how to create a
CloudHSM cluster. So here in the console, let's go to CloudHSM and the first
thing we need to do here is create the cluster.
So for our cluster,
we need to select a VPC and some availability zones, so I'll just
choose my default VPC here, and obviously, we need to select at least
two availability zones for high availability.
So I'll just pick my default subnets in 1a and 1b here,
and we're going to create a new cluster by clicking Next.
We could add tags here,
but I'll just skip ahead and click Create cluster and this process takes a
few minutes so I'll go ahead and speed up the video here.
Now, once the cluster is created,
we need to initialize it. So I can click the cluster name here and
then click Initialize, and in order to initialize it,
I have to choose an AZ here in which to create the HSM.
So I'll just go ahead and choose one here and click Create,
and this process will take a few minutes as well.
So once the HSM is created, there are some additional steps here,
and this gets to be beyond the scope of what you need to know
for the exam, but from here you would need to initialize the
cluster and then activate it and you'll be good to go and then
to interact with your HSM, which includes administering users, generating keys,
etc, this all has to be done with the CloudHSM client software,
which is available as a download from AWS for Windows and Linux. So that's CloudHSM.