Hi everyone.
My name is Craig Golightly, and welcome to my course,
Spring Framework: Versioning Spring Data REST APIs.
I am a senior software consultant.
You may have heard that it's best to avoid any breaking changes in your
API, but what are your options when you can't avoid it?
Is there anything in Spring Data REST that can make it easier?
In this course, you'll explore several different API versioning strategies,
and we'll walk through a couple of implementations so you
can better understand your options.
Some of the major topics that we will cover include when you might need to
version your API, API versioning strategies, how to implement URI
versioning, and using a custom header for versioning.
By the end of this course,
you will be able to decide which versioning strategy makes
sense for you and effectively implement that strategy with
your Spring Data REST API.
Before beginning the course,
you should be familiar with Spring Data and REST APIs.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn about versioning
REST APIs with the Spring Framework: Versioning Spring Data REST APIs course, at Pluralsight.