Hi.
This is Craig Golightly, and welcome to Implementing URI Versioning.
We're going to review how Spring makes it very easy to add a
version to your URI with a single property.
We'll also look at what you need to do to configure any
endpoints that are not managed by Spring Data,
so they also get version information in the URI.
Finally,
we'll review different deployment and management approaches for
supporting multiple versions and go through a demo of running two
versions of your API at the same time.
First off,
let's talk about the one line of code that's going to save you a lot of
time and headache. The spring.data.rest.basePath property automatically
adds whatever value you put to the base of the URI path for all of the
Spring Data‑managed endpoints.
You'll add this in your application.properties file.
For example, if you had an Employee entity, Spring Data maps it to /employees.
Once you add this property with /v2, then the endpoint automatically
becomes /v2/employees. Be aware that the base path is only automatically
applied to Spring Data‑managed endpoints. For any other classes or methods
with a request mapping that you want to have the base path added to their
URI, you'll need to include the @BasePathAwareController annotation on the
class, or else the endpoint will only be mapped to whatever is in
@RequestMapping.
For example,
the getSchedule method in this class will always map to /schedule unless the
@BasePathAwareController annotation is added to the class, then it would map to /v2/schedule if the basePath property is set to /v2.