Hi. This is Craig Golightly, and welcome to Spring
Framework: Versioning Spring Data REST APIs.
So why would you need to version an API?
The number one reason that you would need versioning
is to introduce breaking changes.
A breaking change would be something that used to work in the old version
of the API that no longer works in the new version,
or that requires some modification by the client in order to continue working.
Trying to coordinate an API rollout with a breaking change among
many organizations that consume your API is a very slow and error
prone process. Versioning allows you to roll out the new changes
while still supporting the existing functionality in a way that is
clear to your consumers.
They will know what functionality exists, in which version of the API, and
what they need to do to use that version of the API.
Let's take a look at the types of changes you can make to your API and the
effect those changes have on your consumer from low impact to high impact.
Whenever possible, you want to make your changes backwards compatible so that
they don't break existing functionality.
This has little to no impact on existing customers except
hopefully fixing bugs and adding new features.
APIs can often go for quite some time and never need to introduce a break in
change, so versioning becomes unnecessary. When there are changes that need to
be introduced that are going to break backwards compatibility, that is where
versioning can help ease the transition for consumers of your API, as well as
simplify your rollout process.
You can release the new version, then consumers can choose
to use the new version at their own pace.
There are other times when an API is just going to need a rewrite.
Many major APIs have gone through this where the
service expands in unexpected ways,
and the only solution to really address all of the requirements is
with a completely new structure for the API.
In these cases,
the solution requires more than just a new version of the API, but instead it's a rewrite, resulting in an entirely new API.