Let's take a look at a sample Spring Data REST API and see
what a non‑breaking change looks like,
what a breaking change looks like, and when you might
need to just overhaul your API.
Here's a simple Spring Data REST API project that we can use to
examine some different types of changes that might be made to an API
and where versioning would become necessary.
This particular project is a Spring Boot application with a simple
Employee entity that has a name and a title,
and I've set up an EmployeeRepository using an H2 in‑memory
database to persist the Employee entity.
There's also an example service that returns a message about a schedule.
Let's start up the employee application and hit some of these endpoints.
Here's a few requests that we can run to see what the API does.
First,
let's get a list of employees. Notice how currently there are no employees.
Schedule simply returns the static message that's in the method. Your schedule
is Monday through Wednesday 9‑9. And to add an employee, we'll simply post a
name and title to the employees endpoint.
If we go back and list employees again, we'll see the one that we just added.
And there it is in the employees array with the name and title that we gave it.
We can also just put any of these URIs in a normal browser and see
the data that's currently in the H2 database.
Suppose we made a few changes to the API. For example,
in the ExampleService, we changed the message to be Monday through Friday,
9‑5, instead of Monday through Wednesday, 9‑9.
This is an example of a non‑breaking change.
The client can still call the schedule endpoint, the same as they did before,
and they're still going to get back a string, it's just going to have a
slightly different value. Over in the Employee class, a department
attribute was added with the @NotNull annotation,
meaning that a value is required in order to create the entity.
This is an example of a breaking change.
Clients that used to call the employee endpoint and pass
a name and title will no longer work.
They'll now have to pass name,
title, and department in order to create an employee.
Let's start up the application with these changes to see exactly what
happens. When we hit the schedule endpoint, we can see the new value,
Your schedule is Monday through Friday, 9‑5.
When we call GET on employees for the first time, it's empty again.
Let's go ahead and try to create an employee the same way that we did before.
Notice that we get an internal server error.
It can't commit the new employee because we haven't
included the required attribute of department.
If we modify our POST to include a value for the department attribute,
then it works.
We'll list the employees and see the employee that was created, now with
the department attribute. For this breaking change, versioning would allow
people who were calling it the old way to continue for a certain amount of
time while the new way was available and ready to start using. Suppose you
decided that you didn't want to track employees anymore, you wanted to
track machines.
This is an example where an overhaul of the API would be necessary.
You wouldn't need another version that still had all of the employee
information, you would simply create a new API to track the machines.
In this example, the new API would have a different URI, machines,
and accept different content.
Let's go ahead and add a machine,
then verify that it was added. So if adding a version doesn't
really seem to make sense because you're not carrying over
existing functionality or data, don't worry, you're not the first, and you probably won't be the last to have to completely redo the API.