When managing API versions, try to group breaking changes into a single release.
Releasing versioned APIs isn't something you want to be doing
on a frequent basis due to the overhead of managing the
versions and getting clients to change.
Typically,
you'll only release major versions like v1 and v2. Using minor versions
like 1.1 and 1.2 implies a more frequent release schedule than you'll
want to do and may confuse clients as minor versions typically do not
contain breaking changes. For API versioning, the only reason to ever
version is because of a breaking change, so stick with major,
single‑digit versions.
When you release a new version, set an end‑of‑life date for the previous version.
This will vary based on your application,
but it should be long enough for consumers to
reasonably switch to the new version,
but short enough that you don't add unnecessary overhead,
supporting the old version longer than you have to.
When you make a breaking change to an entity,
you need to think through what that means for your clients.
Are you going to need to migrate your back‑end data from one
version to the next? What coordination is required for a
client to switch to a new version?
Generally,
you don't want to allow clients to use both the old
and the new version concurrently,
they can use the old version until they are ready
to switch, but once they switch, they will stay with the new version.
Depending on your datastore,
you could set up automatic forward syncing of their
data so that when they switch, it's all ready to go.
But trying to do a two‑way sync from old to new and new to
old is going to be more complicated and error prone and
should be avoided whenever possible.
Spring is an opinionated framework. In general, it's going to
save you the most time and make things easiest for you if you
follow those opinionated conventions.
Spring Data makes working with entities extremely easy,
but it assumes one version of the entity and uses the
class name for endpoint mapping.
If you start trying to create multiple concurrent versions of an
entity by appending v1 or v2 to class names,
you're getting away from the intended use.
Also,
if you find yourself starting to create classes with all of the built‑in Spring
Data CRUD and query methods written out so you can assign paths to all of them,
you're definitely going away from the intended use case and creating a lot more
maintenance for yourself going forward.
There are many things you can do in Spring, or JPA for
that matter, but for this course,
we're going to focus on how to handle versioning in a way that
maximizes what the framework can automatically do for you.
An easy way to implement URI versioning in your Spring Data REST
API is to leverage source control branching and a load balancer
or proxy server in your deployment.
When you're ready to make a version 2 of your API, first create a
branch for version 1 so that you can continue to bug fix and
independently deploy that version of the API.
You can then make your breaking changes and build version 2.
Both versions of the application are then deployed
behind a load balancer or proxy server,
which will look for v1 or v2 in the URI path, then route the
traffic to the appropriate deployment.
Creating an artifact per version helps avoid mixing up what is supposed
to be in which version of the application, so you don't accidentally add
a breaking change to the old version of API.
If there are bug fixes,
you can easily port those from the new version to the old version with
something like cherry‑pick if you're using Git. Leveraging tools like source
control branching and a load balancer or proxy server helps remove
undifferentiated heavy lifting from your application code and allows you to
focus in on the unique value add of your application.
The result is a repeatable pattern that allows you to follow
spring conventions and maintain a cleaner code base as you move through different versions of your API.