Let's go through an implementation following the strategies
we just talked about. We'll add some additional properties to
make the app production ready,
then create a branch for v1 and make the breaking changes for v2.
We'll deploy both versions to a server and set up a load balancer to
route traffic to the appropriate application based on the version in
the URI. Finally, we'll go through what fixing a bug in version 1
looks like and see how easy it is to build and deploy updates to your
application.
Let's go through an add a few things to get our application
ready to run in a production environment with a load balancer
or proxy server in front of it.
First, we'll add Spring Boot Actuator to the POM.
This will allow us to have a health check so that the load balancer or
proxy knows that it's a healthy running instance.
Next, we'll define a few other properties in our
application.properties file. We'll specify the port for clarity
and will enable only the health check endpoint.
Now when we start up the application,
we can hit the application at the health endpoint and get a response if
it is up. When we hit the actuator health endpoint,
we get a status: UP message. At this point, version 1 is good
to go, so we'll package it up as an executable JAR to be able
to transfer over to our server.
I'm running Maven,
so I'll do a quick package command, and this will build the employee‑1.0.0.jar.
When I transfer this up to the server,
I'll go ahead and run the command, and version 1 will be running on port 8080.
We can hit the health endpoint on the server to confirm
that the application is up and running.
Sure enough, it's up.
At this point,
I'm going to go ahead and create a branch called uriv1 to
preserve the state of version 1 of the application that is
currently running in production.
This will have all the information of what we just did, so if I need to
go back and do any bug fixes or anything like that,
I can switch to this branch and make those changes in isolation.
This also makes it easy to automate deployments of version 1
and not get anything mixed up with version 2.
I'll go ahead and switch back to the master branch to
make the changes for version 2.
First,
we'll change the artifact from version 1 to version 2,
so when we deploy to the server, we can tell the difference.
Next,
we'll change the base URI from v1 to v2, and we'll also go ahead and change the
server port so that we can deploy both of these on the same machines. In the
Employee entity, we've added another property called department and modified the
constructor to handle that new property.
And just to make things interesting,
we'll make it required with the @NotNull attribute.
Let's go ahead and change the schedule as well. Instead of Monday to
Friday 9‑5, let's make it Monday to Wednesday 6‑6.
With those changes in place,
let's go ahead and build our 2.0 artifact and deploy it to the server.
We'll fire it up on the server.
Remember,
this will run on port 8081 because version 1.0.0 is running on port 8080.
We'll hit the health check, and version 2.0 is up.
At this point, we're not quite there yet.
We have two different versions running, and while we could go
ahead and hit the endpoints using v1 and v2,
we've got the problem that we're running on different ports.
If you deployed to different machines,
you could get around that, but we can do better than that with
the help of a load balancer or proxy server.
I'm using AWS for this example,
but the general principles could apply to any load balancer or proxy server.
I've defined application 1 and 2 so that the load balancer knows
what applications are running on what machine.
In this case,
both applications are running on the same machine, just on different ports.
In a production scenario,
you would have multiple machines if you needed high availability.
On the load balancer, it's listening on port 80, and I've defined
a couple of rules for that listener.
If the path has v1 in it, then it will forward to application v1.
This is our 1.0 JAR running on port 8080 on the instance. If the path
has v2 in it, then it will forward to application v2.
This is our 2.0 JAR running on port 8081 on the instance. Let's go
through and hit version 1 and version two through the load balancer
address on port 80. First, we'll check the schedule message and see the
version 1 schedule, Monday through Friday,
9‑5.
Next, let's hit the version 2 schedule,
and we can see the change, Monday through Wednesday,
6‑6.
We just started the app, so there are no employees yet,
so let's go ahead and add an employee.
We'll double check that it added correctly,
and we can see one employee with the correct information, craig, developer.
Now let's check out the v2 employees.
Nothing there yet. We'll add a v2 employee that must include the
department attribute, and verify that it was added.
We can see one element with the correct information, steve,
developer, in the research department.
Let's see what happens when we try to add a version 2
employee without the required attribute.
We get an error that it could not commit the transaction.
We're missing a required attribute.
If we add that back in,
then we can see that it was successful, and now we have two employees,
karina and steve.
With this simple example with only one entity,
you may not fully appreciate how easy Spring Data makes this for you.
This one property spring.data.rest.basePath, covers all of the entities. Here
we only had one Employee entity, but imagine if you had 50 entities. Would you
rather custom define all of the paths for all 50 of those or change one
property? Anywhere you do have custom services, simply adding the
@BasePathAwareController annotation to the class will add the base URI to all
of the request mappings in that class.
With this model, you can continue working on the 2.0 version in master,
then release and deploy as needed without touching version 1.0.
If you ever did need to create a bug fix in 1.0, it's as simple as switching
to the 1.0 branch, making the change, let's just make a simple change from
5‑9, change whatever you need to on the version,
or have your build do it for you, I'll just do 1.0.1, build the
artifact with the fix, deploy it to the server, then once it's up
and the health check is returning positive,
then we can hit it through the load balancer and see the change.
There's our bug fix, 9‑9. Again, we didn't have to touch version
2 at all, this was completely independent,
so you would only have to test version 1 of your API when you were making
changes to version 1. Way to go! You've seen how easy Spring makes it to
add a version to the URI. Just set the spring.data.rest.basePath property
in your application.properties file.
You've also seen how to incorporate that version into your
other endpoints that aren't managed by Spring Data by using the
@BasePathAwareController annotation.
We've covered strategies for managing API versions and deployment so you
can leverage tools like source control branching and load balancers or
proxy servers to simplify your application code and maximize the benefit
that Spring provides to you.
Join me in the next module where we will look at using a custom header for versioning your API.