Welcome back to the course on Tableau in front of us we see the dashboard the beautiful customer segmentation
dashboard that we created in the previous tutorials of this course.
And today we're going to be putting this dashboard into a storyline.
So just to remind you what we have here is a map of the United Kingdom and how a certain bank how its
customers are distributed across the different regions of the UK.
Also we have a distribution of the same customers by different balance bands.
So these are 10000 dollar bands or 10000 pound bands.
In this case the distribution of the customers by age so five year bands then we can control the bands
here if we like.
And as we click around they adjust.
And also we've got the gender distribution of our customers and the job classifications.
And once again this dashboard is full interactive.
We can click around.
We can see what is going on with the different demographics and that's why it's called a customer segmentation
dashboard.
So what we're going to do today is as we discuss we're going to put this dashboard into a storyline
and provide some insights a story tell the readers or the viewers the people we're going to be presenting
to tell them a story about this bank and its customers and how they differ from region to region.
However before we proceed with today's tutorial I'd like to ask you for a quick favor.
I know you've already brought this up before and if you have left to review thank you thank you so much.
However if you haven't I would really appreciate if you considered leaving a review for this course
it's very easy to do you just have to click this button up at the top and then in this window you just
select the number of stars you think the course deserves and perhaps type in some comments it would
really help you understand how you write the course and if it has met your expectations and also it'll
help other students who are considering taking this course to understand what to expect inside and whether
it's worth their while or not.
So I would really appreciate if you could do that for me today.
And now let's get on back with the show.
So how do we create a storyline.
Well the first thing we need to do is click this button at the bottom which says new story so we'll
do that.
And now you can see a new type of working space.
So it's not a worksheet or a dashboard.
It's a storyline.
What you can do here you can create anything and so but you can drag elements in here and are like a
dashboard you can drag worksheets and you can also drag dashboards into a storyline.
But the main difference is that you can only drag one item.
You can combine items here.
So since you drag a second item it automatically replaces the previous one.
And so here we can drag our dashboard in here.
You've got to pick what you want to drag into the storyline and then once you've added it.
So let's say if I want the map then I can add another point in my story line and add the gender and
then let's say I want the dispersion my balance that way I can create a story and talk through these
points one by one but in our case we will be working all the time before segmentation dashboard and
we'll just be showing different cuts of our member base in this storyline.
So let's go ahead and drag this segmentation dashboard in here and right away you can see it underneath
this storyline control panel.
So the first element or storyline will be the overall representation of our customers.
So it's kind of our customer base line and we want the user or the viewer to be able to see what the
bank looks overall in the whole of the United Kingdom as a here we need to add a caption.
And what we're going to type in is I've already got to prepare this bank's customer base line.
There we go.
That's done all we want to show our viewer at this stage.
Now we're going to create a new point and we're going to drag the segmentation dashboard in here as
well.
Now what we want to look at is the one of the regions of the U.K. and we're going to start off the largest
region or the region that has most customers for this bank.
It's the it's England.
So we'll just click on England here.
And as we discussed previously the insight that we want to convey here is that there's a lot of white
collar workers in this region predominantly they are represent this region.
The customers in this region are represented represented by white collar workers.
Perhaps that has something to do with London being the economic center of Europe.
So we're going to take a new caption and we'll keep it in here.
And it says England is mostly represented by white collar workers 70 percent.
That's all we wanted to show so when you do get to this point during a presentation what will happen
is you can start drilling into this dashboard if it is required.
So obviously you're talking about white collar workers you might want to click on it and then see how
the dashboard changes and perhaps look at what are the male white collar workers up to and look at their
representation by age bands and then look at their representation by in the higher and balances and
and so on.
So it's up to you once you get to this point but to start with to get you started or to create a Segway
between the previous slide and this slide you just need this little caption over here.
So now we're going to update that so it saves and instead of drawing a blank point we're going to duplicate
this chart and that'll save us the trouble of dragging the dashboard.
There we go.
So we've duplicated the tab and now we will look at Scotland and as we discussed here the age demographic
is completely different.
Much older customers the gender is also different predominantly males and the job classification more
blue collar and other very few white collar workers bank with this bank in Scotland.
So let's copula caption and see what it says.
The caption here is larger so if you move away you'll see this scroll box up here and now we can read
the caption says customers in Scotland are predominantly males in their late 40s and early 50s late
40s and early 50s.
Representation of white collar workers is low.
OK.
So that gives us some conversational topics so you might want to click on blue collar workers once you
open up this dashboard you'll see that 95 percent of them are actually male.
And so the other 44 percent.
These are mostly represented by females.
You might also want to look at the older demographics and see how their what their balances are distributed
like and so on.
So that is how or what we're going to convey for Scotland.
And at this point I'd like to show you another cool feature of Tableau and that is annotations.
Now it is a very simple feature and a lot of the time people get to learn it right away so you might
really know it.
But if you don't know.
Not a worry we'll look at it now it's very easy to use let's say on this chart.
I want to point out something specific that there is a lot of workers or customers in this region with
in the in their early 50s.
So between 50 and 55 years old what I want to do here is right click on this bar click annotate and
add a mark and we'll just keep the default for now.
So I'll just change a size to 10 because that's a bit too big.
And what you'll see is this arrow up here and this box with text which you can move around and it's
basically telling the reader some additional information.
So once you get to this picture so the slide you will see this annotation which I hadn't seen before.
And that is very powerful because it attracts their attention and also gives you some cues talking cues.
So what we're going to do is we're going to change the text here and we'll say high representation of
customers in early 50s maybe center of this.
So that's what we wanted maybe change in a bit.
So that word fits.
So that attracts attention and gets you can get to talking about this specific element of the customer
segmentation.
So the age groups you can definitely add them for other elements of your reservation so if you want
to talk about balances or gender or something else something that might not be obvious or something
that you really want to attract people's attention to then feel free free to add annotations.
So we'll just update that and we'll duplicate it again.
So now we're moving on to Wales and in Wales we obviously don't need this anymore so we can delete it.
And as you can see it's stayed here but it's deleted here now.
In Wales our man inside was the balances.
So here you can see something different to the overall baseline.
And we will see it even better if we change the balance group.
So we're going to justice parameter and change it to fifteen thousand dollar or pound bands.
And here you can see that it actually increases first and then drops off so if I'm click Wales in the
baseline you'll see that it always drops off like that for Wales at first increases.
And so let's type in our Inside for Wales the inside for Wales is going to be data for Wales shows an
above average representation of mid-sized balances.
There we go so we can update that and perhaps you can add another caption here so on it annotate Mark
and we'll say above average representation and here will say size 10.
And also centering it is a good idea sometimes so that's how we will deal with this region.
And once you're in here you can start clicking around and understanding what else is going on.
If you need to.
So once you click these balances for instance you see that the distribution by age changes so you can
tell how these people have an abnormal representation of balances what they are who they are and you
see that they are mostly in their early 30s.
They're mostly female and mostly white collar workers.
And finally let's move on to Northern Ireland.
So we're going to update that and we're going to duplicate.
And here we'll get rid of this caption and we will select Northern Ireland right away are inside here
was that earlier a younger age groups and predominantly female.
So let's copy that into our caption.
Here we typed in Northern Ireland is mostly represented by female customers in younger age groups update
that.
And there we go.
So that's all done we can add another annotation here but I will leave that up to you.
Another thing I wanted to show you is that here the parameters are independent.
So tattle has thought this through very well.
If you change the parameter control on this element of your storyline then it won't change on this element.
So even though it's the same dashboard we're dealing with ultimately the actual parameter controls are
independent.
So feel free to change them around and show exactly what you want in every single part of your of every
single region of the United Kingdom.
So you might want to show it like this.
In this particular case that is totally up to you.
So there we go.
Now what we see is a storyline.
So when you're presenting you can start with the UK then you can move on to England and Scotland then
Wales make some comments points and move on to Northern Ireland and conclude your presentation.
That is how to create storylines in tableau very new powerful feature.
Hope you enjoyed this tutorial and just as a reminder I would really appreciate if you could leave a
review.
It's very simple to do and it will take you 30 seconds and help me out a lot.
Thank you very much.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
And until then happy analyzing.