Hello and welcome back to the course on tableau.
And today we're talking about a new and exciting feature in Table 9 which is called the Data interpreter.
And as we discussed previously we already know that machine and human format for Diaries is a bit different.
So let's go ahead and have a look at how tablet can help us overcome these challenges that occur when
we're trying to import human like data into software like Tableau.
So first of all we're going to need our browser and in our browser we're going to go to super data sites
dot com slash tableau.
Scroll down to the bottom here at the bottom you can see a file which is called personal vehicle sales
global.
Let's go ahead and download that.
All right.
Saving that file.
That's good.
And now I'm going to open the folder.
There it is.
So is our file.
Personal vehicle sales lowball.
Just drag that into Excel.
And there we go.
So this is what our file looks like.
It's a report showing how the sales of vehicles personal vehicles have been growing or changing through
the past couple of years.
And so how many years do we have here.
Ten years.
And you can see here these numbers represent the total number of vehicles sold.
So these are not dollars.
These are actual numbers.
So for instance in Austria in 2014 there was about three hundred three thousand personal vehicles that
were sold.
And as you can see the format of this spreadsheet is very much oriented as humans and saying humans.
I'm not a robot.
It's very much oriented at us humans.
So here at the gray grade ones you can see these are approximate numbers.
So estimated figures here there's like a legend a little bit of a legend up there.
And right away you can see like there's a header as we discussed.
There's this top row scrolls along top five rows crawl along.
That's because it's easy for us to navigate that way.
What else.
So here we've got some totals for instance Europe or let's have a look at this one.
Laughter.
So the North American Free Trade Agreement.
That's Canada Mexico United States.
So you can see these totals which will obviously jump into our data and we don't want that then just
America the totals for the whole of America including NAFTA and the Central and South America.
And then there's like empty rows all over the place.
What else do we have here that's that can be a problem here.
We've got all the countries total often immaterial and some comments over here of stars.
You will also notice it took me I took me a while actually to figure that to see this one is that there
is hidden columns in here and you often forget about those superior and hide.
You'll see that there's actually three hidden columns here and that can also interfere with our data
input when we do start doing it.
So this is quite a challenging file as you can see for a machine to comprehend.
Let's go ahead and see how Tableau is going to handle it.
So I'm just going to close the file for now.
I don't actually.
I'll keep it open because we might need to have a look at it.
So I'm going to open up tableau tableau.
And here we've got a lot of beautiful spreadsheets or tabs and worksheets that we've been working on.
So we're going to go to connect in your file excel.
Here we've got the file personal vehicle sales global.
Open it up.
And right away we've got this preview at the bottom.
So let's zoom in a little bit.
We can see here that everything is completely mixed up.
So instead of the column names are like random or if one of two or three and then this one has a name
then it's some random names and some empty columns estimate figures that remember that piece of coal
color legend that we had one item that we've got the region's countries which are actually years or
so regions countries in this column in years in here as part of the data element so completely messed
up dates shouldn't be like that.
So what we're going to look at now is it is a tableau dot interpret it.
What it does is it allows Tableau to help you kind of understand what's going on and that all kind of
like it allows Tableau to be smart about what it can see in the data.
So here you can see a common saying that tableau dot interpreter might be able to help.
So why don't we go ahead and click turn on for that feature.
And so what happens now is the data is changed.
Now we've got regions countries as the name of this column which kind of sounds about right.
Names of these columns include both the year which is right.
So if we go back to our dataset here you'll see that the names of the columns are actually years but
also include a number which is not correct.
And then we've got some numbers it still has the totals which are which is not good but already a bit
better.
So let's try to understand what happened here.
What we're going to click on is this button here.
Review results once we click it.
A new spreadsheet is going to be open for us.
So this spreadsheet pops up.
Basically what it's showing us is it's got some descriptions here but the main tab that you want to
look at is the second tab and it's it's a description of what tableau saw.
So we're going to zoom in a little bit.
I'm gonna make this a bit wider so well that's a bit too wide.
Yes.
So what Tableau is telling us here is it's telling us what exactly it saw in the data.
So Tableau is saying all right these red ones so I can tableau completely ignore these white collar
white cells then these red cells as you can see here tableau saying that's a header I will look at that
as if it's a header.
And that's why in our data in our previous of our data we can see a combined date and the number because
tableau said OK.
So that's a header that's ahead I'll just combine the two combined combined combined combined.
And so that's how it created the header and then it's got these green cells which it considered to be
data which is quite correct to some extent some of these do have to be admitted because their totals.
And then as you can see it ignored the combatant end of this with this asterisks.
So that's a good start.
So we now know tableau can do a bit of work for us.
Let's help tableau out a little bit as well.
So I'm going to close that because we don't need that now.
We're going to close this as well we'll redo that in a second.
So what we're going to do now is we're going to adjust this file so it's so tableau can actually work
off it so it can do all the work for us but it can do definitely can do quite a lot of it.
So what we're going to do now to start off with is we obviously need to delete these totals because
they're the they're just remaining in our data and they're not being removed which is not good.
But before we delete them as soon as we delete the totals as you can imagine we will lose information
on.
So if I delete these rows like this we lost information on which region this was.
So this is Europe.
This is Europe new members we want to keep their information so we're going to add a column on the left
here.
So I basically pressed.
Control shift plus or you can just right click and insert.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to copy the region name here.
Go to copy it.
So this is just an example of how to quickly fix up your data before importing into into tableau Africa.
And then we don't need that.
So next week we're going to do is we need to obviously copy down remember we talked about this.
So we need to copy down the name of the region for these empty cells as well so you can just double
click and or copy until the next one or you can drag an old copy.
This is basic basic Excel stuff.
I like to do what I like to do as I like to select all myself that I need to copy including the top
one.
And then if you press control G on your keyboard and you go through then you click special and you go
to blank.
Okay.
And now you click enter this and then instead of pressing Enter you press console enter.
Then I'll do the whole job for you.
So as you can see Europe Europe Europe new members Russia after and so on.
So now all we have to do is control copy this and then I'll basically copy or paste values.
And now we don't have the formula we have values perfect.
And what that means is now we've got these copied.
Now we can get rid of these totals so we're going to control minus these.
So I'm basically deleting these rows with the totals.
So be careful here because there's some empty ones here South America there's another two.
There we go.
Destroy everything.
All right.
So that's all deleted.
Now we only have our countries and the region that they're from and of course the data over here.
And that's pretty much it.
You just have to obviously give this one a name so let's call it regions.
And he'll just leave countries.
All right.
So that's our file we fixed it up.
Doesn't even matter that we've got this empty row here.
Tabu will take care of the rest.
So let's go ahead and say that that saved.
Now open up tableau as well.
And we're going to go to excel.
Personal vehicle sales global.
There we go.
And once again problems.
So Tableau is it can see these empty empty columns it doesn't have all the names turn on dot interpreter
and voila.
Much better right away.
So this empty column is still here because I think there's like a value in one of the one of the rows.
So we're just gonna click it and click hide and perfect.
So now we can see the region the country the sales of the number of vehicles sold in that specific year
one second.
OK.
So that's good.
Now what we want to do is we want to review results.
Just have a look at what tableau did exactly.
There it is.
So if you go to to the second tab you'll see that this is the header for tableau which is correct.
Then from here onwards it's the daughter Rose.
So the first thing I was a bit concerned with is did it pick up this empty row as a row of data.
But in reality if we count the rows here there's 144.
And now if we go back to Tableau it will tell us that there is one hundred and forty four rows here
so it basically picked it up as a data row but because it was empty it completely ignored it.
And so that's how the data interpret and Tableau works it can definitely save you some time and because
it cuts out these headers for you it ignores black crows and so on.
It doesn't do all the work but at the same time it can help you can nudge you in the right direction
if you import data you check what the data interpreted looked at and saw and then and then you corrected
a little bit and then you send it send it back into tableau again then tableau can really help you out
and do the remaining groundwork for you so you can import the data into tableau in the next material.
We will look at another cool element of importing data and that will be pivoting data.
So that'll be fun.
And I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.