Hello and welcome back to of course and travel.
Previously we learned how to create custom territories through the group method.
Today we'll look at the second method you can use to create custom territories.
Let's have a quick look.
So I want to create a new map.
And this time is over dragging stage right away.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to apply the second method instantly.
So I'm going to select a sales region going to right click.
And what are we going to do is language which geographic roll.
Then I'll say I create from and select state here.
So as you can see sales region has now automatically jumped into this hierarchy of geographic roles
above state.
So let's quickly discuss what exactly happened there.
So if you go to the data source you'll see that apart from these two new calico fields so this is the
group and this is the return on marketing investment that we calculated previously.
You'll see that here.
You've got the sales region.
So what Tableau is doing when you're telling it to create a geographic role for sales region based on
state what is it's doing is it's looking at the data set and it's realizing that actually in this data
set even though sales region is not a recognized geographical role there's a geographical Rule named
state.
And every sales region is associated with a state or actually the other way around.
Every state is associated with for sales region.
So tableau can recognize that.
And then when you tell it to create a set a geographical role for sales region what it basically does
is it aggregates all of the states to the Associated sales region.
So it does that aggregation for you.
And then from there it will know that region 2 is a combination of Arizona Texas Washington Texas Kansas
and so on.
And so basically it does that's a hard calculation or hard work for you.
And in the end you've got two lovely sales regions which you can use as geographical or customer territories.
And let's have a look at that some back in the sheet now.
And what we have to do is I'm going to take sales region and I'm just simply going to drag it onto our
map.
And as you can see now if you zoom out you have we have just two dots because those are representing
our two sales regions.
And I can simply now change this to a field map.
Let me just hand this a little bit so that these blocks away or let's zoom back in so you can see that's
our field map.
And again we can just simply take this called uncontrolled drag it into color and we've achieved exactly
the same results so we can take our revenue right click put it in here average revenue average return
on marketing investment.
Our average average marketing spend.
If you're right click again and we can also put the sales region into our label.
There we go.
So as simple as that.
Now this second approach it might have seemed much quicker.
Just that's just because in the first approach we performed here we had to talk through it and it was
the first time we're talking about custom territories.
Now we already previewed to them and that's why it's so much quicker.
In reality I think that the first approach is simpler because you just select the objects on the map
and you put them into a group.
But the second approach is more versatile and it's more proper.
So you actually create this geographical roll so you can see in this situation we actually puts cells
region we created as a assigned it a geographical roll so in that sense it's more of a solid process
rather than just picking things out on a map.
You're actually assigning the geographical roll and then using it.
So both approaches are valid and depending on your circumstances and what exactly you're trying to create
you might choose one or the other.
Just remember about them and remember that this is a very powerful tool.
So it doesn't have to be states that you can be working with countries and you can put different countries
into geographical regions or you can be working with other existing geographical roles and then assign
their aggregations custom geographical roles so that can be a very very powerful feature as you can
see right away here we were able to create this resolution very quickly and perform some analytics around
it already.
So there we go.
Hope you enjoyed today's tutorial how to play around with that and I look forward to seeing you next
time.
Until then happy analyzing.