Hello and welcome back to the course on tableau.
And today we will be creating a scatter plot.
And we will also learn how to apply filters to multiple worksheets and her.
Finally we're going to create more than one worksheet in our tableau workbook so that's going to be
fun.
Let's get straight at it to start off with.
We've got this map here in front of us that we worked with last time and as you remember we have this
filter that we are applying to the maps so we are looking at one specific year rather than aggregating
across multiple years.
So let's just remember that.
And let's go ahead and create our second worksheet in this workbook.
So to create another worksheet you've got to click this button away here at the bottom which says new
worksheet.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Once you click that it creates a new worksheet and it's a good time now to rename a worksheet.
So you just double click on the worksheet name and he will say map of Europe.
And now if we double click on the second one we will say customer scatter plot.
OK.
So let's get ahead with our customers scatter plot.
So as you remember the first thing that we did in the previous tutorial was to make sure we're looking
at the right time period of our data because it is important to remember when or know when your daughter
includes multiple years or different time periods that you want to look at individually and because
that's a common mistake some times people create a dashboard and they forget to add the filter and there
instead of looking at every single year by itself they're looking at the sum for all of the years and
that might not be what they're intending or to see when they're designing the dashboard.
So once again what we can do is we can drag all the data into a filter select years and you know do
the same thing that we did last time but we're not going to do that because what we want to do is we
want to look at the same year across all of our worksheets and this is where we are.
So if we had many many more worksheets we wanted to look at the same year across all of them.
And so this is where we're going to learn how to apply a worksheet across many different or apply a
filter across many different worksheets.
So to start off with what we're going to do is we're going to add some data into this worksheet and
then we'll apply the filter and I'll explain in a minute why we're doing it in that order.
So let's say we want to look at some of sales and columns and we want to look at the sum of profit in
rows.
And so here what has happened is tableau has aggregated the total sum of sales for all of the years
all of the customers all the regions for everything and the sum of profit as well and now is just showing
one dot.
And as you remember if you want to disaggregated we can either go to analysis and we can uncheck aggregate
measures and then we'll be showing a dot for every single one.
Or let's just leave aggregate measures on.
We can just add some information into the detailed schedule granularity of the view and that way tableau
will automatically aggregate at that level of granularity.
So how about we add customer name into detail and right away we have a dot for every single customer.
So what we're going to do now is we will work with that work to create that filter across multiple worksheets.
So let's go to map of Europe.
And as you remember this filter that we have here on year what we're going to do now is we're going
to right click it and we will say apply to worksheets and we'll say all using this data source.
So that means any worksheet using this data source will automatically have this filter applied to it.
You can also select worksheets.
But I kind of recommend doing all using this data so unless you have a specific case when you need to
select specific worksheets.
So let's go ahead and use it on all the worksheets that are using this data source click that and right
away you can see that a database icon has appeared on the left or the filter meaning that is being applied
at the level of the data source.
So basically anywhere sheet that's using this data source will automatically have this filter applied.
And if we go to customers Caterpillar you will see right away that this filter has been applied here
already.
And if we're right click and we say that we would like to see a quick filter you will see the quick
filter on the left on the right here.
It hasn't been formatted so that's easy to fix customize show all value will just switch that off and
then we'll just change to the single value slider just like in the privacy.
So now if I change it if I go from 2014 2012 you'll see that this has changed as well.
Over here is change 2012.
Now if I go to 2011 and go back you will see that the filter has changed here as well.
So this is kind of a filter that's been applied to all worksheets which are using this data source.
Now you will find that if I go to these worksheets the new ones that currently are not using any data
source because there's no data on the in the workspace the filter has been applied and that's simply
because tableau doesn't know if this was worksheet is going to be using this data source or not.
Because eventually you might add another data source and I use that one and then that case the filter
won't be applied.
So as soon as you drag anything from this works from this data source onto the worksheet let's say number
of records and just drag it here you will see right away that the filter has been applied and that's
how filters across different worksheets work.
It's a very very handy feature and actually took me some time to find out about it and I used to just
apply separate work to separate filters through every worksheet and can be a nightmare when you have
like 20 or 30 whereas when you have when you use the work this filter is applied across worksheets.
It's very easy to make sure you're all of your worksheets are showing the right information for that
specific year or for that specific region or for whatever you're filtering on.
Very good.
In terms of consistency so let's go back to our customers scatter plot and continue creating it.
So what is this scatter plot currently showing us it is showing us the profit profitability of customers.
So basically based on the sales that we made to that customer what is the profit that we received in
return from that customer as well.
So let's make this scatter plot a little bit prettier because there's a lot of dots here and we can't
really country to say anything about the ones that are overlapping.
So what are we going to do is we're going to add some color and the color we're going to add is we're
going to look at our profit margin because in essence if you take a profit and divide by sales that
is your profit margin.
And so if we take profit margin which we calculate field which we create last time and we take you drag
it onto color you'll see that the shapes have been colored now.
Now we're going to change the type of shape.
So we'll just click a shape even though we don't have anything on shape right now.
We don't have a variable that controls a shape.
What we can do is we can change the shape ourselves.
So in this case we want the circles.
And like last time what we're going to do is we're going to change the color to red and blue we'll click
apply.
So next what we're going to do is change the size of these bubbles so if we go to size make them a bit
bigger.
Well that's obviously too big.
So maybe somewhere there.
Yeah that looks OK.
Maybe we'll also change the color in terms of levels.
So we'll go to edit colors and we'll say just like we did in the previous tutorial we'll say minus zero
point five is obese is already bad.
So my zero point five and zero point five is really good.
So apply.
OK.
So that's really looking better.
And now we've got a map of Europe.
We've got profitability of our customers and oh one more thing is because they do overlap here.
What we can do is we can go to color and then change the transparency.
So let's set it at 75 percent so now you can see the times when they overlap.
And once again this is already quite a good scatter plot that we've created so we can see how the customer
profitability changes from customer to customer.
And if we change the years you can see how the profile changes overall.
So here in 2013 you got some very unprofitable customers here you've got a bit of a different profile
more scattered.
And also if you need to do some investigations you can just put your mouse over a certain dot here and
I'll tell you exactly who that customer is what the profit is what the sales was what the profit margin
for that customer is for that given year.
So that is a very handy tool to have right away it can help you like somebody who's analyzing this.
The sales for the shop they can just go and say OK the mall the least profitable customers maybe maybe
something needs to be done there some customer service service or maybe those customers are purchasing
the wrong wrong products or something that.
And then you can look at the most profitable customers and maybe they should be included in a loyalty
program or something along those lines.
So that's how we create scatter plots in Tableau and in the next sartorial we will finally create our
very first dashboard and that will be super exciting.
So I look forward to seeing you then.
And until next I'm happy analyzing.