Hello and welcome back to the course on tableau.
And today we will start on the demographics segmentation of our member base of the member race of the
bank.
So what do we mean by that.
Well we want to see some visuals representing the gender of the members or the customers of the bank
the different types of professions there in the different age groups and so on.
So let's get started with that.
First thing we're going to do is we're going to change the name of this worksheet to map.
And then now we're going to create a new worksheet.
And let's not forget to constantly save our progress by pressing control S..
So here we're going to just create a very simple visualization which is going to be a pie chart.
So let's take gender and drag it into Tableau and number of records which we now know how to use drag
it into table as well as you can see now we have female and male and tells us exactly how many of each
gender they are in total in the bank.
And now we're going to change this to a pie chart.
Probably not the best way to change the pie chart.
Let's try this way.
So there we go.
If you use a show me functionality you get this pretty cheap pie chart.
Now you can make it a bit bigger if you like.
Maybe change the size.
Now what we're after is some labels here because we can see what's going on.
Well first of all probably change the colors will change the male to blue and female to pink.
So there intuitive.
And now we want some obviously some numbers in here.
And what are we going to do is take this some of a number of records and all this just take number of
records from the measures and we'll drag them into label and what we can see here is the total number
of males and females that were Bank of our bank.
We can change the format here just to see this little bit better and keep it consistent with this part
of the future dashboard.
So if this worksheet where everything is twelve and bold so we'll change that here.
But for a pie chart you're not all you're probably interested in the total number of the people or males
and females you want the percentages.
So how do we get percentages.
And this is where we start working we have table calculations.
It's a very powerful feature in Tableau and this is the first time we're introducing it.
So is going to be very helpful going forward for us to add a table calculation.
So basically tell us what is this number what percentage is this number of the total of what we see
here.
You can you just need to do one simple step.
You click on.
In this case the table coefficients going to be added to this field so we want to replace this field
with the table calculation.
So click on this dropdown here.
And so I'll probably move it a bit up.
So yeah we have more space.
So click on the dropdown here and select quick table calculation.
And here from the quick table calculation select percent of total.
And as soon as you select that these numbers have been replaced and you see this little triangle up
here on the actual measure.
So on the right there's this triangle.
It's indicating to you that there is a table calculation being performed here.
And if you go here you can see quick table calculation it's telling you which one has been selected
and it is percent of total as we selected it.
So now we want to format this again.
So we'll go to format and we'll change it from numbers to percentage and no decimal points.
And then you go.
So now instead of seeing the total number of males and the total number of females females we can see
what percentage they make up of the total of the segmentation that we've select the role in this case
the segmentation that's selected is the whole population of the bank.
And that's why we can see that this 54 and 46 percent and you will see what I mean by select segmentation
when we move on to creating the dashboard it will become more clear how by selecting different segments
of our bank these percentages will actually change.
So that is how you perform table calculations.
This is the most simple one.
It is called percentage of total you'll be using it quite a lot.
It's very handy to quickly change from absolute numbers to relative percentages.
And there are more table calculations and we will explore them further on down the track.
So that's all for today.
I look forward to seeing you next time and will then be analyzing.