Hello and welcome back to the course on Tableau.
In today's tutorial we will finally create our awesome visualization and get to that deriving those
insights.
But let's take a step back for a moment and look at what we've actually achieved.
So firstly we have been able to connect to a PDA file a read only static file and extract the data from
that obtained from an open source data provider.
We have been able to combine that with spatial data which we have is not available within tableau which
box and get the proper layout off each of these box in terms of their size and their form and also the
distribution around the city.
We've also managed to iron out a couple of data integrity issues which is of paramount importance.
And therefore this was no easy feat.
And such a valuable skill to have learned.
But let's get back to solving the business case.
All right.
We already have geometry on to our sheet.
Next we'll take the pork name and put that into detail.
And the reason for that is at the moment it is just showing one big polygon and we need to actually
break it up too so we can see where each of the different shapes starts and end.
So we can just do that by adding it to the detail tab.
Now next we can also just take the incidents and add that to color and make sure that that some of incidents.
And we know we want to just make it give it a bit more punch to it and let's use temperature diverging
from green to red and immediately we can see where the box or the more problematic box are.
I do think that the borders are creating a bit of a yellow effect here which we don't want.
So let's just go and take the the borders off and that looks much need to know we could even see their
much smaller box as well.
What we'll also do is just attack the city burrow.
Put that on to filter and we want to select all of them because this will allow us if we do show the
filter and let's just bring it over here it's also selected as a single dropdown.
But this will also allow us to navigate the city burrow by borough as you can see as we scroll through
then we can see what they look like now how it works in New York is that each city borough is funny
enough also a county with in this state.
So what we could do is we can just use them that layers and also just tick the county borders and that
would actually break them up quite nicely into different boroughs.
And on top of that we can select the county names but the county names funny enough is not exactly the
same as the borough names.
So for that reason we'll actually just antique them.
For instance if we look at Richmond over there.
That in case in case it's actually the Staten Island although it's called an already Staten Island so
what we'll do is we'll just to avoid any confusion.
We'll take off the county names and we can then just rename these using the alias and we can just update
these aliases.
So if we click alias over there we can take B update to Brooklyn then M2 man Hatton Q to Queens or to
Staten Island.
We know that refers to Richmond and then good old Bronx and hit in Tyrone.
Okay.
Now we are able to navigate city borough by city borough to see which parks have the most incidents
not seeing as we are able to they navigate to these areas.
Some of these parks have you know obviously their color is adapted to the number of incidents and this
is not correct.
We want to keep the same color rating across all of them.
So if we go into color and just edit this we can just fix the start and end because we know the maximum
is six and the minimum zero.
And we can just hit a block.
Now if we do go in again you can see that it's not that dark or red that used to be when we do in the.
That it was updated the color rating was updated for the specific focus or filter.
Let's also just update our sheet them over here because what we want to call this is the New York City
parks and we just want to put the borough name in there so we can just pick it up from the insert option
over there.
But the city borough and we can actually just make that bold and we can decrease the size to 24 for
both of these and just hits a plot.
So if we do navigate between now we are able to see which one we are working with right in the title
so handy stuff as well.
But I also like to do is in our map.
If you go into map options you are able to see the scale and obviously want to set this to us as we
working in the US.
So now you get a scale over there.
So if you are focusing on a specific area and you can see how it changes.
So on Staten Island the scale is one mile and in Queens it's two miles so it obviously depends on the
size of your visualization then you are able to relate on how far and how close each of these sections
or each of these Fox ought to each other.
Now you can also navigate the city by not only looking at this specific borough bar but just by zooming
in and then immediately you can see even the smaller box where there have more of a number of incidents.
So pretty handy stuff indeed.
So pretty cool way to navigate this as well.
And this also answers our brief that we've set out to do and I'm sure outline will be super happy with
what we are delivering now.
That is how you connect and combine PDX spatial falls clean your data import your data ensure data integrity
create custom geographic polygons using data sources from open source platforms.
Pretty awesome stuff indeed and you can be really proud of yourself.
Now in the next tutorial we'll be looking at a brand new business case and look at some improvements
in tableau relating to how we use tool tips and even look at a brand new chart type.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.