Well this is Carol from super dollar signs dot com.
And welcome back to the courts and tableau.
So what's up of the times we ask.
Well the thing is that I'm super excited about you taking this course.
In fact I am so excited that I really really want you to get to the end and get the maximum value out
of this course and learn how to use Tableau like a pro.
And so therefore I've challenged myself to get you enthusiastic about this course in under five minutes.
And that's exactly what we're going to do today.
And I'll just give you a quick overview.
We're going to look at a massive dataset and I will show you what you can do using the power of Tableau
in a very very short limiter of time.
And I hope you that'll get you excited.
All right let's get started.
First of all we'll need a browser I'm going to use Chrome.
And at the top just type in this in the address bar you need to go to super data science dot com slash
tableau.
And that's where all the data sets for this course are located.
And here you can get the one for today.
It's called the superstore us.
So just download that.
I'm going to save that into my tableau course folder.
That's good.
And let's bring up that folder so there is the dataset.
We don't need the browser anymore and we still have three minutes 45 seconds.
Let's open the data set and have a look.
So what this dataset represents is a list of transactions for a store for 2015 from the start of the
year until analysis for the first half of 2015.
And here you can see every single transaction the store has made for this year.
Aaron's average transaction is represented by a row here.
So for instance the row I.D. tells you the number of the transaction the discount unit price shipping
cost customarily a lot a lot of information.
And at the end here it's got the profit for this specific transaction.
So here for instance it's 4000 miles or minus fifty three dollars.
And it's also broken down in by column it says this is all United States and regions state or province
city.
And if you look at this dataset it's actually quite massive.
Is got one thousand nine hundred fifty three euros.
And the question has been asked is Can you quickly tell us what are the most profitable and the least
profitable states according to this data set and also plots a map right now create a map that will show
us very quickly how the states are performing and you have to do that in a very limited time in fact
in under two and a half minutes.
So let's get straight at it.
This is going to close the excel spreadsheet here close this folder and now I'm going to open Tableau
and we'll see how quickly we can do this.
Two minutes left continue.
OK.
So just follow my steps.
I won't explain every single step but through this course you will learn all of this and even more so
now we're going to connect to our data source over here on the left click Excel find your data set double
click on it it's opened up now.
Now on the left choose the orders tab and drag it into this white space and right away you can see a
preview of the spreadsheet appear in front of you.
Next click this orange button here which says sheet one.
And here you've got to Tableau workspace which right now is empty.
We need to put some stuff in here.
How much time.
One minute forty seconds okay.
Let's do this.
All right.
So what we're going to do is we're going to find country and we're going to drag it in the middle of
this whitespace here.
Oh look and map here while Tableau is quite smart.
Okay so now we're going to look for state or province and we are also going to drag it onto the map.
Oh well look at all these dots appeared in the different states of the US.
Okay.
So what are we going to do now.
We're going to take profit because we were asked about profitability and we're going to drag it onto
color.
And next we're going to take profit arrogant dragon also onto label.
Now we're going to click label and we're going to click the font and we're going to change the font
size to 12.
And that's it.
How much time do we have.
We have 58 seconds so that was all under four minutes.
And what we can we see here we can see that right away just by looking at this map.
It's so intuitive.
We didn't even have to specify any colors or anything.
Right away we can see the least profitable state that will the most losses that were incurred in North
Carolina Carolina.
And the most profitable state is California right away.
You can tell those things and also you can even give more insights according to the map.
These Southern states are not doing that well in this region except for maybe Georgia and the northern
states and over here in the western state of Western states are doing better except for Montana and
all of that was done in under five minutes.
Hope you're super pumped super excited we will learn all of this in this course and much much more and
you will definitely have fun through the way I look forward to seeing you in the next session.
And until next time happy analyzing.