Hello and welcome back to the course and Tableau in the previous tutorial we learned how to create these
clusters.
And at the same time we also identified that even though they are telling us some sort of story and
they are identifying some trends that we are also seeing with our naked eye at the same time they might
not be the final step in our analysis maybe we can somehow refine these clusters to tell of an even
better story.
And that's exactly what we're going to do today.
So to start off with let's just step away from this analytics in tableau for a second and let's just
do some analytical and critical thinking for a bit.
So what company are we working for.
It's important to always remember the domain knowledge behind what you're doing.
It's a very powerful skill in data science the capacity and ability to understand the domain knowledge.
So this company this company isn't just a company that produces pirates for a factory.
This company isn't just a financial services organization that gives out loans to countries around the
world.
This company deals with people.
This company heavily actually relies on people.
In fact this company what they do is they come to your house they collect your washing and then they
take it to their store.
They wash it for you and then they bring it back.
So it's kind of like an outsourcing of your laundry.
That's a service that they provide.
And that's in their entire business.
So in this case as you can imagine their amount of work that they get is directly proportionate to the
amount of people that they can potentially service.
So what exactly I'm hinting at is population to put it very bluntly the amount of dirty clothes in a
city is directly correlated to the population of that city.
Other companies that service a population they might not have such a direct correlation of the amount
of work to the amount of people.
But for a laundry company the more people you have exactly proportionately the more you will have dirty
laundry in that city.
So population of a city might play actually a huge role in their analysis that we're about to perform
and that is important to always remember and understand.
So what if these cities so this company it works all across different parts of the US and as we discussed
at the beginning they can't afford to compete with the major players so they're not present in cities
like New York like San Francisco Los Angeles that we're not present in the very big big cities they're
going for after the smaller cities still large cities with hundreds of thousands of population.
But at the same time a bit smaller so what if what is going on here is somehow related to the size of
the population maybe what if this trend that we're seeing here that even though they're investing more
and more into marketing they're not getting more and more people or they're not getting more and more
revenue.
Maybe that is related to the fact that they've maxed out their capacity or their share of that population
and that associated city maybe there is some sort of correlation there.
Maybe those marketing efforts that they're investing into whether they're online or offline maybe those
marketing efforts have a limit of how much what what portion of the population they can bring.
And in these specific cities maybe they're just smaller cities and maybe we'll see something going on
like that there so is a very powerful skill to have to be able to bring in external data sets into your
analysis to refine your analysis.
And that's exactly what we're going to do now.
So as you remember in our data set we had another file which was the population data set.
So let's go ahead and find that file.
What I can do is I can connect to that file just so I can create a new data source connection and remember
it was an Excel file as a CSP file so if I go to text you will see here among these files U.S. cities
population.
So this file contains information on the population of the cities of the top cities in the US and among
them all of our cities are among those cities.
So what we could do is we could create a new connection and then we could create new tab.
And as you can see we have two separate connections.
So in order to bring these cities into the analysis what we would need to do is perform and blend and
that is one of the options that we have at the same time.
We can now do something that was not possible before in trouble previously in previous older versions
of tableau.
What you couldn't do is you couldn't create a cross data joint so right now I want to create a joint
and I want to join an excel data source or the one we have now to assist the data file the one that
we are going to connect to now the file with the populations.
Previously you couldn't do that in tableau but the tables have created a facility that now you can create
cross out of joints and you can create cross-border joints for lots of different data sources not everything
but for very for a huge variety you can.
And one of them is Excel to CSB.
So that's exactly what you going to do.
We're going to click the Add button over here and from the dropdown we're going to select text file
because we're connecting to a CSP file U.S. city's population.
And once we've selected that as you can see it has been added.
Now before we talk about this joint first thing and we want to do is make sure it's being performed
correctly.
If we click on this button here you'll see that it's been matched by city.
But as we discussed there are duplicate cities in the US and more so there can be duplicate cities in
our data set.
So therefore this could be a do a join with duplicates that's happening right now.
So just city by itself is not a good enough is not specific enough.
And as you can see that is exactly the case.
Right now we actually have 159 rows instead of 150.
So some arrows indeed got duplicated in part as part of this joint.
There's something very important you need to look out for.
So always make sure you're performing in the joint correctly in our case we want to not only join on
city but we want to join on state from this data source and state from this data source.
So we have to make sure that our joint has been performed correctly.
And now if I close this you'll see that there is 150 rows.
So no duplication has occurred.
So if you scroll down you'll see that there's 150 rows and it's always a good thing to check to just
double check that you haven't performed any duplication of rows and that the joints performed correctly.
And so now moving back to this great feature of Cross dinosaur joint what we actually created here is
a one of them.
One of those cross artists joints we've got an Excel file on the left.
We've got a CSP file on the right previously was not possible.
Now we can do that.
We can in fact we can create connect a SDL database with an excel file and a CSP file and also add a
Maya skill database.
So there's lots of different combinations that you can create a great shout out to the guys from tableau
for creating this functionality.
It is going to make analytics much more fun and interesting and it will allow us to perform on a list
that the privacy we couldn't perform.
So that's a great great feature.
And now we're just going to proceed with this combined dataset so we can actually just rename it's a
combined data set.
And here what we have is the original data set with the blue lines at the top then we've got color fields
and then Orange is the new dataset.
So we all all we need from here is actually the population so the 2015 estimate.
So we're going to just select all the other columns.
Hold down control and we're going to right click and we're going to hide them because we don't need
them in our analysis.
There it is the estimate of the population we're just going to call it population for our purposes and
now we can proceed on to our Advanced Clustering or refined clustering and we'll start on that in the
next trial.
Can't wait to see you there.
Until then happy analyzing.