Hi.
I'm glad that you decided to join me on this course and I hope you are ready to dive into the world
of how computers deal with all human language.
But before that in this quick introduction we will we will first talk about what an IP is and why we
finally need an LP.
Then I will explain personally why I feel that energy is so interesting and fascinating.
And finally we will quickly go through the plan of attack for this whole course.
So first what is it not be so happy stands for natural language processing.
So it speaks by itself.
It just means that is the part of a I the feel of a I that deals with the human language.
So the idea is that we want computers to be able to grasp the meaning which in words that's not obvious
at all because computers only deal with sequences of zeros and ones.
And how do we convey a meaning as complex as it can be sometimes we human interactions with those sequences
of zeros and ones.
But that's not an easy task but nonetheless entropy is still everywhere.
Because of course our language whether it be as a text or as species is everywhere around us.
And you maybe have not noticed it but you actually use energy all the time.
For example Google recently implemented something in the search engine with an IP to improve the accuracy
of their results instead of blindly looking for the results that have the same words.
Daniel inputs research what they do now is that the grass the meaning of research and they try to find
websites that correspond to this meaning or if you are part of those people who talk to their phones.
Of course it's full of energy when you are glad because you don't receive all those spammers in your
main inbox.
Again you can think an LP.
So it's really everywhere and you can think of many other applications like fraud detection in huge
contracts or sentimental analyses.
So it could apply for instance to Automated Moderation charts or in forums.
And of course each time we use a translator It's an LP and all the chat bots that we now see on the
Internet there are of course the result of this research in A.P..
So now I hope that you are convinced that it's a very important and useful field of A.I..
I will tell you two reasons why for me it's one of the most interesting and fascinating fields in the
eye.
The first one is that in LP we are really far from reaching the expectations that we had a few years
ago but that's often the opposite with the other fields of A.I..
If you take the example of a pledge to games there is this famous team in Google which is Google deep
mind that achieves great results.
A few years ago with the game of Go When machines were finally able to be better than humans while the
community thought that we will need at least 10 years to achieve that.
So we went really faster than expected.
But that's not how it works in LP few years a few decades ago.
People thought that we would have computers that would be able to talk like humans very soon.
But we are still far from it.
We realize that it's way more complicated than expected to deal with language AI.
But that brings us to the second reason why they'll be so fascinating is that as we still have a lot
of work to do it also means that we have a lot of things to discover and that itchy that new fascinating
discoveries that appear in the research woods.
So that's also exciting to follow this kind of adventure in this energy research.
It's not that we can't wait to dive into it let's have a quick look at how we will do that.
The course will be separated in two main parts corresponding to the two main types of tasks that exist
in LP.
The first one being classification tasks so it's spam detection all sentimental on the license for detections
and many others and the seven part being sequence to sequence tasks.
So it can be cancellations text memorization chat bots well anything that has a whole text as inputs
and outputs while in the classification task.
We have a text as inputs but we will have labels as outputs the first part will be about a classification
task.
And for that we will apply as CNN to it.
So it's an instance for conversion on the will networks.
And of course it was first used for compute divisions so to analyze images but actually it could also
perform really well in an LP for the classification tasks.
So that's what we will use to tackle those kind of problems.
And in the first box we will go into the CNN intuition talking first about the origins of CNN so how
they were applied to images to then make the link between image and text to see how we can apply it
for an LP and then we will go for the applications which in our case will be a sentimental analyzer.
So we will use a lot of tweets that has been labeled positive or negative using the images that were
into it.
And we will create our sentiments out in that saw out of its but of course the idea of the CNN architecture
is really similar for any classification tasks.
So it will fit any other follows with labels as outputs and in the second part we'll see what we call
the transformer.
So it's a recent model recent architecture that has been presented by Google and I'm really excited
to present to this one because for me it's so interesting the way it works and is so so powerful you
will see that's in the application phase.
So same thing that for the CNN we would first go into the intuition.
So I would expect the origins of this one where it comes from and in details how it's implemented how
it works and what are the mathematical ideas behind.
Then of course we will go for the application.
And guess what.
You will be able to build your own translator in a certain way.
I can't believe that I'm saying that because not so long ago I was sure that it was impossible for me
to build a translator.
I thought that was something that only Google or big firms could do but you will see that we can get
great results with AIDS and you will have your own translator that you can that you can beat for any
language of course.
If you have the appropriate data and sending that for CNN these architects are the transformer is very
general so of course we will build a translator but you can use it for any sequence to sequence dusk
so it will work perfectly fine.
If you want to build a chatterbox for instance.
So that was it for all plan of attack.
What we will go through this course.
I hope you are super excited to go into it with me.
So let's not wait any longer and see you soon.