Hi guys and welcome back.
This now because we are finally ready to build a transformer now that we have all big bricks.
That's the encoder and the decoder.
We are ready to finalize this model before that.
Let's have a quick last look at the architecture.
So this is the whole transformer.
We have already made these parts which is the encoder and this box which is the decoder.
So what we just have to do you can divide it in three phases.
The first one is just to assemble those two elements.
We also have to make this last phase which is basically to apply in our function at the end of our decoder.
And last thing that we have not done yet is to implement the masks that we apply inside the Motorhead
attention so we will have to create two masking functions.
The first one to mask the padding tokens at the end of the sentences and the second one is to create
the head mask which makes sure that's the decoder can have access to future words.
So let's start right now.
By defining our class transformer and this time as it a it will be a model and not a layer so it will
inherits from T F that cure us.
That's model but it works the same way.
We still have to define the innards function so let's make a list of all the valuables that we will
need.
First we will have to make to embed things the embedding for the encoder and for the decoder.
So for that we need the vocab size of the encoder the vocab size of the decoder.
We also need the dimension of the model we wants to have at the end of the embedding.
We need the number of layers which is basically the number of time we will apply the encoder layer and
the decoder layer inside of the huge encoder and decoder bricks.
So in the paper they say six we might want to just 4 for the tests to make it a bit lower but we'll
see later in the training.
So we also need the number of units in the in the FIT forwards box at the end of each encoder and decoder
layer next.
We need the number of projections insides of the much head attentional layer the drop dropout rates
and let's give a name to our module which will be transformed.
Right there.
So as before we need to call super transformer self called in its methods and tell its the name of our
model.
Okay.
So before starting to create the call methods we will first build all all masking functions.
So the first one we said that we need a function to create a mask for the pageant tokens.
So let's create this and it will just take a sequence as inputs at these points of the model a sequence
is still just a list of numbers each number corresponding to awards.
The editing has not been done yet.
So what we have is simply the inputs from the data sets and absent the encoding from the token NISA
awards.
It's just a number.
So the sequence right here it's just a list of numbers.
But as it has been botched the shape of SEK is this one batch size sic length OK.
So let's look for the zeros in the sequence which corresponds to the pattern token let's call mask equals
see if that's not that's equal SEK 0 and we want it to be represented as floats so that we can perform
anything we want later see if that casts.
And so this has the same shape as before.
And we want to return mask after adding to New Dimensions new access to efforts.
Access.
And we keep the mask.
So in order to understand why we do this we have to go back to where we apply this mask.
If you remember well attention computation we apply the mask.
In these nerds had attention sub layer and more precisely in the sketch that put it attention.
So first thing to remember is that before applying this get the attention right here.
We have splits the dimension of the embedding which means that we have an additional dimension.
This is what we just wrote.
Why here.
The number of projection.
So this is the reason why we added this new axis.
This is because the mask will be applied for each of the projection.
OK.
And the reason why we added this one is because where we apply the mask is just after the scales project.
So it's inside these parenthesis.
So basically this is a matrix of shape sequence length sequence length and the clever thing is that's
when we do this even if the mask is not a matrix that fits the shape.
If it's just a vector instead of being a matrix it will cleverly repeat the mask in the dimension that
is missing.
So basically what we sent here.
Because this is in kind of an empty dimension.
This is just a row.
And thanks to this empty dimension the row will be repeated as many times as we need.
So now let's explain why it does what we want so to do that I have this little figure that explains
how much exposure application works in our case this metric right here is the attention waits.
So this is what we get after multiplying the queries by the keys.
And basically as a reminder what it means is that it just has all the information about how let's say
words e is related to words J.
And he this second matrix just represents a sentence.
Actually it's not really a sentence because at the very beginning.
Yes.
Each row corresponds to a words but after a lot of processing inside the model it's not the case anymore.
Each row represents the global information about the whole sentence we had at the beginning.
But anyway what is important is that here this metric says how the row number I in the results must
be related to the row.
No change in the values and what we created with all padding masks is that we just said that in one
row the last let's say and numbers will be equal to zero.
And being the number of putting tokens at the end.
Of course and this will be repeated in each row.
What that means is that if the input sentence hides and putting tokens at the end this matrix right
here.
So this attention weights will have zeros everywhere in the lists and columns which means if we have
a look at how the matrix multiplication works if we want to see how this number at the end of the computation
is made it's just a combination of multiplications of those numbers of those pairs and numbers and we
some of them but the last n numbers here being equal to zero.
Those lists and numbers will not be used.
And this is the case everywhere in this results.
So that just means that the lists and rows right here are not used.
And that's actually exactly what we wanted to perform.
So this siding mask kind of disables those lists and rows and that's exactly what we wanted to do.
So that's for the putting mask.
Let's go to the second one def create look ahead mask which takes against self and sequence what we
want to do now is not create just a vector.
We want to create a full matrix.
And the goal of this matrix is to say that we can't have access to future words and the best way to
do that is to use triangular matrix.
So for those of you who are not familiar with this concept it's really simple.
If you take a square matrix a triangle matrix means that's only let's say the half top right of the
matrix.
So this is in a triangle shape will not have zeros.
And the best way to do that is to use the little bend parts methods intensive low.
So we will have a look at this in a few seconds.
First we need to declare sequence length equals t f the shape of our sequence.
So we will have the the shape of our matrix and what we do is look the head mask equals t efforts Lee
now that's bend thoughts to f that once here we just created a match we landed with once sec line minus
1 0.
So let me explain
the size of sequence length and what we want to do now is to add zeros in the top right parts of this
matrix.
And what.
BEN POTTS does is that it adds condition on the indices of all metrics and put zeros.
If those conditions are completed and basically this first part says that's in the row I and the column
J.
In all metrics this adds a condition about how I is supposed to be higher than J and these does the
opposite.
This adds a condition about how Shay has to be higher than I so I can hear a negative number say is
that we don't want to use this one.
And here it just says that we want to change to be greater or equal to I.
Let me just show you what it does.
If we apply this to let's say the metrics of size 5 will actually prints buffer for them so it's easier
to see what happens.
Let's print this one
and that one too.
So here we just created a square matrix field with once and here.
Thanks to these methods we added a condition about how a J should be higher than I in order to apply
0 0 0 if you want to see the other way we added the condition about how I should be higher than J.
In order to keep the original values so we have this bottom left triangular matrix.
But what we want to do actually is to have a strict upper right triangular matrix.
This is how we will say that the words.
No I will not have access to the word no J.
We want to mask the words that will be in the future.
So we just have to add one minus this whole matrix and we get exactly what we want.
So again we can afford to keep those dimensions because we will mix the Look AHEAD mask with the padding
mask and so tensor flow will cleverly know that it needs to add those two dimensions to the look ahead
mask so we can simply return look ahead mask.
And so just to illustrate what are said right now we will actually use those functions to see how it
works.
2 3 4.
And of course gets rid of self.
Do the same thing here.
Gets rid of self
remove the tops so let's define those functions and let's define the FH sequence.
Let's say it's equal to T abducts casts and we need to simulate a batch.
So that's why I add this array into another array and it's random number zero.
We don't want to have a look at this one and let's say three zeros at the end and this will be t f that's
int 32.
Okay.
And just to illustrate what I said before when we will apply the self attention mechanism at the beginning
of the decoder we will use the look ahead mask again so that we don't have access to future words but
also the padding masks and the way we will do that is just if we do t f that's maximum of it's copy
busts creates buying mask.
And
creates
look at head masks.
We can see that we get exactly what we want.
Tenth floor understood that it had to create the first and the second axis for the look ahead the mask
also.
So that's why we get the right Sharpie.
This is for the batch size number of projections inside the self attention sub layer.
And finally the size of the mattress for the attention weights.
And if you have a closer look at where we have the one so each one means that we apply a mask.
So that means that we don't get this into accounts we have here this full column of once which corresponds
to the zero.
And of course the last we once and we keep the top right parts of the mattress as wants.
As for the word no.
Let's say one two three four.
We don't have to.
We don't want to have access to all the words.
After that we don't want to have access towards 5 6 and 7.
So that's why we don't have to add the axis for the first and the second dimensions.
This will do it by itself because anyway we will add a padding mass to the look ahead mask so the maximum
will do all the job.
OK.
So that was kind of the tricky parts dealing with the all the masks but now we have done that.
We basically just have to combine the encoder and the decoder in the call method so let's define call
with itself.
Of course we get in the transformer inputs for the encoder inputs for the decoder and information about
whether we are training or not.
Let's create the masks right now so the first one is the mask that we will use in the encoder.
This is a simple putting mask because here we don't need the look ahead mask so self that creates padding
mask
for the encoder inputs then the first mask of the decoder is this time with the LUCA mask because this
is exactly the moment where we don't want to have a look at the future.
So deck mask and then the one equals as we did before maximum of set of dots creates putting mask the
flight to of course the decode the inputs and self that creates Luke had mask applied to the Dakota
inputs as well.
And the last mask that we want is the second mask of the Dakota which is a simple parsing mask and we
don't want our decoder to have access to the purging tokens that come from the encoder.
So here we just add as parameter encoding inputs.
Quick explanation about why here we have the encoder inputs and that the decoder inputs because you
may think that's as we are inside the decoder.
This is the decoder inputs that we want to use here in order to have all putting mask.
But that's not.
And the reason is that let's have a look at actually we'll use both those things so you can see right
here that in this layer.
So this is in this layer that we want to apply or mask the queries come from the previous layer of the
decoder.
But the values and the keys come from the outputs of the encoder and if we have another look right here.
What we do in the attention mechanism is that we compute this using the queries and the keys.
So in the case we are right now.
This is using the previous layer of the decoder and the outputs of the encoder.
So this part says how they are related to each other how it's words of the decoder is related to the
words of the outputs of the encoder and we use this to kind of re compose the values that now are from
the encoder.
So the result of all this operation is a real regiments of the outputs of the encoder following the
way sentences from the decoder are related to the sentences from the decoder.
So in this process in this combination of the outputs of the encoder This is the putting tokens of the
encoder that we don't want to have a look at because this is the output of the encoder that we are mixing
together in order to have the new representation of all information so far.
Yes.
The final results of our Motorhead attentional error will have the same shape the same form as what
we have inside the decoder.
But with the way we achieve that is by making combination of the information from the encoder and of
course the way we perform those combinations is given by the relations between what we have inside the
encoder and the decoder.
That's why for all fighting mask in the second melty head attention layer of the decoder we use the
shape of the input for the encoder now we really simply have to define the outputs of the encoder as
the results of the encoder layer giving its the inputs the mask and the information about the training
now.
Same thing we just apply our decoder layer decoder and we give it the inputs for the decoder.
The outputs from the enclosure outputs the first mask of the decoder.
The second one.
And finally whether we are in a training phase or not.
So let's apply the last phase which is a really simple linear function.
So a dense layer to the outputs and we turn the results and of course we have to define the layers that
we used right there.
So let's do it he said.
That's called a will be and then coda.
And we simply add all the parameters that we need.
The number of layers of the number of times we apply the encoder sub layer the number of units for the
fit forward part number of projections inside the motel attentional layer the drop out rates the size
of the vocabulary for the encoder and D model so that the embedding is done well and same thing for
the decoder.
Let's define decode a number layers number of units and then the projections show about
vocab size decoder and the dimension of the model.
And finally the last thing we used
a little bit of a dense layer Lee now equals layers that's dense.
And of course we wanted to have as outputs something of the size of the vocabulary of the decoder.
And so yeah of course we want the number of units here to be equal to the vocab size of the decoder
because we want to get the probability for each possible words in our vocab to be the next one.
So well here we are.
This is done the whole transformer has been made.
Guess we are ready to trade outs so let's build the training pot right now and see you soon.