Hi and welcome back to this and because.
So let's start this part about CNN for an by talking about the origins of CNN and how they were first
applied for images.
So for comes division and then we'll see how we can change them to apply CNN's for either peace or for
texts.
So first what does a CNN do.
Basically it's a neural network that we'll take as inputs in the image and output.
It will give us a label.
So as I said in the previous section it could be for instance a number if all input image is a written
number or it could be a class saying whether there is a plane or not in the image.
So many different things.
And it's been a huge part in the A.I. evolution throughout the years with a lot of contests for the
best performing CNN for this kind of classification tasks.
So what are the standard steps for CNN.
The first one is the most important one what we call the convolution.
So this is the step where we create a lot of small features detectors that will go through the whole
image and we will end up with a list of feature maps that will tell us whether or not and where a specific
feature appears in the image.
Then the second step is the max pulling.
So basically we just apply maximum function to all feature maps so that we can make them smaller and
improve the performance of the model.
Then there is this very simple flattening phase where we simply make a huge vector out of the maps which
are mattresses and we finally end the model with a full connection.
So a fit for a network that is a very standard neural network and that we learn from the feature extraction
phase.
How to give a label to all inputs.
So let's go with the first phase.
The convolution.
So first what is an image for us humans.
And the majority of animals.
This is light that comes into our eyes.
But for our computer it must be a list of numbers.
So what we do is that we split anything that we want to represent into very very small areas.
So could be peak sales for instance.
And we put a number in this to simplify it.
We will say that all images will be in black and white.
And so for each of those very small areas or pixel the higher the number the darker this area will be.
And this is how we go from this smiley face to the simplified one with a lot of small areas.
And then finally a matrix.
So at least a numbers that will represent this image.
Of course if the image is in colors we will need three matrices one for each other the primary colors.
But for now we will stick with the black and white version and we don't even need to think about those
three channels those three colors when we will go into the energy parts.
So let's stick with it.
And now that we have our image that is represented as a matrix of numbers and that is usable by our
computer.
Let's see what we do with it.
So the convolution phase consists of a lot of feature detector that are actually small mattresses that
we will apply to the whole image.
So how does this matrix obligation work.
We go through patches in the original image that have the same size as our feature detector.
Our filter and what we do is that we don't do a matrix multiplication standard matrix multiplication.
We do an element y's multiplication.
So what it means is that we all take for instance the top left number of this patch and when we multiply
it by the top left number of our patch of our feature detector and we do the same with all the numbers.
So top middle number multiplied by the top middle number here and we sum all of these results.
So if we have a look at the first batch right here where we wanted to apply our feature detector we
can see that there is no coalition between the once in this patch and the ones in these feature detector.
So here for instance the 0 will be multiplied by the one and this one with an image played by 0.
So the end result which is a single number is 0 and we will put it on the most top left box of our final
feature map.
Then we will repeat the process with the next batch.
We just wanted to shift our feature detector by 1 to the right.
And here we see that there is a correlation between the patch and the feature detector which is this
one way we have a one in our patch from the image and the one in this feature detector.
So when we multiply the patch with the feature detector element y's and then we sum everything we get
the one that we just put here in the second element of our final future map and we repeat the process
shifting off the two detector by one to the right when we go at the end of the line.
We repeat the same thing just shifted by one towards the bottom of the image.
We repeat this as many times as we need.
Finally we will get at this point right before the end.
We can double check the computation if we want.
We can see that we will get ones from this top right spot.
She where we have once for the patch and the feature detector and sending for the middle left parts
here where we have to once.
So when we sum everything we get it too.
And that's what we see appearing here.
And finally the last one when we get one again from the middle left parts of the patch.
So that's the result of one convolution applied with only one feature detector.
So this feature that is detected might not make any sense for us humans.
It could be some computation with numbers that we don't really get.
But when they are all put together and fed to a standard fit for a network the conventional neural network
can achieve great results with it but sometimes it is something that is related to what we can understand
as humans.
For instance if I take the example of the handwritten digits recognition one of the feature could be
to detect if there is a little cross somewhere in the image and if it appears if so if the feature detector
is activated somewhere then there is a high probability that our number will be eight.
So that's the kind of thing that the convolution old parts could do.
And of course we went through an example for only one feature detector but the I.D. that's all CNN will
have a lot of those feature detector and each detector will provide a feature map.
Last thing that is important to have in mind is that those numbers right here they are of course randomly
initialized and those are the valuables that are learned throughout the process of the training of the
model.
So after each prediction after comparing the results with the actual shoe label the model will tune
those numbers in order to learn to detect more useful and accurate features.
So it's interesting to see what those feature detectors look like at the end of the training because
those will be according to our model the most useful feature to detect in the imaging although to perform
all classification tasks.
So the results after this operation is this we have our original image and we get at the end lists of
features maps.
So each of this map corresponds to a different feature detector.
So a different convolution or filter and we are ready to go to the next phase.
So this next step is the max pulling.
So it's just a maximum operation that is performed for each map.
And the idea is to reduce the size of it and the cost of course of the computation by being more global.
So it's not a global maximum.
We don't take just the higher number for each feature map but we will still reduce the size.
So for instance in this example we will apply a much pulling for two times two patches.
So we will take three years of size to two and we'll just take the higher number and put it in a new
pooled feature map.
So that's for the first area that we are looking for we at one then it will shift its by the size of
our patch.
So we will go directly to the next spots without having anything in common.
And we get a new two by two patch where we apply a maximum.
Again we get one and it's not important.
If we go a little bit out of bounds The idea is that we get all the numbers that can be in our fetch
him up and we speed the process again shifting by 2 this time because we don't want to have any number
or any rule that appears in two different Mexico operation.
Here we get a four that will be here and so on.
Finally we get to the last part which contains only one number but that's not important.
The important thing is just that this number had the opportunity to appear somewhere and that nothing
appears two times in our Mexico operation.
So we get here all pooled feature maps.
So the idea is that we don't need to know everything about whether the feature appeared in the image
or not.
We don't need to know everywhere.
It doesn't appear the most important thing is to know whether it appears or not.
But we still want to keep some kind of locality in this process.
We want to know more or less where the feature appeared because in any major positions of the elements
are very important.
So we still want to keep the relations between the positions of the features that is kind of a tradeoff
between getting rid of the information we don't need and also making the maps smaller so that we can
improve the process and reduce the costs.
And the fact that we still want to keep an idea of the positions of elements in the image.
So that was for the max pulling.
Of course we apply this operation to each of our features map and we get the same number of pooled maps.
Then the next step.
Very simple just the flattening.
So the idea is that in order to apply a stand on your network.
So a fully connected network which teal to have a simple vector.
So we just transform each matrix.
So it's called feature map into a vector.
There's nothing complicated about that.
There is just.
We take the first row which is the first part of the vector.
Then we just add the second row to this vector and the third row.
Same thing we added at the end of the vector so we get a vector out of the matrix.
The important thing is that this flattening operation will always proceed the same way so that the locality
that we had there the relations between the positions is kept here.
So it's not in the same form it's less visual but the information is still there because there is an
order in our numbers that directly comes from the order that we had in the matrix.
So we still keep the order and the relations between the positions so that's it's out of those maps
those mattresses we get to vector of course the vector is much bigger than this but this is just for
the sake of the representations and we get something that could be valid inputs for our feed for network.
So a quick look at our architecture are at the steps so far we have all original image and we apply
many different feature detectors to it in the convolution phase.
So we get a lot of feature maps.
We apply a pulling to reaches them but still keeping valuable information.
And we flatten everything in order to have vectors instead of the list of matches as that's its last
step of all convolution of four images is the full connection.
So it's a standard fully connected network that will learn the classification tasks from all convolution
or steps.
It's just very standard.
We have all input vector.
We can add as many he denies here that we want.
So just new ones that we learn useful stuff throughout the process.
And finally we get our output value so hey we decided that for days representation.
That's the classification is to label a classification so all image should be put into two different
classes.
Of course we can have many more Newman's eyes outputs.
In our example for the handwritten digits of course we will have 10 different new ones one for each
number and the higher the number here the higher the probability that's our input image corresponds
to this number.
So usually the relation between a new one and all the new ones from the previous layer is that we multiply
each number by a coefficient.
So by a weight we sum everything and then we apply and only in our function most of the time which will
be what we call really.
So it basically gets rid of all the negative values putting them to zero and we keep all the positive
values which we consider to be the activated values.
So in all implementation this will just corresponds to dense layers.
Nothing really new about that's and that's it.
So here is the final summary of all hope CNN for images.
Input image which is made of numbers.
Of course the matrix of numbers we apply different features detectors and we get a list of feature maps
that our network learns it learns what each conventional filter will be made of.
So what are the most useful feature to look for.
Then we apply a local maximum to reduce the size of all feature maps.
And finally we apply a fit for network to our flattens information so to a whole vector to get as many
new wins as the number of classes that are possible.
So that was it for the quick introduction to CNN for images.
Probably was clear enough and nothing we're ready to see how we can apply it to tests because intuitively
takes is quite different from images.
So first we have to see how we can make the texts similar to Indian age in order to apply these kind
of algorithms and also we have to see what all the small changes and then we have to apply to the architecture
to the whole structure in order to get good performances with our CNN popularity for that and to use
using.