Hi and welcome back to this insult because so we have seen how we used to address the secrets to secret
task by using our names and how we improved them by adding these attention mechanism that was every
powerful tool but it seems that we might be able to go even further in that direction.
And the reason why we needed to go further and to even more improve it is because the thing about Armenians
is that it's a sequential process so it doesn't have a global behavior concerning the the input sequence.
And so we lose information along the encoding process.
The fact that's the last hidden State of the encoder which is the final output of the encoder has not
seen the beginning of the sentence for a long time could be quite disturbing.
So for very long sentences very long sequences we lose a lot of information and that's a huge weakness
for our audience.
So what the Google research teams have been thinking about is OK.
So the attention mechanism added global behavior to the decoding phase but the audience still has this
weakness about not being global enough.
So what if actually all we need in order to perform well in this sequence to secret process is attention.
And so all we need is attention is actually the name of the paper that Google lists when they introduced
this transformer.
And that just illustrates the fact that that transformer only uses the attention mechanism in order
to encode and decode sequences and comfortably gets read off the ordinance.
So let's have a look at the architect's figure that they provide in this paper.
So there is a lot of stuff going on here.
We will go of course into the details of each step of each layer later.
But let's start by trying to have the global understanding of what's happening here so we can clearly
see as before that we have two main blocks.
The first one on the left will be the encoder and the second one on the right will be the decoder.
There are some ideas that stay the same.
Like for instance the fact that we have inputs for the encoder and after that we get outputs from this
and Coda.
And those outputs will be part of the inputs of decoder.
And from that we will get all awkward sequence so this doesn't change but one of the main things that
all difference is that's our inputs for the encoder will be the whole sentence at once.
So we don't feed the encoder one word at a time we just give it the whole sequence and it will process
the whole sequence at once.
And this is important to keep the global aspect of the processing that we wanted to have.
Second thing that we wanted to notice is the inputs for the decoder.
You can see that's here to say outputs.
It's actually because we use the outputs of our decoder as new inputs for the decoder as we did before.
But once again we do it with the whole sentence.
So let's say for instance that's all transformer has been made to build a chat bots and the inputs sequence
will be how are you doing for instance.
So first time we apply our transformer we will have as inputs for the encoder the whole sentence.
How are you doing.
And we will give here as inputs just a single token that we will call the starts talking and it doesn't
convey any meaning.
It's just to tell the agents found out that this is the beginning of a sentence and giving that's after
the first application of the transformer will get us outputs just one element that will be I.
So the first word of our answer and we will add this word eye to the output sequence that we had before.
And this will become start talking.
I then will repeat the process keeping the same inputs here so how are you doing.
And key we will use as inputs father decoder start to can I.
And we will get our outputs.
I am for instance and repeating this we will add new words to the output of the decoder to finally get
something like I am fine thank you.
This is where this shift to the right comes from.
It's just that by adding this taut token at the beginning of the input sequence for the decoder you
shift the whole sentence right.
And with that we know that the last word from the output sequence he will be the predicted next word
for our sequence.
But that's an implementation detail and we'll also see that later.
So that was the first thing to have in mind the fact that we use whole sequences at once as inputs and
that's key.
The sequence we use as inputs for all decoder is the one that we already had at the previous iteration
plus the new words that we will predict at the end of this sequence.
Right.
He said something that is really important when we have a look to the architecture are those orange
cells right there where you can see attention everywhere.
And that's the most important thing about these transformer.
That's actually what we'll do the whole job.
And that is exactly based on the attention mechanism that we so earlier applies to our events.
So just to summarize how it works the idea is when you have two sequences it's just we compose the first
sentence according to how each elements of this first sentence is related to the elements of the second
sentence but you might be wondering then why here as inputs we use three times the same sentence.
And that's actually what they call self attention which is the key of the encoder and the transformer.
So what we did before with the ordinance is that we used a standard new network.
We had information about the beginning of the sentence.
We are the new words we make some computation and we get new information about the sentence.
But what we do here is that we have a whole sentence and we will see how each words of its sentence
is related to the other words of the same sentence and then we will read compose this sentence according
to that.
So so here is for instance an illustration of the self attention mechanism.
So if we take the first sentence the animal didn't cross the streets because it was too times.
When we apply the self attentional mechanism it just computes how each words of the sentence is related
to the others.
So here it understands that that it's right here refers to the animal it's the animal that was too tired.
But if we take another example like the animal didn't cross the streets because it was too wide.
We understand that it refers to the streets because it was the street that was too wide of course but
the animal and the self attention mechanism.
Understand that's so if we feed this sentence to a self attentional layer like we have in the encoder
we will have as inputs just this sequence of words is words being of course doing the implementation
of vector and as the outputs of these attentional layer we will have Q Instead of the words it's we
would have a combination of those words according to how strong the relation with the words is.
So we will have a lot of the vector animal a little bits off of streets of the maybe it's these points
and we will have nothing from the other woods.
And for this sentence instead of it as outputs of all self attentional layer we will have lots of the
vectors streets and a little bits of those lighter blue ones and none of those ones.
So it's just that instead of having just a sequence of words we have a new representation of the information
that can convey a sentence because as inputs we have the lowest possible way to have information about
a sentence which is just one words after the other and the goal of applying these self attention mechanism
is to combine everything so that each element doesn't only represent the words but it represents relations
which in the differing words of a sentence.
So that was kind of an illustration of how self attention works and these self attention mechanism is
how we will encode sentences in the transformer.
So that is used of course in the quarter and that's the main thing that we use.
We also use fully connected network which is to learn more.
We apply this whole thing seven times and we get all final and coded version of the input sequence and
about the decoder we start doing the same thing.
So with a sequence as input here we apply a self attentional layer just to have more information about
the relations between the words and after that we apply an attention mechanism between the outputs of
the encoder and the sequence that we just had.
So that means mixing information from the end closer according to how each element is related to the
sequence from the decoder but we'll see that's into more details later when we will go deeper into the
attention mechanism.
One last thing I want to show you a small illustration that could help understanding how it works.
Is this cool illustration out I've found that's kind of show an animation of how everything works.
So this sees the encoding phase with the input sequence and you can see that what happens is that we
mix all the words together all the relations to get new representation of the input sequence and then
as I said we starts the decoder.
Just one token and we apply several time the decoder.
With also the information from the encoder in order to have a new words at each step like this.
Let's have a second Lukasz so let's get all whole input sequence right there and makes each word according
to how they are related to the others and get new information and we repeat that same old time and get
a new representation of the out input sequence.
And yet now we just apply the decoder the other new word each time and using the information from the
previous words and the whole encoding sentence we can needs little by little step by step predicts new
words.
And finally just get our final answer.
So here the answers the sentences our nuts complete of course it's just an illustration but I find it
pretty cool and it's and it's easier to understand what happens this way.
So that was it for the general understanding of the transformer.
Of course we will go into more details for each element of this model.
But to summarize what we have to understand key is that there is still an encoder and decoder and we
computes whole sequences at once instead of one words after the other.
And the way we do that is by re composing sequences making sums of difference items from each sequence
according to how they are related to each other.
So that's just a way to get global information about the whole sentence.
Just an intuition thing actually that's in my opinion would be how the brain processes sentences when
you have a sentence in mind.
We don't process the meaning of it sentence by going word after the other.
We actually have the whole sentence in mind and we capture the meaning of it's at once and if you think
about it that's actually easy to see when you think about reading.
I don't know if you like me a slow reader but if you read slowly you may experience that you have to
go back many times when you read a single sentence and that's not only because you maybe are not concentrating
enough that's also because if you read too slow would afterwords it's not how your brain is optimized
to understand a sentence when you arrive at the end of the sentence you have already forgotten the beginning
and you are losing the whole sense of a sentence.
Actually a sentence is made to be understood globally as one big block.
Actually it's kind of a burden that we have to use words and that we have when we read or when you write
to get them one at a time because if you think about that you might realize that when you hear someone
speaking you wait for the end of a sentence and then you get the whole idea of the sentence at once.
When you process the meaning of it's and that is actually what the first readers do.
Those people that can read a page in a few seconds and have trained a lot to improve their reading speeds
what they do instead of reading word by word is that they try to use the global vision to get the biggest
group of words at once that they can and to process the whole meaning of it at once and you can do that
because your brain is made to understand language like that.
And so my understanding of this transformer is that it goes in the same direction instead of processing
word by word.
We try to capture the meaning of the whole sentence at once by combining each item with the others and
I find it so interesting that we naturally get to those kind of models and that they are often the ones
that we used before.
So that's it for the general understanding of the transformer.
Now we can go into more details and see exactly how the attention mechanism works and how they use it
and all the other details that they used to make it even more performance popular I'm excited to go
into those details and see you soon.