Hi and welcome back to this email because.
So now that you have seen how CNN is applied to images for comfort division let us see how we can apply
them to texts for an AP and so the first part will be to see how we can transform a text so that it's
a valid input for CNN.
So the idea was to say OK so CNN for images.
What does it do.
It search for local features in an image.
So why don't we want to process text or sentences the same way by looking for local features throughout
the whole sentence.
But in order to do that we have to have the same kind of inputs as images which were mattresses.
So we wanted to get a matrix out of a sentence.
We want to represent the sentence as a matrix because for now it's just a list of characters or a list
of words but it doesn't really look like a metric so far.
So what we would like to have is something like this.
And the most intuitive way is to say that if we have a matrix each row will correspond to the words
and each column New York corresponds to whatever we will find out later.
But this representation means that its words will be a vector.
So let's work around that the easier and maybe more natural way to represent a word with a vector is
also the less effective one.
It is what we call the 1 plot encoding.
So basically if we say that all vocabulary has one hundred thousands words each word would be a vector
of that size and it will be mostly zeros.
It will only have one one.
And for example for Doug if we say that Doug is wood number two thirty eight will add the index to thirty
eight of all Victor we will see a one and all the other numbers will be zero.
So that way we have a unique representation for each of all one hundred thousand words but there is
absolutely no relation between each of them.
There is no mathematical relation that appears there is no meaning that is conveyed to it.
It shows how little meaning and information it conveys.
Well it conveys information about which word we are dealing with but nothing about the relations between
those words.
So what we would like to have is a smaller representation of each words.
So instead of having a vector of size one hundred thousands we would have a vector of smaller size let's
say for instance sixty four.
So that's a common thing in science.
We want to make the vector smaller.
So that means that we add more constraints to our information in a certain way.
It has less liberty and that forces all system to create relations links or even meaning in the process
if we do it the right way of course.
So this time Doug for instance instead of being a vector of size one hundred thousands we have all zeros
but one it would be a vector of size 64 and it won't be binary anymore.
It would be numbers between 0 and 1.
So before going into mathematical details or to see how we do that most of the time we would just have
a look at some cool visual representations to see what it does and what it performs.
So the first one is this quite well-known effects of the what embedding now that they are embedded in
a smaller vector space.
We have some mathematical relations which in the woods as vectors and we can actually send the vectors
and summing vectors means summing meaning in all embedded space so we can actually get some very cool
stuff like if we take the word King for instance and that we say King minus man plus woman we actually
get the word queen.
So if the embedding has been done properly we can actually subtract the parts of the meaning of the
words and add another one.
Like for King we can absolutely get rid of the male parts of King and add the female parts to this result
in order to get Queen.
And another example very simple is Paris minus France plus Italia.
We get from so with Paris minus France we get the capital.
And if we add Italia then we get the capital of Italy which is Rome.
So that means that we are now able to apply mathematics to our words to all vectors and that is very
very useful in the sense of course.
So very good points.
Second visual I.D. You may have to get a little bit closer to your screen.
But this is a two dimensional representation of some words that have been embedded and the important
thing here is to realize that words that have similar meanings will be very close in the embedded space.
So for instance if you have a look at some words here we can see that's kingdom will be close to states
or that data will be close to information also there is relations between the tenses of the verbs here
we can see that there is become that is close to became close to being also close to was final you can
see that he is very close to she which is close to it also.
So by embedding vectors into a smaller dimensional vector space we added constraints as I said before
and it forced of course if we do the embedding properly it forces the positions of vectors all the values
of all vectors to convey meaning and so to make words of similar meaning close in all embedding space.
So that's cool.
We get a vector representation of.
So that will allow us to have mattresses out of sentences and it seems to be a very powerful tool because
it conveys meaning we can do mathematical stuff with it's so awesome.
But how does it work exactly like the process the embedding process mathematically what do we do exactly.
The idea is that with an input vector as a one called encoded vector as we said before.
So all you want but only one one for each what we want to multiply it by a matrix and then building
matrix and gets all embedded vector right.
Actually the fact that we multiply a 1 hardcoded vector by a matrix it just means that if we have for
instance the words I so there is only X eye which is activated that means that we just take the row
and all matrix.
So this matrix is just a list of all the embedded vectors all of the embittered words but that's a detail.
So we want to multiply and you won hearts and got it.
Victor why this match mix and how Victor but the question is how do we train these metrics.
How do we train the weights.
How do we learn the embedded vectors.
We can't of course say that we want from these to get back to the original one because we will just
have to apply the opposites cooperation just to see which way it corresponds to.
And so get the this right here.
So the idea that we want to multiply by another matrix which we call the context matrix you'll see why.
And gets again a vector of size vocab size but we want to get something else that the original input
vector but we still want it to have a meaning to have a coalition with the original words.
We want these outputs.
This vector to have a semantic coalition with this one.
So one idea to do that is to use what we call contexts.
So this is the keep grab model where it basically for an input words we will pick several other words
which we'll call contexts and we want them to appear in this output vector.
So let's say that's word number one corresponds to context words as Number 10 20 and 30 for instance
at the end of this operation.
So after embedding the the word number one and after retrieving information with the context matrix
we want he to have many zeros but we want to have a high number in position 10 20 and 30 which are the
indices that corresponds to the context would that be defined before for the Woods number one.
So in order to get those context words we actually take a huge corpus of texts and for each words we
will take for instance the two previous words and the two next words as context.
So in this sentence in spite of everything I still believe people are really good at Hearts which comes
from the diary of Anne Frank.
If we take the word good it's surrounded by the words are really hot and hot.
So this will produce four pairs of inputs and contexts which will be good.
Are good really good arts and good hearts.
So when we put the words good as inputs so there will be a one only in the position that corresponds
to this word good.
And after embedding it after applying it by the context matrix we want to have the indices corresponding
to are really arts and hot activated of course as good will appear many times in our caucus we'll have
a lot more context vectors as those ones.
But the idea is that it's time we use a pair of input context words we will change those mattresses
the w w prime we will tune the coefficients in order to activate the context words out of the input
words so the global idea about dots was from a single words in one hot unguided version get a smaller
vector and from this smaller vector get several words or activate several words that are often close
to the initial words in our corpus.
So that's pretty clever because we have all embedding face right here but it must convey meaning it
must be semantically efficient in order to retrieve the context information after this operation and
of course this spots was only used for training in order to have something that has meaning.
That's when we embeds a vector.
We only use these spots.
This is the one that we are interested in.
In the end importance an interesting thing to notice is that if two words have a close meaning this
means that they probably in all copies will have similar contexts.
And that also means that they will have a close embedding.
So if we take this sentence again we could argue that the words people could be replaced with humans
for instance.
So as to believe humans are really good at Hearts and that makes sense because humans and people they
convey a similar meaning.
So in all copies we could expect humans and people to usually be surrounded by the same words.
So that means that after we embed the words people all the words humans we get to different imbedded
vectors and within words but when we apply the context metrics we want to get very close results.
Actually pretty much the same results.
So that means that the embedded versions of those two words have to be close and that's where it comes
from what we saw earlier.
That's two words of similar meaning we'll be close in all embedded space.
So that was it for the global idea of what embedding which will allow us to get efficient vectors from
words and so to get a matrix out of a sentence.
If we just want to summarize this what embedding phase using this Skip grab module is that it finds
that dimension reduction in vector representation affords while adding a semantic relation between them
and I would add that this relation is mathematical so that we can use it which turned out operations
in artificial intelligence.
So that was it for the very first step of seeing and applied to entropy which is how to get value inputs
for our CNN of course.
And now we're ready to feed them to sentence and to see what happens in our module and what we will
have to change in order to have properly working CNN full texts.
So that's the topic of the next pots and see you soon.