Hi guys.
And welcome back to this MLP course.
So now that we have all our data processing done we are ready to start writing the code for our deep
convolution of neural network for A.P..
So it just before we do that let's have a quick look at the architecture that we want to implement.
So what we do is that once we have our inputs we will of course starts by applying an embedding layer
and then we will have three different kinds of one D convolution or layer that we want to apply being
of size to three and four.
And we will apply a certain number of each of them.
So each filter after the activation function will give us a new vector and we will take the max of each
of those vectors with Max pulling and concatenate all of this apply a linear function.
So a dense layer.
And finally we will get our classification task done.
So let's start right now by defining a class deep sea and then that we will inherit from Kira's that
model.
So we are defining all own model by inheriting from the T air that carries that model plus.
So we will build our own initialization function.
The call function and we will define all the layers that will be used and right how they should be used.
So when we do that we always have to define these function in it.
That has to be implemented for any model or labor intensive flow and its methods in class will take
self as first parameter and then we just have to tell all the parameters that we wanted to use in order
to build our models so we will need first the size of the vocabulary so we don't know why it will be
yes it will just be given by NISA then we need dimension for the embedding phase.
Let us set some random while not fully random but intuitive.
Default values for those parameters.
Then the number of filters.
So that means for each type of convolution I'll filter.
It's just the number of time that we want to apply it.
Let's say that by default it would be 50 because of course in the paper they said two filters for each
type of filter.
But that was just so that it can fit in one image.
We wanted to use many more of them in order to have a cloud forming model that can learn a lot.
So let's say 50 as a default value then we will need the number of units for the feed for network at
the end and let's sets 512 as default values the number of classes for all classification task.
Let's say that default would be to the drop out rates.
This is during the training.
This is a tool that we use to kind of turn off certain parameters and certain valuables in order to
avoid all the fitting.
That's really standard.
Let's say by default it's 0.01 we would use a training boolean.
So that's the network knows if it's in the training phase or if it's an A evaluation phase.
And this is mainly used in order to know if we wanted to apply the dropouts or not because the drop
outs is only applied to doing training and finally let's give a name to our model does CNN.
Okay.
And first thing we want to do here is to call the init function from the class we are inheriting from.
So this is done by calling super and we have to give the name of the class we are writing right now
self and form super.
We call in its and we just give it the name and that's it's normally our model is initialized properly
using the initialize function from the air that carries that model class.
So now we can start defining the layers that we will use.
So we saw that the first one is an embedding layer equals layers.
That's embedding and for the embedding we need to have the size of the vocabulary and the dimension
of the embedding that we want to achieve.
Now let's define the three different types of features.
So the first one that we call diagram will be layers.
That's.
So it's one dimension convolution layer because the width is the model and we just apply the filter
along one dimension.
So layers that cover on the the number of those features that we want is no filters.
It's all by grams so kernel size which is the.
So the size of our filter would be two for this one putting will be valid in our case it's not really
important which potting method we use because I just tried to we'll be equal to 1 which means that we
will apply our filter by sliding its word by word.
But if we want let's say to just try a number of two or three the last iterations of our filter might
go further than the length of our sequence.
So if we want to apply the filter as many times as possible and thus having the maximum information
we can validate is usually the project method that we wanted to use because it adds the zeros we need
in order to perform from the last convolutions.
But as I said right here we wouldn't change anything because we use astride of one and let's set the
activation function to be really which is very standards and works perfectly well in this kind of situation.
And let's define the pulling layer that we will apply to those filters layers that's global.
Max pool 1 D as well working with one dimensional convolution all layers.
Let's do the same thing.
And by doing the same thing I mean copy pasts with the next type of filters which we call tri gram.
So it's exactly the same thing but this time the kernel size will be three.
And we we will just change the name of the pulling layer right here.
And finally for the third time we will define the foreground again exactly the same principle.
But the kernel size is for and we change this name.
So we have the main parts of our model and all we have to do is to define after the concatenation the
dense layers that are used in order to finally gets the classification task done.
So we first apply a dense layer that will be layers that tense that will be built with a number of units
equal to f f and units.
And again let's use a standard activation function.
So really let us college drop outs key because there is a lot of parameters he and lots of links between
valuables.
This is a good place to apply drop outs in order to avoid the fittings so let's define this layer about
equals layers.
That's drop out rates equals dropout rates and finally we just have to define the last linear function.
The Last Dance layer and the way we will do that it depends on how many classes we have.
If we have two classes then we want to have as outputs just one number which should be between 0 and
1 and if it's below 0 point 5 it means that it belongs to the class 0.
And if it's above all point 5 it means that it belongs to the class 1.
So.
So let's write this.
If the number of classes is 2 then lasts dance layer will be defined but by layers that's dense units
equals 1 and we will use the activation function sigmoid which basically takes any number between minus
infinity and Infinity and we tend to number between 0 and 1 so this is what we always use when we are
doing binary classification.
And if we have more than two classes so let's just say s in this case the last linear function will
be layers that dance and the number of units will be the number of classes and the activation function
will be soft Max.
We've solved Max we get real probabilities all the output numbers will be between 0 and 1 and the sum
will be equal to 1.
This is exactly what probabilities are so that's the best way to end a classification task with more
than two classes.
So now we have all the defining phase but it's done so we can just define the call function.
So this is the function that is used when we call our model.
So basically when we give inputs and we want to get outputs out of it this is the call function that
is used the code methods.
So we always need to use self at first.
Then the call function will use the inputs and these boolean training that we will need in order to
know whether we are in a training phase or not and thus if we wanted to apply the dropouts or not so
first let's say that we apply the embedding to our inputs so X will be equal to serve.
That's embedding inputs and let's define the three outputs of our different filters.
So let's say that x 1 is self.
That's by gram applied to X and Y then wants to apply the pulling to this result.
So x1 equals surf that's pool 1 applied to x 1 then let's do the same thing with x 2 which is the results
of the tri gram.
This one applied to X so that's correct and we apply the pulling to X2 and sending for the foreground
applied to X.
And here this is x3 that we wanted to apply the pulling 2.
So let's merge all that's so merged equals T F dot com cuts and we applied to X1 X2 and X3 that sits
along the axis minus one so along the last axis at this point the first axis represents the batches
the second axis represents the value that we get after applying the max pulling so we wanted to conquer
at all those last values.
And so what we get right after this is something of the shape batch size 3 times no filters because
this number of features P three times once for the diagram then for the program and finally for the
four grams so this is the shape of what we get now.
Next step is to apply our firsts dense layer so that we start the feet forward process.
So let's apply dense 1 to merged.
Then we apply the drop outs right now to merged and we say if it's a training phase or not.
And finally we can get all outputs by calling the lasts dense layer.
And here we are now that we have outputs all we have to do is to return.
It's perfect.
So now we have a fully functional module that has been initialized and can be called to get outputs
from any inputs.
So here we are.
Our model is built.
Now all we have to do is to trainings and we will finally be ready to see if we get good results out
of its popular excited to see how it goes.
And Susan.