Hi guys.
Welcome back to this tutorial.
Here we are for a really quick step.
As you might have noticed if he played through the data we have some really really long sentences in
this corpus and this is an issue for two main reasons.
The first one is that's when we will pads all the sentences.
So we wanted to make all the sentences the same lines for the batch to work.
We will have a huge data sets and the run might be too small to handle this.
The second reason is that it will take a lot of time to train.
If we keep those really long sentences and for this application we don't need to have all those sentences.
And anyway if you have a very powerful machine or if you have access to any other server that has the
adequate power you can keep them all out said the threshold higher but for the sake of this application
we will ask to have a maximum length for the sentence to 20 and you might think that it's quite low
but you will see that it's enough to have really good results.
And we still have a lot of data with this number and unfortunately we can create an array with all the
sentences and then use powerful tools to remove the one we want to remove because if we want to create
an array or 10 so we need all inputs to have the same length which is not the case right now.
And if we Bud's right now in order to make them equally long then the 10 or so of the array will be
too big for the run of the server.
So we will have to use small tricks and the way we do that is we create the viable which which contains
all the indices we want to get rid of.
So I do X to remove will be equal to counts for counts sense sent for a sentence in enumerates inputs
the any rate function is kind of the same as going through all the inputs but instead of just giving
the sentences once it's time it gives the sentence.
And as you can see here it counts.
So the first elements will be zero and the first sentence the second will give one.
And the second sentence and so on.
So this is really handy because we will test if the length of the sentence is too high and if it is
we know that count is the index of this very sentence.
So we can keep it in memory.
So this is what we are doing right now.
If land of sense is greater is greater than the max length.
So here we are list of all the indices we want to get rid of.
So let's do it right now.
We will loop of those indices in reverse.
So I will explain right now why we need to do it in a reversed manner.
Basically let's say that we want to remove the second and the fourth elements.
Once we have removed the second elements of the indices of the elements after those one would be shifted
by one because these one will have disappeared.
So what is now the fourth elements was the fifth before.
So each time we we remove one elements of the indices after all shifted.
So we need to process in the reversed order so that we are removing the right elements.
And now we use the DL function which allows us to remove elements according to their indices right here.
So we of course want to do this for the inputs and for the outputs because we want each input too much
its corresponding outputs.
So now we have removed all the sentences in English that well longer than 20 words and their corresponding
outputs.
And we wanted the same thing for the outputs.
So we want to remove all the sentences in French that are longer than 20 words Let's do it right now.
Let's copy that's posted here.
And basically all we have to change is these spots where we say that we want to use the sentences from
the outputs
and that's it.
We have the code that removes all the sentences that are too long for our application right now.
Actually this part takes some time because as I said before this is really not optimized just because
we can't create an array or attend 10 so with all of the sentences of the same length this would be
too big.
And this is why we have to use this little trick.
This is actually the longest part of the proposed setting.
But once this is done everything will be faster and we are almost ready to build our model populace
excited.
Let's go to the next step and see you soon.