Small clients are just as much work as big clients.
Small customers are just as much work and sometimes more work than big customers.
The reason is smaller customers might not be as sophisticated when it comes to
buying your product or service or they have
a larger portion of their net worth tied up in,
in your company, in your product or service.
So, I've kind of learned the hard way not to deal with small customers,
if you can avoid it.
If you have no alternative customers then obviously you have to.
But if you can try to deal with larger customers only
as there's much less customer support required when dealing with them.
All right. Number four.
Sports is actually very crucial boardroom talk.
I know it sounds funny but I've
found that every person I've met with in business in the United States,
at least, wherever they're from in
the country I always ask them about their baseball team.
I'm a huge baseball fan.
I'm from Toronto, I love the Toronto Blue Jays.
I'm so passionate about baseball. I love it!
And so, if I meet somebody from Kansas,
for example, I'll ask about George Brett,
who is the best player ever played on that team.
Or if I meet somebody from Miami, of course,
I'll ask him about Giancarlo Stanton,
who's I think the best player in the game today.
So, sports is very,
very important boardroom talk and actually golf is very important as well.
You don't see very good at it because I absolutely suck at it.
But, I love doing a lot of business on the golf course.
You're there with your partners,
your customers, your prospective customers.
And you're very relaxed, it's a very social game as well.
So, sports is very important boardroom talk and golf often if you can.
You don't have to be good 'cause I'm bad at it.