Touch hand only once.
You know, when I started working in consulting,
my boss told me that the second an
interoffice envelope or piece of paper touches your hand,
deal with it right away, right away.
And the most successful people are the most busy people. They can accomplish a lot.
And in this day and age,
in a digital setting,
when you see an email, deal with it right away,
right away, right away if you can or flag it and deal with it
later that night if it's something that's gonna take you hours to complete.
But you want to touch hand only once.
You always want to tell yourself, "I do it now,
I do it now, I do it now."
And you'll be much more productive in business and
life if you follow that methodology of touch hand only once.