Two big sales techniques that I've learned from dealing with some of
the most successful CEOs in the world is they do this.
They stop talking once they sense the sale is done.
Okay. Once they've sensed that their customer
actually wants the product or service they're trying to sell,
they actually shut up. They stop talking.
Why? Because what happens is if you keep selling past the close,
then people are going to sense desperation and think that there's
something wrong here and that you might be overselling your product or service.
So you want to stop speaking once you sense that the sale's been made.
OK? And the second thing is — keep selling
until you're convinced that they're not interested.
OK? So if they're interested, stop talking.
But if you're not sure if they're interested,
you keep going man.
You've got to be a pit bull on a pork chop,
so to speak. Awful analogy, sorry.
But, you want to keep selling until you hear the word "no".
And so, quite often when I'm selling,
I'll tell myself in my head,
"All I heard was not 'no'." You gotta be relentless.