Many years ago my dad gave me some advice.
He said you want to keep that letter in your drawer and mail it the
next day and I know that sounds antiquated because we don't use real letters anymore.
But what he was telling me was if you write a letter to somebody or
an email and your tone is slightly negative in that email,
don't send it right away because that might ruin
your career or your reputation or
your relationship with customers or partners or coworkers.
Instead, save it as a draft and then send it the next day.
And I often have my wife,
who's one of my awesome mentors,
she's amazing, I have her read my e-mails,
too, if I'm not sure as well.
And I'm also very careful with tone in e-mails.
I try to include the word please and thank you because
in every e-mail if you don't include please and thank you, and you don't overdo it,
but if you don't come across as very
polite then somebody could read the e-mail out of context.
And so, keep that letter in
your drawer until the next morning and if you still feel like you
want to mail that letter or send that e-mail
then open up your drawer or go to your draft emails and send it.