[Autogenerated] welcome to this course on implementing
analytics in real time data in a W s.
My name is Andrew Estes,
and I am an enterprise cloud architect for CSG
International as well as founder of Quick to Cloud.
This first module in this course is going to
discuss streaming data within a W s.
Now, before we dive into this specific module,
let's just have a quick course overview on what we're
expecting to learn throughout this course.
Now the first thing we want to do is we want to understand the
different use cases for different to nested streams.
Then we'll move on to using data analytic services within a W s.
And these include E M R Red Shift, elastic search and then even quicksight.
And we'll see how these all play well together to
make up analytic architectures.
After that, we're gonna move on to implementing application integration services.
In these services are things like simple notification
service s and S and simple que services sqs.
So we'll look at implementing both and then we'll in the course by
reviewing internet of things also known as I O.
T.
And the different services that AWS offers around I o t.
We'll go ahead and move on to our first module and in this module,
we're going to learn how and when to use can,
is, is.
And this is going to include data, streams,
data, firehose, data analytics and video streams.
So we'll have an overview of each of those.
And then we'll go into the console afterwards and get some hands on experience.
Let's go ahead and in this clip here and we'll pick back up in the next clip. Discussing Ken is is data streams.