[Autogenerated] Okay, let's begin looking at Amazon EMR.
Now, if you've taken the solutions architect,
associate, examine learning path, you should be familiar with EMR.
But for those who aren't,
we'll have a quick review so we can get a general
understanding of what it is before we dive in.
Now M R is a managed cluster platform for running
big data frameworks within a W s.
Now, some examples of those big data frameworks are Apache,
Hadoop and Apache Spark.
So these error very well known frameworks within the big data industry that
allow us to perform different analytics for different data sets.
Now, the neat thing about M.
R is that it allows us to process and then analyzed vast amounts of data.
So we're able to ingest tons of data,
perform some analysis of it and then generate either reports or
some type of output that we can look at later.
And since it's a service hosted on a W s,
it easily allows us to transform and move data into and out
of A W S data stores and data stores.
Here are things like S3 or maybe a relation all database or something similar.
So with the quick review.
Out of the way, Let's go ahead, will dive into the console and we'll start configuring some EMR clusters.