[Autogenerated] all right, welcome back.
Let's dive into Ken.
Is is data streams now.
Can is is data streams are used to collect and process
large streams of data records in real time,
and the beauty of this services that it's accessible via
of VPC or even the public internet.
If you open it up now,
Another major factor is that it has the ability to scale
to keep up with data being produced.
So based off metrics,
we collect we can set our stream sizes to a certain amount of shards,
which we'll talk about here in a little bit in order to keep up with
the massive amounts of data we might be ingesting.
Now can is is data streams also allow us to ingest large amounts of data,
but it also provides durable storage,
and there's a default retention period of 24 hours.
So if there's any failures,
you'll have up to 24 hours by default to replay those records and
maybe re process the data that's within them.
Now, as far as structure goes,
groups of data records and data records are what they sound like.
They're pieces of data that we put into our streams.
They form data streams,
and those get distributed into different shards and shards.
Error.
How we scale our streams for processing.
And we'll look at that here in the console, coming up.
So now that we have a general understanding of data streams,
let's look at an example.
Architecture er So in this diagram, we haven't E.
C.
Two instance hosting a Java application,
and we'll go ahead and assume that this application,
in easy to instantiate as an appropriate I am real
attached to it that allows can, is, is actions.
So what we're doing is, as we're processing data,
our job application is putting records in to arcane
is is data streams in real time.
And with that, we have our consumers on the right,
which are Lambda Functions, and they to get the record in real time.
So a soon as it's put into the stream were able to pull it immediately out,
and then those lamb does go ahead and take that data,
perform some type of action and then store it in S3.
Now, a few things.
The job a application on the EEC, to instance,
is what is known as a producer, so it produces records to put into the streams.
And then our lambda czar What error called consumers.
So they consume the records off of the stream.
So three critical components of a data stream are a producer.
The stream itself with the different shards and then
our consumers on the back end.
Now,
one more thing before we wrap this up and move on to
the console in this part here, where we're getting the records,
these error two separate shards so were scaling out across multiple lamb does,
based on our shard configuration that we made within our data stream.
Let's go ahead and cut here and in the next clip will pick back up within the console and start creating data streams within AWS.