[Autogenerated] Alright, Amazon's simple cue service, also known as sqs.
So what is Sqs?
Well, Sqs offers us a secure,
adorable and hosted cue service for us to use within a W S.
What this allows us to do is to decouple our architecture.
ER, while also integrating are different.
Microsurgery is is so decouple ing and architecture is a key
component in a fundamental understanding.
You have to have to pass the solutions Architect Professional exam.
You have to understand where you can decouple your
pieces for a more optimal workflow.
Now Sqs offers two different types of queues.
There's a standard Q.
And then there's a FIFA Q,
and we'll look at both of those here in the console coming up.
And the beauty of using sqs is there's no requirement for setting up
message brokers in a typical messaging Q system like Amazon.
MQ, for example, or rabbit MQ for on premise cueing systems to use those.
It requires that you set up some type of message broker that consent the
message and received the message from those queuing services.
So Sqs allows us to quickly stand up a cue service within our
architectures and just a fun fact about Amazon Simple que services sqs
was actually the first services ever offered by AWS.
A lot of people think it's compute, but in fact it's actually sqs.
Now with this review out of the way,
let's go ahead and move into the console and start creating and using these different types of queues.