[Autogenerated] All right, let's dive into Amazon s and s.
SNS allows us to have system to system messaging for different architectures.
So how it works is we have a topic.
And then topics have both publishers and subscribers,
and you can see a diagram here on the right that Amazon lays out.
So what happens is publishers send messages to a topic,
and that topic allows us to notify several
subscribers at once using the same message.
Now a publisher does not have to be an application in the sense
of something that you create in your running.
A notification can even come from something like a CloudWatch alarm
that notifies a topic of some action that's going on.
And a really good example of that is using CloudWatch alarms for auto
scaling groups that send notifications to the topic to alert admin is
that it's scaling out or having issues.
So let's just go ahead.
I want to create a new topic.
I'll create one called Pluralsight s and s.
I'll do the display, name the same, and then we have our encryption.
So if we wanted to, we could encrypt our data at rest using kms.
Now you'll notice that in transit encryption is already provided by default.
But they recently added this server side at rest
encryption as an option for compliance.
So I'm gonna disable this.
It moves to our access policy,
and our access policy is what defines who can do what with our topic.
So the default is that only the topic owner can publish and only the
topic owner can define who can subscribe to the topic.
Now, a common scenario for this,
which is similar to this diagram here is you can have the topic owner
still be the only one who can publish messages.
But then maybe you want to notify cross account A W s
accounts with the same message.
So this is extremely popular under enterprise organizations accounts,
so we could have only the topic owner published messages,
But then we allow anyone in different A.
W s accounts to subscribe to the topic.
So that way we can notify several subscribers at once.
Now I'll leave the default here.
We can look at our delivery.
Retry.
So this is defining how many re tries error going to happen if messages
failed to deliver to a HTTP s endpoint and you can see there are several
options here that error specific to this retry policy.
So a number of re tries the different delays,
and then they even have a back off function that you can use.
I'll leave the default.
I'll move on to delivery status logging.
And this is where we can log our delivery status is for our subscriptions.
So for pushing to on AWS lambda, for example,
we can logged the delivery status for those protocols.
So if you want to see or get an insight of how well
your messages error getting delivered, you can use this status logging,
optional setting, and you'll see that when we do this,
it requires permissions to write the CloudWatch logs,
Which makes sense.
So I'm not going to go and collect any logs for this
we can tag it if we wanted to, and then I create.
That's it.
We now have a topic for publishing messages to.
From here we would create subscriptions and depending on our
access policy that we define that determines who can create
subscriptions for this topic.
Now we left the default, so only the owner,
which is me, can create subscriptions.
Let's just go ahead and create one.
You'll see that we can send a several different endpoints,
including Sqs and Lambda.
Now we're going to talk about Sqs and Lambda here in an
upcoming clip when we move into pub sub architectures and
we'll cover a topic known as fanning out.
So for this,
I just want to do email and then let me answer my quick to cloud email in here.
So any time a message gets published to our topic,
this subscriber might quick to cloud email will receive a message.
And below this, we have our subscription filter policy.
So this is a very powerful optional tool that you can use.
So if you have several subscriptions, you can define a policy in here via JSON.
That's saying we wanna look for a specific key in that JSON
message in order to send to the subscriber.
So maybe we're passing a key of email in the message.
And if we match that,
we want to go ahead and send to any email protocol endpoints.
And if it doesn't match the mandatory keys we can set,
it won't even notify this subscriber at all.
So these error very handy when you're trying to filter
out which subscriptions get what?
I'm gonna leave this blank and we can specify a re Docker policy.
So this is a dead letter.
Q.
Now,
we talked about dead letter cues in the previous clip where
we were talking about sqs in general.
So if we wanted to we can send UN delivery ble messages to a particular queue,
and this once again allows for resiliency of processing messages.
So I'm gonna create a subscription here and there we go.
We now get our unique subscription.
IDE and I get an email that's asking me to confirm my subscription,
which you can see here and then once I subscribe,
it brings me to a confirmation screen, and if I go back to my topic,
you'll see that we are confirmed because I just confirmed it via browser.
So now what happens is when I send a message or publish a message to this topic,
I should get an email, so I'll give it a subject.
We'll give it a 62nd time to live.
We can send identical payloads for all protocols,
so email lambda etcetera or we can choose a custom
payload for each delivery protocol,
and you could see them listed here on the left.
So depending on our subscriber type,
that alters the message that sent Now I'm gonna do
identical just since this is simple.
And let me just type a simple message in here, So Pluralsight rocks.
So now that I have my simple message we can set our message attributes.
Now, I'm not going to set any of these,
but this allows us to provide metadata on our messages
for our subscribers to pull if needed.
So let me go ahead and I'm gonna publish this message.
We get a success.
And now in a second, I should get an email from my SNS topic, and I already did.
That's how fast it was.
And this is what it looks like here.
With this screenshot,
you can see our subject line and then you can see our
Pluralsight rocks message that we just sent.
So that's how easy it is to create a topic and then published two and
subscribe to it to receive messages almost immediately.
So a valid use case would be to set up some type of alarm notification for
maybe your compute and then have a W s automatically published to a topic
that has maybe a cloud admin as a receiver or subscriber who can take action
and look in to see what's going on now.
One last thing Before we wrap up, we have our subscriptions page,
so this shows us all of our subscriptions.
Within this region, you can see I have two different topics.
I have an admin alert and then the one I just created.
So this admin alert is an example of what we were just talking about.
Anytime I get messages for alerts,
I get emails to my quick to cloud email specifying what the message was.
So with that,
let's go ahead and wrap up here and then we're
going to pick up in the next clip, talking about pub sub architectures with fanning out.