You guys walking back to the advice our programming course in this tutorial we're going to go through
it for a walk through Africa.
If you were part of our program in Ada Zed's the first course in this series and you'll remember our
walks today we've got another walk.
And once again I wanted to give you a heads up very soon you do me is going to ask you to leave are
you for this course.
Now I know it can be difficult to judge of quality and value of a course this early on.
However the university system has simply changed and they are asking you to leave review earlier and
earlier on in the course.
If you can hear a go I'm following.
I go here.
So now with that in mind we're not going to ask you to leave a fire sorry for this cause but what I
would like to ask is that if you're not familiar enough with the contents of the Course just check these
gals areas.
Hello.
Yeah.
So if you're not familiar enough of the content of the course Zoraida farceur of course then please
scroll through.
Please have a look at all of the amazing things that will cover the different case studies that will
have inside this course adds to the different topics in our program and that you will learn how you
will boost your skills and hopefully that will give you the confidence to write the score so far.
So of course if on the other hand you are unsatisfied about something if you think something is wrong
with the course then please do let us know.
Let us know before you rate the course you can contact the Super this support team directly or you can
leave us a short message in the course Q&amp;A.
Your feedback is very valuable to us by the way.
That's a that's about barabar over there.
Your feedback is very valuable to us and we will get back to you or we will fix up whatever the issue
is and then get back to you and hopefully that will give you the confidence to rate this course of course.
Now on that note if something's wrong then please do let us know.
But if you are satisfied of course if you think everything is going well if you're excited about boosting
our programming skills and if you feel that this is a faster of course then please do rate it appropriately
so that other people will also know that this is a five star course on our programming and they can
to boost their skills here.
So there you go guys that was a quick little walk through Africa and that was a quick heads up about
what's coming up.
Hopefully enjoy this walk and I'm really hopeful that you're excited about the journey ahead as you
have in this course and how are going to boost your programming skills and all the amazing things that
you will.
I really look forward to seeing inside the tutorials.
And until next time I'll be analyzing.