Hello.
Welcome back to the advanced course on our programming in the studio we loaded up our data set into
our studio so we can see this line here.
And we had a look at the different snapshots of our daughter so we looked at the top rows we looked
at the bottom rows we saw that there was indeed 500 rows we saw what columns we have there we looked
at the structural dataset and we looked at the summary.
Now from the structure we noticed that there's quite a lot of factors that have been recognized in our
data and that's why today we're going to talk about factors.
We're going to refresh on the nausea factors.
We're going to find out what they are and how to deal with them in our.
So it's going to be a quick recap and I think it's going to be useful because further down in the section
we're going to be dealing quite a lot with factors.
All right so what is a factor and why is our recognizing some of these variables as factors Well if
factor is basically a categorical variable in our.
Now let's look at one of these as an example.
Industry for instance right.
It's a factor with eight levels.
And if we go down here to the summary we'll see that there's I.T. services health software financial
services construction government and that makes six.
So there's two more here.
And one of them is an empty category so the empty carrier that we see here as well.
So here you have a few examples you've got empty categories and example in construction and then there's
more.
And then you've got these numbers Well these numbers are the identifiers that are assigned to each one
of the categories.
For instance the empty category has been assigned identifier of.
And construction has been assigned the identifier of six.
And that's basically how our deals with these categorical variables because it is a programming language
and all happens in your computer for our.
It's just easier to deal with numbers rather than with words.
For us humans is easier to deal of words like construction I.T. services health and so far is just easier
to deal with numbers.
And this is going to be an important point that is going to come up again.
And one of the future tutorials so just remember that our dogs deal with factors in a numerical sense
rather than in a word a sense or character sense and the way our picks up factors is if our cannot recognize
it as an integer or as other type of number or a boolean variable some kind of a variable that has meaning
to it then are just recognize it as a category as a category.
And most commonly that happens with words with characters because for instance here we've got names
of companies right.
So we've got all the names of companies and our has also recognized that is a factor a factor a variable
with 500 levels because every single name is unique in our data set and therefore it's created this
factor variable which doesn't really bother us that's just how are is going to deal if it's going to
treat as a categorical variable if we wanted to we could change it back into a character because ultimately
it's not really a category it's just the names of the companies.
Then if we go down we find something interesting so inception is the year when the companies were created
and here are has recognized that as an integer and same thing id so IDs identifier of the row and R
has recognized it as an integer.
Now if we really think about that do we really want ID to be an integer.
Do we really need a minimum do we need a median a maximum or are we going to performers arithmetic rip
operations with this variable.
No it's just a numeric variable that is assigned to our rows and we don't want to perform an energetic
operation.
So it could it probably is better if it's recognized as a factor and that will be less confusing to
us.
And same thing for Inception.
We're definitely not going to add these years are not going to subtract any of these years for us it's
just going to be more convenient if we see this variable as a factor.
So those are two examples of when a variable is not recognized as a factor by our.
But we wanted to be recognized as a factor.
Now another example here that you'll see is an example of the opposite.
So here we see a state is OK as a factor series.
Okay.
And then we see revenues recognize the factor and expenses are wickednesses affection and same thing
for Grof.
So while profit is recognized as an actual number these three are not.
And let's have a look at why this is happening.
Well this is happening because for instance in revenue we've got this dollar sign and we've got these
comma's which are cannot convert into a number it doesn't know that this is the numbers recognizing
it as a character and then converting it to factual and then expenses.
Same thing we've got the commerce we've got the space and we've got the word dollars and that is preventing
our from recognizing this verbal as an actual number.
And finally in growth we've got when do we have we have this percentage sign which is preventing our
from recognizing this as a number.
So that's an example of when something is recognized as a factor but in reality it should be numeric
.
And that is also something that we're going to need to fix up.
So in this tutorial we're actually just going to correct the first thing because it is actually very
easy to change something from a non-factor to a factor so let's go ahead and do that.
So here we're going to say changing from non factor to factor.
Let's have a look at how we do that.
So here we've got a variable or a column which is a thin dollar idea and that gives us access to the
ID column.
So as you can see there it is as a vector.
And now we're going to turn to factor just use the factor function and put it around you ID.
We run that.
Now you can see that same thing.
This is the vector for that column but at the end it actually has levels and as we said levels is a
give away for factors.
And now we're just going to override the ID with our variable over here.
So our new factory airball.
So now if we look at a summary or fin you will see that ID is also recognizes factor and we can confirm
that by looking at S-G or for in.
So here you can see that now it is also a factor.
So let's go ahead and do the same for Inception.
So we're going to say in dollar sign in ception is going to be overridden by a factor of when a dollar
sign inception around that.
And we look at those go to Estuardo way here you'll see that Inception is now a factor.
So it's as easy as that.
And if we look at the summary so just copy this way here.
So here you can see that if your conception now it's on giving you the minimum the maximum the median
and so on is just giving you the categories that you have and you can actually tell that there's 93
companies that were started in 2011 83 in 2010 18 2012 and so on and so it's much more committed like
this and not confusing.
And moreover it will be it will allow us to categorize the companies by the year of their foundation
.
So there we go that's what factors are and how to convert and non-fact into our factor.
Moving forward we'll talk about some other interesting aspects of dealing with factors.
And I look forward to seeing you on the next tutorial.
Until then happy coding