Hello welcome back to that ball's course in our programming.
In today's tutorial we've got a very interesting and even intriguing topic.
We're talking about the fact variable trap or the FBT.
So the fact of verbal trap comes into play when you're trying to convert a variable from a factor or
a column from a factor into a non-factor.
We've already talked about the other way we've talked about Turing from nonfactor to Fact is pretty
simple you just use a factor function.
But today we're going to talk about how to convert factors into non-factors.
And that's where this pitfall arises.
Now bear in mind if you do search for factory level trap on Google you probably won't find much because
I came up with this term just for these tutorials.
It's a known phenomenon but it isn't very well publicized it's not much discussed and I really don't
know why not enough attention has been brought onto this issue and that is because it is a major pitfall
that a lot of programmers end up falling into and just simply by covering it in the tutorial.
I'm sure you will get the right knowledge and preparation to avoid this pitfall and know how to deal
with it when you come across it.
So without further ado let's dive straight into it.
Let's see what we're talking about here.
A few minutes we're going to forget about our data set that we've been working with and we're going
to create a new vector so we'll create a vector A.
And into that vector we're going to put the following values.
So we're going to put in 12 13 14 and then we'll just put in 12 and 12 again.
So five values all in quotation marks.
If I look at a now you'll see that we've got the five L's here but because of the quotation marks I
specified they are being stored as characters and not as numerics.
And I can confirm that by just looking at a type of a.
You'll see that it's a character.
Now what would we do if we want to get to the bottom of these values so we want to actually deal with
them as numerics rather than as characters so we want to maybe add them subtract them and perform other
arithmetic operations what would we have to do if a in order to convert it to an American picture.
Well it's very simple we would create a vector b and into that vector we would put the result of calling
the falling function as numeric as an American word something into a numeric.
And here we're going to pass on the vector.
So far on that.
And now we look at B.
You'll see that we've got the same values 12 13 14 12 12 followed the quotation marks.
And if I call now type of B you'll see that it's a double.
So a double is a type of the Merak and therefore we can perform it's megacorporations if we wanted with
this action.
So that's a great way to convert characters into numerics.
So here we can just say four characters but now the question is how do you convert factors into numerics
.
Right.
So let's say converting into numerics just so that there's no confusion because the effect variable
trap actually has nothing to do with this part.
It's only for the second part.
So here we can say converting into the merits or factors.
All right.
So let's have a look at this.
How would you convert a factor into an America.
Well the first thing is we need to create the factor right.
So let's say we have a factor is that which is going to be exactly the same as vector A.
So let's take that with the only difference that is going to be the factor as version of this picture
.
So what does that mean.
Well it basically means that we're telling our Could you please take this vector and treated as a categorical
so take these categories and create a fracture for us where you've recognized these different values
that you find in this vector as carriers.
So if you run this line we've got our vector Zed.
If I run that now you'll see that we've got 12 13 14 12 12 and bear in mind the quotation marks are
not shown here.
What you also see is the levels so are can see the different levels because our knows that it's actually
dealing with sets.
And just to show you the quotation marks here.
But at the same time it depreciates that these are indeed categories so it's not recognizing them as
numbers.
But what can be confusing to us is that we might think that these are recognized as numbers right.
So what would we do if we wanted to convert them to numerics now.
Right so if we said OK we've got this factor variable how do we get rid of this factorization just convert
a to a normal numeric vector.
We might try to do the same thing as we did over here.
We might say we want a new vector Y and we want to say as numeric and vectors then right.
And that's your first inclination.
Once you want to do is all right I want to get to the bottom of these numbers I want to be able to deal
with them not as a factor I want to deal with them as a numeric vector.
How do I do that.
And we're going to run as the merit of zed around and boy look at why Whoa.
Very different right.
1 2 3 1 1.
What's going on here.
Why is it not 12 13 14 12 12.
This is this is completely not what I wanted and if I look at type of Y.
Right.
It's a double.
That's what.
It's exactly what I was expecting here like type of B type of Y.
So we did exactly the same things.
So here we did be as Americ a Y as an exam but the result is completely different.
What happened here.
Well what happened is we picked up the actual factorization of the variable rather than the factors
themselves.
And to understand that a bit better let's run a quick line here.
After we created said this look at type of zed if you like a top of that is actually integer.
Right.
So said is being seen as an integer but doesn't mean this integer that's inside here.
The integer that is that is Zed is the factorization integer.
So let's understand that a bit better because this is basically the essence of this whole factor variable
trap.
So is going to create that line there.
And if I look at that again.
So this is at 12 13 14 12 12.
What are does is it says OK levels 12 13 14.
And as we discussed previously what a factor is is basically are seeing these as categories or seen
this vector that it can be broken down into categories.
And indeed indeed it can.
There's a category of 12 that comes up three times.
There's a category of 13 comes up once in a category of 14 which also comes up once.
And so what does Arlan do.
Then it shows these categories as levels well all the cold levels you can call them categories.
And then in the back end of our what it does it is is it assigns just numerics to them says this is
Category number one category number two category number three.
And therefore when we look at it we see 12 13 14 12 12 when our looks at it it sees 1 2 3 1 1 because
that's how they have been coded right.
It doesn't matter what numbers I have here or if I have countries here or I have names or any other
anything that can be categories.
What are is doing is it is coating them with numbers so that is number one category number one carrier
number two category three that category number one again and number one are you.
So when you're trying to convert using the as Mary function what you will get is the categories so that's
where you get the 1 2 3 1 1 rather than the actual numbers that you want.
And that is the essence of the factor bearable trap that programmers who are not very aware of this
or analysts are data scientists who are not aware of this can easily fall into this trap.
And the worst part is that if you're expecting an American then you get this and you don't double check
your work you can proceed to using these wrong numbers in your results and you will get completely incorrect
results.
So how do we avoid this fact verbal trap or how do we actually convert that into a numeric in this case
.
Well the correct way to do it is to first convert the Zed into character and then convert it into a
factor.
So what we do is we say as a character and I would say Zed right if we run that then you got to 12 13
14 12:12 we without the levels.
And if I go as dark Gnumeric around that and I put that into variable x and now I look at X you will
see that 12 13 14 12 12 have been released.
So from a factor they turned into a character for my character.
They turned into a numeric So basically after they've turned into character we're repeating this process
.
And so now if I look at type of x you'll see that it is a double.
So keep that in mind.
This is the factor variable trap that you cannot convert something that is a number that should be a
or is recognized as a factor that should not be recognized as a fact you cannot convert that right into
a number right away because you will inevitably and inadvertently pick up the factorization values right
so you'll pick up the numbers that are uses within its backhand for itself rather than the numbers that
you're after if you want the numbers that actually are contained in that in these quotation marks.
Then you first need to convert it to a real character.
So as character and then convert it into numeric.
So I know this may be a bit overwhelming at first.
I have a play around with that try experiment create a few of your own vectors to really understand
this better.
And then we will start slowly implementing this in our daughter preparation phase so basically the following
tutorials of the section is a very important part and is going to play a big role in how we approach
conversion of the remaining columns into their correct types.
Hope you enjoy this tutorial and I look forward to seeing your next one.
And until then have a coding