Hello and welcome back to the advanced course on our programming.
Hope enjoy the tutorial.
And today we're starting to talk about how to filter out doorframes when they do contain missing values
.
So in this tutorial which will be a tutorial one of a two part series we're going to talk about how
to filter non missing data.
So records with non-missing done.
So I'll give you an example of what we're talking about today.
Let's have a look at our data set.
And let's look at the top couple of rows.
Right.
And let's say I want to just single out this one row or every single row that has a revenue of nine
million seven hundred forty six thousand two hundred seventy two dollars.
Right so going to copy this value what would we normally do.
We would go and say it would say fin and inside fin would obviously all this create the filter for us
.
Let's go step by step right so would say let's make some space and I'd say fin dollar sign.
Revenue equals this right.
So what does that give us and gives us a boolean vector where every road is checked and basically that
row is picked out as true.
So now if we apply this filter in our data frame we're safe in square brackets then the filter than
common nothing.
So basically that's our filter over their income and nothing.
And if we run this you will see that that Roe has indeed been picked out.
There it is.
But also we have these random mysterious rows where did they come from.
What are they doing here.
They don't have IDs they don't have names they don't have industries anything everything is N.A. in
these roles.
What is going on here or why have they come up.
So the reason why they have come up is because if you look at this filter that recreated it actually
has an ace.
So you can see and hear right and you can see one or here it's hiding.
So there it is.
So that's the end.
That's an over there and that's a.
So those days are coming from the fact that our daughter said actually contains values.
If I scroll up when we're exploring here you do see that we have values that have or rows that have
and they in the revenue column.
And so what happens when you compare Feehan dollar revenue.
Right.
So when you we were basically taking this call on this whole column and we comparing it to this value
.
So there you go.
So are goes through your Rosens like OK.
MATSCH So that's true.
And then you get to this one.
So this won't be falls falls falls falls but when you get to this one what I would say is oh ok I'm
comparing nine nine million 746 cells to 72 turn empty value.
And remember what we did back then what did we do.
We checked that.
Does this equal turn.
The answer is N.A. it's not true.
It's not false so basically Our doesn't know what to do.
Does adro past the filter or does Adderall not pass the filter because the value is empty.
And that's why our.
Tells you about it by supplying these rows it's telling you that hey look I found this row that you're
looking for.
The rest didn't pass the test except for two.
They are two Rosing your daughter said that had a missing value in that specific column that you're
looking for.
And so that's why that's how I'm telling you about it.
I'm just going to tell you that this whole there's a whole ENERO and a hole and a row again.
So I know it might be a bit confusing like why doesn't our just bring up this whole row with it and
say well let's think about it.
If what the other option or could do is actually bring up all these values and write the correct values
for that row and then keep it here and then correct values here.
But that would imply that that Roe actually passed the test that retro matches our criteria.
And that is one of the ones we're looking for which is not the case.
And so in this way our is actually protecting us from making incorrect analysis or performing critical
analysis because if we're not just looking at visually if we perform some calculation taking averages
and so on for us we're taking the average of the number of employees for all of the rows that contain
this desired revenue value.
Then if it had brought up the correct values here for these roses as well then we would get an incorrect
average.
So that's just one of the examples.
Basically our needs to tell you that there is.
And they and this is the best way that they've come up of doing it.
So just be conscious of that if you are filtering your data set which is like the standard way to filter
a data frame.
If you filter your data frame and then there aren't any values you'll get these mysterious rows come
up which sometimes can cause cause issues or even make you feel a bit uncertain of where your code is
correct.
So what are we going to learn now is we going to learn how to deal with this how to actually correct
filter our data set the correct way.
So what are we going to do is simply say let's just bring that up.
So once again we're looking for this value in our data said what we're going to do is instead of just
performing that filter what insight.
Here we go in to specify which operator.
So once again let's probably start step by step.
We're going to say which.
And then we will put Which around these brackets and what does that do.
Well basically let's run let's run this first and then let's run this whole.
So as you can see we've got just one number here.
Where is this number come from well what which does this look at the question mark which will be helpful
.
So let's zoom in here and it says which indices are true give the true indices of a logical object allowing
for error indices and what that means is that which will look through your vector.
So this is a vector and it looks through all of your vector and it only picks out the values the true
value.
So it doesn't.
It ignores falses it ignores that ignores that picks out that ignores ignores ignores ignores and the
beauty is that which also ignores and says so.
It will completely get rid of all their names and all the forces and only return the true value and
that way you're left with just the numbers representing the correct rows that you want.
So basically now you're going to be parsing once we once had do this once I take this filter and pass
it to our doorframe here and then comment nothing.
So previously we used a logical vector to filter our data set.
Now we're actually parsing the row numbers and as you remember you can do it.
Either way you can say I want fin 3 4 and 5 right so obviously like that.
That will give me the third fourth and fifth fros or I can say True true true false false false and
so on to specify which rows exactly are 1.
So here we are taking the second approach Preece we use the true false vector.
Now we are overlaying the which operator on or a function on top of the true force vector which will
now return us just the row numbers just a picture of row numbers.
We need to pick out that correlate just to correspond just to the true values and then once we use that
what we get is just that one row that we are after we fought those days.
So let's have another example.
One of those examples that say.
Let's look at Fin or head Finn.
Right.
So here what I can see is that let's pick a let's say industry or no industry there'll be will be way
too many let's say employees.
I know that there's an end here and there is I think yeah there's this one and this whole dataset.
So if I pick out all the companies that have 45 employees it's all good that so fin thin dollar employees
equals forty five common nothing around that.
You'll see that it's picked out indeed 45 45 45 45.
Oh in fact there were two and a so there is one in a here you can see that there was a company with
an AA in the employees and so are give you these values.
And then there was another one and a one later further down in the data set.
So that's what our does.
Now how do I get rid of these emails and my final result.
Very simple.
I'm going to just copy this line and here I'm going to say which.
So which of these values are actually exactly true.
Run that as you can see just the employees just the companies with 45 employees and no NHS.
So there we go.
That's the power of the which operator.
Sounds pretty funny right.
The power of the witch.
I hope you enjoy this Tauriel and will continue with this two part series in the next one.
I look for you then.
Until next time happy coding