We'll come back to the advanced course in our programming.
In the previous tutorial we applied the median imputation method to our employees call and today we're
going to start by applying the same method to our growth column.
As you can see we still have and and they in the grove call.
So let's go ahead and do that.
This should be super quick because we already know what we are doing very very well.
So I'm just going to actually copy this line into here and now we're going to form a similar operation
to what we had there.
So we're going to calculate the median for growth and it is in the industry of construction.
So construction we're going to by the way if you feel comfortable then you can just pause this video
and perform all of this on your own.
And then we can compare.
So median finance data set industry this is going to be construction and we're not looking at them please
.
We're looking at growth and remove and as true.
So there we go we've got value.
Let's look at the value.
It's 10.
So the actual average growth in that is you actually get very curious what would happen if I remove
this filter what is the average growth across all industries.
Right.
So very quickly on this it's 15.
So it's higher.
So the construction industry grew less than the industry is that the overall industries OK and that's
something to keep in mind.
Maybe you could check that later on.
Just to make sure we're on the right track.
All right so now we're going to say we're going to apply this value or we're going to find the value
we want to replace it once it is and they finish a sign and growth and then we want to say and finish
all the sign industry is indeed in the construction industry our rights common nothing.
So that should bring us that value that we want to replace.
Yes it is call role number eight.
And so now we just take the Slyne and we say ROFE and we assign this value that we have here and now
we just want to check it was line 8.
So thin is correct.
Nothing.
There we go.
We can see that the growth has been applied.
So now if we run this you will see that we only have just a few rows left.
This fall we're agreed we're not going to touch and we have.
So we have three to deal with.
All right.
So this we're going to keep full later because or actually let's go back to the ExCel.
So we've fixed this up.
Smoke screen.
We fixed this up and there's a couple rows at the bottom.
So we're going to keep this for later because this requires some different method you cannot just computed
from the averages over here because it has to be aligned with the revenue and profit so you have to
calculate this and we'll do it in a separate tutorial and then are we what we can do is we can impute
the revenue and expenses using the median imputation method.
So basically exactly the same thing as we did with employees and as we did with growth all you have
to do is calculate the median for the revenue for this industry or actually let's go back here.
So you'll see that there's one company there's actually two companies in the construction industry that
you need to calculate the rowing for.
So the only way is going to be a bit different is that you're going to be assigning two values at the
same time.
But basically all of the code is exactly the same so revenue let's calculate revenue then will Kalka
expenses and then I'll show you how to derive profit for these two rows and then expenses for this one
row separately.
So what we're going to do now is we're going to how are we going to structure it is we're going to actually
I'm going to end this tutorial here and that will encourage you to perform this exercise on your own
.
And then in the next tutorial I'll show you the solution and we'll walk through it so you can check
and verify that you know we've got the same code and maybe make any corrections if you need to.
And then we'll proceed onto the remaining parts.
So there we go.
Good luck with that as a mini exercise.
I'm sure it will come in handy.
And I also encourage you not to copy paste the code but rather to just type it up from scratch.
That will give you some additional experience and I'll look for it see you next time.
Until then happy coding
.