Hello welcome back to that bonce course in our program today we have a very advanced tutorial ahead
of us.
Now this isn't a compulsory tutorial so feel free to skip it or if you don't get the hang of it right
away doesn't really matter.
You can always come back to it later and recap on it at the same time I did want to share this information
because we've learned a lot about the plie functions and if you have been keeping up with these tutorials
and you've been soaking up all this information then you are probably thirsty for a real hard challenge
and this is exactly what we're going to have today.
We're going to combine a few new concepts and we're going to learn with quite a few Also concepts that
we have already possed or have already talked about in this section of the course and we're going to
create something very very powerful.
All right.
So what are we off to today.
Today we are after a result that will tell us something that we haven't yet found so let's look at this
matrix over here.
So we've got the cities at the top and then we've got the metrics on the left so this is a matrix of
the maximums or deliverable 3 where we have for instance Chicago right.
And then out of all of the average high fahrenheits in the weather list here for Chicago.
So here we know that the highest was 84 so as you can see this matrix Let's make some more space.
You can see that this matrix has 84 here and then average Loceff 68 was the highest.
There we go some maxim average precipitation in inches 413 was the maximum out of this whole row.
So there it is.
It's in our result and and 11 was the maximum in this row and hours of sunshine was the maximum in this
role.
So there it is in our result as well.
So the question now is how can we create a matrix that is similar to this but instead of the numbers
let's say we don't care about the numbers we want them months we want to know when was the highest temperature
it was in July when was the highest out of the lowest temperatures also in July when was the highest
average station in inches.
It was in May.
You know when was a days highs days of precipitation.
First one was in March and our house of sunshine when was that 318 that was also in July.
So how can instead of the numbers we can actually get a matrix with the names of the months when that
event happened maybe we're not interested in the numbers we're interested to understand the seasonality
of these effects.
How do we do that.
All right so that is where we introduce the new concept which is which Max which actually allows us
to perform something of that nature.
So let's look at up first of all we always do this which don't.
We always check the question mark because that can give us some ideas.
So let's zoom in here.
Where is the minimum or maximum or first.
True or false.
So here determines the location index of the first minimum or maximum or of a numeric or logical vector
.
So very simple to which we've already worked with.
So usage which men which Max and so x can be in America logical or logical integer or double.
So let's close this now and let's proceed to which Max basically returns the index.
So let's say we have Chicago right so there's a Chicago matrix from Chicago matrix we're going to take
the first row just take the full first roll.
There's our first row.
Now if we apply which Max here which doesn't Max what are we going to get.
We're gonna get the index of where that maximal occurred so as you can see it's 1 2 3 4 5 6 7.
It's telling us it's on the seventh position and actually giving us the name over here on the top because
it was named vector which is very convenient in our case.
All right.
So how can we move from the 7 to the actual name.
Very simple.
We're just going to literally use this name because this is a named vector even though it looks like
just one number.
It is still a named vector as we remember everything and our is a vector is just a vector of length
1 and so we can say names.
And then we're going to take this and we're going to put it inside names.
That gives us July OK.
So that's a good start.
But as you can imagine holy done that for one city and we've only done that for one role.
So we're only doing that for one row.
What does that tell us.
Well that tells us that we need to add two iterations.
We only done that for one row whereas we need to do it for all of the rows.
Sounds like an apply type of iteration right.
So this is how you think about this problem.
We've done this for one row or five so we need to do this this for all the rows.
And when you need to do something for all the rows that sounds like an applied type of iteration and
then I've only done it for one matrix or one city out of four cities that we have a list.
And when we need to iterate over a list what does that sound like.
That sounds like an L apply or an air supply type of attrition.
So by the sounds of it we will have apply right to iterate over rows of Matrix and we will have L apply
or apply to iterate over component size of the list.
So there is an apply probably.
And one of these two.
So let's see how we can bring all this to life.
All right so the first part is going to be the Apply function.
Let's type it up and what are we going to apply.
So we start by working with Chicago which will be our guinea pig matrix and once again and then we're
going to apply to the rows because we want to work the rows and then we want to apply a construct like
this.
How do we do that.
Well we're going to call our own function we're going to say function X right so that is going to be
the role.
So this construct or here is going to be iterating over the rows of Chicago and it's going to be passing
them on to this function as X.
And so all we have to do is copy this part paste it in here and replace Chicago one because that's the
role that we were testing this bit of code on.
Now we just need to replace it with X.
So once again apply we'll be iterating over Chicago over the rows.
This concept will pick out the first row and the second the third the fourth or fifth and every time
it'll pass on the row here for the first row the second or third the fourth the fifth in exactly this
form it will be Chicago 1 km and I think Chicago to come Arthur's show with three coming I think every
time it will be passed on as X into this construct names which Max and then the results of this will
be the result of apply.
So let's have a look at that.
I run this line you will see that apply has created this named vector for us and that is that first
row the result of the first shot was the July average low F.
So that's the second row.
The result was July 3rd row may then march and then June July as well.
So hopefully this makes sense that's exactly what we wanted exactly what we're talking about.
And now what we're going to do is we're going to take this a step further so we've done this part we've
used apply for iterating over those of the matrix.
Now we're going to add the next level where we want to iterate this whole construct and that is why
this is an advance tutorial because we are iterating we've got a function and apply function and now
we're going to take this apply function and we want to iterate that over our whole list.
That's where we're going to add the L apply.
All right so let's apply.
All right what do we want to iterate over the list cold weather and what we want to iterate is we want
to iterate this whole construct.
So basically what we want to do is want to replace Chicago now with that every time the new matrix so
it sort of just having Sragow they'll be l apply will be iterating over the matrices of weather and
it will be putting them in here.
So how do we do that.
Well it is a function and we want why and then here we're going to take this construct everything here
and we're going to place it right in there.
All right so now we need to replace Chicago with why.
Why is that.
Well because l apply whether we'll iterate over the components of weather which are Chicago New York
Houston San Francisco and every time it put that component in here and then this magical happened where
apply will go through the rows of that component put the rows in here and then which Max will do its
thing.
And that names will do its thing.
And so it does look complicated but that's what happens when you nest one thing and sends out another
and another.
So we've got three nice things here.
We've got that's nested inside plie or probably Tuna's things that's inside that are in essence how
to apply apply as nested inside of L apply.
So for on this you can see that for Chicago we've got that same vector that we already had before.
And then we've got there another one for New York another one for Houston and another one for San Francisco
.
You can see the values are changing so that's a good thing.
That means we're not just replicating the same vector again and again.
And in order to make all this look pretty.
What can we do.
That's right.
Just to supply voila How beautiful is that.
And literally takes one line of code.
So there's everything here is just preparation.
This is just that one line of code that we are after and we've got all matrix where we've got the cities
at the top and we've got the metrics on the left.
So that is quite an advanced technique to use an our.
And congratulations if you got to the end of the story and you understood everything get your head around
everything.
If there was anything that was unclear don't worry just either do some finish the rest of the trolls
in this section and practice a little bit more then come back to the store or just re watch this Tauriel
and just take it step by step and practice all of these things with maybe some of your own examples
or slight changes just to really understand these things because ultimately this is indeed one of the
more advanced techniques in our or specifically apply type of functions.
But at the same time it gets even harder or even more complex than this.
So eventually it's a good idea to be quite comfortable with even techniques like the one that you saw
in this tutorial and I hope you enjoyed creating these constructs today.
And I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy coding.