Welcome back everyone to this section of the course on deep learning for natural language processing
our goals for this section are to understand a basic overview of deep learning.
Then we'll move on to understanding specific types of neural networks such as recurrent known networks
or r and n and Ellis Tim a long short term memory unit which is going to be useful when using it to
generate text from source corpus.
So later on in this section of course we're going to actually read in source material such as the Moby
Dick novel and then use our neural networks to generate brand new text in the same style as the original
source Corpus.
Then we'll also learn how to create q and a chat box with Python and recurrent neural networks.
There's a lot to learn so let's get started.
I'll see you in the next lecture.