Welcome back to this lecture on vocabulary and matching with Spacey so far we've seen how a body of
text is divided into tokens and how individual tokens are parsed and tagged with parts of speech dependencies
and limitation.
In this lecture we're going to identify and label specific phrases that match patterns we can define
ourselves.
We can think of this as a powerful version of regular expression where we actually take parts of speech
and to account for our pattern search.
Let's explore this concept with Spacey by jumping over to Jupiter notebook or a hearing him in a new
notebook quite important Spacey and loaded the English library as well.
So I want to point out quickly is we have a couple of tables inside the vocabulary and matching notebook
that are going to be really useful free to reference.
If you come back to an LP Python basics and open up vocabulary and matching here and scroll down there's
a couple of tables such as this from right here for additional parameters and quantifiers.
And scroll down here there's other tokened attributes that we're going to talk about.
So we have these tables here.
I encourage you to reference them and we'll jump a little bit back and forth between these two notebooks
to reference some of the code here.
Let's go ahead and get started.
First off we're going to talk about rule based matching.
Spacey offers a rule matching tool called matcher and that allows you to build a library of token patterns
then match those patterns against a doc object to return a list of found matches a very similar idea
to regular expressions that we saw earlier.
They can think of this is kind of a more powerful version of that and you can actually match from any
part of the token including text and annotations and you can add multiple patterns to the same matcher.
Let's show you how to import the natural library will say from speccy dot matcher import matcher and
then we're going to create a mature object by saying matcher and then we pass in the current vocab of
this an LP object.
So we say matter is equal to matter passing in an LP that vocab.
So here matter is an object that pairs the current vocab object and we can add or remove specific names
matchers to match her as needed.
So we're going to take this matter object and then add or remove to it.
So it's time to find patterns.
So we need to create patterns that we actually want to match on.
And the way this works in fact will create several patterns.
So say pattern one for the first one.
The way this works so spacey is you have a list and you're going to provide essentially a series of
dictionaries into this list.
So the first one we're going to say the key is lower.
And then the value is solar power.
So we're going to read 8 documents or a string in and we're going to try to find solar power and solar
power can appear in the following ways.
We wanted to test it if it appears as one word if it appears with a dash in the middle or if it just
appears as two words.
So solar power.
Single word solar power or a dash or solar power.
Two words we're basically going to try to protect all three of these patterns.
So for the first pattern here we're just detecting if you transform that tokens to all lowercase.
Does it match to solar power.
The second pattern that we're looking for is the one with some sort of punctuation like a dash in the
middle.
So the way that one's going to work is the following will say lower for the term solar comma.
The next dictionary inside of this list is going to be if a key is underscore punk.
And let's make sure that's all capitalized.
So that sense for is punctuation colon will pass in the boolean true.
That's basically asking is this token lowercase Soler then is there punctuation and then we're going
to pass in one more dictionary with lower as a key and then we're going to ask is the lowercase equal
to power.
So this is actually going to find various different types of punctuations in between solar and power
not just the hyphen.
So now pattern three.
Let's go ahead and just say lower.
Should we spell that right.
Is lower equal to solar and then is the token immediately following this when it's lowercase is that
the string power.
So here we're not able to the text for various use cases and I'm going to kind of match them up here
so it's able to tacts the one word pattern that's pattern one pattern to is able to the texts Soler
than some punctuation and then lowercase power and then pattern 3 is able to text the word solar space
and then power.
So we have these three patterns that we want to match on and you can check out again the tables on this
vocab and matching as well as it links the documentation in order to figure out what you want to provide
in as keys.
So you can scroll down here and we have various parameters and if you keep scrolling down you can see
the attributes so we have lower which is in our case the lower case form of the token text because so
much on things like the length is alpha.
Is it punctuation.
Is it like a L or like an e-mail.
Things are parts of speech.
Delimitation the shape and so on.
So it's actually lots of the attributes can provide into this dictionary but the really common ones
specifically are lower and you can also do verbatim if you want to keep capitalisation in play.
Maybe looking for a difference between Tesla if a capital-T as a company versus Tesla a lowercase t
as the actual Tesla car.
Anyways we have these three patterns.
Now it's time to add them to our matcher.
So the way this works is we simply say matter and then we're going to add N and you first name the actual
matcher.
So we're going to name this matcher or solar power matcher and then as a third parameter or a second
parameter we passen none.
So let's say callbacks parameter and you can shift tab here to actually see different parameters.
So you can expand on this and check out the parameters.
But we're going to do it here.
Exit Out of that is set callbacks equal to none.
So we'll talk about more about callbacks later on.
And then we just pass in the patterns who want to match on.
So just keep passing them patterns so pattern one pattern to pattern three.
So now these three particular patterns have been added to this matching object and they're under the
name solar power.
And you can definitely provide this name whatever you want but it should be relevant to whatever you're
trying to match on.
So now that we have this solar power matcher Let's go ahead and create a document and see if we're able
to match on these various phrases.
So as Ina goes on to say the following.
Say the solar power industry continues to grow as solar power increases and then also say solar power
is amazing.
So notice here we have solar power and I has three different versions of it.
I have solar power as two separate words right after each other solar power as one word.
And then solar power has a hyphenated word.
We're going to run this and then to actually find the matches.
You simply take the matter and then pass in that dock or document object.
And we're going to set a variable called found matches equal to this matcher object.
What it returns and what's nice here is I can simply print out my found that matches and it's going
to return back to apples with three pieces of information.
The first piece of information is the match ID.
Essentially the string ID for the particular match and then it indicates the start and the stop and
notice here the start and the stop is really on the tokens.
So we have the first token the index 0 is the and then the second token the next one is Soler.
So for example solar power here is the first match and it's going from one up tube not including three.
So it's basically these two words index one and the next two.
And if you check out the actual vocabulary and matching notebook and scroll down past's example aren't
creating patterns and applying it to the dock object.
We have this nice little for loop here that will actually print out the string representation if you
want.
So let me copy this and kind of explain what's going on.
So I'm going to copy that and paste it here and what this does is it looks up the actual match your
ID prints out the match matcher name the start the end and then print out the actual text.
So kind of a nice little way of printing out everything but essentially it's the same information here
plus the name of the matter object.
Solar power which we defined up here when we added the matter and then the actual text that's matching.
So just a little functionality here in case you find the need to use it.
Now you can make token rules optional by passing and O.P. Asterix argument.
So that lets us streamline our patterns list so mishu.
What I mean by that I'm going to create a new set of patterns we will say pattern one and effect before
we do this let's actually show you how to remove a particular pattern.
Let's say you no longer were interested in this solar power matcher and you were interested in any of
these old patterns anymore you wanted a full update instead of adding to the matcher.
You can actually remove from the matcher so you can simply say take that matcher and remove whatever
he happened to call the matcher.
In our case we called it solar power.
So I'm going to remove that.
So now that we've removed this old set of patterns for the matter let's go ahead and create a new set
of patterns we will say pattern one is equal to.
And we're going to something really similar to what we had before.
Lower as the key.
And then solar power as the value and then for pattern to what we're going to do is a little different
will say lower is solar.
For the first term and then we're going to look for is underscore the NCT for his punctuation set that
the true and true as a boolean and also inside his dictionary.
We're going to set O.P. colon and then set that as an asterix for the string.
And what that's going to allow us to do is allow this pattern to match zero or more times.
And if you check out again the vocabulary and matching We have a little table of additional parameters.
So you can negate the pattern make the pattern optional.
So that's a question mark required pattern to match one or more times allow the pattern to match zero
or more times.
So that can help us if we have like double hyphens instead of just a single piece of punctuation.
So we're going to say as little operator there that we can allow the pattern to match zero or more times.
And then we're going to add and finally lower on power.
So you run that.
And let's go ahead now add in that we're going to call it solar power as we did before.
Make sure you remove the old solar power set and we won't have any callbacks for this particular instance
and we'll pasand these new updated patterns pattern one and pattern to again just to clarify here.
Pattern one is going to be able to find solar power put together as all lowercase.
So you can grab solar power like this or solar power with S&amp;P capitalized pattern too is going to grab
solar and then any amount of punctuation.
That's what the Asterix is doing with the O.P. so it can be double dashes or can be one underscore or
one plus or whatever it happens to be punctuation and then power.
So that's really powerful.
So add that in as our new solar power matching and let's create a new documents we'll say Doc two is
equal to an LP and we're going to say something like solar powered power is solar power Yeah or really
whatever you want.
The key thing here is I want to show you that it's going to be able to actually grab these two hyphens
because we added in this optional parameter
so from matcher we're going to say actually we're going to say found underscore match's is equal to
matter.
We're going to pasan dock to run that and then you can print out your found matches and if found two
matches found the first one at solar power or solar or dash dash power and this one put together at
solar power.
So now these two pattern lines actually replace what we had here as the original three because going
to be able to detect both pattern to pattern through here because of this.
If we scroll down here this optional parameter because the Asterix is actually for come back to this
table.
It's allowing the pattern to occur zero or more times.
OK.
Now we've learned how to actually create our own patterns and match on them using Spacey.
And the main things to cover from this lecture that are important is to understand the space to that
matter in this matter.
You pass in your vocab into the matter.
You create patterns which are list of dictionaries based off key words in the terms you're looking for.
And you can check out the actual tables we provide for you inside of our notebook if you scroll down
you'll see some tables for the options key as well as tables for all the attributes you can search on
and what they should match to.
And if you scroll all the way down we actually have a link to documentation that goes over the official
sections for rule based matching.
So if you check that out you can scroll down here and there's tons of different examples as well as
similar tables to what we provide for you in the notebook.
OK.
Came back to her notebook when you have those patterns.
Add them to the match or given a name that you provide and they just pass in whatever doc objects you
have into this matter and it reports back to found matches.
And we also showed you how you can actually grab the raw text for the match itself.
Coming up next we're going to talk about trying to match on limitation and also trying to match phrases
and viewing those matches themselves.
We'll be right back with part two.