Welcome back to part two of the vocabulary in matching lecture in this lecture.
We're going to go over a phrase matching.
Let's hop over to a notebook where we left off last time.
OK.
Here we are at the previous notebook now in the previous lecture we saw how we can use token patterns
to perform rule based matching in alternative and often more efficient method is to actually match on
a terminology list and in that case we're going to use a phrase matcher in order to create a document
object from a list of phrases and past that into the matcher instead.
Let me show you how that works.
Previously we said from Spacey dot matcher import matcher.
But in this case we're going to say import phrase Mecir and we'll create a metric object from that will
say Free's matter.
And just like before we pasand the vocab.
And for this exercise we're going to import Wikipedia article on Reagonomics.
So we have the source here in the actual link if you scroll down here you'll see a link to the Wikipedia
article.
But we actually saved it for you already.
And textfiles.
So if you're actually looking in the downloaded text files.
So here it downloaded files go to text files.
There should be a Reaganomics t x t.
So that's the file We're going to be referencing.
Make sure you passen the entire file path to that.
So let's go ahead and use that file.
We're going to say with open and Tex files dot Reagonomics you should be able to tab autocomplete if
you're not able to have autocomplete it means you're not in the correct directory and just pasand the
entire file path instead will say as f..
Go ahead and say Doc three is equal to an LP and we're going to read in that file as one long string
essentially passing the entire string of this Reagonomics text file into this document.
So run that and then let's imagine we want to look for several phrases we can do is first create a list
of those phrases.
So maybe you're trying to study Reagonomics and you don't remember what specific term of economics they
used.
Maybe you thought it was called voodoo economics.
Or maybe you thought it was called supply side economics.
And let's also do a couple more like trickle down economics and let's add one more into free market
economics.
Free market economics economics.
OK.
So go in and run that.
So you're trying to do a study of economics.
I don't quite remember what the actually economics term was.
She created a little list of phrases to search.
Next we're going to do is convert each phrase to a document object and we can do this efficiently simply
by using a list comprehension we'll say phrase patterns is equal to an LP text for text in phrase list.
So all we're doing is for each of these pieces attacks inside of the phrase list we're making it into
its own document object.
So essentially have a list of a bunch of docs and phrase patterns then we're going to pass each doc
object into the matcher so I'll say matcher add and then we can call this whatever we want so we can
say Econ. matcher we're not going to have a callback here and then we're going to pasan each pattern
inside this list.
So if we actually check out what this list looks like phrase patterns it's going to look like a bunch
of strings but not strings.
Notice that we actually grab one of them and check the type it's a spacey doc.
That's why I didn't see any quotes there when we actually output it.
So in order to insert each baby doc when you do is put an asterix here and then we can provide each
of them a little bit of short term that if you're familiar of some more advanced functionality of Python
This is kind of keyword arguments and you can pass those in or you can just do Asterix args kind of
same thing here.
This essentially graps each document and passes in individually into this matter as a pattern.
And then what we need to do is actually build a list of matches.
So we're going to say matches or found matches is equal to match her and let's pass in the original
document that we're trying to search which is this Reaganomics textfile doc three so we passed it Doc
three here and then let's check out the found matches so notice it found lots of matches and we can
actually again if we come back up here member we had that for loop.
So we can just copy this and paste it in here.
Run it and it'll show us where it's actually matching and and currently we actually provided the wrong
doc.
We said Doc here.
So let's say Doc three run that.
And now we see the actual matches match on supply side trickle down voodoo free market supply side and
trickle down.
So I had a little typo there because I directly copied and pasted.
There were actually search in the updated documents.
OK.
So there we saw how we can easily create a list of phrases to match on.
And then there's some kind of convenience code and if you want to just copy and paste this convenience
code you can check up vocabulary and matching.
Scroll down and we have the cell that essentially does all of this for you.
It's the same code we wrote but it's in one cell you can easily copy and paste.
All right.
Now again if you want to view the matches all you need to do is copy paste this for loop that we showed
here and actually provide the correct documents.
If you actually want to grab the context of the document where you can do is subtract a little bit from
your start and add a little bit to your end.
So what I mean by that is maybe you say start minus five tokens back.
An end is plus five tokens forward.
And this is actually going to give you the tokens surrounding the term you're looking for.
So when you run this it's going to give you essentially the sentence so policies are commonly associated
with supply side economics referred to as trickle.
And you can if you want to keep going past that could add more to the end and it will keep giving you
more and more.
So again you can mess around at the start and end to grab parts of the actual tax.
So a very useful tool.
OK.
So that's it for this lecture and hopefully now you can see how you can easily use phrase matching as
well as basic token matching.
Coming up next is going to be your assessment to test your new skills.
We'll see you at the next lecture.