Welcome back to make sure you've understood all the topics discussed in this section of the course.
We designed an assessment that mimics what we just did in the previous code along lecture.
Let's go ahead and take a look at the text classification assessment.
And in the next lecture we'll go ahead and go through solutions.
Let's walk through the notebook.
All right here I am at the tech's classification assessment notebook.
So this is going to be really similar to the code along project you're going to perform your inputs
load dataset independence data frame.
Just keep in mind we're now working with movie reviews to ts V.
So it's a very similar data set and you're just going to complete the tasks below performing imports
loading the dataset check for missing values removing those values taking a look at the label columns
using things like value accounts splitting the data into a training and test set building a pipeline
to vectorize the data then trying to fit the model run predictions and analyze the results using it
confusion matrix A classification report and then printing out the overall accuracy.
All right.
Coming up next we're going to work through solutions.
I'll see you there.