Welcome back everyone to part two of our Q and A bot with Python 4 Part 2.
We're going to begin to understand the steps on how to vector victories this particular data set including
vector izing the questions and the stories as well as the answers and then we'll learn how to create
a function that can victories data for us to really go through steps in a bit more of a manual process
and then at the end we'll create a function that does it all for us.
So let's go back to the notebook where we were before and continue where we left off last time.
All right.
To begin we'll say from Caris that pre processing that sequence import pad underscore sequences.
And then we'll say from Kerry's stop pre processing that text import token either.
We've actually seen both of these in our previous text generation project.
The next thing we want to do is create an integer encoding for the sequences of words.
So we'll create an instance of our token EIS or object.
And in this case we don't actually want any filters.
So remember if you look at the doctoring for this there's a list of filters here that could possibly
be used.
We actually don't want any of these.
So we're going to see this as an empty list and you can also leave it as an empty string if you want
that as well.
It just needs to be an empty ignorable.
And then we'll say took a nicer fit on and then we call Tex and we'll fit it on our vocabulary so after
running that you can take a look at your token EIS or object and you should be able to see all the things
we've talked about before but specifically a word index with essentially a dictionary that maps every
word in our vocabulary set to a specific index number.
So question mark is one apple is an index 37 and so on.
So here we have every possible word.
And notice it's been automatically lowercase for us.
So Mary here is now been lowercase Sander is now lowercase and so on.
So you have to keep that in mind as we're building out our own stories that we need to lowercase sometimes.
Have took a nicer dot word index ready to go and then we're going to do is we're going to perform the
same sort of tokenization but for the story questions and answers so I will show you how we could do
this in a manual fashion but then will create a function that will vector write stories for us automatically
so we'll create a list called Train story text set that to be an empty list I'll say train question
text and set that to be an empty list and then we'll say train underscore answers and set that's being
empty list.
So remember there's three parts there's a story the question and the answers and then we'll say the
following for the story the question and the answer in our training data I can simply take that train
story text and then append the story to it.
So essentially I'm just kind of separating out these components almost like an unzipping and then we
can say train question text the append the question and I could do the same thing for the answers I
could say train underscore answers and then append the answer.
So if you run that and you take a look at any one of these.
So for example a train story text this is now just the stories.
So essentially we have just the stories just the questions and just the answers all separated out from
each other.
So what I could do is say something like this my train story sequence is going to be the token riser
and then I call the function texts two sequences and then pass in the list such as train story text
and now I check the length of train story text or sequence it's ten thousand because remember there's
10000 stories the exact same as the story text but if we actually take a look at this object train story
sequence notice it's now kind of the numerical version of what the original train story text was.
So essentially converting this into the index calls.
So Mary remember Mary is twenty three here.
So we come back up here we look up Mary and there it is twenty three.
So somebody is converting each word to its matching word index using the text the sequences.
So what I'm going to do is create a function that can help us out with vector rising these particular
stories.
So we'll say the F vector rise underscore stories and it's going to take in all the data it's going
to take in a word index and we'll go ahead and default this value to the word index that we just created.
You can always overwrite it for other datasets or other sets questions and then we'll also need to know
the max story length as well as the max question length.
And the reason for that is because we're going to be using padding sequences because not every story
not every question is the same length.
But the actual recurrent neural network that we're training on it needs things to be in the same length.
So we want to pad it out with zeros in case there's a story is too short or we want to cut down a story
if it's too long.
So we'll say Max story length is equal to the max story length.
And then we'll say Max question length is equal to Max question length and I'm going to zoom out here
just a little bit so you can see everything.
But essentially I'm taking the data my word index that we defined earlier and then passing in the MAX
story length as well as the max question length.
So nothing too crazy here.
And let's zoom back in.
You can always copy and paste this and essentially this is taking in the data the data that's going
to be both the stories the queries and the answers.
And what I want to do is I want to victories the stories questions and answers into padded sequences.
So first we need to do is loop for every story question answer that data then I can convert the raw
words to a word index value and then I can append each set to their appropriate output list.
So let's create those output lists and create one for stories which were what's called the stories we'll
just call capital X. since that's our main training data.
So here we have the stories that's our X then we have another essentially feature it's gonna be the
actual question.
So we'll call this X Q That's gonna be another empty list for now.
So here we have our questions.
X Q And then finally the target which is why that's going to be the correct answer.
So that's the yes or no so say Y is an empty list.
So have those empty lists and then for all my data I'm going to do the following we'll say for every
story question or else just save a little bit of spaces a query and answer in data.
I'm going to first grab the word index for every word in the story.
So I'm going to say word lower for word.
Let's make sure I spell that right foreword and story and I'm going to create a list comprehension where
so I'm just saying word that lower forward in story and then actually want the index.
So we'll say word underscore index for word dot lower and then I'm going to set this to a lower case
x because I'm doing this for each story.
So for each story I'm creating a list that essentially will look something like this will be a number
like if Mary was the first one I'll be twenty three and then fourteen and so on really similar to what
we just did before.
However it's gonna be for each particular story in the dataset so let's lowercase x and then I'm going
to do the exact same thing but for the questions so such I'm going to copy and paste this and lowercase
x Q word index or that lower foreword except this time it's going to be in the query or the question
now for the answers I can grab the answers and where the answers are a lot easier because it's either
a yes or no.
So I don't need to use this complicated list comprehension.
Instead I'm going to start off by setting up an empty matrix of empty zeros.
That is the length of the word index and then plus one because index zeroes reserve or using pad sequences.
And now that Y is all zeros.
Since we know it's simply just a yes or no.
I can use none pi logic to create this assignment so I can simply say the following y a word index for
that answer is equal to 1 and then all I need to do here is say X thought append the lowercase x x Q
append the lowercase x Q And then y append the lower case Y.
So all I'm doing here is I have these main lists that are capitalized and then for every story query
and answer in the dataset that I pass in I'm going to do the word indexing myself here minus the ones
for the Y and then I will append those Okay so once you're done with that for loop what you need to
do is actually pad those sequences.
So I'm going to return a final tuple that can be unpacked so we'll say return and set up my princess
for the tuple we will call pad sequences.
So pad sequences.
Remember we import of that we'll pass an X and then say the max length is the max story length so that's
the pattern sequences for X and we'll do the same for X Q the questions so pad sequences for X Q or
the max length for this pattern sequence is Max question length and then with this one more time except
for the essentials we just need to make this into an array.
So say NPA array of Y OK so we definitely have a lot of code here.
If you ever get any mistakes or typos or warnings or errors makes you use copy and paste from our provided
notebook but all we're doing here is or vector I's and stories in a really similar fashion to what we've
actually seen before in the text generation a book.
So go ahead and run that and let's check it out.
We'll say inputs train queries.
Train and answers train is equal to victory stories on our training data then we'll repeat the exact
same process for the test data.
So we're going to copy and paste that in except for inputs train we'll just call these all tests so
inputs test if you want it called stories has to we'll say queries test and then answers test on our
test data.
There we go run that and then if we take a look at inputs test versus input train just go ahead and
take a look at all these notes now they're just arrays where we have their word in exposition along
with their word index.
So we must take a look at answers test if we wanted to notice only one of these words are all zeros
except this one at this and this position either the S's or the nose so you can just say something like
took a nicer word index for yes and that's the index twelve I'll say took a nicer word index at no and
that's at index location thirty six.
So let's go ahead and take the sum of our answers test and you notice we have all zeros except at these
two index locations 4 9 7 and 5 0 3.
And if you were to actually go along companies you'd go 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 all the way until you got to index
12 and 4 9 7 which means there were four hundred ninety seven ones in next location twelve otherwise
known as having four hundred ninety seven yeses as the answers and index location 36 5 0 3.
So the word index for now.
Okay so now we have successfully vector i's not only our stories but as well as our questions in our
answers.
And now we have the data in the correct format for creating the model.
So coming up next we'll begin actually creating the model with Caris layers.
We'll see it there.