Go over the solutions for the text classification Assessment Project.
OK here we have the text classification assessment.
So it's for a long and complete the tasks we're first going to import Pandurs as PD and then say DNA
is equal to PD read CSB and then inside the text files folder you should be able to find movie reviews
to ts V and remember because it's a TSB we want to indicate that it's a tab separated file.
So after we run that we can check the head of the data frame just to confirm that the data frame is
correct.
So we see the labels and then we see the actual text review.
Next we want to check for missing values so we can do this by saying DSF is null and then taking the
sum of that.
And it looks like we do have some missing values.
In fact 20 of the reviews are missing.
So we're going to want to make sure to remove those values.
Now we also want to make sure to check for white string spaces.
Next we're also going to check for whitespace strings.
And then after we check for whitespace strings we'll go ahead and remove null values.
It's up to you.
Or do you want to do this in.
And we're going to show you a caveat you have to keep in mind because we haven't removed the null values
yet.
So keep that in mind.
We're going to create a list called blanks that's going to hold the actual index positions of any whitespace
strings we encounter and then we'll say for the index label and review in ZF or tuples this is going
to go and iterate through the data frame we'll do the following.
If the review itself if the type of the review happens to be a string then we're going to check to see
if it's an empty string.
The reason I'm doing this check is because we know we have no values.
In fact many of these reviews are not street types but there are no values.
So if that happens to be the case that it's actually string then I can check if the review is space
then I will say blanks append that particular index position.
So then if I run this and actually check the length of blanks you realize that 0.
So there actually are no whitespace strings.
There's only these missing values that take care of.
Now we can do that easily by just saying the F drop and a and then we'll say in place is equal to true
task force to take a quick look at the label column.
So let's go out and check it out.
We'll say the label and let's call value counts in here we can see we have just as many positive reviews
as we have negative reviews so it's a very well perfectly balanced data set.
And so task five is that split the data into treating sets and test sets.
We'll say from S-K learn model selection
import train test split and then I will set x to be the review and Y to be the label and then finally
we will call train to split.
And then if you put this in a new cell and run the import You should then be able to shift tab and then
expand on this.
Scroll down until you find extreme excess weight training weightiest.
So we'll go ahead and copy and paste those sort of to train test split and or passenger X or Y.
And then our test size go ahead and set that equal to zero point three three and we'll set a random
state of 42 so we run that.
And now we can build a pipeline to vectorize the data then train and fit the model.
So let's go ahead and do that.
We will say from S-K learn and we're going to do it through a pipeline we'll import pipeline singular
import pipeline and then from S-K learn thought feature extraction thought text import T.F. IDF vector
Isar then we'll save from Eski learn as SVM import linear SABC that you will say create a text class
for object with our pipeline object and this pipeline objects going to taken a list of tuples or say
T.F. idea and then insert here a Tina Fey Effect raiser and then the next step in our pipeline will
just be the classifier itself which we're here we're just going to use a linear support vector classifier.
So say linear support vector classifier and then will actually fit the data.
We'll call it on our next train.
And there are white train that we can call extreme why train directly because we're going to have x
rays within the pipeline.
So let's make sure we didn't commit any typos and actually check to make sure this worked by running
it.
OK so don't worry if you get a warning as long as you see the actual output you should be good to go.
So let's run the predictions and analyze the results.
So we're going to say predictions is equal to text classifier or text CNF and we're going to predict
off our test set and then we're going to report a confusion matrix which means we need to import it
will say from S-K learn thought metrics in import a confusion matrix A classification report and we'll
go in for accuracy score and then we'll just print all these out will print out the confusion matrix
with the predictions versus the white.
True so we'll say why test the true values against the predictions.
So let's run that.
So here we can see your confusion matrix.
Let's check out the classification report and then see why test against the predictions.
Looks like it's doing pretty darned good.
And they need 2 percent precision recall.
Let's put out the overall accuracy we'll say metrics and then accuracy score.
We are actually in pretty accurate or we just call it directly and then pass y test of the predictions
Alzugaray the 92 percent accuracy.
OK.
Hopefully this whole process now feels pretty straightforward to you we've seen it several times.
But now you understand what each step is doing you understand is going on behind the scenes with the
vectorization.
And now you're able to form text classification using the raw text data as a major feature.
Thanks and we'll see you at the next section.