Welcome back everyone to part three of our Cuban report with python as a quick note.
Make sure to read the paper before continuing onto this lecture.
If you still haven't read the paper that we're working off of it's really important that this point
in time you read it since going to be fundamental to understanding how the network and the encoders
work so in this lecture we're going to be building out the neural network including input encoder M
input encoder C the question encoder and then we'll complete the network.
Let's jump to the notebook and get started.
All right here we are at the notebook we left off last time and again just to reiterate by now you should
have read the paper to understand the encoders in the full network.
So here's the paper Here's essentially the diagram of the network that we're producing along the encoders
and the long short term memory unit or the recurrent neural network that sees from the paper.
So we're gonna be working on the encoders for the questions and the stories those encoders see an M
from here.
And we're gonna be building this out with Python.
So make sure you read this paper before continuing on.
Otherwise I don't really make sense what we're doing.
It's really come back here and start off with a lot of imports in order to build out these networks
we'll say from Kerry's models import sequential and model and then from Carrier start layers that embedding
is import embedding and then from Carrier stock layers we're going to import input activation dense
per mute and drop out and then we'll also import the operations add dots and concatenate and we actually
import one more thing from layers which is the Ellis team the long short term memory unit that we're
gonna be using OK so we have our sequential and model imported from carrier not models we have our embedding
is imported specifically from layers that embedding so that we can just call embedding and then we have
all these various imports from carriers that layers.
So the first we need to do is hold up in place holder.
So recall that we technically actually have two inputs which we haven't really dealt with before.
We have not just these stories but we also have the questions so have the story that the encoder needs
to understand then a separate question and then we have to link them together in order to provide a
label yes or no.
So we want to do is we're going to create place holders using input so this input function of Kerry's
right here.
This one input is used to instantiate a scarce tensor.
So we're going to do is say a variable called input sequence is equal to input and then the formatting
we're going to use here.
You do shift tab here and check out that we need to pass in a shape so the shape we're gonna pass in
is based on the Mac story length and next question length so we'll do here is just say Max underscore
story underscore alien pops and then we're going to say comma.
So the reason that we add an a comma there is because essentially since this is what's known as a place
holder this is going to be able to take in the inputs of the stories with a shape of the max story length
because remember going to be padding and then the batch size and the way Care's works for this batch
size since we technically want to be able to edit our batch size and we don't know it yet.
We're just going to leave it blank by adding in a comma.
So the shape right now is a tuple with just one defined Max story length and then a comma essentially
a nun there for the batch size since we technically haven't really defined it yet then we will say question
input and really similarly we're going to say Max question length comma.
OK so those are place holders ready to receive input later on of batches of stories and questions.
Now it's time to create the input encoders.
So the first thing we need to actually do is define our vocabulary size and if you remember previously
we defined a vocab set.
So that's basically essentially what this word index is.
But if you keep going up we actually define a vocab length so in order to keep everything consistent
with the notebook that we provide for you we're essentially going to create a new variable called vocab
size which is the same as vocab like it's just how many words you have in your vocabulary.
Remember that's this set right here plus one for padding because the zero index should be reserved due
to the fact that we're using pad sequences later on over here from Charisse so scroll down here and
just create one more variable called vocab size and set it equal to the length of our vocab plus one.
And again just to reiterate previously we were calling this vocab length.
But I want to keep the variable names the same from the vocab or from the notebook that we provided
for you.
So the first thing to do here is then continue on for input encoder M and then we'll create input encoder
c.
So this input gets embedded to a sequence of vectors.
So we're gonna create a variable called input encoder M and then set it equal to sequential
and then we'll say input encoder M and we're gonna add two layers to it.
One is the embedding layer with an input dimension of vocab size.
And if you want can technically put in vocab length here as well but we're just gonna put vocab size
to keep the variable names consistent.
And then from the paper we'll go ahead and use the output dimensions of sixty for and then we'll say
input encoder M and we'll finally add in a dropout layer recall that a dropout layer all it does is
it turns off a percentage randomly of neurons as you're training.
So that means if we set dropout to zero point five that means in this layer 50 percent of the neurons
are gonna be randomly turned off during the training and that helps with over fitting.
So it's really up to you what value you want to choose here.
You can experiment with values as well as training times.
We're gonna go ahead and go off a value of zero point three but if you want you can make that a little
higher and train for a little longer and see if that helps if over fitting but the way I ran this model
zero point three was getting me results that were pretty darn good.
So we'll go ahead use that.
And so what this encoder is going to output is essentially something in the form of the samples the
stories max length and then the embedding dimension.
So that's input encoder M and we're gonna essentially copy and paste this for input encoder C except
we'll change the variables here so input and courtesy input and courtesy input and courtesy.
It's still going to be sequential except this time the output dimension isn't going to be 64 but it's
going to be the max question length and then the drop out.
Again you can experiment if these values of zero point three and if anything between zero and zero point
five should be fine to play around with but again we'll just choose zero point three and then this will
output samples story max length and then instead of the embedding dimension of the output I mentioned
is this Max question length so we'll go and copy that is going to produce something that looks like
that.
So these are essentially what the outputs look like for these two input encoders so have an input encoder
m an input encoder.
See now we have one final encoder which is the question encoder again it's super similar so I'm just
going to copy and paste again.
What's these three layers essentially except I'll rename this to be our question encoder so have our
question in Question encoder it's gonna be a sequential question encoder we'll also take in an embedding
layer so I'll remove this underscore C and it's gonna take an embedding layer of the input I mentioned
again it's gonna be the vocabulary size the output that I mentioned we want to match it to input encoder
m just as they do in the paper so we'll say 64 and then we'll define the input length since this is
specifically for questions as the max question length because remember the output I mentioned for input
could see was the max question length so we're going to copy this and then say input length is equal
to Max question length and then finally we'll add in this dropout layer so take that question encoder
variable add that in all right.
So we'll go ahead and run that and a quick note the output of what this question encoder is going to
look like it's going to be samples the query max length for the question max length and then the embedding
dimension.
Okay.
So let's synch with the output of that question and could it looks like now that we have the input encoder
M input encoder C and the question encoder it's time to actually encode the sequences recall that we
already have our place holders for the inputs if we scroll back up here remember we created this input
sequence for an input as well as this question for an input so we want to pass in these inputs into
our encoders the input encoder M input encoder C and then the question encoder just as they did in the
paper.
So all we need to do is say input encode Ed so make sure I spell this right in code Ed underscore M
No I'm not saying encoder I'm saying this is the result of passing this in through the encoder.
So essentially the form is encoded is equal to the encoder with whatever input you're passing in so
I should really draw this area the other way.
So we've taken our input placeholder pass it in through the encoder and we'll get our encoded result
so input encoded M that's going to be equal to input encoder M and the pass in the input sequence there.
And in a very similar fashion we're going to copy and paste this and we'll do the same thing for C so
input encoded c is equal to the input sequence percent input encoder C and then finally we'll say question
encoded is equal to the question encoder with that question placeholder pass then and now we're almost
done.
We just need to use a dot product to compute the match between the first input vector sequence and the
query just like that in the paper to do this.
I will create a variable called Match and use that dot function that we imported and then as a list
you pass and the two things that you want to compute the match for or take the product up.
In this case it's going to be input encoded M comma and then the actual question encoding so same question
encoded and then will specify axis is two by two
and then we'll call an activation function on this Max or match object by simply saying soft Max for
that match object.
Okay.
So there we have our DOT PRODUCT compute the match between the first input vector sequence and the query
and then we want to do is want to add this match matrix with the second input vector sequence.
So the response is an equal to add we take that current match and then we just like that in the papers
they add it to input encoded C and then the response we call that mute layer and you can check out essentially
is going to permit the dimensions the input according to the given pattern.
So the dimensions we're in passing is 2 by 1 and then we're going to pass in response they're essentially
just converting it to have an output of samples by query max length by story max length so once we have
our response we can concatenate the match matrix with the question vector sequence so we'll say our
answer is equal to concatenate that response with the question encoded and to check this you should
see an answer which is in the background they tensor full of tensor and you should see it.
Here have a shape of question mark question mark because they don't know the batch size yet.
And then six by 220.
So if you're getting a result that looks like this you did everything correctly.
If you get something that looks slightly different specifically differ on the shape.
That's probably most important part.
Then you possibly made a typo somewhere and I would highly encourage you to run through our notebook
download our notebook file directly and just run that.
There's lots of opportunity here to make simple typos especially with some of these variables that are
look quite similar like encoder versus encoded.
So if you ever get any typo or warnings along the way make sure you run our notebook in the provided
environment.
OK so now we have our answer tensor and then we're just going to reduce it with a recurrent neural network
and we're specifically going to choose an Alice tablet for this.
So you'll say answer is equal to Elysium 30 to pass in the answer and we're going to perform one more
series of regularization with drop out.
So answer taking a dropout layer you can choose any value here between zero and zero point five on the
train a little slower so I'll choose zero point five.
Try to regularize a little harder on this.
Make sure to over fit.
And then finally we have our dense output layer for the vocab size and we pass on our answer.
So this is essentially output something that's in the form of samples by the vocab size where we should
only see a marking for yes or no where everything else is just going to be a bunch of zeros just as
we did we victimized the answers.
All right.
So what we need to do is then output a probability distribution over the vocabulary because we'll essentially
see a bunch of zeros except some probability on yes and some probability I know we'll pass it in through
a soft Max in order to turn it into a 0 or 1 so say answer is equal to activation soft Max passing the
answer and then finally we can build the final model.
So same model is equal to model it's going to take in that input sequence.
Remember these are the inputs placeholders that we defined before that it's going to take in that question.
And then finally it's going to take the answer and this answer is what links together all the encoders
the encoder C encoder M and the question encoder and that's how we link our model to those and coatings.
So we have our model here and now it's time to compile our model.
We will say a model that compile the optimizer we will use optimizer is going to be Armas prop
the loss we're going to use is categorical cross entropy since technically we're we're doing this across
the entire vocabulary we should expect only yes as it knows across the answer but instead of doing a
binary category across entropy we technically have a larger vocab size in that but the answer is we
should expect to only see high probabilities on yes or no.
Technically the way we're treating this it is possible for the network to output the answer as like
Sandra or journey but since there are no training results with that other vocab words as the answers
we shouldn't expect to see that we should really only expect see probabilities on yes or no.
If you are getting results of expected probabilities of another word in the vocabulary then I would
definitely look back and make sure you train the network correctly like we did.
All right so we have model compile and lessening what to do is choose our metrics and the metrics reduced
and shoes here is accuracy so run that and then you should be able to call a summary of your model and
it's definitely complicated.
Just like it wasn't a paper they should see something that looks like this with the same number of total
parameters and training parameters and then all you need to do is train and fit our model.
So coming up in part 4 we're going to train the model evaluate the model evaluate it on the given test
set as well as write our own stories and questions and see how it can perform.
So pretty exciting stuff coming up next we'll go ahead and continue on in the next lecture.
I'll see you there.