Welcome back everyone to this lecture on an overview of machine learning.
Before we dive into text classification let's work on understanding the general machine learning process
we're going to be using.
The specific case of machine learning we're going to be conducting in this particular section of the
course is known as supervised learning.
So we're going to be focusing on that supervised learning process.
Because different students have different backgrounds and math.
We're going to be keeping the mathematics behind the machine learning algorithms on the lighter side.
A great textbook on General machine learning especially if you are interested in the mathematics is
called an introduction to statistical learning by Gareth James's companion book.
It's freely available online as a PDA and it's released for free by the authors.
You can simply Google search the title of the book to find the link.
So again just google search I guess L.R. or introduction to statistical learning and you'll be able
to easily find this book for free online.
So let's begin by answering the question what is machine learning machine learning as a method of data
analysis that automates analytical model building using algorithms that it's really learned from data
itself.
Machine learning allows computers to find hidden insights without being explicitly programmed where
to look.
So the machine learning algorithm on its own is going to figure out what patterns and what features
are important.
Now what does machine learning actually used for.
As you may already know it's used across a variety of tasks and industries.
Anything from fraud detection to credit scoring loan applications or the things we're going to be focusing
on things like tech sentiment analysis or e-mail spam filtering.
So this is a small subset here of what machine learning applications can do for us.
Most talk about supervised learning supervised learning algorithms are trained using labeled examples.
That's a key word.
They're labeled so a labeled example is an example where the input and desired output is known.
For example if you have a data point as a segment a text it could have a categorical label such as the
text of an email being labelled as spam versus legitimate or the text of a movie review being labeled
as a positive movie review or a negative movie review.
The learning algorithm or machine learning algorithm is going to receive a set of inputs along with
the corresponding correct outputs and the algorithm is going to learn by comparing its actual output
with the correct outputs in order to find an error.
And then it's going to modify the internal parameters of the machine learning algorithm accordingly
to achieve the best results on its own without you explicitly programming it what it should change.
Supervised learning is commonly used applications where historical data points predict likely future
events such as historical information of previous emails you've received that someone has labeled as
legitimate or illegitimate or spam.
The historical data can be used in order to provide a future spam filter for future emails.
So let's talk about the supervised machine learning process and this is probably the most fundamental
thing to get out of this particular lecture.
So we're going to go through all these steps individually.
Now the first step is to actually quiet your data.
And there's many different ways to do this.
In this particular course the acquisition is pretty simple.
We actually just provide the data for you but depending on where you're actually working or what you're
doing for your personal machine learning projects you can acquire that data through a variety of sources.
You can check out the resource links in this lecture for lots of free data sources or if you're working
on a company you can work internally to acquire data but your customers or even from like things like
physical sensors et cetera.
So we're going to assume then that you've acquired that data then the next step is to clean and format
your data.
And in particular if you're working with text data for natural language processing you'll have to perform
things like vectorization on that data which are going to cover in the lecture text feature extraction.
But you get to do things like remove missing data points from your data and then convert the raw text
into numerical vectors that machine learning models can understand.
So that's a whole process that we're really going to focus on on in another lecture on the future.
But you've acquired that data and you've cleaned in a format of your data.
Then once you have the clean and formatted data you're going to split the data into training data or
each training set and then test data or a test set and know what you're going to do is on the training
data you're going to grab your machine learning model and have it learn or train off that training data.
And that's also known as fitting the model to the training data.
So the machinery model is going to attempt to learn as best it can.
The different application that you're looking for so if you're trying to build an email spam filter
right now it's working on that training set of data and the training data is commonly about 70 percent
of the total data.
So your training your model and other model has learned on your training data.
Now it's time to evaluate your model's performance and for evaluation.
It makes sense to use data that the model has never seen before that you're not cheating.
That's why we have the separate test data set.
Around 30 percent of our data so we take the model we just trade on and then we test it against that
test dataset and then we can evaluate how well the model actually performed using different evaluation
metrics.
And we're going to talk about evaluation metrics in a lecture in that section.
So after evaluating our model we can decide to improve the model maybe edits some parameters of the
original machine learning algorithm so we can go back to the model and training and building phase adjust
some parameters and essentially repeat this process until we're satisfied for a modest performance and
then we can deploy the model
so for tech's classification and recognition this is really common and widely applicable use of machine
learning.
And later on in this section of the course we're going to be learning about the sikat learn library
in order to use Python to conduct machine learning text classification.
Now let's take a quick moment to focus on that idea of the train to split that I just mentioned and
that we just saw her and we're going to learn a few key terms.
So let's imagine a full data set of what is known as ham versus spam text messages and ham is just another
word for legit or correct text messages.
Basically the opposite of spam so we're going to imagine a full dataset and our dataset is going to
look something like this.
Notice that we have a label and the actual raw text message.
So you can see the one in the middle there that's a spam text message offering some sort of bogus free
entry and some weekly competition.
The other text messages are him or legitimate text messages.
So our idea here is that we're going to build a machine learning model that can detect given a new text
message whether or not something is ham or spam.
Now before the split we're going to have labels and features.
And in this case the label is again the historical label ham or spam.
So that means that someone in or someone manually had to go in and read the message and then label it
as a legitimate message or spam message.
So that's a key part of supervised learning is they have to have historical labeled data and often labeling
your data as a manual process.
Now in this course you're not going have to label any data we provide label data for you.
So we have what's known as the y label and the X features features is the actual data points.
They're going to use to predict the white label.
And the reason we have y and x is because in linear algebra notation the way the mathematics work out
usually have an X matrix of features and white label.
And often you'll see why lower cased.
So this is right before the split.
We still have labels and features we haven't actually than a train test split yet.
What we want to do is probably take about 70 percent of these points both the labels and the corresponding
messages and save those for the training data and then take the other 30 percent and have that be our
test data.
So once we have our white labels next features before we fit the model we'll split the data so we're
at take this data and we're going to split.
So this is a really small example of a dataset just five points that we've already shown that we're
splitting it.
So you notice here a total data or splitting it into a test set and a training set.
Remember that we still have a white label on X features.
So we just split the data and we have now our test set in our training set.
And now we can do is we can individually label the subsets of y s and x.
So what you're going to see when you do the actual train test split of python and sikat learn is for
outputs.
You have your y labels your y tests in y train and then you have your X features your X features for
the test set and your X features for the training set.
So don't be confused when you run the train to split and see for outputs why test X test Y train extreme.
All it is is the data set being split into two pieces.
Your tests and your training set and then those two pieces being split along the y labels and X features.
So that's all that is those four terms mean.
So again we have those four components and you're going to see this components often throughout the
course.
So these four components are simply the result of the train to split groups being separated between
features and labels.
Coming up next we're to continue to understand the classification process in more detail and importantly
metrics in order to evaluate a classification process.
We'll see you at the next lecture.