Welcome back to this lecture on visualizing parts of speech.
We just saw how to extract parts of speech tax from tokens and obtain information about those parts
of speech tags.
Let's quickly review how to visualize parts of speech structure with the Speccy we've already seen this
before.
So this is really just a review lecture.
Let's head over to the notebook to begin.
You should import Spacey and also load the space English language dictionary.
Then we're going to do is create our document.
So let's go ahead and just say something like The quick brown fox jumped over the lazy dog
lazy thought.
There we go.
Now in order to display when you say from Spacey import this Blazey and then off this display See object
we can call render we pass in the document we want to display and then we have to choose a style.
And for visualizing parts of speech probably the best style to choose is DGP which is going to this
place syntactic dependency but also show you the part of speech tags.
And then since I'm using Jupiter I'm going to say Jupiter is true.
And if you just run this inside of Jupiter You should see the visualization occur.
So here you can see the speech tag.
So Fox is a noun and we can also see the syntactic dependency so we can see a proposition and so on.
OK.
Now there's definitely options that you can actually use as modifiers for this rendering and what you
do is you create an options dictionary will say options and the various options you can choose are the
distance.
So one of them as I mentioned is distance and you can edit that to create more distance between these
words or less distance between them.
You can also describe if you want it to be compact or not so spacey will attempt to make this as compact
as possible depending on what distance you chose.
So you can say compact and here you actually pass in a string.
True.
You can decide on a color for the actual text so you can say color and this can take in basic strings
or hex codes for color.
So you can say something like I want to text the color yellow.
You can also say B.G. for the background color.
So again you can take in a string code here like red or you can actually passen your own hex code.
So if you do a hex code picker you should be able to kind of mix and match and choose whatever hex code
you want.
I'm going to put one in here that we have in the notes and then you can also choose the fonts.
Keep in mind that every single font is going to be available.
It should just be the ones that are available from the space documentation essentially General fonts
that are available in your browser.
So for example at times new roman and it provide times.
So you can run that and then essentially it lets go ahead and copy and paste this render.
And if you do shift tab here you should notice that there is an options parameter.
So we're going to do is say options is equal to options and when you run that night you'll see the various
options occur and Lotusphere we our distance but compact is going to compact down these curves to just
be flat.
So previously we had this kind of larger curves compact flattens them out hopefully make it a little
more compact along that vertical axis.
We can see the colors now yellow for the words we chose our own custom background color and then we
also went with times new roman font.
So that's how you can customize the appearance.
Keep in mind if you're doing really large tax display see serve is meant to accept a single document
or a list of documents since large texts are difficult to view and online.
You may want to pass a list of span's.
Instead let me show you what I mean by that.
I'm going to say doc to is equal to an LP I will say this is a sentence this is another sentence.
And then let's actually make this one longer.
This is another sentence possibly longer than the other.
And what we can do is we can create a list of spans so I can say span's is equal to and then casting
as a list I'll take doc to call S E N T S.
So I remember that actually GRABBE sentences automatically and then we're going to say the C and what
we can do is we can say instead of render serve and then pass and the span's will again choose the style
to be syntactic dependency style.
And if you want you can pass an options or not.
Now you don't need to pass and all the options you can do something simple like a distance parameter
and so on.
Keep in mind when we say serve it's actually going to serve and render this outside of the Jupiter note
but since we're not saying Jupiter is equal to true so we're going to run this.
They should see something like running on port 5000.
So what you need to do is inside your browser you need to go to 6:59 point zero point zero point 1 and
then say Colan 5000.
So we're going to go ahead and copy this and then open up a new tab and paste that in.
Hit enter and now you should see the various spans so you can say this is a sentence.
And if you scroll down you'll see another spand right there.
OK.
So we just saw how to visualize inside the Jupiter notebook using this Blaikie render.
And we also saw how to visualize outside the notebook using serve.
And again the serving is going to serve on a port depending on how many times you're serving.
This port might be slightly different in which case if it's serving on port five thousand one you would
just do something like 5000 on here.
OK.
That's it for creating visualizations and the unable to visualize the parts of speech.
Coming up next we're going to talk about names and city recognition.
We'll see it there.