Welcome back everyone to this lecture on Keres basics.
We're going to learn how to create a very simple neural network for classifying the famous ires.
They set the goal of this particular lecture is to just get you comfortable with the syntax with.
The data itself contains measurements of flower pedals and steeples and corresponding labels to one
of three classes.
That is one of three flower species.
It's a really simple data set.
It's super famous has its own Wikipedia page.
So we're going to be working on this just to learn the syntax basics.
Let's open up a notebook and get started.
OK here I am at a notebook.
I want to start off by importing some pie as N.P. because we may need to use some pie later and then
I'm going to read in the data set.
The state is famous enough that it's actually built into sikat learn so I can simply say from S-K learn
that data sets import and there is a load Irus function.
So load underscore Irus and then I'm going to create a variable called Irus and then run the load Irus
function.
And if you take a look at what type of object is returned here it's actually a specialized Bunche object
from sikat learn.
And if you check its attributes it has feature names Target Target names and the data.
So it's actually already kind of restructured for us and you can print out the description attribute
and it prints out an entire description of what this is.
So is essentially just as I mentioned simple links and widths and centimeters and then pedal lengths
and pedal with in centimeters and the corresponding class there's 150 instances and there's four attributes
and the flowers belong to a species of Iris it's either iris a Tosa Iris versicolor or Iris virginica
and some some are sticks and then famous Iris dataset.
Lots more info here.
OK so let's actually now grab the feature information and the label information.
It's actually already organized for us with attribute calls from the spunge object.
So I will say my X features is equal to Irus data and if we take a look at X it's essentially a name
pyrite with the four measurements lined up per instance.
So people length's people with Pedda length and pedal with.
So we have X ready to go.
Now what we need to do is grab our labels.
So that's also organized for us in the form of a target attribute.
Essentially the target variable or label target.
If you check out what Y looks like it's sorted.
So we can see we have class 0 class 1 and class 2.
Now because of the way carriers and your own that works work in general we're actually going to want
to convert this to a categorical labeling system.
Essentially what encoding.
So what that means is I want a vector that's going to be zero for everywhere that this class doesn't
match up.
So for example class zero is going to be one index zero and then zero everywhere else for the other
two classes.
So essentially these become indexed additions 0 1 and 2.
So a class one instance.
So if we had class actually this would be class 0 it would look like this.
And then class of one would end up getting a one at that that exhibition.
And then a class of two would end up getting a one or one hand-coded at this and exposition.
So this is known as one encoding.
And we're going to be able to do this quite easily using some built in tools of course.
So all we're doing is transforming each of these into its own little vector of three.
And the way we do this is we say From cares that you tildes import and we import to underscore categorical.
So we can say from Keres import to underscore categorical.
There we go.
And then we simply just cast it.
We say why is not equal to two categorical Y.
And if you check out the shape of y now it's 150 instances.
Now it has three values per label.
So if we actually take a look at what it looks like now you can see it's essentially the one high encoding
so ones are 0.
Then we move onto the next last 0 or 1 0.
Move on to the next last and then 0 0 1.
So now that we have set up for cares what we can do is continue on to split the data into a training
set and a test set.
So we're going to do is just psychic learn from S-K learn that model selection import train test split.
Then we simply call train test split do shift tab as I previously mentioned that we can quickly copy
the tuple that gets created essentially unpacking the values.
So we will copy and paste that X train x test Y train Y test and then just pass it my X features my
y label the sign on a test size.
I'll go ahead and say 33 percent of the data will be testing data and then random state.
If you want the exact same split as I will get.
Go ahead and use 42.
So we run that and now we have the four components the training data the testing features as well as
the labels for the training data.
And then the labels for the test data.
Notice now everything's been shuffled and randomized which is exactly what you want.
You don't want to train on things in an order otherwise you'll get really good at classifying zeros
first and then when it comes to classifying ones you'll get really bad.
So we always want to shuffle that data which is done automatically for us with a train test split which
is why we have a random state because it is randomly shuffled.
So we want to make sure you get the same shuffling I do now for neural networks.
It's usually a really good idea to scale or standardized your data.
So for this particular instance we kind of don't need to but it's a good idea anyways so we're going
to show you how to do it occasionally do it for your own problems.
Simply say for him as he learned that pre-processing and we import min max scaler and what this does
is it simply makes all the values fit between a range like zero and one or negative to 1 to 1.
And what this does is essentially divided by the max value to make sure everything fits between 0 and
1.
So what I mean by that is let's imagine you had a list of values like five 10 15 20.
So if you took this list and then divided it by the max value so this would actually have to be an array.
So if you took this array of values and then divided it by the max value which is 20 when you run that
you'll notice now everything is between 0 and 1 because you divided by the max value.
That's essentially what minimax scalar does.
There's lots of other scaling methods but this one is pretty simple.
So we're going to kind of run on this ideology we just simply create a scalar object just like you would
for anything else with sikat learn.
And then we're going to take her scalar object.
Now we're going to fit it and we're going to fit it to only the training data.
We don't fit it on all the data because that would essentially be cheating.
We don't want to assume prior knowledge of the test data.
So we're only going to fit it to the training features and then we're going to create skilled versions
of our trained data.
We will say scaled X train is equal to the scalar object.
And then we will transform our X training data and we'll do the same thing for the test data we'll call
scalar object and then we will transform our test data.
So if we take a quick peek at the training data.
Now you'll notice all the values are between 0 and 1.
So that converts everything.
And typically that helps neural networks helps the weights and biases from growing to large.
OK so we have the skilled versions of our data.
What we're going to do now is actually build a network of course which is actually a pretty simple process.
We simply say from Karris that models import sequential essentially a bunch of sequences of layers and
then we'll say from cares that layers and we're doing a really simple model here.
So we're just going to import a dense layer later on when we actually perform things like text generation.
These models are going to get a lot more complicated.
We'll import different types of units like Ellis T.M. units but keep things simple just sequential and
dense.
And this is really the syntax we want to get familiar with.
We first create the sequential model and then we simply add layers to the model.
So we say model.
And in this case only important one kind of led to an added layer and each particular layer has different
parameters so dense we want to describe how many neurons or units go into that sense layer.
What should the activation function be.
And then you can do other things like have a bias initialiser et cetera.
A kernel initialiser often those sort of initializers it's fine if the default value is the only thing
you should probably mention is the input dimensions.
So we'll do that as well.
So I'll say dance let's go ahead and use 8 neurons.
I'm just using double the amount of features whether or not that's incorrect or correct.
Literally no right answer for that.
Often people have some sort of domain knowledge that helps them understand what's a good choice for
neurons.
It should probably be something based off the number of features like some multiple of the features.
But again there really is no right or wrong answer for that and they will say input them insuance is
for since we expect for features and then we'll say the activation function is r e l you for a rectified
linear unit and let's go ahead and add in one more then Slayer
so we have that input layer another set of eight neurons and then finally for output layer we're going
to add in three neurons and it's going to have the soft Max activation.
And the reason for that is essentially that three neurons what's going to happen is each neuron is going
to have what looks like essentially a probability for belying in any particular class which is why we
want encoded.
So if we remember what we looked like.
It looks something like this.
So at the end the neurons get to return maybe like 30 percent chance for this exploration a 20 percent
chance for this exploration and then 50 percent chance for this actually correct an expedition.
So that's why at the end we have these three neurons and that's what we choose soft max.
So kind of get some output that kind of looks something like this.
It won't look exactly like this.
Such nice probabilities but this is the general idea is going to tell you what it's leaning towards
based off the expedition.
And that's why we use the soft max.
So at the end of that we simply compile our model.
We choose some sort of loss.
This loss is going to depend on what you're actually performing.
So here we are performing categorical process so we want categories to say categorical underscore cross
entropy.
So that's how we're actually going to determine loss the optimizer will use the atom optimizer.
And then for the metrics we're going to decide this on accuracy.
So that's what we'll be training on and that's we'll be reporting back.
Now if everything worked well if your model you should be able to then ask for a summary of the model
which reports back where each layer is doing what the output shape and the number of parameters created.
All right.
So if you get anything for this lecture it really should be these few lines you import sequential models
and then import the layers you want create your model and then add in the layers and the Pentagon what
kind of import you may have to kind of tune these hyper parameters or the side more hyper parameters.
And then at the end you compile it with some sort of choice of loss.
And this last depends on exactly what kind of problem you're trying to solve.
Then once you have that just like a psychic learn model you simply call models that fit on your training
data.
And remember we scale their training data so Passons scaled X train and then Y train.
We don't need to scale train because it's labels that are already zeros and ones.
So we're going to say pocks and pocks one epoch is running through the entire training data set.
Well go ahead and run through 150 epochs and then there's a verbose.
Verbose is just basically how much output you want information.
So if you put in zero it's not going to report back anything.
If you put in one ill actually show you like a little progress bar.
So two it shows you the pockets on how much loss and what its current accuracy is.
So it's go ahead and run this for 150 POCs this should be relatively fast.
I'm on a really fast computer.
But again the data sets are pretty small.
So at the end of this you should get something around.
I would say 90 percent.
So it may not be exactly this because remember there is some random initialization to the weights and
biases but you should be getting around 90 percent.
You may get slightly higher slightly lower after 150 pucks.
OK.
So another question is how do we predict on new unseen data and how do we evaluate the model performance.
We're going be covering that in the very next lecture.
We'll see if there.