Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to show you how to actually perform latent Thursley application with Python.
Let's open up a new notebook and get started.
As a quick note underneath the topic modeling folder you'll notice that there is an NPR that CXVII.
We're going to be using that and pure that CSFB data file to actually load up some articles.
So make sure you actually look at it underneath the topic modeling folder.
And if you want to follow any of the code that we show there in this lecture you can run it from the
latent location.
I've gone ahead and created a new notebook in the same folder so I can easily access this NPR that see
every file.
Let's go ahead and go to that untitled notebook now and the first we're going to do is actually load
up that data.
So we'll say import pand this is Preedy and then check out what that data actually holds by saying NPR
is equal to PD that read underscore as we and NPR see as we.
So let's take a look at the head of this data frame so we can understand what this actually is what
this dataset is.
It's a couple of thousand articles and each of these rules is the full text of one of the articles.
Notice that right now we only have information on the article text.
We don't actually have some sort of label column indicating what topic this particular article belongs
to.
So for example if we actually want to view one of the articles we simply say NPR at the article call
them and then passen whatever role we want.
So if all of the very first article I could index at zero and it return back the text of that entire
article.
This is essentially the first row.
And if you look up the length of the actual dataset self-check of length NPR there's almost 12000 articles
here.
So you can have fun exploring just any basically any number between 1 and eleven thousand nine hundred
ninety two.
So article number 4000 we can run that was like the comment at that link line and here we can see an
article on this.
So what we don't know yet is what actual topics each of these articles belong to.
So we're going to try to attempt to figure out and assign a topic to each of these articles.
Let's go ahead and continue on.
The first thing I need to do before I actually run LDA is perform a little bit of pre-processing and
we can do that by saying from Eski learn the feature extraction text and we're going to do vectorization
something we've already seen in the text classification lecture.
So we're going to import vectorize or elysée C-v is equal to an instance of Count victimiser.
Now we're going to pasan three parameters that are really useful.
The first one is Max D F and Max the F.
What it does is when you're building up the vocabulary we're going to ignore certain terms that have
really high document frequency.
So this essentially gets rid of terms that are really common across a lot of the documents.
So you can pass in a number between 0 and 1 here.
So such as 90 or 0.9.
And what this is going to do is it's going to discard words that show up in 90 percent of the documents
and you can play around this value.
So if you want to be a little looser of what words get thrown out or not throw away as many words you
can say something like Ok only words that show up in 95 percent of all the documents.
So you can play around that ratio and it's counterpart is mindif which is essentially a minimum.
So what's the minimum document frequency.
So words that show up a minimum amount of times and you can actually passen for both Max T.F. and mindif
either a ratio between 0 and 1 or if you pass an integer it will actually take that into account as
a raw number of documents.
So for example if I passen to here this says that the minimum frequency for a word to be counted into
this count vectorize her it has to show up in at least two documents.
So it can't be totally unique to a single article.
So that's usually a good idea to throw out some really common words and also throw out random words
maybe even typos or misspelling.
So you have to guarantee that they show up at least in two documents.
OK.
And then also you're going to do is we can automatically remove Stoppard's simply by saying Stop words
here and pass in the string English and vectorize or can actually automatically remove those Stoppard's.
We have other methods of doing this as we know if we wanted to we could tokenize all of these Ramoo
stoppers ourselves with spacey but we could also let victimiser take care of all that for us as well
as take out really common words and make sure words are meeting some sort of minimum threshold.
OK.
So there's our count vectorize.
Now it's time to actually apply this and transform to the article.
Again notice here I'm not going to do any sort of train to split because this is unsupervised learning.
I don't have any label to test against So this really makes sense to test train split and said what
I'm doing is essentially unsupervised learning.
We're going to transform to the entire dataset.
OK so we're going to do now is we're going to say a document matrix is equal to C-v thought that transform
and I'm going to do this on the article call them
and then if we check out our document matrix then you should have a sparse matrix.
Keep in mind depending on what computer you have this fit transform may take a while.
This is a pretty big dataset.
But right now it looks like we have almost about 55000 terms and here the number of articles.
OK so there's our turn matrix.
Up next what we need to do is actually perform the latent a.
And this is built in to sikat learn all you need to say is from a scalar the composition
import.
And then you can actually just directly import.
You could have autocomplete this latent there are allocation.
Now we're going to say LDA as our variable name here.
Typically you don't actually have variable names are capitalized but I like this because it kind of
makes it sound like an acronym.
And also it doesn't make the l be confused of a one sort of say LDA and then we're going to call instance
a late since there is only allocation and we can explore some of the parameters.
There's lots of different parameters here such as learning the K learning method et cetera number of
iterations the most important ones that we actually want to go through are number of components and
we also want to make sure we set a random state because there is some random this because remember we
randomly assigned words in the beginning.
So we want to make sure that our random state is a sign that we are going to get the same topics that
I do.
So we're going to do here is first decide on the number of components.
So we're going to say number of components.
And this is where there is no right or wrong answer.
It really depends on your domain experience and your familiarity with the domain that data is from.
I'm going to just say I want 7 general topics returned.
If you want to get into more detail such as maybe subcategories of politics like international politics
versus national politics.
If you're hoping for that sort of level of information in subtopics you might want to make that number
of components much larger.
Again it's totally up to you.
So then we're going to just choose subcomponents as seven essentially looking for seven topics and then
I'm also going to say random state is equal to 42 and I would encourage you to do the same.
That way the words return per topic are the same for you as they are for me.
OK so we have LDA and now it's time to take LDA and fit it to our document turn matrix.
So we'll go ahead and run that and I'm going to fast forward in time.
This should take awhile.
Again it depends on your hardware.
But we are dealing with a large number of documents and remember LDA is an iterative process.
So it's going to keep updating those weights per word per topic over and over again until they've stabilized.
So I'm going to go and hop forward in time until that's done fitting.
OK.
We have finished fitting the model.
Now there's only three steps left.
The first step is to actually grab the vocabulary of words.
The second step is to grab the topics and the first step is to grab the highest probability words per
topic.
That way we can actually interpret the topics themselves.
So we're going to continue right off of this in the very next lecture.
We'll see if there.