Now the way we do that is we first need to scale our test data or new incoming data.
Now we've actually already done this.
We have our skilled X test right here.
But keep in mind if you had fresh data like you just went out and collected the information off a flower
in the field you would have to scale that data first.
Because our model is only train on the scaled versions of the sort of data and then we're going to do
is if you actually take a look at model dot product just like you would for a psychic learn model the
same model that predict and then pass that scaled data and then if you run this you'll notice that it
actually spits out probabilities by default when you called up predict.
If you want the raw classes themselves simply call predict underscore classes and it's going to predict
the classes again something that's important to know here is that it doesn't predict the one encoded
version of classes.
It just reports back the exposition which is convenient in some senses kind of inconvenient because
the original white tests we had to change it to be 100 coded.
So that's a little annoying but we'll show you how to quickly fix that.
OK.
So we're able to not predict classes.
We need to do is compare these predictions to our white test the way we're going to do that is by simply
saying the following.
We're going to say that our predictions is equal to model dot predicts classes on that scale x test
data and then we're going to transform our Y test data by simply saying why test RMX across access is
equal to one.
And what that does is it reports back the actual classes because why test original.
If we again take a look at it the max value is simply going to be at the expiration of the corresponding
class.
So that's kind of an easy fix.
So now we have the predictions and our original Why test values in the exact same format.
So I just need to compare these predictions to the truth values.
And we already know how to do that.
I sikat learn.
We simply say from Eski learned that metrics import.
And we're going to import the confusion matrix the classification report.
And if you don't you can also import the accuracy score and then we can just play around with these.
So the confusion matrix we pass why test RMX access equal to 1.
So those are the true values corresponding in the same method as the predictions are going to be in.
And it looks like we're doing pretty well in this confusion matrix.
Let's go ahead and print out the full classification report and then just copy and paste this here
from that.
And we're getting a pretty good precision recall especially on this 0 class.
A little rougher on this one class.
And if you would actually visualize this is because there's a lot more overlap between classes 1 and
2.
And then finally we can print out the accuracy score.
So accuracy score between these two.
And we're getting around 88 percent accuracy.
So not bad.
OK.
So we learn how to actually evaluate on unseen data.
The last thing I want to do is especially for a really large network.
We spent some time training it.
This wasn't a big deal for this particular 150 epochs.
It took just a few seconds to run.
But if we're running a super large model especially for things like text generation that can take hours
to run.
We want to be able to save and load our model though if we do this is we simply grab our model and then
call that save.
And then you choose whatever you want to save it.
So you say something like my first model and the extension is not H5.
So this essentially saves all the weights of the network.
So we're able to quickly load it up again if you want to load the model so that we.
Let's imagine we shut down our computer.
Next day we want to load this model that we train.
All you need to do is say from cares that models import load model and we can make a new model is equal
to.
And then you just call the load model at the file location of where ever the H5 file is.
So my first model age 5 the only thing to be really careful of is be really careful with this naming
scheme because if I run this cell again multiple times after training maybe I'm just playing around
of things.
This will automatically overwrite any file with the exact same name that can be really dangerous especially
if you have a model and your weights save that maybe took hours to run and you're just playing around
and maybe do something else that took a minute to run.
You will just have overwritten all that work.
So be really careful this naming scheme.
You don't want to overwrite a model that took forever to train.
So now I have this new model essentially works the exact same way as the original simple same model.
And then I can call it classes function for the generator.
Anything I can passen that skill X test data run it and then get the classes predicted.
OK.
So that's it for evaluating model performance as well as exploring how to predict on new unseen data.
All right we'll see you at the next lecture.