Welcome back everyone.
In the next lecture we're going to be working with Python and the sikat learn library.
Let's quickly give a quick preview of how the psychic learned library works before we actually open
up a notebook and get started with it.
As I mentioned we're going to be using the sikat learn package in order to do some machine learning
in this course.
It's the most popular machine learning package for Python and it has a lot of algorithms already built
into it.
If you are using our provided environment file you may need to install it using either Carna install
sikat learn or Pippin's all sikat learn.
So go ahead and make sure you've installed it before you hit the next lecture.
Let's quickly talk about the basic structure of how to use sikat learn first.
The quicker we are the machine learning process remember we need to acquire or data cleaner data split
our data into a training set and testing set test the model on the test set and then we can go into
all of the ultimate.
So we're going to do now is show you an example of this process using sikat learns Python syntax and
don't worry about memorizing any of the steps we're going to get plenty of practice and review when
we actually start coding and subsequent lectures every algorithm is expose and sikat learn via what's
known as the matre object.
S-meter is really just another word for model since all machine learning models are doing or estimating
to predict predicted output.
So first you're going to import the model and the general form looks something like this.
You say from S-K learn dot and then the family of models you're looking for and then import the actual
model.
For example if you want to work with the linear regression model you would simply say from S learn linear
underscore model and that linear underscore model is the family of linear models then you would import
whatever specific model you're looking for and it will show you that you've got a notebook you can use
tab and shift tab to quickly see what models are available.
Keep in mind each estimator or machine learning model has parameters and all the parameters of the meter
can be set when it is instantiated and have suitable default values.
So luckily you don't need to know too much about the actual algorithms before you get started.
Sikat learn because they usually have pretty reasonable default values.
And again you can use shift plus tabun Jupiter to check the possible parameters.
For example we could create a linear regression and state the normalized parameter is equal to true.
And then if you print out the model you'll actually see the various other parameters such as fitting
the int..
Once you have your model created with your desired parameters it's time to fit your model or train your
model on some training data.
Remember you should always split the data into a training set and test it.
Lucky for us sikat learn comes with a trained test split functionality so we can say here from Eski
learned that model underscore selection import train test split.
And then here I've made up some data for x and y and then if you actually pass x and y in the train
to split all you need to do is decide what percentage of it should go to your test set.
So the percentage is going to be between 0 and 1.
So if I say test size is equal to 0.3 then that means 30 percent of this data will go to the test set.
And notice how it brings back x train x test Y train and a Y test just as we discussed in previous lectures.
Now that we've split the data we can train or fit our model of the training data.
And this is done through the model fit method.
All you need to say is modeled thought fit passenger extreme data and then pass your white train data.
Now that the model has been trained on the training data the models ready to predict labels or values
on the test set.
So you get the predicted values by saying modeled up predict and then you pass the X test set.
And keep in mind this dot product method is the same method you would apply for brand new data that
the model has never seen before.
So that's how you can use your model to predict on new values.
So we can then evaluate our model by comparing our predictions to the correct values.
The evaluation method depends on what sort of machine learning algorithm you're using whether it's regression
classification or clustering.
In our case we'll be looking at classification.
So we've already gone over the different classification metrics.
Let's go ahead and actually program through all of this in the next lecture.
I'll see it there.