Hello everyone and welcome to the recurrent neural networks theory lecture here in this lecture we're
just gonna give you a brief overview of the theory behind a recurrent neural net recurrent neural networks
are specifically designed to work with sequence data.
So examples of sequence data are things like time series data such as how many sales have happened over
a previous time series or what the production has been over previous time series.
There's also things like sentences which is what we're focusing on for natural language processing.
So you can think of a sentence as just a sequence of words.
Things like audio or music it's basically just a sequence of sounds or even things like car trajectories.
There's just a sequence of instructions left right forward and back.
So again recurrent neural networks when you understand them you're really going to be focusing on applying
them to sequence based data and there's lots of different ways of applying recurrent year networks which
you're going to learn about in this lecture so we can imagine a sequence as just a vector of information
where the index location basically points out its points in time and then the actual values are the
training values.
So if we imagine a sequence that's one two three four five six a question that you could ask anybody's
Are you able to predict a similar sequence shifted one tiny step into the future.
And for most people it's actually pretty easy.
You feel that there's a pattern here of increasing by one as you move along one time step.
So if I asked you Hey what's the sequence that's similar to this except shift that over one times that
you would hopefully build figure out well I'll just say two three four five six seven so we're going
to try to later on training network to predict a time series shifted over one time step into the future.
You can imagine that would be really beneficial if we're trying to predict sales for the next day
so the way we can do this is by using a recurrent neural network.
So let's review how a normal neuron works in a feed forward network.
Remember that a normal neuron just takes in some input and it can be multiple inputs so it can aggregate
them.
And then once it aggregates those inputs it passes it through some sort of activation function.
Here we're just using the symbol for a rectified linear unit that it can be things like a sigmoid function
or a 10 H function etc. and then from that we have an output.
So that's why a normal neuron works a recurrent neuron is a little different.
What it's going to do is send the output back to itself.
So the output goes back into input of the same neuron.
So we can actually unroll this throughout time.
So if we unroll this throughout time it ends up looking something like this.
So we can see time here kind of represented on the x axis and we have this particular recurrent neuron
where it's input at T minus one gives an output at T minus one and then that gets passed into the neuron
in its state input at time t and then it has an output at time t and then we can take that output and
pass it as input for the same neuron at time T plus 1 and then so on and so on.
So this is called unrolling that recurrent neuron something that's important to note here is that the
neuron is actually receiving both inputs from a previous timestamp as well as inputs from the current
time step.
So you can see each of these neurons has two sets of inputs they're these cells that are a function
of input from previous time steps are also known as memory cells and recurrent neural networks are also
flexible in their inputs and outputs for both sequences and single vector values.
So we'll show a couple of examples of that in just a little bit but I want you to know it's also very
easy to create a layer of recurrent neurons.
Previously we just saw one recurrent neuron then we unrolled it through time but we could do the same
thing for an entire layer.
So if we want an entire layer of recurrent neurons then it would look something like this where we have
input of X and then it goes through those recurrent neurons.
Here we have three of them.
Then we see the output at Y and then we take the output and then just pass it back in to all the neurons
in that layer.
And we could do the same idea and unroll this entire layer throughout time so that we get an input a
T equals zero get an output it's equal zero and then pass that along with the output and input at time
plus one and same idea except now we're doing it with an entire layer.
Now since the output of these recurrent neurons at a time step t is technically a function of all the
inputs from previous time steps you could then begin to think that has some form of memory because we're
technically passing in historical information into that recurrent neuron or into that layer of recurrent
neurons.
So part of this neural network that preserves some sort of state across these time steps is called a
memory cell and later on we're going to see much more complex examples of memory cells.
But for now we have this basic recurrent neural neuron that just sends its output back into its input
recurrent your own networks are also very flexible in their inputs and outputs.
So let's walk through a few examples of different combinations of inputs and outputs we can use for
recurrent neural networks so we can actually perform a sequence input to a sequence output and an example
of that would be passing in a set of Time series information such as a year's worth of daily sales data
and then wanting back a sequence of that same sales data shifted over a certain time period into the
future.
And that's basically the initial example we first thought of that one two three four five and then you
asked back for two three four five six so a sequence however shifted over one step into the future another
set of examples inputs and outputs would be to pass in a sequence input and request back a vector output
so a common example of using recurring neural networks for this sort of input output is sentiment scores
so you can feed in a sequence of words maybe a paragraph of a movie review and then request back a vector
indicating whether it was a positive sentiment such as they really liked the movie.
That's usually indicated by one versus they really dislike the movie which is indicated by usually negative
1 or 0.
So that would be an example of a sequence input.
So that paragraph of words to just a single vector value and you essentially have a bunch of training
data where you have a bunch of paragraphs and then some sort of sentiment score attached to them and
you would train your recurrent your own network on that data to have a sequence input to a vector output.
So on the opposite side you could also feed in a vector input so a single input just a first time step
and basically passin zeros for the rest of your time steps and then let the output be a sequence.
So that's a vector to sequence network.
So an example of vectors a sequence could be just providing a single seed a word and then getting out
an entire sequence of high probability sequence phrases that would actually come out.
So you could have a word such as hello and then the sequence that gets generated something like How
are you.
Because after being trained on lots of introductory text maybe the neural network realizes that just
based off the seed.
Hello.
One of the more common phrases is how are you.
Now that we understand basic earnings we're gonna move on to understanding a particular cell structure
known as Elysium or long short term memory in which is going to be necessary in order to actually generate
text that makes sense because we want to have the network be aware of not just the most recent texts
that scene but also the entire history of texts that it's seen.
So we're gonna learn how that works in the very next lecture we'll see there.