Welcome back to this lecture on visualizing names and see recognition.
Let's review how to visualize any are with Spacey and the spicy.
Let's head over to Jupiter notebook.
OK here I am at a Jupiter notebook and I've imported Spacey as well as loaded up the English library
and I said from Spacey import this Blazey.
Next we're going to do is create a document that we actually want to visualize.
We'll say.
And here we're going to say over the last quarter Apple sold nearly 20000 units or let's say 20000 iPods
for a profit of $6 million.
Next we're going to do is after we define that document we'll call display see and we will render the
doc and then Style say E.A. for entity.
And since I'm using Jupiter I'm going to say Jupiter is true and he can see space to the best of its
ability is going to highlight and color the Anstey's it finds.
So find the date and see in organization money i-Pods his product cardinal for some sort of amount nearly
20000 and so on.
So you can see already the power that displace has to highlight entities.
Now let's imagine you want to have multiple lines and you want to view them line by line.
So for example we're going to create one more line inside of the documents.
In fact we're going to pass in another string.
So inside these princes go ahead and create a new stream and we'll say something like.
By contrast Sony only sold well say eight thousand music players.
And let's say Walkmen music players
OK.
So if you actually call read they're now in the documents it'll show everything as kind of one giant
long string but maybe you only want to do this line by line the way you do that is just separate out
into sentence segmentation by saying For sent in docked that sense and then you're going to call display
C render individually on each of those by saying an LP sent that DXi pass and the text of each individual
sentence segmentation.
Again make sure you say style lips style is equal to E.A..
And since I'm running this in Jupiter I will say Jupiter is true and you can see it gives you a little
more spacing between the lines.
It's not too different between rendering everything versus this.
You can see that each new line is left in that TD instead of.
By contrast is this essentially a continuation.
OK.
Now you can also have different options.
Remember there's an options dictionary.
You can actually choose options for things like coloring or customized effects and more importantly
you can choose options to only display or highlight certain entities.
So maybe you're only really interested in product entities where you can do is say options and under
A.S. key you can pasan a list of what you're interested in.
So maybe we're only interested in product entities then we're going to render this will render the whole
thing recopy And this this and pace it down here and then we'll say options is equal to options.
Run that and then it will only highlight the entities that you said here.
And if you want to add another one like organization you simply just add to this list of options and
then it's going to highlight that.
So that way maybe you're not interested in it.
Entities don't want those highlighted.
You can easily filter out whatever you want.
Then as always there's things like different colors so you can actually choose different colors for
different entities.
There's the default colors but if you really want to choose your own all you need to do is create an
other dictionary.
Called colors and then we're going to do is choose an entity and then you're going to pass in a color
that you want.
So for example you can say that you want this entity to be red.
Then once you've done that you need to do is inside your options state a color is key and set equal
to or set its value equal to this colour's dictionary.
So if you run this you'll let us now that organizations have been read.
And as always you can pass in your own custom hex codes in case you want a color that isn't simple.
So for example I can pass on this hex code color and it'll create something that looks like that.
You can also customize these even more so you can actually add linear gradients or radial gradients.
So let me show you example of that X is going to copy and paste these from the notes we provide.
So there's a radial gradient.
See all you need to do is choose the tag and then say radial dash gradient and choose two colors either
hex codes or string color codes.
And if you run that what's going to happen is going to radial gradient.
The inside is going to start yellow and then the outside is going to go to green.
So for example we could say from yellow inside to outside red and you get something that looks like
that.
You can then also do a linear gradient.
So you just called the linear gradient function and then choose a start middle and end color.
Let me copy and paste that.
So here we're going to choose linear ash gradient and you can choose an actual degree and then a start
and stop color.
So you can run that and it's going to start at kind of this darker purple and go to this pink again.
You can just pass and string codes here if you want.
You can say go from maybe orange red.
Run that it can see it going from orange to red and you can change these to 180 degrees if you want
it to go from top to bottom or so on or you can even choose if you really want like a 45 degree to have
it go from one corner to the other.
It's really up to you.
Usually you won't need to customize color effects that often unless you have a very specific style that
you're looking for.
Finally we've showed you how to render everything inside of the Juber notebook but maybe you're running
a dot PI script.
As always you can simply call the splays see serve pass in the document passen style is equal to E.A..
And if you want.
You can still passen options and then notice I'm not saying you Brezik that true it's that I'm just
saying this.
And when you run that you should see it being served.
So you just need to go to 6:59 point 0.01 at whatever port it's telling you.
So in my case it's a port 5000 you copy and paste that and then you'll see the being rendered at that
location.
All right.
So that's really it for rendering the most important thing to note here I believe is not really the
coloring but the fact that you get to choose and filter based off what you want so you can always have
this ants and then choose specific entities you want to highlight.
Thinks elsea at the next lecture.