Welcome back everyone.
And this lecture we're now going to show you how you can perform non-negative matrix factorization with
Python.
We're going to work on the same NPR that CXXVI dataset and you'll realize how easy it is to swap out
LDK for anti-meth.
Let's head over to Jupiter notebook and get started.
All right.
I've created a brand new untitled notebook.
It's located underneath my topic modeling folder.
So I have easy access to the NPR CSFB file or going to do is just like before import Panthers PD and
then read in the file and we're going to go through all of this quite a bit quicker than we did the
first time around since we already know what the NPR that every file is how to extract features from
it and how to display topics.
Essentially there's two main things we need to change.
The first one is the pre-processing feature extraction because of the dependence on per word count probabilities.
There is still a probability distribution.
We could only use count vector risers for LDK But since non-negative matrix factorization works have
coefficient values.
Here we can actually preprocess the text with T.F. idea.
Vectorization I say from Eski learn the feature extraction the text import and we're going to import
the IDF vectorize or and keep in mind T.F. idea of vectorize are actually performs a count vectorizing
beforehand.
So essentially it takes care of a lot of steps for us and we'll say T.F. IDF are going to create incidents
of this T.F. idea of vectorize.
And just like before we can ask for a maxim document frequency.
So we're going to ask for words that show up in no more than 95 percent of the documents and then we
can also have a minimum document frequency we could pass this in a percentage saying 0.1 something like
it must show up in at least 10 percent of all the documents.
But here a good filter is something like 2.
That way you essentially filter out words that are unique to any particular document because they won't
really be useful for topic modeling if they only show up in one singular document and then just like
before we can provide a stop words equal to the string code English and T.F. idea vectorize will automatically
remove English Stoppard's for us then we'll create our DTM the technically more than just the document
matrix since we are performing T.F. idea.
But just to keep things kind of in parallel as before we'll keep some of the same variable names then
we're going to call a fit.
Transform this NPR article column and then we're going to have our.
Essentially what is our T.F. idea of matrix here we just call it the variable DTM.
So it's a sparse matrix just like before where we have the articles by the number of words.
OK.
And then to perform and MF We simply say from as Kilbourn thought decomposition import and F and we'll
say and M.F. model is equal to an instance of an M F and there's a couple of things to note here.
The first one is the number of components.
So this is essentially the K value that we need to choose which is going to correlate with how many
topics we want we'll go ask for the same number of topics as we did last time.
But I encourage you to play around this value.
And then what I also would like to do is provide a random state.
Remember we initialize that H and W matrix randomly.
So if you want to make sure you get the exact same topics I do go ahead and put a random state that
matches my random state of 42.
Then we're going to do is call an MF underscore model and we all fit it to that DTM and something you
should notice is an MF performs faster than LDA for this particular data set.
That's not to say it's not going to take a little bit of time.
But it should be quite a bit faster than LDA especially because of the way pi works.
It's really well suited for these sort of matrix factorization problems.
So now that the IMF model has been fitted it's time to actually display the topics.
So we're going to kind of skip the introduction to get feature names but remember just like with vectorization
I can call T.F. idea and then say get feature names pasand some index for any particular word and we'll
get that word back.
So we're now going to show you how to actually grab the top 15 words per topic.
So what we're going to do here is say for index Khama topic in enumerate and just like before.
Off to an MF model we can call component's underscore essentially the exact same process as LDA.
We're just going to do some extreme printing here and say the top 15 words for a topic number and then
we'll passen index and then we're going to say prints and we'll print out a list comprehension here
will say T.F. IDF get the feature names I for I in and will say topic thought arke sorts just like we
did before and we'll say go back 15 and then go all the way to the end.
So starting at the end go back 15 and then go all the way to the end.
So those are essentially the values with the highest coefficients.
So previously with LDA ruling with words to have the highest probabilities of belonging to a topic.
Now with an M F redialing before it's to have the highest coefficient values inside of that matrix and
then we'll go ahead and prints a new line.
OK.
So when you run this you should begin to see these words show up.
Keep in mind the order of these words may be slightly different for you but in general they should be
the same or it's things like research virus Zika disease show up in the first topic.
Another thing to keep in mind is that these topics aren't going to match the topic from LDA.
It's a completely different process.
So we should expect completely different topics.
However there should be some topics that tend to match up especially if you're dealing with the same
data set.
So we should see some topics that tend to work for maybe politics here we can see kind of health disease
et cetera.
Here we can see stuff on the election.
Here we see a similar topic like music albums songs.
And then we see something on education schools students college et cetera.
OK.
So again it's up to you to interpret what these words actually mean for a topic.
And usually it's pretty obvious if you're have a good domain experience with whatever you're working
with.
Now what we want to do is simply attach the discovery topic labels so the original articles.
And that itself is pretty straight forward as well.
We simply same topic results is equal to an IMF model and then we just call it transform on that original
DTM variable that we created and then we same topic results.
Recall that if we actually just grab one of these topic results it's essentially a kind of coefficient
value for the top topic that's representative and what we want is the index position of the most representative
target or topic.
So we call RMX just as we did before.
And if we want to do this across the entire array you can simply say RMX x is equal to 1 so that we
run this along columns and then we have the index positions that match up to these topics.
Same exact thing we did before for LDA.
And then we're just simply going to say pure topic is equal to topic underscore results RMX access equal
to one.
We check out our data frame flips head of the data frame and there can see the science topics.
Again these numbers 1 3 6 are essentially just arbitrary numbers that really mean anything.
They only mean something in context of the words with the highest coefficient values.
And so I mean to keep in mind topic number six if an F has nothing to do with topic number six with
LDA.
These are just kind of arbitrary topic number assignments.
The main thing you have to do is decide OK I'm going to label topic number 6 as education and what you
could do if you really wanted to you could create a little dictionary something like this.
You could say one is to and then search here for Topic number one and say GOP Pence President Russia
et cetera and decide what to do with politics.
So you say topic one has to do with politics and then you'd go off topic number two and decide on something
for that.
So some other topic and you would essentially keep doing this dictionary for topics zero through six
and then what you could do is if you wanted to once that dictionary was Creedon say topic and then say
map and you could basically call this my topic dictionary and you would map my topic dictionary and
then you could create this as the actual Like topic label.
So let's actually show you what this would look like.
Quickly create some topic.
So these have 0 1 2 4 5 and 6 and I going to briefly just kind of try to summarize this.
So looks like Topic number 6 positive education so I'll say edu.
Topic number five looks like s do music.
So I'll say music.
Topic number four looks like s do the election kind of just generalizing here.
So say election number three.
Let's just guess.
Looks like it has to do with Syria Middle East ISIS.
So we'll go ahead and say politics here.
I'll say poly.
There's probably more than one politics.
Number two Senate House people coverage.
Medicaid.
Oh go ahead and say this is health care legislation.
So just say Ali G.
I asked for legislation.
Topic number one looks like this.
Do the campaign so will say election.
You can see it.
Overall these articles tend to skew towards politics and then zero research virus study.
So say it has to do with health.
So now I have my topic dictionary.
That essentially is mapping these numbers for the topic to some sort of string code.
And then I'm going to create a new column topic label that maps that dictionary to the topic.
So when I run this and then check out NPR ahead I get to see the topic labels that I created.
So that's a quick and easy way to map whatever the side of the topic label to be to the actual number.
All right.
That's it for this lecture.
I hope you saw that it's pretty easy that once you understand her perform LDA it should be pretty easy
to then switch out for an MF and we could also see the MF was a little bit faster than LDA and that
speed increase is going to be really obvious when you have a really huge data set.
So coming up next we're going to have a project assessment working with a question dataset try to find
topics for those questions and then we're going to use an MF to perform some topic modeling on that
dataset.
So we'll have an overview of that assessment coming up next.
We'll see other.