Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to have an overview of your assessment for this section of the course.
Let's go ahead and show you what is expected of you for the python assessment by opening up the notebook.
All right.
So underneath the python text basics folder you should see a note book called Python text basics assessment
and you should see another one called solutions which we're going to go over in the very next lecture.
If you open up Python text basic assessment you should see a couple of questions here.
Essentially your tasks are just lined up in bold blue.
So first one is to print the string that displays an LP stands for natural language processing.
So maybe it's a little hard to tell from the front.
But basically we have two variables in LP in natural language processing and use of strings to print
out this one single string.
So that's just as string literals.
Little reminder how to do that then files who wants to create a file in the current working directory
called contacts thought Trixi by either doing it manually or running the Sellery here that open the
file and use that read to save the contents of the file to a string called fields and make sure the
file is close at the end.
So fields just be a single string that looks like this.
Then using pi PTF to open the file called business underscore proposal that PTF and extract the text
of page 2.
So underneath Python text basics there is a PDA here called business underscore proposal.
Go ahead and use typedef to open it and extract the text from page to and it should look something like
this.
Next.
Open the file called contacts text me and append mode and add the text page to from above.
Context RTX T.
And there's a challenge here.
See if you can remove the word author's So then we have two solutions one for the normal assignment
and then one for the challenge assignment and then we have the expressions task which is using the page
to text variable created above extract any email addresses that were contained in the file biz's proposal.
So remember we showed you how to extract phone numbers.
See if you can figure out the basic pattern of an email address which should be some sequence of characters
and then the key thing here to realize is the symbol and then an other sequence of characters.
OK.
Best of luck on the assessment coming up next we're going to go over the solutions.
We'll see there.