Welcome everyone to this lecture on stemming often when searching text for a certain keyword it helps
if the search returns variations of the word.
For instance searching for the term boat might also return things like boats and boating here.
The stem boat is going to be the stem for words like boat boat or boating and boats which are conveying
the idea related to boat stemming is a somewhat crude method for cataloguing related words.
It essentially just chops off letters from the end until the stem is actually reached.
This works fairly well in most cases but unfortunately English has so many exceptions where a more sophisticated
process is usually required.
In fact it's such a rough process that Spacey doesn't even include a Stemmer.
Instead they opt for the more sophisticated method known as limitation which we're going to cover in
the next lecture but you'll often see stemming in natural language processing discussion.
So it's they do have an understanding of the basics of studying before you move onto amortisation.
There is a link in the note book to a discussion on why the maintainer's is spacey the decide not to
include a summer in favor of limitation in case you're interested in the history of the development
of space.
So you can check out the new book for that link discussion now because of this decision not to include
stemming in space.
We're now going to jump over to using an old Teekay and learn about various DeMars.
In fact we're going to show you both the porter Stemmer and the snowball Stemmer.
So one of the most common and effective stemming tools is Porter's algorithm developed by Martin Porter
in 1980 and the algorithm employs five phases of word reduction.
Each with its own set of mapping rules.
So in the first phase simple suffixed mapping rules are the find such as the following.
So here we have a table with S1 going to s to essentially going from one word to a step.
So you can see here that the ending of one s s e s will get reduced to s s or caresses gets reduced
to caress or I guess it gets reduced to ice so ponys gets reduced to P and I and Tai's gets reduced
to t.
I so from a given set of stemming rules only one rule is applied based off the longest suffix S1 thus
caresses reduces to caress but not to CARES.
That way there's no confusion and mixing up different types of words to the wrong stem.
Now there are some more sophisticated phrases that consider the length and complexity of the word before
applying a rule such as trying to map relational or national to their stem relates and national or agreed
and feed to their other see them agree and feed.
Notice that we're going from e d to e or agonal to 80.
So there's lots of different complex rules that the porter Stemmer is going to implement.
Now snowball is a name of a Stebbing language that was also developed by Martin porter and the algorithm
here is actually sometimes called the English Stemmer or porter to Stemmer and it offers a slight improvement
over the original Porter Stemmer both in logic and speed.
So you can essentially think of it as an improvement over the original Porter Stemmer.
So let's use Python and NLC can actually show how to use the Strummer's with Python.
Jump over to a notebook now.
All right the first thing I'm going to do is import an LTE K for the natural language toolkit and then
from an LTE K that's them.
Porter I'm going to import the porter Stemmer and then I'm going to create an instance of this porter
Stemmer ogic and I'm just using tap to autocomplete there and let's create a list of words.
So I'm going to have run and runner and then I'm going to have also ran.
So notice technically these are all conveying the same idea.
They just had different tenses to them.
So run runner and ran actually one is a noun.
These are verbs but you can see they're both conveying are all three of them are conveying the same
idea of running and we're going to add one more runs and let's add in a few more words like easily.
And we'll also put in fairly just we can get some more examples.
And the way you stem down these words is you just pass them into the stem method of this porter Stemmer.
So the way this works is we can say for word in words we can print out the original word and then I'm
going to concatenate an arrow to show you what it stems to.
And then off our Stemmer object so off piece Stemmer you call them and then pasand that particular word.
So all I'm doing here is I'm going to print out the original word from this list then I get a print
out an arrow with a string and then I'm going to show the stem the version of the word using the porter
Stemmer.
So when I run this I can see that run goes to run run or goes the runner ran goes to ran runs however
does get turned down to runs and that's according to the porter Stemmer rules.
We should chop off the s and now run and runs get treated the same.
What's interesting here is that easily and fairly they get them down to anything of an eye which is
kind of interesting here.
So the Stemmer is actually able to recognize that a runner is a noun not a verb form or a adverb.
And these adverbs are here easily and fairly.
Their stem to the unusual root of easily and I am fairly with an eye as well.
So keep that in mind for use in the porter Stemmer as we mention there's a more sophisticated and slightly
better version of the Stemmer called the snowball Stemmer.
And in order to use it you just say T.K. that's them.
That snowball import and called the snowball Stemmer and then you can create an instance of that Stemmer
by saying snowball Stemmer and this one also requires you to tell you what language it's in.
So we're just going to pass in English as the language parameter and we're going to use the same words
as before.
So now we're going to say for word in words print out the word and then we'll say print out in concatenation
what the snowball Stemmer steps to.
So as Stemmer stem and then word and when you run this you notice that the stemming performs slightly
differently run and runs both gets them down to run.
But now fairly just goes down to fair which is interesting because maybe that performs better for things
like fairness.
So fairly and fairness may both go down to fair.
In fact we can check that by adding in some more words like fairness and if we run this again there's
that fairness goes down to fair fairly goes down to fair leave and I let's try with this snowball Stemmer
and now fairly in fairness both go down to fair.
Isn't the snowball Stemmer.
And typically it's not really a matter of predicting what the stem is going to be the actual stem itself.
It's not super important.
What's important is that you understand the actual process that's happening here.
There is some set of algorithmic rules that these numbers are following to try to reduce down these
words to some sort of root idea or root word.
And I would encourage you to play around with distempers and see how they differ.
Words of your own choice.
So we're going to show one more list here of words kind of as a fun example we're going to type in the
word generous and then run I write in generation and then we're going to write in generously.
And let's also say generate So some of these are similar words and some of them are not so generous
and generation don't really have anything to do if each other.
Yeah technically these kind of the same Latin root but really they're conveying that for ideas to be
generous is not the same thing as actually generating something however generously and generous or conveying
extremely similar ideas and generation and generate are probably also pretty similar ideas.
So let's run that and let's actually copy the snowball Stemmer for this and run the snowball Stemmer
on that list of words and you can see here that generous and generously actually get reduced both to
generous and then Generation and generates both get reduced to Genner rot ending of a T.
So hopefully that gives an idea of how you can use an LTE system words.
And often when you're reading books on natural language processing people like to perform stemming before
they run some sort of analysis in order to try to reduce words to their root.
Now as I mentioned Spacey didn't have stemming because it figures limitation is a much more effective
way of actually reducing these words.
So coming up next we're going to learn about limitation and see why it's probably a more effective way
of reducing these words to their roots.
We'll see at the next lecture.