Welcome back here we are where we left off last time fitting our model to our ex trainee and white training
data set.
Let's go ahead and learn how to test the accuracy of the model using the test data set to do this.
We're going to say from S-K learn import metrics.
Then we're going to grab the features from the test data set.
Remember that was X test.
Now we're going to predict on this the exact same way we would predict on brand new data we would simply
call our train model called up predict and we passen new data that the model hasn't seen before.
In this case for evaluation we're going to pass an X test against his brand new data the model hasn't
seen before.
But lucky for us we know the correct answers the correct answers are why test.
So we're going to do is pass an X test and we're going to ask the model to predict on this test set
and then see what their predictions are.
So now we have predictions that look like this.
HAM HAM and et cetera there's some spam in there and we have the true values the true values are why
test and here are these true values.
So now we're going to compare our predictions against Why test just as we explain in the slides during
the previous lectures.
There's various ways we can do this.
One way is actually build out the confusion matrix ourselves so we could say metrics dots and then call
confusion matrix and then pasan why test and predictions and then print out the result of this and we
actually get back our confusion matrix.
So our confusion matrix looks like this.
And your confusion matrix may look slightly different depending on your train test split or how you
actually train your model.
But here we can see that overall it looks like we're not able to predict well on spam and you could
actually make the confusion matrix a little better by passing it into a data frame.
And I'm going to copy and paste the line of code that does this from the notes.
So the line of code that does it's from the notes again you can just open up the notebook and scroll
down until you get to test accuracy of the model.
It's right here it is the line I just copied but we'll come back here and we're just passing in this
confusion matrix into a Pandurs data frame and then we're labeling the index in the columns HAMOND spam.
That way if actually the splay this data frame that I could see the labeled confusion matrix.
So it looks like I only correctly classified 5 for the spam.
And here you can see incorrectly classified 44 spam that were actually him and I incorrectly classify
219 spam as him and I correctly classified 1404 for my test dataset correctly as him.
So these results are definitely not good.
Now we're going to get much better results when we take into account the text data set itself.
That means that it's to say the actual text messages the raw text data.
But we haven't learned about text feature extraction yet so we're going to leave that aside for now.
Next I want to show you besides the confusion matrix.
You can also print out a classification report and the way you do this is you say metric starts and
then you call classification report and again you pass your test against the predictions that you made
and you print this out.
And you get back this classification report which tells you precision.
Recall an EF 1 score for each of the categories.
So here you can see I'm getting pretty good precision and recall on my ham but very poor precision and
recall on the spam.
So overall my model is pretty good at the testing Hahm but it's horrible at detecting spam text messages
and I can print out the overall accuracy of the model by saying metrics accuracy score and then passing
tests and predictions and I can print these out and here I see my model is eighty four point three percent
accuracy.
Now what you can also do is choose different machine learning models and see those perform better.
Right now we've only ran a logistic regression model but we could try other models and we do that just
to show you the syntax is actually the same.
You'll say from S-K learn thought and then choose a family of models and to decide what family models
to look at you can just look at the sikat learn documentation but you would say something like naive
Beys import.
And then we're going to use a multinomial Navy base model here it will say and B model is equal to multinomial
and b c a very common classifier for text data sets.
And then just like before we take our model now we fit it to the training data so we pass it x train
and y train.
And just as before we say predictions is equal to our model and then we predict off the excess data
set and then we can printout the confusion matrix we can say confusion matrix and then pasan why test
against these new predictions.
So notice here how this code essentially looks all was exactly the same as the code we use for the logistic
regression here.
We just imported the model create an instance of the model fit the model and then predict using the
model.
And those are really the key steps we want to understand for this lecture.
The fact that we can basically use the same syntax for a wide variety of models with sikat learn import
the model create an instance of it fit the model and then predict what the model and you can use those
predictions with the confusion matrix per classification report.
So running this we see this model also does not perform well.
In fact now we're not able to quickly than to fight any of the spam which means we're essentially doing
zero precision and zero recall for spam.
So we can actually prove this by printing out metrics or Doc classification report and saying why test
and predictions run that and the spam we're failing to detect any spam correctly which is denoted here
by that 0.
So let's try another model and often you can experiment with various models quite easily.
Like learn we can say from S-K learn let's try a vector machine model we're going to import as we see
a support vector classification model will say as a VC model is equal to as we see in this case and
only one of the parameters you can always shift tab on these models after you've imported them so you
have to run this import line first and then you're able to shift tab here in order to see the various
parameters.
One of the things going to change here is just make sure that gamma is set to auto.
It's actually at the fault.
So in that case I don't need to set it.
But if you want a different gamma you could.
So there's Gamma's equal to auto default values.
And then I going say support vector model and I'm going to fit it to the training data and just like
before we're going to see predictions as equal to as we see model predict of X test and then print out
the off of metrics.
The confusion matrix passing in Y test and passing them predictions again the exact same process for
a completely different machine learning model.
If you understand these five lines of code then you basically understand the main point of the series
of lectures for the syntax of psychic learn you import the model create the model fit the model and
then predict using the model and then evaluate your predictions.
So if you run this you're able to see how well the support vector classifier worked.
OK.
So again keep in mind this is really just the syntax we need to know and the way we can test our train
models on new data simply by calling that predict and then getting those predictions.
Now what we haven't learned yet is if we go all the way back to the top Remember we still have the actual
text message itself.
What we need to learn is how to actually extract features from the text information because right now
the length and punctuation that numerical data is not enough to make an accurate assessment or an accurate
model.
We need to somehow convert this text message into numerical information.
So coming up next we're going to learn about feature extraction from text.
We'll see if they're.