Welcome back.
Let's have a quick overview of your sentiment analysis Assessment Project.
I'm gonna open up the notebook and do a quick review.
Okay.
Here I am at the notebook.
We essentially just have two major tasks with an extra challenge associated with each task.
So the first task has to do with those actual word vectors we discussed at the very beginning of this
section of the course where we want you to perform vector arithmetic on your own words.
So we want you to write code that evaluates vector arithmetic vector of Matic is just adding and subtracting
those particular word vectors similar to what we did with King minus man plus woman.
And the goal is to come as close to an expected word as possible.
And if you have really good arithmetic you can feel free to share those success stories on the Q A forum.
So essentially at the end what we want you to do is just follow along these comments.
So import Spacey low the language library and also remember to use the larger model.
So you have access to those word vectors and then choose the words you wish to compare and obtain their
vectors.
So for example you can choose the words that we had in our actual example like man king and woman or
choose your own words.
So I would really encourage you to choose your own words but if you're kind of stuck on this you can't
just follow along the example we did during the course.
So then you're going to import spatial and the finite cosine similarity function.
There's actually cosine similarity function also available and psychic learn.
So lots of different options here for actually calculating the cosine similarity then you'll write the
expression calculating that new vector and then list the top 10 closest vectors in the vocabulary that
results of this new vector.
So very similar to what we did and then what would I want you to do is as a challenge kind of encapsulate
all this into a function so write a function that takes in three strings and then performs an A minus
B policy arithmetic and returns a top 10 result.
So here's a empty function for you vector math you would pass in three strings like King man and woman
and it would automatically return the top 10 for a minus B policy essentially repeating all the steps
you have appear but just enough within a function then Task two is to perform voter sentiment analysis
on your own review.
So we want you to set up a sentiment intensity analyzer and then want you to write your own string review.
Feel free to be as positive or a negative as you want and then obtain that aside these scores for your
own review and then the challenge is to write a function that takes in a review and returns a score
of positive negative or neutral.
Very similar to what you're doing up here except it's actually just returning back.
This string code.
OK so pretty straightforward.
It does match up a lot of what we did in the lectures.
But if you're stuck on anything feel free to go to the next lecture or we're going to go over the solutions
notebook we'll see if there.