Welcome back everyone to this lecture unlimited ization.
In contrast systemin limitation looks beyond word reduction and considers it languages full vocabulary
to apply a morphological analysis towards the lemma of was B and the lemma of mice is mouse.
So we're not just shortening words or cutting off the end of them.
Instead we're looking at the full context of the word.
Furthermore the lemma of meeting might be meet or meeting depending on its actual use.
In a sense this limitation is typically seen as much more informative than simple stemming which is
why the Speccy library has opted to only have limitation available instead of simple stemming and again
limitation is going to look at the surrounding text.
The Terman a given words part of speech.
It doesn't categorize words into just general phrases in an upcoming lecture.
We're going to investigate word vectors and similarity in a lot more detail.
But for right now let's learn how to perform limitation with space.
Let's jump over to Jupiter notebook.
OK to begin we need to do our standard imports for Spacey which is importing Spacey and then also loading
in the actual language library to use it.
In our case it's going to be Spacey load and then an underscore core underscore web underscore S.M.
So run that again that may take some time to put it in your computer and we're going to create a doc
object going to pass in a unicode string here and say I am a runner.
Running in a race and I'll say because I love to run since I ran today.
OK so lots of different use cases for words that seem to all have at the core of the idea running.
So runner running race run and ran but there are some distinct differences.
Things like a runner is a noun versus running as a verb.
A race itself is actually a noun and then run.
In this case here that's a verb and ran as a past tense verb.
Let's go ahead and create that document and then we're going to do is say for tokin in our documents
we're going to print out the following.
Will print out the token text and then we're going to have a tab so backslash t introduces a tab and
then we're going to say print out the token part of speech.
So POS underscore then we'll print out another time then we'll say print out the lemma of the tokens.
That's actual limitation.
And notice here when we say that Lema that's actually going to input or output a number.
So we'll talk about that in just a little bit and then we'll put in another tab.
Essentially just reformating and then we'll say token Lemme underscore So notice here one of these is
just Lemma.
The other one is lemma underscore.
Go ahead and run this and you should see more or less a table that kind of looks like this.
The formatting may be slightly off depending on these numbers if one of them is larger or if this word
is a little longer than the shorter words the overall You should see the original word as the token.
I am a runner.
The speech pronoun verb noun adverb etc..
And then here we actually have a number so that number is going to point to a specific lemma inside
of this language library room of this language library supporters somewhere around like more than 50000
words.
So each of those has actually an individual hash.
It's lemma that we can then reference and then dilemma underscore that's the actual lemma that we're
going to be referring to here.
Now something that's interesting to note here is that some of these words are actually getting reduced
down to the same lemma even though they're being used in different senses.
So running run and ran are all getting reduced down to the lemma run and you can actually check that
it's the same lemma the run by taking a look at the actual hash value for this particular lemma.
So each lemma has its own individual hash reference.
And we're going to be seeing that sort of behavior a lot with Spacey and that not only can you access
the lemmas or the parts of speech with these underscore arguments at the very end that this attribute.
But there's also a hash code that then you can use essentially as a look up for this English language
which is almost asking or it's acting like almost like a huge hash table with a bunch of lemmings.
And parts of speech that you can look up.
OK.
Now you'll notice that this sort of printing out is a little sloppy because of the way that some of
these tokens maybe longer than others so you get these sort of weird outputs.
We went ahead and create a function for you that displays this sort of output nicely.
So I'm going to copy and paste it from the notes and then quickly go over it.
It's essentially that's using f string formatting.
So it looks something like this.
So you can go ahead and run that.
But basically it's the show lemmas function from delimitation notebook inside the python BASIX folder.
And what it does is you provided some text.
Essentially it documents and for every token in that text it's going to print out the token text to
speech the lemma or the hash code and then the actual limit itself.
And we added in some alignment that we covered in the string literals lecture's one of the very first
lectures in this course.
So in case you're a little fuzzy on that you can review it but that's all it's doing is just printing
things out nicely for us.
So then what we can do is we can create a new document something like an LP and then say something like
I saw 10 mice today and you can ask for show lemmas and then say doc to run that and it's going to print
them out in a nicer table than printing manually with these tabs spaces.
So I would encourage you to use this show lemmas and explore what gets reduced down to what particular
lemmas.
OK.
So really that's it.
And again limitation is a more informative way of reducing down words to really their true roots.
And it's also going to take into account the way the words are actually being used in the sentence.
So that's why Spacey is only going to implement limits ization instead of the kind of more crude stemming
methods that we saw that essentially just chop off words.
OK.
Coming up next we're going to have a brief discussion on Stoppard's.
We'll see other.