Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to have a brief overview of the assessment for the topic modeling section.
Let's go ahead and open up the topic modeling Assessment Project notebook.
OK.
Underneath the topic modeling folder you should be able to find the Assessment Project notebook as well
as the Assessment Project solutions and going to overview the Assessment Project and in the next lecture
we'll go over the solutions together.
So the Assessment Project is a topic modeling Assessment Project.
And for this category you're going to be working over 400000 questions from Quora.
Quora is a question answer site where people can post questions and then crowdsource from the community
for answers.
And what we're going to do is to ask that these questions though actually have any labeled category.
And if you're looking for the questions it's simply this Quora underscore questions thought see a tweet
file.
So essentially this is a list of questions that look something like this.
So once asking What's step by step guide to invest in something mentally very lonely which one way to
dissolve water quickly sugar cetera and you can see here that there's a wide variety of topics.
And right now we only have the questions so maybe nice if we can build some sort of automated system
that automatically tries to guess the topic of an incoming question and then we be able to put it in
the correct location on the court Web site.
So we're going to do the things that we did before import pantless read in the CSC file.
You do some preprocessing.
And for this particular project I want you to use non-negative matrix factorization if you want.
You can also perform this with LDA.
But because of the size of the data set it's quite a bit larger than the articles dataset.
And since MF is faster than LDA we only expect you to use an MF for this project.
Again it's optional if you want to use LDK but we only expect an MF so perform T.F. IDF vectorization
explore the Maxy and mehndi parameters.
There's no right or wrong parameters here but you can use the same ones we used in the lecture.
You should get a sparse matrix that looks something like this.
Again notice it's quite a bit larger than NPR.
NPR it was around 12000 articles.
Here we're dealing with hundred and four thousand questions.
Granted the questions are shorter.
So that has to do a little bit with the size difference but these There's way more questions and there
are articles so this data is bigger.
And then you can reform non-avian matrix factorization and you're going to ask for 20 expected components
essentially try to find 20 topics here.
And I also encourage you to use random state 42 so you can compare the same topics that we get to the
ones you get and then print out the top 15 most common words for each of the 20 topics.
So here are the various topics that I got with random state.
You can see some of these are learning languages and books things on the election things on businesses
countries Russia Pakistan things on movies songs job work engineering things on India looks like resolutions
New Year's etc..
So there's a bunch of different topics there.
And then you're going to add a new column to the original court data frame that labels each question
into one of the 20 topics.
So you're going to perform from our original data frame that has a list of questions to something that
looks like this some sort of topics and obviously if you want.
You can add a you know topic name and map some sort of topic names.
Each of these topics that's not really necessary because there's two main topics I would expect you
to manually name them all.
But again essentially at the end of the day we should have something that looks like this.
All right.
So best of luck with that assessment project.
Coming up next we're going to show you the solutions.
We'll see you there.