Welcome back everyone to this lecture on feature extraction from text.
This is part one we're going to be going over that basic theory of feature extraction most classic machine
learning algorithms can't actually accept or take in raw text.
Instead we need to perform some sort of feature extraction from the raw text in order to pass numerical
features to the machine learning algorithm.
For example we could count the occurrence of each word to map text to an actual number.
Let's discuss counter vectorization along with term frequency an inverse document frequency.
So come vectorization looks like this.
Let's imagine we had a list of messages.
So here we have three messages.
And this looks really similar to the data that we previously had.
So right now everything is in raw text or E-string in Python what we can do is using sikat learn we
can perform count vectorization and notice the syntax here looks really similar to the same way we created
machinery models of sikat learn we say from S-K learn and then some family of feature extraction models
specifically from text.
We import this vectorize are now what this is going to do is it's going to count the occurrences of
all the unique words.
So after you create your count vector isor you're going to vectorize those messages.
And basically what happens is it treats each individual unique word as a feature and then it's going
to count the occurrence of each unique feature or word throughout every single document and each document
is essentially just each text message.
So it can think of that term document as just another word for every documented text.
So if we take a look here.
Notice that the word call didn't show up in the first message or the third message.
It only showed up in the middle message or the word dogs only shows up in the last message.
Now some words do show it more than once like the word go.
And the word too.
But overall we should see a lot of zeros because most messages are not going to contain all the words.
So you can imagine for a very large set of documents otherwise known as a corpus we're going to have
what's known as a very sparse matrix a matrix of a lot of zeros.
This sort of matrix is known as the document term matrix or DTM.
Again we're just counting the number of times each unique word throughout the entire vocabulary of all
the documents shows up in each particular document.
Now in alternative to count vectorization is something called T.F. idea.
Vector Isar or term frequency inverse document frequency of vectorize or.
It's also going to create a document matrix from our messages.
However instead of filling in the document term matrix or DTM with token counts it calculates term frequency
inverse document frequency value for each word.
So let's talk about what that actually means.
What does T.F. IETF mean.
Well let's first look at that first term T.F. or term frequency we can think of term frequency as a
function of the term and the particular document and all it is it's the raw count of a term a document.
Basically just answering the question the number of times that that particular term occurs in documentary.
So for example we take a look at the term frequency for the word dogs.
The term frequency for the first two messages would be zero.
And then the term frequency for the word dogs in the last message would be one.
Again the term frequency is just the raw count of a term in a document something that we just saw.
However term frequency alone isn't enough for a thorough feature analysis of the text.
Let's imagine very common terms like stop such as or the because the terms such as the so common term
frequency will tend to incorrectly emphasize documents which happen to use words like the more frequently
without giving enough weight to the more meaningful terms like Unique words such as red and dogs and
inversed document frequency factor is incorporated which diminishes the weight of terms that occur very
frequently in the documents set and increases the weight.
The terms that occur rarely It is the logarithmically scaled inverse fraction of the documents that
contain the word obtained by dividing the total number of documents by the number of documents containing
the term and then taking the logarithmic of that quotient.
So we know that T.F. IDF isn't the term frequency times one over the document frequency or otherwise
known as the inverse document frequency.
So here we can see the formula for term frequency inverse document frequency as well as the full equation
for inverse document frequency.
Now fortunately for us sikat learn can calculate all of these terms for us through the use of its API.
Keep in mind you should notice how similar the syntaxes to our previous use of machine learning models
and sikat learn here you can see that from Eski learned that feature traction the text we're able to
import the TAF idea.
Victimiser And again we simply call T.F. idea of victimiser.
And in this case we're going to want to call it transform on the actual raw text messages which is going
to perform turn frequency inversed document frequency vectorization on the actual text messages.
So all this is doing is not only is it taking into account the term frequency how many times the terms
show up in a single document.
But as well as the inversed document frequency How often do these terms show up in all across all the
documents.
That way the very common words aren't weighed as much as the unique words TAF IDF allows us to understand
the context of words across an entire corpus of documents instead of just its relative importance in
a single document.
Coming up next we're going to explore how to perform these operations with Python in psychic alert.
We'll see it next lecture.