We'll come back in this lecture we're going to go over the solution for the parts of speech assessment.
Let's head over to the notebook and walk through it.
OK so here are the parts of speech assessment.
Don't forget to run the top sell in or its imports basically load English library and then have the
Speccy ready to go.
Next we want to create a doc object from the file Peter Rabbit that DXi and we can do this by simply
saying with open and then we'll say from textfiles.
Peter Rabbit you should be able to auto complete that using tab unless you're in a different directory.
Then we'll say dock is equal to an LP f read.
And now we have a document object the next for every token in the third sentence we want to print the
token text the part of speech tag the fine green tag tag and the description of the fine green tag will
say for token in list doc thought sentence or a sense for sentences and then we're to grab index too
which is the third right because we have 0 1 to 2.
The third sentence of these sentences from that list.
So then for every token inside that tokenized third sentence we're just going to print out the following
A little bit of strings will say print out the token text print out the token part a speech print out
the token tag and then in order to get the explanation we just need to say a string of spacey explain
token dot tag underscore and we're going to add in a little bit of formatting here simply by adding
in Colon and then some spacing will just go ahead and say colon 10 for all these to add in a little
bit of spacing so we get some nice formatting.
You can add that in at the very end of vallies curly braces.
If we run this we should get back kind of this nice looking table OK.
Next was to provide a frequency list of the speech tags for the entire document.
So for this we're going to use count by we'll say speech counts as equal to Doc count by and then we'll
say Spacey to transfer attributes part of speech to then four key value pair in sorted POS counts items
as we did during the lecture.
We're just going to print out using again string formatting here.
The key and then calling Dawk vocab at that key We're going to grab the text and then we'll actually
say the for the value.
So remember the values the actual count.
So if you run this you should see something that looks like this.
And you can add in a little bit of formatting if you want to you can say something like.
There are the counts
so 83 counts 127 counts seventy five count etc..
Maybe you can even add something like ID and then POS so if you run those ID 83 POS a..
83 counts and so on.
Really up to you main idea is to remember you can call count by and that can use a dictionary which
can then sort into items.
The challenge was what percentage of tokens are known.
So one needs to do is figure out how to actually get the length of all the tokens or how many tokens
are there completely.
For that you can just check the length of the document.
And there's 1258 tokens and we're looking for nouns so we know that noun's is 91.
We have it right here 176 counts.
So we just say POS counts and what you could do is check out 91 and that returns back 176.
And then we divide it by the length of the document and if we times that by 100.
So we say 100 times this.
That's thirteen point ninety nine percent of all the tokens are known.
Next we want it to display the dependency parts for the third sentence.
And that way we can do that.
You can just simply say the splays see render and then we're going to pass and a list of Doc sense but
we actually only want the third sentence.
So just like before the index at two call style for syntactic dependency.
In my case I'm using Jupiter said equal to true.
If you're running a script to simply say the splays see that serve and then you can add in more options
if you want but you should get something that looks more or less like this.
This is the actual display see for the Dep. parts.
Next he wanted you to show the first two named entities from the tale of Peter Rabbit.
Remember we can grab all the Anstey's simply by calling Doc A.S..
So this is essentially kind of these tuples of all these entities we're really only concerned with the
first two.
So we're going to go from everything at the beginning all the way index to essentially 0 and 1.
So here they are.
And now we want to print out their properties.
So various ways to do this but we can say for entity in this little short list of tuples I'm going to
print out the entity text plus the entity label plus the string explanation of it so I'll say Spacey
thought explain that entity label and then we can add in some whitespace too.
Just so has a little bit nicer formatting these in between make sure there's a plus there after that
and then add in one more whitespace
so we can go ahead and run that.
And we see that we have tale of Peter Rabbit work of art.
Beatrix Potter person.
Now how many senses are contained in the tale of Peter Rabbit.
For this you can check out Doc that sense run that and remember that's a generator.
So what we need to do is we can cast that to a list and then just check the length of that list.
It's going to turn 56 next for the challenge was how many sentences contained named entities.
For this is going to be a little more complicated.
Well we should first do is get a list of the actual sentence text so say list of sense is equal to and
here we're going to say a.p of sent text for every sentence in Doc thought sense.
So there's my list of sentences then I want a list of any R's.
So it's going to be doc for Doc in list of sentences if Doc E.A. us which essentially is saying go through
every document in this list of sentences and check if there's actually entities there and then we'll
just check the length of list of any R's and this kind of a misnomer is not really the list of any R's
It's the list of sentences with any R's and if you're in that you should get back 49 49 sentences contained
named entities out of the 56 total sentences.
The last challenge problem was display the name and see visualization for list of sense 0 from the previous
problem.
So that would be this list of sentences here.
Let's go ahead and show that we can display the render list of sense zero and then call style is equal
to E.A..
And in my case I will say Jupiter is equal to true.
Run that and wups make sure it's display C C and there we go.
OK that's it for the assessment solutions.
Feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums if you have any questions.
We'll see you at the next section.