Guys.
Welcome back to the course.
So in this lecture Let's talk about portfolios.
I mean to answer the question How important is your portfolio and you probably thought in your head.
Yes it's very important and we know this but I really just want to talk a little bit about why they're
important and better ways of thinking about it.
So portfolios are obviously very very big if since you're new to web development or maybe you are just
new and general you probably haven't noticed that every single development firm or freelancer has at
least some form of a portfolio.
That's the way that we show clients what we're capable of and who we work with.
No it's no exaggeration to say that if you do not have a portfolio you probably will not make a sale.
The exception to this is if you make a sale through some sort of an inside connection inside connections
maybe they don't need a portfolio.
So now that we've pretty much gotten out of the way you need to have some form of a portfolio.
Let's talk a little bit about what clients look for now.
There are a lot of big things that clients look for and the more important ones are the things that
are actually happening subconsciously things that they're not consciously looking for or thinking about.
So the three things that I've noticed over and over again.
Clients first look to see whether or not you have consistent high quality across your portfolio then
they're going to look for whether or not they recognize any of the applications or sites that you have
in it.
And then after that they're going to look to see if there's any example in your portfolio that is similar
to what they're doing either in some technical regard design or regard or just in general.
Okay so the first thing that they look at is is there a consistent quality across your portfolio.
Now why is that worth pointing out.
If I look at five Web sites or apps you made I'm going to expect that each one is going to be consistent
and how good they are how functional how pretty they are.
Now if I were to look at five.
One is fantastic.
One is terrible and three are OK.
What does that signal to me.
It signals to me that I don't actually know what I'm going to get right because one out of five chances
say that you're going to come back something terrible.
And 60 percent of the time when you come back with something that's OK.
So typically clients whether or not they recognize us they're more interested in whether or not they
can see that you constantly produce the same quality.
Now it's better to have slightly lower quality that's consistent then to have quality that's all over
the board.
When you have quality that's all over the board in your portfolio they just don't know what to think.
Now the second thing is do they recognize any of the apps.
If they do that's a huge plus for you for some reason there's just some psychological effect going on
that when they know you've built something that they use they feel like all of a sudden you are much
more substantial you are much much more capable than you really are.
Not to say that you're not capable It's just that for some reason if I know that you've built something
that affects my life already or affects lots of other people I'm obviously going to put you on a much
higher pedestal.
Now the last thing was they're going to look for things that specifically apply to their project.
That's obviously a smart thing for them to do right.
Because if you can build something similar to what they want you to build chances are you can build
whatever it is they're asking for much more effectively.
That is something honestly when you even look for subcontractors look for people that have done work
before that's similar to what you work on or what you're hiring them for.
Now if you took the strategy of picking a specific need to go after then you're probably in luck in
this category because you're probably going to see something that's similar to what they want you to
build.
Now if you did a more general strategy you're probably at a disadvantage but in general if you pick
a wide spread of different things you might get lucky and they might find something.
It also is the case that a lot of times will specifically ask for something.
Or if you're in actual contact with them you can show them something that's similar.
Now just be aware at the very beginning of this whole process you're going to be at a huge disadvantage.
But I've built out this entire section to help you go from zero to something.
And I'm going to share pretty much all the hacks.
I know that you can use to get to a point where you know you're not at a huge disadvantage anymore.
Now one big takeaway I want you to get from this lecture is that a lot of people don't realize this
but almost all big companies out there almost all prospective clients are only going to show five to
ten portfolio items and on the client side they're only going to look at maybe five to 10 portfolio
items.
Now what does that mean.
That means that you the upstart maybe with no portfolio at all.
You actually only need to get to that range after which that point there's not a huge advantage to being
a large established company at least in terms of a lot of companies out there have hundreds of the portfolio
items they're not going to show all of it it's unrealistic to show it and even if they do clients don't
look at that many.
The biggest vintage they have is that they can pick five to 10 that have consistent quality and probably
have some type of name recognition.
Or they pick probably their best projects.
So keep that in mind.
You do not need a 100 portfolio items to establish the same amount of trust that you can get with five
to 10.
So that's a big advantage for you and just keep in mind you just need to get to the five to 10 range.
OK.
Any questions posed in the group discussion in the next lecture.
Going to keep this going.
We're going to talk a little bit more about easy ways to fill your portfolio how to tackle the arts
in the next lecture.