Hey guys.
Welcome to the first lecture of this course.
I am super excited to be teaching this.
So in this lecture we're going to cover course overview I'm going to talk about each section in this
course what you should expect to get out of it.
What skills you're going to have at the end of each section.
We're also to cover the course format and work on setting some expectations so you know what you're
going to get out of this.
All right so in the first section or just going to cover introduction material in the first section
it might actually be more skewed towards people who are thinking about starting a web development business
because we're going to cover.
How do they work.
What do they look like and what are the benefits to starting and running one.
We're going to talk a little bit about the sprint kecks story.
I'm going to just talk about how I started my web studio.
What were my problems.
Trials tribulations anything that might be interesting and you can laugh at all my mistakes.
We're going to talk a little bit about framing this because a lot of people are going to be coming at
this from different expertise some of you will be from design some more you will be marketers some small
business owners are going to help you understand in each case how you can apply all the learning in
this course to you or to wrap that section by talking just a little bit about how you can get the most
out of the course.
So in the second section we're going to cover some general understanding.
I'm going to cover different ways that development firms operate.
What are the options available to you.
What are some more macro understanding things that you should understand in order to be successful.
I'm going to help you set expectations of what you should expect from your development business.
When do you see the benefits from all your activities.
What should you know that is Section 3.
I'm going to help you plan out your strategy to make the most profit and to make the best business possible.
I'm going to help you make decisions along a variety of things how to operate in knishes how to find
Meesha is whether or not you should operate in a niche whether or not you should hire in-house or contract
exclusively.
We're going to talk about what zones you should use if you choose to use outsourcing.
I'm going to help you pick what type of development you're going to do.
Are you specialized or generalized.
I'm also going to introduce some frameworks that are can be incredibly helpful for helping you understand
what's possible with your development business and what is simply a waste of time.
Then in Section 4 we're going to jump in and get our hands dirty.
I'm going to show you how you can create a professional web presence for as cheap as $9000.
You're going to follow along as we take a deep dive into how do web studios and web development businesses
create their web presence.
What are the popular standards what works for getting your messaging out there and how to figure out
who your exact client group is going to be.
I'm going to show you what your options are for getting your web presence up.
How do you go about that.
What do you need to know.
I mean going to help you pick your name and how to pick what message you're trying to exude with your
web presence with your name with your entire brand identity.
Under cover.
Briefly how you should plan to upgrade your web presence and some cool tricks that we use at Sprint
Qik to really up our game when it came to our Web site.
Then in the next section we're going to do an in-depth coverage of how to find an ad subcontractors
to your team.
Now not everybody is going to do use a subcontractor strategy but it's something that you need to know
if you want to be good at managing and good at finding help.
That's going to bring your business to the next level.
We're going to look at the three biggest platforms for finding contract work.
We're going to cover how you should get acquainted with them what you need to know what are the things
you should ignore.
What are the tips and tricks for getting the most out of them.
That is the next action to cover portfolios.
We're going to address how do you start off from nothing.
How do you build a strategy around gaining the best portfolio items and we're going to cover some tips
and tricks some really cool strategies for getting awesome portfolio items very easily.
Then the next section we're going to cover 13 different strategies that we used here at Sprint click
to get clients.
Some of them are more generalized.
Some of them are very unique.
You will only hear them here and I must show you exactly how I did them.
We're going to cover all sorts of things one to cover tutorial making strategies white papers.
We're going to cover how you can use things like perpetual discounting how you can use your prior established
affiliations to bring in sales and in order to cover some timeless techniques that were a little bit
of time you can bring in a steady stream of leads.
The next section we're going to cover proposals we're going to cover what the clients look for what
clients care about.
We're going to cover what are the easy ways of making professional proposals what you should focus on
what you should ignore in the next section.
We're going to cover some of the best this is when it comes to managing our clients keeping them happy
and getting them to send you repeat work year after year.
We're going to cover things like setting the tone in your relationship how to stay confident even in
situations where you don't know the answer to a question or even what you're doing.
We're also going to cover more technical hands on things like what's the proper way of billing your
client and how you can go about picking a tool to do so.
In the next section we're going to cover a monster knowledge base of best practices and techniques for
growing your business and maintaining your business fundamentals or Dekha frameworks for growth.
We're going to talk about things like agile methodologies.
I'm going to introduce you to some basic techniques like figuring out what your client's budget is and
being able to tell how valuable your client is before you even pass over a dollar.
We're going to talk about how to structure your billing.
We're going to talk about red flags you should look for with clients where you can even get to cover
really common scenarios like running projects without contracts.
What you need to know how you should do it correctly.
There's a ton of information in that section.
I can't even do it justice talking about it now so go and look over the lecture list in the next section
or uncover some easy to use free online project management tools that will dramatically increase your
efficiency as a development business.
First we're going to look at to get acquainted with it I'm going to show you how it works.
What are the advantages and then I want to show you how you can customize a sauna to fit your development
business.
Specifically we're going to show you some really cool techniques how you can turn it inside out to increase
transparency and keep your clients happy.
After that we're going to cover Trello which is a brand new and very popular visual layout project management
tool.
I'm going to show you how you can use that system to actually encompass a lot more than a sauna.
And again how to customize it for your specific use case.
After that we're going to cover Google Drive really quickly where I can show you some really cool functionality
that you can use to keep your projects on time in budget and you can use as a technique for attracting
more clients.
So after that we're wrapping it up and I'm going to include a section where we give you all of our free
contracts that you can use and customized for your development business.
These are contracts we made custom and cost us thousands of dollars well over $10000.
You can use them for whatever you please.
They've been sanitized and ready for your use.
So after that we're wrapping up the course so you should be an expert at running and growing a development
business.
So the Course format for the course is actually quite simple it's split between three different things.
One you have talking head videos or I'm talking to you right now.
Then we have a lot of screencast where you could see over my shoulder and I get to walk you through
as I show you platforms Web sites techniques and I show you exactly how I did them.
Talk to you throughout the entire way show you step by step.
The third type are more out in the field at the very end of the course.
I'm going to attach some real life kind of case studies where I can show you things that worked for
us and there are actually real.
Not just made for a teaching course.
OK guys so I hope you're excited to take this course.
Any questions at all.
Post them in the group discussion.
You can always send me a private message.
I'm always around respond to those.
Take advantage of me as a resource.
All right guys.
See you in the lectures.