Hey guys welcome back to the course so in this lecture we're going to go over a sauna.
A sauna is a free and very very very popular project management tool that a lot of startups use.
I believe it was started by the co-founder of Facebook.
It's very light.
It's very easy it works on every single device you have.
Now we're going to cover how to get acquainted with it which features and kind of aspects of it.
Should you be familiarized with.
And then in the next lecture when I go over how you can use this for your actual situation and for your
actual contractor kind of scenario.
Now asana is great for a lot of different things.
It's Personally my favorite project management tool and it's what we use here at Sprint.
OK so without further ado let's get into a sauna.
Start messing around start getting used to it and then we'll start talking about how you can make this
work for you and your project and how you can make it dramatically increase the efficiency of your project.
So let's go to the screencast.
All right.
So let's get acquainted with a sauna now.
So the way that a sauna works is it kind of looks like any type of web Administration panel that you've
ever kind of logged into.
Looks kind of like Wordpress when you log into it.
It's essentially a system of task lists.
You can see right here this is literally the first page you'll see once you create an account it all
uses lists to put everything together.
That's a little bit different than base camp and it's a little bit different than the other popular
project management tools and it's one of the reasons why we like a sauna so much because it allows you
to list anything you're doing quite literally anything in a linear fashion.
And make sure that you can itemize out every single thing and then move through them.
So if you're not familiar with a sauna literally you just go to a sauna.
Dot com.
Go and create an account.
It's quite literally only two screens and this is the first screen you will see.
Ours is a little bit different because it has some projects in it and it has some data that I've already
inserted before have multiple counts.
But you also look essentially like this.
So the way that this works is right here on the left hand side we have all the different sections of
the song.
So my tasks are all the tasks that are assigned to you.
Things that you are involved in your Diasporan is the area where you can get project based summaries
and then these other sections right here just show all of the items that exist within their project
management tool.
Now the simplest way of using a sauna is to simply just create a project and you create a project is
down here so you go down to projects that plus and we can call this whatever you want.
Read then you can choose privacy.
So the way that this works is I can say it's open to sprint kicks so I said this anyone in our company
could see this so this would go to the master kind of a sauna and if I said this to private that wouldn't
mean that I have to invite every single person to the project to see it so I could have people who are
in this Assata looking at some of the other projects but not able to view this project.
So you would pick private if you use the sauna for multiple projects so say you had some project that
was completely unrelated to the other one and you're keeping track of it in Asuna.
A lot of times also people use this as a personal productivity tool.
They list out all the tasks they need to get done today or this week or this month and they use that
and so you obviously wouldn't want to share that with a contractor or someone you're outsourcing with.
So if that was the case you'd want to pick private.
Now if you have multiple projects where the people that you're working with they're going to bring into
this work across different projects which happens quite frequently especially when you find someone
that you really enjoy working with and they have multiple skill sets which most developers or designers
do in that case you can actually add them to multiple projects and if you set this to open they can
actually jump across and see what's available in the other ones just for the purposes of this.
I'm going to show you what it looks like when you can open project.
And here we can put a description descriptions are helpful for you to remember what exactly this project
is about or to give a snapshot because a lot of times you'll have lots and lots of projects so it's
very helpful.
Keep it simple.
All right so right here off about this is our project and it looks kind of like a legal pad almost as
you can see it's quite literally just a vertical view of what is essentially a task list.
Now the core of Ossana is you can literally just add a task.
So I wanted to add a task I would just click and I would add a task I could say you know create first
you know application you know depending on what you're using you could do this in any way you want.
That's how you are a task if you want to add another task you simply just hit enter and you can move
all the way down.
Now within each individual task there's a lot of different things you can do.
So right here you have the check box and that just means you market complete.
Now if I click this it's going to say that it's complete it's going to disappear.
You can see the completed task by going to view tasks to do and then you can go to a recently completed
tasks and I'll show up on today.
Now it can also you can also select yesterday.
You can also select one two and three weeks it'll show up in these three and this one but not yesterday.
Now the reason why this is helpful is because as you are running a project and you have multiple people
contributing to the project multiple people adding tasks removing task etc. it's really helpful to see
you know when you log in first thing in the day what happened yesterday what got finished what do I
need to check.
So what you typically will do is when you create a project you go off and list all of the main overview
points of what you need to get done.
This would be a theoretical project so we could say you know build first screen because they build a
screen and you know you could say second screen
so literally you can put whatever you think you need in your project.
This design project could be really anything.
I mean you're going to use this for brainstorming.
You can put ideas down now after you've created a task there's again several things you can do.
You can check it as done.
You can also assign this task to someone.
Now the way that you do this is you simply just click it and you can put in the email or the name of
the person you're signing into.
Now when you do that any person who has been assigned to Task has that show up in their mind task section
it also automatically keeps them in.
To get push notifications if they have this on an app it also gives them email notifications and gives
them tax notifications as do dates are coming or as they're assigned a task or as a task they're assigned
is finished.
So it's going to keep all of the relevant parties in each task notified.
Now the easiest way to add someone to your screen.
The easiest way to add one to a project is quite simply to go over here and say invite people here you
just put in the email address of whoever you are in a work with say its freelancer freelance dot com
and I would invite and that would send them an invitation for them to sign up and get into this project
page or they can now see everything.
So it's very very easy to on board someone.
And that's why I also suggest using Assata to manage your projects because it's very easy to get a contractor
or an outsourced freelancer into this.
Now convincing someone to use a project management tool might have some resistance up front you might
have some developers or designers be resistant to the idea.
And the reason why they might be resistant to using a project management tool like this is because for
one a lot of them have their own processes by which they create their own projects.
Now the reason is a lot of them don't want to feel like they're being monitored and feel like they have
to and feel as if the person they're working with can see their progress on a day to day basis.
And here's the thing.
You know there is some truth to that as a freelancer freelancers you get very comfortable in the way
that they work.
I personally always like using this with all of our contractors or outsource teams.
And the reason why is because it's a great way of testing to see whether or not they're good freelancer
or contractor if they really don't want to use an online project management tool that it's a chance
that this is probably not a good person to work with.
You really want to work with people who are adaptable and people who are open to change.
You want to work with people who value things like transparency and value things like being able to
communicate effectively.
Now if they insist on using say like an E L'anse page or using e-mail to monitor your project progress
they're basically saying I prefer to keep you in the dark and they think that the hassle of updating
you more often.
And it's very easy to use an intuitive way is more valuable than actually being able to tell what's
going on in the project and for you to know whether or not your money is being spent correctly.
So I like it because you can quite literally just add an email and invite them all that means is that
you need to have their email address so if you've hired someone off up work you hired someone off of
really anywhere.
All you need is their email.
You can add them and they're in.
And now all of a sudden we can start adding tasks assigning it to that person and then we can start
working and see now that I've added someone right here it's going to wait till they confirm and once
they confirm and sign up then all of a sudden they'll have more functionality.
Usually the color of their icon changes but I can still assign them tasks so I could say this one is
now assigned to you and you can see now that this freelancer freelancer is assigned to this task.
OK so now on the right side of the pain this is where we get the drill down on each individual task
on the individual task what we can do is we can change the project it's and we can add a description
of each individual task.
This is where you know we can take a high level description and then get into the details.
But most importantly now you have a thread where you can have a thread and describe what's happening
with this task What exactly do you mean.
Do your requirements change.
Do you have more information at the other person can also respond with where they are in the process.
They correspond with questions directly to this task and you can answer this an efficient way and as
long as you're added to this task you will get notified every time that happens.
Now imagine doing that e-mail if you told them I would install this widget in my Wordpress and you didn't
give them all of the information they would need.
Or maybe they go in there and something's different something in the Wordpress code is changing the
widget has changed its documentation.
The is different.
And also there are other things that are happening in the project or they just send you one big bulk
e-mail to send one big project update and Elance or up work or freelancer.
This is very inefficient.
It's very inefficient in terms of organization in terms of speed.
In this case as they're quite literally responding to something I can get the information from them
and I can respond specifically to that task.
That is one of the bigger problems with project management especially around web and mobile projects.
You don't always know exactly what a developer or designer is talking about.
And this allows you to literally drill down on whatever it is.
And typically when you build tasks they're going to be much much more specific than this.
But I'm going to show you how you can make this a little bit more sensical in just a second.