You guys come back to the course.
So in this lecture talk about this kind of an adage that has been going around and freelancer circles
forever and it's under-promise over deliver.
So for those of you who were never heard this before I'm going to give you a brief explanation of what
it means and why it's important.
Then after that I'm going to give you my take on it and give you a little bit more of a nuanced approach
to it as it applies to development businesses.
Now under promise and over deliver what it means is that it's always better when you're talking with
a client to promise less than what you're capable of.
And then when you actually deliver the project over deliver.
So as opposed to what ends up happening a lot of times is people promise the moon.
They say I can do this and this and this and this can do this on a time and then they fail to meet those
expectations.
The opposite of it is a more realistic approach to always keeping your clients happy and focusing on
customer retention.
So that's where that really just comes from.
We always want to be timid with how much you can propose or promise and then always just plan on either
meeting those expectations or blowing them out of the water.
Never plan to at best make your expectations and most likely miss the mark.
Now why though kind of in general is this good advice.
Well in general you want your project to be built on realistic expectations.
You want them to know how complicated it is how big it is how expensive it is because that's going to
keep them in tune in sync.
And that's going to give them the same priorities as you.
Now if a client thinks you're going to be delivering something that you aren't or thinks are going to
be delivering something that was never agreed on those are unrealistic expectations.
You want everybody on the same page because if that's the case then there's not a lot of miscommunication.
There's not a lot of puffery in the sense that you don't always have to try extra hard to impress that
person.
They know exactly what they're looking for and what they're going to get out of it.
It also makes it such that you don't feel inclined to lie or embellish if they know exactly how long
this is going to take and you are completely honest with them.
Then you don't have to feel like lying about oh where your development schedule is or how quickly it's
coming along or trying to hide the fact that you might have hit snags.
Now if you fail to live up to your expectations of your client and you do that habitually and you've
kind of built a practice around promising everything and then delivering always short of what you've
said well you're basically dooming yourself to a situation where you spend a lot of your time looking
for projects and not all of your time working with repeat clients.
That is a very an ideal way of running a development business development businesses should focus on
what they're good at making apps.
They should not have to focus on constantly looking for a new fresh load of clients that have no familiarity
with your company.
So in general under-promise over deliver is a very good kind of mindset to follow and kind of a rule
to follow with regards to your clients and your clients work.
But I think it's really important for you guys to understand that that does not cover all bases.
When you're starting your business under promise over deliver that will get you zero clients forever.
At the very beginning your portfolio is going to be very small.
It could be absolutely zero items.
Your Web site's not going to look as good as the final version of it.
You're not going to have as many contacts you're not going to have as many references.
So getting someone to sign on the dotted line on a contract that's really hard right and especially
hard if you're being really pessimistic about what you can do for them and you're under promising.
So I've seen a lot of people use that kind of adage before under-promise over deliver.
They go into a business and they try to do that at the very beginning and they just don't get traction.
That's why it's important to understand why it's different when you're starting your business now.
You need to understand that any development project there's three things that you have the opportunity
to exaggerate on or kind of under-invest.
Number one is cost.
Number two is time line and number three is expertise or ability.
So in any given project when we're thinking about whether or not we promise the moon it's really along
those three categories.
How much is this going to cost how long is it going to take us.
And can we do this specific thing.
So with regards to starting your business let's go through those three.
Number one do not ever exaggerate on your timeline.
That's something that is true.
The first day you start this business and the day that you ring in the 10 year of being in business
lying about your time line or during your time line never works out in development the timeline is just
not something you can really fiddle with.
I mean unless you somehow have the magic ability you have people work 100 hours a week and think that
your product quality is not going to go down.
That's the only time I can think of where this would happen.
You know realistic circumstances you can't dictate how many hours a week they work.
And if you could.
It's always detrimental.
So don't focus on timeline.
The timeline is what it is.
If they're telling you that's not right.
That's ridiculous.
They don't know what the timeline is.
You won't actually be having a problem because another one is trying to overpromise their timeline.
Now the second thing was cost and cost is absolutely the thing you should manipulate to get more sales.
At the very beginning of your business you shouldn't be focused on how much money you're making per
project you should be concerned about your portfolio items and bringing in good long term clients that
you can show off to other people.
So cost is kind of your edge at the very beginning it's something that you should be able to kind of
flip.
Whichever way you need if you have a project and they're looking at multiple vendors and this is very
early on you and you can tell that they are trying to decide between them.
It's very much a good idea to try and see whether or not you can manipulate your price downward to get
to the point where they accept you as their vendor because at the very beginning you just need clients
you just need something to show off someone that can give you repeat business.
Get the ship afloat later on down the line.
That doesn't really make sense.
You shouldn't be competitive necessarily on price unless for some reason this is a fantastic project
that's great for many other reasons.
So remember that at beginning just get some clients.
So don't worry about cost.
Absolutely mess with your costs.
You can always over promise on cost.
Just make sure that you're not over promising so much that you're losing a ton of money.
You can go into the red and you can plan to lose money on some of your projects.
That's up to you and that's up to whether or not you're OK with that risk.
That's a great way of getting clients but it's not for everybody.
Now the third thing is ability now ability just kind of refers to whether or not someone says hey I
want to have this feature and maybe you're not totally sure whether or not you can do it or if they
say you know I need something built in this technology and you're not totally sure that you can do it.
A lot of times someone will ask and it is built on this platform.
You don't need to build it for iPad but you also need to build it for you know some Android Nexus tablet
and you only do one or the other and that honestly does happen quite a bit.
And it's one of those things that you might consider that over promising by saying hey I can do this
one and the other one because remember you're not going to get that project unless you could do both
of them.
So in general that's considered over promising to the way that I typically suggest people handle it
is that you just you just kind of hedge your bets at the very beginning clients are really really really
important.
At least the first couple ones that you get so you might be more inclined to give them some kind of
flexibility or at least to make some kind of a promise of adding some new technology that you might
not have right this moment.
But the way that you do this correctly and the way that you do that is in a nuanced intelligent way
is you don't ever say I absolutely can do this.
Just say you know I can build it for this platform and I'm very confident I can build it for this platform
and then you just basically say but if for some reason I can't this is realistically what's going to
happen.
So in that second kind of contingency what you can do is you can try to soften the blow and say well
if that's the case that happens I can lower the price for you or you can just say if that's the case
that happens well it's only something that's going to take me another month to figure out.
A lot of times you'd be surprised people don't even care about that.
They can be really happy about your price being lowered but they also don't even really care it's going
to take an extra month.
They're more or less just concerned that one vendor deals with more of their project and they're not
going to have to work with multiple vendors for different technologies.
So don't ever say 100 percent absolutely I'm doing it.
It's done expect.
Don't say I'm confident I can do it.
But realistically that might mean it takes a longer.
And if for some reason I can't do it well then we'll lower the price of your project.
That's something that works really really effectively.
OK guys so in general we know when in doubt go with under-promise over deliver.
But in the very beginning of your business be realistic.
I mean only one of those three things that you can manipulate is not is unmoveable is something that
is just insane to move and that's timeline.
You could always manipulate your cost.
Feel free to do that.
In fact actually that's one of your strongest tools to get clients at the beginning and the other one
is just you know ability try to be realistic about it.
Never promised 100 percent but be confident and tell them you're confident that you can add additional
services even if you're not sure you can.
That's how you close clients at the beginning and that's how you get this ball rolling.
You guys have any questions.
Otherwise in the next lecture.