Let's talk about where you should go to find freelancers and freelancing firms.
For me there are the big three Elance oDesk and freelancer dot com.
I'm sure you've used other Web sites people per hour.
Seems to be a decent one.
There are lots of freelancing sites that target certain niches.
You'll notice things like like video pixies or freelancers for videos specifically Ines of course we're
talking more about building mobile applications or web applications so we're going to focus on software
freelancers the Big Three Elance oDesk and freelancer these are the ones I've used throughout my career
and this is the ones I've used for over 50 60 apps.
Each one of these has their own pros and cons.
Elance is probably by far my favorite for finding high quality contractors when you bid on elance you
can get bids from pretty much all over the world.
When you typically post something I see a good mix between Western countries and typical outsource countries
and then people all in between you'll find a lot of freelancers who are simply location independent
like traveling programmers very very vibrant community of people.
Elance is where you would go if you were looking for a better established firms or essentially higher
quality freelancers freelancers that are in the mature stage of their freelancing career.
A lot of programmers who have full time jobs that work at reputable companies will go on elance and
bid on projects for their weekends and off hours.
The firms on elance typically have better portfolios they're usually better at articulating what they're
good at.
They are typically going to give you better more thoughtful responses to your project briefs.
Now like the other three it doesn't cost any money to post the differences here.
You'll notice that most people that bid have read your project and will actually respond with detail
and with thoughts on it that obviously comes with the downside.
You'll notice that in Elance the prices are usually a bit higher if you were to take the same application
with the same brief and post them across these three systems Elance you'll notice on average is going
to have the highest price and also the time line probably is going to be longer.
And obviously the reason is because the people who are bidding have more experience and they also probably
have more clientele themselves so they're not going to lie and say that they're going to rush the project
and they're also not going to be taking kind of a loss leader position meaning that they're not going
pricing so low that they're actually losing money just to get your business.
The second one is oDesk oDesk in Elance I believe are a merged company but these two different products
oDesk is a little bit different it's not like Elance in the sense that everybody who bids is going to
be a high quality oDesk differentiate themselves by what they use called the team view and they have
the thing called a team room how the team room works.
It's a web application with an ode ask that when you hire someone they get added to your team room and
then they use this screen capture software on the freelancer's Web site so that you can maintain how
much they've been working and what their productivity looks like and you can kind of notice if they're
not working.
And if they try to bill you you can look back at their time logs.
Also you can use that way to combine other freelancers into the same room so that they can communicate
to each other and coordinate.
It's good if you're trying to put together a team from multiple freelancers or multiple development
teams which is sometimes that is the case sometimes you need someone to do data entry.
You need one person to program and you need one person to do graphic design.
And that makes it quite convenient however because that is the focal point of their product and what
they're selling point.
It means that people typically go to oDesk if they're looking for per hour labor and it means that they're
skewed more towards things like virtual assistants.
Most of the projects you see on oDesk will skew towards.
I need someone to do this manual task and do it in perpetuity and do it for a set amount of time people
do obviously post web projects and mobile projects on there.
It's just better if you're looking for an individual who can just work towards your project and essentially
it until it's done and it's not a great place you're trying to find a fixed price because of them.
The team room benefit.
It doesn't really help you in any way.
ODesk is in terms of quality engineering it's a little bit below Elance but it's above freelancer.
Freelancer dot com is the last one.
Prancer used to be a big deal back in 2001 2002 came out of the Internet bubble but it stuck around.
It is probably the least polished of the three.
You go and you use it.
It is kind of confusing the way that they use a credit system you will for instance when you pay freelancers
you will upload money into your account and then you can pay them and freelancer automatically will
deduct certain amounts of money out of your account.
So it always keeps a certain baseline amount of money in your account and that can be kind of annoying
if you're trying to do small tasks but freelancer.
It's kind of the Wild West of the freelancing Web sites.
I use it all the time but that's because I'm skilled at managing outsourced teams and knowing what I
want and I can tell very easily if a freelancer is being unrealistic.
Freelancers the place you go if you want pretty much a heavy skew in terms of your bidding group from
outsourced countries.
When you post an freelancer you may get some people from western countries but the mule predominantly
get people from you know Eastern Europe India Indonesia Vietnam places like that.
Now freelancer's great if you're trying to get something done extremely cheaply.
The people who bid on their bid very very low.
And if you have the experience and you have the time to oversee what they're doing then you can have
some pretty huge cost savings.
But I always say kind of stay away unless you have experience doing this because you can get burned
very easily.
Often what happens on freelancer you will see that if you post say you want to make a web site and say
your web site is something similar to another Web site you very often will find people who will create
clones of Web sites for you.
Watch out for people who are going to build your web site using a script.
You don't know what the intellectual property rules are around that script are you don't know where
they got the script.
Who owns the licensing.
But that happens quite often in freelancer and that's another reason why your rates are so cheap.
I notice that a lot of freelancers start off on that Web site because it is kind of the Wild West.
They can get some shady air projects to get reviews.
You also notice on freelance at dot.com they started listing the completion rate for each project for
each freelancer because that's a big concern on freelancer.
A lot of times people will bid and they'll were way too low.
Get into the project and then abandon it.
So I would say that freelancer is something you want to dive into if you have some experience.
It's where you get the best cost savings and it's a place you'd go if you are some really kind of sketchy
deed or task you need to get done.