Hey guys welcome back to the course in this lecture.
We're going to talk about red flags for bad clients.
How can you tell beforehand whether or not a client is going to be a nightmare down the road and whether
or not this is something you should steer completely clear of.
Now your quality of life as a project manager as a developer as the business owner is really going to
depend on the clients that you end up working with.
Some clients are fantastic.
They just get it you will learn a lot from them they're easy to work with they always have the right
budget.
They always respond on time.
They're very forgiving when anything happens and they understand that some things are outside of your
control.
Those people are great.
They make this so much sweeter because you're getting paid to work with people that are great now on
the flip side you will run into some difficult clients clients that are a nightmare.
Clients that have a lot of expectation issues clients that have a lot of authority issues you run into
ones that are mature ones that are completely unprofessional.
You'll run into ones that have trust issues and ones that just take forever to get anything done.
So to help you recognize some of the telltale signs of a bad client Let's go over some common scenarios
are some common things you might look for or start to notice.
So number one this is like I see all the time do they disagree with your estimates.
Now there's something that's very very strange in the development business.
You know if you're buying a shirt or buying something on the street someone might have the potential
to disagree with the price of something maybe they saw it the same price somewhere else.
But in development this is not a commodity.
We're not selling you a glass of orange juice or selling you something that's very very complicated
and very very technical something that's very very complicated and something that's almost always very
much customized to your individual case.
It's also the case that in development projects unless you're the one doing the estimate there's no
way you could possibly know exactly what it's going to take to build something.
So if our client is disagreeing with your estimate saying it's wrong saying one section is too large
that is a generally a big red flag and this is why I put this is number one.
A lot of times you'll have this happen you'll have a client who's not even technical trying to say oh
that didn't take as much time.
We have this problem a lot with graphic design and UI design because UI design sometimes it just takes
a lot of time up front until you get a general design theme or a lay out and then they use that to build
the other pages faster.
But that first batch will work.
We always get people saying no way that took X amount of hours.
The fact that your client even thought that they could make a judgment on how long that took and they
could go so far as to say that it's wrong.
Huge red flag.
Steer clear.
Number two does their project idea make no sense.
Now here's one thing I want to say is that when you're in the development business and I say this frequently
you're not in the business of picking winners.
If that were the case you'd be in venture capital.
You'd be an angel investor who'd be somebody who hops from startup to startup you're not in a position
to make a decision about whether or not their market opportunity is good enough whether or not their
execution capacity is good or the team is a fantastic setup.
That's not what you're doing.
You're here to build whatever it is they want.
And do the best job possible.
But since you are getting a lot of time thinking about it estimating it you should have a decent idea
of whether or not this idea is terrible or if it's OK if it is the case that they're giving you something
that just doesn't make any sense whatsoever.
You couldn't possibly imagine why anyone would use it or it's something that's completely derivative
of something else.
Usually that's a red flag.
Now it doesn't matter if they're copying something else that happens all the time but if they're trying
to make something that just flat out makes no sense they're talking about users using it in a way that
can't work or any general kind of disconnect in that sense.
This might be a project or client you might want to steer clear.
The reason why is because a best case scenario this is a one off project.
They build something it goes out there it completely fails because a person is unrealistic or an insightful.
What they're doing.
The worst case scenario is that this bad project idea is indicative of a bigger problem it's probably
a bigger problem has to do with the client themselves.
They probably just have a whole lot of bad ideas and you're going to have to deal with a lot of bad
ideas later down the road.
There's no reason to think that they might have some bright ideas to fire you in the middle of the project
or to bring up issues that don't even exist.
Number three are they trying to haggle with your rates.
Now there's a big difference between haggling and just saying I can't afford something.
No make that a distinction.
If they're coming up to you and they're saying you know I need twenty five dollars an hour or $50 an
hour to do this and they're saying well I'll pay you 15 or trying to do a lowball pitch.
They're haggling with you.
If someone comes up to you and says oh I only pay for 22 an hour and I really want to work with you
that's the case and they just don't have the budget.
Those are two entirely different things.
You have someone coming up and saying no that's not worth it.
I'd rather pay you this.
And they're giving you a low ball.
That's haggling.
That's a big red flag.
If that has ever happened to you remind them that they're paying for wages they're not paying for an
object they're not paying for something that you can mark down at will if they pay you last that means
you pay your people less which means they wouldn't want to work on the job so why would you take it.
In general I'm not very accepting of haggling at all.
It's awful.
Some people out there do and I personally think that diminishes their brand considerably.
So if a person comes up to you and they're haggling over the price of your project take that as a red
flag it generally means that they're unrealistic about the project.
They've never done this before.
They're not being particularly professional and their priorities are probably out of whack.
They probably only care about the price nothing else.
Why would you ever haggle with a long term partner someone who is going to take charge of a very important
project that has a large impact on your life.
It makes no sense to underpay that person.
It's also indicative of someone who doesn't have a budget.
A lot of times people don't have a budget or just trying to see how low they can get the price.
So if they're honestly worried about the hourly rate they shouldn't be talking to you.
Generally that means you're just about to waste a lot of time with someone who doesn't have money for
the project.
Number four are they giving you multiple proposals at once.
Are they asking you to give you an estimate for this application and this application and a whole about
two other applications.
If that's the case then you might have a scatterbrained client who's probably not committed to whatever
project they pick to make a project successful you need to spend a lot of time and effort thinking about
the project developing it and making the concept as bullet proof as possible.
If you're all over the board with multiple proposals it means that they're just scribbling things down
on a napkin.
And even if they decide to go with one of them who knows how.
Honestly how committed they are because they certainly are not focused.
That just spells red flag for me.
That can be an issue down the road if they get distracted on something else so they decide to divert
the resources over here.
You want to work with someone who's at least serious about what they're doing.
Number five do they argue over trivial items.
I've had clients argue with me over for sizing.
I've had them argue over taxed in their contract that doesn't actually mean anything there are conditional
clauses in their contract.
I've had people argue over what we call projects internally and how we spell them.
These are all trivial things and basically what that means is you have someone that isn't able to prioritize
isn't able to figure out what's important and they're more concerned with getting their way or proving
themselves in some way.
Typically that's just a sign that you're working with a client who's insecure and immature probably
don't have a large track record of success.
People are successful in development projects are not the type of people who nitpick things that just
simply don't matter.
Also to be completely honest that person is going to drive you crazy so do you really want to work with
them.
Number six are they being unprofessional.
Now this one's pretty plain and obvious you should know exactly what I mean.
Are they this certain person that has a tendency to throw tantrums.
The person who has a tendency to say things they shouldn't or do they often lie about things blatantly.
There's a lot of different things that wouldn't be very unprofessional do they constantly miss phone
calls that you've scheduled very basic things.
That's another pretty big red flag.
It means that they can't possibly have been successful in anything else they've done.
Who knows how they got the money for their project whatever they're going to put their name on and put
their effort towards probably is going to be dead in the water.
You shouldn't subject yourself to that.
It's just not worth it.
OK so those are the biggest red flags I've seen with clients.
There are some other ones obviously that you could easily think of.
These are the ones that I think kind of fly under the radar and are more important least in my experience
and experience with the other development businesses that I work with.
Do you guys have any questions or anything you want to comment on.
Any ideas for other red flags you've run into or you want me to say whether or not something is a red
flag post in the group discussion.
Otherwise I'll see in the next lecture.