You guys will welcome back to the course so we're kind of a quick collector on something that a lot
of people who run the development business make a mistake with and that is don't ever quote off the
top of your head.
Now this is something that you might not imagine right now but once you start getting into it happens
all the time.
Such and Such we'll say I want to build this and that and they will ask you on the spot how many hours
do you think this will be.
A lot of times you'll say oh I don't know and they'll still press you what range of hours do you think
it's going to be.
This is something that you should almost never ever do even if you're really experienced with giving
estimates.
Just don't do it.
The upside potential is actually quite small.
And the downside is quite large.
Now the biggest reason why this is a problem is because if you try to give an estimate and then later
on try to give a full estimate back to the person chances are you probably miss something or the client
forgot to mention something which happens all the time.
And then the Eserine you give them is going to be different.
That's a bad scenario.
90 percent of the time if you give them a second estimate that's not even within their original range
you gave them you're going to lose that contract.
Why.
Well it just honestly it just makes sense.
Even if you believe that person really tried their hardest to give you an estimate.
You came back to them and they gave you a different one.
What would you think the price was higher than you would assume that they're trying to rip you off.
If it's lower you just assume that they're an idiot and they don't know what they're talking about.
They're just throwing numbers out at random.
You don't want to lose authority and you don't want to lose your position as an expert.
So just don't do it.
Now one thing to keep in mind is that it might frustrate the person you're talking to but be realistic.
No other development firm is going to do that.
So it's not as if you're the only person sticking them.
If they're talking to five different companies none of them are going to do that.
And if one of them does that one is taking on some serious risk.
So it's not as if you're withholding information they could get from other people.
You're not putting yourself at a disadvantage you're pretty much doing the industry standard.
The best way of tackling these situations is to always say you're not sure but I can give you an estimate
in a short amount of time.
Then you need to rely on the framework you've established to give a ballpark estimate.
We covered that in a separate lecture.
That one is so incredibly crucial to landing clients focused on getting that framework done so that
you can create ballpark estimates worst case scenario.
You can just give them a full estimate and a full proposal.
So best case scenario is you might make them slightly happier with you.
And worst case scenario is you block them off from ever being your client and you come off looking like
you don't know what you're talking about.
Now it might be possible that you run into a scenario where you absolutely just have to answer the question
some reason or another.
If that ever happens to you do this don't give them a range with two ends.
Give them a one end of the range that is usually enough to satisfy them.
So as opposed to saying hey your project is going to take a thousand to 600 hours to build say it's
going to take over a thousand or under 2000 or under 6400.
Basically what you're doing is you're kind of hedging your likelihood of getting the estimate correct.
And if it ends up being that you miss it just shyly then you might adjust the price to still capture
the client.
That's enough information to at least give them idea of hey this is big or hey this is small which is
really all they want if they're being really really pushy about it.
OK.
So regardless of how well you think you know this project there's still information you're missing and
it's just a gamble that's not worth it.
The upside isn't very good and the downside is quite bad.
So don't do it.
Don't call off the top of your head.
This is something I get stuck with all the time.
I still make this mistake so try to avoid it as much as possible.
Worst case scenario gun to your head.
Give them one open ended range and don't give them the other number.
That should at least increase the odds that you don't shoot yourself in the foot.
All right guys.
Questions posed in the group discussion otherwise seen the next lecture.