Hey guys welcome back to the course.
So in this lecture we're going to talk about meeting your client in person.
What should you plan for.
How should you tackle this.
Now if you are using a substantial amount of contractors in your development business you know that
you couldn't run your entire business without ever actually meeting your clients.
And in my experience the vast majority of them never actually come into our office or meet any of us.
Why.
Well really it's just because today people are more used to working with people through Skype or email
or using like a sauna.
It's also the case that you might be working with a company on the east coast or on the West Coast.
It's unrealistic that you're going to come visit them unless it's a multimillion dollar project and
for some reason they really wanted that.
Even if I'm in San Francisco and a company is in San Jose it's pretty unrealistic to think I'm going
to take an hour and a half to go take the train down there to meet with them for whatever reason.
But in general there are two reasons why you might meet with a client in person.
One is that you need to meet them to close a potential sale.
Client wants to meet you because they want to see what you're like.
They want to see how quick on your feet you are and they want to see you explain in person what you
did with your projects in the past and explain your portfolio or explain your approach to their project.
Now the other thing that could happen is you're working with a larger company and they just have a culture
around the meetings and meeting in person.
And so for them it's actually a considerable hassle to change everything to work only exclusively with
you through Skype or through email.
So occasionally they expect you to come in to help them deploy or explain something it's going wrong
or to do basic check ins.
Now in general if you have the opportunity to meet your client in person I do suggest doing it at least
once.
It really does help establish a bond between you and them.
They know you on a personal level and it's not just an email address that will really help you retain
clients and have them feel more confident in you.
They feel more confident in you.
They give you a lot more leeway for everything you're going to do now.
Like really anything your success with the meeting in person is really going to come down to your preparedness
your composure and your confidence that you're prepared.
That's really going to come down to how well you can anticipate what they want and what the context
of the meeting is.
Your composure has more to do with your personality in general and your experience having meetings like
this and then confidence really just comes down to whether or not you feel confident you can answer
their questions.
How technical you are or how proud of your portfolio you feel like.
No I honestly can't help you improve your composure improve your confidence.
That's just something that's going to come with experience and that's going to something that comes
with you trying out different things and being willing to fail.
That's one of the things that I think really will help you de-stress before meetings.
Just understanding that you know not every single client means the world to you.
And then it's really really hard to screw up an in-person meeting.
So I wouldn't necessarily stress out about it.
It's very hard to screw up.
And if they do if you do end up doing that it's not the end of the world.
So now if you are meeting with someone for say it like a sales pitch the thing you need to focus on
is being able to present your past portfolio items.
Being able to explain what those apps do how long the project took you could even say how much it cost.
Being able to demo it in some way will help immensely as well.
So whether or not that's you coming with a bunch of predefined links that you can just talk through.
Or if it's a PowerPoint that helps you talk through different things it's really up to you and it's
really up to your style.
I personally kind of just wing it.
I usually will bring all my portfolio items in because their portfolio items and I spend a lot of time
on I can just talk about them for days and I can show them everything and I can tell them funny anecdotes
about the project or tell them why the project successful or why it's interesting or yada yada yada
it should come naturally to you if you are actually part of the project.
But if your type of person needs something more scripted try to put some things down on a PowerPoint
slide just to help you walk through it.
Now the odds of you using that presentation that might actually be small but just knowing that you have
that prepared will help you immensely.
The other part of an in-person meeting for like a sales meeting is that they want to know on a personal
one to one level you understand what their project needs are.
So you need to focus more on being empathetic to what their user problems are connecting with them on
what problem they're trying to solve and help them understand that you get what they're trying to do.
In general this is not a time for you to dictate and tell them what they should do with their application.
You should absorb their vision their idea their project requirements and insert your insight and your
wisdom when you can.
It's OK to be quiet during these meetings because you are listening to them.
Don't try to set the tone by being away too pushy or authoritarian.
They're not here for a strategy consultant necessarily but they are looking for someone who is an expert
in making awesome products.
So they want someone who can at their appropriate times insert some information tell them that oh that's
not going to work or tell them hey this is an interesting idea you could try out.
Now if you're trying to meet with someone in person or company in person simply because it's a check
in.
You need to evaluate a couple things.
One is it worth the client contract if you have to meet them say twice a week.
That's a big contract as it promises that there's gonna be a lot of work in the future that maybe it's
something you should do.
Also if it's a company that just naturally does that they just naturally operate in meetings then you're
going to have to adapt to them and it's not them making you jump through hoops because they don't value
you.
But in general if it's a smaller contract you're not needed the portfolio item.
Maybe reconsider.
Try to factor that into your margins and try to calculate what's the loss in terms of your time and
how much time you could have spent on other things as opposed to traveling and then meeting in person
of these people.
Keep in mind a lot of these meetings are incredibly redundant just in general.
There's rarely a reason that you have to meet in person with someone.
There's nothing you can't fix through a phone call or an email or through project management tools.
But if you do have to end up meeting with them try to minimize how often you have to meet with them
try to make it as communion as possible.
Most importantly try to be positive about it.
So and in general regardless of what type of meeting it is always be prepared to talk about yourself.
But if it's never brought up don't focus on your client and your client's needs and only if they ask
you then be ready to brag about yourself and talk about all the great things you've done before and
what your team is capable of.
Now some of could also help you is that if you're not technical you're not a programmer.
Try to explain to people how your process works so that when you don't have say estimates on hand or
ability to answer deep technical issue questions they actually understand why that is.
Try to explain to them hey this is how we typically work idea what this portion this is.
This is why I think this is not working but if you give me this amount of time I can get back to you
very easily.
It might be a little frustrating but if you explain why it is they can't really be frustrated at you
know the last thing they think that's worth covering for in-person meetings is something goofy that
everyone always asks What do you wear.
Well the best advice I can give you is to be like a mirror.
Try to mirror whatever the group is you're going to do and how they dress.
If you go into a fancy bank and financial district try to dress in a suit.
If you go to that meeting and you're underdressed it might not work.
The reason don't you want a mirror what other people do is that people just naturally again notice patterns.
But also they have a tendency to trust people that look like them.
So a banker who wears a pinstripe suit is probably going to trust a web developer or also dresses in
a suit with pinstripes.
If you walked into that meeting wearing flip flops in a hoodie.
Mark Zuckerberg style you might stick out so much that they're going to spend more time thinking about
why you don't fit in and less time thinking about whether or not your proposal is any good.
Now the opposite end of the spectrum is what if you go to like one of those startups those San Francisco
startups and where everyone is dressed in practically pajamas.
Now if that's the case what I always say is there's always going to be a bare minimum of professionalism
you should ever drop to and with regards to your dress code if you're going to one of these places it's
always worth dressing up a little bit more than them try to go with something more casual but you're
never going to get blamed for wearing something slightly nicer.
No one's going to kill you for wearing a button up with jeans.
And in fact you'll find that it probably doesn't even stick out at all.
But don't ever get so low that you look unprofessional.
A lot of companies are ultra casual because when they're working in the in their work environment they're
not trying to impress anyone.
You on the other hand pretty much are.
And honestly the rule here pretty much is if as long as you're confident you can probably pull it off.
Try to match what they wear and if you don't know what they wear try to pick something and a happy medium
that's professional but slightly relaxed.
No one's ever going to fault you for that.
And you know going forward now you know OK guys if you have any other questions you want me to look
over your wardrobe and tell you if you look ridiculous posts in the group discussion.
Otherwise I'll see the next lecture.