Hey guys welcome back to the course so in this lecture we're going to talk about planning for the grind.
Now what do I mean by the grind.
The grind is that when you first start out your business there's going to be this period of time where
you are not bringing in any business or not a lot of business and are going to be trying a lot of different
things that simply do not work.
Unfortunately every business you ever start is going to have this problem.
If you aren't coming from this with an already successful development business and you're looking to
expand this you're probably going be starting from scratch.
And if you're starting from scratch you're going to have to figure out what works and what does not
work.
Now that applies to what you build.
And it also applies to what clientele you're good with and what are good ways of finding new clients.
So the very beginning you're really going to be working out a lot of different kinks and you're failing
more often than you succeed.
Now that sounds scary but anybody who has built a business before knows that this is just it's kind
of the way that it works.
Every business has trouble at first then you'll find things that work and then you take those things
that work and you do them a lot more you scale them up and that's how you grow.
Now in this course we cover all of the strategies that we use to grow in all of the tips and tricks
that we use to keep customers happy and to keep them coming back also had a very intense focus on your
fundamentals focus on the fundamental metrics that make you a good business and make you appealing to
new clients as well as clients that are thinking about bringing back work to you.
But everything we teach you in this course it's not guaranteed to work if I teach you 10 strategies
for you specifically maybe six out of the 10 work the strategies are going to teach you applied for
us.
And for every you know five strategy I give you that worked for us.
We tried probably 10 other things that did not.
So it really depends on your Nishi depends what you're trying to build and it depends really who you're
trying to go after.
So keep in mind it's just finding that right combination.
Finding out the best way of finding clients and then finding out the best way of finding the best clients
and then just figuring out how you can do that repeatedly until you have a very solid stream of business
coming in.
The biggest set of advice that I can give to you to get through this period is well obviously one prepare
for it know that it's coming.
No that this period is going to happen so that when you start this business you don't just get into
it and think what's happening nothing's working.
You should know that this period is going to happen.
And the second thing I can give you advice on is do things that do not scale.
Now what do I mean by that.
This is actually a word of advice for startups from a very popular kind of luminary in Silicon Valley
named Paul Graham.
He suggests that for early start ups but it also applies to early development businesses as well.
So for you those of you who don't know what scale means scale just means grow and the reason why it
says scale is because what it's suggesting is that you scale exponentially so give you an example maybe
run an advertisement and I spend $100 and that hundred dollars gets me 200 dollars.
Well if I then decided to spend a thousand dollars I'm scaling.
Notice how it went from $100 to a thousand dollars.
That applies to any business activity that applies any technique you use to find clients any production
technique you used to produce.
It's just that when you grow you are scaling so any time you take an effort and try to do more of it.
That's called scaling.
So now what do I mean by things that do not scale.
That means that let's say in that case where I said $100 for this advertisement if you're using a Facebook
ad that does scale because all I have to do is type in 1000 as opposed to 100.
There is no incremental amount of work that I take on because I've now advertised more.
Now let's imagine that my advertisement time is actually a physical sign that I had to make because
I'm only one person and I want to build a sign.
Now if I want to build two signs I have to put in twice the amount of effort they want to do 10 signs
I have to put in ten times as much effort.
And the reason why it doesn't scale is not only are there no time savings as you do more of it.
It also means that I'm only one person so I couldn't realistically say I'm going to build 10000 signs
that just simply does not scale.
It's not something that I can do repeatedly for ever even eventually you get to a point where you don't
even know where you can put that many signs.
So now that you know it's scaling means.
Now I can explain a little bit better what do things that don't scale means basically means when you
start trying to think of a couple strategies you want to use to find clients or find subcontractors
or improve the quality of your applications.
Think of a couple maybe two three four or five something like that.
Now when you do them try to do each individual one of them as cheaply as possible and you do it manually.
Now you're doing it manually allows you to monitor costs but also not spend any money in the case that
it doesn't work out.
So to give you an example let's say we go back to before we're saying let's create a Facebook.
Let's say one of our strategies was that we're going to run Facebook ads to look for a certain type
of client if we run a Facebook Ad.
Now you have two options.
You design the campaign you run it you monitor it or you hire someone to do that for you.
Now the best way of getting through the grind would be to not hire someone to do that for you.
That's going to spend an unnecessary amount of money and energy and the likelihood that that campaign
is going to work out is always pretty small.
Again it's going to take many tries before you find something that works.
And if you hired someone you didn't up having to fire that person and you just wasted a lot of money
and time.
But if you did it yourself you can do all of the initial work to figure out whether or not it works
and if it doesn't work out it's not a huge loss because you're the founder.
Your time is not nearly as expensive.
I'll give you an example here.
Sprint kick one of our strategies for finding new clients was to use a popular portfolio Web site online
and to use a growth hacking technique.
So there's a popular portfolio site online.
We'll talk about later in depth right now.
You're actually going to tell you the name of it was what they did is they created this free service
for graphic designers to display their portfolios.
Well one of our strategies was to go after graphic designers and offer our services to them because
they themselves have clients and they can make a lot of money by adding development services to their
product offerings.
OK so what we didn't end up doing was looking at the pages that were being offered and we found out
that every single page had the same snippet of code over and over and over again and each individual
page.
So at that point in time we had two options.
One option that didn't scale and one option that did scale the option that did not scale was me myself
looking through manually through Google using search terms and hard requirements in my search to find
a large group of people that threw that way and then to contact them.
Now the scale option would have been to build out a program that could run through Google rapidly collect
all the information and contact them.
Option one would have taken me two hours.
Option 2 would have cost us several thousands of dollars and probably you know 20 30 40 hours of time
management and development tweaking.
So now if I pick the second option I would have wasted a lot of money because that technique could have
ended up being a very poor choice but because I chose to just take a couple hours to test it out to
see if this actually works.
Period.
Even at a small rate I was able to figure out yes or no whether or not it's worth it.
Then you can focus on scaling five scaled first could have potentially wasted a ton of money.
So when you're doing activities that don't scale you're probably going to be thinking to yourself Man
if this blew up and all of a sudden I had thousands of these I'd be swamped.
I couldn't do this.
And that's completely rational because right now and during the grind we're going to focus on doing
things like that.
There's a concept in startups called a concierge service and essentially what that means is a lot of
applications when they first start off they're trying to validate whether or not they're ideas popular
and what people pay for it.
So a lot of times it ends up happening is they'll simulate what an application does but in reality the
founders are doing the work on the back end themselves manually.
That does not scale but it saves them an enormous amount of time effort and money upfront just to figure
out whether or not their technique is good and their product is going to be popular.
So keep that in mind up front to get through the grind.
Try not to burn a lot of money and time and try not to scale your efforts till you have something you
absolutely know is going to work.
The other thing is just have patience.
You're going to have to try multiple techniques before something works really well for you.
With us it probably was six seven different things were for one kind of worked and we used that to get
our first batch of clients and then we kept testing new ones until we got a couple more traction channels
that we used to then get more and more clients.
OK.
So plan for the grind.
It always happens when you start a new business but especially with a client base business like this
it's very much like a snowball process you start off small and you slowly grow and eventually get to
a point where you have so much momentum that everything gets a lot better.
But at first it appears as if it's unnecessarily difficult.
So be aware of that.
And second of all try to minimize your cost and your time investments by doing things that do not scale.
Don't burn out very quickly just because you found something you think works.
Make sure you know that it works before you do that.
Another example of doing this would be like if someone gave you some business and I asked if you can
do an additional work task for them.
That task might be something that's not in your product or it might be a technology you don't coverage
or maybe a platform you don't like to use at the beginning.
You might want to say yes because again that does not scale.
You're saying yes just to take on new business taking on new business will get your portfolio.
It'll get you a better client relationship and it will help you understand whether or not this is something
you want to offer in the future.
So at the beginning you say yes later on you say no.
That's a very important distinction.
Be aware that this is typically the way that development firms work.
OK if you guys have any other questions posed in the group discussion we're going to keep moving on
with the getting started section or we kind of go over a more theory more planning more.
Getting your head around how all this works and the world that you're going to be operating in next
section though we're going to start getting into actually creating a presence showing you how you can
create something that looks professional online or see the next lecture.