OK and you'll notice similar elements here we use more of a landing page design meaning that you hit
our PAGE ONE sentence and then we try to push towards a call of act called Action button which was our
kind of decision because this is something we've found works for us.
It doesn't necessarily work for everyone but if you're noticed like over here we use a very similar
thing.
So we're going to pitch you our value proposition very quickly it only took me two clicks to get over
to that
and this would be a value proposition type of thing where we talk more about again integrated we help
with other things we try to position ourselves more as a consulting firm because so many people we work
with come to us when the idea is just that an idea and we can't just make it based off what they tell
us.
That's not going to be a successful project.
We really need to help them in all different directions.
And so that's kind of what we're pitching over here.
OK so look at Octa and we can pretty much tease out their value proposition very quickly say like early
scroll down a couple inches and look OK leading global brands.
They're pitching you that other expensive people with lots of money like to pay them lots of money.
Emerging growth companies.
OK so they're probably focused more on startups.
That's a very euphemized version of saying startups are emerging growth companies.
If someone wrote that for our Web site or copywriter wrote that I'd probably slap them because that
is just jibberish to discover new opportunities.
Define intelligent user experiences as opposed to dumb user experiences and then they focus on things
like innovative digital services and Cedric's that are a lot of this is just jargon and gibberish but
basically what they're trying to say is hey we work with elite brands and startups those are two kind
of groups we care a lot about user experience I mean right off the page they mentioned user experience
is not something you see all the time.
Design innovative digital services that's quite literally nonsense.
But what they're saying is when they say digital and if you guys remember in our vocabulary section
or we talked about suffixes digital means agency digital means hey we don't just make Web sites we also
make movies or we also make video content and other things like that.
And then again now they pitch a little bit about you being successful with us.
That's a very common thing you see with larger groups.
They really do focus on client success and later lecture we talk about why.
But the difference between a rich client and a successful client is and basically the moral of the story
there is that successful clients will bring you a lot more money.
Rich clients are always usually one off.
And then right here this seems to be important enough for them to just say right off the bat.
Engagement experts.
OK so they're going to focus more on engagement meaning like they're focusing again on being user centric.
They focus more on people paying attention to your Web site so maybe they're caring more about Flash
and polish and things like that things that someone who's more of a technical web developer is going
to care less about and then right down here.
Honestly even though this might seem like they're not pitching you your value proposition.
They really are.
And they're saying not only do we make great Web sites we're also a company that is focusing on thought
leadership.
We do a lot of research on the side.
We build white papers and etc etc..
Ok so I think you guys get the point.
Typically you will find their value proposition very quickly.
So in the previous section where we helped you guys develop your value proposition make sure that all
of your main points are on here and don't try to clutter it up too much.
OK.
Moving on to the third thing you always will see and you should always include services.
Notice how it's a services right there and here we they call it products because I believe that they
they build their own products but they're trying to sound like a product company.
Over here we have services and services and these guys probably have it.
They are going to call it.
They might have it as a sub tab.
But the point here is that everybody always needs to outline what exactly they do.
It's something that as you'll notice over here these guys might have forgotten to do it.
Basically what you need to do is you need to make sure that whoever's at your page isn't going to spend
their entire time in their page and not sure what exactly you do because at the end of the day you are
a vendor.
So you need to know that whoever's coming to your Web site is looking for something specific.
So you need in some way show them Hey this is what we do as plain as day.
OK.
And so like on our Web site we've made this as simple as possible we call it design plus development.
So what you understand is we also include design in our development.
We use a lot of language to make people understand that we're development focused design after thought.
And the reason why we kind of do that is because typically the clients come to us are not ones that
are trying to create groundbreaking design.
They're more interested in making technologically advanced web sites and applications and that they
need good design but they're not trying to look like path or look like urban B or previous Air B and
B the old air being be the new Air B and B looks ridiculous.
So right here I just try to make it as simple as possible.
We just said wow look at all these things we work with we can quite literally work with anything that
we catch all over here.
Oh these are mobile platforms we work with and again we work with everything.
And you'll notice every hear a lot of people use the opportunity to pitch what they do specifically
as an opportunity to sell you a little bit more.
A lot of them see look they'll use it like a case study kind of thing.
But what you can essentially get out of here is what exactly they do and then in this case they treat
niter as you describe how they're more of an agency.
They do the entire you know study beforehand on your application.
They give you marketing advice they give you Development advice they are pretty much the whole package
and similar to here.
They're going to do that as well.
And so here they're a little bit more literal they'll say you know we can design and develop new products
we can improve existing products and we can discover new opportunities.
That's what they do and then they focus.
You know this is their focus.
And these are the things that they've done before and they're good at it.
So remember you're always a vendor there are always going to list their services on here.
That's helpful right.
So if you don't do mobile design make sure that you have a Web site that says I only do web design.
You don't need to say I don't do mobile design.
It's fine you don't need to say every single thing you don't do because trust me there's more things
you don't do than you do do.
But it's important to have a services page because a lot a lot a lot of people will be interested in
your style what you're saying but they're not going to contact you unless they know for a fact that
you make the BlackBerry and you're going to be able to make whatever specifically they're looking for.
OK so the number four thing that every single one is going to have and I'm not going to end up in trouble
saying this every single one lists their portfolio.
And we have an entire section on this course on portfolios follow that if you want advice on what to
pick how to build them where to display them etc. but you'll notice that every one is going to list
out their portfolio in some way.
Like here products is their portfolio look a case study on a Web site they made and sapient Lytro we
just go over to work and work is things that they have built.
They have an insane amount of things to show you are going to show you right here if we go to our work
and here they're going to you know give it to you kind of case study style.
And here are some of the ones that are really really proud of these guys even do it as well.
Well could it work.
Right.
And so a lot of people do it in this thumbnail design or just list out everything.
And if you guys follow our portfolio section I can tell you why this is not effective it's never affected
given this many items.
It's always better to do a deeper dive on your top 5 to top 10.
But anyway.
So pretty much every single person does their own portfolio.
We are actually kind of an exception to the rule in that we use really is we ask people to request our
portfolio and then we send it to you.
Reason why we do this is just because we want to build an email list of people who are interested.
That helps a ton when it comes to bringing in new business and looking for other contractors and partners
for internal projects.
So don't forget to add a portfolio you'll notice all web companies are going to list a portfolio in
some way or at least make a reference to it.
OK the last 2 things are about us and contact us so about us is pretty simple.
Usually it's some form of information about who we are.
And a lot of ways it can be different it could just be a thing at the bottom that just says hey here's
where we are.
This is who we are.
This is what we look like.
A lot of times it's under a tab called like company.
A lot of times it's under a tab that's actually under contact us you to go to contact us to figure more
about them.
The reason why is because typically if you're doing large contracts and especially you're pitching to
people who don't know you they want to feel comfortable knowing who you are.
And it's really a good opportunity to help them understand who you are what's your culture like what
do you care about things like that it's just another opportunity for them to feel comfortable with you
and to get close to you were a little bit of an exception in that we describe ourselves throughout our
Web site but we don't actually have a company section mainly because we've found that it's harder to
build something like this when you have a distributed team.
So our team is primarily distributed about 80 percent of us are pretty much on Skype all over the world.
So it's a little bit harder when you can't have these like glorious shots of our hardwood floors and
our red brick room office space.
But what you'll notice is that if you do have some a group of people or in some way it's very helpful
to give some information about you if you have a distributed team.
What I do suggest is maybe you describe who you are specifically as the founder or just giving generic
information when we were started who we work with what we focus on things like that.
The last thing you'll notice is just contact us you need to have some way of being contacted.
So pretty much everyone on here has contact forms.
We do it up here and we also do it down here pretty much everybody has some way of sending them information.
And so like they'll call it connect or even contact.
So that's crucial.
Obviously a lot of people put that thing up and they forget that you need to put an e-mail address or
an e-mail form or something along those lines right.
Because this whole idea is to capture attention and then drive them towards you.
OK so hopefully you guys have a decent idea of how some of the more popular web development firms out
there designed their web presence.
These are more developed web sites.
A lot of them out there are very simple.
Don't be kind of put off by how fancy these guys are.
I'm just showing you these because they're kind of the top of the line.
And so a lot of the design conventions and standards follow these people so you should be aware there's
plenty of other ones out there that are much more simple much less graphically intense like this.
And obviously ones that have not been around as long so obviously don't get discouraged by how over-the-top
these are.
These are very well-established firms that I picked up so if you guys have any other questions this
post in the group discussion and we can kind of go over it.
But the main takeaways here is that everybody seems to have the same patterns of information.
So if you're making your site and you think you're leaving something out.
Just go and look at somebody else's.
And you'll notice there's a section pretty much all across the board that you're probably missing and
you should probably include.
All right see the next lecture.