Hey guys welcome back to the course so I thought this would be a kind of a fun lecture record talk a
little bit about what the story was spread.
Where do we start.
How did we end up where we are today.
So a lot of people don't actually realize this but I actually started Sprint kick drum roll in India
not Indiana.
Actually in India I had moved there to start it.
So before spring kick actually worked at the venture capital firm and a lot of what I did is I would
embed myself with small teams that had only received a moderate amount of funding and were going for
the next big round.
The number one thing I saw over and over and over again was the inability to recruit technical people
and find good engineers.
And so that's kind of where I came up with the idea that well it seems like everybody should actually
have the opportunity to outsource or at least contract out this work.
They just need to get over the stigma and they need someone who can actually help them bridge the communication
problem with the contractor or the project management problem with an outsourced firm.
So in one of the crazier decisions I've made my life I decided to actually move to a city called Hyderabad
and in Hyderabad Well I didn't wasn't immediately successful at first.
Once it was actually in India what I did is I started putting together the best team I could.
I have a lot of experience with outsourcing and I had known that the only difference between a good
project with an outsourced team and a bad project to the team is your project management layer.
The people who build your projects in other countries they're just every bit as brilliant technically
as the people that you would hire say in the United States or in Europe.
The problem is just communication and the problem is just different standards.
So I knew that I could insert myself into the mix and I could essentially be the catalyst from taking
cheap and turning it into good.
It took a lot of time and a lot of grinding it out took a lot of learning learning on a higher in India
is incredibly strange and incredibly difficult.
I learned that we had problems with putting people the same religion in the same room.
I had learned that certain people have problems with air conditioning as other ones do not.
I had learned that holiday schedules were incredibly difficult to build around.
Nevertheless it only took about a year before I put together the core team and build a client base that
actually could support growing the company and what I actually did as I started growing backwards.
So after that I actually worked backwards and started adding people in-house in the United States.
A lot of people do it the other way around right to start with employees and then add contractors on
top of that.
There's no reason you can't do it the other way around.
So fast forward pretty much three years later I've learned a ton about running web development businesses
snowballed a lot of mistakes and I've kind of accumulated a lot of strategies and skills and I've put
this all pretty locked into this course now where we are today.
We're a referral only agency.
What that means is we only accept new clients if we have a referral.
We've finally gotten to the point where we can pick exactly who we want to work with because we know
we're at the size that we're happy with and we know that we have a growth rate that we're happy with.
We're also happy to say that we're almost 90 percent distributed.
We run pretty much everything outside of the home base with a very small core.
We like to focus on having in-house designers because that's probably the best value you can get.
Great designers make great projects.
We're going to cover that later in the course but everything else can be contracted for the cost savings
and for the flexibility We've also expanded into a lot of different things.
We originally started with just webapps and then we expanded into mobile applications and we even expanded
into things like BlackBerry and Windows phone which I thought no one cared about.
We've also put a lot of effort into add on services focusing on offering graphic design as well as offering
help with launching and strategy consulting.
We've started to do that because we've realized that it's easier to grab on to one client and hold them
and charge more than it is they find lots and lots of different clients and only take control of one
section of their product launch.
So if you guys ever want to reach out just message me or post in the group discussion I am more than
willing to have a chat or help you out with any issues that you're having.
Hopefully through this course and through everything I'm about to teach you you're going to learn an
enormous amount and you're going to see the same successful growth that I saw.
But in a fraction of the time that's the point of this course.
I can't wait to see what you guys do with this course.
I'd love to see successful student testimonials.
I'd love to see you guys take the techniques that we're going to teach in this course and implement
them for yourselves.
I love it when you guys collaborate and add in some extra stuff that works for you as well.
All right guys like usual questions posed in the group discussion.
Any comments anything like that.
Otherwise see in the next lecture.