You can bring up user interface for what that looks like.
So in an actual job so this is a job that I built to an application that I'd built previously and you
can kind of see what it looks like after you've selected someone.
I use the programmer name Nicholas.
It puts me in a work room with them and there I can see messages.
I can see my payments and they use an escrow service.
It's very easy to use.
You know you just fund an amount and then you use it like you'll use it like a milestone.
So you'll say you know five hundred bucks to get this done and five hundred bucks to get this done and
a thousand dollars to get this done.
And as they finish it and deliver it then you can release it to them.
Elance holds onto the money like an escrow so that you can dispute it if anything happens so they don't
deliver it or they deliver something that you didn't ask for.
Here is an area where again oh here's this.
This is the tracker.
So if I wanted to I could ask them to use the freelancer tracker.
I didn't because I use a project price and I trusted this freelancer I had worked with them before.
But if you wanted to you could use this and this is a way of keeping them honest when they're talking
about charging you per hour but also seeing how productive they are if you're doing manual like virtual
assistant task or someone's filling out a Excel sheet or something like that.
That could be quite useful.
Being able to make sure that they work for eight hours they are actually working for eight hours and
they're not working for 10 15 minutes of that hour.
They also give you the ability to upload your contract onto here.
L.A. is pretty good at looking at the contracts that you use and then going off of that information
when it comes to a dispute.
So it's not just to prove that you have some legality behind this.
Lance does use the contract language you use to enforce whatever is happening in your project.
Let's see now I think that honestly covers pretty much everything you would want to know about Lance.
Again it's something that I enjoy quite a bit.
I like using it.
I've gotten some really good really talented people off of here.
It is usually my go to unless I'm trying to cut costs from trying to cut costs.
Then why would go to freelancer.
And that's coming up.
And if I wanted to have someone who wants to work per hour because they don't know how big the project
is or I want to have a relationship with someone that goes on forever I would use oDesk and so Odessey
is going to be next.