OK so here was an estimate that we had created a while back project that never got off the ground but
nonetheless we used our usual technique for estimating this out.
OK.
And as you can see on here what we basically did is we took every single subtask and then put them under
individual tasks and the tasks are either some large feature or when you see the bolded section that
actually connotates a section.
Now remember if I was doing an altogether estimate you actually would just see the total at the bottom.
This is all I would deliver to the client right there.
Now if I was doing a section by section all I would deliver would be the messaging.
I'd say like messaging and I'd say how many hours does a server set up and packaging how many hours
it does.
I would say group messaging and then I'd say how many hours are associated with that.
Now with piece by piece now you can see that we actually go and we estimate out individual tasks and
how long we think they're going to take.
Now I obviously think this is the by far the superior option.
There have been numerous occasions where we have the one client's because we used a piece by piece estimation
and the people that we were competing with used a section by section or an all together estimate.
And the reason why we ended up winning those was because clients actually love piece by piece estimates
and it's something that not enough people do.
The reason why they love it is because even if they're not technical they love to be able to see individually
how long every single edition takes.
That gives them transparency.
That immediately establishes trust with you and that sets up a situation where they know exactly what
it's going to take to put every single section.
And they're also confident that you know what every single section is going to take.
And in general they're not expecting you to give them that much transparency.
In general our industry is very opaque.
People generally will try to hide a lot of the information because they think that protects them.
What we try to do is we try to show off as much as we possibly can.
We found that that actually establishes trust early that helps us close sales.
It also helps our clients and a lot of different ways what they can do is they can look at a piece by
piece estimation and they can pick the things they want to add and pick the things they actually want
to drop.
We can also do things very Now if you listen to the other lecture we talked about a strategy of constant
estimation.
We can add in things always at the bottom we can add in additional features very easily down here just
put in a new section say potential features optional task optional optional features and then just add
it like normal.
Create a different subtotal so they know what is the proposal total and the other one is the proposal
plus the optional.
So it ends up selling a lot easier.
It makes it easier to explain to clients what's unnecessary and what's necessary.
That allows the client to be more successful in general because they can save their funds from sections
that are abnormally large and put them towards things that are actually smaller.
Now you think that would be a negative for you.
But again if you listen to the other lectures that we talk about rich clients versus successful clients
we talked about tying your project to your customer success.
That's actually quite important right.
You don't want your client to run out of money especially if it's a decent sized project.
Now if you want to create one of these it's really really simple honestly and in general this is one
of our secret techniques that have really really helped us grow.
People really like seeing this level of detail.
They will instantly get you noticed if you're competing with a group of other people.
It really helps to educate the client and helps the client really kind of connect with the application
they're making.
And it really shows off that we know what they're talking about even if we don't necessarily know exactly
what they're talking about.
We've just given them a lot of detail and really something to work with a lot of times our clients come
to us and we give them a really complex piece by piece estimation.
They can use that to convince other people that A we know what we're doing and B hey look this is an
actual concrete explanation of what we're trying to build which a lot of times clients will come to
you with just 19.
Just a business plan or just something scribbled on a napkin.
Now they see this.
Now it's real.
Now they become a lot more serious about it.
Now if you guys want to create a piece by piece estimation it's really quite simple.
I can include at the very end of the course a template if you want to but honestly it's not really that
complicated at all.
Typically what we do is we just divide everything into columns on the left side will name tasks and
a task can be something large.
Easiest way to think about this is actually just call it a feature.
These are the features with the exception of server setup and packaging.
The easiest way to think of this is task our task slash features typically like a feature like Sign-Up
or a feature like messaging.
This is be listed under attack because it is a task but also things like server setup and packaging
even things like time you take to submit something to say like an Apple store or an Android store.
Those are things that you can call tath So in the first column we just list out all the major tasks.
Then enter subtask.
We try to give as much detail into the process of what that actually entails as we can.
We don't every single time know every task that it's going to take that's why it's important to obviously
hedge when you send these proposals to people say that you know this might be a draft or this might
not be a finalized version and then come back to them with the finalizers and once you get enough information.
But for the most part it's not really something to fret over.
So in the second section try to break down every single large task or large feature and do as many separate
task as you can think of.
And then the third column you can choose between what we did here we gave an explanation.
Even with more detail where we said this is how many hours it will take on your back and back and meeting
the server that handles the information to the application that we're building.
And then over here we individually describe to build this is for a mobile application we described what
it would take to build on every single platform but you can imagine if we're just talking about say
a site you'd have the back end and the front end.
You could divide it that way if you wanted to really up to you.
Typically we only give three columns.
But in this case the person wanted a lot more.
So we actually added another column.
You can also put notes on the side.
These are things that are really helpful because you can put comments you can say that you have doubts
about something in the subtask you could say we need more information about this.
You could give some clarity for why a number is larger than you would think or smaller than you think
you can explain why one of your numbers might actually be zero until you get more information than what
we typically do is we'll put another section where the client can give comments and we can just go back
and forth that way.
And that's a very easy low tech way of collaborating with the client.
So guys really really simple.
I suggest you do it.
Clients love it.
It's really a competitive edge.
It's something that gives you transparency and it's something that establishes trust early which is
something that is crucial at the beginning of your business especially when you're working with new
clients.
You can impress them by doing this.
It doesn't really take that much time.
It's something that I think is definitely worth it.
You spend more time on it but you close more deals.
It's a way you can set yourself apart.
So if you're doing a subcontracting strategy I suggest talking to your subcontractors about setting
up a system like this.
Typically they're pretty amenable to that if you are developing it yourself then this is something that
I think you should consider developing as a skill.
I don't think it takes that long to get used to.
You just need to get used to getting your bets giving rough estimates and then doing more research to
give more specific estimates.
Once you know that the client is pretty much on board and there's a very high likelihood that you're
going to land the project.
All right guys see in the next lecture.