Hey guys.
Welcome back to the course in this lecture.
We're going to talk about sniffing out your client's budget.
What do I mean by that.
Well when you start the project process very beginning first point of contact with the potential new
client.
There's a lot of back and forth that happens before you guys agree on what you're building how much
it costs and what your timeline is going to be.
That process I just described actually can take up a considerable amount of time.
Larger projects have a lot of back and forth a lot of estimation a lot of re estimation and a lot of
negotiation.
Now it's in your best interest to minimize how many times you go through this process.
For clients that don't end up working with you or becoming paying clients.
And one of the biggest reasons why clients drop out is because of the budget either they don't have
the money to make it or they're just not confident they can get the money or they have enough money
to build the project they want to build a lot of times they have money but it will require them scaling
down their application.
Now it's important for you to have some general idea of your client's budget while you're going through
this process for a couple of reasons.
One that it's helpful for you because you can shift resources if you believe you're with a client that's
unrealistic.
You can also change your strategy.
Start pushing them them towards things that are more practical more cost effective.
Start pushing them towards more of a minimum viable product model and essentially just try to pitch
them on the whole idea they should start off smaller but also what ends up happening is a lot of times
if you work with clients you no idea what their budget is they'll accept a project and they simply do
not have the funds or they're not in a good enough cash position to make the project correctly.
A lot of times they build something out and they quite literally spend every dollar they have building
it.
And then when it needs editing it needs fixes when you find out that user feedback says this section
doesn't work.
This section needs to be fixed they have nothing to work with.
And so you're working with a dead project now and you just stress this that a lot of contractors will
ask for your budget up front.
It's surprising how many people do that and it's something that you should never do.
It's it's such bad manners it's so really unprofessional and I'm kind of amazed by the people that actually
stick by asking what the client's project is upfront.
I teach other courses on you to me where I actually take the other side of the fence and I teach people
how to be a master at purchasing software and mastering kind of the freelancer business relationship.
And I always say that people that ask for their budget upfront are more likely to be unrealistic about
what it's going to take to get your project done.
It's also just bad taste.
If I'm someone who's looking for a long term contractor or someone to work on a very important project
I'm not going to be interested in working with someone whose first question is how much money do you
have to spend.
I'm interested in someone who is interested in my project.
I would like to work with someone who has a personal connection to it.
You should follow that as well.
You should always make your client feel as if you are interested in what they're doing.
Make it look like you're thinking about it in other ways and that money is not the most important issue
an issue to you.
What are the things that always drives me crazy with other freelance businesses is they ask for your
budget and if you tell them your budget you magically you'll find out that their estimates always seem
to fit your budget.
That's typically just shows that a lot of people use that as a technique to be dishonest.
They use it to figure out how much money they can squeeze out of you and not to objectively answer the
question of how much does this cost.
What is it going to take.
So be realistic.
Get your priorities right.
And don't ask for your budget up front.
But there are some certain things that can help you understand roughly whether or not your client is
even in the right range of your project and to give you some idea of whether or not they have a healthy
budget or a budget that simply cannot support the project they're proposing.
So I'm going to go over some of the most common things you should look for and some simple ways that
you can actually press the issue find out what their budget is without actually asking explicitly and
being rude.
Now this is not an exhaustive list but these are the ones that I see coming up all the time.
If you guys have other ones post in the group discussion can definitely add them in here.
That would actually be quite helpful.
These are the ones I've seen.
OK.
So number one.
This is something that I see constantly.
Do you have a client that is constantly assuring you that a section that they're proposing to build
is really simple or really cheap despite how educated your client thinks they are.
They don't ever know how big a project is.
They very rarely have the slightest inclination how a section is they're wrong more often than they're
right.
And I also kind of believe that most clients at least subconsciously understand that they don't know
what they're talking about what's happening though when they're doing this is they're signaling to you
budget is probably a concern.
I'm telling you this is simple in the hopes that you believe that it's simple and you return to me a
price that is quite reasonable.
Now someone who has a budget that's easily going to encompass this project they're not going to be as
concerned with telling you how simple projects pieces are.
Number two look for how much specificity your client gives you a client that gives you 16 20 25 pages
of documentation.
Wireframe specifications that person is probably more realistic and probably more aware of how big their
project is.
People who have gone and actually done each individual section probably has a decent idea of whether
or not this is a big project a medium project or a small project and consequently they are probably
more realistic about what the price is going to be if they're coming to you and they have all of this
sketched out all of this planned out not only are they more serious about the project they probably
have the budget to pursue this.
People who go through and map out the entire thing don't usually get to the point where they're asking
for your services unless they are pretty confident they can pay for it.
Now people who are completely clueless who just email you saying I want to build Instagram.
Those people have absolutely Probably no idea how much it's going to cost because they have no idea
what the cost range is.
It's less likely that they are realistic about price or have the money to pay for it.
Number three this is something I see quite often it's the I versus we when typically when someone says
I assume it's a person but when you hear people say we my partner and I.
That basically means there's multiple people making this purchasing decision.
Now you might not read into that too much but in my experience typically when they have partners that
means They're pooling their money together.
Typically when they say we it's multiple people they brought someone on the more serious about this
and there's multiple people to draw from to bring in money.
A lot of times you're talking to the entrepreneur.
The we refers to the entrepreneur and their limited partner the partner who provides the cash.
Now that's not a rule across the board.
Plenty of partnerships don't have the money to work with you and plenty of single individuals do.
But just statistically more people are probably going to have access to more disposable income and more
funds.
So typically groups of people are more likely to be able to pay for it.
Number four consider how much you know about the client.
A lot of times you will go through hours and hours and hours of estimating going back and forth discussing
and it occurs to you you have no idea what this client does for money.
Are they a past entrepreneur.
Do they work for a giant company or their college student you have no idea who they are.
Typically if you're working with someone who's employed and they're doing this on the side if they're
at a point in their career where they're thinking about side projects and they're willing to purchase
software on a side they're probably more realistic about what it's going to cost and they probably have
been putting away money to pay for this for a while.
Now if you're talking to someone like a college student that's not usually the case unless you're asking
the kid who lives off a trust fund.
They're probably just completely and realistic they're probably overly idealistic about their project
or they think it's abnormally simple to build and they have no idea what development projects cost.
So if they have a job chances are they have been putting money aside and they probably have some of
a budget not a huge one but enough to build a decent application.
So number five how quickly do they go through the process.
That's something you'll notice very quickly.
Some people will go through seven rounds of discussion in seven days.
Some of them will go through seven rounds of discussion over the course of four months.
Typically the ones that respond quicker are less concerned or have fewer issues with what you're proposing
them.
Often it's the case that if they're speeding through the process that's because money is not an issue
to them or they don't see it as something that's insurmountable.
Now there are exceptions to this rule a lot of times you will find people who just love kind of going
through the process trying to get the most out of it and they've not even thought about the price.
But that's usually the exception and not the rule.
Typically people who respond quickly are confident about what you're telling them and they're confident
about pursuing this project.
If someone's delaying they could be slow rolling you could just be waiting and waiting and waiting because
they don't like what they hear and they don't think they can pull it together.
Another one you'll notice as a red flag is do they ask for additional feature estimates.
And then you notice that in the total project it never gets added.
I have this all the time.
People ask for I want this really big project.
And can you tell me on the side what does this and this will cost.
And then when you go back to piled the complete estimate they're removing those estimates you gave them
or you never see them incorporate that into their larger estimate.
Now again as a rule not a 100 percent true but typically what's happening is they're not including that
estimate.
It means it's either non-essential or they can't afford it.
So it's usually one or the other.
If they keep doing this over and over it happens a lot.
You have someone say how much for this.
OK and you tell them and they say no then they say how much for this.
You tell them they say no they'll keep doing it back and forth until they can figure something that
they can fit in the budget.
Typically that signals constrained budget probably only have enough for the main project and not much
else.
Probably not a healthy budget.
And number seven this is just a technique and this is the last one I'm going to go over for figuring
out whether or not they have the budget.
If you watch the other lecture we talk about ballpark estimates.
Those are incredibly useful when you can actually use those as kind of an exploratory tool.
When you have somebody asking you questions you know how about this.
How about this.
What if I did this and you're not feeling whether or not they have the budget or you're concerned about
it.
Often what you can do and it will save you a ton of time is just go ahead and do the ballpark estimate.
And in one of your e-mail correspondence says just tell them hey you know this whole thing probably
if I had to guess is 400 to 600 hours or whatever that ends up being for you.
Ten to fifteen thousand dollars and just leave that out there.
See how they respond if they skip over that without a beat.
Then they probably are perfectly fine.
That's not really an issue but if someone doesn't have the budget for that that'll stop them dead in
their tracks.
And now you know they probably didn't have the budget you can apply your resources and apply your time
elsewhere.
OK guys so those are pretty much the seven things and kind of red flags that I've noticed.
The best way I honestly if you're in doubt give them a ballpark estimate.
That'll pretty much shut it down if they keep going past that point.
You're pretty good.
Other than that just try to use your spider sense and think about their partners.
Are they employed.
How quickly are they responding.
How much thought have they put into this project.
Are they really insistent that certain sections are really small or inexpensive.
Do they ask for features and never seem to add them to the bigger project.
OK guys be aware of those things.
Look for them if you have any other things that you've noticed yourself in your experience posts in
the group discussion.
I'd love to hear it otherwise see in the next lecture.