Pick guys welcome back to the course so this lecture I want to talk about a really cool trick you can
use asana for in your development business.
Now we covered how to get up and running in a sauna before we cover how it works how internal teams
use it to manage tasks and make sure that everyone's on the same page.
But what you need to understand is that everyone out there for the most part uses this in turn only
and that's how a sauna designs their systems.
But what they don't realize especially for us in the case that we have clients and we are also internally
collaborating on a development project is that we can actually use a sauna and turn it inside out to
serve a lot of the purposes that we need.
With regards to client management they've heard me talk before in this course about client management
and how important it is to let your clients feel like they are in the loop whether or not they're in
the loop and actual wildy is not really the important part.
It's not they feel like they are on the same page and they know what's happening.
Now one of the reasons that clients can very easily become a pain in the ass is because they feel as
if they need to assert some type of control over you.
Now regardless of whether or not their input and their micromanagement regardless of whether or not
that actually helps you have a good outcome or make a good product they still do it.
They're not going to entirely blame clients out there.
They do this because it's simply not appropriate for them.
The purchaser of your software to just sit there for long periods of time and not hear anything from
you even if you're doing a weekly stand up calls.
So you're talking them on a Friday that might not be enough for them.
They might have a boss who wants to know more and asks more frequently than once a week.
So use the trick that we had Sprint kick here use for our client management we use this sauna the same
way we use it internally but we turn it inside out for clients just so that they can feel like they
are giving us their voice so they can see on a granular basis where we are and what is getting done
and also so that they can give a specific feedback on each individual thing that makes it a lot easier
to understand what they are referring to when they say they don't like the color of this or this section
doesn't work the way we're supposed to.
All right so let's jump into a sauna and I set up here a sample version so that you can see kind of
like the way that we generally will set it up.
We set it up in sprints.
In actuality to be a lot more complicated I did take and copy actual tasks from our actual asana through
them in here.
But this is typically what it's going to look like when you and your team are working on developing
your product you're going to list off your tasks in sequential order to list them off on when you start
on them when you should probably deliver them.
But also notice here that a lot of these things here are kind of designed for internal consumption.
They're messy.
We use things like this.
I put the hourly marker here that doesn't make sense to someone who's not on the team.
We have long tasks that actually include so much text that it wraps around.
Now a developer is fine.
They know exactly what that is.
They can click it and go through it but just keep in mind this is one of the internal Ossana panel looks
like.
Now if you wanted to take this and flip it inside out for your clients just go over here to whatever
project it is and you can click on these three little dots and you can use as a template copy your project.
Now I ask you what you want to do in your copy project and how much you want to put over to it.
So what you want to make sure you're not doing is don't trick assignee because that information is going
to be relevant.
In our second Ossana project you want subtasks you want attachments you want tags everything like that.
You do not want project members.
Explain that in just a second so make sure to uncheck that and create a new project.
Give it a second and it'll make a complete copy of what you just made.
OK.
There we go.
Now we can hop into an exact clone.
Now here what I'm going to do is I'm going to do the same thing I was doing before in the example project
but I will convert it for external purposes.
I'm going to clean it up.
I'm going to change some of the wording so it's easier to understand.
And also I am only going to link one other person in my team to this now and the other internal project.
If you go and look at it and this is just obviously an example.
Lots of people are sharing this.
OK.
And that's generally the case is there are lots of different people some of them only see certain sections.
Some of them are collaborating over here.
But when you do your external that is not relevant information you need every single person in on this
you just need one your client and to one of your developers that you designate as the best communicator.
Now if you have a project manager or a developer that's acting as a project manager then perfect that's
who you want to attach to this.
Now the reason why you do this is because you're going to copy these tasks over your clients can to
be able to see them.
Your clients are going to be able to comment on them.
It's up to you to then respond to them give them the information they need but you essentially be doing
a subcontracting strategy you won't be able to actually update these in any meaningful way or answer
technical questions.
That's why it's important that you have one developer or someone on your team that is communicative
That is absolutely plugged into the loop to add the tasks when they are made to click through them when
they are done and to answer questions that are technical because these are things that you just can't
do yourself.
So I'll give it a cleaning and I'll see.
OK so I just clean this up a little bit.
I just removed information that would make any sense to your client because they probably are non-technical
and also simplified the wording and a lot of things took out the wordiness and then pushed any details
into the descriptions on the actual sub pages and I just did that because you want to make sure that
you are walking a balance between showing that you have technical prowess and that what you're doing
is complicated and they can't do it themselves.
But also being able to speak in a way that they can actually understand if they can't follow this then
it's not particularly helpful to them.
And if it sounds ridiculously simple and easy then you're going to have problems in your client because
they think that it's too simple why are they paying you.
So take a little bit of time.
Throw in some Polish maybe throw in some screenshots so that someone who doesn't know exactly what's
happening on a day to day basis can follow along.
Typically I suggest you change the name of your project doing the exact same thing as your internal
but then changing it just slightly so that you can tell the difference right here.
So instead of copy for example project the code example project and mean this is actually what we do
which puts Brint care at the end of that.
Knows that that means doesn't matter just helps us know that this is the external.
And this is the internal You can do it whatever way you want.
There you go.
Now you have an external sized version of your asana you share that with your clients.
They can log in and see exactly where you are.
They don't have to ask you.
They don't have to call you and you just see yourself.
Seriously hundreds of hours of management just given this panel and they will get so happy as they see
these things get checked off because look it's like progress.
Their app is getting done.
All right guys see in the next lecture.