Hey guys welcome back to the course.
So in this lecture we're going to talk about a best practice that revolves around looking for the right
clients.
And I call this one look for clients that have depth.
What do I mean by that.
No I don't mean look for clients that have really rich personalities and deep wells of knowledge.
Your clients can be as shallow as you want them to be.
That's not what I'm talking about.
I'm talking about their projects look for clients that have projects that are not only ambitious but
actually have development depth to them.
Now you might think to yourself but it's so easy to find someone who wants a custom WordPress theme
installed.
Yes that's great.
Yes that's money.
And I'm not going to discourage you from doing that.
You have to understand that has a place when you're starting your business and you go after any client
you can alert someone who's doing a very basic one off project like doing a WordPress theme install.
That's fantastic.
Only at the beginning.
Now that type of client that I'm describing is what I call a web presence client.
Someone has a web presence client is someone who is not necessarily in the business of making their
own application.
They're just in the business of getting a web site or a mobile presence application.
Those are typically people who literally just want a web site to display information about who they
are what their company does or to announce an upcoming product or something along those lines.
There's a very large portion of development projects out there that fall under this category people
who just want to say hello internet.
This is something to represent whatever I'm doing who I am and it's up online now there's multiple problems
with web presence clients being your main crop of clients.
First of all remember when I said that in any given development project design is always smaller and
the development and development is always the largest by far portion of the money spent now with Web
presence clients.
You're really kind of testing me on that rule because in a lot of cases the design is actually more
expensive than the development that is the biggest exception to this rule.
These projects typically from a development standpoint are not very deep.
There's something that is very easily put onto a platform very easily catered to from a Web site like
Squarespace or Wick's or Shopify or WordPress.
Very easy to go after.
These are clients that typically aren't looking for adding complexity they don't have any new ideas
that need to be made they don't have any custom specifications for any algorithms or new features or
really anything out of the ordinary.
They're just looking for flat pages that do very very basic common functionalities.
So one reason why they're bad clients is that there's a lot of competition for what they're trying to
do.
It's very hard for you to compete with another company that's out there that is spending millions and
millions of dollars to create a platform that can do everything for them.
The second thing is that they are often people with very very small budgets.
It is almost always the case.
Ninety percent of the time that after you do a web presence.
Work they have nothing else for you to do.
That's generally not something that you want.
Remember we're trying to escape the cycle of constantly looking for new clients because that sucks up
a lot of time and that's time you don't get paid for.
You want to focus on finding clients that stick around for a long time because that's where they really
get profitable.
That's where you really get kind of the juice out of this relationship.
So were present clients even if they stick with you for a very long period of time you don't actually
get the benefits of retaining a client even if they do have work it's typically very small and it's
often just a distraction.
It's like you have to take a developer who's working on a larger project and say hey this client needs
four hours of work done that is just hard to get into.
That's hard to make money off of.
And often it's a bigger detriment to another project.
So in general try to focus on projects that are trying to expand try to focus on projects that have
some sort of novelty the very beginning you're perfectly fine bringing on web presence clients.
They were great for your portfolio but when your portfolio is full or past a point where you can display
them anymore you need to start looking further down field looking for people who are trying to build
applications trying people trying to build things that actually have some uniqueness to them and more
importantly they're going to be people that bring back significant chunks of work over the long term
and not just bring in trickles of money in trickles of billable hours.
That's a strategy that's just not sustainable.
Even if you are a solo freelancer you can fill your plate off of these web presence clients but you're
never going to grow this into something that's ideal or better than the situation you're in if you stick
with this client type questions comments concerns complaints anything you disagree with me post in the
group discussion.
Otherwise see in the next lecture.