Hey guys.
Welcome back to the course so in this lecture I'm going to answer the question if you have your own
existing consulting business or freelance business how can you add development services to that.
So it's actually very very easy and going to cover just a couple of my favorite ways that you could
integrate this into your existing business.
So one way of doing this and it's usually very simple if you have your own freelance business or you
already have your own graphic design marketing SEO firm or small business or whatever it is you probably
have a Web site or somewhere where you list your presence and list out your services.
So the obvious answer to that question is you can just list this somewhere else on your Web site.
Now if you're worried about this being conflicting with what your primary focus is you can very easily
just add a separate tab or even add an after note at the end.
Now keep in mind most people are probably coming to you for what you specialize in so you don't want
to spend half of your web page or half your web presence talking about your ability to also build what
it is that you consult with them on.
You want to keep it obviously proportionate.
It's usually an afterthought if you're adding subcontracting so you can add it in a foot or you can
just add it in separate sections.
Again people are focusing on what your expertise is but it's an added perk or an added bonus that you
can also develop it for them.
Another way that you can also remind people that hey I also do development work is pretty simple.
You actually just end up adding it very simply to your branding.
So I'll give you an example.
Sprint kick started out as a development firm primarily.
That's all we did.
And when we actually started hiring designers all we did was change our tagline from development studio
to design plus development studio.
That's typically it.
If you have a logo and you already have a subtitle it's very easy to just add something in like that.
You can also just make short references to it in your head or you can make a reference to it in your
business cards.
There's a lot of really simple subtle ways of pointing out that hey I also do this.
You can also change the way that you phrase your company as opposed to saying you're an escrow specialist
you could say your SBO and web studio you can use something that's more broad.
You can even transition to saying digital agency digital studio digital is a very common catchall word
meaning we do this but we also specialize or can do all of the other things that are involved in creating
a digital product.
So looking to some of the other words in other terms you can use I would suggest that hey I do more
than just what my specialty is.
So the third one is actually my favorite technique and it's because it's really subtle.
It doesn't come on very strong but at the same time it's very very convincing.
So you probably already have clientele and you probably are sending those people estimations and you're
probably also sending them bills.
So what you can do and we cover this later in the course is very easily attach Development estimates
to already to your marketing or your SBO or your design estimates.
OK.
So let's take an example.
You design web sites.
Let's say that your client asks you to design for pages for the brand new website.
You say it's going to cost you this much and then attached to your estimate as an appendage or even
just a separate row as a side thought you can say Oh also here's the estimate for building it for you.
Now you can do this whatever way you want.
You always you don't want to come on too strong because you want them to focus on your design.
You can put it as an afterthought.
A lot of graphic designers will just show Rose saying this section cost me this much or this is just
my generic estimate for how many days it costs.
Or 17 days it's going to take and this is my day rate.
And then all you have to do is just attach to the end.
Also this is my rough estimation for building it.
You also follow later in the course when we talk about ballpark estimates.
So what you can do is just attach say also if you're interested I can you have it developed for this
much if they're not interested they'll ignore that.
If they are interested they'll definitely keep that in mind.
Same thing works for bills.
You can actually if you're billing someone for work you did.
You can also attach onto it estimates for other things.
People will always find this as a positive thing because for them it's not as if your coming on too
strong or being too pushy by giving them an estimate.
It's always helpful to know how much you think something's going to cost or how long it's going to take.
That's helpful because that's information information they didn't previously have.
In most cases when people are looking to design and then develop a Web site they probably are going
to shop around and look at prices the more prices they have the better position they're in to make a
good decision.
So you're giving them an estimate that's a positive thing that helps them.
That actually saves them a little bit of time.
OK so you can get creative.
It's very easy just to add it on.
A lot of you guys already add on other services or familiar with upselling for add ons but for web development
it's just as simple as anything else.
There's a lot of different ways you can go for it.
There's other ones I haven't even covered anything really think those are the three that I've seen work
really really well.
All right.
So in the next lecture.