Hey guys welcome back to the course so let's talk about who is this course for and who stands to benefit
the most from the skills and everything that's packed into this course.
So to put it simply literally anyone can start a web and mobile development business.
Do you need to know how to code.
It helps but you absolutely do not take me for example.
I started Sprint kick just myself.
I couldn't code to save my life.
I literally took it from where it was four years ago it was just me and a laptop in the middle of nowhere
to where it is today which is 18 employees in six different countries.
Do you need a ton of time to start a development business.
Well no we don't actually really have to at all.
This is definitely something you can manage in a part time capacity.
Now if you want to do this as your main thing and you want it to grow very quickly and you want to focus
on high growth then I'd suggest that you spend a full time amount of commitment towards the business.
But if you're more interested in a modest amount of growth or something that adds an extra 50 60 K to
year salary every year it's definitely something you can do part time.
Unfortunately you can't really pick the hours because you don't know when a server is going to crash
or you don't know when a client wants to meet.
But if you have a flexible job this could be something you could work out if you have a separate project
that you're working on or a separate job.
I personally started doing this full time and then I transitioned into doing it part time and it honestly
didn't make a difference.
I was perfectly satisfied with the growth trajectory that it was on.
So what skills do you need to have.
Well technically none.
The only thing that you need is an interest in web or mobile applications.
It helps if you have strong opinions on what works what doesn't work.
It helps if you pay attention to trends or pay attention to what are new techniques or things that catch
your interest.
But again if you don't have these you know prior established opinions it's something that you develop
very quickly throughout this process.
Naturally technology lovers are going to have an advantage it's going to come to you a lot quicker.
But it's still open for really anyone who wants to get into this.
So the way I see it there are three main groups of people who can start a web development business or
who can strongly benefit from a business like this.
So the first group are programmers.
You might in some capacity already know how to program.
You might have worked as a freelancer or are working as a freelancer and you might actually have your
own client set that you're managing most likely you're probably working with other contractors that
your client has hired or you're just working so low as yourself on individual projects.
So you start a web or a mobile development business and you can finally transition into bigger projects.
You can actually transition out of doing the day to day programming or if you prefer to actually stay
programming every day.
You can stay in the pits except now you can add bodies around you and you can multiply the amount of
money that you make per hour that you work.
So imagine it right now you work maybe you charge $20 an hour if you charge 50 maybe charge to 100.
But if you take on a larger project and you have people next to you who work underneath you you get
paid for every hour they work on top of how many hours that you work.
Now you can only do that by starting your own business and treating it like a business learning how
to go after clients learning how to manage them.
Learning the entire process from finding someone to getting the contract to working on it to delivering
it to keeping them happy in the future and bringing them back.
It's also likely that as a programmer you have a certain technology that you're really passionate about.
You started development business you can build an entire business around that technology.
You can build your reputation build your skills and build a decent income around that technology.
You're passionate about.
So the second group that can easily start a development business and benefit immensely from it are non-technical
entrepreneurs entrepreneurs who want to start their own business but they're not necessarily technically
oriented.
Anybody who has a business background marketing background or even specific skill sets like a CEO or
PR or anything like that.
Anybody who doesn't who considers themselves to do everything other than the programming you can still
do this.
I am actually one of you and at first I always thought I couldn't do a development business as well.
And there's absolutely no reason why I couldn't.
So if you want to build future capacity for your next startup if you want to learn in-depth how technology
works what makes a great product and get yourself ready for the next thing this is an excellent business
to start.
If you want to learn how to program and you want to learn how to program on your own projects that you
yourself grab.
That's fantastic.
And oh let's not forget if you also want to make a ton of money it's also a fantastic business to start.
So you're in the world of Web and mobile applications and you want to grow your network grow your income
and learn some awesome skills that are going to benefit you regardless of whether or not you grow this
to 200 people or you move on to your next startup or you take a gig at another startup that's blowing
up.
And the third group is anyone who is a freelancer or anyone who does their own consulting work.
So you don't necessarily have to be a freelancer or maybe you have a business and something else in
marketing.
If you have a business in graphic design maybe of a business in identity and branding CEO any of those
auxillary services around web projects and mobile projects you're the third group now if you are a freelancer
or you run a freelance firm you probably have your own clientele.
So the way that this course or starting a web development business benefits you.
Is that now all of a sudden not only can you sell your clients your regular services you can learn how
to build out the capacity to offer them development services.
We cover another lecture y That's awesome.
One of the biggest reasons is the development side of every single web or mobile project is by far the
largest portion of the money that goes into the project.
So you have a client that wants you to design a web site offer to design the web site and build it for
them.
You have a client who wants you to run a marketing campaign offered to build them a Web site to assist
in that.
Do you have clients who do management or marketing consultation with if they have a business idea or
a separate feature or a separate product not only can you consult them on the best way of doing it but
you can also tell them that you can build it for them as well.
So wide range of people can benefit from this immensely.
You don't have to be technical.
You could be a designer or marketer or just a generic non-technical entrepreneur.
A lot of people can do this.
You can learn a lot of great skills and skill sets doing this and you can make a ton of money with a
great ratio of work to actual reward.
So I'll see you in the next lecture.