All right.
Welcome back.
When I go over freelancer dot com I'm going to try to keep this as brief as possible.
I had mentioned before that freelancer is the least like the other two freelancer has the most the largest
user base of freelancers of about seven million there also.
Strangely enough the least profitable of the three.
Mainly because they make most of their money off of project upgrades and all of an assortment of fees
that they've kind of come up with.
So we're just going to go through this pretty quickly as you can see it is just kind of a mess in terms
of a user interface during this demo if something breaks or something doesn't load.
I'm not entirely surprised freelancer is the place that I call it the Wild West.
A great metaphor or A B comparison is it's kind of the Craigslist of freelancing services.
There's not a lot of rules.
Pretty much anything goes.
And a lot of times you find some things that are really kind of what you'd call like black hat or a
very kind of scatch.
So anyway speaking of scatch I use this as a burn away account.
I just have a fake name associated with it.
But I was using freelancer for quite a long time mainly because they're the best if you have a small
task or you have something that's not you know it's harder to get done.
A lot of times like I might be thinking I'm I mean a an artist an illustrator I need someone who specializes
in video or audio or something that not I don't think necessarily lends itself well the answer I would
ask.
I go to a freelancer freelancer has people that do pretty much everything and as you can see over here
here's some progress that I've actually been using freelancer to help out with my you do me courses.
So you'll notice here it kind of looks like the other two poster project here you find your freelancers
here you can browse other projects they give you a lot more controls over it.
You can look for all of the projects that I like ending soon ones that have no bids.
Ones that fit your skills if you're a freelancer post contests not to be confused with post project
freelancer also has a secondary function which is that they have a contest section of their web site.
If you click on this button right here you can see the other services they offer.
So freelancer's the main one freelancer contest is their answer to 99 designs freelancers services.
Is there a copycat of fiver or dot com.
I don't even know what these three are but chances are you probably will use them.
Freelancer is a little bit weird or you will upload money into your account and so like you'll deposit
funds and then you'll pay your freelancers freelancer.
Keep in mind that there's not a lot of support when it comes to people who disappear or don't do your
work.
Don't do it correctly.
They have tried to automate virtually everything and to the detriment of their community.
So we can check out what a project looks like.
Here as an example earlier in the course you've seen some hand drawings I actually use this as a way
of drumming up leads for looking for a graphic designer who could help me what they will do.
So what they do is they will show off at the very top of each project who they suggest.
Now this is something you won't notice with Lance Lance doesn't usually suggest a user oDesk won't suggest
a user freelancer well.
And also a lot of times you'll notice that they have sponsored listings meaning someone can pay to show
up at the top of your list.
They also do this weird thing which is on purpose.
I can't hide bids.
Wow you can't even talking about freelancer and how much their user interface is kind of crap design.
You notice that constantly things are just cut off.
But what this is I think it says report meaning I can report it if it's spam but I can never seem to
get rid of any bid anyway.
Yes that is how they design the layouts.
Keep in mind people that can sponsor their bids can show up at the top.
I try to stay away from sponsored bids.
A lot of freelancers sponsored bids at the beginning so that they can reach so they can get a lot of
projects at first.
They have built in a chat system so this is along with a frequently used contact list.
So NLC you little notice if someone is online you can see that they will pop up and will have a green
dot.
So they've integrated instant messaging into their system and then they've integrated all sorts of other
web sites into a kind of a hodgepodge it's really kind of a melting pot.
That's why I call it the Wild West.
You can get some of the greatest value possible out of here and at the same time you can get some of
the largest headaches.
Dot com.
It's typically a great option for instance if you want to get a clone of a Web site.
It's also great if you want someone to do some advertising for you.
So actually if you want to bend the rules a little bit and you're fine.
Kind of walking the line between spam and not spam.
This is kind of a place that you would look for people.
Let's see freelance.
I'm also a strange thing that they do is magnifica even find it they have tried to Gamefly their system
quite a bit.
Where is it where.
OK here it is.
Myra Woodwards I thought this was goofy.
If you are someone that does a lot of projects a lot of the time they have made a whole badge system
and a credit shop and in all sorts of just goofy things.
You know I'm level 12 journeyman and so I could use this to upgrade and to get free featuring and free.
I'm not even entirely sure.
But anyway it's kind of like a rewards program.
You know maybe some of you might find some use out of this.
Maybe you won't see.
All right.
So anyway I promised that I'd keep this one short.
We're not going to do a deep dive into this Web site there.
Honestly there are enough features on this website to make an entire course out of it seems like.
And for your purposes you really just want to focus with the basics which is posting a project and then
managing your freelancers and also just knowing kind of ahead of time what exactly the interest is about
this Web site here.
I mean this is the Czar you'd post a project.
It's virtually the same.
This is one thing that is worth posting or talking about very briefly.
They make most of their money off of upgrades.
So if you want to for instance increase the reach of your page you can do a free trade listing cost
$29 if you want to do.
Urgent urgent means that you just put some marker next or that says urgent.
And then more people know that you're trying to pick someone soon and so you get a lot of bids.
Recruiter is a service they offer that I don't believe the other to offer you pay $29 and they will
help you recruit someone.
In my experience it's not particularly helpful because the support they give you is very minimal.
But I believe what ends up happening when you're a recruiter is you get an automatic upgrade to being
featured.
And that's kind of how they justify paying for the service.
One of the goofy things that will happen is when you post a project it will ask you if you want to upgrade
and you can do to.
And if you don't upgrade it says you want to do a free version and it says the free version you have
to wait and someone has to manually review your posting.
That is not true.
So if you get the free version it loads it pretends that it's getting reviewed and then it just posted.
It's actually computer rhythm that checks it over.
There's actually no delay so don't get tricked into paying extra money if you don't feel like it.
Freelancer another Web site.
I definitely think you should add to your toolkit if you have.
I think it's better for auxilary services and I think that it's great for finding people that are kind
of your odds and ends things people can fill in the gaps and.