Hey guys welcome back to the course so in this lecture we're going to talk about something that can
severely hamstring your portfolio and something that when addressed correctly can dramatically improve
your product in Project quality.
Now a lot of times you have a project that you work on that's big it's grand It's ambitious it's interesting
from a technical perspective you put a lot of work into it.
And when the product launches it is just not something that you want to show off.
Now I'm not talking about something that you might have botched in some way or something that you just
don't really like what it's about.
I'm talking about it's a product that comes out.
It's just not very impressive.
It looks like it's from the 90s.
It's something that just doesn't look like it's trendsetting or something that might reflect a high
quality application.
Now a lot of times the culprit in this situation is the design.
And since this is for developers are people starting development businesses that is technically something
that might be outside of the scope of your control.
Now this is the problem happens to developers all the time.
You work on something.
It's great but the designer is just not up to speed.
They're not high quality and it ends up making the app look bad.
We control all the functionality of the application we control everything that happens below the visual
layer but customers on the other hand they see the visual layer first and only the most acute the most
experience ones even pay attention to how complex the back end interactions are.
Simply put ugly user interface is ugly to everyone.
Ugly code is only ugly to the developer that's looking at it.
So if this is a problem you're having you're having a lot of cool projects but none of them are really
portfolio worthy or something you really want to show off.
And it's because of design.
I have a couple of tips for you to how you can fix this.
So keep in mind great design makes a great portfolio.
The first thing you can do is take into consideration who is the designer when you make a decision to
work with a client.
Take some time to actually look at who they employ.
Look at where the design is coming from and see if you can request this up front.
Now I'm not saying that if it's bad design it's not a project you should take on at all.
But I'm saying that you should take this as a factor in your judgment about whether or not this is a
client you want to work with whether or not there's a client you don't want to work with or whether
or not it's a client you really do.
And someone that you want to put a lot of pressure on or work really hard to try to create a contract
with.
So take that into consideration ask them who it is ask to see the designs before you get them.
Another thing you can actually do is to keep a list of all the designers you worked with or ones that
you admire that you think make good reasonably priced design.
And when it comes to that point because remember you are usually contracted after the conception stage
and potentially after the design phase introduce that person as an option to your client.
A lot of times clients are also not happy with their design or they simply don't have that design.
So if you introduce someone you know creates high quality work you're setting yourself up to work on
a project that could actually be shown off.
Now the last option is to offer design services yourself.
There's a lot of reasons why that's helpful and why people like that a lot find a designer that you
work with.
Well try working with them on a couple of projects to find out very quickly the ones you really like
and the ones that you can work with for a long period of time.
You might even consider not making a margin on their rates because remember whatever they design is
going to be the face of anything you develop.
So if they're really really good it shouldn't matter to you you're getting a lot of benefits just from
working with them.
If you have a top of the line designer and they're up on the trends and there's someone that puts a
lot of thought down to every pixel of what they put together anything they produce and anything you
then subsequently develop is going to look great.
Doesn't matter how ugly or how clunky your programming is.
It could have been one of your worst projects ever it's still going to look good and it's going to look
good to 99 percent of the people who see it.
Now that is true.
And you know in the reverse scenario where you have great development ugly design what we already covered
that's terrible.
You have to remember that clients are at the end of the day customers and there are no real difference
between them and their end users.
They still look at an app and they see it and they see it just the same way that any old an educated
user is going to see it.
So take this into consideration.
Bad design always gets hidden away and you never could just show it off.
Again it's just as valuable as the dollar amount that you put into it.
And great design can honestly really change how many leads you get how many clients you close how great
your web presence is and how great your portfolio is.
So if you're running into this problem try to tackle it in a variety of ways.
Make sure you know who the designer is.
Make a judgment on whether or not you think there a good designer and decide whether or not that's a
cause you want to take on.
You can similarly open up your own network designers and use them as an introduction to your client
so that you can know that someone you've worked with before is introducing the project.
Now you could also go as far as to do what we do and have your own designer and then include them in
any development package that you do that gives you additional benefits as a service.
But it also allows you to know exactly the quality of the design that's going to come down the line
for you and then put into your portfolio.
All right guys questions on this post in the group discussion.
Otherwise see in the next lecture.