All right guys, welcome back to the course.
Next up, we're going to look at back-end
languages, i.e. languages that are used
to run on the server and service the website
or web app that you're using.
Back-end languages are the unsung
heroes and bear the lion's share
of complexity when it comes to creating an application.
Someone who primarily studies and
masters these back-end languages
with a moderate knowledge of the
front-end languages we just covered
is what we traditionally will call a software engineer.
If you look at any boot camp, and it says "software engineering,"
guess what you're probably going to be learning?
It's probably a back-end web language, like PHP or Python,
or you're going to learn multipurpose languages that could work
on both websites and desktop operating systems.
These guys get paid the big bucks
and are generally the ones that focus on
difficult challenges the web team faces.
That's not to undermine the front-end work, which is difficult
in its own way, but is generally speaking less work than the back-end.
It's not uncommon that building an application takes
15 hours of work on the front-end and 80 plus on the back-end.
After all, front-end just dictates the paint that's on the house,
back-end is everything that is in the house.
All right, next lecture we're going to start
with Python, one of my favorites.
All right, see you then!