And we are back.
All right, wrapping up on our tour of need to know
back-end languages is the new kid on the block, Ruby.
Ruby, you may or may not have heard of.
It's popular, it's new, and as a result
of that, it's a bit controversial.
Let's get into a little bit about what makes it so different.
The biggest thing you need to know about Ruby is that
it was designed with one thing in mind, and that's speed.
That is most often what you hear from
people when they try to justify using it.
Inside the language system itself, it includes a lot of automation
and intuitive changes that save time for the average developer.
It's frequently touted as an app that you can learn to create
a relatively complicated application in in a very short period of time.
Whether or not this is actually true is kind of hard to say.
One thing that is true is that it's the cool new kid in town.
They just moved here and nobody knows
enough about them to know their history,
but their newness and mystery is intriguing.
Yeah, that's basically Ruby.
Ruby actually got started back in 1993, but
didn't come out and get popular until much later.
So the upsides you need to know is
that it's fast, it's new, and it's trendy.
So what exactly are the downsides?
Well, one major downside of Ruby is the size of the community.
Its newness means it had less time to gather a following.
Combine that with its popularity and demand,
and you have a recipe for some issues.
High demand, low supply means prices for Ruby developers
are often some of the highest you'll find out there.
It also means that the most people are trying to transition into it,
which means it has the largest glut of
inexperienced junior developers using it.
Very hard to get someone who has eight years of experience
using Ruby if it's really only been popular for four years.
The other downside is simply structural.
For whatever reason, it has this notoriety attached to it that
it has poor performance when used for larger and larger systems.
So what about Ruby do you actually need to know?
Well, it's designed to be fast and can theoretically
save you development time, hence its popularity.
It's relatively easy to use and setup,
and it's kind of the "in" language right now.
Etsy uses it, Airbnb uses it, Shopify uses it.
There's a strange glamour to it.
The flipside is just that it's young, which means
it's underdeveloped in its community,
and has a small pool of talent that you
can pick from if you want to use Ruby.
Some companies like Groupon used Ruby and,
because they grew so abnormally fast,
ran into immense problems hiring and scaling.
All right guys, so that's what you should know about Ruby.
Keep that in mind, and I'll see you in the next lecture!