Hey guys, welcome back.
So, in this lecture we're going to get a little bit more in depth
with the concept we learned last lecture, tech stacks.
Tech stacks, if you don't remember, or you
skipped the lecture for some reason,
are like houses, or sandwiches, or hamburgers.
They're a combination of technology that is
slammed together to make a delicious system.
On the web, we for the most part
need to make four different decisions.
Number one, an operating system, number two, a server system,
number three, a database, and number four, a back-end language.
Now, some of you out there who are more astute
than the others, might have asked yourselves
"Why is it that we don't pick a front-end language
in that stack to make our sandwich much larger?"
Well, the reason why that is, and the simple truth is that everyone
uses the same technology for the front-end,
so there's no point in specifying what it is.
Every single person or project will use HTML, CSS,
and JavaScript, there's no escaping that.
The rest of the technology process is
indeed modular and indeed does change.
So let's take a deeper peak at some of the other
common stacks and why they might be popular.
The first one we covered as an example
is an everyday household item called LAMP.
That one stood for... anyone? Anyone?
Linux, Apache, MySQL, and PHP.
This is the classic design and the go-to for people
who are just building their first application.
It's classic because it's used probably the most often.
And that's the case for a good reason.
Each piece of technology in this stack is well
supported and has been around for quite a while.
Now, the downside to that, of course, is that older means
it hasn't yet picked up on some of
the newer advances in technology
and thus could be giving up some efficiency, theoretically.
So that's a good baseline for us to understand this.
LAMP is the vanilla ice cream of technology stacks.
When in doubt, it's often the case that one opts for this classic setup.
Ok, so what might happen if, say, I have
different needs for my technology?
Well, there's lots of different scenarios, so let's explore a couple.
Let's say I'm at a big company, or I'm in an industry
that has strong concerns for things like security and compliance.
These are industries like finance, healthcare, ed tech, you know them.
Well, in this specific type of scenario, one of the
most popular stacks opted for is called WINS.
WINS, like Donald Trump wins the presidential election.
I'm going to pause the camera right now to go cry.
Yes, WINS, like you're wincing at the screen
because this is getting a little bit obscure.
Took a beat line in the politics.
Now what you can guess what WINS stands for without Googling it,
I'll give you a million dollars. I don't have a
million dollars, but I can give you some cash.
WINS stands for Windows Server, IIS Server,
.NET, and Microsoft SQL Server. D'oh.
Windows Server, in this instance, works as the
operating system, hence why it's in the first position,
the IIS Server acts as the system that routes
connections to the right information on the server.
It's often called the host, like a host
who takes you to the right table.
Remember, this is the equivalent of Apache in LAMP
.NET serves as a backend, which is a
language developed by Microsoft
and used almost exclusively in large companies, and then Microsoft
has its own version of the SQL database, which
they very creatively called Microsoft SQL.
This stack, great for big enterprises.
The focus is on security and on IP protection.
Everything in this is backed by a large for-profit company.
The downsides, well, it's slow as crap to use, it's expensive,
and you often have to train your employees on how to use it,
because there isn't a sufficient number of programmers
learning exclusively systems built by Microsoft.
Let's explore another scenario and what tech stack you might see.
What about a small scrappy startup that
has a product that needs to be cutting edge,
it needs to load extremely fast, and it needs to focus on
polish for the end user, for the best user experience.
A great example of stack for this type
of situation would be one called MEAN.
Now, I don't really expect you to understand this one,
so we're just going to kind of breeze through it,
and hopefully you pick up a little bit.
Later on, we actually have dedicated
lectures for each of these technologies,
so if it doesn't make sense now, hopefully
it will make a little bit more sense later.
MEAN stands for MongoDB, Express.js, Angular.Js, and Node.Js.
I don't know if you've ever heard this phrase before,
but it's that "JavaScript is eating the world."
The reason why people will often say
that is JavaScript is now being used
as a back-end language as well as a front-end language.
We're going to get more into this later, as we
get into more and more advanced topics,
because this concept and why it's making
huge changes, it's kind of hard to understand.
Ok, so those are the three examples of common tech stacks.
It's helpful to know at least a couple and to know that
different companies have different needs, and they're going to use
different stacks depending on different circumstances.
Pros and cons really to all of them, but it's important just to know
that there are many different ways to "skin the cat," so to speak.
All right, go yonder and pick ye technology stack.
See you in the next lecture!