Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
So, this lecture, we're going to talk about another advanced concept,
and it's called continuous integration.
All right, so you need to understand what I mean by integration, right?
Integration, especially in programming sense, refers to when
I write some code, and you write some code, how do we integrate them together?
Or how do I integrate something I've written into something
that's large and already existed, like a content management system?
Now, this is a big problem in the development world.
One of the biggest issues is that in large team environments,
even medium-sized team environments,
when you're working on an app, the basic rules of division of labor would say that
one person works on one thing, and then another person is in charge of another thing,
and then another person is in charge of another thing.
Let's say we're making a mobile app.
One person might make the home screen, the other person might
figure out how to integrate Stripe for payments, and the other person might
do something else, set up another API, let's say with Facebook.
Ok, that's all fine and dandy, but what happens at the end of the day
when you take those three things and see if they work together well?
That is what is humorously referred to as "integration hell,"
and it apparently takes up an enormous amount
of time for developers that have to do it.
If you ever had two people write a paper on the same topic,
and then you had to figure out on how you could combine the two,
it's an entirely new process in and of itself.
So one of the solutions is a concept that's called continuous integration,
and it's actually part of a system protocol that includes continuous delivery,
continuous deployment, and continuous integration.
We're going to kind of refer to it all as continuous integration.
So the idea behind continuous integration is that you make a somewhat elaborate
server setup that can automatically do these integrations for you.
The way that it solves this is by making everyone check in more often.
In the original version, one person makes something, and when it's done,
they say "Hey, it's done, let's stick it together with your other piece."
With the continuous integration, instead, you actually check in
and see if what you're making, even if it's incomplete, fits with the rest of
what everybody else is making, and what's already been made in the application.
And the way they do this from a technical perspective,
we're not going to get too detailed about this,
they set up two different servers, one is called a version control server,
and the other one is called a build server.
The idea here is that several times throughout the day,
people will take what they're working on and
stick it up into what's called a version control server.
Then, the build server is basically designed
to constantly look at the version control server
and see if the things that are being uploaded fit, see if the code executes properly,
see if there are errors, or something pops up, or there are just general issues,
and when it finds something like that, it usually will notify people immediately.
Then, when it happens, pretty much everyone stops,
and then they look at the problem, and they try to solve it.
That's infinitely better than trying to solve large problems
after everyone's built what they're trying to make,
versus check in more often when the problems are smaller.
So really the idea is just to speed up the process of development,
because it limits how long you have to spend
checking if Jimmy's code matches Timmy's code.
It's kind of a miniature project in and of itself,
and that's why a lot of places don't use it.
It's usually something that you see with larger companies.
The usual method that people use to make apps is they'll just use
a test server and a live server, so when you build something,
you put it on the test and then you just see how it operates in the wild, in a browser,
and with users, and if it works, then you move it over in batches to the live server,
which is what people see when they go to the actual URL.
So just keep that in mind.
Continuous integration is a system to make large
team development much easier and faster,
but it's not something that usually you see with smaller teams,
because it takes a lot of time to set up and operate.
There are also some other downsides to it.
A lot of people don't like to work in a start-stop, start-stop, start-stop way,
and also it kind of has this prisoner dilemma problem, where
let's say in a team of ten, and nine people are putting their code up
every single day the correct way, and one person is just not doing it.
Well, in that case, it actually defeats the whole purpose,
because still at the end of the day it's like,
"Oh man, we have to take that tenth person's stuff and integrate it
with everybody else's stuff," and you hate that tenth person.
So that's really all it is.
It's a process to speed up development for large teams, such that
you don't have to spend as much time figuring
out if people's code match other people's code,
the idea here is that it saves you money,
you can spend that money and that time you saved on other things.
All right guys, see you in the next lecture!