Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
Ok, so we know what WordPress is, we know
what Drupal is, we know what Magento is.
WordPress is the lord of the internet,
Drupal is that small weird cult with respectable technology,
and Magento is buy-buy-buy, sell-sell-sell all day.
The way those got installed is you literally download a package off the internet,
upload it to your server, and then open that package through your web browser.
The system then just runs and does the rest for you.
While that sounds nifty, and easy, and all that,
that simple set of 4-5 extra steps I just described
actually made a significant division
between the types of users that would use it.
I said "would" because anyone with the time and effort can use them,
but that extra "computer-y" sounding part was
enough to discourage large groups of people.
At this point I want to point something out.
Do you notice this trend?
First, there were no CMS's out there, and the only people playing
in the internet's sandbox were people who could teach themselves
how to program and were fine taking hours to write and upload something.
The general population in this scenario just watched from the side lines.
With the creation of the CMS, more people found creating websites accessible
and as CMS systems got simpler and more
intuitive, more and more people started using them.
So what was left to optimize? You might ask.
Well, two things happened.
One, we started seeing websites that acted
as platforms to let you create your own website,
much like something like WordPress, except that you made the site
while using their site, and everything you made was stored on their servers
and sometimes even listed directly from their domain.
Now, what do I mean by "make it on their site"?
Well, I mean their websites literally had you walk through steps
to select you site's aesthetic, font, headers, content, etc.
Now this is as opposed to just giving you a
massive administration panel to do as you please.
They were like the Apple to Microsoft.
They assumed you were dumber, and so controlled more of the process,
allowing you less ability to customize.
WordPress junkies would say "How dare they?"
"Doesn't everyone want complete control of their website?"
Well, no, and this is a lesson we learn over and over.
It's the exact lesson we learned from Linux and
the way it tried to battle with Macintosh's OS X.
The second thing we saw happening was the emergence of what we call WYSIWYG,
which is actually an acronym for What You See Is What You Get,
as in, no more were we creating our websites by selecting the size of each image
through a drop down box, or editing our site in this
hidden bunker-like system of an administration panel.
With WYSIWYG, you would build your site visually,
much like a toddler would build a building out of Legos.
You look at it, you grab what you want, and then you place it where you want.
Lastly, unlike the free CMS systems that only
charged for upgrades or special modules,
this new guard of CMS, well, they charged every
month just for the pleasure of using their service.
So if you thought WordPress is too technical or unnecessarily complicated,
which in some respects it is, then these new systems were a God send.
Now, three WYSIWYG closed system CMS systems have emerged
in the last odd 5-7 years that are worth discussing:
SquareSpace, Weebly, and Shopify.
Let's start with SquareSpace.
SquareSpace kicked off its existence much like the other new guard CMS systems,
by treating this exactly like a startup and not an open source project,
like the creators of WordPress and Drupal made their projects.
They have also raised an obscene amount of money,
and they have something like well over 600 employees.
SquareSpace is worth knowing as they decided to go
as far to the "closed - limited customization"
side of the spectrum as they possibly could.
On SquareSpace, you can create a website within a given set of templates,
and you can only edit within those templates so many different things.
Want a layout they don't offer? Tough luck.
Want to host your site, say, off of SquareSpace? No way, Jose.
Want to use a third party template for your design?
What do you think this is, a website that lets you do things?
SquareSpaces' main angle is design.
They focus all their effort and all their money
on making the prettiest looking websites they can,
because, well... what else do you care about in a website besides prettiness?
And this is very telling. They are, after all, going for people
that are either the least tech savvy of the bunch, or simply
the least willing to put large amounts of effort into customizing their site.
So, did it work?
Well, you'd have to try it out for yourself.
I will admit, they do have some very sharp looking websites,
and as long as you stay within their limited set of use cases,
you can come away with something that actually looks pretty sweet.
Now, on to the second one, Weebly.
Kind of like wobbly, weebly, I don't really know how they came up with the name.
Now, why do I introduce Weebly and, let's say, not Wix.com?
I don't know if you've ever heard of Wix.
Well, the reason why is because Wix.com is basically another SquareSpace.
Limited control over what you can do and very closed end to end system.
There's really not enough difference to point out, although I guess, though,
if you have some free time, still check them out. It's worth seeing it.
Now, Weebly sticks to the WYSIWYG paradigm religiously,
but unlike SquareSpace, it lets you have some customization control.
You can install integrations, you can install third party themes,
you can move things around a little bit more.
Like SquareSpace, it's designed to be as easy as possible to use,
and it generally targets the same group of
non-technical business owners and freelancers.
Unlike SquareSpace, they are less popular,
have raised less money, only 6-10 billion or trillion,
and they did not start out targeting businesses, like SquareSpace is doing.
They actually started off as a personal website or a personal portfolio site creator.
It wasn't until later when they started adding more and more features
that you could start using it for a whole lot more than just the site that says who I am.
But remember, its genesis story was in personal portfolios you put online.
Also unlike SquareSpace, Weebly had a bit of an ISIS problem.
Apparently, extremist Jihadists found the user interface of Weebly to be
just exactly what they needed. Very intuitive and with great customer support,
exactly what you need for warning the world about infidels.
I digress.
All right, now the last one we're going to talk about is Shopify.
If you haven't noticed from the last lecture, there is a pattern here.
People notice a need in the market for creating websites, they rush to fill it,
and in their rush they always forget about poor, poor e-commerce.
That's exactly what Shopify is for.
Shopify is the WYSIWYG, highly funded,
and limited customization version of Magento.
With Shopify you can set up a store really quickly,
and you can add all sorts of cool advanced features and integrations,
something that Magento can offer, but takes
significantly more effort to do on their platform.
Worth noting, Shopify is opening up and letting people customize more and more.
But they still operate like a drag and drop builder for a store.
And unlike Magento, Shopify takes a percentage
of your store's sales, as well as a weekly subscription.
So keep that in mind.
Shopify, again, also worth noting, is written in Ruby on Rails, also known as
that trendy language that makes you sound cool, but is actually a nightmare to hire for.
All right, that's enough talk.
In the next lectures, let's play around with some of these
so you can see in the flesh what they do.
See you then!