Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
In this lecture, we're going to talk about
two really important concepts in programming,
the concept of the development environment
and the concept of the integrated development environment.
Tricky already, I know.
Ok, so hopefully, now we have a pretty good understanding of frameworks.
They do different things depending on what
area of the application you're working on,
but in general, they are essentially a template
system that allows you to program faster.
They are usually things you install onto your server
where the rest of your code you write hangs out.
Now, there is another concept that often gets
conflated with the concept of a framework,
and that's what we call an Integrated Development Environment,
also known as an IDE.
To tackle this concept, I want to break it down a little bit.
Now, does anyone remember Adobe Dreamweaver?
It had a green logo.
You probably thought it was a generic website building application,
but in reality, and more technically, it was an IDE.
Now, integrated development environments, first of all,
are programs that programmers can use to make their applications inside of.
The concept here is very similar to, say,
a word processor, like, let's say, Microsoft Word.
If I was going to write a paper, I'd probably create it in Microsoft Word,
because it allows me to do a whole lot with that paper,
like export to different document types, spell check, it might give me a thesaurus,
it might give me dictionary lookups, it'll handle inserting images, etc.
Now, image how different the experience would be
if you just made the paper in, let's say, a raw text application like text edit.
It just takes in your text, no bells and whistles attached.
So that's exactly what an IDE does.
Programmers write their programs inside of one them,
and they provide tools that make the job a whole lot easier.
Some of the most common things you'll see in an IDE
are things like the programmatic equivalent of spell check.
So in this case it's making sure that the syntax is correct
so that it doesn't create an issue
when you actually run the program or the code.
They often have things like auto complete features to help developers
write the same lines of code over and over again,
which is something that they do constantly.
They'll usually help developers organize and structure the files
before they upload them to a web server, and in better ones,
it will help the developer even keep track of which document is new or outdated,
so essentially it will handle something called version control.
But the biggest thing, I think, that an IDE does is that
it creates an automatic development environment.
And this is hopefully where we can kind of
clear the confusion between the two concepts.
Essentially, what a development environment is is a setup on your computer,
or on a web server space, where you can write code for your program, test it,
and then automatically see how it runs for
real as if it were uploaded to a live website.
Imagine you're someone who writes books.
What tools do you think you would need to put on your desk
to be the most efficient way of writing your book?
Examples might be: pencils, pens, papers, staplers, dictionary,
and then some way of understanding how what you're doing
translates to how it would be presented in a book.
That's the most similar analogy I can think of, so you'd better like it.
Now, if you don't have a development environment already set up,
you can still write programs, because after all coding is just
text inside of a text document at the end of the day,
but you won't have any way of getting quick
feedback on whether it was made correctly,
whether it's coming out the way you thought it should, etc.
The alternative is to set up a tool that allows you to test it in the wild
and an IDE is actually a great example of that closed kind of feedback system.
So try not to conflate the two of these.
Frameworks are the template you use for
your resume, but an IDE would be Microsoft Word.
In some ways, these two things overlap in what they offer,
and sometimes the line between the two is blurry,
but from a conceptual standpoint, they're actually entirely different.
If you're curious and want to check out some IDEs, here are
some of the most popular ones worth taking a peek at.
If you're writing in a more general purpose low level language,
you might use something like Visual Studio by Microsoft.
If you're making an app for iOS, you are
definitely going to use an IDE called XCode.
Dreamweaver, believe it or not, still exists and is still used today,
although it's not, I don't think it's that popular.
Other ones you might tinker with, if you want to learn Java
or have some experience with that, look at Net Beans,
PHP Storm is something that's often popular for writing in PHP,
that one is actually popular because it
helps assist in installing frameworks into the IDE.
I know that can be confusing.
So the upside of an integrated development environment is,
well, lots of tools that can make writing
easier, and getting feedback more seamless.
Often times, entire companies will use these because
it can help share files and code between team members.
Now, what of the downsides of using this?
Well, one, they can cost money,
and they often can add a lot of extra code to your project
that doesn't really do anything or might not be entirely necessary,
this is a concept we refer to as "code bloat."
And two, you actually have to learn how to use it,
which a lot of times can take a significant amount of time,
especially when you're onboarding team members,
it's just another thing you need to understand
before you can actually produce code
to add value to the application or the organization that you're in.
All right guys, don't worry about that one,
we're not going to grill you too hard in the quizzes on that concept.
In the next couple of lecture, we're going
to cover a concept known as the API.
All right, see you then!