Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
This lecture, we're going to do a brief drive-by of how you can get out there
and learn some form of back-end development.
The idea here is that if you wanted to learn back-end development,
you either are someone who wants to do front-end design or front-end development
and be familiar with back-end, or you're trying to become a full stack,
or you're just trying to become a software engineer.
Now, you're in luck, because there are a lot of options
for learning back-end development,
it's really the stuff that has the most documentation,
it has a very long history, because it developed way before
front-end technologies kind of exploded in the last five years.
So really you just have options and options for days.
Really, my suggestion is to pick which back-end language you specifically want to learn,
and then follow a separate process for just that language.
There are different programs and different tools for each individual one,
and some are better than the other.
So how do I decide, let's say, between Python, Ruby, PHP, and let's say, Java?
Well, the first thing I would suggest doing is, if there's a specific company
you want to work for, or a specific industry that you want to work at,
go and look at the companies in the space.
Use that tool that we talked about earlier, called Built With, and see what they use.
If you want to work at AirBNB, they use Ruby, ok,
so you're going to have to know Ruby on Rails.
If you want to work at Google, you're going to need to know Python,
and if you want to work in enterprise software for like, Oracle, or Microsoft,
it's probably more helpful to know something like Java.
Past that, the way I look at it is,
Ruby is best for web development, so if you know you want to be
in web development, and you know you want to work with startups,
then I'd suggest maybe going that path.
The reason why I say startups is because Ruby is like brand new comparatively,
and so the people that have picked it up are usually going to be startups.
Big enterprise companies haven't picked up Ruby, it doesn't really make sense for them
to rework their entire systems and code base for something that's so new,
and they don't really know what the future is going to be.
So if you know you're going to be working on the web
or building web services for mobile apps, I think Ruby
is a decent opportunity, it's also great for getting a job.
Now, the way I think about Python is, well, it just kind of depends.
If you want to work for Google, obviously yes,
but if you want the flexibility of being able to program on the desktop, and the web,
and in large data sets, then I think Python is a pretty interesting way to go.
If you're not really sure if you want to be data science or a programmer,
you're going to have to go Python regardless, because either or,
you're going to have to work with one of those.
Unfortunately, if you learn like PHP or Ruby
then go to data science, you just wasted a lot of time.
Now, why would you learn PHP?
Well, PHP is probably best, the way I think of it is,
if you want to start your own thing, maybe you want to get into freelancing,
maybe you want to build something relatively quickly
and you have a limited budget, PHP is great.
PHP 7 is out now, and those of you who are watching this in the future,
I mean PHP 8, and 9, and 10, and 12, but it's really,
really improved on a lot of the complaints people have about it.
The reason why I say that is because PHP is open source, lots of people know it,
it's cheap and easy to learn, there's a lot of people out there
that will help you or tutor you for cheap, again, because it's so international,
and then, when you have to use frameworks and tools,
and things out there, for the most part, they're all free.
So that's why I suggest it for personal projects,
or people who are kind of like web freelancers.
And then the last one was Java, and Java is just largely good
if you want to work at a large company,
or if you want to work specifically on the Android platform.
Ok, so your paths for learning this are pretty wide spread.
You have books, you have online courses, you have bootcamps,
and you also have traditional college courses.
In the next lecture, we'll cover what you should do in terms of a path
if you chose one of those languages over the others.
All right, see you then!