Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
All right, this lecture, we're going to talk about
how computers send and receive information.
It's a quick lecture, let's just cruise through it.
Ok, so we know basically, on a really high level,
how a computer works to
process and store the information you give it.
How does it actually get that information it plays with,
and how does it deliver a response
is the question we're going to answer right now.
Don't worry, you'll get the answer relatively quick.
In the world of computing there are tons of
what we call computer "peripherals."
Ok, that's a term you need to know, "peripheral."
Things like monitors, keyboards, trackpads, mice, rats, etc.,
those are all peripherals.
All the stuff that's external to that beautiful
Gateway computer sitting on your desk.
We call them peripherals because they work
outside of that closed circuit
system that is your computer, outside of
the CPU and the two different types of memory.
I guess it's kind of like, you could think of it like this,
like your computer is the sun,
and the peripherals are the planets floating all the way around it.
Trust me, not all the names and labels in computer
and internet technology make any sense at all.
Now, these devices allow you to give
the computer information, and they allow
the computer to take that information,
run a process on it, and send it back.
You could open up, let's say, Minesweeper,
and start clicking your mouse.
By clicking your mouse, you are giving the computer input.
That input is essentially just information,
and with that information,
it can run a calculation, and then respond with output,
respond onto your monitor.
Great. We just saw that I clicked there and I blew up.
Good work, input - output.
Put information in, get information out.
A keyboard works pretty much the same way.
If you click A
and it says to your computer, like a Canadian, "eh".
* How's it going, eh? *
And that's really what the computer - programmer
relationship boils down to.
It should be pretty obvious at this point how this all
ties into your role potentially as a programmer.
The code you write for whatever program
or app can be thought of as simply
input that the computer receives, and then the computer
will respond by giving you a corresponding output.
Whether or not that output matches
what you intended with your input
depends on your ability as a programmer.
And whether or not computers will soon
be able to just read our minds and
program themselves, well, that's a horror story
for an entirely different course.
In the next lecture, we're going to get into
how exactly computers "chat," so to speak,
with themselves and with your periphery devices.
We're also going to talk about how The Matrix perfectly predicted
everything we experience today in life.
Stay tuned!