Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
This lecture, we're going to talk about another tech trend,
and something you really need to know about, it's called SWIFT.
Now, what SWIFT is is a relatively new programming language
that was designed by Apple specifically for their operating systems.
Now, originally, if you wanted to make something for iOS, say, like, make a mobile app,
you'd have to make it in a language called Objective C.
That was pretty much the way that it worked ever since
the iPhone came out in, like, what was it, 2004?
But the problem with Objective C, if you remember
from way back in the first couple of sections,
is that it's a low level language, which means that it's typically harder to learn,
it's often very strict, and it has a lot of constraints.
So Apple said, "Well, why don't we just make a new programming language
that's easier to learn and allows you to cut out a lot of the redundancies and code faster?"
And so Apple envisioned this bird like logo for their programming language,
and like Apple, they tried to make it fun and trendy.
So right now, we're kind of experiencing a shift.
Most iOS developers know Objective C and a lot of them are making the decision
whether or not to learn SWIFT, because you can make an app in either currently.
At the same time, people who are learning how to make mobile apps are deciding,
"Do I learn SWIFT or do I learn Objective C?"
Now, there are some upsides and downsides to SWIFT.
The upsides, and it's kind of odd, but this is how they sell it,
is that it's a safer language to use, and they mean safe by
it's easier to recover from mistakes you make in your code,
they even give you this system called playground,
which is kind of just a development environment
where you can test out your apps beforehand.
Now, most people who've made mobile apps before know that
there's plenty of tools out there that do something similarly,
but SWIFT is the first one I guess to integrate it.
They also sell it as something that's fun.
I'm assuming that it's fun because it's faster, they've found
ways to remove a lot of the repetitive work that goes into making apps.
Now, there are three things I think you should know about SWIFT,
regardless of whether or not you're going to go into mobile development.
The first is don't think of SWIFT as just something for iOS.
iOS has sister operating systems, and SWIFT is actually designed to work on all of them.
There's OS X, as in your laptop or your desktop, there's Watch OS, Apple Watch,
and there's even TV OS, for the Apple TV.
So SWIFT works on all four of these.
Another thing I want you to come away with is that Apple is doing this
because they want to accelerate the developer community
in the developer platform for their system.
In general, you see this happen a lot, if you are building a platform,
lots of people are participating, but they're hamstrung, or they're kind of being impeded
by old technology, a lot of times the company will just
take it upon themselves to create a new technology.
The last thing I want to point out is that SWIFT is supposedly really easy to learn,
but if you actually get into it, I would suggest researching it beforehand,
because from what I've been able to tell, what most people say is that actually
if you don't have experience in Objective C, learning SWIFT can be pretty difficult.
So it was supposed to be a much better version of Objective C,
but in reality, it was more or less built as an extension of it.
All right guys, that's SWIFT, it's Apple's new toy,
everybody is trying to decide whether or not to learn SWIFT
or stick with the tried and true Objective C to make things
for OS X, iOS, and the Watch, and TV operating systems.
All right, see you in the next lecture!