Hey guys welcome back to the course so this lecture I'm going to answer one of the more common questions
I get which is should I specialize in new technology such as the mean stack the stack that includes
Mongo B-B.
No.
Yes.
And one of the other one it's angular jazz.
Now I know it's tempting to think while cutting edge is what I should be learning.
Right now everybody is just blowing up about react.
It's change in the name of the game etc. etc..
I should learn that.
Here's what I'll tell you is that the technology is constantly changing and a lot of times people get
hyped up about something that doesn't pan out.
Does anybody remember cold fusion.
No of course you don't because it flopped.
Now that's not to say that react Imber and angular and all these non-relational data bases aren't a
big deal and they're not going to be around.
I'm just saying make sure you have kind of a historical view of it and I generally suggest stick with
the stuff that has persisted over time.
If you're someone who knows that they're going to go into freelancing or it's going to star web or a
mobile development studio I actually second that advice I said before the reason why.
Well there's a lot of cool technology out there.
You can learn it and it can.
For instance making more efficient at what you do.
Build things faster and you think that's obviously a benefit.
But guess what it actually the only thing that matters is what you can explain to the client.
The client doesn't know what re-act is or what it does.
They don't really care so it doesn't give you a competitive advantage to win that game you're just going
to focus on the basic skills like selling yourself explaining what you do and communicating well you
can make a studio out of some crazy new language but just don't expect people to be beating down a path
to your door because most clients just don't know what it is the time to suggest learning some of these
newer types of technologies is just if it comes down to personal preference through that type of person
that hates javascript but loves what's called Asynchronous JavaScript like node.
J Yes if that's the case then maybe you go with more modern things and the things that are cutting edge
just make sure that you're keeping up to date with what's going on because the stuff can turn on a dime.
The last thing I'll say is make sure if you're trying to get a job just keep your eyes open for changes
in the industry.
If you're someone who for some reason wants to be a database administrator it's worth paying attention
or at least learning how new databases work because we do see large shifts in that technology.
For instance Hadoop is a system that people use for big data.
While a lot of companies are moving towards using big data and so might use Hadoop so it's probably
something you should learn to at least stay with the trends.