Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
All right, so let's talk about the big bad JavaScript.
Now, this is not to be confused with Java,
which is a very popular back-end language
used largely by enterprise teams.
Of course, other companies use it,
Twitter is a good example, but it's not the same as JavaScript.
Chances are, if you've ever had some
sort of interest in programming,
you probably at some point ran into JavaScript.
And it makes sense, because every time we use a web page
and something makes you go "Oh, that was cool,"
it probably had something to do with JavaScript.
JavaScript has come a really long way,
so even having an understanding of
what JavaScript does and is is kind
of like shooting at a moving target.
A moving target that's on fire, and you're also
on fire, and the whole place is on fire,
because JavaScript is one of the most
obnoxious programming languages to learn.
Before we even get into some of
the details, let's just talk about
what JavaScript, or JS for short, does at 10,000 feet.
In three words, JavaScript is interactivity.
Say that ten times with your eyes
closed and you'll never forget it.
But then, what do I mean by interactivity?
Well, I mean clicking buttons, I mean
pages loading when you scroll,
I mean clicking a button and having it
change the page without refreshing it.
JavaScript can show or hide certain parts
of a webpage depending on the circumstance.
It can change font sizes, it can create
popups, it can create slide-ins,
it can load something onto a page
only when the user needs it,
it can even animate elements on the page.
But that's not how JavaScript obviously started,
and if you've noticed a pattern in these lectures,
I love me some history.
All right, let's teleport back sometime
into the 1990s, when people had
bowl cuts and frosted tips, and artists supported
themselves exclusively off the sales of CDs.
What's an iPod, you say? That's stupid, this is the 90s.
So at this point in our teleportation time,
websites really did only a handful of things.
They had text, images, tables, graphs, and maybe forms
where you could submit information, but that was really it.
One of the biggest problems people were
having was with the forms themselves.
If someone, let's say, submitted a form,
and they decided to use a username
that's already been used or taken by somebody else,
there was no real way, prior to JavaScript, to let them know,
"Hey, you need to pick a different username."
The solutions we had prior to JavaScript
were very clunky and heavy,
and it usually made you go back a couple
of screens to be forced to be told,
"Hey, you need to be a little more original."
With JavaScript, you could do that, and that was one of the
original functions actually that JavaScript was created for.
JavaScript, if you remember from the previous lectures, was actually
created by Netscape and the alpha nerd Marc Andreessen.
Originally, it was named, no joke, Mocha.
I'm assuming it's because Java already existed
and Cappuccino just isn't that catchy.
So, and like that, Marc Andreessen said, "We shall call it Mocha,"
which is a good name for a dog, a bad
name for a programming language.
During the browser wars, as browsers wanted to do more,
and websites wanted to get all sorts of fancy,
JavaScript was the go-to way to make the site
experience more interesting and enjoyable.
It also helped make sites run faster, because it
could do things like what we described before,
check with the database and stop the user from doing something.
The alternative, of course, was the much harder, clunky way of
sending a full query after the fact,
and done manually, which was awful.
What else do you need to know about JavaScript?
Well, one thing you need to know is
that JavaScript is quickly becoming
one of, if not the most important programming languages out there.
Later on in the course, in the tech trends section, we're going to cover
the concept of full stack JavaScript, we'll cover what that is,
and how exactly it's changing the name of the game.
In the framework section, we'll get actually
more into depth about all the technologies
that are popping up to assist JavaScript
and make it faster and more powerful.
There are so many tools designed to help JavaScript,
there's actually a term called "JavaScript exhaustion."
So here's a common question. Is JavaScript easy to learn?
Well, some people say yes, and some people say no.
Attached in the resources, we have a guide that
would argue the latter, saying that it's actually easy.
That guide is called JavaScript for Cats,
because, I guess the idea is that
JavaScript is so easy to learn that a self-interested furry mammal
with a walnut sized brain could figure it out.
Arguing in the "Yes, it's really difficult to learn" corner, actually
I've included some online discussions
in the resources, as to how difficult it is.
The most common response to the question
of "Is it hard?" you'll notice is "Kill me."
All right, got it? Next up, we're going to start looking
into back-end languages, like PHP, Ruby, and Python.
All right, see you there!