Hello everybody and welcome to this lecture where I get to introduce myself to you bit nerve wracking
because what I'll be doing is taking over the unreal remaster from Gavin who has sadly left us now.
My name is Michael some of you will recognize me already as part of game dev team especially if you've
taken any of the blender courses we've got.
However I'm slipping over to the unreal course now to help you guys really master the Unreal Engine
and C++.
So what I've been doing over the last couple of weeks is making sure I'm up to speed with where Gavin
was in the course.
I've been liaising with Daniel student instructor primarily to make sure that any questions that get
repeatedly asked are rancid in the remastered content nothing that's vital to make sure you guys have
a great learning journey and from that we've already decided to add some additional content that was
later in the course a bit earlier but in a more basic form now I'll be introducing myself again at the
Bull Cow game so I'll see you over in there and I'm really looking forward to seeing what you guys
end up making with Unreal and I really hope you enjoy the journey as you go.
Take care and I'll see you in one of those future lectures.