I'm welcome to this section where we'll be creating an arcade style tank game.
This just means that we won't be focusing on accurate physics based movements.
Rather, we'll be focusing on quick, snappy movements and providing the most player feedback.
You could think of this game as an entry that you might make for a game jam with some simple but refined
mechanics.
Game rules and a four game loop with win and lose conditions in the game.
You control a small toome tank and you're tasked with taking out all of the enemy turrets around the
level.
And this small game has been created with the focus of helping you get a much better understanding of
class inheritance, sharing logic between both player controlled and A.I. controlled pawns.
My favorite parts implementing components and effects to really bring the game to life.