Hello everybody and welcome back in this lecture we're going to talk about actors.
What is an actor.
Well any object that can be placed into your level is called an actor whether that's a light whether
that's a character whether that's a starting point for your pleasure.
These are all actors.
They all have a transform which means we can scale rotate and translates them.
And as alluded to by the fact they can be any object that's placed into your level there are several
different types of actor.
Let's dive into unreal and find out more okay.
So first of all let's have a look around our world.
I'm going to just move these handles slightly because I want to focus on the main window here but I
need these other areas especially the details area over to the right.
So let's have a look and say well let's go out and we've got lots of different things in this well there
are a lot of mesh type actors in here.
We go ahead and click on let's say a ha cow with the left mouse button.
We can see that it's a static mesh act.
I'm going to have to make this area bigger to see all of that information.
There we go.
Static mesh actor.
When we click on the player starts it's a player starts.
That's the type of actor it is.
As you can see you can have lots and lots of different types of actors.
And the thing that I want to draw your attention to in this particular lecture is the fact that you
can manipulate these in multiple ways.
The first thing we can do for instance is select one of these cows and we notice that we've already
got this gimbal over the top of it.
That's really useful.
This is the translate or move Gimbel and we can simply click and make our cow levitate or place them
on the ground etc..
And if you do want an object to snap to the ground it will snap based upon this origin point where that
white dot is and that can be activated up at the top here under the editor snapping options if we do
surface snapping we will find that now when we move our cow around it will stick to the surface and
even go up a hill.
Pretty cool being able to do that and it enables you to build up a level really really quickly.
You can also press the end key on your keyboard and suddenly your actor will snap to the ground which
is really useful but you do have to make sure there's nothing around your actor that it's going to get
stuck on as it goes down towards the ground.
Now there are other types of tools we can use so we've got our three axes that we can move our cow on
but how about rotate.
So we've got controls at the very top here right next to the snapping we can turn on rotation or scaling
and you'll notice that as you go across them we've got W E and R so you can use W E and R to change
the type of transform you're going to do.
So in this case with scaling we can make it tall on just the z axis there if we wanted to if we didn't
want that we could go control in Z and undo if we wanted to be able to scale the entire thing equally.
Then we go to the center point and then drag their click and drag and then we can have maybe a mummy
and a baby cow next to each other.
I'll leave that up to you to decide how you want to play with your level and quickly the rotation tool
as you can see here it gives us the axes in which we can move our model around and we've got some fine
snapping as it goes round there to 10 degree increments if we want to turn that off we can go at the
top here we've got a couple of options when it comes to snapping we've already played with the placement
snapping where it will snap to the ground with that toggle on which is this one here surface snapping
we've also got enables or disables snapping to a grid when dragging options around.
Now that's really really useful if you've built a set of assets that you want to slot together being
able to snap to a grid will allow that to happen really easily.
Providing of course the assets fit into that grid well and you can see here there are three toggles
depending on whether you want the snap rotation scaling or translation If we go back to rotation and
turn this toggle off we see that we can now have a much finer control if we go ahead and turn that back
on what you will notice is that it resets at zero from there onwards.
So that can be a little bit confusing if you happen to have rotated something by an amount and then
you can't get back again.
Remember you can undo and the final thing to talk about with that surface snapping there is we have
another option here to rotate to the surface normal.
Now that is generally something you'll probably want on but sometimes it might not be something.
So what that means is at the moment the cow if we go ahead and move the cow all the way over to the
Hill notice that it leans forwards as it goes up the slope and then straightens out or as it moves around
here it will lean depending on what is on now the tree for instance that might look a bit odd.
Now this is made up of two mesh objects.
So when we go ahead and move that see that it's now leaning to one side.
That may be the desired result.
Here we go on the cows head.
It's much better.
But here we go as we go up we may not want a tree to actually lean.
If that is the case then what we will do is go in here and turn off the rotate to surface normal and
then it will remain upright as you move it up a slope.
So we've played lots in the viewport itself.
And that is likely the majority of you will use these tools.
However let's not forget that we've got some very fine controls over on the details tab that transform.
If it's not open you can click on the little triangle to the left of the word transform and then we've
got options for the location rotation and scale.
We've also got a lock option here as well which is really useful so if we turn on the lock there and
then set the scaling of this tree to 10 it will scale it on all of these by 10 rather than having to
type them all in manually.
It also gives us an option to finally control where things are placed in the world.
Now you probably with this more organic scene not going to use that but with a more rigid scene perhaps
one that was based upon geometric shapes this would be incredibly useful.
And the numbers that you're seeing here are based upon the world origin.
So we set everything here at 0 0 0 0 and 0.
We'll get an idea of where the world origin is.
It's right bang here.
So the whole level as you can see here as we zoom out is based around the single world origin and that's
where all of the coordinates are based on that global or world coordinates hello it's Michael from the
future a couple of tips here which I think would be really useful for the challenges coming up.
First of all if you want to select more than one object like this tree here you will see it's made up
of two objects.
You can hold down shift as you do that when you do that make sure you are selecting the appropriate
things.
Here we go.
You'll also notice that then you're able to move things around together really useful.
And so we've got multiple trees in the background here.
Once again we can then move them all at once.
Really useful when you've got to bulk move things around and the other thing that you can do as we've
just alluded to this area over here where we've got the transform information is if you do need to copy
information of a particular transform notice you can go ahead and right click where we have location
rotation and scale.
So for instance I can copy the location of our tree so we can copy that there and then we can go ahead
and grab the cow and paste its location in and it will move across or alternatively let's say something
like the tree get separated as you'll see later on and I totally forgot that this exists because the
origin point of both the top of the tree itself and the stump are supposed to be at the same location.
What we can do is copy the location of the trunk itself.
So here we go.
Copy.
Grab the top of the tree and then paste it in.
And that rejoins the tree as it's supposed to be later on you'll see me trying to line it up manually
totally forgetting that that was even an option.
So feel free to laugh at me then anyway.
And now it's time for your challenge okay.
See your challenge is to simply edit some actors.
Try changing the transforms of your actors.
Use the viewport controls.
Get comfortable with those and also try to transform setting with in the details window as well so you're
familiar with the multiple ways that you could change an actor's transforms possibly an hour and give
vertigo Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead hop back on over into unreal and edit some actors OK.
So I think the first thing I'm going to do here is make this tree a little bit smaller again.
I've already got it locked.
I can't remember what it was inside I'm going to look at the others to point to five okay.
So that's another thing that you can do is look at the details to see what the shape and size of other
objects are as well and then that just needs to be roughly the is the danger of doing things from a
distance.
It looks like this.
If this wasn't on the ground so I'll turn on the ground snapping again which is.
So there we go.
That's definitely on the ground.
And it just needs lifting up a little.
That's interesting.
I wonder if I move this top one by accident as well at some point.
Perhaps I did but there we go.
That's everything all fixed there.
I'm going to go ahead now grab my cow and downscale it again to match this one four point four to five
four point two five.
There we go.
And I'm going to move them back right to the beginning again will make sure I grab the right area.
So I'm happy with my arrangement here I know I've not added much to the scene.
Please share any of the work that you've done over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next
lecture.