Everyone to welcome back.
So we're going to pick up straight from where we left off in the previous lecture and start implementing
our turret porn firing logic, depending on the results of a couple of checks that we've mentioned.
So back in the turret, check fire condition function.
The first thing that we want is to check whether the player pwn even exists as some of the steps laser
will need access to this function, such as checking whether it's alive.
So we made one account for this night.
That's gonna be a variable that will be stored and defined in the tank class later.
So of course, doing this without a valid reference will cause us some issues usually ending up in a
hard crash.
So just as an example, we could do something here like this where we will find a reference to the player
using the get player point function.
This is going to use a function in the U.
Gameplay Static's class and then call the get play a function that's gonna take a quick look at what
this is doing.
And the argument requirements for the get to play a pawn.
So this is a function of type, a pawn.
This is just going to return a reference to the player pawn.
If a vantage result is found, it takes in two arguments.
The first is the world context.
You object.
And just a quick Pu's here.
We've used this previously and I mistakenly thought that this is being covered in the previous section
of the course.
So something that you may see quite often, I think we've used this once or twice in the section already
is the reference to the world object.
And this can be used in many cases, which again is why you'll see it quite so often.
But basically, the world is the top level object that can represent a map or a sandbox in which the
actors and the components exist in a game.
Because as we've touched on before, objects are the highest kind of level class, but they don't have
a representation in the world, which is a little bit confusing because the world is an object and will
be kind of interchangeable using that term in a moment.
But then actors are derived from objects and they are the highest level class that actually resides
in the world.
So in this context, the world can be a kind of single persistent level or made up of multiple sublevels.
When we're using things like the level streaming features.
But the important thing here is the concept of the word itself and not so much how they work.
And then because the world, like I've just said, is an object and objects don't exist in the world,
which is the confusing bit here because of the use of the same term.
But it just means that in the game they don't have a kind of physical presence as such.
So this means that with an unable to do things like spawning actors or returning references from them,
unless they're provided a context actor that exists in the game or again, that exists in the world.
And that's what this first argument is actually doing.
And humbling.
It's providing a context actor to the world object.
And that's why you'll often see this being provided as the argument as we can just directly pass a reference
to whichever actor class a world context function is being called from.
So just wanted to go back and kind of highlight that here, as you will see it very, very often.
And that's what it means.
Why would usually just going to see it being passed in the argument of this, as we always going to
be calling this usually from an actor class.
So we're just passing in our own reference as that world context.
So moving on, the second argument is the player index.
And this is used to track the number of players.
And we can then use that to pull information on a specific player pwn using functions like this.
So in a single play, a game like ours is a zero based number system.
So passing in the argument of zero will be what we need in a multiplayer game.
This would allow you to send queries about specific players based on that given index.
So back over in the head of file, we can pass this as the you object world context argument and zero
to check the first player point the you game play static's is accessible because we didn't quite get
to including this section previously as the previous lecture ended up being quite long.
But we had already included our Kismet gameplay static's include.
So that was ready for us to use now.
So now that we have a check, which will be false if this function returns, no.
Whilst this isn't the most expensive check, especially in C++, it's just another performance that
we don't really need every X amount of second.
And besides that, we also know that we have a few benefits of making a fairly strict single play a
game in that the pawn will always exist and be created immediately by the game mode as well as this.
We already know that we're going to be needing to reference some variables in the tank class later.
So we again, kind of future planning here.
So instead, what we can do is store another reference in the head of file.
This will be of type A porn tank.
So we'll need to forward declare this as well as.
This class won't know what the custom class that we've created.
It's and then in the private section, as we won't need this outside of the C++ code, again, we can
just create a pointer to the A porn tank class named player PWN.
Then back in the Cartwell in the begin play.
We're going to set this variable by using something called a cast and this will be a cast to the.
A porn tank class.
The casting is something you'll see quite a lot, especially when it comes to cross class communication.
And this just allows us to convert a provided a type to another using the built reflection system in
the unreal engine.
For example, here we'll be passing in a generic porn class.
So a pool, which is, of course, the bass class of all control of all classes.
And then we'll be converting this to check whether it is not only a porn, but that it's a type of a
porn tank class.
And that's what then allows us to access any exposed tank specific functionality, because we then have
a reference to not just the porn, but the specific tank version that we've built.
So it's got this working.
We want to say that our player porn is going to be equal to a cast to the A porn tank class.
We don't need to provide the player porn to convert.
And remember, we already have that in our check.
Fire condition.
So we can actually just cut everything apart from the F statement here and paste that after our cast.
So this is now finding the A porn class returned from the Player Zero Index and storing this as a tank
class four years later.
So because we've stored this variable as a method variable means we have access to that everywhere in
this class.
We've now found and stored a reference to our player.
So we can I use this as the check in the check via condition.
So we'll just ensure that nothing else in this function triggers if we don't have a valid reference
to the player saying F isn't player porn.
Then return.
Or another way to look at this in kind of more normal speak is if the player isn't valid, then return.
As I mentioned before, we don't yet have anything to check whether or not the player is alive.
So, again, we're just gonna keep that in mind and come back to that a little bit later.
So the next thing that we do want to do, though, is calculate the distance between the target and
the player point in the world.
So we'll go back to our header and declare another function to handle this.
Just gonna tidy this up a little bit as well by keeping all of the variables together, followed by
the functions below that.
So just moving around the code a little bit.
And the next function will be of type float.
And we'll call this one return distance to player and then implement this function as usual, using
the shortcut.
And to start the function, I'm just going to copy that f check from our check via condition, paste
that in here and change the return value to zero just because we need to return a flight value here,
even if we fail to process anything.
We technically shouldn't ever need to use this.
But just to ensure that we don't have any situations that allows the player validity Czech in the Czech
fire condition to pass.
And then, for whatever reason, fell on the next frame in here.
We'll just include this double check to avoid any potential hard crashes.
Then as long as we have a valid player reference, we will create a temporary flight named Distance
and to get the distance between two actors.
We're going to use a fairly standard calculation in the math library.
That's already provided for us when we're using effectors.
And that is the DST function.
This just provides the distance between the two vectors that will be providing at the moment, and it
returns the site as a flight value.
So the two vector points that we want to find will be the distance between our target and our tank.
So for the tank, we already have our reference, which means we can use the play a porn reference that
we've stored and then call the get actor location to return its vector coordinates in WorldSpace.
Then after a comma, this function just takes in, like said, the two vector parameters separated by
the comma and it would all of the math with these two behind the scenes.
So the next thing we want is the location of the turrets.
And we can do that by calling the get active location function directly multiple pass in the location
of the current target.
And then finally, we can just return that distance value.
And in fact, looking at this night, we can simplify this so we can just cut out the creation of the
variable here and just return the result of our distance calculation, pretty much the same thing.
Just one last line of code.
And this is just because if we look at this, this is kind of the end of the function.
We won't be using our distance value again.
This might have made sense to create this if we were doing some further checks with the distance.
But as this is going to be a very simple function, we can just cut some of the extra code.
So now, because we have defined this as a function, returning a flight value, we can use this directly
in our distance check statement, back in the check fire condition.
And we just want to check if this is less than or equal to a given range.
So, as usual, we're not going to create any magic numbers here.
We'll go straight back into the had a file and create a new variable to very precisely show what this
is representing.
So I'm just gonna copy the file rate flight, including the property as well.
We want this to be exposed in the same way.
Two lines to, again, quickly update and check different ranges in the editor to see which one feels
good.
I'll give this the name of fire range and then set the default range to 500 units and back in the check
fire condition one last time.
We can check whether the distance to the player is less than or equal to our firing range or fire range.
If it is, then of course we can fire as we don't have any functionality for that because we already
kind of considered this.
And this is going to be something in the pawn base that will be adding later.
I'll just leave a comment here and add a debug log just to check that our functionality is working as
we've added quite a lot of code over the last two lectures.
So it's check that logic.
I'm just going to move the log into the F statement and I'll change the text to fire condition success.
And one final thing is that I think I've forgotten to include the PWN tank at the top of the code file.
So let's go back up there.
So that's going to be include point tank dot h.
As we are already kind of storing references that we will need that.
And with that done, I think that should be everything.
So if we go back over and open the other to make sure that this compiles and then we can check our implementation.
Also remember that if you've been following along, going from one lecture straight to the next and
you haven't restarted, you're gonna need to do that anyway just to get this new class refreshed in
the project because of that small completion issue we had previously.
So I've already done that between lectures.
So I have that.
You can see that my porn star is now appearing in the ED.
The compilation has been successful.
And before testing anything out, we actually need to go in to our TAAT blueprint and change this to
derive from the target C++ class as currently.
If you remember, this is going to stop using the base class.
And of course, this doesn't have any of our check fire functionality.
So here's a small challenge for you just to make sure that the process is still fresh in mind.
From what when we made our tank class changes inside of the turret blueprint just change the parent
class to use the point art C++ class, pause the video and give that one to go.
This is really just to make sure that you have remembered the button locations.
So we can do this by going to the class settings tab, which is the main part of the challenge here.
Use the pawn class, drop down to the side, and then just search for the pawn turret.
With that done, we can go back to our map.
Be sure to drag in at least one turret blueprint into the level and press play to give that test.
And there we go.
So if we look into the output log, we can now see that every two seconds we're being fired at.
And when we leave the range of fire, that functionality will stop.
We can also grab our turret pawn and we can change and test some of these values and add something like
an update the fire rates and increase the firing ranges to something larger, too.
So as you can see, I have made an absolutely impossible enemy to defeat making the firing at an increased
range and also doing that every point one of a second.
So play around of these values, find something fun or something you think might work really well for
the implementation in the full game when we have the full firing functionality ready.