Okay, so to finalize our level creation, we're going to play with the landscape itself.
Let's make the viewport slightly larger.
And let's zoom out.
So you may want to adjust both the look, these textures applied these materials on the surface.
Or you might want to put another hill in.
Let's see how you'd go about that.
So over in the mode's tap, in the Mode's window, for those of you using a version of Unreal since
four point two five, you'll notice that the Mode's pain is no longer here.
Over on the left, by default, it's now on the taskbar.
So you click on modes here and then you can use the different options here to select landscape, et
cetera.
And that gives you a new tab over here on the left.
We've got a series of options along the top and now that's that's open.
You probably guessed we want the landscape option, which we can see there.
The shortcut key for is shift three.
If we go ahead, click on that.
We have a series of options.
We've got Manege sculpt and paint.
Let's start off with the sculpting itself.
So let's zoom out ever so slightly, move around.
Let's use this area over here to practice then, because it's a bit of dead space, as it were.
Now, it's often the case that a lot of levels that you work on will have an artificial wall around
them.
And you can do that with a mountain range or something along those lines.
At the moment, you can see as we go over the top, we have this brush.
It has a main area and then a fall off to it as well.
So it's not jarring as we start moving and we can see here under the brush settings, we've got a size
and fall off if we change the size of the full office.
Can't can't really do it there.
But you can see as if I set the brush fall off to one.
It's a very, very, very gentle hell that it will create.
We set that down to zero, will end up with a much harsher transition, more like a plateau.
Now, of course, the brush size is rather large at the moment.
That's absolutely fine whilst we're playing around.
We do have other options as well.
We've got the strength of the brush is set to point three.
And that basically means that as we start changing the landscape, as you can see here, is only moving
a little bit with every click.
We start moving the mouse around.
We do get some additional landscape forming.
That's pretty cool shape.
I've just made that.
If we turn that all the way up to one, you'll get rapid transition and very quickly see, you will
have to watch out for that.
Of course.
How do you go about undoing this?
Say we've made it to two and we want to shrink it down a little, but without just undoing everything,
which could be a bit too much to do.
So we can redo any undo with control and why there was some programs you may be used to control Shift
and Z.
But in this case, it's control and why?
We'll bring that back.
So with the strength set to one.
Anything that I try and do is going to be very rapid.
So let's bring that back down to the point three.
So you can both drag your mouse around here or type in the value that you want and press enter.
Now we can hold down shift and it will do the opposite of what it's currently being doing, which is
really useful.
We can then change the landscape backwards and forwards to get the overall form that we want.
You'll notice at the top here, we do have some slightly different tools at the moment.
We're using the sculpting so we can go through and flatten or smooth out.
So we've ended up with a lot of jarring geometry here where the landscape is.
We could come in and smooth that out.
And there we go.
It it's a lot easier to follow around now and it's very easy to get very carried away with this and
really start enjoying the process of making our world.
But before I get too carried away with the sculpting tools, I want to introduce you to the painting
tools.
So you probably guessed where this is going to do.
It's gonna give us a series of options in terms of what this is going to look like.
So we've got a couple of layers, a couple of layers that we can paint onto our world.
And we can see quite clearly we've got our path material running through.
We've got grass and we've also got this beach colour so we can add some warn areas in as well.
So we can carry on the path if we wanted to.
Not with this size brush, though.
Let's make that smaller, maybe 300 or so so we can just come in and let's say the path goes down there,
maybe want to make that's a little larger and strength.
This might be one way you do want it to be 100 percent for the first run.
So you can really define where the actual path is and then maybe come back later with a lighter brush
and come in and make things just a little bit smoother as we go round.
Now, of course, this is entirely up to you, how you end up making your world look.
It's a lot of fun to start playing with things.
We can see here that we had shaders compiling for a moment.
So this area of landscape just disappeared.
Don't fret if that happens.
I'm also going to turn my brush, fall off a bit higher as well, which is going to give me a much softer
edge.
So we can have a Sandy area there as well, and I can add a bit of grass in as we go back.
Perfect.
You may also notice that the path itself has these mesh items placed on top of it as well.
And you already know how to do that.
So there we go.
That's pretty much everything you're going to need to know in order to make this world your own.
And one thing I do want to cover just before your challenge, if we go ahead back to sculpt mode and
go to where we've already got something on the ground.
Let's have a look at this tree just here.
If we decide to raise up so let's go not to the smooth tile, but back to sculpt if we decide to raise
up the ground.
Notice that the assets that was on the ground get swallowed up.
In fact, we could swallow up the cow quite easily.
This is a problem, of course.
And why you need to be careful about making sure your landscape is what you roughly want it to be first.
Otherwise, you may end up burying a ton of assets unnecessarily.
So I'm going to undo that for the moment.
Let's say we did put a little bit of a mound here.
What we can then go ahead and do is place the tree back on top of it.
And to do that, we will need to switch back to the place or shift one.
Once we've got that tall, I'm going to shift select the tree and then making sure that we have surface
snapping turned on.
It won't take long if we grab the little ball here to snap it to the surface.
And you can see the moment I've done that has separated the top here.
They've got different origins by the look of it.
So I can put that back on top.
And then we've got our cow as well.
Now, this is perhaps where you do want rotate the surface normal because a cow might be stood on on
the top just up here or even looking down the slope like that.
Let's go ahead and press play to make sure things make sense now because I've moved my interface around
a little play no longer exists up here.
We have to go to the double Chevron at the end and then we can hit the play button.
Alternatively, you can get used to using the shortcut key OLT and P, and there we go.
We can see here that with a wider frame, it's going to look roughly like that.
So we can set things up based upon how we're starting.
And of course, looks a bit more closely if we were setting the player start.
Not so close to the sign.
And now it's time for your challenge.
And the challenge is to make the world your own.
So edit the landscape, add some additional actors.
Those are the two main things that you can do in this particular case.
And most importantly, I'd like you to have fun.
You should find yourself much more comfortable in Unreal now that we've been playing with the interface
and the level itself.
And that's really important because then you're not focused on how do I use this thing when it comes
to the coding, which we're going to be diving into really soon.
So once you've gone ahead and made the world your own.
I'd like you to share some screenshots of the level that you've created over in the discussions.
Pause video.
Now make the world your own, and I'll see you all in the next lecture.