Hello and welcome in this lecture, we are going to be sorting out the angle of our BLENDE space, hooking
that up to our game play.
And in the process, we got to learn a lot of maths, a lot of transforms and vectors.
So let's dive in and figure out how that works.
OK, so we want to be able to get the angle at which we should be moving.
However, before we do that, we need to do a little bit of maths because we want to understand how
we can get this angle, which is local to the player.
And I'll explain why that what I mean by local and global and how we can get that from a global velocity
and what those terms mean anyway.
So let's have a look.
First of all, we need to have a bit of a basic primer on transforms and what transforms.
We've seen them or you have seen them a little bit before.
When you look at any of the seen components that these ones in the hierarchy, you can see they have
a transform.
Here's the location, rotation, scale properties.
That's basically what a transform is.
But one thing that you're not seeing here is that also part of this transform is the fact that these
same components are in a hierarchy, meaning that the transform also has a parent or, you know, basically
hierarchical.
So how does that work?
Well, here's a kind of toy example.
We've got the cube here, which is our base.
It's the center of our world or something.
And so that's gonna be our world space.
We've got this character here, the little smiley face, and he's got a position in the world relative
to his home base.
And then this character has a gun and the gun has a position relative to the character.
So the way this hierarchy works is that the parents of the gun is the character.
The parents of the character is his home base or the world.
And then we have some local coordinate systems within these.
So the worlds coordinate system is the the world system, the global system.
Then the coordinates of our character are then local to its position.
So the gun is positioned relative to its character.
What does that mean?
That means that if the character decides to go off on a little escapade, then the gun moves with it
because the position of the gun relative to the character has remained the same.
But because the character has moved, its position in the world has moved.
Same happens with rotation.
Here, the character turns around.
The gun must turn around as well.
That's how transforms work, essentially has also scale.
But we're not going to look at scale.
It's the same, but it's it's just complicating things.
And we don't need to do.
Have a look at that's not relevant to us.
So let's have a look, a different look at this.
We've got global space and local space.
So the global space has the base at the center of the world and the character has gone off.
And to the right, the local space, on the other hand, sees things in the opposite light.
It says that the character is the center of the world and that the base has gone over to the left,
has gone backwards.
You know, that's the difference between global and local.
It all depends on your point of view.
Everything is relative.
So this is what we mean when we talk about transforming between global and local space.
And which one are we interested in?
For our angle, we're interested in a local angle relative to where the player is looking.
We're saying, you know, are we moving over to the right?
That's what we're saying, that not globally, but locally.
Are we moving to the right locally to our player?
Because I favor players turned around 180 degrees.
He shouldn't play a left animation just because he turned around.
So one more important distinction is how we do transformations for vectors of different sorts.
The first example I want to look at is a position vector.
So a position vector basically is a vector that gives us the difference between the current location
or the zero point in our coordinate system, which, when we are focused on the character, is the character
himself.
And then it gives us an arrow that points to where something should be.
So in this case, it is the gun location vector.
Now, if we transform this in that to our worldspace, this is what happens.
The arrow now points from the center of our new world, the global space.
And it points to the gun.
So that's what happens if you transform a position vector.
Now, if you do a direction vector, things look a little bit different.
A direction vector is one that says this is the way I should point, not necessarily where a thing is.
And this transforms rather differently because we now aren't interested in it pointing to the same location.
So that position doesn't really get updated.
Instead, it get the fact to get some rotated and scaled or whatever it is.
And we end up with it looking a little bit like this.
So that's actually the kind of transfer.
Motion that we want to be doing because we're dealing with a velocity, which is a direction vector
rather than a position vector.
Velocity doesn't tell us anything about where we should be.
It tells us about what direction we should be going in and how fast we should be going in that direction.
So with that theory out of the way, let's go ahead and calculate our direction from this velocity.
So we know the velocity is in the global space.
And we want to convert it to local space.
Now, that means that, generally speaking, we're always trying to do things the other way round,
usually because we're saying, well, we've got the position, the local position of a gun.
It's local transform.
We want to figure out what it is in WorldSpace so that we can render it relative to everything else.
Now, that's not what we're trying to do here.
We're trying to do the opposite.
So what we actually want is called an inverse transform.
The transform goes this way from local to global.
The inverse transform goes from global to local.
So because we've got this global velocity, we want to inverse transforms.
Let's take off here and look for inverse transform.
And you can see that we've got these two options.
We don't care about these matrix ones.
We've got the two options of four direction and location.
And as I said, the difference is that a location will move that position around.
The direction is just going to apply the rotation and scale.
So we want the direction.
We need a transformer to rotate it by, we're gonna have to get that transform of the pawn itself of
the character, where is that pawn in the world?
So let's go ahead and grab off the pawn owner and look for the transform.
Property get actor transformed, that would be the one.
We'll pipe that into our inversed transform direction.
And we've got ourselves a new vector out of this.
So the next step would be to get the rotation of this vector.
So we're looking to look for rotation.
See what we can find.
We've got fine look rotation, make rotation axes to Kitani on.
Now let's have a look at rotation from X vector.
If you read the documentation here, it says it's going to set the yaw and pitch from this vector,
but it won't set the roll because it can't get that information from a vector.
That's fine.
We don't care about the role in this case.
All we care about is the yaw because we want to see how far we turn to the right or left.
So rotation from X vector, that's the one that we want.
It's going to return.
It's a rotator.
And for us to get just the you're from that rotates.
We're going to right.
Click on the pen and hit split struct pen.
She goes ahead and splits that struct into this role pitch and your.
You could do that on a vector as well by the way.
I think you can.
Right.
Click and let's see.
I think I'd have to break the link to do it so I'm not going to show you.
But basically we've now got our your here.
And that's what we want to set.
So again, many challenge set up the yaw to be the angle and test it out.
So, again, many challenge set up the your to be our angle variable that goes into the BLENDE space
and test it out, try it out in the game and see if you're able to run around successfully.
Kay, welcome back.
So we're going to drag in again our angle variable set angle, going to set the angle from the your.
And we're going to get the execution pin from the end of speed in a compile and save.
That's and we're going to go over to the sandbox and hit play.
And now let's try moving around a controller would be ideal so you can test out the different gradients
and that nuance says and sure enough, you can see if I start moving around now, I'm able to move backwards.
I'm able to move forward, sprinting and sideways and 45 degrees.
All of that works based on the maths that we've calculated to calculate our angle.
Great stuff.
So we've learned a lot about transforms and vectors and how you can transform vectors.
Both inverse and forward transforming.
And in the next act, you're going to look at fixing this foot sliding that we are seeing here.
I'll see you there.