In this lecture, we'll be seeing how these child classes will implement the functions that we've already
defined in the parent class.
So let's start with a function we can actually test.
And that's the rotate starts.
We already have pretty much everything we need in the game to track a target.
And remember, we'll be implementing this function in the base class.
So in the rotate target function, we can start working with some of the variables we're ready have
available and we need a few to go along with these.
The first device will be a new effort later named TAAT rotation, which will be the value that we need
to pass into the set world rotation function to make the target match rotate towards the target to fill
this volume.
We'll use another function find in the result of a vector calculation called rotation, which returns
an effort to value together rotation.
We're just going to take two vectors away from each other.
And we already have those available, which will be the look at target, which is ready being passed
in.
However, we will want to make some alterations to this value to avoid weird kind of taat rotation behaviors.
And make sure that we're only rotating around the turret and not up or down.
So we can do this by creating a new F vector and filling it with the X and the Y of the look at target
axis.
So that's gonna be look at Target X.
And look at Target Y.
Which is just extracting those flight values from the vector.
We already have them because it's going to be the Z axis that we want to keep in place.
We're just going to use the turret mesh, get component, get location Z, because that's something
which will not be changing on either the tanks or the turret classes.
We don't want to take this away from a second vector location and that, of course, will be our own
location.
So to ensure that we get these same Z location as used in the first part of the equation, we want to
use the TARP mash, get component location as our second vector, because remember, we're getting the
Z axis of the component location in the first part of the calculation, which is the Z axis height of
the turret MASH component specifically.
So if we get the entire same thing for our second part of the calculation, we're still using the same
Z axis there as well.
So we now have our calculation.
However, this is getting a little bit long and cumbersome to look at.
So if we just jump back up a couple of lines and we can improve the readability here, we'll do this
by creating two new effectors.
The first one.
Our name.
Look at Target cleaned because we're essentially just taking the look at Target, which is we're being
passed in and we're cleaning this to kind of account for the weird rotation things that I mentioned
could happen if we allow it to rotate around the the roll in that we don't want as we just want it to
go around and follow horizontally only.
So this will be equal to a new effector.
And for this, we can just cut and paste our first part of the calculation and we'll paste that just
here.
So that's our cleaned up version of the look at target value to ensure that we're only going to be looking
at the X and Y values on the plane whilst using the turret mesh components application for these Z here.
Then for our second vector, we'll name this one start location and this will be the second part of
the calculation.
So again, I'll just grab the target match, get component location.
With our two new effectors, we can fill in the f vector argument we had previously with the same values,
but just taking up much less space and this will be much easier to read.
What's happening when we come back to see the rotation details.
So here we're getting the look at target cleaned minus the start location of the turret.
So at the moment, of course, we're just getting the direction to look at as a value.
We don't need to actually use this value and apply this to drive the rotation of the turret match.
So to finish this off, we're just going to say that the TARP match set world rotation and passing the
turret to rotation value and that's it.
So actually, quite easy once you have the math and the calculations them and we have our turrets now
ready to rotate around.
So let's start them by using this in our turret class.
We'll use a similar check to what we've done previously to ensure that we have a valid reference to
the play A Pawn.
And also that we're in range.
This is what we'll be doing in the tech function, we can then return out of this.
If those requirements are not met, then we can use our function to rotate and look at the players location.
So here's a quick challenge for you.
Call the rotate turret function in the tech event and provide the location of the player as the argument
suppose video here and give this one to go.
Okay.
So this is no different than calling any other function that we have before than we already have our
reference to the plane as well, which is our play, a pawn.
And all we want to do is use a function again that we've seen before, and that is the get active location.
That's gonna be the value that we want to look at.
We can also make another quick change here.
What I'm going to do is cut the unroll, log from the fire, check in the if statement here, and then
we'll just replace that with the fire function from the pawn base class.
So, again, this is just cooling the base class fire function, which at the moment won't be doing
anything, which is why we have our log.
So we go back over to the base class and I will paste this into the fire function so that we don't have
our projectile.
We can at least check if this function is being cooled correctly.
With that done, we can compile and start checking if the target class is working correctly.
Now, I've just run my compiler and come back with an R, and that is that I must have just been typing
what I was saying.
And I've typed and implemented a function named rotate taat function, so I'll just go and change that
to rotate turrets in the header file.
And also the code file implementation.
And I've also missed the brackets on the get to component location function.
This is just the function code inside of the rotate turret function.
As you can see just here.
So I'll add those in as well.
With that corrected and the game compiled.
We can now see that the fire function is still working as we we'd have hoped.
Even though we've moved that log over to the base class and of course, the PWN tart's is tracking to
play a movement, as long as we're in range, you can see that moving and rotating around.
And then when I leave the range, I'll stop back in the hour ahead.
We're also going to see how to declare the final function and override it.
So to begin, we're going to use the virtual void again before creating the handle destruction function
name.
This time, no rules are going to add our override, specify to the end of this to confirm that this
will be a function expecting to override a function from the base class.
We don't need to implement this or use the C++ helper shortcuts again.
We then call the super function on the handle destruction function in the taht code file, which will
ensure that we enter the parent function, call first, run through the effects logic before returning
to the child class and performing the overridden logic, which in this case will just be to cool the
destroy function for now.
So we won't be able to see our handle destruction for a little while.
So let's go back over to the tank class and make our implementations for the functions that two.
First, we can implement the handle destruction function.
I'm just going to leave a small comment here as we don't have anything at all that we can do right now.
But we should probably drop the hiding logic into its own functions.
So I'll make a comment to that effect to remind us to do that a little bit later.
And, of course, remembering to include the supercooled to the parent function class as well, because
like I've said before, we want to make sure that our tank also plays the destruction effects, such
as the signs and particles.
So for the platform, we'll start this time by implementing the fire function in the set up a player
input component function.
We want to create a new player input component binding.
But this time is going to be of type BINDE action.
So the axis bindings that we've used before, we run constantly and used for things that can provide
at different values between a range of zero and one or minus one.
Usually this would be things for accounting for incremental changes that might be held over time, such
as movement input actions are just single press events or inputs returning a state of either being pressed
or released.
And they usually use for situations such as interaction, presses jumping and in a situation firing.
So we're going to be binding this to the fire input in the same way that we did with the axis bindings
by providing the name of the button referenced in the project settings.
And this is where it gets a little bit different in the next pot as well.
So assigning this to happen when the button is pressed using the IHI underscore, pressed for the input
event whether we won't be using it.
Just to note that we can also get other events such as IEEE Unreleased, which is when the button is
released.
And a common scenario for using both of these would be for control schemes where you might hold C to
crunch.
You'd then bind one of the functionalities to the I'I underscore press event for the crouching down
portion of the logic.
And then you'd assign another set of logic to be called when the I'I underscore released has been called
to return the player from the crouching position.
So you can see in this quick example I've just presented, both are still assigned to our imaginary
cracked binding, which would be the one that you'd see in the project's settings.
So this is the button assignment.
But two different functions would then be called to handle the crouching state changes depending on
the button state.
That's just an example.
As I just say, that you're aware of how this can be used.
But again, this the classes that we have don't really have a need for such thing.
So I'm just going to remove that example as I can't see much use for a crouching tank right now.
So back to our fire binding.
We then need a reference to the context class, which is this.
And finally, we're going to use the address of the AP and tank and call the fire function when the
fire input is pressed.
So for the tank turret rotation, we want to use the hit result under cursor on the player controller
as this is something else that we're going to want to do on the tick event.
We'll head over to the head of file and declare a player control controller reference, making this
a method variable so that we can access this anywhere throughout the class to allow us to store and
save this reference rather than repeatedly finding it in the event take later.
So this is going to be a pointer to the A play a controller class and we'll name this one player controller
ref.
Then in the code, fall on the begin play.
We just saw a reference here by casting to the A play a controller.
And using the get control to function.
This is very similar to the cast functionality that we've seen before, but this time we're doing it
to find the active player controller that's been created by the world to handle the play porn and storing
that as our player controller RF.
We'll be looking more at the play a controller class in its own topic a little bit later as this is
kind of a topic unto itself.
But just know that this kind of controls the general possession, the status of the player porn, how
the class is possessed and things based around that sort of functionality in the tech function.
We'll want to check to ensure that we have a valid player controller reference.
If we do, then we can call the get hit result under Curser from the player control class.
This is just going to essentially trace from the location on the screen where the cursor is currently
detected into the WorldSpace and find the resulting location that that casts would happen.
So it's just kind of beaming into the world and giving us some real world space coordinates, which
we're going to use as the location of where we want the target to face towards.
So for this, we have a few different arguments.
The first thing is the trace channels.
And for this one, we'll be using the visibility channel to trace on.
The next thing is the type of collision checks it should be doing.
We've got the option between complex and simple collisions is asking if we want this to do complex tracing,
which we won't need for this.
So we can set this to folks as complex tracing is more for things like specific limbs or sub meshes
on the classes that we want to check against for collision, which might wrap cleanly around a mesh
we're using of a simple collision set up, specifically using our capsule component.
So we won't need that complex tracing.
And then finally, we're going to need an F hit result two years later.
And this is what I was kind of describing a moment ago, where the trace that we're doing into the world
will return a lot of different variables.
So it's going to jump up a line and create this one night.
So, as I said, it's a type of F hit result.
And we'll just name ours trace hit result.
This is going to store information about where the cursor has traced in the world, such as the hit
location, the normal's the rotation, the actor that is hit.
And much more.
We can bypass this in as the final argument for the function.
We don't need a new F vector named hit location, which we'll find from any trace hit results that we've
just filled from our function that we want to find at the impact point.
So this will be the location in the world that the trace has hit.
And that is going to be the end location that we want our tank target to look at.
Finally, like we did with the porn tarts, we can call the rotate taat function and just fill in the
vector parameter with how a calculated hit result.
And again, because the apparent class is accounting for the vertical rotation.
We don't need to worry about anything here just providing the effective results and we're good to go.
Otherwise, if you think about what's happening, the net result is going to be looking at things like
the.
It will possibly be tracing underneath where the tank is.
If you're tracing to the floor, if you hit a wall, then it might be higher than the tank.
And again, if we weren't making that Z offset in our calculation, then we'd have the tank turret trying
to look up and down to either face the floor or the wall or anything that might be in the way in the
world around that.
So if we head over to the editor and compile, we should now have the tank top rotation and the fire
functionality work.
And we can see here they are just press play, and every time I click, I'm getting the fire function
being called and we can see that the rotation is working almost as intended.
So the tank, it does rotate to find the mice.
The current rotation, though, does feel a little bit off, but we're going to be addressing that with
some tweaks to the player control class later in the section.
So is that done?
That is the PWN class is mostly implemented by the technical parts of the functions that are working,
and we just need to create some extra classes for the more visual aspects of the game.