Hello everybody and welcome back.
Now when it comes to setting up your idea with an unreal.
If you're working from the default settings then Visual Studio community will already have been set
up for you.
However we're using v s code for cross system compatibility.
Now we can see what the current one is straight away if we go to file and where we have generators.
We've then got Visual Studio project.
I don't want to use Visual Studio projects.
I want to use Visual Studio code how do we go ahead and change that.
Well what we need to do is go to the next menu along the Edit menu and go down to edit editor preferences.
Once we've gone ahead and done that we can go to the source code area on the left hand side.
When we've done that we have a dropdown it's a nice simple one to work with.
We click on that and we get a list and here we can see Visual Studio code.
Select that you will notice that a restart is required.
So let's go ahead click restart now and we've got to save.
So let's go ahead and save.
I'll take a few seconds to reopen the project and what we should then see when we go to file is the
fact that we can generate a visual studio code project.
So the editor preferences have opened up once again that's closed those down go to file and yes look
generate Visual Studio code projects.
Perfect.
Now before I go ahead and do that let's have a look at my file system and we'll see what's being generated
when we do that.
Okay.
So we have here the file system.
Look at what it looks like at the moment.
Looks good.
If we go ahead and go file generate visual studio projects this may take a few moments to do.
But what unreal is doing is setting everything up.
So it's ready to work and we can see it added here bull Cal game Doc code dash workspace.
Now this is something that's unreal can generate to any point which is useful.
So we're not going to open it up through this method.
What we are going to do is go to file and then we can open visual studio code.
So let's go ahead and click on open Visual Studio code.
What we should then say I've got the welcome screen here I'm going to toggle off show the welcome page
on starts up and then close down the welcome.
Now if you don't see this hierarchy here on the left you may need to open up source Volkow game and
inside there will have these files the ones where you're going to be focusing on mainly the ball cap
cartridge C.P. and the ball cowl cartridge Doc H.
And we can go ahead and single click on bulk how cartridge the H.
The head of files now load it up and also the bulk cartridge CBP.
Now you'll notice here that as we click on them they just open up.
But what we can do is then double click on CBP and double click on H and then they're all open up the
two files individually.
So we've got the C++ file ready to type our code into really exciting was so close to getting there.
And also the header file as well.
Now this will be a bit overwhelming if you've never seen this type of code before.
But what we have here is just the basics of making sure that the terminal within the game works as we
expect it to and don't be scared because by the end of this section we'll be able to understand exactly
what's going on within this file itself.
So there we go.
We've got visual studio code all set up to work with unreal.
Now if you've just been watching I've got a challenge for you.
So your challenge I'd like you to get your I.D. set up so set up your I.D. as the default editor in
I'm real.
Now you may choose to stick with Visual Studio code or if you're on the Mac you may be using x code.
It's entirely up to you which I the use but I'd like you to set up your idea as the default editor in
Unreal Engine 4.
And then once that's done make sure you can open up the bulk cartridge dot H.
The header file and the bulk cartridge dot CPB are main code.
Now I've already got mine set up.
I hope you have as well.
And then we can start cracking on with the coding in the next lecture.