If you are using Visual Studio Code with Unreal 4.5, you are going to notice some errors with auto
complete.
You may notice that includes have red squiggles under them.
If you hover over them, they say something undecipherable about cannot open source, file UBC, compile
platform, blah, blah, blah.
Or you might just have noticed it when you're trying to auto complete an arrow, something like MASH
arrow here, do an auto complete and there is no suggestions.
Now what's going on here is that there's a bit of a bug in the Unreal Generation code that generates
this project file.
So if you go and find the file in your project, that will be under the product folder, under DOT V.S.
Code and then see Peepee underscore CVP properties, dot Jason.
Then this is auto generated by unreal to give you auto complete, unfortunately.
At the moment it's not doing a particularly good job.
And if we just closed down this include parts which is very long and that's okay.
The problem is there are no defines in this line here, 238 in my file.
We need to replace that with the defines that I'm providing as a download against this lecture.
And what it's basically saying here is that you need to have a bunch of defined values here that would
usually be defined for you when you're building a game but aren't being done.
So what we have to do here is just go ahead and replace the whole lines.
Like the whole line and just paste over it.
Because I've got all the defines that you need around there.
And then we need to just change out a couple of things here, namely where it says, my project, you
need to change that to the name of your project, which will be the same as the name of the folder.
All of this is in.
So in my case, it will be simple shooter use the same capitalization here and then uppercase for this
one here where it says, my project is gonna be simple shooter.
And the API version is also going to be simple shooter.
And if you save your file, the CCP properties dot Jason safe that you can now go over to the other
files and hopefully your autocomplete will work.
It may take a little while of rebuilding Intellisense down here.
You can see this little flame icon saying that it's rebuilding Intellisense.
Often things will change in color after it's done that.
And now you also complete should be working, as you can see here is now given me the auto complete
for the mesh component.
One thing to note about this fix is that every time you regenerate the product file, you're going to
have to reapply this fix.
So you might want to keep your defines dot text handy, but hopefully this will tide you over until
the next unreal update that I'm in, which I'm sure they will be fixing this issue.