Hey and welcome to this lesson where we're going to check to see if the sum and the product of the player's
guesses is equal to the CodeSum and CodeProduct variables we declared.
So to do this we're going to be writing an if statement. We can use if statement to execute parts of
our code.
Only if a condition is met.
And this is what an if statement looks like in C++.
We start off by writing "if" and then we have these parentheses that contain the condition.
We then have some curly braces that will contain the code that will be executed only if the condition
is met.
So for example our braces could contain a line to print a string to the terminal that says "you win" any
code within these braces is known as a compound statement or a code block.
So a condition is required in order for this code block to execute.
We put the condition within these parentheses and we'll start off simple. In order for this code block
to execute the condition will need to be true.
If we didn't want this code block to execute we would want the condition to be false and right now I
want you to implement your own if statement in your code.
So underneath where you declare the GuessSume and GuessProduct implement your if statement. Hard code
the condition as true then add a compound statement also known as a code block that will print a game
winning message to the terminal. Then save your work compile your code and run your program and see what
happens if you make the correct guess then run your program again and see what happens if you make the
wrong guess.
So pause here and have a go at implementing this if statement yourself and then we'll continue in a few
moments
Okay, so let's take a look at this together underneath where we declare our GuessSum and GuessProduct
variables we can add a new line and we can start by typing if then we can add a space and we can open
our parentheses that will contain the condition and we're gonna hard code in the condition as true for
now.
Then on a new line below this we can add our curly braces so we can start our compound statement.
We're simply going to call cout to print a game winning message.
We can just print something like "you win" to the terminal for now.
Now let's check out what happens if we save our work and compile our code and then run Triple X.
So if I enter the correct answer in which is 2 3 4 notice it displays our game winning message.
But if we run the program again and enter 2 6 7 which is the wrong answer it still says you win.
So this is because the if statement is hardcoded as true.
If we set this to false and save our work and compile our code again and then run the program we can
see that it doesn't print the game winning message.
If we enter the wrong answer and if we run the program again it doesn't print the message even if we
enter the correct answer.
Again this is because the condition is hard coded in.
So we need to create our own condition that is linked to our gameplay.
We only want to print our game winning message.
If the player has entered the correct answer.
So we need a new condition.
We can't hard code in true or false.
But we can enter an expression that will return true or false. By the end of this lesson
we want to print our game winning message
if our GuessSum is equal to the CodeSum and if the GuessProduct is equal to the CodeProduct.
But let's focus for now on the GuessSum.
So how can we say if the GuessSum is equal to the CodeSum.
Well it's quite easy to do.
We start off with the variable GuessSum inside our condition and then after a space we can use a comparison
operator to compare it with the CodeSum.
This is the equality operator or the "equal to" operator which is symbolized by two equal signs.
And we can use this to check to see if GuessSum is equal to CodeSum.
And this will return true or false depending on this expression.
And we must remember that this is two equal signs to do this comparison if we used one we would be trying
to assign the value of CodeSum to GuessSum which isn't
our goal here we just want to do a comparison.
So always be aware of your equal signs in your code.
So let's try this now let's change our condition.
So it says if GuessSum is equal to CodeSum then go ahead and execute this code block.
So let's save our work and compile our code and let's run at Triple X again.
And now let's start by entering the wrong answer so let's just put 5 8 9 so no message comes
up.
If I run the program again and enter the correct answer which is 2 3 4 we can see we now get
the winning message.
Okay.
Awesome so we're getting somewhere here.
Now how can we change our condition to say if the GuessSum is equal to the CodeSum and if the GuessProduct
GuessProduct is equal to the CodeProduct.
Well this is also quite easy to do we just need to use the "and operator" which is symbolized by two
ampersands. So we can say if the GuessSum is equal to the CodeSum *and* if the GuessProduct is equal to
the CodeProduct then go ahead and execute our code block below.
Okay.
Awesome.
By the way if this condition returns false it doesn't exit your program or anything it just simply skips
this code block and moves on to the next line of code.
This code block will only execute if the condition is true.
But what if the condition is false.
How do we print a message that says to the player they've lost the game.
Well we can extend our if statement to an if else statement.
We can add else underneath our if statement and add a code block that will execute if our condition
is false.
And I want you to implement this yourself.
Now think of the theme of your game and print a winning message.
If the player has entered the correct code and then print a lose game message if the player has entered
the incorrect code. Then share your work so far in the community either post your code or post screenshots
from your terminal to our community forum so other students can see what you've been up to.
Okay.
So pause here for this final challenge.
Okay, so I'm going to type in else and when we hit enter Visual Studio Code already adds in the code block
for us  ready for us to start typing out our code.
So I'm going to print "you lose" to the terminal.
We can save our work.
We can compile our code and we can run Triple X.
So now if we enter the correct answer it prints you win and if we run the program again and end to the
wrong answer it will print you lose.
Okay awesome.
So we now know how we can execute different lines of code based on conditions.
So great work our full game loop is pretty much there. In the next lesson
we're going to move on to cleaning up some of our code and we're also going to be taking a look how
we can create our own function.
So when you're ready I'll see you in the next lesson.