Hey and welcome to this lesson where we are going to learn about functions.
But before we dive into functions let's just review the code we've been writing over the previous lessons.
We start off our program by printing our intro messages to the terminal.
We then move on and declare the code that the player will have to guess.
It's hard coded for now but we will be looking into randomize in this soon.
We print hints to the terminal for the player we print the sum and the product of the code that they
have to guess.
And then we move on to declare the variables that will be used for storing the player's guess.
And we do this just below by using cin, this allows the player to enter their guess as to what they
think the code is.
Now we haven't commented this code here so let's do that now let's comment this code as store player
gas or something really simple and we can also clean this code up here.
We didn't have to have cin on three separate lines.
We can remove these two lines here where we call cin on GuessB and GuessC and we can use this line
where we just call cin on GuessA we can use the extraction operator again I call that on GuessB
and then the extraction operate again to call cin on GuessC.
Okay, so from here we move on and declare the sum and the products of the guess the player has made.
Then we check to see if the player has made the correct guess or not.
And we could add a comment here to something simple that summarizes this code.
We can just comment this as check if the player's guess is correct and then we print win or lose messages
depending on that.
Okay great.
Now we've been using end line from the standard namespace to print our strings on new lines.
But there's different ways that we can do this.
We can use some special characters within our string to help us do this.
These special characters are known as escape sequences. Escape sequences are used to represent different
characters within a string and they allow us to modify the format of a string.
Let's look at an example.
Imagine we want to print to the terminal "he said."
And then within some quotation marks "Hello, World!". You might try to write this in your code like this
but there's an issue here because strings are wrapped in quotation marks.
Our string would end before "Hello, World!"
We finished the string here and this would cause an error.
So an example of how an escape sequence would work here would be like this.
The backslash double quote represents the escape sequence.
This is how we would form a string to have a quotation mark inserted here.
Okay so how can we use an escape sequence for feeding a new line.
So we don't have to use end line from the standard namespace.
Well it's very simple.
We would use the backslash an escape sequence for a new line.
And now I want you to modify your strings so you use the new line escape sequence instead of using end
line from the standard namespace.
So pause here and modify your strings and then we can move on into taking our first look at creating
some functions.
Okay so I've removed end line from the standard namespace everywhere in my code and I've used the backslash
'\n' escape sequence instead for feeding a new line.
I've used two of them next to each other at the end of my intro messages to print two blank lines before
we move on to print the hints.
Now we need to be aware that we can't use the '\n' escape sequence on the end of a variable name
.
We can only use it within a string.
So just note that you can use these escape sequences at the start of your strings for starting new lines
as well.
I'm making use of this here and where we print the strings.
If the player has worked or lost the game.
Okay great.
Now let's move on and take our first look at creating our own function.
A function is simply a group of statements that together perform a task and is given a name.
So one thing we already know is that every C++ program must have at least one function which is the
main function and we can use the main function as an example to help us understand the syntax of a C++
function.
Functions can return a value.
So when we implement a function in our code we must specify a return type.
We can also specify the function to return it.
No data that will be taking a look at shortly.
In this lesson though the main function we can see that it returns an integer by looking at its return
type.
And we also see this in its code.
Next we have the function name.
So remember.
Naming is really important.
The name is used to describe what the function does.
So we always want to be clear with our naming. Functions can have parameters that we can pass arguments
into by using these parentheses to affect the functions operation.
Now the main function isn't a good example of this but we will be taking a look at how we can create
parameters in the upcoming lessons for this section and it'll become much clearer by then.
But these parentheses are a part of the syntax so it's really important that we include them.
Then we have the function body that makes up the individual statements of our function so we must follow
these guidelines when we write our own function.
Now we're going to write our own function that will handle playing our game and we're going to move
our code we've been writing so far into this function.
Our function will return no data type the name of our function is going to be PlayGame and we want
to make use of Unreal's naming convention here which is UpperCamelCase also known as PascalCase is going
to have no parameters and the function body is simply going to contain the code for playing our game.
So let's switch back to Visual Studio Code and start writing this function together.
I'm going to add a couple of new lines at the start of my file.
Now we need to start with the return type but we don't need this function to return any type of data
yet so to do this we just need to use void as the return type.
Next we want to name the function we're going to name it PlayGame and we're not going to create any
parameters for it but we still need to add the parentheses.
We don't need a semicolon on the end of the line either.
We can start a new line and open our curly braces to start writing the function's body but we're not
going to write any code into this.
We're going to select all of our code we've written in the main function and paste it into our play
game function.
So to do this we can select the start of the first line in the main function and then we can scroll
all the way down and then hold left shift and left click into our code just before we return 0 at the
end of the main function.
Now we can hold "Control + X" to cut it and we can scroll up and paste it into the play game function.
Remember if you make a mistake you can press "Control + Z" that to undo as well.
So we don't need to type "return 0" at the end of our play game function like we do in main because our
play game function doesn't return any data.
That's why we use the keyword void as its data type void means that this function will return no data.
So let's see what happens now.
If we save our work compile our code and then run our program we can see now that nothing has happened.
It's like our program isn't working but this is because the entry point of our program is main.
main runs and it simply returns zero and then the program exits.
We haven't told main to execute our PlayGame function. To do this
we simply type the name of the function inside the function body of main followed by the parentheses
and a semicolon and we can remove any blank lines we have here as well.
We can also remove the blank line between the if and else statement at the end of our PlayGame function
because we traditionally wouldn't have a blank line between the if and else statements.
So now if we save our work and compile our code and then run TripleX again we can see now that it runs
our program but I've got an issue here.
Notice that I'm now entering numbers.
On the same line my text is on.
This is because I'm not specifying a new line at the end of my hints.
So if I scroll up to where my hints are I can actually make use of and line from the standard namespace
here because we can't use our escape sequence that starts a new line on the end of our variable name
so we can use end line to output a new line.
But we could use backslash and we're in quotes here to have the same effect.
We just can't use the escape sequence on the end of the variable name.
So now if I save my work and compile my code and run my program again we can see that it's now being
displayed properly.
So if I entered the wrong answer it says I lose if I run the program again and entered the correct answer
it says I win.
Awesome so our program is now working and our code is in our own function.
So now I want you to create your own function.
Make the return type void and I should stress that void is all lowercase and then go ahead and name
the function PrintIntroduction because I want you to move your code where you print your introduction
message into this function and then call print introduction at the start of play game and for a real
challenge why not modify your introduction message to include some ASCII art.
Have a look around of Google Images for some cool ASCII art and see if you can come up with some yourself.
Then post your results in our community forum so pause here to create your first function and then we
can wrap this lesson
Okay so I've implemented a function called PrintIntroduction into my code and I've moved my introduction
messages from the PlayGame function into this.
Then at the start of my PlayGame function I execute PrintIntroduction.
I want to point out that my PrintIntroduction function is above main but it's below play game.
So let's take a look at what happens if we try compiling our code.
We can see that the compiler tells us that it doesn't know what PrintIntroduction is.
This is because as the compiler goes through and compiles each line of our code it sees that PrintIntroduction
is called in PlayGame but it doesn't know what it is yet because it's declared.
Further down our code there's different ways that we can fix this which we will see where we move over
into Unreal.
But for now we're just going to move PrintIntroduction above our PlayGame function.
Okay.
Awesome.
So we've now created our first two functions in C++ in the next lesson.
We're going to take a look at making our PlayGame function return some data.
So when you're ready I'll see you in the next lesson.