Hello and welcome.
In this lecture, we are going to be covering lots of cool things, but most importantly, we're going
to be looking at how we can child a actor to another actor.
As you can see here, the rifle is a child of the character and how we can make it such that the mesh
there is actually attached to the hand of this skeletal mesh.
As you can see, that gun is moving around with that player's hand.
Let's dive in and see how it's done.
So the first thing I want to do before putting a gun in the hands of this mash is we want to remove
or hide the gun that is currently there.
Now, I find that the easiest way of doing this is to hide the bone that has the gun mash.
Let's have a look.
So if we go over to the shooter character, BP would be a good entry point for this.
And then I want to fine.
Go to the actual MASH.
Hey, we got skeletal mesh.
And if I go to the skeleton, then we can find that there's a gun here.
If I click on the gun has got a bone leading up to it called the weapon bone and weapon underscore.
Ah.
And basically want to hide this.
But the easiest way to hide this across the board is going to be to do it in code and we're going to
do it in C++.
So the first thing is to get hold of the mesh components.
The way to do this when you're on a character subclass is to call to get mesh cool.
So we've got to get mesh.
Then with the mesh, we want to hide the bone.
There is hardly a hide bone by name methods.
And this actually exists on the parents of these skeletal mesh component, the skin, the mesh components.
Have a look at the head of file briefly.
Skin mesh component dot h.
There is a couple of functions here.
The one we're looking for is hyd bone by name.
So you can see the signature here.
We've got the bone name comes in and F name.
And then the second thing is this e fiers body up.
Now, as far as I can tell, this isn't used in the code base, but we've got to provide it because
it's there in the signature.
So let's go ahead and use it.
So Arrow going to do the hide bone by name for Shamai Autocomplete is not working.
That's a bug in four point two five at the moment.
And V.S. Code Autocomplete doesn't 100 percent want to work.
But that's okay.
We can learn to do the manual way instead.
Then we're gonna want the name of the bone and I'll leave that up to you as an exercise to fill that
out in a second.
And then the second thing is we wanted that fiz up body thing.
We're just going to go for that.
That's an enum.
So we're going to need to fill it out.
Got to use f twelve's go to the definition and see what we have got.
MPB o none.
Don't do anything.
That sounds like a sensible defo.
Let's go with that and then we'll use the semicolon to finish off our line right there.
So let's compile lists and see if we've got all the includes we need code.
Looks like it's working.
So we must have all the includes we need.
Now let's.
What's your challenge is to put in the Bowen name.
Give that a quick go mini challenge and come coming back.
The boat name is Weapon Unschool.
Ah, it was hinted that a little bit before weapon underscore.
Ah should do the trick.
If we go ahead and recompile with that now and we hit play, you can see that he's no longer holding
a gun.
Fantastic.
So the next thing is to put a different gun in his hand.
The axe, the gun.
So we need to go over to our skeleton and what we want to do here is add in a new socket.
So we're going to add in a socket in place of our weapon.
And what is the socket?
A socket.
What as it sounds like a plug socket is something that you can plug in.
It's a point at which you can plug in other things.
So you might want to be able to plug in, for example, a gun and you want it to be child ID, not to
the mesh as a whole, but to a specific bone of that mesh, which means that it will move correctly
with the character's arms when he's doing an animation, when he's jogging around.
It's going to look like it's attached to his hand rather than somewhere on it.
You know, not rigidly fixed to his torso.
So we're going to add a child socket to a weapon.
OK.
Do this.
You go to the skeleton, you right.
Click on the bone that you want to attach this socket to.
And you click add socket.
And we're just gonna call this one the weapon.
Socket, I'm using Camil case here as my convention.
And that's what we're going to want to attach to now.
You'll see where this comes in handy when we go to actually do the attachment for our gun.
Now, the thing to note here is that we don't want to do a set up attachment, as we would do in the
constructor at runtime.
When we do attachment, we have to use a different set of functions rather than the ones we use in the
constructor.
And remember when I said that's the only hierarchy here really is between Sene components.
Now, fortunately, we don't have to go in and get the root components of the gun and attach it.
There is a helper method on the actor that allows us to do attachment and that is attach to components.
So let's see where that's defined.
If we go to look at the actor Dot H.
Had a file and there's a couple of these.
We want the one that lives under game framework and we're gonna go and search in here for attach to
component open brackets and find the actual declaration.
Here it is.
So what's this gonna take in?
It's gonna take in a UCM component.
The parent that we want to attach to in this case, it's gonna be our skeletal mesh of the character.
The transform rules will get to this in just a second.
And then they go the socket name.
That's where on a skeletal mesh should we attach to?
If it's a skeletal mesh, it'll attach to the socket if it is not a skeletal mesh in the leg, nor the
socket argument and just attach if it's a static mesh, for example.
So we want to attach to get mesh.
We have these transform rules.
What are those?
Let's click through F 12.
So click through to that.
The different rules that are available.
There's these are the preset rules.
You can define your own, but you might as well use these preset ones.
We've got keep relative transform, keep world transform, snap to target and including Sky.
We'll ignore these.
Lastly, the main two to look out for.
Are these first two.
And it basically means when we're attaching should it stay the same place it was in the world, or should
we use that world position as the new local position?
In our case, because we want that gun to essentially be at zero zero, which would be its location
in the world, we want to keep the relative transform.
So let's do that.
We're going to have the F transform rules, keep relative transform.
So I have transformed rooms.
Rules come on, code on.
And then it should be.
Let me see.
Just copy over the keep relative transforms like so.
And then we want the socket.
So again, text macro here.
And then the socket name which was within socket.
And finish off the line, that's going to set up the attachment and now the final point is going to
be to we want to set up.
The gun to have this class as its owner.
This is a bit of a subtle point.
Why do we have an owner?
I just said that there wasn't any hierarchy between actors.
Well, there isn't in the sense of transforms.
But they do have ownership.
And where this ownership really comes into play is in multiplayer and in damage.
So we'll see later on how we will need to know about the owner.
It also allows the gun to know what is the owning character.
And it can use that to get references to the owning character later on.
This will be useful.
The moment we don't particularly care, but we're just going to do it for completeness sake.
Now, I should name this wrong.
It shouldn't be set up owner, but set owner to this because it's the actor that is the owner of the
gun.
Cobain's let's compile and see if this is working.
Compiled, successful, let's dive in and play the game.
Awesome, we have got a weapon in our hands.
Is it in the right place?
Let's have a look.
That's F eight out of here and have a look at the hand.
Not quite.
You can see that we could do a little bit of adjusting here.
So that's what we're gonna do.
And this is a challenge for you.
Basically, what you're gonna try and do is find what the offsets should be on the mesh such that this
handle is actually inside and meshes Raith character's hand, pulls a video and have a go at that.
Welcome back.
So I'm going to do this by selecting that mesh and trying to move it.
I'm gonna have to set the grid snap size in the viewport to a little bit less.
And I'm going to try and zoom in as best I can on that hand.
OK, bring that down a little bit.
I think that's a good shout.
Now, let's go ahead and copy the location and open up to the content browser and open up the BP rifle.
Open the full blueprint, Ed.
Go to the MASH and stop simulating and paste the location that we had copied in there.
OK, cool.
Copy that.
And let's go and hit play.
And let's see that it's actually brought across the right thing.
F eight out.
And zoom in.
By the way, you can use the scroll wheel to slow down your movement when you're moving in this in this
kind of way.
Fantastic.
Looks like he has got his hands directly on the handle.
Awesome stuff, so we have learnt how we can.
Child actors to other actors and how we can attach sene components to sockets of skeletal meshes in
the next lecture, we're gonna be looking a little bit at shooting and how the gun architecture basically
dovetails into a shooting architecture.
So I'll see you then.