So this lecture will look at creating some materials for our models.
We're going to set up some parameters we're going to expose those parameters to our material instance
so we can scale the texture and not just scaling it on both axes we can set it up so that we can scale
both the U and the v coordinates or the X and Y or the image accordingly which is great because it means
that if something is not quite square and we want it to be we can make it square.
So let's hop on over into one real and start transforming our materials textures.
Okay.
So the first thing I want to do here is texture the floor using the wall texture.
Now in order to do that we're going to do the similar sort of things we did before and create the wall.
We're going to go to our original stone material right click and create a material instance and we're
going to call it stone.
You probably guessed this floor okay.
Brilliant.
Now it's almost to the point where I think we can start.
Well not quite.
But if we have much more in here it might be worth branching out so it's not just models but also materials
as well.
Okay.
So we've got our stone floor here.
I'm gonna open up that material instance and I'm going to dockets at the very top window here so I can
switch between building escape and the stone floor very quickly.
Now there's nothing here that I can use to adjust the scale of my material.
So this is only going to be useful once we've exposed the parameters we need to use.
Let's go back to the building escape tab and open up our stone material now.
Yes.
That's opened up and it's opened up in the tab.
Useful.
Okay.
So let's have a closer look at this.
We've got stone material here.
This is the output node.
This is the results we hover over it.
And as always these key tips here is the result node of the material so what is what's going to look
like we then have a texture sample node and that's the texture that we've got plugged in.
That's fine.
Now we need to control how the U visa mapped there are there are a couple of ways that we can plug things
into these sockets of our nodes so we can go ahead and click and drag out and look that will place a
new node that's directly connected to you vs.
Let's do that now and search for texture coordinates REO texture coordinates pressed enter and it's
added that in and over on the left hand side you can see material updating that's because we've got
live preview turned on.
So it will compile the material and we can see here we've got the you tiling and the v tiling.
That's pretty awesome.
So what happens if we set this to five and five.
What what effect does a bigger number create.
We have to wait.
Oh look smaller brickwork.
Okay so now if we go ahead and save that what does that mean.
Well it's going to compile the material and save it and then we just have to wait for a while to for
it to be updated.
Brilliant.
Now let's have a look at our stone floor material instance.
Nothing's changed there.
Let's go over to our world.
Oh.
Oh dear.
Look at the wall has gone all small.
So this is an example where we modify our original material.
We don't have any independent control.
The wall material the floor eventually that stick the stone floor on the floor.
And of course we've got the same material applied to the door frame and unfortunately it's changed all
of them so that's not the way forward and we certainly don't want to create tons of just the same material
but scaled differently that would be silly because we'd have to wait for it to update you saw how slow
it was every time we made the change it had to compile.
Well let's expose our first parameter so the type of parameter we want to expose is a scalar parameter
so another way of adding a node in like this texture coordinate node is just by right clicking and we
want scalar the SC A L and then we go parameters scalar parameter.
So it's just gonna be a number and we can call this text just scale.
And if you have a look over in the details of this case in the lower left we have a default value.
I'm going to set that default value to 1 and look that preview just disappears.
Now that's not annoying me at all.
I'd rather that actually be there.
So I can see what's going on but I just want to highlight how slow that is because when we start playing
with the material instance in the moment you see how much quicker that is.
Right.
How do we join these two things together.
We're going to need to multiply node so I'm going to right click in the middle of nowhere this time
and create a multiplying node.
So M you LTE I multiply that we go.
Now I need to join this together.
Now we don't have to disconnect this one go from the texture corner to the text to samples it will automatically
disappear the moment we plug something else into that socket like so which is pretty awesome.
However if we did want to remove this one manually we could hold down the old key while we clicked and
that all unconnected the sockets from one another.
So we're going to multiply our texture coordinates by our text to scale and then we can plug that into
the movies.
Now with the texture scale being 1 in this particular case we should have it looking exactly the same
as it was before.
But we do need to go back to attach coordinates and set that back to one as well on both for you and
the V.
Remember you a V is just a x and y of our texture itself.
If you imagine an image which is essentially what this texture is.
I'm going to save my material.
Now when we go to our stone floor we'll see that the texture scale is an exposed parameter.
Now let's go back over to building escape.
Excellent.
So everything's reset itself and the floor itself looks like the walls now are going to detach my stone
floor instance at the top here so that we can see it next to this.
In fact we may be able to dock it.
Is it going to allow me to dock this anywhere else.
Unfortunately not for the moment maybe up here next to the world outline to make sure we've got our
tab.
Now it's not allowing me to dock.
That's a shame.
OK.
So with the stone floor just detached here I'm going to put a tick in the text just scale.
That's our parameters name.
Let's just make this a little bit bigger.
Look texture scale and we get texture scale currently at 1 but the great thing here is I can click and
slide and look at that.
So lower values make it larger and higher values make it smaller.
But look how much quicker that is updating.
Now if you push it negative it is going to invert the image not in its color but it's going to flip
it round.
So what was the top left will become the bottom right.
And so forth.
So going from one down to zero makes it larger and going higher makes it smaller.
So that is amazing how much quicker that is when I said that 2.5 for the moment no I think points to
make.
So these are nice large floor slabs now but then not quite square I want them to be square.
How do we go ahead and do that.
Well let's to save are instance there and slot it back at the top there.
Currently we've only got one parameter so we're only scaling the U.N. v coordinates by the same amount
each time we want them to be scaled differently.
How do we go ahead and do that well back over to the main material and instead of just the texture scale
here let's have two parameters.
Now instead of going ahead and creating a new scalar parameter I'm just going to go control and see
and then control them v it'll create a new scalar parameter that's called texture scale but that's no
good we need to have a unique name.
So I'm going to click on the top texture scale go to the details tab and call this the you texture scale
click on the next one and call this one the V texture scale.
Now the good thing about making sure that I've copied it.
In this case is it will inherit the default value I've already set up.
Now that's just one parameter in this particular case but in a more complex environment you may want
to make sure that you copy it.
Now we're going to keep the rest of the notes sets up here but we've got to join the EU and the v coordinates
together how are we going to do that.
Well what we want to do is add in an append node I'm going to go through the last way of adding something
here.
Over on the right hand side you've got a pallet with everything we possibly could have.
And I'm going to type in append and we want the top one here append vector and we can just drag that
into our scene.
I'm going to connect a M B to you and V and then this output into the B of the multiplier.
Now hopefully what this will enable us to do is now we should be able to save our material go over to
our stone floor and it will now be updated hopefully.
Let's just wait for a second.
There we go.
The you texture and the v texture scale and look it does look stretched here at the moment.
And if we scale that up we can see we can scale the horizontal and the vertical scaling independently
from one another.
That is brilliant.
That's exactly what we want.
But this sphere isn't particularly representative of the floor or brickwork.
It's a great way of demonstrating a particular surface.
However down at the lower right we have some previews.
I just want a plane at this point.
Now you may end up with a view that looks like this which is no good.
I hear you say well that's because we've got a few issues here.
We've got black face coming so we actually need to look at it from this side.
Now this is something that will flummox some people so left click here.
We'll rotate around right click.
We'll zoom in and out.
So it's a slightly different view control than before but this on a plane is going to give us a much
better appreciation about what's going on.
And to pan around you can use the middle mouse button.
Okay.
Now I'm not sure what I need here so I'm going to zoom in with the middle mouse button.
Let's make it square so let's lower this down.
Oh no.
We need to raise that up.
But we know that at the moment with it like this.
Mm hmm.
You know what.
Just looking at it here I'm going to detach the stone floor again so we get the general scale right.
Because that's not right that we know we were down at point to point a point to before.
Yes about point two.
So let's look down at the floor and zoom out here.
In fact he is not going to be such a great representation for us.
So this looks like it needs to be scaled vertically or horizontally.
I'm going to scale it horizontally maybe point three by point so no that's too fast.
Maybe point two five.
Now that looks about right.
Look at that.
Perfect.
And of course you can tweak it by clicking and holding and just racking so maybe a little lower.
I think I might have stretch that out a little bit too far.
You know it's very difficult to get it right.
I think around there and I could tweak this all day to be honest right.
There we go.
That's the floor.
All done.
And the great thing here I can save and close down the stone floor material instance.
The great thing here is this is a shared texture so anything we do to change this material here.
Now bearing in mind we only have a color on this material at the moment which looks like this stone
if we were to go ahead and add a normal map ambient occlusion and all the other possibilities that we
can put on here the wall and the floor and the doorframe will all inherits it straight away.
And that's the power of material instances.
OK time for your challenge and your challenge is I'd like you to finish texturing your test level.
So just throw another texture on there perhaps use the wooden door that we've already got and apply
it to the ceiling and then stretch it out because I think that's also not square.
So you'll be able to copy and paste from one node setup to another that's something I'd like you to
try to texture the rest of your test level.
Use only the one texture and scale appropriately for the objects you applying it to and in my case that's
going to be the ceiling at this point in time.
So go ahead pause video now and give that a go
okay.
Everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead and finalize all texturing Okay so it's just the ceiling at the moment.
I'm going to give ourselves a wooden ceiling so we've got the texture already applied to the door which
is great.
Let's bring this up slightly we've got our dorm material and our metal wood which is the base material
we're starting to get these asterisks on all of our materials and one of our models here.
I'm just going to highlight all of my stuff making sure of course I've selected something down here
first right click and I'm just gonna go save to make sure that everything is in fact saved.
Okay now the broken concrete is a material that came in as part of the naming structure part of the
materials that were added to the door frame itself.
Now because I'm not using that it's brought it in.
Is a dead material.
I'm going to kill that by deleting it now because I'm deleting it and it's not attached to anything.
It's not referenced anywhere.
We don't get any warning that it is referenced elsewhere in our project.
So I can go ahead and delete it nice and safely.
Okay.
I'm also going to delete my sample queue.
I don't need it in my scene.
It's not in my safe and all it's doing is cluttering up my view.
Okay I'm now going to create a new folder and I'm going to call it materials and I'm going to create
another one called textures.
No I'm going to call this materials and textures materials and textures.
Excellent.
And then we've got our models separate from everything else.
We're gonna move them there not take a copy.
It's gonna take a while to move.
There we go.
So materials and textures we've got the door material that's the one I'm going to share something with.
Take an instance of the metal would create a material instance and cool this sealing for the moment
because I spell selling it will do.
And let's slap it to the ceiling.
Oh did I miss it make sure we aim it correctly.
There we go.
And it's not quite the right shape at the moment.
Now this is where we can go into our stone material and grab this node group here.
I'm going to copy that and then you'll go back to building escape and open up the metal Woods.
The source material that's opened up on another screen let me bring that down.
Let's zoom out with the scroll will pull this across and paste that in so that's a very quick way or
miss the socket there click away try and reconnect it and save so it is really useful if you've got
a node sets up like that that you can just copy and paste it to the next node available which is brilliant
that's now done.
But we do need to remember.
Let's just close those two down.
Yes we do want to save any changes that we've made.
And then with the sealing here when we go to it we need to make sure let's just bring it down so we
can see what's going on that we put a tick in these two boxes.
Otherwise we won't be able to scale it accordingly.
Now I want to go four point five to begin with.
So it's bigger.
And then what do we need to do here we need to increase this or increase the you or decrease the V.
Something that go with point five there and try.
Point four here which is I get that the wrong way round point two.
Yes I got about the wrong way round.
Silly me right.
Let's go back to point three here.
Let's try.
Point three and point so hole pretty much spot on but I confess I think I could do with just a tiny
bit more tweaking.
There we go.
That's looking pretty square to me.
Okay.
Now you could spend the time lining everything up with the ceiling in the corners but going back to
just remembering that this itself is a test level it does not have to be perfect it just has to be representative
to be quite honest trying to match the ceiling perfectly is going to be a real challenge to do.
And this is not really the place to do it.
You need to even do it in blender or another 3D editing package with the movies there and you can manipulate
them and fit them exactly to whatever the ceiling would be which uses be a squashed cube essentially.
But there we go.
My level is now all textured and quite happy with how it's working out.
We've got a couple of lights or a couple of spotlights in the corners look really nice looking forward
seeing how you've textured your level and also the textures you've used.
Now this is obviously just two textures in here and this yellowy brass knob on the door itself.
So this is a really simplistic setup.
I'll be really interested to see if you've gone the extra mile and included extra textures especially
as we progressed through and create create more of our level.
So do share your work over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.