Hello and welcome to this lecture, we're going to be getting some line tracing set up so that we can
shoot at the walls and see these debug points appearing.
And we're gonna be doing this using a new function line traced by channeler.
We're gonna see why we're using that overline traced by object type, which is what we've used before.
Let's dive in and see how it's done.
So back in our building escape, we used line traces and we use this function here, the line trace
by object type.
And is this what we want to be using?
Well, what is the difference between line traced by object type?
And it's very close sibling, which is a line trace by channel.
Well, object type says, I'm want to search through this line and see if I find an object that matches
this type.
So in I believe what we used in building escape was something like the physics body object type.
And that's great.
It will hit physics bodies.
But if you decide something that you want something else to be hit a ball, it doesn't leave much room
for options.
So Channel is better for that because it allows us to define our own custom channels and then define
what sorts of objects are transparent to that channel and which ones block it.
So that's great, because what we want to be able to do is say, okay, maybe a Bush type of thing is
can't can't block a bullet where as a wall will block a bullet, but it won't be taking any damage but
that we can deal with later on.
So channels all the route.
We're going to go down and we can find the correct method here by doing control P.
And by the way, there's this little extra cool bit that I only recently just learned is if you use
the at symbol, you can search for symbols within this file and or even other files.
But if you have the file open, it's much quicker than you could do something like line that trace and
you can see there's giving us the list of all the symbols which are functions or classes or variables.
And we can find a line trace test line trace single by channel by object type.
We want this first one line trace, single by channel, which is going to have an outer parameter for
what we hit the starting points.
The ending point, the collision trace channel will come to that in just a little bit and then some
query parameters which are have got some default.
So we actually don't have to worry about.
So just those first few things, the out hit start and and trace channel are what we want to worry about.
Let's set up a trace channel.
We're gonna go to settings and project settings for this.
And then we're looking under engine for the collisions area.
And under here you can see we've got object channels and trace channels.
Object channels is actually just another way of saying different types of object.
So if you wanted to have as well as the default sets of objects like pawns and stuff like that, if
you wanted a new category of object, you could go down the object channel route.
But the Trace's allow you to define the opposite end of the spectrum, which is like, you know, I've
got a bullet.
What objects can it hit?
So we're gonna go down this route, add a new trace channel and we're going to call this bullet.
And the default response is going to be block, which basically means that all object types gonna block
unless we now specify otherwise, can go ahead and accept this and we can look at our presets down here.
If we just expand that out, The Presets are going to show you that we have a bunch of different things
that we can apply to, things we can say.
We want this to be a physics actor.
In which case it's object type, which is going to be what is a predefined object channel will be physics
body.
But if we expand this out, you can see what its reaction is to the different types of Trace's here.
So we've got outrace types who camera our own bullets, visibility.
It blocks all of these.
And that's got object types.
So that's how it interacts physics wise with other objects, such as pawns and vehicles, et cetera.
And that's not how it interacts with line traced by object.
That's slightly confusing and it's confused me before.
So the trace type is what's interesting.
And we can just go and have a look through here and see no collision should be set up to not collide.
So let's make Bullet not collide with that as well.
So just overriding some of the presets such that our bullet works as we would expect, overlap all,
for example, should basically overlap with the bullet and probably invisible wall.
An invisible wall dynamic should also be ignored for the purposes of our bullet.
Same with dynamic here.
You can see the work basically ending up with some it's quite similar to a visibility trace.
But the reason for keeping it separate is that we might want to make slight distinctions, such as you
can see you can't see through this Bush, but you can shoot through it.
Those kinds of things mean that having our own traced channel is really, really handy.
Now, we'd like to be able to use this trace channel in code.
And it's a bit funky how we have to do this, because there's an enum here and a collision channel.
And if we go F 12 to its definition, you can see there's a bunch for the predefined ones, world static
pawn, his ability, et cetera, down here.
But then there's a bunch more engine trace channels, one, two, and game trace channel one, two,
three, et cetera.
Predefined.
Which one of ours is this?
You know, it's we don't have a bullet in here.
We actually have to use one of these game trace channels one.
So it's really a little bit confusing.
Which one is it?
So the way you do this is by going to your project folder and go into config.
And what we want is the default engine any and we want to open that in a text that say you could do
that in any text that you like.
I like to drank it into visual studio code so that visual studio code is the one opening it.
And in here, we want to essentially look for our bullet and see what it has been assigned to.
And I think this first line here tells us that the channel it's been given is the game trace Channel
One.
Fantastic.
So that's what we are going to use when we're doing our line trace.
So let's start to get the structure of this line trace in place.
The first thing we're going to need is a start point, we already have that that's the location of our
viewport.
We also need an endpoint for our line trace.
That's slightly harder to calculate.
So let's create an F vector for our end and we're going to calculate this by using our start points,
plus the rotation multiplied by the amount, the distance that we want to go away or not.
The rotation.
But the vector that points in the direction of the rotation for slightly confusing.
But actually, if you do rotation dot vector, this gives you a vector that points in the direction
of this rotation is kind of doing the opposite of what we were doing in the animation blueprint to get
a rotation from the vector.
This goes the other way.
So we're gonna do location plus this rotation vector.
And then we want essentially a max range.
So I'm going to introduce a new You property here, make it add it anywhere.
And it's gonna be a float called Max Range like so.
And we can set it to a default of something like 10000 or a thousand max range.
That's gonna be about 100 meters sorry, about 10 meters.
And we're gonna go over to do a rotation dot vector multiplied by the max range.
So that's gonna be the vector that we get from that rotation is gonna be a size one.
Multiplying it by the max range will make it a vector of size.
Whatever the max range is.
And then we add that on top of the location to get as the end point.
Don't worry if you don't follow that math 100 percent.
The important thing is that this is how we want to get to our end point.
Then who's going to do line in here to add in some line tracing and are gonna remove this draw debug
camera?
Because I want to do a different draw debug helper here.
I want to draw a debug point, which you can find here, takes in the world, takes in a position and
a size and a color.
And whether it's persistent or not, we probably do want it to be persistent, to be visible.
So we should be able to do something along these lines that say draw debug points and we're going to
do a get world right off the bat here.
And then we'll start off with the location of our viewport instead.
Just as a test to see this, Drew, how this draw debug point works, give it size to give it an F color
of red and make its persistent ness true.
And then we are going to capital for the semicolon and see whether this is working as hit compile ever
in the engine.
And that's hit play.
So now if I shoot and move slightly back, you can see there's a point there.
However, it's really, really tiny and hard to see.
So they're going to increase this to 20 instead.
And let's see if that's better compile and play.
Yep.
Sure enough.
Now I can see a very, very clear point.
So time for your challenge to do a line trace by channel.
We've done it with object types before, so hopefully we can extrapolate that to doing it by channel.
So use the location and end that we have defined already as the start and end.
Check the success of the result, making an if statement so only getting the out parameter.
Okay.
In the outer parameter of the hit result and only drawing a debug point.
If we successfully hit the point and remember that we're using that channel that we found in the dot
any file as well.
So pause the video and see if you can sort out all of those parameters and arguments into the line trace
and get that debug point drawing where we hit with our line trace.
Pause video.
Have a good.
Okay, welcome back.
So let's dive right in, we're going to get the world, first of all, and do an arrow set that we're
going to go to do a line trace single by channel.
Then we're going to need a hit result.
So OUTFRONT, we need to first declare our hit results struct to pass in as an out parameter.
It's going to call it hit and they're going to pass it in as the first argument here.
Then we need the location.
And we need the end.
And then what?
What comes up next, the e collision, a collision channel.
So that's gonna be an E collision channel, Kolon, Kolon.
And then it should be E.C.
What did we say?
Let's go and have a look.
In the default engine, any ECAC game trace channel one is the one that the default any has configured.
Are there any more arguments here that we need?
Let's go along.
We've got the collision parameters which are defaulted outside.
No, we do not need anything in here.
And then what we can do is we need a boolean result for this.
So be success.
And it sounds very helpful, isn't it?
B, success, let's say an F.
B, success.
We are going to want to draw that debug point.
So, again, to move this down, I can do this with OLT.
And then the arrow moves the line around like this.
And then I can indent it with a control and the right square brackets on your keyboard.
And that gets it to look like so.
And now instead of the location, which is the start point, we she wants the hit location.
So that's going to be hit dot location like.
So it looks like I'm missing a semicolon on the end of this line here.
Let's build that and give it a go.
Once that's compile, that's hit play, go into the world and try and shoot at our walls.
There you go.
You can see we got a point showing up on the wall just where I shot.
I can do this multiple times.
It seems to hit.
If I go too far from a wall, it doesn't hit at all because of our max range being quite short.
And you can see once I get within the max range.
It does hit and it does draw a point.
So that is a challenge successfully completed.
We are now able to show and line trace to a particular point.
The next step is going to be getting that to actually show some particle effects, which will be much
cooler than just drawing a debug point for that.
I'll see you in the next lecture.