Welcome back to this lecture where we'll be fleshing out some more of the game mode class.
So we have a lot to do in this class.
So we're going to begin by setting up what the goal of the game is and the actors relating to that.
The first two things that we need to reference are going to be the number of targets in the level for
the player to destroy and the player class itself to check against when an actor is destroyed.
So if we start off in the head headphone, we can forward declare our a apen turrets and a pawn that
tank class.
Then in the private section will create a pointer of type A porn tank named Plier Tank.
As we also know that we need to know how many tyrants the player will need to destroy for the when condition
will create a new variable of Type 32 named Target Turrets.
So we'll just be using this a little bit later to find and then keep track of the number of remaining
turrets in the level.
This will also be managed in the C++ code.
So I'll place these new variables at the top of the private section where any of our variables without
the U.
Properties can be stored going forward.
So that should be everything that we need in the head of file for.
And I say back in the code file, we already know that we will be needing to reference the two porn
classes.
So at the top of this class, we can go straight ahead and include the tune.
Thanks.
Forward Slash Poons, forward slash pawn tank Deitsch.
And then we'll also need the team tanks for slash pawns forward slash pawn turret.
Dot h.
And whilst we have I know that we're going to need the game play static's functionality.
So, again, we can include this from the Kismet Library forward slash game play static's dot h.
Just noticed as well when we created the begin play function, we haven't called the parents begin play,
so we'll just do that now by using the super beginning play.
After this, we can then start by finding out how many tart's there are in the world for the player
to destroy.
To do this will use the new game play static's.
And the function within this could get all actors of class.
So if we're going to take a dive into our get all actors of class function here and we can see what
the arguments required to complete the function.
And also kind of get an idea of how the function works.
So this will find all of the actors in the world of a specific class.
It takes in a world context object, as we've seen before.
And the two important requirements for our use of this is the actor class, which is the type of actor
we're looking to find.
And then this tea array of act actors, which is an array of actor types.
And this will be filled for us as the return of the function.
So this will be our list of the turrets which exist in the world.
When we've implemented this function.
So this will be nice and easy to validate.
We'll use the get word function to return the world context object.
Then we can find our taat class in the level by passing in a pawn turret.
Static class and the static class function that we're using here just means we're not requiring an object
instance.
And this will return the UCLASS of the act type that we're calling from.
So here that will be returning the A pawn taat.
And then this is just making use of the unreal reflection system.
Which leaves the final argument that we can just jump back up a line and we'll create a new theory of
type actor to match the argument type one tameness taht actors with that ready we can now pass in our
final argument as the target actors.
We won't need to worry about casting or checking specifically against the porn star, classier as we're
not going to be referencing any of the class specific properties from the array, simply getting and
tracking the number of that type of actor in the level so that when I fill our tier right with that
variable stored.
We can use that to say that our target target.
So our INT 32 made earlier is equal to the target actors Donham, which is simply getting the number
of elements in the array, or first, that will be the number of targets in the level.
For the play, a reference, we just go and use the get to play a porn function.
So this is achieved by creating a cast to the type to check against the A porn tank, using the new
game gameplay static's.
So that'll be your game play static's get play upon passing in this and the player controller index
of Player Zero.
Again, we're using a single player game, so that's going to be the first and the only player in the
game will be Controller zero.
So that when I give us all of the values and references that we need to complete, the actor died function
so we can jump down to that function whilst we're still in the game mode.
So if we handle the player, check first, we'll do this using an F statement.
So if the actor is equal to our play a tank reference, then we're gonna want to call a function in
the porn class to notify the porn to handle its death functionality.
So if we go back to the porn based class, we can look here to see how we've set this up and we've actually
created our 100 destruction function and place this in the protected section, meaning that this wouldn't
be available outside of the porn class.
And it's child classes.
So I'll begin by cutting and pasting this back above into the public section.
We've likely done this in the child classes as well.
So let's just return to the tart and the tank class and we'll move our override functions into their
public sections as well.
This will then ensure that these are all available outside of the class as we'll be needing that in
just a moment.
With that done, just ensure that you've saved all of those changes and then we can return back to our
game mode code file and we can finish the call from the player tank to the handle destruction function.
Well, then also cool our handle Gameover function in the game mode, passing in a false boolean to
indicate that the player didn't win at this stage.
So that is the kind of first condition checked for.
If that's not the case, then we'll use an if statement.
So if the actor that was destroyed wasn't the player, then we'll check and store a temporary pointer
to the a pawn turret class named Destroyed at Target.
So using this, we'll use a cast to the AP and class referencing the dead actor.
So if that is true.
So if this cast is successful and the thing being destroyed is a target, then this will also store
a variable first reference in the moment as well.
So your challenge here is to complete this out check by notifying the destroyed heart that it has been
destroyed.
Then go ahead and update how many turrets are left in the game.
And if the target target value is now equal to zero, then call the handle game over and pass in the
correct win lose state.
OK, so let's go through this to check the first step is pretty much what we've done with our planet
tank.
But this is going to be cooling the handle destruction on the destroyed tarte.
Next, we can revisit a topic from the previous section, which is something you've looked at, the
pre increment of the value or how to pray increment of value.
So it's collapse everything into a secondary F statement.
This time, of course, we'll be using the predicament operation so we can say F minus, minus target
tart's is equal to zero.
So this is taking away from that value that we want to handle the game over.
And this time will pass in the true value for the player winning because they've removed all of the
titles from the level and that's it.
So we can now start at least kind of visualizing some of the Gamefly pretty soon with the help of some
start and end game widgets as these are all handled in blueprints, we want to make sure that those
functions are being cooled in that C++ handle counterparts.
So in the handle game, start function, call the game, start function, which remember is going to
be our blueprint implemented function.
And in the handle game over function, call the game over.
And remember to pass in the player one that boolean.
We just want to make sure that the handle GameSpot is being cooled and we should do that on the begin
play just after storing all of our variables and references.
And then one thing I'm noticing back in the game play is that our functionality to get the number of
target targets is a little bit long.
So this might be better suited in its own function.
So we'll go ahead and do that quickly before finishing up with the class.
So back in the header, let's create a new private function of type in 32 named Gett Target, Target
Count.
Then we need to implement this in the code form.
I'll be doing that using these C++ helper as usual.
And for the implementation, I'm just going to grab everything apart from the target tart's equals.
And then I'll cut this and paste this into the get target Tarakan function.
Then in front of the turret, actors don't come.
We just need to include our return as this is a type based function and it will be returning and thirty
to value, which will still be our target.
Actors count.
But what we now call this from the begin play.
We can I just say that target targets equals to get target to count and everything is just a little
bit more readable at a glance.
Using it this way was tidying up.
We could also drop the target targets and the player tank initialization in to the handle GameStop function
just before the blueprint game start function is called to make sure that we have all of those variables
ready to go before the game is initialized, essentially, unlike with a lot of the large implementations
we've made.
There's not really anything we can look at right now that would have changed in the game mode or if
we were to press play in the editor.
But be sure to save and compile this.
So you're ready for the next lecture where we can start creating our widgets to highlight the Gamefly
using a lot of the stuff that we've just implemented here.