OK, so we're going to be covering it, use of widgets in this lecture.
This is gonna be nice and simple as there won't be a whole lot of communication between classes and
will only be used for a kind of fell ahead.
To emphasize the start and end of game flow, meaning we won't need to whereby things like button interact
from different menu sub settings and things like that.
So we're going to begin by creating a new folder in the blueprint structure named Widgets.
Inside of the new folder, right click, highlight the user interface, select widget blueprint and
name it WPP underscore game start save for widget blueprints and the name of the blueprint we are creating.
If the widget class is something new to you, then there may be a lot of information on screen.
But we're going to go through this step by step and use what we need so that by the end of the lecture
it should all make a lot more sense.
The main things to notice or understand, first of all, is that we're currently in the design section
of the widget, which is the visual area where we create our visual components, such as text buttons,
sliders and things like that for our menus, loading screens or just kind of visual representation screens
like we're using here.
Next to the designer text, which is actually a button is our graph button.
And this will take us to the development section where we can add our blueprint implementation similar
to most of the other blueprints.
You may have seen the project or the engine before.
For another, we're just going to be working to get the visual aspects implemented, which for our start
menu is going to be super simple as it consists of a single text element.
So in the pallet section to the left, search for the text option or you can see it just here.
If I scroll down a little bit and then we just want to drag the text element into the canvas, which
is the section in the main window just here.
This is just done a few things.
So in the lower left section, we can see that we have a hierarchy panel which controls the placement
order of the widget elements.
At that moment, we've placed the text element onto the existing canvas element and the canvas is just
a term for the holder of everything that will be displayed onscreen.
When the widget is added to be rendered and the hierarchy here will control the order in which things
are displayed to ensure that things that you place in front of another element obviously are rendered.
On top of that, not every element can be placed on top of each other.
But those that can follow a hierarchy where the lower elements will be rendered on top of the other
elements.
The other thing that's just happened as well is that to the right of the screen, we can see the user
details panel, and this correlates to an anchor that is just being placed in the top left of the canvas,
which is where the text will be aligned and tried to keep its position based on a dynamic screen resolution.
So there's a small slider just to the bottom right of the canvas.
And if I drag this around, we can see that the text will always try to stay a set distance from the
anchor.
And whilst I'm doing this, I'm just going to zoom out a little bit and I'm going to snap the canvas
to 1920 as a slightly more standard screen resolution.
So I want this text to always be roughly centred on the screen.
So I'm going to change the anchor to the middle of the screen by selecting the anchor dropdown and choosing
the middle option.
Can I change the position of the text based on its anchor?
So zero at the X and the Y positions.
And because screen positions are calculated from zero zero, which is the top left of the screen, you
can see that the text is actually anchored at the same point.
So to fix this, I'm just going to set the alignment two point five on the X and the way of the tax
element and that will center the text force.
And I also want the text to be much bigger.
So this is going to be like a main focal point.
And we can do this by going to the options here and dropping down the font options.
And we can just increase the font size to 80 and also change the font to use the light typeface, just
as the robots so bold looks a little bit unpleasant to me.
So this is no throwing in our placement off again, because we've gone past the X and Y binds here.
You can see the outline of the green box, which is trying to kind of contain the text with him so we
can fix this by just using this tech option to set the text to size this to content.
And this will automatically update the kind of binding box for this based on the size of the text as
it updates.
Okay, so now we've got something which is perfectly central and this can look a little bit unsettling.
So I'm just going to move this up the screen.
Minus 200 units on the Y.
So the final step we need to take for our text element, and this is very important.
So really make sure you don't miss this stage or else you'll be stuck later when we're implementing
our logic to update the text.
So, again, really important.
And that is to take this very small is variable box at the top of the details panel.
Super easy to miss.
A lot of people can forget to do this.
And it means that we will not have access to anything in our development section that isn't marked here
to be a variable.
And this isn't too important.
But I'm also going to rename the text just so we know what this is at a glance, rather than having
the generic text with a number after it.
So we can now move over to the graph section and start implementing our logic for the widget.
So we have three default elements here.
The tech, which you'll be familiar with is the constant update function.
The construct is similar to begin play.
So this is run when the game starts and the pre construct is essentially a constructor, which allows
us to visualize a widget changes in the editor.
So be careful here because if you place things and try to reference something like the player, which
only exists in the context of playing the game when you started running it, you'll be likely met with
the editor crashing as you're trying to get a reference that doesn't exist for our use.
We only actually need the construct.
So I'll just remove the two other events and to get this started.
I'm going to control drag the text element into the graph, holding controlled and dragging something
in.
We'll get the variable rather than setting the variable.
And this will allow us to start updating some of the properties.
So if we know drag from this return pen and search for a set text.
I then filled the text with get ready.
And this will just be something to give the player a heads up that the game is about to start.
Next, I'm going to create a timer by function name.
And this is the same as the time as we've been using in C++.
You can see here on the return node.
You even have an F timer handle.
So in a similar way to how we've used this in C++, we're just going to call a function.
So that will be the function name we have just here and we'll be calling that every so many seconds.
So I'm going to set this to be called Countdown.
And this will play every one second to create a kind of stopwatch style count display to make sure that
I don't have any spelling issues here.
I'm going to just copy the text and create the new function that we want to call.
And I'll paste that in here then to keep things nice and tidy.
I'll select everything that we've just created.
So those two nodes and on either of these nodes select to collapse this to a function and I'll name
the new function, initialize text.
Then something I tend to do with timers in blueprint's is to track in the function that the timer is
calling so that if I have a need quick access to this, especially in larger blueprints, I can just
double click the mode and that'll take me straight in.
That's one issue with blueprint timers.
Is it because you're only querying it by the text string or the name of the function?
It can make it kind of cumbersome to find the function that's calling if you've got a long list of functions
in the panel to left.
So doing this just is a nice, easy way in and out of the time of functions.
So now back inside of the current time function, we need a new variable of type int that.
Oh, cool.
Start delay.
And as soon as we enter this function, we want to use our decrement in option.
We can then update the text condign text.
But this time it will read the value of the start delay integer.
So plugging this in will automatically convert this from an integer to a text variable force.
Then once we have our current on time is starting to show.
Then going to run a branch check from this site.
Kind of like an if statement.
And we'll see if the start delay is still more than zero, meaning that we haven't reached the end of
our countdown.
Then we're going to call the countdown timer again in another seconds time.
And if that's false and we are zero, then we want to set the text to go, which would just be again
the kind of heads up plan notification that the game has started.
Rules are going to clear the time here by passing in the name count down.
So we're stopping the count on time from running again.
And this is just kind of a security check to make sure that we haven't accidentally set something to
looping where we don't want it to.
And if you were to recall the timer, when you're not expecting it to fire off another time, then we
could have issues where restarts the countdown or start showing text when we don't want it to again.
And the final step is that we're going to create another timer by function name.
And this one will cool remove UI.
Again, just to make sure that I don't misspell this in the new function, correct.
I'll copy this text.
Go over and create a new function and paste in the remove UI text.
Then inside of this function, we just want to call a widget specific function, which is the remove
from parent for widgets.
This is basically how you remove a widget from the screen and also destroy it because it's not an actor
or an object in the same kind of way.
You don't use the destroy function like we've seen before.
We specifically use the remove from parent.
And there's one more thing that we need to do, and that's to create a function named set start delay.
We can outrank the start delay value into the graph.
So this is the other option from we use control drag previously out drag will allow us to set the variable
and we just want to hook the execution pins up from the start of the function to the variable.
And if we also drag the green int value pin into the start delay function mode, this will automatically
create an input value for us.
So just a handy tip.
If you're not familiar with blueprints and the notes, you can prefill input or output values like this
by just tracking them in.
You can say it's automatically named as well.
So super handy.
So this function will allow us to keep the start delay value secure in this class.
But we can call the function from other classes to easily update how long we want the start delay to
last.
When creating this widget.
So in a similar way to how we've been setting many of our variables in the C++ classes to be in the
private section to avoid other classes being able to access or accidentally override a property between
classes, we can do something very similar and blueprints.
By selecting our start delay integer and taking this to be private in the private checkbox here.
So this will be used later when we create our widgets from our game mode class.
But we kind of already know how we're going to be setting this up so we can get this ready for use later.
And just plug everything in when that game night class is ready to go.