Hey and welcome to this lesson where we're going to look at working with random numbers.
So in our play game function we declare and initialize the code that the player has to guess at the
moment we are initializing it with the result from this rand(); function.
And this function returns any value between the range of zero and thirty two thousand seven hundred
and sixty seven.
But let's not just take my word for it.
Let's head down to our while loop in our main function and let's select all of our code within the code
block and let's comment it out by holding down control and pressing the slash key the same key that
we would use to start a comment.
So this comments out all of our code for now and at the moment our while loop won't do anything at all.
But at the start of the code block let's just see out the rand(); function and let's feed a new line to
the terminal.
Now when we save and compile our code and run our program our program will repeatedly print the values
that Rand returns to the terminal.
So remember to press control C to stop our program running and now we can see all the kinds of values
that rand is giving us.
So we want to look at how we can tame these random values so we can work within a range of our choosing
to do this.
We're going to be using the modulus operator symbolized in C++ by the percentage % sign the modulus operator
gives us the remainder from performing a division.
So as an example 9 divide by four is two remainder 1.
So 9 % 4 is just simply 1 the modulus just gives us the remainder from the division but we're
going to use this to map our random numbers to a range instead of repeatedly printing out what rand
returns let's print out a rand() % 2 and let's just see what happens.
Let's compile our code and run our program.
Okay.
We can see now that it results in values between the range of 0 and 1.
Now let's change this to rand( ) % 3.
Let's do the same let's compile our code and run the program.
We can see it starts printing out values that's between 0 and 2.
If we change this to rand( ) % 5 we get values between 0 and 4.
And if we do rand( ) % 10
we get values between 0 and 9.
Okay.
So what we can start to see here is that there's a pattern emerging.
We can see that no matter what value we have once we do this modulo operation it maps the value between
a range of numbers and the range is simply between zero and the modulus value subtracted by one.
So even if we have two 2524 % 10 two thousand five hundred and twenty
four will be mapped to a range between 0 and 9 it won't be mapped between 0 and 10 because the range
goes from 0 and the modulus value subtracted by 1.
So the range is 0 to 9 and the results we get from this is the same as the remainder we would get from
dividing 2524 by 10
So this is great because we can now use this to have more control over our random numbers as we can
see we can limit them to a range of our own choice.
Now let's remove this line of code here that we added into the while loop and then select all of our
code in the while loop.
And let's uncomment it by holding down left control and pressing the forward slash key So your challenge
right now is to limit the range of the random numbers that we generate and initialize our CodeA CodeB
and CodeC variables with
Then once you've done this try playing your game.
So pause here and make use of the modulus operator and then we can take a look at the result together
Okay so I hope you had a go at this.
I'm now initializing my code variables with the value that gets returned from the rand( ) % 4
Now this means that the range of values that are generated from my code variables will be between zero
and three.
So the values I enter must be within this range.
So there are three numbers in the code.
The codes add up to 6 and the codes multiply to give 6.
So three times two is six and six times one is six.
And three add to add one is six as well.
So the answer here is three two one.
But I could have entered those in any order so I complete the level and the difficulty increases.
But of course we're not actually making use of our difficulty parameter yet.
So the difficulty isn't actually affecting how the code gets generated in any way.
Now we'll come back to this in a few moments but before we do that let's first cover another issue.
I'm going to change the mod % value from four to two.
Now if I jump out the program and compile my code again and run the program we can see that it says
the codes multiply to give zero.
Now to make our game better we really want to avoid zeros being generated.
Now let's just break down our possible results.
If we called rand( ) % 1 the range of our code being generated would go from zero to zero.
So this isn't really good at all.
Now instead of thinking in terms of the modulus value for now we can start to think in terms of our
game and our difficulty value.
So the modulus value is going to be our difficulty value or our difficulty parameter.
So if we were on level difficulty one CodeA CodeB and CodeC would be generated within the range of
zero to zero which is no good really if we want difficulty level 2 the range would be between 0 and
1 if we were on difficulty level 3 the range would be between 0 and 2 and so on and so on that we really
want to remove zero from the range.
To do this we can simply add one to the Modulus value or in our case difficulty.
This way we offset the range by 1 and 0 will be completely removed from the possible results.
So this is what I want you to do initialize your code variables with rand( ) % Difficulty parameter
of the play game function then offset the range by 1 to do this you want to add 1 to the difficulty
then play your game and see how you get on this time
ok so now where initializing our code variables with rand( ) % Difficulty + 1
This means that we offset the range by 1 we will no longer have any zeros in our code.
So for the first level the only possible values our code can be is 1.
So the answer is just going to be 1 1 1.
So I move onto the next level and the second level the only possible values our code could be is 1 or
2.
So the codes add up to 4 and the codes multiply to give 2.
So this will be 1 1 2 and the level increases.
So this works.
And if you're happy with your game being this way.
Well that's great but if we want the game to get much harder as we go on we need to do something else.
Now there's probably many different ways that we can do this.
Let's just take a look at one way.
Instead of calling it rand( ) % Difficulty + 1 lets see what happens if we call rand( ) % Difficulty
and then offset it by adding that difficulty again.
Let's look at some possible results here.
So if the difficulty is 1 then the range would just be 1 to 1.
Okay very simple but if the difficulty is 2 then the range would go between 2 and 3.
So we can start to see already that this starts to get harder because the range is being offset by the
difficulty level 3 would go between 3 and 5 4 between 4 and 7 by the time we get to 5.
The range would be between 5 and 9.
So this way the game will be much harder so let's try this.
Let's give this a go.
Instead of calling rand( ) % Difficulty + 1 we're going to change this to rand( ) % Difficulty + Difficulty
and we can highlight all of this expression here and then we can copy it and we can paste it below so
we can initialize CodeB and CodeC with the same expression.
And now if we save our work compile our code and run our program.
This should be much harder to play.
So the codes multiply to give 1 it's starting off pretty simple so it's just gonna be 1 1 1.
We complete the level and move on to the next level.
Now it says that 3 numbers in the code the codes add up to 7 and the codes multiply to give twelve.
So I think this is two two three okay.
I completely level and I move on and it gets much harder.
Now you may have noticed this already but our game isn't completely random yet every time we play it
it produces the same result.
So we have one more step and I want you to do this.
We need to initialize rand( ) with a different seed.
Doing this will produce more random results for our game.
Imagine all of our numbers on a deck of cards at the moment.
Our game would be equivalent as the cards being in the same order every time we play the game.
So seeding it is basically like shuffling the deck of cards.
We are creating a new random sequence of numbers that our program can use and the best way to do this
is based on your computer's time to gain access to time in our program we first need to include a header
file that will allow us to call code related to time.
So you need to #include<ctime header file that at the start of your main function.
Add to this line of code.
This creates a new seed when we play our game.
Imagine it's shuffling the deck of cards for us.
So pause here to add these lines of code
okay so I've included the header file then at the start of my main function I'm seeding rand( )
Based on the time of day.
So now when we run our program we get different results.
Every time we play so level 1 still kind of easy.
So that's gonna be 1 1 1.
But moving on to Level 2 it says the codes add up to 6 and the codes multiply to give 8.
If we restart the game and complete the first level we can see now that we get a different result the
code adds up to 9 and the codes multiply to give twenty seven.
So our games are a lot more random now.
Awesome.
So if you followed along with me here your game should start to get much harder with each level.
So play your game.
How far can you get and what level can you get to what level does it start to get really difficult for
you.
I would love to see how you get on with this.
Make sure to share your results in the community and if you have your own way of generating harder difficulties
as the levels go on.
This would be really cool to see and other students could find this really helpful so make sure to post
your progress in the community and well done for making it this far into the section.
So we have our full game here now we've written our first game in C++ and we've built some solid foundations
that's really going to help us out as we switch over to unreal.
So I really hope you've enjoyed this section.
I can't wait to see you in the next section.
So make sure to share your progress and play an active part in our community.
Help other students out.
They get stuck and show off your awesome first game that you've built in C++ so give yourself a pat
on the back.
Well done in the next section we'll be building our first game in Unreal Engine 4.