Hello everybody and welcome.
In this lecture I'm going to make sure that we can use the player input itself before we start assessing
it we need to make sure that we are happy with retrieving it.
So go ahead and play our game and see what we're going to have by the end of this lecture is really
straightforward.
I really want to make sure that we're not losing any of you at these beginning stages so go ahead.
Press tab presents to continue.
Okay so if I start typing something like our head and work it will assess it at the moment but it's
gonna repeat it back to us it's going to say cake which proves to us that we're taking the user's input
and we're doing something with it.
We're just repeating it back at the moment.
And if I was just typing something else it would repeat it back.
Of course it's not a nicer gram.
So we could try something else.
There we go.
So they're all repeating back to us.
And that's key there because that shows us that we're using the player's input for something else.
Okay.
Welcome back over to visual studio code.
The first thing we need to know is what are we going to use what we already know that we're going to
print a line out to our console so we can put that in straight away but at the moment we're not actually
printing anything and our inputs got to be stored somewhere.
Now some of you will automatically have already reached for this word input.
Now let's break down what's going on here we have a function that's called on inputs essentially and
it's referencing the user input which is of type f string which is good.
That means that in here we don't have to type anything else other than that variable name.
So if we type in inputs within here everything should clear down which is great.
We can save our file.
We can go over into and rail and stop the play that was going on.
I can reap compile my code.
It should take a few seconds to do.
And once we've done that we should find we're able to access and repeat back whatever the user has typed
in essentially parroting.
So now of I typing cake badly it all repeats it's if I type it incorrectly it will also repeat it back.
So that's brilliant we're able to now grab the user's inputs if we have a look.
It's this variable here inputs.
It also means when we go ahead and create our variables we cannot call anything inputs.
In this case because it's already been declared and we're going to leave that as it is as that's parts
of the base code we're working with do run through this very simple projects here and make sure when
you compile in unreal it behaves exactly how we're expecting which will mean that we're now able to
assess the user's inputs which means we can start making our basic game loop and we'll continue this
in the next lecture.