Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to dive straight into a challenge we've covered.
If statements before and being able to evaluate one thing against another so I think we've got all the
core skills we need in order to complete this challenge.
So I'd like you to write all of the code that you do in the on input function.
Now this will be changing around later on especially as we discuss some of the issues that writing everything
in this function will cause.
However it will work as far as we're concerned for what we want to achieve.
If you do have some introductory things you want to change.
By all means leave in the game start function.
Now after you've written your code and run it successfully What do you think about having all of our
code here.
Can you foresee any issues.
Think about it carefully.
One of the issue you may notice is that it doesn't follow our flowchart.
We need to do something slightly different we need to put some of the code in different places in order
for it to run the same as the flowchart we've created.
So that's one of the problems that we'll need to fix and it will raise some of the others as we actually
go through the code once we've got it in front of us.
Now write code that evaluates whether the input is equal to the hidden word.
And in order to do that I suggest you use an if this is true.
Do this else do that in order to check and evaluate the inputs.
So go ahead pause a video now if this takes 10 15 minutes or so to run through.
Especially if you're new to it don't worry.
That's perfectly normal.
And then we'll run through the code itself when UNbacked supporters video now and give us a go okay.
Everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and write code that evaluates the inputs and the hidden word.
Okay so this is our code as it stands at the moment.
And I will run through some of the issues that we may come across as we actually start typing the code
as well.
So we're working with in the on input function that's fine.
Remember the code runs as it's seen.
So clearing the screen is the first thing we want to do.
If we put all our code above that.
It may be on there for a split second or a nanosecond but we won't see what we've types of clear screens
going to have to be at the top then we're going to have to declare and initialize the hidden word.
That's fine.
The next thing we need to do is perhaps give.
Well if we give instructions at this point what happens and we think about sets and we give instructions.
It's too late because this is after the users press enter.
So if we asked the question please guess the four letter word and we put it down here.
We would have a problem.
It would appear straight away.
So I'm immediately going to put that at the very top here.
So this is one final instruction where begin play happens Press any key to continue.
Well actually we're going to guess the four letter word we'll hard code this in for the moment.
So we guess the four letter word.
Now the problem with this is that we've hard coded the number of characters it is if you want to change
that we've got to remember to go back to that point in our code and change that number so I'm going
to make a comment here and I would suggest that you make comments as you go along as well that we've
got ourselves a magic number.
It's going to be a pain in the backside to remember remove won't do it.
At the moment though sit down here we don't need this print line.
We don't need our code parroting back to us.
So we need an if statement.
And fortunately if I just press tap it asks for the condition.
So we're really evaluating the inputs and the hidden word.
So if the input itself is exactly the same as the hidden word and we can do this type of evaluation
because they're both strings so we can assess them like that's the next thing we need to do.
I can press tab to go down to our code block.
So if that is true we've won the game.
So at this point in time I can print out a line and of course I've still got it stored up there and
typing.
You have one.
It's as simple as that exclamation mark.
Now I'm going to copy that again because I'm going to use that with my else.
So else press tab.
We've got the code there.
We're going to print out and change the one for a lost.
So let's run through our code and what we expect it to do and perhaps highlight a few more issues as
we go through.
So first of all it would be great at the moment if the hidden word was declared at begin play.
But the problem with it being declared and initialized in begin play is that it has scope only with
him begin play.
So on impact has no idea what hidden word is.
So we need to elevate it up and we'll talk about elevating it up and not now making it global but making
it what's called an instance variable also referred to as a member variable in an upcoming lecture.
But for the moment for this one shot it's absolutely fine.
The other issue with this is if we had more than one life the hidden word is being set every time it's
asking for input.
And that's another reason for the hidden word being outside of this function.
So let's make a comment that
and we'll talk about where we're moving it to later on.
So if the inputs is exactly the same as the hidden word then you've won if it isn't.
You have lost let's see if this works.
So we're gonna save our work and then open up bull cows once it's open remember to press compile.
I know so many of you because I used to do it as well.
When you save your code you forget to hit compile and then wonder why it doesn't work says compile complete
remember that if it does say compile complete in you play and it still does the previous thing.
Then you may have to press compile again I've seen that a couple of times but I know it's worked because
I've only just added guess the four letter words I know that's there.
Perhaps too many exclamation marks.
So let's guess how.
Well simply typing Kake you have one.
If we type in anything else it will say you have lost including if we type in nothing because it's on
inputs.
So that's another question that we're evaluating inputs just based upon when someone presses return.
So unless it's the right one then we won't have one.
Perfect.
So we've got everything working that it's not ideal at the moment because we need to rearrange our code
so it works a bit more logically.
It certainly isn't following our flow chart but we have let's just have a quick look at that before
we finish up okay.
So according to this flow chart we were to print a welcome message.
Then we set our hidden word and then we ask for a guess.
Well at the moment we're asking for a guess before we set the hidden word.
Now that wouldn't be ideal because later on we'll be setting the hidden word and assessing its length.
And when we assess its length we won't be able to ask for a guess of the x.
No word because we won't have had the information yet.
Anyway we're now on this bit here really.
We're waiting for inputs.
So both a hidden word and asking well asking for a guess is above.
That's fine.
The hidden word is being coded beneath here which makes no sense in the long run because it's being
reset every time we run this code which means if we had multiple guesses the hidden word might be changing
every single time and then at the bottom we have our if statement is it correct yes or no.
And that's pretty straightforward.
So that it's absolutely fine.
But there's something in the middle here that we need to rearrange.
And it basically hinges about the hidden word and how we store that and how we access that.
So remember to share your thoughts and concerns what issues could you foresee.
It's always important to evaluate your own code assess it against your flow chart that you've made and
think logically through your code and try and catch any potential issues nice and early like we're starting
to do now and we'll get to fixing these things in the next lecture.