Hello and welcome and this lecture, we're going to be dealing damage to this actor here.
We're going to do that by overriding a virtual method called take damage on the actor.
And you can see in the log here, we've got the health decreasing as I shoot this character all the
way down to zero and then it stops zero, not going into negative numbers.
So let's dive in and see how that's done.
So while we are currently being able to do damage to the actors that we hit here, such as this guy,
we are not actually receiving that damage.
So this is where virtual methods of the last lecture come in, because just like begin play or tech,
we want to be able to receive damage on an actor.
Now, fortunately, if you go to the actor Don H and have a little look in here, you can see that there
is this take damage virtual method.
Now, this can be done also with events and you will possibly have seen it done that way before where
you register for events.
Now, what I'm going to do is just a different way of doing damage where we actually have damage stored
against the actor rather than in a component.
And one easy way of receiving that damage is through a virtual method here.
And this is the virtual myth that we're going to override.
So I'm going to go ahead and copy this and go over to our particular actor, which is the shooter.
Carrots can be crickets.
It's just go search for the shooter's character, Dot H.
And the one thing that I wants to check is where this comes in.
The actor.
H.
So if we scroll up, we should be able to see which section we are in here.
So I'm just going to scroll right up until I find that what whether we're in public or what.
They go we're in the public section.
So this ought to be in the public section here as well.
So I'm just gonna stick it underneath our tech and set up play input component.
Over in the shooter dot h.
And we'd just paste it in.
And as I said, in the last nature, you can use override to make sure that you're indeed overriding
a virtual method from the parents.
And it's not necessary to have virtual in front here, but we'll keep it anyway.
And he can see all of the data that's coming in to take damage.
We have got a damage amount.
The damage events and the controller that is causing the damage, the instigator and the damage caused
all that stuff that we'd passed in from the gun is cropping up here as well.
So that's great.
Now, if we go ahead and do a control shift, P creates implementation or copy and paste, then we can
go and make the implementation for take damage.
But the first thing to be wary of is that whenever we we're overriding something we want to think about
calling the O the parents class version of take damage because there may be some implementation in there
that needs to run.
So that's what we're going to do.
We do this always.
We've done it with tech.
We've done it with begin play.
You can see we've always got this supercool at the beginning.
And that's because when we override a method, we override it completely.
We completely remove that behavior.
So if we do want that behavior, which we typically do, then we should always start with a call to
super.
So we're going to do a call, take damage.
That's going to take the damage amount.
So this is where it gets a little bit tedious, sadly, my alter complete tool doesn't do this for us
damage event.
Then what was the next one we had the control.
So the event instigator, it's just copy and then we've got the damage causer, which is the actor.
So all of that gets called up to the parents implementation of take damage.
And the one other thing is that this has a return type.
So the actual damage applied.
So we're going to float.
Damage applied is the return value from take damage.
So we're just going to keep hold of that damage applied there and realistically, that's going to be
the same as the damage amount in our particular use case.
But not necessarily.
So we're going to use the damage applied.
The next thing I want to do is keep hold of the information about how much health we've actually got.
Now, the way I'm going to do this is with two variables here.
The first one is I'm going to make both them you properties because I want to make the health visible
in the inspector, at least for now.
And we're going to have the first you property be the max health.
That's what we initialize the health to initially.
So you property, it's going to be an edit defaults only because it's going to be used in Biggin play.
And so changing that value of Mac's health after the fact, it's not going to have any impact.
So, Max, health, I'm going to set the max health to 100 here, and then we're going to have one other
property here, which, as I said, is going to be a new property just for us to be able to inspect
it.
And I'm going to have that as visible anywhere.
But not editable, because we don't want to be able to change that health, at least not at the moment.
He might want that for debugging purposes, but I don't.
So we're gonna have health here and in begin play, we're going to set it up so that that health.
Is equal to the max health.
So we start off with Sporn, we have our maximum health and then we can start decreasing.
It says time for a challenge for you to decrease the health of the character.
So you're going to use the damage applied here rather than the other option here.
So we've got to shoot character CVP, take damage.
We've got a damage amount, but we actually want the damage applied that comes back from take damage
cause that could have been reduced by some process in the parents.
So we do that.
Then we reduce the value of health and log the results just for simplicity's sake so that you can check
that when you're shooting at that A.I. that his health is going down and then test it out.
So pause video and have a go.
Okay, welcome back.
So let's give it a shot.
So health, we basically wants to decrease that by the damage applied.
But is that enough?
Well, what if and damage applied is greater than the amount of health we have got left?
Well, in that case, we probably want the damage applied to be that amount of health.
So the way we can do this is we can say that the damage applied.
Should be equal to the F math dalts, men of the health.
And the damage applied.
So this is the damage that we basically want to apply.
So we're going to I'm actually gonna go ahead and rename that instead of calling it damage applied.
I'm going to call it the damage to apply.
Damage to apply like Soga, rename that throughout here and then the damage to apply against health,
minus the damage to apply.
That makes sense and that basically at worst, that's going to be the health.
So that's going to set our health down to zero.
And remember, we're supposed to return the damage that we actually applied.
So to return damage to apply, which has now been applied.
And we finally once a year, we log at the end here, which is just going to be a warning so we can
see it.
And I want this to be the health left here.
And that's going to be a percent F two percent lowercase F to show a float.
And then we can pop in the health right there and go ahead and hit.
Build.
Now, mine's compiled after fixing a missing semicolon here.
Let's go and make sure that we have a window.
Developer tools and we want the output log here so that we can see that log message.
And I'm going to go ahead and hit play and go and try and shoot at this character.
If I shoot him, they go.
Health left 90, 70, 60, blah, blah, all the way down to zero.
And if I keep shooting, we don't go below zero because of that F math dot min.
So that tells me that we've got our health setup correctly, just another way of doing it, as opposed
to doing it within a compound.
You can do it within the actor as well as some pros and cons of that approach.
Eventually, you may want to strip this out into a separate components so that you can reuse it on different
elements.
But this is just another way, as I say now, because this character isn't looking particularly dead
after we shot him down to zero health.
We need to fix up the animations to support that.
So we'll see that in the next lecture.
And I'll see you there.