Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to start using the trigger volume in anger so trigger volumes are extremely
useful tools.
We've covered some of the examples in which you could use them.
However you can pretty much use them to trigger any behavior in your game that you want.
It's simply a volume that can detect things entering or leaving.
And that's really useful because that means we can walk into the trigger volume and trigger the doors
open and if we leave it we can trigger it to shut.
And that's very key to the dynamic for simple game mechanics that we've got now.
We're using one as a pressure plate and you can use one as well.
Anything you like you can trigger any other thing to happen in the scene.
Now one of the really useful things that you can do is control what when it enters that trigger volume
will trigger the pressure plate to activate and open the door.
So we're going to choose what can open our door and we're going to use is over lapping actor on a trigger
volume in order to do that.
Now we're going to you be using something called polling versus events a brief word on that so polling
is simply just checking all the time.
Similar to when your kids are in the back of a car.
Are we there yet are we there yet.
Are we there yet.
Whereas an event driven system the parent would turn around to the child and say oh we have arrived
and events are something we will cover later on in the course.
Okay.
So to start off what I'm going to do is currently we have a pressure plate here being what is going
to be opening the door and we really want something else to just define what can activate the pressure
plate.
So perhaps an actor that opens and then we can go and select ourselves in order to test it.
Now at the moment I will just give you this hint as we move forward when we press play we suddenly exist
in our scene.
If ICE open up the hierarchy the world outline or a bit more you can see all of these yellow items that
appear but only when we press play they're temporary actors that are spawned in.
And if we press eject at the top here and just have a look back at ourselves this is what we currently
look like when we start playing the game.
It's a very basic porn which is simply a player controlled actor.
There is another type of actor called a character which is a much richer actor.
However it does come with a ton of boilerplate code so we want to keep things simple at the moment and
we'll approach that again later on.
So now I can go ahead.
I can stop that for the moment and let's go and expose a property on our open door component so we can
select the actor that opens.
So let's go ahead and open that up.
Okay.
So this is going to be another you property.
Hayes is working nice and quickly.
Is it going to come up with edit anywhere quickly.
No it's not going to.
Okay.
So what are we going to put in here.
So what do we need here What type is going to open our door.
Well currently we're thinking about when we walk into that trigger volume so if that would be a pawn.
So we start typing a pawn then we can use that in order to open the door.
However later on we want to be able to put something else in there which is probably not going to be
a pawn or a character it's more likely to just be a standard actor.
And remember that a pawn inherits from the Actor class.
So we can be a bit more generic and have an a actor.
Once again this is going to be a pointer.
And what can we call this.
Well I'm going to call it the actor that opens.
Be very specific about how you're naming things.
Okay so that save our code go over it's unreal and compile and what we should see is down on the open
door this will update in a moment we should have our target your the pressure plates that it's linked
to.
And then finally the actor that's going to open it.
Now this is where you can potentially end up having a crash if we're not careful because in a moment
when we actually go to this implementation of this and starts coding in the actual opening of the door
this is where we're going to start having a problem.
Okay so we wants to enter this volume but we don't exist at the moment.
So in this dropdown we can have a look down the various actors we don't exist yet because we only exist
when we press play.
So we can actually go in and inject select the door go to the open door component.
And now we exist as the default pawn in the scene.
So we'll be able to test that in a bit but we cannot do that at the moment because we haven't got the
code in place so let's go over to the implementation and pop that in now.
Okay.
So over in the implementation file I'm going to jump in straight away with a challenge.
So it's time for a bit of practice with your refactoring and then we'll get back on to just finalizing
the code.
So I'd like you to go ahead and put the code we have created into in the tick component function into
a new function called Open Door so we're gonna refactor all of that out.
And then of course we can call open door.
This is the reason for doing it when we need it rather than just every frame which is not how we want
to play our game.
Now remember you will also need to add code into the header file as well.
Now it's the first time we've done that in this section so you might have to refer back to your previous
notes.
I'm sure you'll be absolutely fine.
And then of course we'll finish off our code.
So go ahead pause the video now refactor your code and I'll see you back in a few minutes Okay everybody
Welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and refactor our code okay.
So let's go ahead and do the refactor now I'm going to go to my head of our first line like doing it
in this order.
So it's not going to return anything.
It's going to be called open door.
If I spelled that correctly open door.
There we go.
And what do we need to pass into it.
We are going to have to pass into the delta time but I don't think there will be anything else at the
moment.
Otherwise we can't use delta time or not also delta time and a semicolon on the end.
Okay.
I think that's all we need to do there.
So it's not returning anything as we've discussed it's parts of the class open door so open door come
along code on open door that's fine and we're passing in the floats for Delta time let's make sure we
spell things correctly and then we can open up our curly braces and then we should be able to just move
this chunk of code down and into it's using ult and the up and down arrows.
Okay.
Now this here was just a test.
I'm going to comment it out for the moment.
Do I want it down here as well.
I will keep it here for the moment but we're going to have some different comments in a bit.
So get the expectations a string.
Yes that's fine.
That can that can go reading it's absolute clear what that does.
Okay.
So we've refactor that.
So the final thing to do after any refactor is to go ahead and call the function we've just created
and make sure everything works as we would expect it to.
Let's go ahead over into unreal.
Now it should once we compile it behave exactly like it did before providing I've not missed anything
silly okay.
The compile has failed what have I missed.
Oh I've not passed out to there you.
I have missed something silly too few arguments in here so let's pass in delta time.
Silly me.
OK.
Let's compile a complete let's press play.
Excellent.
It opens up.
OK so let's go ahead back into the implementation file and we need to say open door but only if something
happens.
So let's start this off if so what are we saying here we're talking about the pressure plate itself.
So.
So if the pressure plate and we know that that is a pointer.
So we need the arrow operator.
Okay let's.
Using tele sense here as well as the documents if we need them.
So if I type in overlap which is something I'm looking for.
Excellent look at that is overlapping actor returns a boolean that's really useful because that's what
we want is overlapping actor that's fine it's going to need something coming into it.
And that is the actor that opens now is open.
If I missed the s Yes I have.
Okay.
So actor that opens actor that opens let's make sure those are saved.
And I don't think that's used anywhere else at the moment.
So watch out for spelling mistakes like that.
And then what do we want to do what we want to open the door now that we have this implementation of
our code.
This is where it's very easy to start crashing because we can have what's called a null pointer which
simply means that the pointer doesn't point to anything.
If you did reference a null pointer which results in undefined behavior which quite literally means
that the C++ standard doesn't say what the behavior should be.
So literally anything can happen but most likely it will end up in a crash without any useful error
messages.
OK.
So before we go we've got a couple of red squiggles here and I think yeah we're missing a brackets at
the end of that.
OK perfect let's save our code go over into unreal and I want to press play I don't I need to compile
first and this is where you need to make sure I know I've got it.
But on the open door component you need to make sure you have a pressure plate selected on any of the
objects that have open door on them.
Otherwise when you press play on real crash at that point due to the referencing a null pointer will
go and protect against that in the next lecture.
But for the moment if we eject and then we can look back it's our lovely port but what we can now do
is go to our door go to the open door component in the act that opens we can set it to the default porn
just for testing.
We can repossess and now hopefully if I walk into this corner I'm going to walk backwards.
We should see that our door opens.
Awesome.
Now notice here that it's only opening on that one door.
Let's eject again for a second so I'm going to Whoops.
Okay.
Now the reason why was this door over here on the far side had active open set to something.
This one was still none.
However we don't want to have to do things like that and we're going to setup programmatically in the
end anyway excellence.
We've now got our trigger volume doing something.
We just need a bit of protection in place because otherwise it will crash and we'll sort that out in
the next lecture.