Welcome in this video, we are going to get Visual Studio Community 2019 set up and installed on our
computer.
The reason we're going to do that is because with it comes a compiler.
So I need to define what a compiler is.
Well, we when programming our games in unreal engine programming in C++, we want to speak English
or something as close to English as possible.
A lot of people have say C++ isn't very English at all, but we want to be as close to English as possible,
otherwise known as a high level language.
We want to use words that are familiar to us.
But the computer wants to communicate in something very different.
Ultimately, it wants ones and zeros.
It wants binary in order to perform its operations.
So the compiler, in very simple terms as a first definition, is something that converts R code on
the text of our code into ones and zeros that the computer can run.
And this process overall is called compilation.
Right.
So the reason the primaries and we're installing Visual Studio Community 2019 is because it's the easiest
way to install a compiler.
Now, if you're on a Mac, hang with me for just a moment, because I'm just trying to explain a little
bit more about the unreal development environment.
Then you can skip forward to the next video where we'll show you how to install X code, which is going
to be the equivalent package on the Mac.
So this is the wider picture.
We want to make games in on real engine.
We also want to learn to code in C++.
So what we gonna do on the P.C. is install Visual Studio Community 2019 and on the Mac we're going to
install something called X Code.
We're also I haven't put it on the diagram for simplicity.
We're also going to install something different on both systems, which will also work on Linux called
Visual Studio Code.
And we'll see a little bit later how that's different and why we are using, in addition, as a second
option for you.
But once you've got Unreal Engine and one of these two, what they call integrated development environments.
You also have behind the scenes a compiler.
This thing here and then that actually writes code and the code files to the disk system.
So that's the folder there.
So you see an unreal engine.
It runs code from your desk.
Unreal engine and your integrated developed environment.
All talk to the compiler, which turns text that you've got on your desk into other types of files on
the disk, which executable, and that can be run by the machine.
So that's kind of the environment we're working in, again, at a very top level view, just so you
understand where we are.
So what I want you to do in a moment is to install Visual Studio Community 2019, literally just do
a Google search reveals studio whole, your favorite search engine being or whatever, and go and find
Visual Studio Community 2019.
You don't absolutely have to have a Microsoft account to get this running.
It will ask you to log in, but you least at the time of recording, can skip that.
Probably worth just grabbing a Microsoft account or using whichever one you've got.
Anyway, I'm not gonna take you step by step through the installation, but I am going to show you the
end result.
So you basically it's a standard software installation.
It's gonna change a little bit over time.
So there's no point in me showing you absolutely verbatim.
But go get Visual Studio at a time of recording.
It started off by downloading a 70 or 67 megabyte, an initial set of files.
Then it presents you with an installation screen, something like this.
Again, this is subject to a small amount of change over time.
But what we're looking for is the game development with C++ option.
If you scroll down, it's about halfway down the list and take that option.
It'll pre take a whole bunch of things that are required.
It'll give you the top three, maybe one or two other options.
But basically you want the default there.
Plus, it's important that you click Unreal Engine Installer, even if you already have unreal engine
installed.
So please make sure all these settings are set.
Game development, C++ on the left hand side there and then the four checkboxes that I've got on the
right and that will make sure that you've got everything you need and all of the dependencies that you
need installed.
So once you do that and set the download going, as you can say, it's up to seven gig of total space
required.
But the download on the next screen isn't seven gig.
It's like one point eight at the time of recording.
And that's gonna take what depends on the speed your broadband doesn't.
It could take minutes, could take hours.
It will helpfully also install while it is downloading.
Okay.
And when that whole process finishes, you're going to end up with something like this, which is your
log in screen.
And one of the options will be I don't want to sign in.
I could sign in later.
So that's what I was talking about.
Now, if you're still on Mac, if you're on Mac rather and you're still watching, do skip over to the
next video, because I'm going to be showing you X code.
Obviously, you won't be doing still visual studio community twenty nineteen on Mac because it doesn't
exist on Mac.
So your challenge now is simply to catch up with where I am and install a visual studio community 2019.
Simply get visuals to the community 2019 stowed and help each other in in the community as required.
When I come back, I'll show you how the end of the installation looks.
And just make sure it all works for you.
So over here on Windows, I have started with a completely fresh installation of windows.
All I had before I started this process was a vast installed.
And I've used the installation options that I showed you in this slide here.
I take game development, C++, an unreal engine installer.
And where I've ended up is here.
But the epic games don't in my desktop.
And I'm ending up being able to choose my theme.
I think I'll go for dark and start Visual Studio.
Now, that might take a little while.
As it says to start, we're not going to dwell on Visual Studio at the moment.
We just need to know that it is working right.
So I could click, for instance, continue without code or create a new project.
It doesn't actually matter what we take.
We just want to make sure that the thing is installed and looks something like what's on the screen
when it is.
Then you can just close it and then you can close the installer and you're good knowing that you have
visual studio ready for later in the course.
We're going to use a different cut down version of Visual Studio for the beginning of the course to
keep things simple for you could visual studio code.
But you have it ready for later.
You have it as an option.
If you want to use it at any point, you can follow along in visual studio community.
This thing we've just installed if you want to.
I would only do that if you're somewhat experienced as a developer.
If you haven't ever used visual studio or visual studio code before, then.
Just follow along the videos verbatim.
And do what we do as we go along because it'll be a lot easier for you.
Awesome.
So we are in good shape to carry on with the course.
And I shall see you soon.