Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to protect ourselves you may have already experienced a crash.
Let's give you an example.
In a previous iteration of this when I was playing around getting all the lectures sorted I had quite
a dense environment in front of me as I was trying things out and I had inadvertently I will try and
replicate it here a forced replication when I drag this door kind of into a position it was roughly
in when I was playing with it.
So about there also.
So I thought I was selecting the door when I was adding the open door components.
Let's make this area here because so we can say it's.
I didn't overtly select something like this sphere behind and added the component didn't notice that
I had added this particular component to something else and our seen that wasn't a door.
And equally it being a sphere would never rotate visually anyway so that we could see what was changed.
So I thought I just missed or forgotten that it happened.
Now if you have done this because I've been quite clear about this setting the pressure plate is essential
if you don't then you will find the unreal will crash.
Let's see that happen now.
So completely out of the blue you go.
Okay let's test our scene play and you'll get this crash report coming up and I'm just going to make
it a bit bigger here so we can see all of this text in front of us.
Quite frankly I know what the issue is it's because that's not been set.
We've got ourselves what's called a null pointer.
So we get undefined behavior and unreal just crashes it doesn't like it still.
Unfortunately it doesn't say here you have a null pointer go sort that's out to actually took me ages
because I thought that that wasn't the case so I'll just send a restart.
I hadn't realized that other attached to this component so something else.
So what we need to do is go into our code and set it up so that either error doesn't happen.
But even better we get a a message in the logs saying what is causing that problem.
So in this particular issue it's the fact that the pressure plate was not assigned on a certain actor.
So that's the important thing that's what we can output to a log.
And that's incredibly useful because then we can go to our logs and go Well why did it crash.
Let's go to our code and fix this issue.
OK.
So over MVS code the first thing I'd like to look at is what's called lazy evaluation.
This is not the way I really want to go with it because whilst it does protect us it doesn't give us
any useful feedback.
We're just protecting ourselves which in some cases is might might be what you want.
So if statements if they've got a series of checks they they lazily evaluate if the first condition
is false then it won't actually execute any code further down quite a good optimization.
If all of these things have to be true and if the first one isn't then there's no point in carrying
on.
So the way that we can do this is go if pressure plates and then we're gonna have to put up a bit of
a space there so I can actually type in pressure plate and then to Ampersand to say and and what this
will do if we go ahead and save it and go back over it into unreal.
Now if we go ahead and compile our code and if we go ahead and attach it once again this time not by
accident but on purpose the open door component to this sphere but do not set any pressure plates on
it we will find that it won't crash but it also won't give us any useful feedback either.
So let's go ahead add component our open door component we go and yes that's all there.
But we haven't set the pressure plate.
And before that would have crashed.
Unreal.
But if we go ahead and press play it will now work as we would expect it to which is really awesome.
Now that is the temporary fix for this.
If you've been having crashes we still need to make our carrot to be able to open this and we'll sort
out how to have the carrot to activate the pressure plate in a bit but before we go on and do that.
Let's first of all have something useful coming in the output log here.
Something that says Warning or even error in this case that's the sphere or whatever it's called has
a open door component attached to it but no pressure plate set.
OK.
So we can leave what we've already put in there as a layer of protection which is a good start.
However we can if we go ahead and press play we want it to check right at the very beginning we don't
want it to check every frame otherwise we'll get the error report at whatever the frame rate for game
is which is just silly we just need it once.
So at this particular point we need to log something.
OK.
So what happens when there's no pressure plate set.
Well this is going to be your challenge.
So what I'd like you to do is say that the actor name or words to this effect.
So you're gonna have to go and get the actor's name the actor name has the open door component on it
but no pressure plate sets.
Okay.
I should be pretty straightforward to do.
Possibly now and give that a go
Okay so that was a really quick challenge there.
Now of course protecting yourself against null pointers is incredibly important and will cover this
several times as we continue as well.
But making sure that if you're using pointers and that if there's not one sets you going to have issues.
So let's try and protect ourselves where possible.
So this is going to be a Yui log.
Again it's going to go in the log temp.
This time I'm not going to use just a log or a warning.
It's gonna be a proper error because this is quite quite serious because it crashes.
Unreal.
If we're not careful let's go in and create.
Here we go.
So has the open door on it.
But no pressure plate sets.
That's fine we can use that in there.
But we need another string in here to say the actor's name.
How do we go ahead and do that.
Well with that format specified there hopefully whatever we find will return a String.
Now we're going to need to d reference because of the F string that's required and then we can get Owen
up.
Excellent.
Now in get toner if we have a look with the arrow operator Let's type in name and just see if we've
got something that we can do a pen name that's got to be a gets name along here.
In fact there it is.
Get name.
Perfect.
Of course that's a function call.
So that's why hover over it XOM is returning an F string so that's going to feed directly into here.
That's a name that's now self-explanatory so we don't need the comments anymore.
So let's get rid of that so that is nice and clean.
It's checking beforehand.
Now when we go ahead over and turn real and compile Okay so let's press play.
And here we go.
We've got the same warnings that we've had sets up for ages but also this additional error that sphere
five this one here has the open door component on it but no pressure plate sets.
I think that requires a bit of punctuation on the end as well an exclamation mark.
How serious is brilliant.
That's exactly what we want.
So I am going to go back over here.
Put the exclamation mark on the end and save my code and stop my game from running.
There we go.
We have protected ourselves from unreal just randomly crashing.
And because this doesn't require any any open door component on it I've been warned about it so I can
come in here I can hover over by the way over in the world outline there we have spear fire if that's
what it was referring to.
So I can just delete the open door component from the actor.
And there we go.
But you know the pointers are something that will catch you out time and time again.
I hope they don't.
Protecting yourself as you go along as a sure way to help mitigate those problems.
And of course every time you're putting in that the level of protection it means that you're aware that
it might happen which means it's less likely to happen in the first place.
Okay.
That's it for this lecture and I'll see you guys in the next one.