Hello and welcome in this lecture, we're going to be getting a line of sight to our player from the
enemy so that we are able as the player to hide behind obstacles and not have that enemy followers not
have it.
Keep aiming at us until we pop back out and are visible to them.
So you can see here of hidden behind a corner and he can't find me.
Let's dive in and see how this can be done using unrolls tools.
So it's not ideal that this enemy A.I. concurrently follower's round corners, no matter how far we
go, how no matter how much we hide behind pillars, it's still going to find us.
It's still going to come and keep aiming at us.
We want to correct that.
And we're going to do this by checking the line of sight from the enemy to the player.
Now, as many things here in Unreal.
There is already a function for this in the controller.
Dot h.
Called line of sight.
And if you go in search of that, you can find that there's a function that returns a boolean.
So telling us whether or not we have line of sight.
And then it takes the actor that we should try to check for line of sight to.
And it automatically takes into account things like the eye position of the pawn in question.
All this sort stuff is already coded into one real's recall.
So it should be fairly straightforward.
If we go over to our A.I. controller, DOT, CBP, what we basically want to do is change things up
in tech so that we, first of all do an F line of sight.
Then what we want to do if we've got line of sight, is we want to move to and we want to set focus.
However, if we do not so in the ELT's, what we want to do is clear focus.
Remember, we saw that function before and we want to do the let's see, the stop movement, basically.
And that's another function that exists that we haven't seen yet.
So what I'm gonna do here is I can challenge you to implement the whole of this yourself if you feel
confident.
Otherwise, this ELT's is the more complex bit that we haven't seen before.
Because the other two we've already done to move to acto.
We've already done our set focus.
We've done that before.
And there's just this if line of sight, which we have just seen, is pretty straightforward.
You could implement that.
But how about this ELT's?
Let's give a go at implementing the just the ELT's clause.
It's not going to comp. because you obviously need an if before and else.
But let's go and just write out the ELT's clause.
So the first thing clearing focus, basically, we're saying stop trying to track the player because
you can't see the player.
You shouldn't be giving off the impression that you know where the player is, even though they are
high off with the can because it can access the player's location and so on and so forth.
But we need to give the illusion that the Alaya only knows as much as it can see.
So what we're going to do is we're going to call to clear focus.
And if we go over to the controller Deitsch and have a look at clear focus, you can see that it takes
in the priority that we need to clear now a reminder that these priorities are basically different levels
of focus.
So we have typically default movements and gameplay gameplay being the highest priority thing.
And what we set by default is gameplay priority.
So what we want to do is clear the gameplay priority, which means that if we have focus based on movement,
for example, if our A.I. then wants to move back to its guard point, then that focus will not be cleared
and it will be off moving back to its guarding point.
So that's the way focus works.
That's the way the priority system works there.
So what we just want to do is copy this EAA focused priority Kolon Keylong gameplay.
And that is the priority that we're wanting to clear on this line here.
And then the other thing is to stop the movement.
So we want to go over to the ALA controlled at H again and have a look at the stop movement.
And here, sure enough, there is a simple no arguments function called stop movement, which allows
us to do just that.
So they go.
That is basically the ELT's statement written.
So now it just reminds a remains a challenge for you to implement the F portion with the F line of sight
and the move to and set focus.
And you basically want to remove this code here and it's going to comment it out and sort out where
you want that to be.
So pause video, no challenge.
Slide here.
Just go and implement these three lines for yourself.
Okay, welcome back.
So let's start with that.
If so, if open brackets, line of sight to and then we want to do a line of sight to the actor, which
is the play a porn that we want to get access to.
So let's just uncommented that play a porn here and it's mucked up an indentation a little.
Let's fix that.
And then we want our brackets.
Curly brackets here and we want to do a move to actor.
Well, fact we can just copy and uncommented and move to actor here.
And we want to uncommented it.
Yes.
There we go.
And the focus, we can move that as well.
Now the focus.
It doesn't matter whether you do it before or after.
Move to actor because we'll move to actor does set a focus.
It sets a lower priority, the movement focus rather than the game play focus.
So it doesn't matter which order we do those two operations in.
And then finally, we can remove this commented out line where we are getting the play a pawn in Biggin
play because we no longer need it and everything's in tech now.
So we could remove begin play.
I'm going to leave it around in case we need it later on just to save me the hassle of adding it back
in.
Let's head over to unravel and compile and when that's done, let's play.
So let's see if we can hide from this act or I'm going to try and move around the corners reasonably
quickly.
This is a little bit tricky because they can move just as fast as you can.
But if you get round a corner like that, they go.
He's lost sight of me.
He's stopped trying to chase me.
I can just peek around the corner and see that as I'm moving.
He's not changing his aiming because we've cleared the focus.
Can peek around the corner from the other side.
See Pache Rand over here.
They go.
You can see he's still aiming at the last location where I was.
But if I should pop up in to sight, then he carries on aiming and moves within the acceptance radius.
Talking of which, I want that acceptance radius to be configurable by the designer.
So let's move it into where you property.
I'm going to create a private section here with a new property.
Which is gonna be an edit anyway, and we want that to be a float called acceptance radius and give
it the default value of 200.
And then this acceptance radius, we can go ahead and use in our move to act.
And if you compile, that's gonna give you exactly the same behavior, except now that you can change
that in the way I control a blueprint.
So that's it for this lecture.
We have discovered that line of sight function, allowing us to check whether the A.I. can or cannot
see something which implements this basic hiding functionality so the A.I. doesn't follow us when it
can't see us.
Next lecture.
We're gonna take things up a notch from these custom programmed A.I. and use behavior.
Trees are really powerful tool in unreal to make our eyes adjust that much cooler.