We're now getting to one of my favorite topics and things to implement when making the game feel pass
of a project.
So in this lecture, we'll be looking at the basics of camera shake.
Classes, what they are and how to use them.
This will be a primer to get ready to implement them into the game in the next lecture.
And to get started, I'll just create a new folder inside of the blueprint structure, a nameless one
general.
Then we're going to need our new camera shake class.
So we'll create all of this in blueprint as it's just a lot more convenient for this type of work.
As you'll see when we've created and implemented some of our classes.
So because EPIC had an understanding of just how important a feature camera shake can be.
They've been kind enough to create a default class type to handle the basics of any good camera shake
implementation.
So we're going to make use of this as we don't need to implement all of this from the ground up, adding
offsets and things to the camera like you would normally be expected to do in many other game engines.
And to find this, we're just going to type in camera shake into the search section just here and select
the camera shake option.
I named this new class, BP underscore camera shake hit.
And then use control and W to duplicate the class and rename it to BP, underscore camera shake explode.
So we don't have the two main camera shake classes that we'll be using.
And this is one of those scenarios which, like I've mentioned, would just be much more visual and
is suited more towards blueprint's than it is C++.
You could, of course, assign all of your values in a C++ class, but due to all of the values available
and the refinement that it usually takes to get a camera shake feeling right, we're going to want very
quick kind of instant results when testing.
And this is going to allow us to very easily tailor high-Strung the Shakey's for different scenarios.
And all joking aside, whilst camera shake can be a really effective way to display the kind of RGU
impact of a force being applied or the result of an event happening.
If it's overdone or applied with too much force, then it can take away from the player experience and
even make some people feel a little bit motion sickness.
And that's another reason that we want this very quick kind of iteration when working with this class
as refinement has going to be very important.
So let's begin by going into our camera shake hit and take a look at the properties available to us.
So this class is actually one of those.
We don't want the full kind of blueprint, Ed experience to make this a little bit easier to navigate.
We won't be doing anything in the event graphs.
This is all going to be purely changing the variables we have.
So if we close the window and then reopen this class to get the data only blueprint view, we can see
a lot of the properties available to edit a quick tip here as well.
I'm holding the shift and the left clicking the dropdown option to either collapse or hide all of the
properties in a category in one go rather than opening each dropdown section at a time.
So let's start looking at some of these settings and get an idea of how they will affect the basics
of camera shakes.
So the first three that we usually focus on are the oscillation and mights, which are how much movement
the camera will receive.
The duration is then how long this will last.
With zero being no movement and the blend in and act time are the percentage of time that it will take
to reach the maximum oscillation and begin to ease back to no movement.
Note that the blend in a light on normalized.
So this is between a range of zero and one.
So I already have some values tested that I feel work quite well for the smaller and quicker camera
shake here.
So I'd recommend using these just for.
And then after showing you how to implement these.
Come back and try some different values to see how the results may change.
Next, we have the options to change the rotation, location and field of view of the camera.
So generally it's gonna be the rotation and the field of view options that can cause people prone to
motion sickness to feel uncomfortable when this is implemented.
So we're just going to focus on moving the location of the camera during the shake.
Of course, this isn't to say that you shouldn't try using the rotation or field a few options.
But if you do, then I definitely recommend providing an option in your settings to enable or disable
the camera shakes or even consider making different options for perhaps an intense or a subtle camera
shake.
For those who still want to have some of that impact, but on a less intense scale way, you may even
remove some of the field of view or rotation options.
So for the location, though, I'm just going to set these to a kind of spherical shape using an amplitude
which controls the strength and frequency that controls how many times the shake will occur during the
camera shake duration that we have set.
Both of these will be set to a value of 10 on the X, Y and Z.
So this is a very simple implementation.
But the intention is that you'll be building on this and testing your own results as an example of what
you could do to emphasize something like a really large shot from a slow but powerful cannon.
You could really amp up the amplitude on the X or the forward axis with less frequency to have the camera
take one kind of big knockback towards the where the players looking from then have some smaller, more
frequent values on the Y and the said to make it feel like the camera's trying to correct itself.
So we've that class done.
Let's head on over to the explode hit shake and get that implemented before finishing off here.
So I'm can set the duration and the plan times to something higher for this one.
For the location effects.
I'm going to set the value of fifty on the X in the Y amplitude and twenty for the frequencies.
I'll leave these at axis set to zero for both.
Just because these changes then make the difference between the two effects much more obvious when we're
going back through and testing these.
So those changes made when I'm ready to start cooling these effects in our C++ code.
And hopefully it's really clear why we're setting all of these values in the blueprints just because
of the amount of.
Tweaking, they're going to be doing a number of properties available to us to begin with.
Going back, changing something here.
And then recompiling in C++ is just not going to be the best way forward for this type of implementation.