Hello everybody and welcome back.
This is a nice and quick tip about Find and Replace.
Now some of you will be familiar with this.
Some of us it will be totally new too but we'll take you through step by step the process of using it
within Visual Studio code.
Now find a replace is not just within the same file.
It's across multiple files as well so the moment we have C++ File and our header file and we've really
only got something in three places that we perhaps want to rename.
However it is worthwhile knowing that as your code grows it's likely that you may need to find something
deep within your code and you can also use this technique for that.
Now I will say now and forevermore please use this with caution.
Find the replace and just blindly clicking replace all which is one of the options can lead to trouble
especially if you've even got parts of a word selected and that's involved.
In other words or you have got something that's used in multiple places within your code let's dive
over to visual studio code and take a closer look.
OK so let's have a look at my in it game example.
I no longer wants to have setting up game as a comment.
I want this to be named appropriately so I don't need a comment against it.
So I need to find the other instances where init game exists.
Now we have a look under the Edit menu.
We get all of the controls we need.
We've got find replace which is kind of an extension to find as we'll see in a moment.
And then we've got multiple files so we can find in files and replace in files.
Notice controller nature and control shift h when it comes to replacing control an F and control shift
F when you're finding something in multiple files so I would always recommend highlighting your search
term.
What you're looking for.
And then if for instance here if we go control an F we get at the top right in it game and we're searching
for it and we have a couple of options here.
Bear in mind matching case is going to make sure that it's exactly how it looks.
And then we've got match the whole word.
Now the whole word is important because then you're not going to end up accidentally searching for parts
of words.
Now let's have a look at what happens if we click the little dropdown we toggle it to replace mode.
So if we wants to replace this with set up game we could do so and then we've got a couple of options
we've got replace and replace all.
I would recommend not just going replace all.
I'd certainly step through your selections.
We can see here we've got left them right arrow.
I go ahead and click the next match.
It will go down to where we've defined in it game and if we click that's again it will cycle back to
the top one.
So that's really useful for previewing.
So in this case I would happily click replace all.
However if we did that we would end up with a problem.
So I'm not going to do it at the moment I'm going to go to my ball Cal cartridge we've still got this
one here in a game and because we've got to find menu still open and we're searching for any game it
has found it.
Now what I'd rather do is be able to do that all at once rather than waiting.
So in this particular case I'm going to search for and replace in files instead so replacing files is
control shift nature or you can go to this menu and then we end up with a different option a search
box appears from here.
It's this little magnifying glass or looking glass on the left hand side of this area just a little
bit smaller.
And what we're looking for is just in it game.
So as I said before it's much better if you've highlighted the word you're looking for first your search
term and then searching for it.
And we can see when I pressed the control shift and H there is now just searching for it game.
Now I'm gonna to press enter there.
So actually does a search.
And we can see here it's found the two instances.
Notice there's a number two here in the bulk cartridge C++ file and the one instance within the header
file.
Brilliant.
And then it finds a load of other things as well.
So this is an example here where just replacing all is incredibly dangerous because we don't want to
just replace all we want to only replace it in these three instances at the very top.
Now this looks a bit noisy here.
We can collapse all of those by going to the top right of this area and just collapsing all it just
makes it a bit easier to read.
Now we can review each one of these one at a time so we can click them and run through just like we
were doing over here when we were going forward and back.
And if you're happy with them you can replace.
If you look here there's a little replace button that you can click on or use control shift and one
so you can do it at the level of the selection itself or within the file itself there load.
Notice here is bull cow carcasses dot CBP.
So if I go ahead and click replace all I know that it's replaced.
Oh no I didn't make sure there was something in the replace area.
So this is something else to watch out for something that you may have set up in this particular field
when we were just finding replacing within one file does not automatically appear over here.
So let's undo that.
There we go.
And we're going to replace it with set up game and we can see here what it's going to do as well.
So that's another clue it's removing in it game and replacing it with set up game.
So I'm happy with that.
I will replace them.
Excellent.
It will complain at this point because we haven't done it in the header file either.
So I'm going to replace it in the header file as well.
So we've now declared it over in here.
Let's make sure that everything is saved and there we go.
Our red squiggles have gone perfect.
So there we go.
There's the quick tip on finding and replacing use it with caution but you will find that it's very
easy to go ahead and find areas of your code very quickly once you get used to using it.
So for instance one of the examples here I haven't used I'm going to clear the search results and get
rid of search area on the left hand side.
So I wanted to find where we remove a life and I didn't know where it was in my code.
I could go control an F to find and let's decide type in life and there we go.
I found it and the view automatically moves as well.
That's perhaps something you didn't see before because we were at the very top of the file.
The other thing to note is right on the far right where you have your scroll bar you can see there's
a little area that's been highlighted that indicates where in the block of code we are where your search
term has appeared.
And here we go.
Highlighted red.
Here it is perfect.
I hope you find that really helpful.
That's entirely up to you whether you go ahead and rename your init game function setup game function
or perhaps you've got a better name.
If you have please share that in the forums.
But for now I can remove setting up the game because that's very explicit on what it does it's very
specific.
It is going to set up the game.
That's perfect.
I'm going to save my file.
Everything sorted and then of course final thing.
The litmus test is to make sure that your code she runs before you end up doing anything else brilliant.
So once your game is loaded up remember you will need to click compile and because we've edited the
header file and the C++ file is going to take a little longer to compile.
There we go with the compile complete we go ahead and play our game.
So typing in there you have lost you have one perfect.
That's exactly the behavior I'm expecting at the moment.
Excellent.
And as I mentioned before if you have indeed chosen a different name please share over on the forum
and I'll see you all in the next lecture.