Hello and welcome.
This lecture we're introducing to new types of asset, the behavior tree and the black border, which
are two assets that allow us to do a very interesting thing, has with A.I. allow us to make a much
more complicated A.I. very easily.
Let's dive in and see how we use them and set them up.
OK.
So we want to create some sophisticated A.I. behavior.
Now, the way we typically do this in Unreal is using a system called behavior trees.
Now, what are these?
Well, the best way for us to find out is to create one.
So let's go ahead and write, click and go.
We're looking here under the artificial intelligence.
And there's two options here.
Behavior tree and blackboard.
We are going to want both of these.
So let's go and start with the behavior tree.
The prefix for this is Beatty, and we're going to call this the enemy.
So behavior tree enemy A.I., just finish off with that Nago.
And we also need to create the other thing in there, which was a blackboard.
Now, what on earth is a blackboard to get to that in just a second.
But we're just going to call it the B B underscore enemy A.I. So Beebee for Blackboard Beatty for Behavior
Tree.
And while we're at it, we've got a few things relating to a I have got to create a new folder called
A.I. and we are going to move the blackboard, the behavior tree.
And somewhere here we have got our shooter, A.I. controller, all of that goes into A.I. move here
and then we can go into that A.I..
Deal with everything A.I. related.
Let's open up our behavior tree, first of all, and dock it to the main window.
So what on earth is this?
So this allows us to create trees of behaviors where you might say we've got part of the behavior here
is for chasing.
Part of it is for trolling.
Part of it is for something else.
Opening doors, all these kinds of things.
They typically structure behaviors as lots and lots of trees of behaviors and sub trees and so on.
We will see that all going on in detail.
But suffice to say, it is a great way of putting together natural behaviors in your games.
Now, it's not the be all and end all.
There's lots of A.I. techniques.
This might not be the one that you want to go with for your game, but it's a great start and you can
achieve quite a lot with it.
Now, the next thing we can see over in the top, right, these two assets are linked to the behavior
tree and the blackboard.
What on earth is a blackboard?
Well, the blackboard is kind of like the memory of your A.I..
It's essentially where you store a bunch of variables.
You input them from the game, play very much like we were doing with the animation system where you
had these these different properties that are being set by the gameplay.
We do the same thing with the A.I. We set lots of properties that give it information about its game
world and then the behavior tree draws on those properties and uses them to decide what it's going to
do.
It can set those properties.
It can use them as a memory.
It can read from those properties and all that lovely stuff.
So with that in mind, how can we set up our behavior tree and blackboard so that they are linked to
one another?
Well, we're going to expand out in our details pain.
You can see here that there is this blackboard asset and automatically it seems to have filled it out
for us such that the blackboard asset is linked to this be Beebee Enemy, A.I. Blackbaud Asset.
Now, we are going to be departing from C++ for a little bit to use these assets because obviously behavior,
trees and blackboards are entirely within the editor.
They're not blueprints as such.
They are their own ED tools.
And we can interface with them in C++.
But it does mean we're gonna be using the editor for the next couple of lectures as well as C++.
Not so much blueprint.
So it's great that we've got ourselves this behavior tree and this blackboard.
But how on earth do we actually use it?
Well, for that, we go back to our A.I. controller.
I if you remember, I controller is entirely responsible for running our behaviors.
And that is no exception here.
The behavior tree is just another thing that the A.I. controller can use or run.
So the way we're gonna do this is we're gonna go over to our air control dot h.
And we need to have a way of referencing in the blueprint what behavior tree we want it to run.
So the first thing I'm going to do is I'm actually going to go with the air controller TPP and comments
out the stuff in tech because we're going to be replacing this functionality with behavior, terie functionality
instead.
And then that means that I can remove this acceptance radius here because we no longer need it.
And instead, we're going to be using a pointer to the U.
Behavior.
And I have to spell this the American way tree and pointer.
That's the behavior tree you want there.
And I need to forward declare this with a class in front of it.
And then basically here, what I want to say is that this is the A.I. behavior.
And.
I'm going to keep the American spelling here just for consistency, so this is the A.I. behavior that
we want here that's actually run the behavior, it couldn't be simpler again.
The A.I. controls on each has a built in function for this.
We've got this run behavior.
Tree function turns a boolean.
Whether you are able to successfully execute it or not, start executing it, that is.
And it takes in the B.T. asset, which is appointed to the you behavior tree.
So that's what we're going to want to use and we can do this over in begin play.
So what we're gonna do is, first of all, we're gonna check that we indeed have a behavior tree here.
So we're going to say A.I. behavior.
Is not equal to null pointer because we do not want to be using it otherwise.
And then what we can do is we can run the behavior tree called our A.I. behavior.
It really is that simple to get an A.I. behavior running and we can go ahead and compile.
And one more thing we can do with the heavy trees is we can kind of see them running at runtime.
But to do that, you need to have some sort of node in here.
So we're just going to add in a node without fully understanding what it does.
I'm going to add a sequence node and I'm going to hook it up by dragging down from the root node, the
bit underneath the root node, the highlights when I mouseover it down to the bit above the sequence
node.
And I'm going to save that.
I'm going to go over and hit play and go into my behavior tree asset.
And you should be able to see a drop down here, but with not because it's not currently running.
So let's stop playing.
And why is it not running?
Because we haven't hooked it up in our shooter A.I. controller.
So let's do that many challenge for you to hook that up operation.
Be too hard.
Okay.
Welcome back.
So if we go and have a look in here, we're looking for at A.I. behavior.
Some reason it required a recomposed for me to show up for me.
But here it is.
A.I. behavior is what we want.
We click the dropdown has only one option at the moment.
We've only got one behavior tree.
So select that one and compile and save.
And if we now go ahead and play the game.
And go and have a look at Beatty enemy A.I., you can see that it's highlighting the note that's currently
running.
And you've got this little drop down next to the pause stop buttons, which tells you which A.I. controller
you're currently observing, the behavior trial.
So this is a great functionality for you to be able to jump in and go, okay.
Why is that?
I just standing still.
Why is he not chasing the player?
You can see which part of the behavior he's currently running and go, ah, that seat.
You know, that thing's gone wrong.
It's really helpful for debugging.
You can go and have a look at what all your A.I. and the world are up to by using this dropdown.
Great stuff.
That's all for this lecture.
In the next lecture, we're gonna be looking at how we can set information in the blackboard memory
of our A.I. from C++.
I'll see you there.