Hello and welcome in this lecture, we are going to be setting a blackboard key from our C++ so that
we can set the player's location and begin play.
Let's dive in and see how that works.
OK.
So as I said in the last lecture, we want to be able to set some state from our game, play in the
blackboard for the A.I. to act upon.
So the blackboard looks like this and it currently has this self actor key, but it doesn't have any
other keys here.
We can add keys like clicking on this new key button.
You can change the type.
There isn't actually a type for actors or anything like that that just goes under the nebulous type
of object for everything else.
There's boules classes, OENOMAUS, et cetera.
But you can choose what kind of type that you want.
That object to be by going to your blackboard, details dropping down and choosing what base class you'd
like.
So, for example, it's saying here that the self actor is of actor type.
This has just been put in here by default.
But what we want to do here is set a new key.
And to do that, we need to do.
Find out how we can gain access to this in the C++ so weak.
Already have an easy function that allows us to get hold of the blackboard by doing a get blackboard
component on the AA controller.
So simple as we can just to get blackboard components.
And let's have a look at that blackboard.
Components.
Don H.
And have a look what is available in here.
We want to be doing something like set key or Set Blackbaud, where in fact, it's as simple as just
set value.
So, hey, you've got a bunch of different functions on that blackboard, components that allow you
to set these different values so you can do it by a key name, which is an F name here.
Then you can set the value as an object or you can set the class.
All of the different types that are available here.
So let's give that a go.
I'm gonna go over to the C++ and try and set our player porn's location as one of the variables.
So we're going to do first of all, we need to get hold of the blackboard components.
So let's give that a shot.
Get blackboard components.
Then we need to have the right includes.
So if I hover over the blackboard component, right.
You can see that we need to be including behavior tree forward slash blackboard components.
So let's do that hash include then it's going to be the behavior tree forward slash blackboard component
or H.
Now we can use the arrow operator on that type.
And we should be running.
We want to in this case, be setting a vector.
We can set the location.
So setting a vector and not copy the whole line but just set vector.
And then we want to what's the first parameter is the name that we're trying to set.
So we can use our text macro for that.
I'm going to call it the player location.
That's gonna give us the location at the start because of calling it in begin play.
And then we need to actually set the location so we can get that from the line of code, getting our
play porn first and foremost.
So uncommon that and then we want to do the play a porn arrow and get actor location like so and finish
off the lineman's semicolon.
And it's as simple as that to go ahead and set a blackboard value.
So your challenge is going to be to do the other half of this, which is to create a key in the blackboard.
So add the key to the blackboard.
Make sure it's at the right type, the right name.
And then if everything works correctly, you should be able to check that value at runtime.
Remember last lecture we saw how we can see the behavior tree.
You can do the same thing.
You can inspect the blackboard at runtime when you're playing and you should be able to see what value
was set by the C++ code.
Pause a video and have a go.
OK, welcome back.
So I'm gonna go over in to the editor.
Hit compile.
I haven't done that already.
And we're going to add a new blackboard key.
And in this case, we have to get the names right and the types right.
Otherwise, things will go wrong.
So we've got a vector key, which we're gonna be calling our player location, and I'm gonna copy that
to make sure that we have got the right spelling here.
Yes, we have cool beans.
And then what we're gonna do is we're gonna head over and just check that the blackboard details are
okay.
So, yeah, there's a name you could add a description if you wanted.
The type is a vector.
That's cool.
Instance sinked.
This is a variable that we're not particularly interested in at the moment.
Cool.
We've got our code has compiled.
So let's go and hit play and see whether we can inspect that blackboard value.
Go over to the blackboard and you can see we can still have that dropdown of choosing which A.I. we
want this to relate to.
We've only got one in our world.
But you can see that self out there hasn't been set, but the player's location has indeed been set.
Let's check if that is roughly correct.
If I f eight d possess.
Have a look at my player and have a look at the player's location.
You can see that.
Yes, it's pretty much correct.
Two thousand minus five thousand one hundred two thousand minus five thousand one hundred.
So that's setting the value through from C++.
Simple as that.
We can start to see how we can interface with our behavior trees in the next lecture.
We're going to look at the actual structure of behavior trees and making them do something.
The exciting part.
See their.