Hello everybody and welcome back.
I'd like to jump into another quick challenge with you all.
I'd like you to think about being a bit more designer friendly when you're constructing your code.
This is not only a benefit if you're working in the team being able to expose values make sure there's
nothing hidden away but also it's a great thing for you as well and having to go into your code every
time to change a simple value when it could be right there in the editor was perhaps something that
we should all think about when we are writing our code.
So I'd like you to think about removing magic numbers from the code.
Obviously sometimes you do want to hard code something in.
So for instance let's take the speed at which the doors will open and shuts.
And of course we've got that delay as well exposing those values may or may not be beneficial that delay
definitely.
Because then we put a door elsewhere we can adjust the delay that it's open for.
But perhaps you want to keep the speed at which the doors open and shuts permanent.
In which case you do want to hide those things in now.
The next thing I would say is think about which parameters you want to expose.
Often they'll be the things that you are accessing most often and you'll only really know that after
you start playing with your game itself.
And the other thing to think about is perhaps you could expose all of those parameters.
It's entirely up to you.
And then of course if they're all exposed then everybody's got a an idea of what will happen of course
at that point if you do expose something you probably want to give it a default value as well just to
make sure that a it's a sensible figure when you start using it.
And of course expose them to the editor as well with you property edit anywhere.
OK.
So go ahead pause video.
Go through your code and make this more designer friendly so that anybody who is using your open door
component could tweak the parameters that they would need in order to open and close the door.
Paul's video now and give that a go OK everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead hop on over into unreal and make this a little bit more designer friendly.
Okay.
I'm glad we've jumped straight into the head the far because this is where I need to do most of my editing.
Now I think that I would quite like to be able to control the clothes the lay so I'm going to copy you
property at anywhere so I don't have to keep typing it over and over again.
Now the door last open that's absolutely fine actor that opens.
I'll leave that there for the moment as well.
The angle of the door when it's open the target your.
Well that's a good question that we've said target your because we're dealing with the actual names
of the Afro taters values.
However it's might be a bit more friendly to not call this target your but open angle.
So I'm going to cut that out of the way and go open angle and then I'm going to go over to the implementation
Find and Replace target your with open angle and we can happily replace them all.
OK so that's a that's a great start though.
That's much more readable so it's not just about exposing parameters but making sure that it's clear
as to what it is that you're setting.
I would also like to give the designer an option to both adjust the opening speed and closing speed
of the door myself.
So this is another you profit property edit anywhere and it's going to be a float.
It's a completely new one in this case is going to be a float and that's called it.
DOOR OPENS speed something like that so DOOR OPENS speed we could call it velocity as well as entirely
up to you.
And then we need another one which will be a float DOOR SHUTTING speed or door close speed to be consistent
with our other other naming that we have there's a door clothes speed.
There we go.
So we need to use these somewhere and that will be over in the implementation itself.
We have the door open speed that is here.
So that's go ahead and at the end so DOOR OPENS speed.
Excellent.
And this one here is gonna be the door closed speed as the door closed door opens Pete silly me door
close.
Speed.
Okay.
The other thing that I need to do is give them sensible values to begin with so the door opens speed
was nice and slow to be enticing that was point eight so that's that with a default value.
And this was to I believe if I remember correctly that wasn't safe.
I have just smash the keys.
Okay.
I think that is the ones that I want to expose this go over into here and see is is there anything that's
a magic number left in here.
No there isn't.
Excellent.
That's a great job going through there and sorting that out.
Now of course we've changed quite a bit to code there.
Let's go over into unreal and make sure it's all working Excellent.
Let's go and compile our code and with a compile complete list Go ahead press play.
So a game still appears to work.
SHUTS.
Perfect.
Let's come out of that and go and have a look at our open door component.
And here we go.
We have the open angle the clothes that lay the open speed and the close speed.
Now the pressure plate in the act of the opens I'm going to puts all the pressure plate is actually
something that is kind of important when you're using this but you only set it once.
I might move that further down and the actor that opens that may go in in to be quite honest in the
end so let's go back into our code and I do want to tweak that ever so slightly so this block of code
here I'm going to keep the door last open with the rest of the door stuff and his ult and the up marriage
to move this block of code up OK inserts just another line there for readability.
OK.
And looking down this code actually we've got an issue here with the door last opened.
Now I know I created that in the last lecture so I'll go back and have a little Arto there because I've
managed to make this undefined.
If we have a look in our implementation file here the only time we're actually setting door last opened
is here so we have to actually be on the pressure plate in order for that to be initialized with anything.
Otherwise it remains unfinished allies and whatever was in that memory address when we declared this
new variable.
That's what it's taken hold of.
So let's actually give it a value that is a float.
So in this case I'm just going to set it to zero.
Okay.
Excellent.
Yep.
I am happy with that.
Let's save the file and go over into on real.
And then when we go ahead and recompile because this is already open we will see it updates and that
will just reorder to what I think is a better order again later on if it turns out that it's not no
hard you know no hard times we just go in and we reorder the code itself which is just really easy to
do.
So no sweat.
There we go.
So everything is reordered how I want it now.
What did you expose did you expose a similar set of things that I've done here.
Did you do less.
Was there something else that you tweaked did you change the order of everything that's there.
Share your thoughts and how you handle your doors set up over in the discussions and I'll see you all
in the next lecture.