Hello everybody and welcome back in this show.
We're going to be modifying the default porn actor it's going to be the first step in making our grabber
system.
So first of all why blueprint is helpful in this particular case.
So there will be some times when coding things is better and sometimes why blueprint would be the right
way to go.
In fact let's go over that right now.
Blueprints is really helpful when you're making templates of assets because it's very visual.
It's very clear in the ED WHAT YOU'RE CHANGING AND You're preventing yourself from hard coding changes
to assets into the c++ code which makes it a lot harder to edit things later on.
And also if you wanted to change like the name of an assets then the editor will actually track those
changes.
Otherwise it would have to be done in code.
We'll go on to show you how to make a blueprint from the default porn.
Now are notes here that this blueprint class that we create is going to inherit from the default porn.
So therefore an is a relationship from the standard default porn class.
Now blueprints themselves.
They're like a template there a plan for building something which is great because it gives us a structure
by which we can place our grabber a.
We'll be going ahead and making an instance of our new blueprint in the scene itself and we'll explore
instantiating from the blueprint and modifying and seeing how those behaviors interact.
So creating an instance is instantiating and then we'll look at what happens when you go ahead and modify
its whilst it's in the scene when you modify in that instance.
Okay.
So over in on real if we go ahead and press play and then immediately inject ourselves we can look back
at our current default porn now the way that this is being set up is over in your project settings.
As I've indicated before over on your maps and modes the default game mode.
This is a C++ game mode which means that anything that was setting down here needs to be done in code.
However what we'll be doing in a moment is making a blueprint version of that.
We shall then enable us to select our own default pawn a blueprint version of it in the selected game
mode.
So this default form being specified here is this one here that appears the moment we press play.
So how do we go ahead and modify the pawn itself.
What if we go ahead and select sets you can select it's in two different ways.
Remember we're going to have to make sure that we play the game ejects ourselves look back upon the
default pawn that's in our scene.
You can either select it in the editor window itself or over in the world outline that once you've done
that.
We can go up the top here it's a blueprints and there's a couple of options.
And what we want to do is convert the selected actor into a blueprint class.
We'll go ahead and click on that.
It gives us a couple of options.
Let's pop it in our blueprints folder.
That would make sense and we've got a blueprint name here.
Default porn blueprint but we could also just append it with the name BP so we know it's a default porn
and it's a blueprint.
Let's go ahead and click Create blueprint.
Okay.
So that's opened up a new window unfortunately a multi monitor setup so I'm gonna have to drag that
down so you guys can see it.
You probably have this that's now appeared.
Now I could dockets at the top here so easily accessible but for the moment we'll come back to this
in a sec.
But for the moment let's just close that down and have a look at our world and see what we can do now
in our contents folder we now have our default porn blueprint and we can click and drag and create an
instance of that in our world.
Pretty awesome Hey.
Okay.
So that is just a copy of our original default porn and has all of whatever the default porn had as
well.
So if we go down into the content browser and double click on our default porn a new window will open
up because back to our blueprint again.
And if we have a look here we can see at the very top right the parent class is the default porn.
So that's where it's inheriting all of these settings from which is pretty awesome that we've got this
copy of our default porn.
And of course the great thing is that we can now go ahead and edit this.
So what we can do here is if we want to add some books we can't change any these at the moment.
We can go ahead and open up the full blueprint editor go ahead and click on that.
And of course it's opened up on another window for us.
We can bring that back down.
And wow we've got a lot of options here.
We've got all of our details that we were just looking at a moment ago over on the right hand side.
And we've got this big area in the middle.
Pretty awesome.
And we've got these three tabs of the top.
We're not going to worry about the event graph construction script at the moment but the viewport itself
this is where we can start let's say perhaps altering how our porn looks.
So we didn't wanted to be a sphere anymore we could modify it.
So it looks a different shape.
In fact I think that's what we'll go ahead and do now as your challenge Okay so your challenge was I'd
like you to do is try making a rugby ball porn on American football if you're watching this over the
pond now modify the default porn blueprint somehow.
Now we know about the various transformers you can do.
So go ahead and play with those for example scaling on one axis would tend to make that kind of shape
that we're looking for Create an instance by dragging it into the world so close the blueprint editor
and then drag it from the content browser into the world and then once you've done that.
See how modifying the instance the one we've just dragged into the world so scaling on a different access
or rotate it around doesn't change the original blueprint.
And then when you're done just revert your changes to the default porn itself.
Okay so go ahead pulls of the now and give us a go Hello everybody and welcome back.
Let's hop on over internal rail and make ourselves a rug people.
Porn Okay so I've got the default porn open in front of me here.
I can close that down if I want and reopen it.
So just in case you guys don't have a open for a drag it once into my scene well I can delete that from
the scene.
Let's go ahead.
Double click it go to the viewport options here and going to select it and I'm just gonna scale there
on its y axis.
So this is going to be a very elongated I'm going to try and make it a bit more rugby ball shape.
Yeah about there that although I'm going to save it.
That's important.
And then we can go up and I could close that down but I'm going to come back to it in a bit so can undo
those changes.
Let's go back into our scene we can see that immediately the thumbnail associated with the default porn
looks different.
And when we drag it in look at that it's a completely different shape and because it's an instance of
it it doesn't really matter what we do here.
And if we go ahead now and change something about this we could make it wider we could make it even
longer.
It does not change the original blueprint.
We can go back here will always look like this.
And that's useful because that means you can have different instances having different properties so
the changes themselves don't get written back to the blueprint.
Now there is a way of doing that but we're not going to complicate things at the moment.
Now we're in the world and playing at the moment and that's one of the things why a lot of this lot
is all great out some of the click stop.
These will all come back again.
The details here.
We've also got this option at the top left to compile.
Now in general as you could see there that wasn't really changing much.
There's not anything really compile worthy at the moment.
But with our blueprints as we generate ones that are far more complex we can go ahead click compile
and it will just make sure the blueprint is working as expected.
Now you probably know this is where we can add components and we'll be doing that in a bit by adding
a grabber component up here.
And I asked you guys to set this back to being spherical and we can do that very easily.
Over here we've got all three scales and at the moment they're not set evenly.
So I'm going to come along here go point five and just tap between them and then I know I've got myself
a sphere back slightly bigger than it was before.
It's perhaps the sorts of thing that if I was paying attention to its original scale I might have I
might assumed in too much as well.
But when I clicked compile click save have a look in my world it looks pretty big.
So it was probably smaller than that before.
But I'm happy with the overall scale there.
Okay.
And we'll get rid of that default porn in the scene.
And now it's time to go ahead and make the grabber.
So what we can do here is go down to to add new we're going to add a new C++ class.
It's going to go on the actor itself.
It's going to be an active component.
Remember our default pawn here pawn inherits from actor.
Going to be an actor component.
Let's go ahead and click next.
And once again we're going to have to give it a name so I'm going to call it grabber oh dear I've hit
caps lock obviously so I'm going to call it grab there and go ahead and create the class.
Now it's going to take a few moments to do that okay so there we go he's opened up the grabber header
file and implementation file that's absolutely fine it's got all the boilerplate code you'd expect to
see in there as well.
Skip back over into unreal and you can see down at the bottom.
That's our content browser now has a grab a component in it.
So what we can now do is go to our default porn blueprint and add components.
And this is where we can search for our grabber boom.
So now our default porn has the grab component on it.
Now we have changed something here so we're going to have to click compile and I'm gonna save that and
just shut that down for the moment.
I don't think we need to go back to that just yet.
Okay.
So let's go back to our blueprint strike in the default porn once again and lift that up and out to
the floor.
Now if we go over to its details panels it's going to be almost the same as it was before.
But there we go.
We have the grabber component attached to its already brilliant.
So this is now the reusable objects that we are going to be able to replace our standard default porn
with because remember when we go ahead and press play and then injects ourselves from the scene look
back at ourselves and look at these two actors that are in our scene one of them doesn't have the grabber
on.
So we do need to have the grappa there.
Otherwise we're just not going to be able to pick up anything.
So what we need to do next is changing out our game mode.
So we're using the default porn blueprints that we've just made here and we'll do that in the next lecture.