Hello everybody and welcome back in this lecture we're going to talk about early returns.
Now the great thing about early returns is it's going to be able to give us some simpler if statements
at the moment.
We've got this nesting going on and it can very quickly end up very complicated to read even though
the code itself isn't that complex.
So when running through a series of checks you can do something that's called an early return so you
can return from the function call back to the rest of your code early you don't have to run through
the rest of your code and this will help prevent dense nested if else statements.
As I said before it will make our code simpler and easier to read.
So let's go have a look at that and then a little challenge to make your code read much better OK.
So wherever in our implementation I'm just going to hide my file explorer on the side there and let's
have a look at what we're talking about.
So we're really talking about the implementation of our process.
Guess so we're coming in here and we're saying the first thing we say the first check that we run is
if the guess has been guessed correctly.
And what we can do after this.
So we don't have to do any other checking we don't have to run through the else is we can do a return
and that's it.
It is as simple as that.
And what we can then do is we can run through the other checks that we want to do.
So here for instance we could go if let's say this then do something else and then return and then we
can continue in this fashion on and on so we can then go.
Let's say that and return.
And then finally that say we've got one final check something else.
And then finally of course we return afterwards.
So this is a very quick way of checking through code.
You can see here you're going to check for this.
Then we're going to do this.
If that isn't true we just keep going down the list.
So it's a nice check that we could go through and equally in this we can decide where we decrement life
as well.
So we just put in the parts where we lose a life.
So let's just say if they've guessed correctly obviously they've won but if they've typed in the wrong
number of characters or perhaps they haven't typed in an icy gram we can then remove a life here
so that these will not decrement a life for everything else below it will do.
So that's one way of managing your code and what happens as you run through it.
Now one thing I will point out here is notice that this is highlighted blue.
Now this is a keyword that is reserved.
So this isn't something that you could use in your real code.
So I'm going to remove all of this now ready for our challenge and before we do our challenge Let's
just scroll up here where we've got our pseudocode in place.
What we're going to run through because that is what we're going to use to help guide us as we start
writing the rest of these checks so let's go to your challenge.
So the first thing I'd like to do is code in your additional checks using early returns.
Use code or pseudocode for the remaining checks.
We haven't gone through the process yet of checking for an ice grab.
So that's something you can use as pseudocode for the time being.
And we're in the process where you decremental life if you don't have to do it at the same as me at
this point this is where you can start changing your game and making your own do you want to be really
harsh and decrement in life the moment they make any mistake what do you want to give them the benefit
of the doubt with a warning that perhaps whoops you made a mistake there.
Try again and use the earliest pseudocode of flow charts for your reference and of course if you do
have any pseudocode please move it to the appropriate place in your code itself as you start optimizing
process guess pausing video now and give that a go OK.
Everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and optimize process.
OK so let's start by going and grabbing our pseudocode from the top here.
Basically all of this is going to be used.
We can drag it all the way down to our process.
Guess what Plunkett or where shall I put it.
Let's put it just after this first if statement here and I need to make sure that return is here early
return.
There we go.
Perfect.
Check if I a gram that's fine that's one of the checks that we've got so I'll leave that in place prompt
guess again check the right number of characters prompts guess again that's that is fine that's the
check the right number of characters.
That is what this is here.
So let's go ahead and grab this bit of code and pop it right under there.
So we know where we are checking the right number of characters.
And then of course an early return making sure we spell it correctly.
Sorry guess again.
And I think here we should also say let's print out a reminder.
So the hidden word is and then format specified letters long and hopefully that won't go off the side
and we don't want to get robbed in that way we want a word.
So the hidden word is this long and of course we need to pass in the hidden word length.
So hidden word dot.
Okay.
And our semicolon at the end.
So I think that's fine they're sorry.
Try guessing again you have so many lives remaining the hidden word is this long.
That's fine prompt to guess again.
That's what we've done so we don't need anything else there.
Then we go to go ahead and remove a life and that's this part of our code.
Of course you can retype this if you want to.
And I'm a little concerned about this.
I think we're gonna end up with a random number coming down.
I think this was a debug line that originally put in so I'm going to remove that.
So we just decremental ing the lives and doing nothing else there.
That's fine.
And we're obviously saying to the user we've lost the life which is fine because the next thing is the
check whether the lives are greater than zero.
So let's move that up and just tidy up this bottom bit here okay.
It's the next check here is if the lives are greater than zero.
Well that means we're still playing.
It's one of these ones just like above that if we check if it is a nicer Gram.
Well if it is a nicer gram we can still be playing.
So we really need to check whether the lives are less than or equal to zero so less than or equal to
zero.
Then we can say you have no lives left and in the game.
Now at this point I would say that if we have no lives left that's fine.
And then we end the game something to think about not in this particular game brave end game.
This function call that we were doing would actually take the player off somewhere or display a different
screen.
They would never ever see this particular state as.
Something to bear in mind with your code flow.
We could quite easily move this.
You have no lives left all the way up to the end game itself.
That would be absolutely fine because this is really the.
The screen if it were as it were.
That shows them the end of the game.
In fact thinking of that.
Let's let's do that.
Let's assume that we're going to end the game and we will need an early return here as well.
Because otherwise any code beneath who still executes.
Let's bring that up into the end game.
So we're going to say you have no lives left.
But let's also clear the screen.
So let's go ahead and clear the screen at this particular point.
Tell them that they have no lives left.
That's fine.
And also we need to tell them what that hidden word was.
But I suppose we don't have to tell them but it would be quite boring game if you don't know how close
you were.
So the hidden word was.
And then our format specified.
And we're going to need the asterisk with the hidden word.
There we go.
So that reads much better to me.
Now I want a blank line in between that and the instruction.
So let's go ahead and put a new line in there.
We could also put the new line at the end.
Entirely up to you how you go ahead and do that.
But that will ensure that presence to play again comes after this group of texts and there'll be nothing
on the screen when we say you have no lives left the hidden word was okay.
So that is good.
I'm liking how that's worked out.
Let's just tidy up the very bottom bit here.
So what's happening at the very end at the very end.
We're going to show the player and we haven't actually said this when we were typing in our pseudocode
before show player the balls and the cows now because we are actually still playing.
This is where we can instruct the player to guess again.
You have and then our format specify our lives left.
Of course we need to include lives in here.
OK.
So we are checking if the lives.
Yep yep yep.
And we're not going to quit the game as such.
So that is fine there.
Let's have a closer look at the check.
If I see Graham.
So why are we going to say here we're going to say if is ice a gram.
I think that's a good name for it.
Have you come up with what you think is a better name than share it's over in the discussions.
So if is ice a gram.
Well the challenge here is to check whether it is an ice a gram.
So we're not gonna check if it is we're going to check if it's not.
So then there's gonna be some code in here we might call another function.
So here we need to say ah no repeating letters and to guess again.
Hopefully that will fit all on one line.
And of course we need us semicolon at the end.
Okay now I cannot test this statement at the moment this check because is ice Graham doesn't exist at
the moment so I'm going to go and comment.
That's how completely I'm going to save my work.
And before I check that it's running what I will go ahead and do is just run through my code because
I think I'm actually going to have a problem.
Notice and gain does not lose screen or wind screen.
It's actually just end game.
So if we run through the first part of where the gas is being assessed if we get it right it will end
the game and when we end the game it's going to clear the screen and say you have no lives left.
It's not going to say you have one.
We will never see that.
It'll be too quick.
So we need to move these things back down to where we have.
If the lives are less than or equal to zero let's go ahead and grab those couple of lines 44 and 45.
And in fact 43 as well so 43 44 and 45 if we grab those I'm going to cut them out.
Apologies for moving up and down the code but it's something that happens when you read three code you
have an idea you start implementing it and then you realize if we had run that that would have been
a bit silly.
So we can clear the screen which makes sense.
You have no lives left the hidden word was this and we're going to do the end game the end game will
simply then say press Enter to play again.
That looks like a much better flow.
Let's tidy up this here and save.
Let's go ahead over into unreal compile.
So now if we win the game we've lost life.
Well let's lose a life first and see what happens when that when that does occur.
So we're not checking for ice grams at the moment.
No lives left to hit and word was case presents to black.
Okay.
That is the behavior that I wanted to have.
Now if you decided to code ahead a wind screen little blue screen.
Good on you.
That's great.
I'm not going to go for that.
I think just those stepping screens would good.
And then we've got cakes.
That's the other thing.
We've won presents to play again it resets everything now I could set that to also clear the screen
to say you have one bit of a difference there when you lose and win.
I'm happy with that.
And then the last thing to check is just the right number of letters.
There's nothing else that we can do whether we type 5 or 6.
Try guessing again you have fireflies remain hidden hidden word is five letters long so I'm gonna flip
around.
You have five lives too many.
And the hidden word is five letters long.
That is important.
Otherwise it's kind of the wrong way round.
So the hit.
So let's tell them.
Oh hold on a minute.
The hidden word is five letters long.
There we go.
Or number of letters long.
You have this many lives remaining.
Okay.
Yes there is one final thing here.
I've missed an S off the end of letters.
Apologies for everybody who spotted that beforehand because they probably screaming at the screen.
Anyway I would like to leave you with a little bit of a thought experiment a micro challenge as it were
to think about the ordering which these checks happen.
If you look at their varying complexity we have three different checks happening before we get criminal
a life.
Now what I'd like you to do is think about the order and see whether there is a better order we can
put them in.
As to what they would be at the moment and also more importantly why might you change the order of checks
in your code pop your answers in the discussions I'll be interested to know make sure you share your
work as you go looking forward to seeing how your projects are coming along and I'll see you all in
the next lecture.