Hello and welcome this lecture, we're going to be making an enemy more of a threat by implementing
a chute node in C++.
Let's dive in and see how to do it.
So one piece of functionality that's clearly missing from our behavior tree is the ability to shoot.
What I'd ideally want to do is move to the player's location and then shoot.
But we want to change a little bit first how we do the movement.
There's a couple of things I want to tweak.
So if I select the move to node, one thing I want change is the radius.
I don't want the enemy to be coming right up to me.
So if I change the acceptable radius, then it's going to stop moving five meters away from me.
So it's going to stop.
Give me a nice five meter distance.
He comes up to me, they go and he stops and stares.
Now, the other thing I want to do is down here in the blackboard section, you can see there is an
observe blackboard value.
If we don't have that checked, let's see what happens as I move.
He basically and this was a slightly more obvious when we had a smaller, acceptable radius.
So let's just stick that down there to five for now.
And if I hit play, then you can see that as I move, he goes to my last location and then he only then
when he's reached that, does he come an update.
That's not what we want.
What we want is it to be constantly coming towards us.
And if you check the observed blackboard value, then essentially what it's saying is that every time
the player location changes, we're going to update where we are moving to.
So if I go ahead and hit play and move, you can see he's continuously following me and updating his
path.
That's exactly what we want.
So now we can change our accept radius to 500 and it becomes less obvious.
But it's still good that we have our observed Blackbaud value there.
And then the behavior that we want is that once he comes within radius of us like so he's going to stop
and shoot at us for that.
We need a new type of task.
So we gonna create a new C++ task here.
So I, I get to add new new C++ class.
Then we're going to go and show all classes and look for the Beattie task.
Now which one do we want, the Beattie task node or the Beattie task blackboard base.
Well, we don't actually need to use a key because we're just going to try and shoot.
That's all we going do.
We're gonna pull the trigger on our gun.
All the aiming is gonna be done elsewhere in our behaviour tree.
So let's open up the B.T. task node.
The base class here.
And we're going to call this B.T. task.
Underscore.
Shoot.
Let's go ahead and create that class.
Then we end up with something just like this.
So we want to do the same set up.
So a little bit of a mini challenge for you to do the same sort of setup as we've got for our blackboard.
Clear blackboard value.
We want to have a name.
We want to have an execute task.
Now, suppose videos have a go at that.
OK.
Welcome back.
So that was a mini task.
I'm just going to copy over the signatures from my clear blackboard value over to shoot, including
the public and protected sections.
I'm going to change the name of our constructor.
I'm gonna go ahead and implement our constructor.
And what was it that we needed to do?
We need to set node name equal to shoot.
That's what we're going to call it.
Then back to the header for the shoot task and we're going to try and implement the execute task now.
And we just need to call up to super some kind of copy that from our Clear Blackboard Values GPP file.
And then we are ready to start implementing.
So the first thing we're going to need to do here and let's have a bit more space is we're going to
need to get hold of our pawn.
Why do we need to get hold of our pawn?
Well, let's have a look at the shooter character, which is a pawn.
Remember the shooter character Dot H has a shoot method.
That's what we want to be calling essentially the same as we as the player is doing.
He's holding down the trigger button and that's calling this shoot method.
We want the A.I. to be able to do the same when you have the shoot task.
It's going to hold down the trigger button or repeatedly press that trigger button.
So the execute task is going to be the right place to do this.
We're probably going to return what here?
Because remember, this action is just one shot.
It's not continuous shooting.
What are we gonna do?
We're going to return the EBIT node result success.
If we succeeded, if we succeeded because we don't need to continuously call tick, we don't need this
task to be running any longer than a single frame.
And the other thing we need to do is get hold.
As I said, of that pawn class.
Well, what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna show you how you can get hold of the A.I. controller.
And from the A.I. controller, we know that we can call get porn to get the porn that was controlled.
And we know that we can cast that controlled porn to our shooter character implementation.
So how do we get hold of the A.I. controller from this?
Well, we've got our behavior tree component, which we know is on an A.I. controller.
So maybe that has something that we can use if we go to the you behavior tree component and have a look
in the here for any methods that might be helpful.
There's a lot in here.
But if we look for a controller, we aren't seeing anything but maybe somewhere in one of its base classes
because the parent class for the EU behavior tree component is the.
Brain component.
We follow up to that one and look for controller in here.
You can see there is a property for it.
Is there a Geter?
Yes, there is called Get a AI owner and that should return if we hover over it.
And I control a pointer, so you should be able to use that to get hold of the porn, cast it to shoot
a character and then call the shoot method.
So that's going to be your challenge to cool the shoot method.
Make it public.
Get the porn cast the porn call shoot and then test it out in your behavior.
Tree pulls a video and have a go.
Okay.
Welcome back.
So first of all, first step is we're gonna need to make this shoot method public because it needs to
be called from outside of this class.
So I'll put it just under take damage.
We'll have shoot.
Give a little bit space to it.
Little breathing room.
I like whitespace.
Helps me see.
Help me think.
Then we're gonna go to the Beatty task shoot.
We're going to first of all, check that I controller is not.
No.
Otherwise we can't use the arrow operator on it.
Just general good practice to do these null checks.
So if this A.I. owner is not equal, if Sara is equal to null pointer, we're going to want to return
early with a failure.
So this task will fail if we don't have an A.I. controller.
That's pretty straightforward.
So.
And do a return.
IBT node results.
Chalong Kolon failed like so.
And then we are going to do the owner component.
Get a own.
We're going to get porn on it.
In fact, we might need to include a header file here.
So let's do a hash include.
And it's gonna be game framework and the controller.
And in fact, I think, yeah, any controller should do.
But I think we need the A.I. controller because that's the type of the point of the game back.
And then we're gonna do an arrow and we're gonna do a get pawn here complaining about something in my
head, a file, maybe I haven't got something right.
So forward slash A.I. looks like I got it wrong.
And still actually in game framework, you just have a AI controller to include.
Teach me for being so blasé about that.
So there we go.
We can now get the porn from the A.I. owner.
And as I said, we also need to do a.
Past.
So we're going to do a cast.
To what type we're going to need to cast to the end of the shoot.
Character.
So that is in its full form.
A shoot, a character, a shoot, a character.
And we're going to need to check the result of this as well.
But we need to include Ashrita character.
So hash include at the top.
The shooter character, Don H.
Like, so.
And we're going to store that in a pointer type shit character star.
Gonna be our character.
We'll call it.
We'll store it there.
And basically, we need to make sure that neither the get porn return because get porn might return.
No.
If the A.I. is not currently controlling a porn or this cast might return.
If the type is not an eight chute's character, if he's controlling a different type of porn.
Fortunately, these two get down quite well together.
So if you try and cast a null point.
The result is just a null pointer, which is why we can do this.
These checks all in one line.
Then we can do an if character.
Equals null pointer.
Then we want to fail again.
So return.
IBT node results, Callon Kolon failed.
Like so.
And finally, after all of those checks and we know that we've got ourselves a shooter character, we
should be able to call Chute's so character Arrow and shoot like say.
So that will finally get us able to shoot.
Let's go over to a behavior tree.
And in here, we're going to want to pulldowns place new node and look for the new shoot task that we've
got in here.
And I'm not sure whether I.
Comp. So I'm just gonna make sure that everything compiles again.
And once that's done, we can go over and hit play.
And see if this guy comes up and shoots.
Okay.
Yes, he does.
Unfortunately, he's shooting repeatedly and shooting himself in the foot.
So something is not quite right right there.
So there's two things going wrong for a start.
He managed to kill himself with the shots.
And it also seems like he is shooting every single frame, which would make sense because we're getting
to see the player.
We move to them and then shoot is the last action we've got here, which we're going to execute repeatedly.
So what we want to do is actually turn this into a sequence.
So I'm going to drag off a node here, call, make a sequence node.
And what we're gonna do is we're gonna shoot, then wait, then shoot, then wait and repeat that indefinitely.
So shoot first.
Wait a little bit.
So maybe we wait.
I don't know for one second between shots and then we're going to want to repeat this, which we can
do with a decorator.
So if I.
Right.
Click add decorator and look for the loop decorator.
Then you can see how many times you want it to loop.
It says three times.
We don't want it three times.
Wanted basically to infinitely loop until we need to move or we need we've lost sight of the and we
need to go and investigate.
So we're gonna go ahead and hit play and see if that works.
Comes up to me, shoots, shoots, shoots.
But he's not actually hitting me.
You can see that his shots are actually landing on himself.
And we're gonna deal with that bug in an upcoming lecture.
See that?