Hello and welcome in this lecture, we're gonna be introducing a new thing in the behavior tree, the
services.
We're going to find out what services are, how they help us with persistent running behavior and how
we can write our own in C++.
Let's dive right in.
Now, there are only a few pieces of logic left in our control that aren't in our behavior tree.
One of these is setting the start location.
This I still want to set here from the A.I. controller, but things like tick now that I would like
to do from within a behavior tree.
What do I want to do here?
How do I get it to do?
And so I play a location to update the last known player location.
Both of these we can do with something called a blueprint service.
So let's go over to our blueprints and see what's going on.
So if I go to my A.I. and open up the behavior tree, dog it the main window, then I need to show you
what services.
We've never used one before.
And it's essentially a way of running something every take or every so often whenever a particular path
is active.
So if I had a service here on the chase behavior, then something would some code would be able to run
all the time that the chase behavior is active, whether we're moving, shooting, waiting, any of
these things.
It would always be running.
But if we're an investigate, it would not be.
So this is exactly the kind of situation that we're looking to use a service.
Now, let's have an example service.
One thing that we notice when we are playing is that the once the A.I. comes within range of us and
we move around, he's not rotating to look at us.
And we can fix that with an already built in service here.
So.
Right, click on this note and go to add service and look for the default focus service.
You can see it's a different color.
It's green.
And if we select that default service, it also goes underneath these sequence nodes as opposed to above
them, which is what the decorators do.
So with the default focus selected, you can then choose what you want to focus on.
In this case, we want to focus on the player location.
Go ahead and hit save hit play.
And now if we go and have a look and move around, you can see he's rotating to follow us.
Cool stuff.
Now we want to be able to implement a similar service in C++ that will update our player location all
the while and update our last known player location.
While we are chasing.
So we're gonna do that as two separate services.
And you can see how that all.
So automatically services can make things a little bit more efficient than doing it in tech because
you can only run the last known play location.
When you're in the right part of the baby tree.
So let's go over to the sandbox.
Get the content browser.
Add new new C++ class going gonna show all classes and look for what our options are here.
We're looking for BTR service.
And then there are a couple of options, just like we had with our B.T. task.
We've got the blackboard base and we're actually gonna want the blackboard base because we want to know
which key we should be updating.
For example, should it be the player location?
Should it be the last known player location?
So we gonna go and hit next on this one with the blackboard base selected.
And we're going to call this BEATTIES service underscore player location like so.
And go ahead.
Create that class.
So once we're done compiling, we gonna go over into Visual Studio Code and you can see that we have
got this BEATTIES service player location, which is inheriting from the service blackboard based court.
That's what we wanted.
Now, what functionality we're gonna move into this?
Well, I'm gonna try and move the simplest functionality possible, which is just to set the value of
the basically last known play location, though this key will be configured in the behavior tree, not
here in a plain text, but it's going to get the play a porn location and set it to a blackboard key.
And it's not going to do any of the line of sight.
Checking reason being, if we are running it in our behavior tree only when we are chasing, then we
don't need the line of sight check.
We can see the player that's automatically we know that's the case.
So another simplification there for doing it in a service.
So this should be fairly straightforward.
If we know how to get a method, call here in the B.T. service.
So let's go and have a look at our BEATTIES service.
H to see what is available there.
What's the documentation?
What can we do?
The main methods here, you can see are on become relevant on cease relevant.
The take note and on search start.
On search start.
We're not particularly interested in.
But take note.
Yes.
That is where we are going to get an update all the time that this service is on an active path.
So that's when we're going to want to implement.
We go in, search through this files, find the full signature here.
We can see is here.
Let's see what section is it in?
It's under the protected section.
So we're gonna go to BEATTIES service that we've created and create a protected section.
And paste in, it's automatically an override here because BEATTIES service was inheriting it itself
from a parent class.
But no harm in overriding it again ourselves.
We can do a control shift P to create the implementation and then we want to call to super.
So we want super tech node and we want to pass in our own comp and a node memory.
And let's see, there's some other things in here.
We have a Delta seconds as well.
That's what we need to pass up as well.
And finally, finish off with a semicolon.
Should be an issue of implementation of take node.
Now, in here, we basically want to do that behavior from the A.I. controller, S.P., the one where
we are getting the blackboard component, then setting a value as a vector.
Well, we know how to get Blackbaud components from ONA component references.
So that's pretty straightforward.
We're just going to do the owner comp dots and then we can do the get Blackbaud components, remembering
that we need to hash include in here for the behavior tree forward slash Blackbaud component.
Then we can use our arrow operator.
And what we should be able to do here is just to set value as vector and then we need a key.
Well we know how to deal with this, but let's just refresh our memory.
If we go to our BEATTIES service, underscore Blackbaud Base.
You can see it same as with the task.
We've got the get selected Blackbaud Key.
So what we're gonna use gets slightly.
Blackbaud Key gets the key that was selected over in the behavior tree.
And then we want our vector value where we're going to get that will exact the same as the A.I. controller.
We're going to be getting the play a pawn first and foremost up here at the top.
Then we need to check whether or not this is null.
And we also need to include our game play static.
So let's make sure we have the game play.
Static's include from the A.I. controllers, GPP included in our player service player location.
Then we're going to do.
And if the player porn is equal to no pointer, then what we're going to want to do is again return
early here.
It returns void.
So we can just do a quick early return.
Then we can use our player pawn here to simply get the actor location.
And we may need to do and include here.
We'll see how we go.
Well, it doesn't hurt to be safe, does it?
And explicit about these things.
So we're gonna do a include for the game framework and then a forward slash.
It's going to be porn dot h.
So that we can make sure that we've got everything in order here.
And then we're just setting the value as back to that should be all we need.
Let's go and compile and see if this works.
In fact, one more thing.
We probably want a nice pretty name, so we should have a constructor here.
So I going to create a public section with the constructor, which is gonna be the name of the class.
And then we go ahead and create that implementation.
I'm gonna bring my implementation above the implementation for TEQ Node and then we're gonna have set
the node name equal to it should be update player location and let's build and see if that works.
Let's look at a missing semicolon.
Let's try that again.
Once that's compiled successfully, we can go over into our enemy A.I. And as well as the setting focus,
we'll add a new service which we've got showing up here as the play location, which where the pretty
name basically comes up as update player location.
You can see that it wants to it tells you the frequency of ticking every point for two point six seconds.
That's better than using tick because we know tick runs every frame here.
This is running less frequently, which is a good thing.
And we can go into the details and create a blackboard key dropdown and select that we want to update
is not only the play location, but the last known player location, because that will happen every
frame as long as we are chasing and that is the behavior that we want.
So one more service node we want to go ahead and create is going to do the elite controllers behavior
go down and to take and see what's left for us to do here is to update the player location conditional
on whether we have line of sight.
So we want it to update the player location.
If we have line of sight, clear the location.
If we don't.
So that's gonna be a new service.
Notice slightly different behavior.
We're going to add new new C++ class.
We're gonna go to show all classes.
And again, we're gonna do BEATTIES service, underscore Blackbaud bases our base class and we're gonna
call it B.T. Service Underscore.
Player location if seen.
And go ahead and create that class, because this is all stuff you've mostly seen before.
It's gonna be your challenge to implement this service.
So you're going to implement tech node using the code over in the A.I. controller as your guide.
You're going to need to get hold of the A.I. controller, a pointer from within the Beatty service.
Now, this is exactly the same as we did in the Beatty task.
So use that as a guidance for getting hold of the AI controller pointer.
You'll need the AI controller pointer in order to check for line of sight.
Remember, line of sight is a method on the A.I. controller.
And then you need to update or clear the key depending on your line of sight check and then place this
node in the behavior tree.
Where do you think is going to be the right level of the behavior tree for this service to run?
Have a little think about that.
To the weight of a chicken scratch pause video and have a go.
Hey, welcome back.
So this has opened up a new BEATTIES service over in Visual Studio Code.
Now, it's pretty much gonna be identical in the header, so I'm gonna go ahead and copy that over into
our newly generated header.
The exception being that we need to change the name of the constructor to match.
Now we're going to create an implementation for the constructor and give it a node name to update player
location if seen.
And add a semicolon on the end here.
Let's not forget that this time, then back into the C++, going to implement TEQ node as well.
And I'm just gonna copy across if we can find ourselves the play location CVP and just gonna copy it,
cross the call to super and the getting of the play a porn and the checking of the null return.
In fact I'm going to copy the whole body and we're going to modify it from there.
So copying that across.
And also we're going to be copying the access to the blackboard component with it in the include for
the blackboard component.
The gameplay static's and the porn, because we need access to all of those.
In fact, much of the functionality is shared here.
You could think about having them somehow share this code.
But I think there's not so much duplication that we care enough.
So what we're gonna have to do here is also check that we have an A.I. controller song and do it.
If the owner components on a comp dot get a guy owner is equal to null pointer, then we're going to
wants to go ahead and return.
At this stage, then the next thing we're gonna want to do is check out visibility.
So we're gonna do an if owner comp dot gets a A.I. owner and then we're gonna do an arrow here and we
need to include AI control here.
So it's gonna be hash include.
And then it's going to be a high controller, so h then we want to do line and see what's the correct
usage here.
If we go over to the controllers, GPP, its line of sight to is what we want.
So line of sight to then we need to do line of sight to the player porn.
In this case, do we have line of sight to play a porn?
Is that what we're doing over in the TPP?
Let's just double check that.
Yes, we are.
Then we're going to want to go ahead and set the values differently.
So we're setting the vector value to the player porn.
Get actor location.
Yes, that's if we've got line of sight or else if we do not have line of sight, we know that we need
to be clearing that value.
So we're going to be still getting the owner component get Blackbaud component.
Then it's gonna be clear value and we're going to be clearing the value of the selected Blackbaud Key
still.
And that should pretty much cover us for the implementation of player location if seen.
Let's go and compile and see if it works.
Well, a compilation succeeded.
Let's go in to the behavior tree.
Now, at the level I want this to run, it is basically at the top level in the initial selector because
I wanted to be updating the player location.
Basically all the time, because we need to be able to abort any of these other behaviors based on the
play location being set.
So we need to be able to set an unsettled at any time.
So I'm going to go and right click on the top level selector ad service at the player location if seen.
And then we're gonna need to select that service node and select its Blackbaud Key, which is gonna
be our player location.
So that would say in the play location, the update player location, the modem one is updating the
last known player location.
And we should now be able to go into our A.I. controller and essentially remove all of this code in
tick because it's been superseded by our services instead.
And we can go ahead and compile and see if that works.
Let's go over to the editor and play and see if we've still got an enemy coming up to us.
He's coming running to us, loses sight, then comes back at us, starts shooting.
Yep.
Basically, everything is working as it was doing before, except now it's doing it entirely via services
that we wrote for ourselves in C++.
Next lecture, we're gonna be fixing that pesky bug where the A.I. continues to shoot and eventually
manages to kill itself off.
I'll see you there.