Hey Hey fellow wonderful Mac people.
So if you're on P.C. or Linux you may as well completely skip this video because I don't think there's
any value in it for you.
But if you're on macOS first thing we need to do is check whether or not you have at least macOS
10.14 Mojave
Because if you don't then you're going to have trouble with Unreal Engine later.
So if you don't then upgrade and I hope that you can upgrade that's part of the course prerequisites.
Awesome.
With that out of the way and talking about prerequisites.
The reason we're doing this as a reminder is that Unreal Engine is going to need something called a
compiler.
Now to find a compiler in the previous video if you didn't watch the previous video watch the first
two and a half minutes or so because they will go through some of these basics and explain this diagram
in more detail but we're over here on the right hand side.
Installing Xcode to go alongside Unreal Engine but also to make sure that the compiler is available
to do its magic and work between Unreal Engine and the disk and make things that are actually runnable.
Okey dokey.
So later in the course we're gonna be compiling C++ code ourselves from the terminal or at least from
within inside Visual Studio Code.
And for that to work then a command called a g++ would need to work and at the moment you don't
need by the way to follow this.
I'm just demonstrating that if you were to open a terminal and try that now you'll get the following
dialog which will say it can't run because you don't have the necessary prerequisites.
Well you may have the necessary prerequisites but even if you do what I want us to do is make sure that
we get Xcode.
So that's gonna be your challenge in a minute.
You can have two things in your challenge one is gonna be to get Xcode.
The other thing we're going to need installed is the Epic Games Launcher.
So I don't need to teach you how to install software.
He is a very simple challenge for you install Epic Games Launcher and Xcode. Get Xcode installing from
the AppStore agree to any terms and conditions.
If you're on a slow broadband you might want to let that finish before also getting the Epic Games Launcher
going that's up to you but also get the Epic Games Launcher installing and we're gonna use that later
to get Unreal downloading but not in this video we'll do that all together with the P.C. people and
any issues help each other in the community so go ahead get Epic Games Launcher and Xcode downloading.
All right welcome back.
So well I've got this Epic Games Launcher page open up for a start that going pretty simple.
You need to download for Mac and that will start.
So I'll leave that going in the background and go back to the App Store.
Now in the App Store of course you need to be signed in pretty obviously so I'm going to click on get
Xcode and then install Xcode.
It's a free program and don't worry about the low ratings that's people complaining about various things
it's actually a pretty good system and required for us to work inside Unreal with C++.
So sign into your Apple I.D. If you haven't already. username and password let the App Store do its thing
its whirligig is going to go round in circles until it's convinced that you have a valid Apple account
and then you are worthy of downloading the mighty Xcode.
All right so while that works out whether I'm worthy or not I'm going to pop back to safari and see
how we're doing with our Epic Games Launcher download.
I think it's done. Yep.
And I'm just gonna install that.
It also mentions Unreal Tournament.
You'd also use the same launcher to launch things like Fortnight and other games.
It's basically Epic Games launcher.
If anything to do with Epic Games this is how you launch. Normal software install not going to talk you
through how you do that just go ahead get that installed.
I'm going to eject the image file there.
I always eject my image files on the Mac by the way immediately just for cleanness and also to make
sure I'm running the program actually from my install directory not from that image.
If you end up with a whole load of images sitting there needing to be ejected maybe that's the time
to tidy that up.
Okay now the Eepic Games Launcher won't actually open on my virtual machine but I'd like you to get this
far and try and open it.
It should open on your machine and that is a good indication that you are ready to go.
Don't download Unreal Engine yet just get the installer going and then we just need to wait for X code
to finish downloading and installing and I'll resume the video.
When that's happened on my machine.
All right.
So after some patience we're at this point where we agree to the Xcode software license which may
require you to put in your macOS password and then the final installation of components will go on
and the last thing I want you to do is just make sure that Xcode is actually going to open.
So I'll come back once this component installation is finished and eventually you'll get to a screen
something like this just to check it works.
I'm going to create a new Xcode project but we're not going to concern ourselves with Xcode at all
in this course as long as you end up with something like this template view for your project you can
cancel out go to Xcode and quit Xcode and we aren't done.
We are on the same page as the P.C. guys now we have our prerequisites installed in their case it's
Visual Studio Community.
In our case it is Xcode and we have the Epic Games Launcher installed so that we can all together install
the Unreal Engine the appropriate version 4.22 and move on from there.
So I'll see you shortly.