Hello, everybody, and welcome in this lecture, we're going to be downloading the bull cow assets
so that we've got everything running and working to start the project.
Now, first of all, we'll be checking.
You have unreal engine four point two, two or greater installed with download the assets from the Udemy
resources.
Now, the Udemy resources themselves, you might not be familiar with them.
So make sure you are.
And they will make sure the project works as well.
So let's go ahead and dive in.
I'm going to go ahead now and launch the epic games launcher.
And if you don't already have it selected, you can go to the left hand side and click on Unreal Engine
once.
For that, we've got Unreal Engine and I can see I've got unreal engine four point two two point two.
If you have multiple engines installed, you will have to go to the library and have a look under there.
I can see that I have an update there.
I'm not going to run that at the moment.
That can take a while to do on screen, but I'll probably run that in a bit in the background.
So once we've got everything all sorted there, this may take an hour or so to download.
I know unreal engines quite big.
But you will need to make sure you got version 4.0, too.
And then go ahead, click launch and make sure that the engine itself launches.
When you first launch it, it will come up with Unreal Ed Unreal, its four point two two point two.
This is not how we're going to be loading up.
Our game will actually be double clicking on the ball calvey game itself in order to launch it.
And the first time you launch Unreal Engine, it might take a while to open.
But if you get to this stage here, seem the Unreal Project browser, you can have a look at the various
projects that are already in there.
Obviously I've got a few in here already.
Yours may look different, including the bull cow game because I've been showing you stuff.
So let's go ahead.
Let's close that down.
So that's all done.
The next thing we need to do is download the assets from the Udemy resources.
Okay.
So when you're watching the video over on Udemy, you may not have the sidebar open if we wiggle our
mouse around.
We've got a coarse content arrow at the top.
Right.
We go ahead and click on that.
It's currently lecture 38, but that may change as I'm adding bits in and moving things around.
And we have importing bull cow game under the resources will be able to get to.
In this case, the bottom one here, the bull cow gained starter kit dot zip.
You'll need to download that to your computer.
It's around twenty megabyte file, so it should not take too long to download.
Once you've done that, we can open up the file.
Now you're going to have to extract this from the CIP file.
In this case, I'm going to extract here to a folder on your computer that you're working on now.
I've got a very specific folder because I've got all of my projects under source control.
So I'm gonna go into my repos, into my own real folder and into my bowl cal games.
I'm going to click okay there and okay to extract it doesn't really matter where you're putting on your
computer.
But this is going to be the folder in which you're working.
And we go and check out that folder now.
Okay.
So I know I just said it doesn't matter where you extract it onto your computer.
I'd made the assumption there that no one would try to extract it into their program files directory.
Don't do that.
We're not extracting this into unreal.
We are just extracting it to a standard working folder on your computer.
So whether that's your documents or folder on your computer that you've set up specifically to do this
type of work, that's absolutely fine.
And of course, you may have already created a blank repository if you're working with any sort of version
control as well.
That's the sort of thing that we're going for.
And let's get back to it.
We can see here that the folder is there and ready to go if we go into that folder.
We can see we've got everything else here as well.
Now, all I'm going to do at the moment is make sure that the bowl cal game is working in order to do
that.
And this is what I will be doing.
From now on, in order to launch my project is double click on the ball cal game, unreal project file.
When we do that, it may give you this warning is very likely to the following modules are missing or
built with a different engine version.
Would you like to rebuild.
And the answer is going to be yes here.
This will take a few minutes to do.
Depending on the speed of your system.
Hey there, Sam.
From the future.
Here's give you a quick message.
If you get any build errors while you are trying to open this, then have a look and a lecture that
is coming up in just a bit called Help US to Help You, which will give you instructions on getting
hold of logs in unreeled so that you can ask proper questions.
And also, you might find some information in there that helps you solve it for yourself.
Now back to Mike.
And here we go.
Once that started going through the game itself, we start loading up.
Won't take too long at all.
Okay, brilliant.
We've got everything all loaded up and we're in our game.
Couple of things that we're going to just do real quick at the moment.
I haven't got it because I've already launched this and unrolls aware of it.
But you may have down in the bottom, right?
It's saying that it's doing something with shaders.
It will take a few minutes to sort that out.
On my laptop, it took maybe five to 10 minutes to actually sort out the shaders.
So your world might not look quite like this with a lot of colors in.
Instead, it sorts that out.
The other thing that we can do here, just to check everything really is working properly, is we can
click on the build button, they'll get rid of these reflexion captures need to be rebuilt.
It's not the end of the world at the moment.
We can do that at any time.
But more importantly, I'm going to click this compile button.
This one's going to come back to haunt you if you don't realize it's there.
But if we go ahead and click compile, you should have down at the bottom.
It's saying compiling C++ code.
After that's finished, you should see it's a compile complete and that's how we know that everything's
working and structured properly.
If that doesn't happen, for whatever reason, give his shout in the queue and ICE will help you out
there.
So if you've been following along, brilliant.
We've got to the end of this lecture.
If you haven't and you've just been watching, I've got a challenge for you.
Okay, so your challenge is to go ahead and open the bull cow game.
So make sure you are using unreal engine four point two.
So I understand that it may be still be downloading, even though you've got to this point in the video.
If it is still downloading, then whilst that is downloading, go and grab the book.
How Game Starts.
A kit from the Artemis Resources, extract the files, ready to go and then check.
You can launch the game.
Obviously you're going to have to wait for unreeled update, but once that's all done, check.
You can launch the game and then we're good to go.
So go ahead.
Pause video now and give Vassago.
Okay, everybody, welcome back.
Congratulations on getting the bull cow game installed.
Just to reiterate that, when you go ahead and open up your file directory for me, which is all the
way down here, I've still got it launched at the moment, has closed it down.
If I double click on the Bull Cow Game Unreal Project, it will take a few moments to launch.
Now, if that error comes up again, I'll show you how to dismiss that as well.
It's not an important issue.
Yes.
As so we just go down to the bottom.
Right, click on clear the messages in this log.
I'm going to close down that window and simply even go control.
In essence, save or just save current.
Once you've done that, you will find that the next time you open it up, you won't get the error message,
which is really nice to have.
Now, that's not to say that we should avoid having error messages and just hide the mouse the way that
one is not important.
In this case, some here with a quick answer to an frequently asked questions that we get about this
project.
Now, some people ask, why are we being given a project, has a bunch of code in it?
Why aren't we building all of this code from scratch?
Now, don't worry, this isn't a precedent.
The following sections are all going to get you working from scratch, creating the products entirely
on your own.
But in this project, we just wanted to give you a leg up, seeing as it's the first time we're introducing
Unreal for a lot of you.
And Unreeled got a lot of things to introduce.
Who wanted to make sure that you had a clear and easy starting point to get started with when making
the jump from pure C++ to unreal C++?
So that's why we've done it.
In future sections, you are going to encounter the raw might of Unreal all on its own.
So don't worry, we will get there eventually.
So there we go.
We've got everything sorted and ready to go.
And now we've done that.
We can start having a look at the interface as a whole and how to interact with the unreal editor.
And we'll do that in the next lecture.