Hello and welcome back.
In this lesson, we're going to begin our C++ journey by writing the most minimal program.
And we're going to be starting very simple here.
So this is the code that we're going to be writing in this lesson.
And this is known as the main function in C++.
Now, why are we starting with this?
Why don't we just start with one simple line of code?
Well, there's very specific reasons for this.
Every C++ program requires this main function.
A C++ program can have many different functions in it.
But the main function is very special because when you execute a C++ program, the operating system
will look for this main function when it runs.
It's the starting point of your program.
And without it, your program will not even build some.
Here with a quick tip for you.
Just before Gavin dives in, it's going to be much easier for you if you open a folder in Visual Studio
Code before you create any files.
That means everything will be nicely organized together.
Visual studio code just works better when you're working within a folder.
So you need to do this from this button under the Star welcome tab.
Or if that's not open, you go to file open folder.
And then you can create yourself a new folder.
And hey, I'm gonna cool mine triple x and then I'm gonna hit enter and go into it and then select the
folder.
And you can see it's just gonna open up like this.
You can see over the left hand side there's the explorer windows gonna show all the files inside your
folder and other things are going to just work a little bit easier.
Now let's jump in and start writing our code inside Visual Studio Code against come up to file and then
new file.
Now let's immediately save this file by hitting control s or command s if you're on Mac and that Save
the File has triple X dot c p p by saving a file as dot c p visual studio code is going to understand
that we're working with a C++ file, as we can see down in the bottom right corner of its interface.
And it's also going to provide some code formatting for us, as we'll see in a moment.
Now follow along with me here.
We're going to start by typing out I and T for NS and notice how he starts this with a lower case I.
Okay, so it's case sensitive.
We need to be aware of how we type our code after ends.
We're going to add a space and spaces in our code, unknown as whitespace after our space we're gonna
type out main.
So this is the name of the function and this is gonna be followed by some parentheses.
When we add the parentheses visual studio code, you put our cursor on the end of the line and when
it does, we can hit enter to go into a new line and we can open some curly braces or curly brackets.
If we start by putting in a left curly bracket, this whole studio code is going to help us out by filling
in the right curly bracket and put our cursor in between these brackets.
And we can hit enter to go onto a new line and the right curly brace goes to the fourth line here.
And on the third line, our cursor is now slightly indented here.
Here we can type return space zero and finish the line with a semicolon.
So this is the int main function.
Let's hit control s and save our work.
Notice that our code here is all different colors.
And this is what I mean by code formatting.
Now let's just break down this main function.
Why do we start with NS so into short for integer and an integer is just a whole number without any
decimal places.
So functions in C++ can return values to the operating system.
And in our case Int Main is telling us that it returns an integer and we're actually doing this.
We are returning zero here.
We'll come back to this in a second.
After int we have Main, which is the name of the function and then we have these parentheses here said
the parentheses are used to pass arguments into the function.
Now we're not doing this right now, but we will be covering this for out the section.
And next, we have the curly braces and the code within the curly braces.
This is known as the function body, which at the moment only has our return statement here.
So the main function is special because its return value is used as an exit status to the operating
system.
So zero signals that the program has run successfully.
While any of a value will signal an error.
So what can we expect when we compile our code and run this program?
Well, let's just find out.
Remember, we always want to save our work before compiling so hit control s we can even turn on autosave
by coming up to file and then checking autosave here to compile our work.
We're gonna come to the Explorer here.
We can right click triple x dot CBP and open it in the terminal.
Notice that the terminal shows the directory of where we saved our file.
We can compile our code on a Mackle Linux by typing G.
Plus plus space triple X dot CBP space minus O for the output file name, which will be triple X.
Now I'm on Windows, so if you're following on windows we can just type C L space triple x dot c.p.
So this compiles our code and to run our program on Makela.
Next you're gonna want to type dot forward slash triple X, but if you're following on windows we can
just type triple X.
And this opens and runs our program.
Now, this doesn't look like it's done anything, but our program has just run and it's exited without
any errors.
And currently, this is all our program does at this stage.
So this is totally expected behavior.
So earlier in this lesson, I mentioned that spaces in our code are known as white space.
And right now, I want you to do some exploring on your own to see how it affects your code.
Try writing all of the code that makes up the int main function onto one line.
Then compile and run your code to see what happens.
Does it even compile support here for a few moments to try it?
Okay, so let's take a look at this together.
I've made my line of code a bit drastic here.
We've lots of white spaces between it.
Now, if I come down to the terminal and compile.
Remember, we always want to save our work if you don't have autosave on.
We want to compile by typing S.L triple x dot CVP.
If you are on windows that will compile.
Remember, we can use the arrows on the terminal as well.
But notice we've compiled with no issue here, even if we put our code onto different lines and have
lots of whitespace between it.
We still don't have any issue when we compile.
And this is because the compiler completely ignores whitespace.
Now, this doesn't mean I want you to be unorganized and completely reckless with your code.
I'm just making you aware that the compiler is going to completely ignore the white space in your code.
And there's an exception here that we will see in the next lesson.
But I'm going to leave you with this.
Before we move onto the next lesson, I want you to reorganize your code to match my code we see here.
And this is the exact same way we set it up at the start of the lesson.
Then once you've done this, we can move on to the next lesson.