Hello everybody and welcome back in this lecture.
We are going to assess one letter of a word against another.
And if they equal one another that we know it's not an eyesore gram.
So let's start off with the word that we are currently looking at.
So we're looking at C A K E S.
Excellent.
Now this is Element Zero One Two Three Four.
Okay.
So how would we go ahead and assess this.
Well first of all we would go and assess Element Zero against the next one so against element 1.
So we'd check 0 against 1 then we'd go zero against two zero against three and zero against four.
Now this is a bit of a multidimensional problem after we've assessed everything against the first letter.
We then have to go on to assess the other letters against each other as well and we'll get to that in
the next lecture.
So let's dive over into V.S. code and work out how we just do the first one here.
Okay.
So now that we're over Invesco the first thing I want to do is a tiny bit of tidying we've got this
call for.
Is Isaac gram to print out.
We don't need that anymore in our game so I'm gonna remove that.
That was a great test to make sure we knew how to iterate through.
And then we have here.
So this is Isaac Ram this is where we're going to be working.
Okay.
So looking at the is Isaac Ram function let's go and comment outside existing for loop and then we can
work higher up.
Now there are a couple of ways that we can go ahead and format what we're about to do now thinking about
it.
We need to integers now I'm going to declare them and initialize them here and then we'll see how that
impacts are for loop and we can also initialize them within the for loop itself so I'll show you both
ways of doing it.
So to start with we've gotten in 32 index.
Now this is going to stay the same but we're going to initialize it with a value of zero and then keep
referring back to it as we assess each other character against that index.
And then we've also got something else so we need this something else.
So we can compare to it.
So I'm going to call it comparison and we're going to initialize that to index plus 1.
So we're going to start comparing the index against index plus 1 and then of course we can increment
the comparison each time as we go through always checking it back against the index.
Now when it comes to later on in the next lecture we'll do it ever so slightly differently because we
need to increment the index as well eventually.
So now that we've got that sets we can start our 4 loop now because we've already set an initialized
our two variables that we're going to compare we don't actually need something here at the first point
where we're initializing and it's quite common to see for loops written in a similar manner to this.
Now in this particular case we're going to be incrementing the comparison so we can simply say here
whilst the comparison is less than the word length.
Now you may think at this particular point that you need to do less than or equal to the word length.
But the problem is that if you go beyond the end of the word length you're going to end up out of bounds
and that will crash on real hard which we don't want to do.
And then we're going to increment comparison so let's go ahead and increment it's excellent.
Okay.
So that's the for loop setup.
Now there'll be something in here and if statements that will return False if these two are equal to
one another but then we also need to remember to return true which we've already got down here I almost
wrote that again.
Let's go ahead return true.
Now the other way that you can write this is to put these two initialization right at the very beginning.
So what we can do here instead of initialize them up here and this is down to code style at the end
of the day.
We can also go in 32 index equals zero.
Just like we did before.
And then we need our comparison as well.
And we need to give it a value.
Now we don't start declaring another type at this point you may be thinking oh why didn't I go in 32
again.
We don't do that and we can say this is equal to index plus 1.
Perfect.
So this will work in exactly the same manner as declaring them and initializing them up here.
The primary difference between the two is in fact the scope of these variables that we've just declared
If we declare them outside of the for loop they exist in at a wider scope then within the for loop themselves.
So that's something to bear in mind there.
It does change the scope of those variables.
So we have our first for loop Ritson but it doesn't do anything yet because there's no code in here
and that is going to be your challenge okay.
So your challenge is to check whether two characters of the same.
This should be relatively straightforward.
So create the if statement within our for loop that is needed to check the first character against all
of the others.
Now bear in mind when you do this you'll also need to return something.
If that happens to be the case pause the video now and give us a go
Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead now hop back on over interveners code and completes our if statement okay.
Everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead and type in the code that we need.
So this is going to be an if statement.
Let's go in then.
Now what's the condition here we're basically saying if the word index is equal to the word comparison
if those two are equivalent then we're going to return false.
So if the word open your square brackets which is called the subscript operator and we could indeed
put a magic number in here we could go zero.
And that would work for this particular example because we never change index at all.
However we want this to be able to be changed later on so we'll type in if the word index which is fine
is the same or is equal to the word comparison.
Then we're going to do something and that do something is going to be to return false.
And now what that will mean is that when it returns false it will come back up here and it will return.
So if this is not true if it's false we're going to say no repeating letters and to guess again let's
put a bit of punctuation in there.
There's also a few the hidden word is I've missed some punctuation here.
I bet some of you have been telling me about that as well.
Anyway let's go load up bull cows and see if it works.
OK.
So now this is loaded up.
We can click compile.
Okay.
So whilst that's compiling let's think about what we will get out of this code if the first letter of
our word is the same as any of the others it should say oh no repeating characters are how we've complete.
However if any of the other letters are the same it will just continue and it will take a life because
we're not assessing the other letters yet against each other.
So let's try that.
So if we were to go ahead and type in a b c d e we should get a loss of life.
That's fine.
If we go A B C D no repeating letters guess again and we'll find if we repeats this throughout the other
positions that repeated letters can exist and we'll get no repeated letters.
Now is the A that's repeated there.
That's just do a D DDD and we're fine we'll lose a life.
So we're not assessing those other letters yet but the A is working let's put a at the end as well.
There we go.
So our code is working exactly how we expected to.
This is really exciting.
This little bits of code that we've been working on here is going through checking each one of the letters
against the first letter of a word.
Just gonna do it tidy up around here and delete our extra whitespace.
Now we've not quite completed this yet.
However we have moved on from this.
So let's go ahead and remove that from our code.
So it's nice and clean.
I'm just going to quickly go up an eyeball.
I would recommend doing this from time to time it helps get your eye in code and it's formatting and
I'm guilty of missing things as well or leaving extra whitespace where it's not necessary.
Nice clean code makes it easier to read.
There we go.
I'm happy with that.
How are you guys getting on.
Please share your work over and the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.