Hello everybody and welcome to part two of checking your characters.
So this is where we are at the moment we're checking each or the first one against everything else but
then we need to move on and check one against two three and four and then two against three and four
and then three against four we never need to do that last one there so we can expand what we've got
here and I'll try and keep my writing as neat as possible we can expand what we've got here to check
the other way as well because essentially what we end up with is a grid.
So we have C A K E S perfect.
Now.
The interesting thing about this grid is we don't need to check things against themselves.
So this check this check this check this check and this check are null and void.
We just don't do them.
Which basically means here that we don't check anything in these particular cells although the cells
are quite hard to read.
Maybe I'll draw some lines.
I think you guys go Well I mean that we don't need to check anything against it now because we don't
check backwards either.
So once we've assessed element or index 0 against everything we don't then check ELEMENT ONE BACK AGAINST
Element Zero just wouldn't make any sense.
So all of these are also null and void.
We don't need to check them in the past backwards and this makes our code quite straightforward because
all we need to do is keep moving forward in this direction.
As you can see here we don't check s against anything which is great.
So the only checks we need to loop around are these ones here which is really useful.
We've already done the first one which is the one you can see at the top here.
We've compared C AGAINST A K E and S..
So this is Element Zero of our index of our word.
And we've checked it against one two three and four.
We then need to increment that after we've done that check.
We need to increment it to the next one element 1 and then we check it once again against K E and s
element two three and four and then we.
And then that's the important thing.
And then we increment it.
We've got to do this check first and then we increment it and then we do the next check.
And then we increment sets and so forth.
And of course when we gets to this one here we should be in this case element 3.
There's no point in incrementing any more so we can actually stop the loop sooner than we would have
done otherwise.
And with that in mind I want to actually jump straight into the challenge.
I think you've got all the information you need in order to create your nested for loop to iterate through
the entire word and check everything against itself.
Okay.
So straight into our challenge here what I'd like you to do is create a nested for loop to go through
each letter and compare it against the others.
Now we've done nested if statements before a nested for loop is exactly the same we'll have a for loop
within a for loop and then our if statement checking within that final for loop if you're really unsure
about that Don't worry.
There are a couple of hints coming up and I'll let you guys pause the video before we get to those if
you think you've got it.
Now remember if any of the characters are the same then it fails the test.
We've already done that in the if statement.
So our current if statement within those nested for loops should be absolutely fine.
And rewrite it for practice.
Now what do I mean by that.
Well if we have a look at our code itself it's almost there it's tempting to change it.
But what I would advise you do is actually rewrite it.
It's better for your coding skills to actually go ahead and retype things out.
Obviously comments out what you've got there and you've got the new code working.
Now if you're happy with that and you're ready to go ahead pulls the video and give that a go if you'd
like one or two hints then hold on a moment.
Your first hint is now so the first loop will be the index.
Then you'll be looping the comparison so that's the order.
If you're happy with that and that's just made you go yes I've got it then pulls a video and give that
a go now don't worry if you need this extra bit of help nested loops and thinking through the logic
of how it runs for a beginner can be challenging.
So this is the layouts that we're going to do now.
I haven't filled in all the blanks I obviously want you to use your brain and try and work out the details
of this but this is roughly how it's going to be laid out.
We're going to have a for loop based upon the index and nested within that.
We're going to have a for loop with the comparison and nested within that we will have our if statement
checking whether two values of the same.
And then we can come out of that we will need to return something should it fail that test.
And then of course we've got our return true at the end.
So there you go.
There are a few hints to get going pulls with you now and give us a go.
Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and code up our nested for loop that's going to check every character not just against
the first one but against the other ones as well.
OK so back over into V.S. code one thing that I wanted to just point out before we move on is another
alternative way of writing this.
We've got this or this and of course what we could have done here is actually sets the index to zero
and then within this loop done the comparison.
What do I mean by that.
Well let's line 93 let's say and comment that and then we can just remove index equaling zero so we
can set it up like that as well.
And the main difference as I mentioned before is scope comparison is only going to work within the scope
of the for loop index is now available to everything within this function itself.
Okay.
So let's just comment all of that out for the moment.
Thanks for that.
I'm sure just double commented some stuff.
Yes line 94 is double commented.
Here we go.
Right.
Let's make some space at the top here and work out what we're going to do.
So we're going start off with a for loop that's gonna be focused on the index itself.
So we're gonna call this an int 32 index and we'll get a set to equal to zero because that's the first
letter and then whilst the index is less than now it's going to be the word.
Now this is something we're we're familiar with at this point this is pretty much what we've done before.
And then we're going to increment the index.
That's fine.
Now within here this is where we write our second for loop.
So the first for loop is going to iterate around the index but until this reaches the end.
So the comparison when that reaches the end it's going to dropouts again and then increment the index
again.
So starting from the next number up.
That's the important thing here.
So what we've we've got here we've got another in 32.
Now this time I'm in the press tabs so I can just typing comparison rather than oh dear that's about
spelling sorry rather than having to fart around with it.
Now it's not equal to zero is it's it's equal to the index plus one.
And the comparison here whilst it's less than again the word dot Lang and then our parentheses.
Now it is tempting here as I've mentioned before I think to put less than or equal to but by the time
we reach the last letter what that would actually do if we want to do that is it forces out of bounds
and unreal would just crash is like comparing it to a question mark what's what is greater than the
last letter of a word.
Well there isn't an answer there.
Whoops I end up leaving that in however I do realize later on and remove it.
Right now it comes to our if statement.
Now I am tempted to just copy and paste this in but I don't want to do that one thing will do though
is remove this return true other wasn't going to end up repeating myself there.
Okay so this is going to have an if statement in it and we're going to say if the word we're looking
at and then the index is the same as the word comparison then we are going to return false.
Okay.
With that saved let's just run through what this is going to do.
So we're going to start with index at zero then it's going to carry on it's going to go to our next
line of code it's gonna set the comparison to index plus 1 and then it's going to start comparing the
index which is 0 to the comparison which starts off at once it's going to compare 0 to 1 if that is
not true then we will just loop back around again until we reach the end of the words we'll go through
each of the comparison letters the moment we've done that and we drop back out it will increment the
index by 1 and then we're checking the second character against the third fourth fifth etc. and we continue
doing that until we've run out of letters we never assess the very end of the word because we have nothing
more to compare it to as we saw in the sketch at the beginning of this lecture.
So all being well this should be a matter of tidying up a bit of white space I think there's the last
one here and let's save that and before I start deleting all of this lot because it's now redundant
we don't need the comments there.
Let's go ahead and run our game and make sure it's working.
Okay so let's go ahead and compile the code.
Now I won't be able to test every variation but within a few tests we're going to know that it's working
as we would expect it to.
Okay compiling is complete.
Let's play the game.
Now what we're expecting here obviously is if we type something into the right number of we've got a
crash with an out of bounds era did I.
It was like demonstrating something and left it in.
Yes I left it in.
How silly of me.
So there you go.
There's a real example of how when you're demonstrating courage you can leave something in there and
you get the out of bounds error.
That was very confusing.
Okay so let's fire up bull cow again and this time with our code corrected hopefully we won't be crashing.
Unreal this time round.
Let's compile the code.
I feel so silly for doing that.
But never mind.
Okay so let's press play this time.
Excellent.
So when we go bikes we've lost the life.
However if we went b b a k e.
No repeating letters but we know it would have done that anyway because we were checking it against
the first one last time.
So if we type in something like this of course this is not a word at the moment.
No repeating letters no repeating letters guess again you've lost a life.
This seems to be working exactly how I'd wanted to know repeating letters.
In fact that's the same as one that was further up.
Okay.
I'm happy that everything's working as it should do including my mistake earlier.
Isn't that incredible that we've managed to nest two loops together.
And as they go round they're able to assess an entire word just those few lines of code are able to
accomplish that and we're gonna be able to put this to the test.
Now when we go and grab a word list to insert into our game because we need to validate that word list
and make sure that the hidden word that set from it is actually an eyesore gram itself.
Otherwise the player will never be able to guess the correct word and we'll put that together in the
next lecture.