Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to create our own array a list of words that we can pick a hidden word from.
Now we've talked about and looked at the tea array before when we were talking about the individual
characters that make up strings.
Now when it comes to a tea array it's got a certain format to it.
We'll run through it and then do an example MVS code.
So we have a concert t array and then we define its type.
Then we give it a name and then we need to make sure that the array contains something you can't have
an array that doesn't contain anything.
So then we open our curly braces and we put elements into that array that match the type that we've
declared.
And those elements have to be the same type that you've declared.
And there's no mixing or matching of types a t array only holds one type.
Anything that you give it must be that type or directly implicitly convertible to that type as well
so that's the theory part's over let's dive over into V.S. code and take a closer look okay.
So overinvest code the first thing that I'm going to do is actually create a new file where we're going
to keep all of our words.
So let's go ahead and go to file new file and we're going to save it straightaway so we can reference
it.
So here we go.
We can save as well we could pick save leave it in the same place and let's call it hidden word list
dot H.
It's gonna become a header file.
It's a separate file.
There's no point put in all of those words so that could be the hidden word in the code that we're running.
Now this not only makes our code a lot easier to read because otherwise it's adding a lot of noise into
the code and it does of course allow us to swap out the words that we're using quite quickly because
they're all within one file.
So go ahead and save that.
And we've got our new hidden word list had a file.
Now before we do anything else we cannot just type in at the moment.
Well let's try.
If I type in t array it doesn't know what we're talking about.
So we need to make sure we include the minimal requirements in order to do that.
So we hash include and then open quotation marks.
Call is it going to give it says on the list.
Yes here we go.
Call minimal dot H and what that's going to allow us to do is type in things like t array.
There we go it's right there.
Okay.
So first of all it's going to be a const T array.
And why is it const.
Well in this particular case we need to make sure that our array and the elements within that array
are not going to change.
We don't want that to happen with way through it protects us.
So the concert there make sure that we're not going to break that promise.
Now we need to give it a type.
We need to say what does this array contain.
For this example we can fill it with integers and because it's in 32 I think a good name will be numbers
we could call it integers as well as entirely up to you.
And then we need to put some values and we can't just leave it like that.
So we need to open up some curly braces and let's say one comet to come a three Come a four so we can
separate our elements of our array with commas.
Now I would also space these out to make it more readable and of course we need our semicolon on the
end.
So this here is an array.
It's called four integers in it and just like before we need to access individual elements of the array
we would access index zero to access element one of our array.
Much like we've been doing when we've been checking letters of the word against one another.
Now when it comes to formatting this if we had words in here instead that would be slightly different
I would formats it's like so.
So I'd make sure that these were on their own line and this probably indented back like so.
And then each word I would probably put that on its own line as well just for readability because you're
going to have things like the text Grover.
So is going to be very difficult to read if they stretch along the screen will end up scrolling horizontally
which is not what we want to do.
Okay.
So that's a great stance with arrays and this leads us nicely onto our challenge OK so your challenge
is going to be to create a hidden word list now include the hidden word list or h the header file that
we've just made in the bull cow cartridge.
Include five words for testing.
And remember that the text macro is required.
Now don't worry at the moment about a bigger list to choose from.
This would be great for testing and what we will do in the next lecture is show you some advanced B.S.
code cursor manipulation so you can handle lots of elements.
Say we go in grab a word list from the internet and just cut and paste it in.
We need to be able to quickly wrap things in our text macro etc. supposedly are now and give that a
go
Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and create a hidden word list of five words.
The first thing I'm going to do here is just change this from an int 32 to f strings.
That's important.
Otherwise it's not gonna work numbers.
That's not a very good name is it.
What should we call it instead.
We could call it words.
It's as simple as that.
And then of course we've got a series of numbers here that won't work.
So we need to have text open our parentheses.
And then we've got the string that we want to put in here.
So we have cakes as one to write one of our examples to see a k s and then.
Well do I want to keep typing text and then adding things in.
The answer is no.
So I am going to copy this a couple of times.
One two three four so that will take us up to five and it's happily indented when I didn't want to.
So shift and tab to bring them back 1.
Now we don't need the comma on the end there that will fail if we do that.
So let's think of our five words we can have cakes we can have water I'm going to stick with five letters
I think for the moment we can have plums kings and knife.
So those are going to be my head and words check in there all I saw grams.
Is quite hard to think of ice grams.
I wanted to put apple in there and thought No I can't do that in bubble and now you can't do anything
that's got repeating letters.
So that's fine.
We got everything set up there.
I'm going to make sure I save that and we do need to include it in the bull cow cartridge CBP farm.
So I have the top here we've got hash include bull cow cartridge H.
So hopefully you guys did not have any issues going on including the hidden word list the H.
Excellent.
And now I think we've got everything sorted perfect.
How did you guys get on.
Did you remember to change the type that's all elements will be in the array.
That's something easy to forget.
And up the top here make sure you've included your hidden word list the h file.
So when we go ahead and pick a hidden word from that list we're able to access it.
Which words did you decide to place in there.
Did you make a mistake like me and think of a couple of non ISO grams.
Make sure you have ISO grams in there.
Otherwise it's not going to work.
And I'll see you all in the next lecture.