Hello and welcome and this light show, we're gonna be introducing this piece of code here, the T actor
range, and see how it allows us to iterate over all of the actors in a given level.
Let's dive in and see how it works.
So at the moment in the porn killed of an KMEL game mode we are calling a game has ended on the player
controller.
But in actual fact, game has ended is a function on all controllers, whether A.I. or player controllers.
And we should probably be notifying the A.I. controllers as well that the game has ended.
And that's certainly gonna be the case, or it's going to make it easier to do a win condition as well,
because we won't necessarily have to play a pawn coming in here.
So how do we go ahead and do this?
Well, I'm going to create a new function in the KMEL game mode, a private one called End Game, which
is going to be responsible for this act.
So end game.
And it's gonna need some information is gonna need to know who has won.
Has it been the player or has it been the A.I.?
So I'm gonna create a pool here called B is play a winner.
And that is going to be what tells us whether or not we should be telling the A.I. that it's one or
telling the player that it's one.
Because remember, in here, our game has ended.
Takes Boolean telling the controller whether or not it is one of the winners.
So what we're gonna have to do is figure out, first of all, let's go ahead and create the implementation.
So I'm gonna do my control shift P and then create implementation and then we're gonna have to figure
out how we can find all of the controllers in our scene so that we can cool game has ended on those
controllers.
Now, the way we're gonna do this is using a an engine helper call.
So forget to hash include going against use engine utils dot h festival.
That's going to bring into scope the help that I want.
And the helper is called T actor range A..
Actor range is a template thing so we can do the angle brackets here.
We can then put a controller and then the parentheses and get world.
Now what's this gonna do.
It's going to returners a range object, which is basically sort of like a list that goes over all of
the controllers.
That's why we've got that controller parameter in there in the world, a.k.a. the level, and we can
use this in a full loop.
So let me start wrapping this in a full loop.
So we're gonna do a four over the A controller.
So that thing that is the variable that we're going to be ranging over.
It's going to be an A controller pointer, which I'm gonna call controller, and then we use the Kolon
for what we're going to range over.
It's going to be this TI active range and then we can put our close in parentheses and our curly brackets.
So what's this saying?
It's saying that we're going to do a full loop over every controller in the world and it's gonna be
in this variable called controller.
And now there's a couple of things that you might need to know, so one thing is we can query a controller
for whether or not it's a player control without having to cast.
We can actually just do controller arrow.
And then I think I'm going actually needs to include my controller here.
So hash include at the top.
We're going to do a game framework forward slash controlled dot h and now to complete will probably
work.
Yes it has.
So what we can do is obviously we can call game has ended.
That's what my first autocomplete here.
But also we can say is player controller.
Basically it's going to say is this thing in the world to play a controller?
And that will allow us to decide whether or not we should be passing in true or false two game has ended.
So my charge to you is to fill out this for loop by calling game has ended with the correct boolean
parameter.
So we're gonna do this.
So that's basically it should be true.
If the if the controller that we're talking to, the controller currently in the for loop is a player
controller and they're boolean that we have passed in says that the player controller is the winner,
should also be true.
If it is not a play controller and not the player, the player is the winner, basically saying if this
is an A.I. and the A.I. is the winner.
False if the player controller.
But the player isn't the winner and false if not the play controller, but the player is the winner.
You kind of see where this is going.
Hopefully so.
Pause video and have a go at implementing it like this.
You might use if statements.
You might use some other logic to allow you to calculate this boolean pause video and have a go.
Okay, welcome back.
So you could do this a number of ways, one way might be to say if the B is play control a winner and
then we're going to put something in this if statement, we might do a Boole up here to decide that
basically B is player controller.
Which were going to save from the fact that we do a controller.
Arrow, the is plant controller like so and then we might say, okay, well, we want to call Controller
Arrow.
Game has ended.
We're going to pass in the null points for now.
And then we're going to say, well, if it is a player that is the winner and we are a player controller,
then yes, basically go with that value.
So play a controller.
Otherwise, if it's not the player controller, it's going to have lost.
And we can just negate this.
So we can say else that we're going to call the controller.
Game has ended with not is play controller, basically, because we're saying the player is not the
winner.
The A.I. is the winner in this out statement.
And so what we want to do is say that the depends on whether or based the opposite of whether the player
has one, which is to say that the A.I. has won.
So that's one way of doing it for sure.
But there is another and simpler way, which is simply to say, are we the winner?
So B is winner.
And this can simply be to say that whether you are the player controller is equal to be is player winner.
Now, let's think about this a little bit more, and I'll just complete this fully and then we'll talk
about it.
So we're going to say controller hand game has ended is going to be the null pointer with the B is winner
past in here.
Now, why does this statement work?
Well, let's think about the cases.
Right.
So we have a player controller in here and the player is the winner.
Then, yes, we are the winner and they are equal.
True and true.
How about if this is not the player controller and the player is not the winner?
Well, then this is false.
And this over here is also false so that the two of them are equal and the result is a winner.
Is that true?
Yes.
Because if we are the A.I. and the A.I. is the winner, then we should be the winner.
Otherwise, if these two are not equal, i.e. that we've got an A.I. controller but the player is the
winner or we've got the player controller and the A.I. is the winner, then we're going to have a true
and false or a false and true.
These two aren't going to be equal and the Boolean is going to evaluate to false.
So you can see then each of the cases and I've gone through all of the cases there.
This ends up with the right answer.
So we know that this is the right answer.
This is the great thing about booleans is that usually you can evaluate all of the cases because you
can say, okay, well, what are the cases?
It's gonna be true and true.
It's gonna be true.
And false can be false and true.
It's gonna be false and false.
You can evaluate all those cases.
If all of those cases are correct, then you know, you've got a correct boolean statement.
Cool.
So that's how we're going to calculate the B is when I finally we just need to call our end game mode.
At the moment, we're doing a direct call to the player controller.
Game has ended.
And what I actually want to do here is go ahead and call end game.
And we want to pass in false because this is a situation where the player has actually lost and that's
basically what we want to achieve.
Now, one more thing to note here is that there's no points.
We've been Paskin is going to lead us to problems down the road because if the player has actually won,
it's going to try and take away the focus from our player pawn.
So what we want to pass in here is simply that the focus should be on the controller dot get porn.
And that's basically saying that you should put the focus of your own player controller, be it basically
where should your camera be pointing?
It should still be pointing on your porn.
Why is it important that we do this?
And why is there this option here in the first place?
Well, in a lot of games you often or a little off match style games, you might have that if the game
has ended, you want to go and follow the porn.
That was the winner.
So imagine like a fortnight scenario, you often go and follow the person who killed you.
This is the mechanism for doing this.
You basically pass in the pawn of the person who did the killing.
That's what we're doing in our game.
We're going to carry on looking at our porn, whether we'd win or we die.
So that's pretty much it for the lateral.
Let's just compile and see whether it's working.
Let's dive on over into Unreal and hit play.
Let's go and get ourselves killed.
There you go.
Everything's working.
As before, we're still getting that cool to the player controller.
And then we re start.
Great stuff.
So in this lecture, just a recap.
What have we seen?
Well, we've seen how we can iterate over actors in the level in order to do something like calling
a function on each of those actors.
Next lecture, we will be using the T actor range again, this time to calculate whether the player
has one.
See you there.