Hello and welcome to this lecture.
We are going to be making the wind condition work so I can kill all of the enemies in my level and it
will show me this windscreen.
Hurrah!
Let's dive in and see how it's done.
So we'd like it to be possible for our player to actually win this game at the moment.
They cannot.
So how are we going to do that?
Well, you could do it in a number of ways.
One of them would be when porn killed is called and the porn is not the play controller, but an A.I.
We could subtract from a variable which says how many A.I. there are in the world, how many we have
to kill.
And then when that goes down to zero, we can end the game in favor of the player.
However, I think that's a little bit fragile because it requires us to put how many enemies there are
in the world in two places essentially needs to be in the game mode.
But also, it needs to be in the world when you placing the enemy's down and those two can get out of
sync.
And that's going to cause some problems.
So the way I would prefer to do this is to simply say, let's count all of the enemies in the world
every time a pawn is killed.
Let's do a recount, a head count of all of the A.I. and see which ones are still alive.
If any of them are still alive, then we get not going to end the game yet.
The game's not over.
But if they are all dead and the play controller is not, then the player has won.
So in order for us to do this, we need to have a way to query a player controller as to whether it's
dead or not.
Sorry.
I mean, the A.I. controller.
So let's look for our shooter, A.I. controller Dot H.
And what we want to do here is create a new public method that allows us to query whether it is dead
or not.
So we're going to do a pool is basically is dead.
And it's going to be a contest because it shouldn't change what's actually happening in the controller
when it's called.
And we can go ahead and create an implementation.
Now, we should be controlling a porn that can tell us whether or not it is dead.
If we go and have a look at that again, we have a look at the shooter character, which is a porn,
remember?
We have already this is dead concert function there.
So essentially what we want to do is just pass on the request to the shooter.
I control now.
Yes.
One thing is you could say in the KMEL game mode, you could get hold of the controller, get hold of
the porn that the that that's controlling.
Do a cast and then check whether that porn is dead.
However, that's generally not best practice because it means that if suddenly something changes about
how we calculate death and or the A.I. controller is going to control different types of porn, suddenly
we need to go and change the game mode, which doesn't make sense.
So it's better to do this and do the passing on inside the A.I. controllers more robust.
It stops us from fiddling around inside the internals of somebody else's class, which generally means
that we can restrict when things change, we can restrict how many classes we have to go and touch and
update and change, which is always a good thing.
So what we're going to want to do is get the porn and cast the porn to make sure it is a shooter character.
Say, let's do a cast.
It's going to be to a shooter.
Character, and I think we're gonna need to do it.
Hasher include at the top of our eye control to make sure we know about the shooter character like so
and then against the cast during a get porn.
And we're going to want to store this in a variable.
So it's going to be a shooter character pointer called let's call it controlled.
Character.
I can't just call it character, because that's already a variable on the A.I. controller.
And put a semicolon at the end of the line.
And we're going to check whether this is null or not.
So control character is not equal to null pointer.
Then we should be able to query it for its status as to whether it's dead or not.
So we should be able to return that the controlled character.
Is dead.
Basically, we forward on the request to our controlled character.
If that control character is a shooter character, however, notice here we don't have a return statement
in the other case.
We do need to have a return, Sam.
There always needs to be a return.
If the return value isn't void.
So we need to put a return statement out here outside of the statement to catch the case where we haven't
already returned inside the statement.
And here we're just going to say, is this character dead?
Well, yes, essentially.
If it isn't so true, basically it is dead.
If we don't have a pawn, if we're not controlling a pawn, then essentially this A.I. controller is
as good as dead to us.
And that could happen because remember, the pawn detaches from its A.I. controller when it dies.
So we're gonna go back over into the game mode.
And what are we going to want to do here?
Essentially, what we want to do is a for loop over all of the A.I., the shooter A.I..
In world.
And with that full loop, what do we want to do?
We want to see is dead.
Basically and or basically is not dead.
And if any of them are not dead, then we instantly know we don't have to check all of the A.I. at all,
if even just one A.I. reminded Raines alive.
Then the game is not over.
So we can do what's known as an early return, which you've probably seen before, which is going to
just exit from this function without executing any more of the code in it.
So everything after this early return will stop executing the full loop, will stop executing anything
after it will stop executing.
But then we can say if we manage to successfully get through this full loop without it early returning,
meaning that there are no living A.I. in the world, then we need to go ahead and end the game.
Simple as that.
Now, one part of the puzzle that we need to look at here is the end game calls at game has ended on
the player controller.
Let's have a look at how the shooter play controller currently deals with this.
If we go over to it, C.p, what we currently see is that it's currently totally ignoring the B.
Is Wynans currently ignoring whether or not it is the winner?
So what we need to do is say if B is winner.
Then we're going to do something otherwise, else we are going to display our lose screen.
So cut these lines here that are responsible for displaying the loose screen, put that in the out statement,
and we'll restart in both cases anyway.
So currently, the B is winner.
What we going do?
Well, we're just gonna go ahead and probably create a screen as well, which is going to be fairly
straightforward.
We go over to our header file for the shoot to play a controller.
We can duplicate our loose screen class and make a win screen class in here.
We can also go ahead and fight this.
A mini challenge for you.
Maybe go ahead and set it up so that it can do a screen.
Kay, welcome back.
So hopefully you've given that a shot.
We're going to just go in and put windscreen here instead of all of the losers and copy essentially
everything else.
Like so.
Gonna go ahead and compile this, then head on over into the ed and find ourselves the player controller
class, and we should now see there is an empty windscreen class.
And what we're gonna do is go over into the UI and I'm gonna duplicate the loose screen to call the
windscreen.
And you could create yours from scratch if you wanted to, but I'm just going to be using it very similarly,
except I'm going to change out the colour for green.
And make it into a you win instead of a you lose.
Because the restart logic is effectively just going to be the same, some reason it reset my color that
I'm just going to go and set the color screen again.
OK, so that's great.
But we still have this lump of pseudocode over in the KMEL game mode that has not been filled out.
That's because it is your challenge to calculate the win.
Fill out the pseudocode.
Use the T Act to range from below in that class to help you out.
Use the new is dead function that we created on the controller and test it out.
See if your windscreen shows up when you kill all the A.I. in the world.
So just gonna leave it with the pseudocode on your screen for you to have a look at.
Kay, welcome back.
So let's start with the flip.
So I can do for what are we for looping over?
It's not a controller this time.
It's going to be the shooter A.I. control.
So we need to hash include that it's going to be the shooter.
A.I. Controller H.
And that's means that we're going to be looping over a shooter, A.I. controller, star, Star Trek
of Just call the controller for shorts and then we're gonna do a T actor range over again that a shooter
A.I. control.
We need to get these two types to match, then get world.
So we're doing it in this level.
And then we've got the body of the full loop here where we're gonna be asking if it's not dead.
So if not control, the arrow is dead.
So we're saying make sure that we aren't dead.
And if it's not dead, then we'll just go ahead and return to this early return because we know that
the game can't be over just yet.
And otherwise, if we got through the whole full loop without returning, we do need to end the game
because the player must have one killed all of the A.I. in the level.
So in this case, we could do an end game.
True, because the player has won.
And that should notify all of the player controllers and A.I. controllers around.
Cool.
So let's go over and compile that.
First of all, then I'm gonna go over into one real and have a play.
Some reason my editor thinks that I'm in this edit specified color operation, so I'm just gonna close
it down and restart it now that it's reboost.
I'm going to go ahead and hit play and I'm going to get killed.
First of all, yes, I still lose.
That's great.
Now let's see if I can kill this guy before he kills me.
Let's go, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
I lose too quickly.
Let's go and find the gun again and set.
We have that damage from the gun really high for testing purposes.
I'm gonna go and set the damage down.
Back to maybe 20 this time.
So it's still fast, but not as fast.
Go and play and hit this guy a few times.
And what we saw there was that actually I did win because the level restarted.
So if I go and kill this guy again, you see nothing's happening.
It's saying in the message log that create which it was called with a null class.
And the reason for that, if we go over to a BP shooter, plac troller again, you can see we haven't
hooked up our windscreen.
One thing that I forgot to do so you can go and compile, save and play.
And now hopefully if I kill this guy through new doom, I win and I'm going to restart in five seconds.
And I want to show you that the same is true.
If I put more play controllers in the world, it's going to require me to kill both of them.
So let's go and bring in the shooter character over here.
And this is gonna be my second enemy to kill.
So kill this guy.
Boom.
And it hasn't won.
Then I go over to the second guy.
Boom.
And now I have one because I've killed all of the A.I. and we didn't have to go and change any variables
to do that because our for loop counts.
All of the living a lie.
Every time.
From scratch.
So currently we're now living in quite a silent world.
So in the next lecture, I want to start looking a little bit at how we can do some audio.
I'll see there.