Hello everybody and welcome to introducing input binding.
We are going to look into settings project settings engine input.
We're going to look at how action mappings are used for on off actions and access mappings are used
for analog value so consider a driving simulator you might have a steering wheel or a flight simulator
you might have a joystick.
Anything that's not on and off and has analog inputs and of course a game controller with its two analog
sticks would be another example of that.
Now of course you can give players a way of remapping that's quite common in games you're not gonna
cover that in this particular section though you can bind many keys to the same action and we will go
over how to call a function on a key press all when the key is released.
She can be really useful when we're grabbing something because we don't necessarily want to hold onto
it for ever.
We might want to hold down a key to pick it up and then when we release that key we will drop it.
In this lecture we are going to map a key to do a certain action.
In this case it's going to be to call a function and that function at the end of this lecture will be
showing a grabber press down in the log and then we'll do a final bit of implementation over the next
couple of lectures so we can start picking our objects up.
Okay.
So the input component here is a little bit hidden away.
So when we press play what we used to be able to do is inspect the default porn and see it as parts
of the components that would appear at runtime.
But now all actors have an input component.
It's just built in as part of that class.
So we don't need to worry about attaching anything here or making sure that something has it's there
by default.
So now we know that's going to be there by default.
Let's go into our project settings and go to input which is down here under engine.
Scroll down a little you'll find inputs.
So a new window for us to explore.
So we have action mappings here they are on and off switches.
So like a button press and then we have here our axes mapping.
And that's the analog sticks.
And we were talking about earlier or steering wheel throttle and you think that's not just on or off.
Okay.
So we want to create our own action is not going to be an analog one so we can use the action mappings
we're going to hit the plus button and we come up with new action mapping that's the name.
That's not a very good name.
It's not very descriptive.
We're going to call it grab instead.
Now you can select many keys here but in this particular case look at that we've got tons of options
there and different settings as well.
And you can see here if you're programming a game for multiple platforms you have the code in one for
the X Box controller one for the P.S. For controller what happens if a user is using their mouse and
keyboard again that's going to be a different set of inputs and that's the basis of why you can have
many mappings all linking to the same thing.
So I'm going to search by typing in the letter E and well can we do keyboard and then e so keyboard
and E.
No.
It looks like we're going to have to scroll down here and there we go.
E is on its own just there.
So I'm going to use the E key in order to pick up and let go.
And of course we can add another key as well so we can click the plus button again look you can have
more than one thing here and let's use the mouse this time I'm just going to use the dropdown mouse
it's right there in front of me.
Now let's bind it also to the right mouse button so we can either grab something by using the e key
on the keyboard or using our right mouse button and of course if you have a controller plugged into
a computer why don't you try selecting one of the options on your controller.
So we've now defined that the right mouse button then the key are both mapped to this action here.
This grab and that has to be exactly the same over in our code and this is the sorts of things that
the player can have control over if you give them access in a menu system for instance.
Now we don't have to click save or anything.
Our binding is now set up and now we can go over to our code as well.
Okay.
So in begin play we have our physics handle where we go and get the owner and then find the component
by class.
Now the input component happens to be hidden so we can see it there.
But what I'd like you to do now is create a similar set up to this.
Probably don't need the else but you can just for your practice if you like and that will also confirm
that we've actually found this as well so perhaps because it's invisible it would be a good idea here
to just logout that we found an input component supports video now and go ahead and create a new variable
called input component lock it up using a similar set up to this and then underneath if you found the
input component then say we found it otherwise so that it doesn't exist now it should exist on all actors
so that won't be an issue but just practice the code for the moment pause video now and give that a
go.
Okay everybody Welcome back.
So let's go ahead here and start something called input component.
And we're going to set it equal to get owner remember we're going back up the hierarchy that is going
to be a pointer so we use the arrow operator and we've going to find the component by class and we don't
need anything else in the end there.
So what are we going to look for here.
So let's use fuzzy search.
And then if we can't find it with that we can use the documents instead.
So it's going to be a you input component.
There we go.
That's exactly what we're looking for.
Now we've got a red squiggle here it's undefined.
That's absolutely fine.
Let's go ahead into our header file itself and we're going to also need to include a similar setup as
we had here.
So this is going to be our new input component.
Look at that.
It's a pointer we're going to call it inputs component.
And we're also going to set it to a normal pointer to protect ourselves as well okay so that's that's
all sorted and that will eventually stop having its red squiggles.
Okay now we need to protect ourselves here by saying if input component and what are we going to say
here in the input component.
Well first of all let's test that it actually does exists.
So we're going to do a log log temp let's set it as a warning.
And what should we say.
Let's just say.
Input component found.
Okay.
And we need to reference something here what are we going for.
Well we're going to get owner because that is a pointer we use the arrow operator and we can get its
name.
There we go.
Remember our parentheses on the end.
We need a semicolon right on the very end and we need an asterisk just there next to get owner Whoops
I've just reviewed this and realized that I was going to say input component found on and then a format
specified percentage s some fortunately my owner get name doesn't do anything in this particular case
but if you wanted to print out to the log the actor that the input component is found on that's what
you would need to do.
Okay now we don't have an L statement yet.
So let's pop that in as well so else.
Well it's really this except we would say that we cannot find one to copy that.
So the same again.
And I'm going to say that input component missing like so with three S's that will be very distinct.
Okay.
So that should be all fine.
Let's go ahead save our work go over into real and first compile and then we'll play and what we should
see down in the log is that we've got an input component.
Would just confirm it's working.
Let's press play.
Warning.
Input component found.
Excellent.
So it does exist even though we can't see it.
Okay.
Let's roll back slightly and talk about what else we can do here.
So if input component which is going to be true all the time anyway so let's just comment that out for
the moment if input component.
Well so we're going to type in input component.
So we've got our input component we know.
And if we hover over it it come up as a pointer so we can use our arrow operator to access the members.
Now we need to bind an action that's what we want to do and then we open up some parentheses and this
is going to be a string in here and the name has to be exactly the same as that which we gave it over
in the projects settings under the inputs when we set up that new action we can see here that the next
thing we need is an input event or key events here.
It's in a numerator.
So we could do a bit of fuzzy search here or we could go to the docs and look everything up I know is
an input event and here we go.
This is quite good.
So I see is short for input events.
Then we've got the Axis double click.
That's quite useful Max pressed and released.
So we're talking about if we press a key down.
Excellent.
What's next.
The object so we can use the keyword here.
This.
Now this is the first time that we've used this.
And what this means is that it is a pointer to this object.
That is the instance of the class that is executing this code not to be confused with the reference
to the actual class itself.
Now the final one here and then we look at that signature is a bit of a mess and very confusing and
we're not going to delve into and potentially quite confusing.
So we're not going to delve deep into this syntax right now.
But basically what we need is an address to a function that we haven't written yet.
So we're going to write this in there grab a file that's absolutely fine.
But first of all we're going to have to point to it.
So we need the address off with the ampersand and then we need to fully qualify where we're going so
we're going to be doing it.
You grabber over actually came up then as I was typing.
So the you grab.
That's fine.
And then the scope operator followed by a function that doesn't exist yet which should be grab.
Okay.
So is complaining at the moment that grab doesn't exist.
So let's go ahead and create it.
Now let's go over to our header file okay so we can pop this in our private section.
It's not going to return anything so it can be void.
And we're going to call it grab and it's a method.
Okay.
So that's all we need for the moment in the header file.
If we go back over to the implementation I think here is going to be a fine place to put it for the
moment.
Again it needs to be fully qualified as a void you grab a along came on for the scope operator and it's
just grab.
And then finally we'll put our code in here.
So what will happen here is when this key is pressed wherever we've decided to map it to in this case
e and the right mouse button it will call this particular function.
So we've mapped user inputs to a function code.
So without diving into great detail at the moment let's just make sure all of this works by a quick
log out so you log as has we've done a few times before and then log temp we'll just do a warning here
and then we will use our text macros we always to test keep typing test.
Okay.
Text macro and we can say grab a press or something along those lines.
And then when we go ahead and look in the log we should find that both the E key and the right mouse
button trigger this function call.
We should just log something.
In this case grab a press to a log.
Let's save.
I always gets a little concerned you know when I see red squiggles but it is important to know that
your idea can send you on wild goose chases if you start chasing red squiggles all the time.
Now if I have happened to have made a mistake somewhere the compiler will tell me in a moment.
So let's go ahead and compile our code.
The compiler is complete.
Let's go ahead and press play.
So when we move around our scene you can see already I hit the right mouse button there.
That's the right mouse button.
And this is the E key.
Now of course the key is also bound to going up you see this is what I wanted to show you here and why
are maps to the EAC his Q and E go up and down.
So you do have to watch out what you've mapped that to.
So I think in this particular case what we can do is remove that binding.
And then I think we'd done for this video.
So I'm going to just escape out of play go to a project settings and where we have it bound here we
can just click the little cross at the end so I'm just going to bind it to the right mouse button.
We don't need to do anything only to save anything there.
We've now sorted that out.
Okay.
That's it for this lecture.
And I'll see you guys in the next one.