Hello, welcome, in this lecture, we are going to be making sounds, so we'll have a muzzle sound
and we'll have an impact sound.
Let's dive in and see how we're gonna do that in the process.
We gonna learn how we can attach sounds to other components so they move with them, such as the muzzle.
So now that we've got a nice and tidy pull trigger function, it's quite clear where we want to be making
sound effects.
Now, in my game, the only real sound effects I want are on the muzzle flash and on base of the impact.
So the places where we're already spawning emitters, I just want to add sound to that.
Now, that's relatively straightforward.
We've done some similar things in the past with the game play static's.
You can do a play sound at location, which is going to play that sound unattached to any object.
So it won't be moving around, it'll just stay fixed in that location until it's finished.
However, we also wants to be able to play an attached sound in the same way as we're playing an attached
emitter up at the top.
And that's that's fairly straightforward.
What we're going to look for, though, is, first of all, we're passing in this type and let's try
to understand a little bit better.
So we've got the play sound at location, which takes in the world context, but it also takes in this
you sound base.
Now, why is it a sound base and not just a sound wave?
Because if we go over into one real go into our asset packs, shooter game sounds, weapon, assault
rifle and mono, you're going to see that if we hover over any of these clips, then the type here is
sound wave.
And that actually corresponds to a type in unreeled called You Sound Wave.
And if you go and have a look at that sound wave class, you can see that it inherits from you sound
base.
So what is sound bass?
What else inherits from it?
Well, something called an audio cue or sound cue, which you're gonna be using in the next lecture,
which allows us to do more complicated things with sound waves such as randomise them than modulate
their pitch.
So we're not interested in those just yet, but just know that these functions will work just as well,
whether we're passing in a single soundwave or a collection of sound waves gathered together in a sound
cue.
And that's by virtue of the fact that they take in a sound base which encompasses both of those types.
So what's useful is if we go and look through our game, play statics for the use of sound bass, what
else can we play a sound with?
Well, here there's a Sporn sound at location, a slightly different variation on the previous function
you can see here.
It returns the audio component that it spawned.
We're not interested in that one, though.
Well, we are interested in is our Sporn sound attached?
Now, this takes in our sound and then it also takes in a component that we want to attach it to, as
well as an optional attach point.
If we're dealing with a skeletal mesh.
So that's the one we're going to want to use.
So I'm going to go over into a gun, see?
And in order to call it, we're going to need a sound to call it with.
So we're going to add that to our configuration in the header file, where I'm going to add ourselves
a new property and I'm going to add it just under our muzzle flash called you sound bass is going to
be the type star and it's going to be the muzzle sound like so that we can then configure in the editor.
And I'm gonna go over to the gun c.p and we're going to spawn.
So as you gain play static's again and we're going to call spawn sound attached and we're going to pass
in this time set of the muzzle flash, the muzzle sound.
Then we've got to attach it to a mesh and to a socket.
Actually for that I'm just gonna copy both the mesh and the socket from above because we want to be
doing it to exactly the same location.
Essentially having the sound come out at the end of the barrel of our gun.
And if go ahead and compile, we should be able to go over to our rifle, BP and find a new property.
Sure enough, when the compile finished, the muzzle sound property popped up here and we can select
from the dropdown.
One of the Soundwave files, we don't currently have any sound cues or we do.
They come from the engine, but we don't want any of those.
We're just gonna go with the assault rifle shot.
And if we go and play, you can see that we are getting the correct sound effects when firing the rifle.
It's now time for your challenge to play the sound at location.
That is the function you've probably used before to play an impact sound of which we have a few in here.
When I did my drop down, you could see those the assault rifle shots.
But if we also look for assault rifle, we can see that they are these impact concrete sounds as well.
So you might want to choose one of those who are going to play an impact sound and use the L.A. sound
at location from gameplay static's hook it up and test it out to see that you're getting both of those
sounds in your world.
Pause a video and have a go.
Kay, welcome back.
So let's give this a shot.
First things first, that s the configuration.
So I'm gonna mostly copy the configuration from the muzzle sound.
Put it underneath the impact effect, and I'm going to call it the impact sound.
Then what we're gonna do is just set it off.
Compiling this.
We made a change to our head of file and I wants it to be quick.
Then we're gonna go down to where we're spawning our emitter at a location.
We're gonna do a new game, play Static's Kolon, Kolon, and we're going to be doing a instead of Sporn.
Sound attached is gonna be a play sound at location.
We're going to have to give it a world context.
I'm to do a get weld.
Then we're gonna give it the sound that we want it to play, which is gonna be the impact sound.
And then we need to give it a location to play the sound, which is gonna be the same as the location
for doing our particle effect and direction.
Doesn't matter in this case because our sound is going to be the same in all directions.
But some echo on the end of that line and go and compile it and head over to the BP rifle where we now
have the new configuration variable for the impact sound.
As I said, there's gonna be something with impact concrete in it.
So I'm gonna go and select number one from that.
Go ahead and play and try this out.
And as you just heard there, we were getting an impact sound when we were hitting something.
And if we weren't hitting anything but just shooting, all you were hearing was the rifle muzzle sound.
So that's it for this lecture.
We've seen how we can spawn a sound attached to an object.
The next lecture, we're gonna be looking at how we can randomize those sounds so they aren't always
exactly the same every time they played.
See, they're.