Hello and welcome.
We are going to be randomising our sounds in this lecture.
You can hear the soundscape is far less boring than it was in the last lecture.
We're going to be using each built into one real cold sound cues that allow us to do this.
Let's dive in and see what they are.
So our sounds are a bit monotonic.
As it stands and I have alluded to the fact that there's something called a sound cue which allows us
to fix this in Unreal.
It's a new type of asset.
So let's see how to create it.
First of all, I want to create a new folder for the sound cues for both of our shot and that impact.
So this fall is going to be called SFX for sound effects.
And we're going to go into there right click go to the sounds menu and then select the sound cue in
here.
Now, the naming convention here that we start with an a underscore, as we would with a sound wave.
Then I'm going to give it a useful name, such as the rifle shot and then underscore capital C Q.
So it's saying that it's an audio asset and it's specifically a sound cue at the end.
Now we can go ahead and open this asset and you can see we get this fun little blueprint editor with
a node editor in the middle, just a bit like the material editor, the animation editor, in that it
has this output pin ready for us to plug stuff into.
And the way we could start plugging something in is if we write clicked and looked for wave.
You can see there is a wave player node, select the wave, play a note and get to the details painted
on the left.
I could select one of the sound wave files to play and then I can pull out of its output pen and plug
it into our output node.
And essentially I can use the play buttons at the top of the queue to preview what this cue is gonna
sound like, but unimpressive.
Li is just going to play that one clip.
Obviously this is not why we put a sound cue in place.
Well, we really want to be able to do is to do other cool stuff.
And he right click.
You can see there's a whole load of nodes that we could choose from.
There's attenuation branching concatenation so we can do all sorts of stuff, such as play different
sounds depending on the material of what's being impacted.
We can add some looping.
We can do Crossfade and so on and so forth.
But what I'm really interested in here, some randomisation.
So there is a random node here where you can add as many pins as you like.
And what it's going to do is it's going to switch between its inputs and give one of them out randomly
as its output has a few properties that you might be interested here in the details, Pane.
The most interesting one for me was the randomise without replacement.
And this is basically saying that the type of random it is going to use won't cause you to replay anything
until you've played all of the clips on the left hand side.
It's basically a random shuffle.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna output an assault rifle, shot one in to the random node and then
output that in to the global output here.
And I'm also going to copy and paste that assault rifle, shot one and do a shot, too, and put that
into the random note as well.
And I'm just going to delete the extra inputs that we had here.
And now you can hit the play cue and you can see how it's basically just switching between these random
outputs because of this randomize without replacement.
We uncheck that.
Then you're going to see that occasionally it will play the same clip two times in a row.
And that's why often times is useful to have that randomise without replacement so that we don't hear
the repetition in our game.
Okay.
So that's cool.
What other interesting nodes do we have here to help us have a more random sounding effect?
Well, one of them is the modulator node.
And if you select that, the details should give you a bit of a hint as to what's going on here.
It's got a min and max pitch and a M. Max volume.
And as you might guess, the whole purpose of this much lighter note, if we just plug it in to one
of our clips and to the output, is that it's going to randomize the volume and the pitch.
Let's try it out.
Now, the effect is not very noticeable there because we don't have very big ranges.
So I'm going to go between half volume and two times volume and see if we can hear that.
Now, hopefully you're able to hear the variations there.
Let's also try some bigger variations in pitch, two times pitch and half pitch.
And let's just reset the volume.
So hopefully you're able to hear the difference there in the Min and Max pitch as well.
So then what we can do is we can put these two nodes one into another and we're then going to get random
clips and additional modulation on top of that.
Now, we have a lot more clips here than just these assault rifles shot one and two.
So I want to get bring all of these in.
But it can be a bit tedious to duplicate and select the clips.
So here's a little shortcut for you.
We go over to our content folder.
Go down into the asset packs, shoot game sounds and then the weapon assault rifle, Monzo.
You can see we've got the clips that we want here.
So I'm going to select from shot one to shot six.
Then I'm gonna go over to my Q editor and I'm gonna right.
Click in there and you can see there's this from Selected Option which allows us to bring in multiple
clips in it to various nodes that take multiple clips.
And the one we're interested in is the random node.
And if you select that, then you get.
Six different wave players all inputting in to a random note so we can now delete the other random note
we had manually created and we can use this new random note instead.
And that's sounding much better now.
I just want to tweak the settings here for our pitch.
I don't think we want such a big variation in pitch.
It's going to reset those down to the defaults.
I do want a slight more variation in volume, though, so I'm going to go four point seven to one point
three and then let's go ahead and play that.
I think that's a good variation and definitely doesn't sound boring anymore.
I'd like you now as a challenge to apply the same process to the impact sound effect.
So create a sound cue, add randomization, add a modulator, and then play around with the volumes
and the values, rather, to see what works best for the impact sound.
Pause video and have a go.
Okay.
Welcome back.
Let's give this a shot.
So we're going to go over to our content SFX right click and we're going to try and create a new sound
asset.
And it's a sound cue.
So a underscore.
We're gonna call it reifel impact and then underscore cue.
Let's go ahead and open that one up.
And we essentially want to do the same thing here.
So first of all, I'm going to add in a modulator, an output that's the output note.
Then we're going to go over to our sandbox again, up to the root content asset packs, shooter game
sounds, weapon mono and then on gainst select from all of the impact sound effects, there should be
six of them and then gonna go over to the impact cue.
Right, click and add in the random node and output that random node into the modulator.
And then from my playing around I found that the modulator works better here to have a bigger pitch
difference because something plinking off concrete's or whatever substance that is could make various
sounds depending on what angle it's hitting it at.
So I'm gonna go between point five and two with less of a volume variation here.
Let's go ahead and try playing this cue.
Okay.
So I think that sounds good with a good amount of variation.
Now, all that's left to be seen is if we can put this into our rifle.
And you may have already tried doing this.
We can just go over to where we have our sound effects in the BP rifle and change out the wave that
we were using for a sound cue so we can swap it out for the rifle impact or shot.
Q On this a muzzle sound, then the impact sound we're going to switch out for let's go and find it
should just be something called impact.
They get rifle impact.
Q We can go ahead and play that now and we can hear a good amount of variation in the sound that was
going on there.
That the different muzzle flashes sounded different and the impact sounds sounded different.
Now if you're playing this with headphones, you will notice that it all sounds a little bit flat,
like there isn't a sense of space.
That's what we're going to be dealing with in the next lecture.
So in this lecture, what we have done is we've over viewed what a sound cue is and how it can allow
us to do lots of cool stuff with sound, including adding randomization and making sounds less boring.
I'll see you in the next lecture.