Hello everybody and welcome back.
It's time for your end of section challenge to build what I showed you at the very beginning of course
you don't have to follow along exactly with what I've done make the level your own and have a lot of
fun.
So you're going to create a new level go up to new file do new level and give it a name and then you
can go to your levels folder and go backwards and forwards between the one you've got and your new one.
Now let's make something a bit more than just a rooms with a couple of things in it that we can move
essentially or we have at the moment is a tech demo and that's not as inspiring as you could have otherwise.
Now I would recommend getting some assets from the assets that you don't have to do that you could use
BSP and build up a simple game that you're working on from there.
It's entirely up to you how you approach this but what I would like you to do is just combine all of
the knowledge that you've learned so far.
Now I'm going to go onto the unreal asset store and use the medieval dungeon pack.
Now if you want to know how to do that then watch the first part of the challenge solution.
But if you already know how to do that then you can plow forward and get one of those asset packs.
Now this one is now this one is free which is great because we can just go ahead and use it.
And of course this will test your level design skills even though we've not done any formal training
on it.
Just make something that's simple and have fun.
I mean my level itself is quite big.
So if you remember right at the very beginning making something like that's probably going to take you
between two and five hours to do so I wouldn't recommend going over the top make sure it's small enough
that you can you feel confident that you can get it done in maybe a couple of hours including anything
extra that you want to do.
So an example there might be that you instead of having the doors open on a hinge you might want to
have them lift up and down or slide.
It's entirely up to you but have fun.
And then finally I want you to show off your creations in the discussions.
I want to see what you guys end up making Paul's video now and give us a go okay.
Everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead and start building our level Okay so one word of warning here.
If you're on Linux I'm afraid you're going to have to go and grab or a friend or grab a Mac or P.C.
in order to do this.
Parts of it you cannot access the marketplace on Linux.
Currently there are some third party things that you can use but I'm not going to show you through that
in the course because they've they've turns out to be pretty unstable.
So under the Unreal Engine side tablets go to the market place in the marketplace.
There are quite a few different options available to you so you might want to go ahead and pick something
different.
Now I'm going to search under the free category.
See here free and providing you've signed it of course you can pick any of these things that are in
here for free.
Now what I'm looking for specifically my search for products and go for dungeon I start typing is bound
to find it any way.
There we go.
So I've not got the free tab enable it's quite simple to do over here on the right hand side on filter
on the max price.
I'm going to select free.
And there we go there's the medieval dungeon.
You can see I've already got it.
If you go ahead and you want to follow along with the kit I've got you can see this is pretty awesome
for creating something.
What you can then do is go ahead and add it to your project so you can click that dropdown and select
the projects that you want.
Now I've already popped into my project so I won't be doing that and I'm basically going to jump into
a speed run now of me building the level as it took just over three hours in total to do and that would
be a very long video to watch through.
Okay so I'll play that now and I'll see you all again soon.
Okay.
So here's my final level.
It's much in the same spirit as the original one.
Everything's a little bit larger.
So we've got the God rays coming through there some nice highlighting from the sun in the background
as well I really like the deep orange I've picked her.
Now I did see if I could jump over the gates and it turns out I can.
So this is one of the great things about play testing you don't necessarily find out these things unless
you start mucking about.
But I know how to win the game so go and grab the dark puppet next to here and then I can steal the
golden statue.
Of course the moment I remove it the doors shots in hats I managed to get the statue out but not me.
So replacing the gargoyle exactly the same stuff that we worked with in the course itself.
And then the door opens again and we can run off.
Goodbye everybody.
It's time to go.
Excellent.
So I had lots of fun putting that together and I'm really looking forward to seeing yours.
So please share your work over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.