Hello and welcome this lecture.
We are going to be filling out Animation's state machine so that there are more states here allowing
us to have a animation that jumps us into that initial jump state.
As you can see, there's a little bit more spring to my jump.
And we are going to learn about such things as automatic transitions and how to nest one state machine
within another, which is what we're going to do for our death animation.
Now, let's dive in and see how it works.
So as promised in the last lecture, we're going to hook up our is airborne variable to the gameplay.
Now, the way we're going to do this is to get from the poor or particularly from at a shoot a character.
We want to find out essentially whether the character is airborne.
And I find that the only way you can do this is essentially through the character movement component.
So let me show you what I mean.
If we go to our cast node that is casting to the shooter character, then we can drag off of this.
In fact, what we can do is a more general cast in this particular instance because we don't need the
specific information associated with is dead.
So what I'm going to do here is we'll take this pin the pawn owner, and we're going to do a cast to
character.
In this case, because all we need to know is that this is a character instance.
Then we're gonna add a new execution pin up at the sequence node, drag that down to our cast character.
And then from the character will drag off of its character PIN.
And we're going to look for basically something along the line of airborne.
Nothing there.
Maybe jump seems to be more interesting saying is jump providing force can jump, jump all that sort
stuff.
We've got something there, but that's not quite it.
How about if we look for falling?
There you go.
We've got an is falling.
And if you click that, you can see that it automatically gets hold of the character movement component
from that character to see whether we are falling or not.
Then what we can do is we can pass that in to set the value of is airborne.
And obviously we're only going to be setting this if our cast to character succeeds.
So let's hook in that execution pin right there and go ahead and compile that.
Obviously, it's not going to change the preview.
So we've got to go and try and play it.
So let's play.
We jump.
And you can see we've got this falling variable instantly being true.
And that is working quite nicely, actually.
We're able to jump and land and jump and land and kill our enemies, obviously.
So now I'd like to add a little bit more complication to Adam Graff.
So in The Locomotion State machine at the moment, we've got two states here.
But what I'd really like to do is to play a jumping animation, then an animation where we're airborne
and then a landing animation when we hit the ground.
To do that, we need some more states in our state machine.
So let's go ahead.
I'm going to do one of the set of states and you can do the final one.
So the first one is going to be at Jumping State.
And that is going to play an animation that gets us off the ground to say, let's go into the jumping
states and to the output animation pose, we're going to link a new animation.
We'll have a jump.
We're looking for the ones suffixed with combat's.
So we're going to look for jump start combat.
There you go.
And that's what we want.
Then we're going to go back to our locomotion state machine.
And we want to hook up some transitions.
So we're gonna transition from grounded to jumping.
That's going to happen if we're airborne.
So put in the air is airborne in there.
And Fusun is no way that I could see of changing the transition.
So we're just going to have to delete the old transitions here.
In both cases, then we're going to need to transition from jumping to is airborne.
But we don't have a variable or state for that.
So when is it that we're going to transition from jumping to is airborne?
Well, we want to do it when the jumping animation has finished.
When we've finished jumping.
If you go and have a look at the jumping animation, you can see that it involves him lifting his feet
off the ground like this.
And so we want to basically transition into our apex animation when it's finished.
Fortuny there's an option for that in the transitions.
If you select the transition rather than going into it, you could look at its details, pain.
And there's one option here.
Which I like, spanned out, says automatic rule based on sequence player in state.
If you check that, basically what is going to do is when we've nearly finished jumping, it's going
to start transitioning into the next animation.
And you can actually control when that transition is and how long that Crossfade is here in the BLENDE
settings.
You can see the duration of the BLENDE is about point two.
But seeing as these two transitioning into each other particularly well, I'm going to make that nought
point nought ones.
I'm going to make a really short transition.
So let's see what that looks like.
So we're going to go into is airborne at play?
Is that jumping animation and then goes straight into the airborne state, wants the animation is finished.
Let's try that one more time.
We can't try it one more time.
That is the problem because we've got no transition out of the airborne state back to grounded.
And that is indeed going to be your challenge.
So what you gonna do is add a landing state, which is going to play a landing animation.
So at the new stay at the animation that's most appropriate for landing, in your opinion, you might
want to look for things with the jump prefix and the combat suffix.
Then you're going to transition from airborne on a boolean into this landing state and then from that
landing state, you're going to transition to grounded when the landing animation has finished.
Play it, play around, see how it feels.
Does it feel good?
Does it look right?
And you may want to look at tweaking those transition times to see if that makes things feel better.
Pause a video and a half ago playing around with astate machine.
OK.
Welcome back.
So let's give this a shot.
We're going to add a new state in here.
It's going to be called landing.
And in this landing state, we go in.
We need an animation for it.
I'm going to search for jump.
And what we want is jump.
Land combat like so.
And then we can get back up to our locomotion state machine.
We need to transition from airborne to landing.
Double click on that.
And this needs to be the not in and not airborne basically.
So not node than the is airborne past into that.
So that's our transition condition.
So when we are at the apex, once the knot is airborne, is unchecked.
Then we go into that landing state.
Then from our landing state, we want transition to grounded when finished.
So if we click on the transition and check the automatic rule checkbox, it's going to do that when
it's finished.
So let's try that out.
We're going to go into his airborn it place jumping.
It goes into airborne and then uncheck it.
It goes to landing and back out.
Let's do that again.
Seems pretty good.
Okay, so what we're going to do now is try playing it, jumping around and landing.
Okay, this is feeling quite good.
There's a little bit of lag when I'm landing.
Between me landing and the running animation being played.
So I'm going to click on the transition from landing to ground it and have a look at our bland blend
settings.
Now we've got this duration of point one.
That's how long it's taking us to do the transition and what's going on.
So in our landing combat animation, how long is that landing combat animation?
If I pause it, scroll along here.
You can see that is about nought point two.
So it's actually taking the whole of that time and transitioning during that time in to our grounded
locomotion.
So that's kind of what we want, because as soon as we've landed on the ground, as soon as the gameplay
is telling us, we've landed on the ground.
We want to start showing some foot movement because otherwise it's going to look a little bit weird.
So we want that transition to actually start happening as soon as possible, which is why we're playing
very little of the landing animation and transitioning into the grounded one as much as quickly as possible.
The only thing that we can really tweak here is the transition mode, which kind of dictates the shape
of that curve, the shape of how much landing versus grounded we have over time.
And you can test out various of these options, see which ones feel best for you.
For me, it's the exponential out that feels best because that shows as much grounded as possible as
early as possible.
But without it feeling jarring.
So if we now do is airborne and then go back to ground, you can see that it feels like it's going into
grounded pretty quickly, which is what we want.
So I'm going to go ahead and hit play and see if that feels better.
Yeah, it feels a bit more responsive to me hitting the ground, which is exactly what I want.
Now, in practice, if you had more animations here to work with, what you might want to do with the
landed state is to have a blend space there and have a recovery animation.
So depending how hard you hit the ground, you might hit you might play a recovery animation, which
is blended depending on which direction you're moving in.
So he would land with a hefty thud, but kind of stagger over to the left, for example.
Now, that is not something that we're going to cover here.
But just because we don't have the animation, but in theory, that's what you might do.
So now one final kind of mini challenge for you is that we've currently got this BLENDE poses by Boole
going on for our death animation.
This could be done with a new state machine for death.
See if you could try and refactor this Annam graph so that it works with a state machine for death.
Instead of this, BLENDE poses by Bool Kaso.
Hopefully you took me up on that challenge.
What we're going to do is we're going to right click do a new state machine, entirely new.
We're going to rename the state machine to death or something similar like.
So then I'm going to go into that state machine and we're gonna add two states.
One is going to be the state alive and the other state is going to be dead.
OK.
And then we're going to add some transitions.
So transition from alive to dead.
That is going to happen if we double click.
It's going to happen.
When is dead is true.
Like so.
And then we want a maybe we want a transition back to alive, and we can just have that for testing
purposes, at least that's going to have a not boolean and it's going to have is dead.
So basically is not dead.
We're gonna go back the other way.
We want to default to being in their lives state.
That makes sense.
And then we need some animations to play.
So for dead.
We've already got that death animation.
So I'm gonna go in back up to the Annam graph to cut that out.
Go back into the dead state and paste that death animation in here.
Then in our live state, what do we want to play there?
Well, actually, we want to play everything else.
We want to play the aim offsets.
We want to play The Locomotion.
So I'm gonna cut all of that.
And this is where it gets interesting.
Now we've got a state machine running within a state machine, which is entirely possible.
So we can then pipe in this aim, offset into our output for the alive state and go back up to Adam
Grauwe entirely.
Remove all the nodes here and just pipe our death state machine into our output.
And this works because we've got two top level states.
Basically, we're saying they're either alive or dead.
Your daddy just play a death animation.
If you're alive, however, you do this aim offset and you do your locomotion state machine, which
in turn has its own set of states, says layering state machine on top of state machine.
Hopefully see how that can be really powerful so we can do now is dead, which overrides everything
else that's running.
It's no longer running the locomotion state machine because we're just playing at death animation fi
undying as we go back to running the animation for alive.
But we can replay our death crucially, which previously we couldn't do.
And that's because when you leave a state in an animation state machine, it resets the animation within
it.
It resets it to the beginning.
So that's a really useful feature here for death.
So to recap, what we've learned about in this lecture is how to make more complex state machines and
nesse state machines within each other.
And we've seen about automatic transitions and how they can help us make a sequence of transitions happen
more easily.
And I'll see in the next lecture.