Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to have a look at random and the UAE for docs.
Now before we even get into this lecture what I'd like you to do is have a look at random yourself.
See if you can get to the E4 docs and find out which function you would use to give us a random number
only spend about 30 seconds to a minute on it and use your google fu okay.
Welcome back.
Let's carry on.
Well why would we have a look at the E4 docs I hear you call.
Well we will be using Rand range and it rather than just me telling you that I want to take a closer
look at how you might go ahead and find out that thing for yourself whether or not you want to work
out how to do random or something else.
Now one of the reasons why you want to refer to the use for docs rather than just searching for stuff
online with C++ is you may find that's what you find does work in the contacts that we're currently
doing.
But if you were to compile game for a different system it may fail because we didn't use the Unreal
Engine for specific random range function.
But why this one.
And how would you know other two big questions.
Let's go ahead and do a basically a search online and see what we come up and give you a bit of guidance
how you might find this yourself.
Okay everybody so we're over on a search engine here.
You can choose a different one if you don't like Google.
That's absolutely fine.
So how would we go ahead and search for random.
Well I would first of all start off with what we want so random you E4 and then look the second search
there and obviously this is going to be somewhat skewed because I've also been doing searches for it
but I could go people as well as C++ it will come up with a similar results and we get a series of options
and of course Google is a great way of finding out how things work.
But specifically there are two here.
There's the rand range and Rand range and it's brilliant it comes up straight away.
That's given us an insight in that's probably what we need to use when it comes to being random within
unreal.
So let's just click on the top on here and see what we get.
So we end up with the rand range function itself.
What it can take in as its parameters so it can take in integers of both 32 and fourth 64 bits and floats
as well so it's pretty simple and we can click on Rand range here and it will take us to.
Here we go the names but the structure that contains all the math help her functions of which Rand range
is one of.
Now this is important because as if you cast your mind back to when we were doing triple X when we reached
into the standard namespace to do C out we needed to make sure we went FTD colon colon C out otherwise
we couldn't use it the same is true here we're gonna have to go f math colon colon Rand range and if
our Entebbe sense is working it should enable us to do that quite well but even better in this itself
it has the include file.
Now one thing to mention here is since I think it was about four point fifteen or thereabouts anyway
unreal version four point fifteen it switched over so that you now have to include what you use.
So before this you may have been able to use Rand range without having to include the math young real
math utility header file there.
So that's something that we're going to have to include in our code.
And one final thing that we should look at here is the remarks themselves.
So let's just open that back up returns a Random number greater than or equal to the minimum and less
than or equal to the max.
The reason why I'm bringing this up is some functions may not operate like this.
It may not include the minimum or may not include the maximum.
It might just be less than the maximum.
Let's see how we can go ahead and implement run range over in this code.
OK.
So are over it in our implementation.
I'm going to add those two lines that I seem to keep deleting perhaps I should just leave a gap there.
Now ordinarily we can't just call up brand range as we've mentioned before.
What we'd have to do is do f math and then colon colon for the namespace and then ran Grange.
Now the reason why this is appearing is because at some point in another header file it's been included.
So let's go to the ball Cal cartridge header.
I'm holding down control whilst clicking on these so one of these other included headers includes the
necessary header files so let's go have a look at what that was.
It was the math anew unreal utility header file.
So let's see if we can find that and see where it's being used because this is a useful things go for
I think it's going to be in the core minimal so we got a hold down control and click on that and I'm
going to search for that up here.
So here we go.
So in the core minimal that's been included from the very beginning.
This also includes our unreal math utility header file.
The one thing we need to be aware of is that's not always is something like that going to be included.
So if you wanted to use Rand range in your own projects you may not have everything all the prerequisites
there.
You would have to hash include the unreal math utility like so I shall comment that's out and leave
it there for reference.
So f math Rand Grange and then we would need to give it something.
So we would give its size zero and 10 as an example and then our semicolon on the end.
Now at the moment we're not doing anything without generating a random number and they're not doing
anything with it.
So we could pipe that straight into let's say a print line text.
I have a space there that on a dummy all to completion for me.
And then this here is probably going to give us a an integer but you haven't defined anything yet but
let's pop in and it will probably be implicitly converted for us that we want f math and range between
North and 10.
And yes if we hover over it we can see it's been converted to 30.
So have I got the right number of brackets.
Yes I have.
So let's go and see what that prints out there we've saved our work.
Let's go over into Yui for and press compile.
Now that hasn't actually compiled the code that's kept it as it was before so I'm just going to click
stop and recompile.
Okay.
So with that compiled when we go ahead and press play now we should see a random number somewhere between
0 and 10.
If we stop it and play it again we get four and it's just going to keep going round giving us a random
number within the range that we've specified and we've got seven twice that and there we go.
So that's giving us out a random number which is great because what we can now do is say we want a random
number of a particular array which is really useful because then we're going to get back a random word.
If we target are valid words array.
Okay.
So let's go down to our hidden word.
So here we go.
We got where this is where we set our hidden word and we got our valid words list and all valid words
list comes back when we utilize our get valid words.
So let's go ahead and pop that in.
So we're going to get valid words.
There we go.
That comes back and we're going to pass into it's our words which shall be our first word list that
we have which is good.
Now what this is saying at the moment is that it equals an array and we don't want that because this
is returning valid words which is a T array which is not what we want we want an element of that's here
right.
So we can get the element of that's here right here with our square brackets and then we can just say
zero for the moment and we can see whether or not that works.
Let's save it come out and press compile.
OK.
So when we press play now we should see that the hidden word has been set to the first elements of our
array.
So the hidden word is able so we successfully pulled an element from the array that's really good.
So now we just need to put within those square brackets something that will return us a random word
from the valid words list.
So your challenge is to use round range and set the hidden word to a random word from valid words pulls
a video now and give that a go
OK everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and use random rage to set the hidden word to a random word from valid words.
OK so over in our implementation you probably worked out the we need to put something in the square
brackets using the round range.
So first of all we need to go f math prolong colon Rand range.
Fortunately is at the top of the list there.
So we need our minimum and maximum while the minimum is going to be zero.
We already know that.
But what is the maximum going to be.
Well our maximum here is going to be the number of elements in our array of valid words right.
So we're going to be calling this function again.
So there are a number of elements in this array minus one.
That's important because it may have 30 elements in the array but that will be from zero to 29.
I can't remember how many valid words there are in here but we need to put it in code form so if we
change our word list the code works it's not hard coded to do anything else.
So we returning all valid words we're going to have to use to get valid words again.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So here we go.
So we're going to go get valid words and then we're calling that function with words in it again.
Otherwise we'd be comparing a different list.
After that we're going to need our DOT name function to bring us the number of elements in the array.
And then finally we're going to have to take one from it.
And if you were unsure of those values you can always print it out to make sure that it's working properly.
In fact if I grab get valid words dot num minus one.
This little bits of code here and then print it out along with here's the number of valid words is and
then up here do a print line forms like another debug line I suppose.
Print line text and then valid words minus one is what we should find is it's one less than the number
above it.
And we don't need the extra brackets on the end.
Or do we just have a look where was that.
Yes.
Yes we do need that brackets.
Okay.
All of our brackets are correct that I'm happy.
Let's save our code and go over to unreal.
Here we go so the number of words is four hundred and fifty one.
Perfect that's exactly what I want to see.
So I hidden word is same brilliant.
So let's type in essay.
Well let's type in SRM e we've won.
Brilliant.
We play again.
Typing your guess and press continue.
Well it's not going to be the same word this time it's going to be something else.
And because we've not included our debug code in the repeating parts of our game we don't have a debug
line there.
So that's something we could potentially move around so we can test the game.
I don't know what this is going to be so I'm just going to type in same same and same now it was body.
No no of course we don't have our bulls and cows yet.
So there was really no way of guessing that but presence to play again.
Brilliant.
We've got a working game here.
Apart from the fact that it doesn't give us any clues as to what that hidden word is going to be.
So there we go.
Brilliant.
I think I'm going to do a few tidy up bits to my code.
Now how did you guys get on.
Did you manage to get round range working.
Did you remember to minus one at the end.
That's something that I know that when I was just quickly putting this all together that's something
that's very easy to forget about that you're talking about the number of elements but you actually start
counting from zero.
And we've come across that before and it's something to watch out for.
So this spits at the top here this setting up of the game and this debug this whole system here.
I don't really want to know the number of possible words anymore.
That is all fine.
I'm going to comment.
That's out for the moment.
That's nice and clean.
But this debug line here the hidden word is.
Well I'm going to put it elsewhere because at the moment it's only happening at Biggin play and it won't
happen any other time.
However a good place to have it will be when we set up the game.
So we start the game we set up the game we set the hidden word but at the moment we don't have any debug
line so this is going to be a great place to put it.
So in order to get to that next line 44 I'm going to press control and enter and that's going to make
sure I go down to the new line.
So this is a great place to put that and we can turn it on and off as we want this top rates up here.
Well at this point we can just get rid of all of that.
And our example code up here.
So now we begin playing we just set up the game and then we wait for the user inputs.
So that's brilliant.
I'm going to make sure quickly that my code works.
Now please do share your work over in the discussions I'm looking forward to seeing how you're getting
on.
Here we go.
Now my code is nice and clean.
I'm cheating of course but there we go that's exactly what I want to see happening.
Brilliant.
Our game is really coming together now.
The final thing is to really give now the player the bulls and cows.
So we will start doing that over in the next lecture.
Take our.