Hello everybody and welcome back.
So what's this lecture about.
Well we've kind of gone out of the frying pan into the fire when it comes to being performance.
So we've used a function just for a number that seems a bit silly to me especially since that function
has to run in order to get the details from it which is a bit of a waste.
Just for that single number so let's go have a look at our code and see the problem.
And then I'm going to challenge you to fix it OK.
So if we have a look at line 31 here we are calling the get valid words function twice once absolutely
fine because we need to do that anyway in order to get the word but then we're doing it again just to
get this number here which is just too much.
There is a way around this.
In fact there are several ways that you could work your way around this problem.
And one of the ways of doing that is to assign get valid words to a variable and then we can go ahead
and use it more specifically a member variable and then we can use it in multiple places.
And we're going to do that up here at Biggin play or rather you're going to do it in your challenge
okay.
So your challenge.
What I'd like you to do is create a member variable.
Call it ISO grams.
That is the valid words t array.
Use that instead when initializing hit and word pause a video and give that a go
Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead and create our new member variable.
I said Grams okay.
So before we get going the first thing we need to do is go over into our header file and declare it
as a new member variable.
So we've got a t array.
There we go.
Also complete is working wonders today.
And then it's going to contain f strings which is absolutely fine.
And we're going to call it ISO grams.
There we go.
So that's all sorted and we can save that.
Let's go over into our implementation so now we can say ISO Grams equals our gets valid words and then
we do need to pass words into it and there we go we've now got the variable ISO grounds that we can
use throughout our code and perhaps more importantly we only do it once and only when the game begins
instead of every round.
Right.
And this is the place where we want to be able to do it so we're not calling this function unnecessarily
get valid words we can get rid of that there and put in iso grams and the same over here.
Now bear in mind using the auto complete here is often a good thing.
I've in the practice runs I often typed in iso gram instead so perhaps I should a picked that is the
word.
OK.
That all being good we should be able to now go to unreal click compile OK.
So let's go ahead and press play and.
Excellent.
It looks like everything is working.
Let's go into our game and yes brilliant.
So everything is working there.
How are you guys getting on.
So the takeaway there is depending on how your code is constructed it may just work which is absolutely
fine.
We're not aiming to get code perfect here but if you spot something that's a quick weapon like that
and you can make your code more performance because of it.
That's always a good thing to pursue.
And it was just a tiny refactor to get everything working again and it was also a nice circle back to
member variables which we covered much earlier in section.
How did you guys get on.
Let's crack onto the next lecture and get the bull cow counts coming back to the player.