In this lecture, we're gonna be adding a little bit of Polish with some background music.
And a little bit of an introduction text and a little bit of an introduction sound as well.
And we're going to look at a list of things that you could improve and build upon in this shooter project
as mega challenges for yourself.
Let's dive in.
So it is nearly time to wrap up.
And for me to say good bye.
But before we do, I would like to leave you with a few challenges to expand upon this project.
These are my mega challenges, distinguished in the fact that I won't be showing you all of the solutions
for that.
You're going to have to rely on the community and talk to each other and help each other out and really
explore the engine.
Hopefully this will help you really get to grips with unreal.
So the first mega challenge is going to be level layout and I am going to do some of that in this lecture.
So basically, I mean, lay out your level, put your enemies where you want them to be.
Make it really a challenge.
Try and play.
Test.
Get your family and friends to play the level and try it out.
The next one is background music.
I do have some background music assets in there.
And again, in this lecture, I'm going to show you how you could add those in.
So if you want a challenge for this lecture, you compose a video and have a go right now.
Okay.
Welcome back.
So I'm going to go in and do these challenges just a bit.
But in case these were not the ones that you want to tackle and you want to try some other things here,
the rest of my challenges for you.
One of them is to implement weapon switching.
At the moment, we've got quite a flexible weapon architecture that would support weapon switching.
But at the moment, it does not.
So I'm going to give you some pointers on how you might want to go ahead and implement that.
But I'm not going to go through the entirety of the process with you.
The other one is implementing ammo with the weapon.
Again, I'm going to give you some pointers on the process here, but not the actual code.
Then some more advanced A.I. What do I mean by this?
Well, if you're introducing ammo and weapons switching, maybe your A.I. needs to know when to use
each one of these.
So you might need to add in some behaviors for switching weapons and so on.
You might also want to have an I have an idea of whether it's under fire, whether it's being shot at.
In which case it might want to try and take cover so you can have some more advanced behaviors like
that.
All of that can be implemented with behavior, trees and services and custom tasks.
You might want a main menu in order to select between multiple levels and yes, multiple levels.
Add in some other layouts of level.
Put your A.I. differently, make it more challenging how a progression and have it so that you move
from one level to the next.
When you succeed.
Now, I'm going to go through the details of weapon switching and ammo in just a second.
But first, we're going to do at level layout.
First thing I want to do is move.
My player starts to more of a neutral location.
I go delete the main player, start we've got and I'm going to take the player, start over here instead.
So I'm can look for place actors pain and I'm going to look for the player, start and stick it in here.
And that should mean when we hit play that we end up in this corridor.
That's good.
Next up, what I want to do is add in some enemies.
I'm going to put one enemy in here.
So BP shoot a character in here.
There's one enemy then.
We've got already an enemy over here.
I like that.
I'm going to add a couple of enemies, one over here and one down here.
So you have to kind of go out of your way to find them and they're going to try and shoot at you and
come and find you as soon as possible.
Then we've got one enemy over there.
That's good.
I might stick.
And just sticking enemies everywhere.
One round this corner, one up here.
That's great.
Another one maybe here.
Maybe a couple down here to shoot you as well as maybe one up at the top of the stairs here.
To just shoot down from rain, bloody fire from up there, and then we're going to stick a quite a few
in this command center type room, one few to ambush you round the corner here and maybe one or two.
Down in this little pit that we go out.
Now, this room is gonna be a real challenge when you come in here.
Just gonna be shot to pieces.
So if we go ahead and play, we're going to go and try this out.
It's going to be pretty tough at the moment.
And you may want to tweak it much further than just gonna mute here.
You want to tweak it further and tweak the amount of health you have, maybe to make it the right level
of challenge.
Or maybe you wants to tweak how many A.I. there are in the level, all that sort of thing.
You can try by playing through and just starting this game to bits.
And then one final thing I want to do is add some background music and some ambience.
So if you look for sound in the place, actors, you can see there's an ambient sound actor.
We can drag this into the world.
It doesn't really matter where because it's going to play some sound everywhere.
And then what we want to do is select a sound from here, which I'm going to look for music.
And we basically want the shooter game music here.
And you can pretty much just leave that as it is.
And if we go and hit play, you can see that we've got background music going on, giving us a lot nicer
ambience here.
And then one more thing I want to do is just add a little bit of an intro text, which I'm going to
do from our player shooter character.
And I'm going to open up in the blueprint here.
Open up the full blueprint, Ed, and I'm going to go to the event graph and off of the begin play note.
We're going to add a play sound at location, the location.
I want to be the actor location.
So and then the sound asset that we want is going to be I believe I've got something called intro,
which is something that I recorded myself just to say, yeah, let's go and kill these guys in the level
or something to that effect.
So now if we go ahead and hit play, we get a little bit of that introduction telling the player what
to do, that they need to go and clear this base of all of the enemies.
Now, as promised, what we're going to do with things like weapons switching and ammo.
Well, weapons switching roughly the flow is going to look like this.
That's where you're going to add an array of weapons or weapon classes to the character so that it knows
which weapons it can use spawn.
All of those weapons into yet another array.
So that you can keep track of the different weapons that character has.
So basically going from using a single weapon class in a single weapon instance to having an array for
both of them, then you want to have something like an active index integer that keeps track of which
weapon is currently the active one you're going to hide.
All of the weapons basically deactivate and hide all of the weapons except for the one eye and the active
index.
And then you might want to bind the scroll wheel or the numbers so that that changes up your active
And you can update once you do that, once you change the active index, you want to make sure you're
updating the weapon that is currently visible.
And you also need to make sure that you bind the fire so that it selects, which have a weapon is currently
active, so that it uses the fire method, the trigger method of your currently active weapons.
That's weapon switching a brief kind of outline of how you would implement that and how you'd go about
trying that.
The other one is ammo, which is also fairly straightforward.
If you follow along with these steps, you're going to need some sort of ammo variable on your weapon.
There's an integer saying, how much ammo do you have left?
You're going to subtract from that every shot until you get down to zero.
Very much like health, really.
If you think about it, you're going to prevent from shooting.
That won't be possible to shoot if you're amigos.
Less than zero play some sort of empty sound to give a signal to the player.
And you might want to create some sort of pick up act as a create a new actor.
Something derives from actor at a collider, at a match to it, so that when you overlap with it, when
an actor, a character overlaps with it, you're going to get hold of the currently active weapon on
that character and you're gonna add your ammo to it.
And finally, you probably want to disable collisions and hide the mesh, at least for a short amount
of time.
You might want to re-enable it on a timer, but you want to disable it at first, once you've gone over
that pick up so that you aren't continually refueling your ammo while you stand on it.
So that's it for this lecture.
I'll leave you with the challenge slide of things that you can do to expand on what's already there.
Do check out the Q and A. and the discussions and at Dischord Channel for input, feedback and other
people who are sharing what they have done to continue their journey with this shooter game.
Can't wait to see what you make with it.
I will see you in the discussions.