Hello everybody and welcome to the end of the bull cow game section.
We've covered so much in this section.
I bet you had finished it.
Now did you take the last lectures advice and implement your own features.
One of the best things you can do and I know I sound like a broken record saying this but by applying
the knowledge that you've already learned you will definitely improve your skills.
So make sure if you've not done that I'm going to say go back and do that again.
And we've got a very exciting section coming up for you next where we escape from a building where we
start interacting with the world around us.
So there's so much to cover in that section.
I can't wait to get into it.
So dive over there now and I'll see you all real soon.