Hello and welcome.
In this letter, we're going to be introducing you to Animation's How We can use the same animations
on multiple different types of measures using something called a scouten.
Let's dive in and see what all that's about.
So as I said at the end of last lecture, this is looking weird without any sort of animation.
So it's time to do a one on one on animations.
The first thing to do is to see if we can find some animations in our asset pack.
An easy way to do this is using the filters in the content brands, which you've probably come across
before, and fildes by all sorts of stuff here.
And one of them is the all animation assets.
And it's going to go ahead.
Check that.
Is it ads in all of the animation assets?
You can see there is a bunch of stuff in here.
We're particularly looking for the green ones because these are basic animation sequences, as they're
called.
Ben, go ahead and double click on one of those and you can see it automatically starts playing in the
animation.
Ed, there's a lot going on here in the animation, Ed, but the main thing to see is this timeline.
That's the main difference.
We've also got the asset details, which is, you know, a desales pain.
We've seen that sort of stuff before.
There's also this stuff up at the top, right, which we can dive into into second.
But the main thing to look out for is that it's looping through this timeline, which you can go ahead
and grab points to any keyframe in this timeline, if you like.
You can play it forwards.
You can play it backwards as your heart desires.
You can step through frame by frame.
You can also use this asset browser over in the bottom right.
And that asset Browse just allows you to search through all of the animations related to the skeleton.
Now, I just use the word you probably don't know a skeleton.
What is it?
Well, we're dealing with a skeletal mesh animations.
What is that?
That's a mesh that has a skeleton.
It's a mesh that you want to manipulate through a bunch of bones.
So if we click up here in the top right on the skeleton, you can see that this guy is in an ape pose.
Here's a mesh.
But then he's got a bunch of different bones here.
We can select any one of these bones and we could do something like rotate it.
And you can see that that one wasn't a particularly useful one to select.
Maybe if I select with my mouse the spine and I rotate the spine, you can see how that changes the
rest of the mesh based on changing the spine.
So great.
That's kind of what a skeleton is.
But that's not all.
The skeleton kind of exists within the modelling program that was creating this mesh, but a skeleton
unreal has a slightly different function.
So this skeleton asset here, its main function is to tie together the meshes and animations.
You can have multiple measures which all use the same skeleton asset in Unreal and set multiple animations
that use the same skeleton.
And because of that, we can share those animation assets between different meshes.
The example here is the Arrow, a couple of different Raith measures that I've included, different
skins on that Wraith mash and some of them have extra bits and bobs on the mesh.
But they're going to use the same animations because those animations are based on a skeleton that they
all share.
So that's why we have this a little UI setup widget in the top.
Right.
We won't look at the blueprints just now.
That's another asset that depends upon the skeleton, but not one that we're currently interested in.
So the skeletons, what hangs or all of this together brings it all together.
They all depend upon that same skeleton, which means that this dropdown allows us to choose between
different matches that use this skeleton.
And the dropdown next to animation allows us to choose different animations that rely upon this same
skeleton.
So I can go and swap out to a different animation.
I can swap out to a different mesh if I so choose.
And you can see how that meshes different, got different spiky bits.
It's got different textures on it.
So let's try out a challenge.
Let's see if you can find a suitable running animation that we can play just on a continuous loop at
the moment.
It'll look a little bit weird in the game, a less weird than a guy running around in an ape pose.
So look through the available animations using either the content browser or that browser.
Inside the animations, editor set one for the Wraith carrot's to go into our BP character that we've
already created.
Go and find the MASH and see if you can find a way of setting the animation.
A little bit of a challenge there.
Haven't shown you have to do it, but see if you can find the right property for setting an animation
and then try swapping that the Wraith character for a different mash that has the same skeleton and
see if that continues to work.
Pause video and have a go.
Kay, welcome back.
So let's see, first of all, I need to find a run animation, so I'm gonna do this via the asset browser
in this.
Ed, you could do it by either searching it through the asset browser or doing the dropdown on the animations
and searching.
They're going to look for run.
And interesting love doesn't come up with anything automatically there.
So I'm against searching the asset browser run.
Not coming up.
Let's see, maybe there's a walk see ability.
Let's see this one.
Maybe that's with the right mouse button held down.
So he's aiming.
That's probably a good one.
Start off with you want the forward one.
So we gonna hit play forword.
There's one for Backwords left.
Right.
You can see how this stuff is going to start slotting together.
Right now we're just doing a one oh one on skeletal animation.
So let's use this ability.
Are M b walk forward and let's go and find ourselves, first of all and get to cancel out this filter
for Animation's gonna go and select out BP.
She's a character and open up that blueprint, go to the mesh in the components hierarchy and then select
the in the details pain down in the mesh setting.
We've got different skeletal measures that we could swap out.
And just to clarify, the scandal meshes of the ones that have skeletons, the ones that are able to
deform themselves with a skeleton, whereas static measures are the ones that can't deform the cells
usually used for rigid things like cars.
So in the section above this, we have animation.
You can see this animation mode and anime class.
So we'd have to do a dropdown on the animation mode if you had figured that out.
Don't worry if he didn't, but it was good to have a little look around.
Then you can see we can use animation asset in here and we can swap that animation asset out for what
was it, AAB M B and then underscore walk.
I believe they'll go walk forward and that's gonna be on looping.
We're going to play it initially from the initial position of zero.
Let's try that out.
If we go to the viewport, you can see he's already doing that walking animation so I can go ahead and
play and he's going to be walking in my game as well.
And as long as I'm moving forward, that all looks hunky dory.
But as soon as I start moving backwards and sideways, it all falls apart.
We're gonna fix that.
Don't worry.
But for starters, we've figured out how to do this.
The other thing we need to do is try with a different mesh.
So we've done it with a basic raith mesh.
There are other measures in here, but they're not gonna work because they're not based off the same
skeleton as the animation.
In fact, you can see unselected the animation to play.
So if we go back to our mesh and change that out for the Wraith skeletal mesh, then go to our Annam
and look for the walk again, walk forward, then swap out a mesh for one that has a compatible skeleton
such as the Luna Ops skeleton.
You can see it hasn't removed the animation because they share a skeleton, so they are compatible with
one another.
Awesome stuff.
So now hopefully you understand a little bit more about what an animation is, how you're able to play
it and how it relates to skeletons, and it's a skeletal meshes.
Next video will be a brief interlude on how to fix a little collision bug that we may have seen just
glitching in the background there.
So I'll see you there.