Hi and welcome back.
So the engine is going to take some time to download but that's absolutely fine.
We've got plenty to do.
So we are also going to install something called Visual Studio code.
Let me address why we're doing that at this stage in the course.
Well it's a fast free and familiar development environment.
It is supported in Unreal since four point one eight so I'm giving you a sensible alternative.
Importantly for the beginning of this course it's exactly the same on Windows Mac OS and Linux.
Otherwise if we demonstrate using a different development environment you're going to need a different
thing on Windows namely Visual Studio community MacOS namely Xcode and Linux namely Well you've got
to go and pick something.
The only thing out there that works on all those platforms that isn't Visual Studio code is something
called CLion not as in the aquatic animal that goes *aw aw* but is in C-L-I-O-N.
But that's not free that software and it's unnecessarily complex for a beginner course like this.
It's also about 10 times smaller to download than Visual Studio community which is a bonus.
But please install both of these things on the same drive.
So if you installed the VS community or Xcode on one drive particular on windows whatever drive you
installed VS community on please install this VS code on the same drive and we can extend this to our
needs later.
So we're gonna be using VS code as the demonstration program in the beginning of the course so that
everybody on MAC, PC and Linux can follow along saying the same thing if you already know Visual Studio
community or Xcode you can use those too.
Okay.
It's an option for you but if you're unfamiliar and uncomfortable use VS code and we may switch to
visual studio community later in the course but a similar program to me starting with the simplest thing.
All right so I'm gonna get you to install VS code but I'm just gonna get you started so that we're
in the right place.
Pretty easy really we just go VS code into our favorite search engine and code dot visual studio dot
com is what you want.
It should detect your platform if it doesn't you've got options for Windows Mac and Linux both Debian
and others for Linux and let's go ahead and download that much smaller download.
As I said then VS community I'm going to run it directly and once that's going we'll get it installed.
So your challenge is simple install VS code get it installed and then once we're in there we're going
to add something called the Microsoft C/C++ extension.
Now if you want a challenge and you want to look around VS code yourself before I talk you through
it then try and do that yourself.
If you're lost doesn't matter.
Just keep watching and I'll show you how to do it in a second but if you can find where extensions are
and find the Microsoft C/C++ extension that's a great little challenge for you and watch on after
the challenge for tips and testing.
So pause the video see if you can get VS code in that extension installed now and I'll be back in a moment.
OK.
Welcome back.
So I am going to accept license agreements and just install VS code.
Now it's in a very similar place on MAC and PC by the way on
PC I am going to say open with code action to both of these things.
The windows file explorer context and directory context menus just can be useful.
It's not vital but I'm just gonna do that because it's useful sometimes.
All right.
So while it installs close the web page in the background Linux people MAC people very similar it's
just a straight forward software install.
Okay there's nothing complicated about the initial installation of the VS code may spawn up on Microsoft
Web site the getting started document probably worth a look.
And actually on that getting started document look they've given you that one of their top extensions
is the C/C++ extension.
So if you click that and click install from the website that would be one way of doing it.
Right.
Windows is asking me if I can switch apps.
So that's one way of doing it.
I'll show you another way of doing it as well.
Either way you end up here which is it the extensions control panel where you click install.
Now another way of doing this is to click extensions on the left hand side and just to search for C++
and when that comes up you pick this one here make sure it's from Microsoft it should have millions
of downloads.
The actual code of the extension is ms-vscode.cpptools
That's the right extension and we install it.
What is an extension an extension is something that does exactly what it says it extends the functionality
of this basic editor for us so that it helps us visualize C++ a little bit better and helps us do a
few things within C++.
So that's pretty cool.
So once that's done you can toggle on and off your extensions thing on the left there.
There's a debugger on the left which we're not really using for the moment is something to do with version
control on the left.
We're not gonna be using that.
This is search facility and then there's a file facility.
The thing that we do want open is the file explorer which is the top tab on the left hand side.
All right.
You can agree to any usage data as you wish etc. and we are most of the way there.
So it's open now I'm going to give you some survival tips for VS code preferences.
You can get to the color theme if you want a different color theme.
A couple of ways you either go to the cog down the bottom left let me move this so you can see cog down
the bottom left and then color theme.
That's one way of doing it.
There is another survival tip which is if you go to view and then command pallete within visual studio
view command palette and there is a keyboard shortcut it will bring up something is very rich.
It's got a lot of stuff in there.
If we now search we can also get to say the color theme settings from there.
So all of the settings in visual studio code are available through view command palette.
You want to find anything that's a good place to go it's kind of a tiny little portal into a lot of
settings porthole or portal portal I think.
OK.
We also want to tick file auto save to save your sanity.
So if we go to the File menu and then auto save and then when you click it again just make sure there's
a tick against auto save down here.
What that will do is make sure that your files are saving because it's a very common beginning mistake
to be writing code and then for them not to be saved to the disk and then to wonder why things are out
of sync.
So I think auto save is probably a good idea overall.
What's the next step.
OK.
We'll see later I just want you to bear this in mind when you want not only when you're watching my
videos but when you're watching Gavin's videos and later Mikey's videos that compiling code is a
separate issue to running the code.
Okay so the three step process that we are going to go through is we're going to create a code file.
We're then going to compile a code file into something the computer can run and then we'll run that
code.
I just want you to bear in mind the compiling code is separated to running it and as I said earlier VS
community or Xcode are optional alternatives for you here now as it happens my epic games launch has
finished at this stage those might take a lot less or a lot more time and it wants to make some changes
so I'm going to let that go ahead.
This is it installing the engine in the background.
You don't need to be using the engine right now so we can close the Epic Games don't show whatever stage
in the course you get to when your engine installs you can close the Epic Games launcher and you're
good to go.
OK.
So Linux and Mac people we are done you should now be able to follow through our basic C++ coding videos
in VS code how about  Windows people what I want you to do is close VS code.
You only need to do this in windows.
I want you to go and find your developer command prompt which you search in windows for developer developer
for developer command prompt or developer command prompt for VS 2019 open that I would suggest you
now pin it for the moment to your taskbar so you've got it available and then what we're gonna do is
we're gonna use the command prompt to open VS code rather than opening it from windows and the way you do
that is you just type code.
So we go to the developer command prompt doesn't matter what's on there and we just hit code.
Okay.
That'll spawn VS code within Windows.
The reason we do it that way is that we can now compile our code where is if we didn't open VS
code this way we wouldn't be able to compile our code and that would be a real pain.
We can test that that's worked by going to terminal and new terminal.
It may come up blankets can be a bit buggy but if you just hit return you get a terminal if you try
Try typing C L that is the compiler the C++ compiler you should get this Microsoft optimizing C++ compiler
version something you can share that version in the community with this if you like and you celebrate
that you are ready to go this is your sign in windows that you are good to go if you're on MAC and Linux
and still watching Die Hard at just trying to see if you can grab any value then on MAC you would have
a command MAC and Linux you have a command called a g++.
All right but cl is what we need on windows and that tells us the compiler is working.
This is how we want to launch coding as a recap.
You open the develop a command prompt here and then you type code.
Okay simple as that.
And then we're in the right context without doing any complicated setup.
Okay.
And the final thing we want to do here on Windows is just to change our default shell from powershell
to command and this is so that when we run our programs later they just run without having to mess around
with putting top forward slashes and things in so the way you do that if you open your terminal if it's
not open already so terminal and new terminal you click where it says powershell and you go to select
default shell that is only on windows and then we're going to choose command prompt.
Okay so we want command prompt to be our default shell let it do any whirly gig its wants to do and when
it's finished closed the terminal just open a new terminal and it should say cmd if it does we're
all good to go.
And then when you come to run your programs later they should run without any fuss.
Awesome.
We're ready to go.
We're ready to start doing basic C++.
Thank you very much for bearing with me.