Hello.
And first off congratulations on completing this first section of the Python programming course.
Some things were new Some things were different.
I'm sure there were some challenges but nevertheless you poured through it and you got to the end.
I'm super excited for you it's a very big first step into learning Python.
And today I've got a very exciting tutorial for you.
I've actually got a homework exercise prepared for it.
Know right away I wanted to mention that if you're coming from why our programming course this is going
to be exactly the same homework exercise and that is going to be the beauty of it that if you've done
that course and you've done this homework exercise and are you going to see how different is going to
be in Python you're going to be able to for yourself sit down program the same challenge in a different
programming language and then compare the results.
So that's a great advantage if you have already done our course if you haven't then maybe after this
Python programming course check out the art course and you'll be able to do it in reverse order.
Nevertheless let's jump straight into this exercise and I'll share around.
It's very exciting.
All right.
So this is the law of large numbers and what is it telling us here and why are we even talking about
it today.
Well the law of large numbers even though it might look a bit complex at the start is actually a very
simple mathematical concept that is extremely extremely powerful.
Personally I like it so much that I use it everyday in everything I do whenever I can bring up the Law
of Large Numbers even just to justify something myself or explain how things work in even in the real
world.
I do it because the Law of Large Numbers is such a simple and yet powerful concept so let's discuss
it a bit more detail what the Law of Large Numbers is telling us here.
Well to send a lot of large numbers.
We need to first understand the environment in which is operating.
So imagine you have a sample of observations.
So for instance it could be coin tosses or it could be you just picked out 100 or 1000 people out of
the population so you took a sample of some bigger population.
So what the Law of Large Numbers is telling us is that the average over a certain value so x is a measured
value for instance.
It could be the height of the people in that sample that you picked out that average across the sample
which represents a number of observations in our sample.
So the average across the sample will converge to the expected value of that same measure when an increase
is to infinity.
So hypothetically speaking we know that there's several billion people on the planet and we can consider
that to be very close to infinity.
And we also know that the expected value of a person if you take the average value across all people
on this planet.
Let's say for example it's a 1 meter 72 centimeters or in feet it's let's say six feet.
This is our expected.
So the expected value of the height of a person is six feet.
Now if your sample size is 10 people if you pick out 10 random people from this planet the average of
their height will might be 6.5 feet might be seven feet might be five point five feet as you increase
and as you increase the number of people that are in your sample as you go from 10 to a hundred thousand
to 10000 people.
But the average of the measured value in your sample is going to start to converge to the expected value
.
Now I know it might be hard to grasp at the start why this is happening but let's have a look at a more
specific example.
And it will all make sense.
So here's an example of coin tosses.
Let's say you performed 10 coin tosses.
Then out of 10 coin tosses you just think of pause and think about it for a second.
Out of 10 coin tosses if you'd just like take a coin right now and you throw it ten times.
It is not unlikely that you will get seven heads and three tails right.
Statistically speaking heads and tails should come with equal frequency.
Right so your expected value is 50 50.
So 50 percent of your tosses should be heads and 50 percent battels.
But still it's totally normal.
If you toss a coin to get head seven times or even get heads nine times out you wouldn't be surprised
if that happened right.
Well it's a coincidence but nevertheless it's normal even feels normal.
Then if you do 100 coin tosses the likelihood of getting 70 heads and 30 tails is much less probable
.
If you've got 70 heads or 100 you'd think that something might be wrong with the coin you wouldn't feel
normal.
But at the same time getting like 52 heads and 48 tails.
Yeah that sounds sounds about right.
So there could be a bit of a deviation from what you're expecting 50 50.
Right.
If you throw a thousand coins the probability of getting 700 heads and 300 tails is very very low.
If you get 700 heads out of a thousand coin tosses you're probably going to think that the coin is definitely
rigged.
It's it's weighted to one side or something's wrong with the coin if you get 500 into an 498 or if you
get five hundred and nine and four hundred ninety one you wouldn't be that surprised that can happen
right.
It can deviate a little bit so not only just mathematically but even from the point of view of perspective
like how it feels right or wrong.
It's it makes sense that as you increase the number the likelihood of deviating away from 50 percent
50 percent would quite far is decreasing.
So as you can see in our examples at the start is there are 50 50 70 30.
Then as we increase the number got to 52 48 then go to fifty point to forty nine point eight and so
on.
And so that's what we mean that as we increase the sample size the average of the measured value is
going to start to converge to the expected value.
Now that is the Law of Large Numbers and for this article we're going to need one more thing.
We're going to need the normal distribution.
Now we've already mentioned the rand and function which generates a random number from a normal distribution
.
And we learned how to work with it.
We saw that that number can fall anywhere between minus 1 and 1.
Most of the time that's where it fell as we saw Sometimes it falls further away sometimes and falls
further away.
And so what does this chart tell us.
Well this chart is the bell curve is a position of the normal distribution and we not even going to
bother with the vertical axis here because everything is already written out for us inside the charts
.
And so what it is telling us is that if you have a normal distribution or normally distributed variables
or if you just take let's say for example of that function that we talked about the rand function if
we take one normally dispute variable here we've got the the percentages are telling us what is the
likelihood of that bearable ending up in each one of these segments.
So the likelihood of that bearable being between 0 and 1 here we got 1 sigma but sigma is the standard
deviation so we're just going to pretend that sigma is actually one.
So then this is going to be a normal distribution with a mean of zero and a standard deviation of 1
.
In this case your likelihood of that variable or that value that regenerating the likelihood of it falling
between 0 and 1 is thirty four point one percent between minus 1 and 0 is also thirty four point one
percent.
Then it starts to drop off very rapidly.
So between one and two there's only a thirteen point six percent chance that all four there then it's
there's only a 2.1 percent chance between two and three and then 0.1 percent that it's greater than
three.
So it drops off as you can see this is how the normal distribution works.
What do we need this for.
Why do we need the old distribution Why do we need the law of large numbers of what curial What are
you talking about.
Why do we need these things for this homework exercise.
Well the reason is because in this homework exercise we're going to be testing the law of large numbers
.
How cool is that.
We're going to be using the normal distribution to check if the law of large numbers actually holds
true.
Let's have a look at in more detail what exactly we're going to be doing.
So test the law of large numbers for and Aranda normally distributed numbers with a mean of zero and
standard deviation of one meaning just use the brand and function and create a Python script that will
count how many of these numbers fall between minus 1 and 1 and divide by the total quantity of.
And you know that the expected value of x is sixty eight point two percent and you need to check that
the mean of X and where is your sample size is converging to the expected value of x as you run your
script while increasing.
And so I know that's a lot to take in.
Let's go back to the image and walk through what we're going to be doing.
So here we can see that we're going to be analyzing the interval between minus 1 and 1.
So we're going to be generating numbers random numbers and we'll take a sample of.
And for instance could be 100 or next time it'll be a thousand but we'll be generating in one go and
random numbers and we will want to see how many of them actually fall in this part.
So let's go here we can see that fall between minus 1 and 1.
Right.
And where does the sixty eight point two percent come from.
Well we can see here that three four point one plus thirty four point one actually gives the sixty eight
point two percent.
So we will be expecting that from our sample sixty eight point two percent of the observations will
fall into this interval.
Right.
And so what we need to test is that as we increase our sample this means so we might if we only have
10 observations we might get 50 percent fall in there or 70 percent or so only 5 percent but then we
use as we increase and as we take more and more numbers so a hundred or a thousand 10000 numbers we're
expecting that we're going to be testing that the means so the actual observed number that fall into
that interval is going to be slowly getting closer and closer to sixty eight point two percent.
All right.
So hopefully all of that makes sense.
And it's slowly shaping up in your mind how you would attack this problem.
Right.
We've already discussed quite a lot of Python concepts so we've discussed how to generate random variables
so we would use the Rand and function then we've discussed the if statement will need the if statement
here to see where exactly the values fall.
We'll need some logical operators and logical variables we'll need some counters we'll need some of
the earth network operations.
So as you can see everything that we've talked about in this section of the Course is slowly shaping
up.
And of course we will also need a loop.
Right.
We're going to need to loop across those random variables that we're going to generate.
So once again a lot of the things that we talked about in this section of course are really coming together
to create this one statistical slash programming says slash mathematical test.
And very exciting very kind of data science starts into this course are starting to the end of this
section the start of the course.
So hopefully you can have a go at that and pause this video give it a shot see how you go and if you
find that you're getting stuck in new Qantas or the challenge then not a worry come back because I have
two hints for you.
I'm going to reveal those hints just now so if you want to give this a shot then go ahead.
Otherwise I'm going to show you the first hint because I think I need to show that hand with you.
It's something that we didn't actually discuss in the course and it will be very handy to solve this
challenge.
All right.
So Hint number one how do we generate a certain number of random variables.
Well you know that's in our section we used the rand and function with no arguments.
Well what you can do is you can posit a value so if you pass around and 100 then it'll generate instead
of one.
Ill generate 100 random variables 100 normally distributed random values.
And what we have here is actually the loop that will be used in the solution so we'll be creating an
iteration variable which will be iterating across all of those hundreds values that will be random values
that we're going to be analyzing.
And then inside that loop you will need to perform those calculations.
So that's a tip.
And hopefully that will get you on the right track.
If you still feel that you need a bit more guidance then stick around.
I'm going to open the second event now.
So Hint number two and for Hint number two.
I've got a fill in the blanks exercise.
So this is the solution but here to make it still a bit challenging I've replaced quite a lot of the
code with underscores at the same time there's a lot of common so it should be total sense what is going
on here.
So your steps from here would be to copy this code or just type it up on your side and then replace
these underscores with the correct code.
So there you go.
That's the challenge the homework exercise for the section and at the very end of the Course you'll
find a separate section with all of the solutions to these homework exercises.
So once you have taken a go at this exercise come and check out the solutions and we'll discuss how
to create this code there.
And I look forward to your next step.
Until then happy coding.