Blown Welcome back to the course in Python programming.
I hope you enjoyed the section that we've just completed.
And today we're going to quickly recap on what we learned.
So in this section we learned the Bourne importing data into Python so finally finally we've covered
enough materials in this course in order to have learned how to import into Python.
I was very excited to discuss that Tauriel two together walk through importing darent Python and we
looked at several methods where you can just specify the full path to the file or you can change your
working directory.
And also we looked at doing that in Windows and in the MacBook.
And I must say that's in a lot of other courses and tutorials you'll find out there.
This is one of the topics discussed is discussed at the very start of the course.
But personally I think that it is a great approach to only introduce the import of data when we're ready
for it.
And this time we were because we already knew about functions.
We were quite comfortable with coding in Jupiter.
And we were ready to do it.
And so now going forward you'll be able to import data sets your own data sets through CACP files whenever
you need to work with them in Python.
So congratulations on that.
This is a very very big step which opens up the world of data science in Python to you.
Next we learned about doorframes Why are pandas and the bandas is the main package that we learned to
use for our friends and we will be using then we learned how to explore data set.
So we learned about the head function that tail function that in full function which is similar to the
summary function in our.
And we learn about the described function which is kind of like the SDR restructure function in our
.
Then we talked about renaming columns of a doorframe.
We learned about subsetting doorframes we learned about basic operations with a door frame so we talked
about things like deleting columns adding columns into doorframes.
Then we talked about the 80 and 80 functions which allow us to access individual elements of a door
frame.
And this was an advanced tutorial and we learned the difference between the two and how to not get caught
up in that trap of using the wrong one of these functions in certain doorframes.
Then we talked about filtering doorframes a very important concept in data size.
So filching is very similar to filtering in Excel except for that here and we have to code it so we
have to grade that filter and pass it to the door frame it can look a bit complex when you look at it
filter door frame the code for a two doorframe and for the first time.
But the way we introduced it was step by step.
We first learned how to create the filter and then how to parse it to a doorframes So hopefully that
all made sense it's all clear what exactly is going on in the background when you're filtering a doorframe
in Python.
Then we had our introduction to Seaborn seaborne is a weasel zation package for Python some very powerful
realisations.
And as you'll see in the next section of the course we will be working with some very interesting very
unique type of missiles that the seaborne makes very easy to create So that's going to be a very very
exciting couple of tutorials in the next section.
Also we talked about keyword arguments in the section of the core skewered arguments are arguments that
can be passed to functions through dictionaries so there was a very practical use case for the dictionary
knowledge that we developed in the previous section of the course.
So I hope you enjoyed the section this was definitely a very fundamental section for darte assigns because
indeed you will be working with doorframes a lot in your career.
That is the main way that relational data sets are represented.
So we took us quite a bit to get here first we talked about lists which was a stepping stone for us
to talk about arrays which was a stepping stone for Osterwald matrices which were a stepping stone for
us to move onto doorframes finally.
And so this is our main main fundamental concept.
Doorframes and how to import data into Python and further in the course will be heavily relying on all
this while we're discovering new topics Conway to see in the next section of the Course.
Until then happy coding