Hello.
Welcome back to the course and by the programming and the previous tutorial we've finally created our
first visit zation So congratulations on that.
It's a big step.
I know it doesn't look that too impressive yet but it's already a huge step and you should be proud
of yourself for getting this far in this course.
And today we going to add more lines or more players to this realisation so we can compare them side
by side on one chart.
All right.
Are you ready for this.
Let's get straight into it.
So more of his Alsation.
All right.
So what do we want to do is we're going to take this Plaut and we're going to copy this first line.
And so what that does it.
Had a second line to the plot.
So we like building the plot.
We're adding elements to the port until we actually show that plot this one.
Let's say we want to read.
It's going to be a player with index 1.
And here let's change it keep the lines sound like that but it will change the marker too.
Well this has been like this for now.
And let's let's just run it so shift and turn so you can see there's a second player.
But this time will change the marker to a circle.
So just in all.
So you can see there's our second player.
So a bit more of a consistent trend and ended up in the same spot.
Even though Kobe Bryant was earning way more throughout the past 10 years.
All right.
So what I wanted to show you here is first of all lines.
So if you google matplotlib or Pipelet line styles you can get to this page.
So this is matplotlib dot org Web site.
And here they've got the documentation here for lifestyle so you can see all of the different parameters
that you're able to specify.
We're only using some of them as you could see.
And that's what I meant when I me but are saying that we're not going to learn everything because it's
virtually impossible to learn everything we're only going to learn the bits that we need.
And then if you need more things as you go along you can always look them up.
Kind of a lean approach to learning a programming language.
So line style here we've got solid dash started you can use words or he can use as we did just symbols
so here I'm just going to zoom in a bit.
We just use that double dash in our line style and then marker's same thing if you google for pi plug
markers you go get to this page eventually you'll get to this page and here you can see the different
markers that you have.
So we're kind of using it right now.
What are we using.
We're using the old for the circle.
We're using somewhere here was the s.
There it is.
As for the square so we're going to use more different ones but it just helps make the viz. more segregated
so you can see the different players separately not just the colors differentiate them but also the
different styles of the markers.
That's two players so far.
Ok going good.
So so far we know below this one is Kobe Bryant.
This one his player of index number one action look them up.
Who is that.
Here let's have a look.
Joe Johnson Next up is going to be LeBron James All right so let's add another one.
So just take this all copied here and we'll just go add another one so that will be to be LeBron James
.
Let's say green and we use their hats.
I can.
So if you're on this you'll see that that's for Triangle.
You'll see that we kind of slowly getting more and more right.
What will happen when we have four.
Let's do another one.
I'll just do it on the Simplot.
So what will happen now if we add another one three three and here we're going to say blue.
And here we're going to say.
So actually I had I would say just if you could follow the same colors and markers so that when we perform
the analysis we have the same picture that we're looking at so far on this.
You can see we already have we already have quite a lot on one charge.
And that's we're not even halfway through them.
So how can we add something that will tell us which player we're looking at.
So how can we basically add a legend to our chart that's going to be an interesting step for us so let's
go ahead and do that.
I'm going to copy these lines in a new one.
And what I want is I want to add in a legend.
It's not that hard especially that we've been saving these labels as you can see we can see them on
the chart but we've been saving so every char every line on this chart has a label attached to it that's
going to help us.
So now we're going to add a legend which will pick up these labels.
So just say BLT dot legend.
That's how you create a legend in PI plot and then we'll say so loc is location or where you want to
walk.
Either way you can remember it where you want to look at the legend so let's just for now as for now
let's get rid of that and let's just round this like it is so here you can see that we've got the legend
right and it's in the ways on our chart.
How do we fix that up.
How do we change that.
Well the way to do it is we'll say lock equals upper left.
And what that means is that we want to take the upper left corner of all legends.
So not the chart but the legend it has this box we want to take up the upper left corner.
And where do we want to place it.
Well we want to place it the next parameter is.
I know this one is a bit lengthy beatbox underscore to underscore anchor equals.
And then you need to parse a tuple where you want to Lochley and so based on your chart.
So if this is the charts lenth this is one and this is one in terms of x and y where do you want to
place it so if you say 1 1 that means one horizontal length and one vertical then.
So we want to lock this corner of this legend to this corner of the chart.
So let's run that.
You'll see that that's exactly what happened.
So if for instance I say what will happen if I say 0 here right.
Where did the legend go it went to the bottom because we want only one lenth on the x axis and we want
zero lengths on the y axis.
Plays 0 0 here.
Then the top left corner will end up in the bottom there.
So that's how we can move around a legend and you can.
You don't have to lock the corner left corner or you can say upper right.
Then this upper right corner will be locked in over there.
So let's try that.
You see it's ended up over here so you can move this legend around and I highly encourage you to do
that so you can give us a bit of practice to see what's going on so you could say 0.5 sort of point
five the top right corner and up in the middle of the chart.
Right exactly like that.
It's totally up to you where you'd like to play said.
I'm going to put it in over here because we have some space there.
That's right outside the chart looks nice.
And as we get more players it all started growing it won't affect our chart.
But it's always good to know that you have that flexibility and control over where the legend goes.
So that's how we add the legend.
Maybe I'll just add a comment here.
Adding a legend.
All right.
And now we're just going to continue with our players.
There's quite a few to go but nevertheless we're going to go go through them.
So what I wanted to mention is while I'm doing this by the way this is going to be magenta in terms
of color.
What I wanted to mention is that this is not the best approach to creating this is Alsation obviously
.
Obviously there are other approaches which are better but at the same time it's a very good approach
because it allows us to build this chart step by step.
That's the first thing and second thing is as you will see further down in this specific section of
the course this will approach will allow us to actually practice building functions.
So it will prompt us to create our own functional be a very valuable skill to have very valuable tutorials
so bear with me as we create this.
In fact I'm just going to probably cut the video from here too when I'm finished.
And then you'll just have the actual results and then you can just copy along.
All right.
So there we go that's all 10 players as you can see.
We recycled some of the colors and we even recycle some of the markers but because they're going in
a different order we never have the same color with the same marker and that gives us that variety.
So we can still visualize all the players.
So that is how the salaries a matrix looks like.
And that is already a great start for us so you can already compare.
You can see that Kobe Bryant was always at a much higher salary and of get this is in tens of millions
of dollars and then some players you know caught up to him.
And you can explore different players in terms of how their salaries were changing and you can always
take the same desolation and just copy it here and put in a different matrix.
For instance you can look at how many games each one of those players played.
So if we just do that very quickly and so far on this now you'll see that is the game as a matrix.
Very interesting as well.
So you can see how many games on those players played in every single one of those seasons.
You can see the injuries.
Who is that.
That's Derrick Rose injured there and then Derrick Rose and Kobe Bryant injured in the 2013 season.
All right.
Some very interesting insights and as you can see this is much more insightful and much easier to read
than just looking at the tables that we're talking about previously.
So hope you're enjoying this.
Hope you're excited about what we're creating so far.
Further down in the section we'll refine it even further.
And for now I encourage you to play around with that.
So just copy this whole code into a new cell and replace the matrix of a different one and try explore
different matrices and even some of the ones that you created.
Some of the matrices that you created through division or other operations and see what insights you
can gather now that you have this powerful tool of viz. in your arsenal and Alcyone the next internal
Until then happy coding