Welcome back to the course on Python programming.
I hope you had a chance to practice with what we learned in the previous tutorial.
It was a very powerful skill and a very important one to have and hopefully going great so far.
Today we're going to learn how to access individual elements.
Interesting.
I thought we really talked about that you might say I thought we really talked about looking at rows
and columns and yes indeed we did but we never actually accessed an individual element or cell in a
doorframe.
So how would you do it.
What's your first instinct.
Well you'd say starts to come into something that right.
Because we know that in matrices this approach works.
If I run that I will get an error.
Interesting.
Why doesn't it work.
Let's type in our favorite comment error.
Why.
Why is it happening.
Well first thing I wanted to mention is that we haven't talked about this yet.
And also this tutorial if you find it complicated Don't worry about it you can always come back if you
ever need to learn the skill.
You can always come back and relearn it but otherwise when it's not such an important skill to have
.
And that's why we're only covering it off now and that's why we haven't talked about it yet because
if you think about it with doorframes you're rarely going to access individual elements you almost are
going to be using filters are going to be visualizing them are going to be subsetting them.
But how often do you actually need a certain specific value from a doorframes or in Excel from a table
from a table in Excel.
How often do you actually need to pool all just one single value most of the time you're working with
lots of others.
But nevertheless it does happen sometimes so that's why I thought it would be important to cover of
this topic.
And once again you can always return to it if you need to use this skill.
Further down the track.
All right.
So here we go.
Let's look at our doorframes stats dog head.
There it is.
And the functions that we need have specific names.
There are going they're going to allow us to access individual elements.
There are two functions we need the add function or it's called the dot at and the dot I at.
So what does this one do.
This one is for labels so important here is important too.
We'll put it separately important even integers are treated as labels.
And here this one is for integer location.
So what does this all mean and why.
How does it work.
And oh do you remember these names.
Well the way I remember them is a T as an at it's X that's all you'll see how we use it just now but
it will allow us access elements and specific cells.
That's why I remember is that it says at that cell or it's at that cell it's at that cell.
And that is you'll notice we'll be indexing by an integer.
So we are looking at an integer.
We're using an integer to go and find something at that cell at that silence on.
So I know it might be a bit confusing right now but nominalist let's give it a go.
And I think you all come into place so I'll say stats and instead of saying three four which we know
will give us an error we'll say that instead of saying stat's three four which were all yours and arrogance
is stats dot iat 3 4 let's run that I would get upper middle income.
So let's see how that works.
It went third row fourth column.
All right.
So zero.
That's the first one are actually 0 0 1 2 3 32.
That's that.
And then fourth call them 1 2 0 1 2 3 4 fourth column upper middle income.
Wonderful.
Let's try another one let's say stats Daut at and they all say let's say row number zero and call them
number one.
What is that going to give us.
What do you think.
Is there a one country code for a Ruba wrote in Missouri.
Call them number 0 1 AB W..
There it is.
That's what we got.
Wonderful.
So that's how I am works at this stage you notice I actually counted.
I didn't just look at the number here and you'll know you'll see why exactly.
In a second but actually counts physically counts the rows from the top count the columns from the left
.
And it gives you the result there.
That's why it's called the integer because it counts it counts with those two years.
Now how do we use at that is how do we use at what what X does is it looks at labels.
So instead of counting it will look at the labels and labels here.
0 1 2 3 4 and so on.
They are integers indeed they are integers but they not necessarily have to always be in this place
.
And you'll see that in a second.
Those are all integers.
Now those are labels for rows and these are labels for columns.
So to use at you need to use labels.
So let's say one birthrate and here we're going to say first we need the row right so we're going to
say row number two which is the label number two you just don't even count this time you just look for
the two here.
OK and then we'll look for column birthrates are we supposed to get forty five point ninety five.
So it's the birthrate.
Run that 45 4 9 8 4 9 9 9 9.
Beautiful.
That's our approach with labels.
You can try another one for yourself if you like but what I want to show you now is the reason why we
need.
That's right you think.
You think you can just do everything with as well or I at it.
They can be useful in different cases sometimes you might know exactly which number row and number column
you need sometimes you might know the labels but there is a very specific difference between this value
and this value.
Let's have a look at that.
The way they're treated.
Why we need start at.
So let's create a new matrix will say subset 10 and we'll say all of the values every tenth of value
and let's have a look at that subtend.
So I'm not even doing the head function here.
I'm just printing out the whole object the whole doorframe so you can see that we've got 0 10 20 30
40 every 10th row in this Adoniram that we had got subset it into subtend.
OK.
And now why did we do that.
What is this going to show us.
Well let's have a look let's say sub 10.
I at 10 0.
Right.
So we're saying give me the tenth row or roll with index 10 and the column of index 0 there whenever
they cross give me that cell and let's see what it'll brings it'll give us Libya now which you would
think is if you do subtend I chat and you do 10 and then what is the country name here country.
Or what does the column column Zero name its country name.
You'd think that this would give you the same results right.
You're just basically saying 10 10.
Replace the number of the column with the count with the name of the call.
You're on that different results.
Very interesting.
Why is that.
Well because of their behavior.
So what does iat do.
iat it actually counts remember what we talked about it counts out 10 and goes 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10
.
In this new object in this new doorframe This is the roll with index 10.
And that's why you gives you this row and this column column of 0 Libya or country name the they their
intersection is Libya.
That's why you get Libya on subtend dot at.
You've got 10.
And then country.
But this time as we discussed as go up to the top as we discussed the dot at looks for labels it doesn't
care about their sequence.
It cares about the labels who's going to look for the label 10 as you can see label 10 is here and country
name.
So you get Azerbaijan.
Azerbaijan.
There we are.
And this behavior of subtend at all actually not something that the misbehavior of a subset.
Doorframe is very similar to what you get in are and are also when you filter a data frame or subset
it this way what you get is these labels that don't get updated.
So definitely watch out for that.
If you're going to be using at night that then know the difference and use the correct function when
you need to access either by integer.
So when you actually fix that you really count which row and column or when you need to access it through
the labels.
There's a big difference.
And sometimes it can affect the final outcome.
All right so hopefully you enjoyed that tutorial and now you know how to access individual elements
of a daughter frame and scenics them.
Until then every coding