Hello and welcome back to the course of the python program and I hope you're enjoying creating this
first function.
I know it's quite tedious.
I know it's been quite a while that we've been working with this code to finally move from just create
a plot to create different players on that plot and then started to create a function.
It has been a lengthy process but in the end it's definitely worthwhile and we'll see that we'll witness
that in the final tutorial for the section with where we are deriving the insights.
It'll be obvious how easy it is to derive insights once everything is prepared.
But for now we still need to finalize our function and that's why this tutorial is called advanced function
design because we need to take our function to the next level.
And it has to be able to assign different colors and markers to different players.
So let's go ahead and get started on that.
There's our code which is going to create a new line here a new cell.
So basically what do we after.
Well we can see that the data the information changes so if every iteration as we pass this player list
maybe let's copy that as well as a process player list the data changes it just takes the name of the
player into account and picks the right data right and then the label also changes what doesn't change
is the marker and the color we want them to change.
But at the same time we don't have somewhere to look them up.
We don't have a place where we could look up the colors that correspond to different players.
So how about we create that.
And what would we create.
Well you'd create a dictionary would say color equals.
And then here as we learn about dictionaries in these rackets we need to specify combinations so pairs
we need to specify key one and value one.
Remember that and then key to value 2 and so on.
So here it's actually key and so on.
So where do we get these keys and mallees.
Well we can get them from the code that we already have here so they just copy that temporarily we'll
place it here and you can kind of see what I mean when I said that we have quite a lot of code for this
section.
So let's actually try to zoom in maybe or work.
All right so what we want is we want the players here right.
So we a list of players let's go ahead and get one from the very top all our code is on the way here
.
Oh in fact we can actually just copy this save some time.
Already has the list of players so let's go ahead and copy that.
Put it in here instead of the numbers.
We're just going to specify the colors black goes here red.
So I'll just cut the video up to where I've done it and you can just follow along and then we'll have
the final result and we can compare that.
All right.
So there it's done so you can see Kobe Bryant Black Joe Johnson red LeBron James Green.
Just make sure that they're the same.
So that we get the same results then Carmelo Anthony blude Dwight Howard Mike Jantar Chris Bosh black
Chris Paul red.
Kevin Durant green Derrick Rose blude Dwayne Wade magenta.
All right so there we go that's the result.
Let's get rid of this of this information or here.
Yeah let's get rid of it.
For now we can always return when we need to.
So let's run this line shift enter.
And now let's run this line and let's see what it looks like.
All right.
We've just created the dictionary we haven't used the dictionary so let's go ahead and use a dictionary
here instead of the color.
We're going to say we're going to look up the color in the dictionary.
So I'm gonna say dictionary and then look up based on the name.
So every time a new name is passed that name is used to look up the color from the dictionary.
So for now press shift enter shift enter here.
You'll see that while everything is looking much better so now we can tell which players which by their
color Kobe Bryant the brown James they're across.
Awesome.
So the only thing is that we know that some of these colors or every couple of colors actually used
twice.
Right.
So once we have players with the same color that's going to be confusing.
So how can where else do we need to do we obviously need to fix up the markers as a small challenge
.
I invite you to pose this video and try do that on your own.
It's exactly the same process as we did with colors so try posing the video and fixing up the markers
and then unpause the video on.
Now I'm going to do that so we can do this advanced function design element together.
All right so we're going to create this picture.
Well basically we're just going to copy this and we're going to say let's call it MRK for marker.
And now we're going to go back here again.
I will just copy this code like that.
And that will allow us to put in the correct markers for every player.
Right so s goes here.
Here s then oh then the hat sign then D has a couple more.
It's only six left s.
Then they start cycling again o hat and D.
And then again S and O.
All right.
So let's check that check that we got the same result.
So Kobe Bryant s Joe Johnson all the brawne James the hat come or Mella Anthony D capital D Dwight Howard
s Chris Bosh O Chris Paul the hat Kevin Durant d capital D Derrick Rose s Dwayne Wade.
Oh all right.
So hopefully you got that resolved as well.
And now how do we look it up.
We've got two marker instead of s here we just say marker and then we'll just say they like that.
So now we can get rid of this code simply at the top.
Again we are on this and we run this line again.
You'll see that the markers have been fixed up as well as President of the Rander crows both have squares
so we can actually add more in here.
And by the way it doesn't matter in which order you add them so I can add Joe Johnson who usually on
number on spot two I can add him here.
Doesn't matter because it all fits into our algorithm anyway properly.
And the plot look exactly the same as previously can see Joe Johnson was always red and with circles
again Joe Johnson red circles only difference is that now he's at the bottom of the legend but that's
the only difference to that other shot.
So there we go.
Now we have a fully working function my plot which accepts parameters and can build some players.
The only thing that we have left to do if this function is we need to specify the fix up the input so
we obviously need to allow the function to accept an input except that the matrix that we're going to
be looking at as an input right.
And that's very easy to do.
All we have to do is let's just take this again and we'll say here fix up the inputs.
So what we want to do is we want to add the Matrix and we're going to be looking at.
And so we'll say we'll call it Dora.
And now we want every time we specify so let's copy this.
We're just going to add a new line here before running that one.
So I'm going to remove Joe Johnson for now this is.
These are the players.
But also I want to say which matrix I want to look at so maybe I won't say I don't want to look at game
for now maybe I want to look at points.
So I want to ask people to say points and then I want to then only look at the players in that matrix
so here points is going to be positive data and the list of players is going to be passed to the player
list.
So therefore Dhara has to go and replace games.
Right.
So now I know that this is the matrix I want to look at.
Why are we looking at data why are we looking at games if it should be done.
So it's as simple as that is simple substitution so points will go here.
And then from here it also will be passed on to the function and from here it will go into the body
of the function albis be replaced here.
So if I if I say games here are games over here and then or your place here.
So if I were on this line then around this line you'll see that.
Now I've got the points visualized or I can say celery.
Simple as that.
So now I just rerun this line.
You can see now I've got that salary visualization that we talked about before.
And one last thing that we're going to do here before this function is fully ready and this and other
advanced function design element is we going to say player list because players.
What does that do.
Well players as we know is just a list of players.
If I just run players here.
So it's basically just a list of all of the players.
And what we're doing here is we're specifying a default value for the function.
So if I don't pass a list of players if I just say something like that if I just say salary and I don't
pass the actual list of players what'll happen is all I have to first of course are rerun my function
.
Now if I run this you will see that the salary for all of the players is specified.
So those are very two simple adjustments.
So basically we added the matrix that we want to look at and then replace it here.
And also we were added a default parameter.
So you know how in Python some functions have defined parameters.
Well now our very own function also has a different parameter.
And what we're doing here is we're saying if the player list is not passed to the function then by default
take all of the players with the same effect you could specify certain players here you could say just
LeBron James or specify your own list of players here interest in square brackets you could say let's
say for instance only visualize Joe Johns.
Right.
So in that case if I run this line and on this you don't pass the salary or the names of the players
then only Joe Johnson by default is visualized.
If you do pass the list of players you should say Kobe Bryant and LeBron James then they will be visualized
.
Right.
So again we're going to replace his back with players.
So every time the list of players is not passed the function then all of the players will be visualized
for that specific matrix that we're looking at.
All right.
Make sure to your on lines.
And there we go.
This is all ready.
I'm just going to add Derrick Rose back in here.
The function is ready to go.
And we are ready to proceed with the insights.
It's going to be a fun process exploring inside and looking for patterns and anomalies.
Can't wait to get started on that tutorial and play around with this for now.
Just make sure that everything is that we've covered.
Makes total sense because from here we going to focus on the analytic side of things.
We're pretty much done with the coding for this part of the Course code.
See you next time.
Until then decoding