Welcome at the another episode of our Spring Boot Full Stack course.
In this section we take a look at a way how to receive email in our application.
We are not talking about sending email here.
We are talking about receiving email from the outer world into our system.
We are working on in Java specifically using a springboard web framework or entire environment.
In the real systems, we usually interact with email system in some way.
We usually send emails from our application outside, but we usually also need a way how to be able
to receive emails from the outer world and to be able to process those interact with the outside world
world.
That way we have a several options commonly used here.
The first one is using existing email system, using existing mailbox and communicating using standard
protocols like IMAP or pop free.
On the Java client side, we have several IMAP or POP3 client libraries we can use here.
We can fetch such emails on scheduled basis using an inbuilt spring scheduler.
For example, processing emails or fetching emails dead way usually means there is a small, smaller
or longer delay in processing emails.
Everything is completely on the on the ground and we have to set up some interaction with the user being
able to see email that just sent to our into our system.
Another common option is using a webhook like communication.
This kind of communication is more a push based approach to fetching emails using IMAP Free, which
is kind of pool based communication.
There are several email systems that are able to take incoming email and post that email.
Using a web hooks means a special URL or endpoint we are creating in our application and post all.
Email related information like a subject, body
images, attachments into end point in our application, and then we can do further processing as required
by application itself.
The web hooks available availability is not a wide and it's usually not used in real system at all.
In the third option, and not probably the least one, but this is the one we are supposed to focus
on in discourse is using or creating or running a small and by that snap server directly inside application
means when our application starts up running web server inside of or if we are running our application
as or package inside, for example, Apache Tomcat that the embedded S&amp;P server is starting as a part
of our application and listening for incoming requests.
And that way we are able to process or communicate with email.
Clients or alter email systems receive email immediately processed or even.
To not possess such email, depend on some kind of rules and present such process email immediately
to the user.
So it's a very efficient way.
Also dead way.
We are a bit independent on the on the altar email system, but we don't require email system on for
example, on the customer side, no interaction with the email system and dead way.
We are completely standalone and our application can do exactly what is supposed to do in in that manner.