Guiterrez is important part of Mongo database great of as is specification for storing and retrieving
files that exceed a size limit of 60 megabytes.
We usually we usually store attachments or a file uploads directly into file system or some abstraction
over the file system.
Great.
As is the way how to store such files in mongo database directly and to storing files into database
in general is not recommended, but a great Avaz is a very special feature of Mongo database that is
specifically focused for that purpose.
There is a few use cases or not few, maybe even many use cases when great FS is much better solution
for storing files compared to file systems and so on.
We can store a bunch of small files, we can save really huge files into Great Avaz and we can use a
different MongoDB features, features like sharding to work with the data.
What's even important, we can store a metadata together with files saved in grid avast.
So not just the files and basic data like a file name or size are going to be saved.
But we can save metadata of any kind and it usually very good and reflects specifics of our applications.
This is also the reason why we are going to include grid of apps in that course.
Spring Boot has very good support for MongoDB and Grid Avast included, so it's very easy to enhance
existing or new application and include the support we need.
We can look at our basic application.
We have a Maven configuration here.
We can see we use version 2.7, but greater fast support is included even in a 1.5 version of spring
boot.
So we can use a legacy application.
The only dependency we need is to start it's spring boot start data MongoDB dependency.
So if we use that, we have a grid of full support and in our application we are adding a few more packages.
But this is very minimal application so there is not too much dependency and you can see how easily
storing files in grid of apps in MongoDB can be done in spring boot application like we have.