Okay.
So now to connect the dots, we are going to create controller part so we can actually call something
from the browser.
In the controller, we are going to use things we just created.
I mean this PDF Generator service and it's create PDF method.
So let's create a new class name at PDF Controller.
We are adding a few annotations.
Here we are at controller so we are defining this is really controller and we are adding request to
mapping with the path that we are going to use in a browser to to call that controller.
So we have a slash p.
We are going to add this idea of generator service.
We use that at all to our annotation so we can use it and and endpoints implementations.
And now to add endpoint implementation, we create a new method.
We have some mandatory things for providing dynamic output from the controller.
So we use this response entity class and we provide some details of the type of the response.
So let's choose the correct implementation.
This is the resource that we are going to return to the browser and this resource contains everything
for that dynamic file we are creating using a PDF Generator service.
This create PDF is actually the the end point definition.
So we use that at getting at get mapping annotation and we use a title as a request param.
So let's add annotation and define that this is not required and we can define some default value when
for situation when this param is missing.
So let's add the default title text into the PDF.
So we have that method signature and we need to create the pdf.
We use this pdf generator service create PDF method, we call it create PDF method with the title information.
So now we are creating a PDF variable as byte array output stream.
So at that point or a deadline, we have a PDF object created containing the actual PDF file, and now
we have to return that byte array output stream in some way to the browser, so browser can recognize
that as a file download.
So we use that response entity object who we call OC defining a status information.
For the browser we defined, we define a few headers saying that this is attachment or kind of in-line
content.
So we, we, we are using even a file name defining how the, how the file should look like in the browser.
So we have this HTTP headers helper class helper class with content disposition variable here.
So we have that header information and now we, we are just sending a body and the body for the body.
We are wrapping this byte resource and we take the PDF and we convert that PDF byte array output stream
actually to bind array itself.
So everything is green, there are no errors in the code.
We can also define content type.
So you can see we have a few more things to be added.
So we define this as kind of media type and we specify
type related to file download just to listing options available, we can see a bunch of media types
for different purposes.
In our case, we need to something related to file download, so we just provide information called
application octet stream.
This is just saying we are providing a file back to the browser so browser can behave properly in that
case.
So to sum up, we have that, okay, saying everything is fine as a status back to the browser, we
are defining a content type saying file is coming.
We set some header and that's actually all.
So we can start the application and see if everything runs without any error.
So let's see if application starts correctly.
We can't see any errors in the ID, so hopefully completion will be fine.
So let's just open the browser and call the end point and we use the slash p, you are L and we have
some bug here.
And yeah, it's this HTML tag we used in HTML is not closed and this is something related to time leave.
Time level requires all attacks being closed.
So we use this metal tag so we have to use slash and just to close the TAC, just to reload into browser
and we can see something is running.
So PDF was created and download it and we try to open that.
And yes, we can see a very simple PDF with the with the default title and the time timestamp inside.
So code is running correctly.
A PDF file is created on fly based on input information and to HTML we created, which is quite simple
at that point translates input value and input values like a title and timestamp into proper texts.
And all this stuff is being translated from the HTML to PDF.
Using a library we are using as a dependency and you can see in the browser we have that nice pdf created
and served dynamically.
So it's not a static PDF, it's it's a dynamically created.
And we can define even a title using request query string parameter.
So let's add that option to to the URL and we can see the PDF created contains a custom our custom title.
We provide it in a URL.
So it's really working.
It's quite dynamic and very easy to use and we can just work on that.