Okay.
So let's start with simple message listener implementation.
So it's a core part of our implementation.
This is a service or class that will implement, accepting and email delivery.
So let's create some infrastructure in our application source code.
We create some default packages.
We have a mailer and service package, and now we create a simple mail listener implementation.
So let's name it.
Simple message listener.
Simple.
We we need to.
Implement the interface.
The interface is coming from the one of our dependencies.
So we have this simple message listener.
Interface we are going to implement here.
So just to avoid any confusion.
Now the idea show us shows that we need to implement.
Actually two methods.
So we have a two method methods here.
We have a accept and deliver.
The first one.
The exit method is just for making decision whether we accept the incoming message or we are rejecting
that.
So we return a true or false.
So when we return, a true message is accepted.
This accept method has a two parameters.
We have a from and recipient information so we can reuse those for making a decision whether we accept
it or not.
The same parameters are going to the second method named deliver.
Deliver method has also the from end recipient information coming into and we have input stream data
structure containing the entire email structure.
I just tried to say body, but it's not the body itself, it's our email.
As such, we switch the accept return value to choose, so we don't have any specific logic for accepting
email right now.
And it's okay for testing purposes.
And if we need anything else and we have that to deliver method here, we can also reuse this from recipient
information directly and then we have to decode that input stream data and just to pass those data as
an email data structure.
So we know that from a recipient directly and then we have to decode that.
So basically that's all we need to accept email specifically, we need to or we can specify some kind
of logic here based on those from and recipient information.
We don't have anything else here because we are just rejecting email as such if needed.
And then we have the deliver method that is doing actually the email processing so we can add some lodging
here.
So we use a Lombok logging infrastructure, we're using that annotation and then we do use some a log
information writing to console.
So when we start an application and send email into, we can see a LOC message coming to the console
so we can just reuse the from and recipient informations here and display those on the console so we
can just check that everything is working without any detailed code right now.
So that's all.
That's all.
It's quite simple here and we will continue in the next lecture.