To continue with the weather implementation, we create a new endpoint that will actually serve our
dynamically generated Excel file.
So we create a new class.
Let's name it an Excel controller.
We asked a few annotations here from the Springboard Add controller and we also assign a path or address
we use in URL and now we re use our Excel generator service its manage being so we can alter wire this
class into our controller.
And until now we can create a real endpoint that that will serve Excel file we are creating with our
service.
So we create an endpoint.
The signature will reply with a response entity.
And too, we can just get the war book.
As we said in previous lectures, the word book is actually the Excel file.
So we create a workbook variable we call the Excel, generate the service with the method we just created
in previous lecture, and we can take that workbook and just reply or send it back to browser so we
can use this response entity object to.
We choose this OC as a.
As a status quo status quo representation, we specify a content type as our application octet stream.
We set header defining that we are providing a kind of attachment or a file as a response.
So we specify a content disposition.
You can see we are using the HTTP headers helper class with predefined different header names and we
can specify the value as inline and we have to specify a file name being sent back to the browser.
So let's just call it an excel.
And now we have to define actual the content of the response.
So we defined a call method body and we sent the information from the workbook book who we just created.
So we have the workbook created as the first line of that end point representation.
And we use we just return and say Let's.
Create a body from the workbook book information.
We just specify more the return values streaming response body.
So everything is green now.
No issues, no errors.
We just have to add also a map.
Get mapping information.
So this Excel method now is understood by Springwood as an endpoint definition.
So let's just try to start the application and see if everything is running correctly without any issues
and application starts as we supposed to.
As we could see, we created a request mapping for the controller with slash e u r l.
So this is something we use in the browser just to access our method, our endpoint.
So let's use this localhost to switch to use flash e endpoint and we can see there is a Excel file,
provide it and we can open the file in the library office and now we can see the sheet one at the bottom
and we have the first cell on the first line and first column with the name for a cell volume, exactly
as we defined in our code.
So we have that endpoint, we have the helper service created.
You can see we have a just a not too much code and we are able to create a fully featured Excel file
and that is very easy to serve.
And the only dependency we use this dependency on the Apache po po i library and implementation is quite
straightforward and can be updated and enhanced as we are going to do so in next lectures.