As mentioned earlier, we rely on HTML two PDF Translation and PDF can contain different tasks and different
formatting.
Even CSS can be used to for doing formatting that will be translated into PDF properly.
So we can take a few approaches here.
We can define the style attribute at each attack, so we can define kind of formatting, like adding
a border with a color, using some kind padding, using margin, define just some space on the on the
screen.
We can just refresh our project so we can just reload a browser page and can see what happened.
And we can see really the line which is a rat left to right.
We can see some margin above that line.
So formatting is actually okay and follows what we have done in.
Uh, in HTML to test things.
It's very easy to do because we use spring boot def tools and we can just reload things to speed up
things and just to rely on something existing.
We can include bootstrap CSS.
It's well known and used in HTML quite often and this formatting stylesheet can be used even for that
HTML two pdf.
So we can just reference that CSS as we can see from the website.
So on the website there is a link for a hosted version and we can then add some some HTML in classes.
So we can just use that alert block and reference classes that are defined in a bootstrap.
So let's take the title and add the the class definition into the div tack.
So we have the diff, we can just move it to span just to B to see how it is applied.
So we have a diff with the title inside.
We just refresh the project and we should see some formatting based on bootstrap CSS.
So just let's refresh that in the browser, save the PDF and open once again.
And what we can see.
Yeah, really, we see this is the green box we have.
We have the title inside and the formatting is just coming from this bootstrap definition so we can
reuse the existing CSV as if there is some stylesheet provided but by different team people.
Or we can use kind of corporate style sheets here.
So we have a few options how to define the HTML and how to do formatting CSS, CSR as reference to embedded
directly into HTML.
Or we can use a style attribute at the tag level.
So it's very easy to format and to use.