In this lecture, we start creating a way how to embed images into PDF.
The way of the support of embedding images in PDF is to put image into HTML in base 6 to 4 format.
So we don't reference image directly, but we embed the image as encoded text in base 6 to 4 format.
That way we can use render to render image directly as the image in PDF.
To do so, we create a kind of utility class for that purpose.
So and to using that class, we can we will be able to convert it to images stored in the disk into
base 64.
We have a full implementation here right now because it's not directly the core of this course.
So we we are using a libraries to do so.
We convert it to we can convert the image to base 64 using those two methods directly into PNG or to
format we we specify we take a reference to image storage and data source inside of our project so we
can put image into our project.
We can reference the the image specify image format and we can embed or create data format attack.
That will reference the image in image TAC in HTML.
We have a few way how to do it.
We can use Default Java Base 64 and coder for that purpose.
It's probably most straightforward way to do so and to we can just reference an image and do proper
conversion.
We can take the image we just created.
We create a helpful directory for us in that templates, PDF Subfolder so we can create something where
we can embed the image.
So let's create a images folder here and we can just paste predefined image here.
Just take a look how the image looks like.
Yeah, this is my custom image and we reference that image and in during the conversion.
So yeah, we have a templates, pdfs, images, image one dot PNG.
This is a full path where we reference to image.
And that's that's the first step we need to do.
We need to we need to make a conversion.
So in the HTML we can create an image tag and we can reference the image using a time leave syntax like
a
source and we reference something called image one.
And this image one should be a part of the context we provide for time leave.
So this will be part of the for the implementation.