In this last lecture describing ways of using or creating Excel files on fly in our applications, we
we try to implement the way how to embed to images into Excel sheets.
We have to create some infrastructure code, something that we can use to embed the image we have already
uploaded in our projects directly in the sheet.
So we create sheets.
We use this Excel, generate, generate the service we created already and we created embed image method.
We have the way or method signature defines a way how to specify image path.
We provide a workbook and sheets information so we can just put the image directly in the place.
And now we have to handle the image itself.
We put images into resources folder of our projects.
We have to convert image to array of bytes.
We have to add image to the workbook.
We get a picture index, something that describes our image.
We do some other handling for the working of images in the workbook.
So we basically we add image to the workbook as such.
And then we have to place such image inside the sheet so we can have a.
A lot of images in the world book and we have placed the image at the correct position on the particular
sheet.
So for that purpose we have this great picture method.
We specify a position and we specify a picture index.
This is just a kind of variable describing our picture in the book.
So just putting all those things together help us to place the image we we have into the sheet.
We can use that method for placing any kind of images on the sheet.
For our purposes, we we are going to use a PNG file, but we can use a JPEG for example as well.
And to having that embed image method, we have to just call it in a in a method when we create Excel
file so we specify the path or image name, we can even specify a full path if needed.
So we specify a PNG image name.
We provide a workbook and sheets variables to our method.
And now we also have to upload the image we would like to display.
We don't have any image yet, so let's just pays the image into the new images folder.
So we have just image one BMG right here.
And this is the one we are referencing and this is the image we are going to see an Excel file.
So let's restart our application and see that everything is working as expected.
And till we can again access the end point we created for that purpose and open the file that's been
updated.
We can see the text format.
It still remains the same and we can see actually the image we embedded into Excel file.
We have we have that anchor that's just position image on the sheet.
And the same way we can embed many images on the same sheet or we can use a different sheets for place
of images as we are requested.
We can now take a quick look to picture types being supported.
We use a PNG file, but we can use the JPEG or some other formats as supported by the library.
So it's very easy to switch to something more friendly to your project easily, and that's actually
all we need to provide or embed the images into Excel file.
Just implementation.
I think it's quite straightforward and easy to understand and this is important for us.