So we have the back end party operations in place.
We just created a very useful method for listing files, finding one file by ID.
So listing files we used that method for providing items attribute for our HTML and we put that information
in HTML itself.
So we create a section area and for a listing of the all files uploaded in grid of S.
So we have that kind of HTML.
It's a bigger one.
We have a header here, uploaded files list.
We have a table for providing a list of files.
We have a header like a file name ID and we implement a download link and link for deleting a file.
And then we have table structure for listing all items.
So we are referencing items from the modal attribute.
So we have time syntax here for, for going through the list of items here and each item is put into
the item variable so we can reference the variable in inside HTML.
So we have that file name, we have an object ID here listed on the screen.
And we provide a link for downloading and for deleting file from grade of s.
So we for both matters for download and delete, we provide an ID and in time leave so we can find out
the file in the back end and do actual work.
So we have some files in grade of as you can refresh that, we can see we have two files we just uploaded
in previous lectures, so we should see those files on the screen actually.
So let's start in application and see if everything is correct and in place.
Uh, so on the screen with the new file upload, we should see at the bottom the section we have the
list of grade of s or file uploads available.
So let's see it on the in the browser.
So we have that first part we already created for submitting a file and we can see the second part.
This is uploaded files list and we can see just two files we created in previous lectures and we can
see the links available for us and we need to implement in our back end code mainly in controller.
So it doesn't work yet.
So we can see the error message, the link doesn't exist, we actually don't have any points for those
links.
So let's create those end points in controller.
So we are switching back into our Java code and to create an endpoint for.
Downloading the we created a new method here for downloading a particular file.
So again, we defined a method which is actually public because we need to call that from the browser.
We can specify a return time as void for now, and we can see how that evolves in the implementation.
So let's name it download file here and of course through through the link we provide ID of that file.
So we have to specify ID here.
An implementation and idea is kind of a request param with the same name.
And of course we have to annotated in point that it actually become an endpoint with the get mapping.
And we specify you are done download.
So we created a mapping with a slash download and this is the same as we have in that endpoint definition.
So we have a download URL for that endpoint and we provide the ID here.
So in the download Mountain File method, we need to find the file and to create a response like object.
So we use the following kind of definition.
We have to fix some changes here.
We we have attachment service.
Just let's fix a small typo here and.
We have the full implementation here which actually returns file download object properly defined as
needed for springboard.
So we have attachment service.
We are filing one grid as file item based on ID.
This is the method we just created.
We are checking if this object is not null and if that object is available, we create a set of headers
required for file download the important one.
One is that content disposition and we say this is kind of attachment and we define the file name here
coming from grade of S.
So we have that as of file item here object and we can get a file name from it.
So we had Heather's object and we used it.
Heather object for creating a response entity.
And we can see response entities using grid as template.
We don't we haven't used that object yet.
And so manage being provided by springboard data so we can just inject or or to wire that object in
our controller.
So we have that grid template available for us.
And that object provide a useful, useful method for returning a resource like object for item we found
in grid of S database.
So we have that response entity created and of course we have to fix response type for our download
file method.
Just to reflect to what we are actually replying with.
So we have this response and the object created with all the headers defining define defining file size
and content type and providing a body as a resource coming from grid of s.
And this is actually the right way.
How to provide a file download to the browser.
So we use spring springboard structures here and I think everything is in place.
If we don't find an item in the database, we provide a not found information back in the browser.
This is also the correct way how to how to do it and but if the file is available so we can simply serve
it to the browser.
And that's that's actually all we so we have the download and put and create it we have that okay and
not found defined for both situation and we have the link in timely template.
So we have the link to the download.
So let's restart our application and refresh the application in the browser and we can see we have download
buttons here and we can click and of course the file is available here and we can see the file is downloaded
correctly and we can see the file in the in the image browser here.
Yeah.
So things seems to be working just fine and our download button is active on the screen.
Now just to complete a picture, we have that delete button on the screen as well, so it's still not
available and need to be implemented.
So we can just follow this the same way as we have down for file download.
Of course the operation is a bit different, so we need to create a delete.
End point definitions.
So let's name it the lead again.
We are supposed to provide an idea of that grade of object.
So we define request, parameter and notation again.
And.
We defined that endpoint using a gap mapping.
This is not the best way how to do it, actually, but let's keep it for simplicity.
So we name it, delete that endpoint and we return redirect to our slash a screen.
So the actual logic is click on the delete, we delete the file and we present the screen again.
The list should be updated and delete file should not be listed among other files on the screen, and
we can provide some information for the user.
So we have those redirect attributes structure we use already.
So we.
I can't add information back to the user.
So we have attachment service, delete, delete, file.
This is the method we created.
We provide ID here and will we delete the file using grid of s operations?
Operations has that delete method to be defined criteria here and we call it from the controller itself.
And then when operation is successful, we add that information into a flash or redirect attributes.
So let's add a flash attribute with the name message we already have handler for the message objects
on the screen.
So we just re-use it and we say file delete it from the database or from grid of ASP, which is actually
Mongo database.
So we have that on the screen.
So we have that section.
If a message is available, it shows up on the screen so it can create a complete picture for us.
We have filed delete defined here and it's very easy operation just two or three lines of the code and
we have data link saying delete with ID we just re-use and at end point.
So we delete file or we add a flash attribute and we redirect back to the screen.
We have the list of items, so let's restart the application and see if everything is in place and working
for us correctly.
So we have that.
Let's click on delete.
So we have a to actually to.
Items in the grid have as we can see those items on the screen, we have a delete button so we can delete
the first file and file has been deleted.
So we have that information in the message section and the file is now missing in the list.
So we have only one file in the list right now and we can check that in MongoDB.
We can refresh the collection with F FS files and we can see only one file here available.
So the file has been deleted from the database itself and it's reflected in the browser.
So list contains one file now, so we can upload the file again.
We can see the entire application is working.
We can download that file, we can delete that file and everything is in.
Please.
So the entire code is quite straightforward.
We just maintain attachment controller here.
We have a bunch of end points created, but it just follows the logic we use.
We are listing the files on the screen, we are processing for uploads.
We are providing a download or delete operations from the browser.
So we created endpoints for each operation and we created the implementation using attachment service.
So we just following a logic we are doing, we are listing files, uploading files, we are downloading
or deleting files.
It's like a basic craft base operations for maintaining a full logic and we still have one HTML and
we keep all the things together.
And in the browser, it's just a very simple layout showing up all the files and operations we we define.