In this lecture we are going to finish implementation of embedding image in PDF.
We prepared image utility class.
We created a TAC into HTML template.
And then now we need to specify the image one context variable and specify the way how the variable
is being represented.
So we here in render HTML for PDF, we add a new context variable named image one as we reference and
we call our image utils convert image to base 64 and we have to mention or reference image itself.
We we passed image into PDF images under the image one dot PNG name.
So we just reference this name as a part of converting image to Base64 method.
And this is actually all this is the part we we need to use.
We have this create PDF already available so we can run the project and see if everything fits together
and the entire implementation and implementation is correct.
So let's see if application is running.
We can again call controller method and we can just store it and open the PDF.
We just create it.
So let's see how the.
How the test file looks like and we can see our HTML converted to PDF and we can see the image being
embedded into the PDF the same way as we could see in the resources part.
So this is quite straightforward way how to embed the image into PDF.
We just need to take the image static one of or generate generated one and we have to just convert the
image into base 64.
This is a very easy way how to do so for many different image sources and just show up image in PDF
easily.