In the first lecture on this great topic, we mentioned a few advantages when using grade FS for storing
files.
One of those is using a kind of metadata.
We mentioned that metadata is a map like objects.
We specify each metadata with the key and the content actually can be almost anything.
It can be a string number or array or information.
And this way we can store metadata together with the file itself.
So it's very easy to to add some application specific.
Logic and to when we go to a MongoDB UI, we can see one greater as object and we can see a metadata
section and object data and we can see as well the name, size, image type information, the metadata.
We actually provide it in our implementation.
So it's stored in a in one record with the file.
And when we are retrieving the single file or a list of files, we have that information available for
us to to present to the browser to make it available to the user.
And we can use that information to filter items from the database so we can use it for a kind of access
control definition, for example.
So grid of assets, there is a there is many advantages we can use.
There is a very nice documentation on the MongoDB website and spring data implementation covers all
the features and this is first class implementation for the MongoDB usage.
Great advice and great advice include it.
So I really encourage you to use it.
It's very easy to handle if I uploads in your application and manage that for a long time.