In this lecture, we are going to add support for embedding barcodes into PDF.
It's a very the same way as embedding images in PDF as barcode is image as such, but instead of using
a static image already created, we have to create that barcode image on the fly.
So we use a few libraries from the Google for that purposes.
We have the support for different barcode flavors and we use those libraries for creating
barcodes.
Resources.
So let's create a barcode service.
And to create some implementation.
We first one is creating a method for getting a barcode or creating a barcode from the text string.
And we use also kind of a helper method for converting a barcode to basis 64.
For the conversion, we use Google based dependency library for converting to a specific barcode we
use for our PDF file,
creating a barcode to contain the different options here, even for different barcode types.
So it's not the core of this course.
So we can just skip it with a basic implementation.
Using Code 128 type, we specify a text, we specify a type of the barcode and some other stuff that
is required and can be found and in library documentation.
Then we create a binary output stream very similar way as we use with static files and we do a conversion
of the barcode into a JPG image.
So at the end of of this method, we can get a barcode and type of byte array, PNG data format, then
we have to convert that to data into base 64 in the very same way as we have done for a static image.
So we can create even a helper function here that can do it for us.
Let's see.
And then we have to of course add that barcode into context variables.
So we have that context object, we create a new line, we can name it barcode one, barcode one, and
we can call a barcode service and get barcode as base 64 with the invoice number information.
So the text we would like to convert into base into barcode is mentioned as a method parameter.
So we just call that.
And we are getting back PNG image converted into base 64
the same way as we have down for static image.
We have to create a HTML tac to make that barcode visible in HTML and then that HTML will be converted
into a PDF the same way as we have done for image.
So let's copy paste the image tag.
But to just use a barcode, one variable name, this is the name we've done or we used in this context
variable.
So we have that context variable and.
Now everything is in place, and we should just try it.
Just reload our endpoint, save and open the file.
And something is wrong here.
So let's just recompile.
HTML.
This is something we have to think about that.
And if something is not visible, usually it means we didn't refresh something in our application.
So we refresh the template and we can see the barcode is inside the PDF under the image we re provided
previously.
So it's very easy way how to embed a barcode.
You can use different types of barcodes.
We can position that on the in the pdf the same way as we position something in HTML.
So it's very easy and we basically don't need to learn some PDF related language for formatting output.
We just need to know come on HTML and we are good to go.