In this last chapter on processing income incoming emails topic we are going to show up how to take
email that we are just processed and how to save that email into the database so we can provide some
kind of persistency for our purposes.
We get we are going to use a MongoDB.
We we can use some configuration options coming into application properties.
We defined a host port and database name.
We can just check that in MAVEN configuration, we have that MongoDB dependency all included already.
So this is actually everything we need in springboard application to use MongoDB.
So we use that springboard start starter data MongoDB and using the configuration and application properties,
we just provide it.
It's basically the minimum configuration we need Springwood to be able to talk to, to MongoDB or to
database
in our application.
So that's all from the configuration side.
I think everything is in place dependencies there already so we can start with some details of implementation.
We need just a few things to be able to save that information into the database.
First one is something called entity.
It's actually the email data structure that we just fill up with the information coming from from a
mail client.
So we create a new package called Modal.
And we can create a new class.
We can name it an email just to follow the logic.
We add some annotations here.
We add annotation document saying This is saying that this is a MongoDB document.
We add at data annotation, it's a Lombok support, so we can just create a properties without defining
getters, setters and so on.
So we are just adding a few properties that we are going to save into database.
We have a from subject and body and that's enough for our example.
And also of course because we are storing information into database, we need some identifier.
So we create this ID as a string and use that at ID annotation, which is also spring data related annotation
and default implementation.
Actually assign ID when our model or entity is being saved into the database.
So we have a modal and we also need something called repo or repository.
So we create a email related repo name ID, email repository we extend.
Uh, some pre-existing
implementations or interfaces.
We have a great repository.
We say we are working with email and ID is type of string.
So in that way this is just something very minimum.
We don't need anything else.
If we don't need any specific method to be called, we just need to save something so that's enough.
And now we just need to add that repo into simple message listener implementation.
So we add repo property here.
We create a constructor that will use this object as parameters so we can just assign it to when a simple
message listener is being created.
So we have that in the place and we just simply fix that problem here in parent class.
So we have that managed service, simple sort of service.
We add this repo as well, we market as auto wire, so it's been injected by spring boot when our service
is being constructed.
And we add this to that, we are adding that parameter to simple message listener implementation.
So constructor is used and at that point we have this repo in the code.
And we can use it in delivery method right after this received email is created.
So we created our emails.
Data structure is the one being saved into MongoDB, so we create a new email instance.
We set a few properties we created, so we set a subject coming from email subject we can set from information
and we can also set body information.
Coming from the data structure, setting a body means extracting correct value from a list of messages
so we can take a look at that email object.
Just fixing a typo email.
We have a.
My list of messages.
It's actually a list of email message data structures.
So we can just pick one from the list.
We can just pick a first one, and then we have to read content.
So we, we, we get canned content which is just returning a string body representation and then we
have a repo we can call just save.
We have the variable of that email we just created so we can see we created an email set the few options
here subject from a body and we call a repo method.
Save the save method is default one coming from the default implementation.
We just we just enhanced by creating our own repo for emails.
We can start that application in the back mode the same way as we did in previous lectures.
So we can send an email to our application and we can go through the breakpoints and see how things
are.
Do work like we are through reviewing where the MongoDB is running on our system.
So we have a hostname and port.
We are using a robo client for getting information from MongoDB.
So this is how applications started.
It's connected to MongoDB.
Running locally in MongoDB installation is out of the scope of this lecture, but just so part of prerequisites
we need to use.
So we use
Thunderbird client for sending an email so we can see we can type, recipient, subject and body whatever
we want and we send that message.
And now for us the voucher is activated so we can see we are at the point of the saving information
into the database.
We can see the ID is now because it's not saved yet.
We set or populated all the fields required to be saved and we can then continue.
We can see the item or repo method save is being called so we can just review a database, we can see
collection email and we can see also one item available in that collection and we can see the values
being set and saved correctly.
We can see from and subject and body information coming from our Thunderbird client.
So we can see a full featured solution from the beginning to the end too.
We started with a simple, simple message implementation.
We we were building upon that creating a SMTP server.
We added several options needed for running SMTP server locally.
We check that our implementation is actually working fine.
We and at the end we we saved incoming email into database using MongoDB using a mode.
MongoDB is just straightforward, no need for data migrations.
We just save information as it is.
So it's very easy to to be used.
And if there are any attachments in emails, we can use a grid fs of MongoDB storing files right into
the database, which is quite fine and fully supported by MongoDB.
To use a MongoDB is also very easy.
We just implemented modal or entity email.
We created a repo for saving or working with those entities.
The implementation is very easy.
We just create an interface and spring data is creating this email repo for us as a managed being so
it can be auto wired.
So we are auto wiring that repo directly into a SMTP server.
We just send it down to simple message listener and uh, this simple message listener has been enhanced.
And to when email is being processed, we just create our email data structure.
This is the data structure related to email collection in MongoDB.
We set several fields.
We just created subject matter from and body and we save it using the repo.
And if everything is in place, MongoDB is running and the port and hosting configurations are fine.
We can see that the email is actually being stored into database and this is a step we just added to.
We have actually a full feature solution here.
Yeah.
So you can if you need to read emails or process emails directly in application, you can just
use that implementation and add that into even a legacy application.
As I mentioned at the beginning, the solution is running in production since spring boot version 1.5.
So the compatibility is quite good.
And from the beginning to the end we can see email message is accepted, delivered or processed and
saved into into database.