The last thing we are going to look at is the way how to support using a different fonts in PDF output.
To use a different fonts, we can download the fonts in two type of format.
We have this free library sans font available and downloaded and stored inside resources folder and
to.
We can reference that to type fonts in the create pdf it's method.
So we use we set u r l resource pointing to those two fonts and then we use those two URLs for the render
specification.
So let's just enhance our configuration.
We use this render get font resource resolver and we at each font into the renderer the same way.
So we have those two URLs, first one and second one, we add those fonts.
So Render is able to recognise fonts being used by name.
And then of course we have to bind this together with each HTML we use for creating a PDF.
So we have to go to our HTML template and we have to specify font family the way we basically use for
HTML pages.
So we create a body style information and we can specify font family that fits the name of tru type
font we we are using.
Then when we create a PDF, the font being used as the one we reference in HTML in this very easy way.