With the PatientEntity type in place, I can now implement an item processor.
Note again that I'm defining the processor as a Bean and annotating it with
StepScope in case I wanted to access the step context.
Unlike the stub implementation, I'm now returning a Java function.
For our simple transformation, this works well; however,
more complex transformations may take a different strategy for processing.
Oftentimes this includes the implementation of chain processing,
which is outside of the scope of this course.
Note that this processor method will return the PatientEntity
instance transformed from the PatientRecord instance.
With the exception of the birthdate,
all fields map directly from the input to the entity.
I've included a transformation of the birthdate as I wanted
to save it as a date type in the database.
Now let's add this item processor to the project.
I'm going to add the new item processor logic to
the BatchJobConfiguration class.
This also requires some clean up of the stub processor,
as well as update of the job step configuration.
Note that I'll be following Demo 16 found in the DEMOS.
md file in the root project directory.
I'm going to implement the full item processor for this demo.
To do this,
I first need to remove the stub implementation and
update the job step configuration.
Open up the BatchJobConfiguration class.
I'm going to scroll down to the existing processor method,
and I'll simply just remove it.
Now I'm going to drop in the updated item processor code to the class.
The item processor simply returns the Java function.
I'm mapping each field of the PatientRecord to a PatientEntity attribute.
For the birthdate,
I've converted it into the format that it's expected by the database.
Now I need to wire the new processor into the job step.
Let's scroll up to that.
I'm going to replace the existing job step Bean with updated code.
I've made a few updates in the step.
First, I'm now passing in the processor as an argument to the method.
I've also updated the chunk call to use the
PatientEntity type in place of PatientRecord.
Finally,
I've updated the processor call to use the processor passed in the method.
Since I've changed the type for PatientRecord to PatientEntity,
I now have to update the writer.
I'm going to scroll down to the writer method now,
and I'm going to replace it with updated code.
I simply switched all references to PatientRecord in
the writer with PatientEntity.
When I execute the job, it will now output the PatientEntity data on write. That completes the demo for creating the item processor.