As I'm going to read data from a FlatFile,
I'll need some type of construct to open the file,
skip the header line, read each line of content using a tokenizer,
then map each data field to a PatientRecord instance attribute.
Luckily,
Spring Batch provides this construct out of the box with a FlatFileItemReader.
Similar to the job and step, I'm going to use a builder for defining this reader.
I'll use the builder to first define the name for the ItemReader.
Then I'll identify the resource for the ItemReader to use.
In this case, it's the path to the file name I'll specify as a JobParameter.
Next,
I'll set the number of lines to skip in the file to one so
that the header row of the file is not read.
Finally,
I'll construct a line mapper to tell the FlatFileItemReader
what strategy to use for converting data from each field into
an attribute on a PatientRecord.
Let's look at the code for this.
Here you see the implementation of a Spring Bean for a FlatFileItemReader.
The reader is annotated with StepScope.
This allows me to inject values from the step context into my code.
Here we see the value annotation is used in front of the
file name input parameter to do just that.
The file name jobParameter will get injected for me at
runtime into the input parameter.
Next, I defined the builder for the FlatFileItemReader.
I defined the name of the ItemReader using a Constant.
I build the PathResource using the input path from
properties and the file name input param.
I set the number of lines to skip to 1.
And finally, I define the lineMapper, which is implemented in a separate method.
Let's look at that code now.
The lineMapper method is another Bean,
which simply tells Spring Batch's file ItemReader which PatientRecord
attribute is mapped to which field in a record.
I use a DefaultLineMapper with a type PatientRecord,
then I use the PatientRecord constructor to read each string from
the FieldSet into a PatientRecord attribute.
Finally, I set the LineTokenizer to a DelimitedLineTokenizer instance.
This uses a comma as the delimiter by default.
Now let's implement reader in the project.
I'm going to demonstrate creating the two methods for the FlatFileItemReader.
Note that I'll be following Demo 11 found in the DEMOS.
md file in the root project directory.
I'm going to implement the FlatFileItemReader now.
This will take each record from the input file and create a
PatientRecord instance from its data.
Open up the class BatchJobConfiguration if you don't already have it opened.
I'm going to drop in the code for the reader now.
You'll notice that there are two compilation errors.
Let's fix the first by updating the Constants class file.
I'm going to open up the Constants class,
and I'm going to drop in the constant for the Item_Reader_Name.
Similar to this step in the job,
this just provides Spring Batch with a name to identify the reader.
Let's open back up the BatchJobConfiguration class.
First, note I've included a StepScope annotation.
This allows me to inject values from the step context.
Next,
note that the file name parameter is the example where I
use a value from the step context, specifically,
the JOB_PARAM_FILE_NAME.
I use a convenience class from Spring Batch for FlatFileItem reading.
The Builder takes a name, the resource is the input file,
a number of lines to skip, which in our case is 1 for the header,
and a lineMapper that I'm going to implement next.
Let's drop that code in.
This is the implementation of the lineMapper to be
used by the FlatFileItemReader.
It just simply maps each field to a PatientRecord attribute using the
PatientRecord constructor that I created earlier.
Finally,
I include a DelimitedLineTokenizer that accepts a
comma as the delimiter by default. This completes the implementation of the FlatFileItemReader.