As this is a course to get you started with Spring Batch,
the primary focus is on the basics of the framework.
As a result of watching the course,
you should understand how to do the following.
You will know how to configure a Spring Batch job.
This includes configuration of both the framework and outside dependencies.
It also includes configuration of the job repository,
job steps, readers, writers, and processors.
You will understand how to implement a Spring Batch job.
You will learn how to construct the various aspects of
the batch job from the framework.
You will know how to implement the reading,
processing, and writing of data for a batch job.
This will be done in the context of a requirement to
load patient data from a file, transferring the data,
and then output the results into a database.
Finally,
you will learn how to implement unit tests that cover the
various aspects of the job including the reading,
processing, and writing of the data.
Again,
the primary focus will be to get you up and running with a
working batch job using the Spring Batch framework.
Given this, let's look at what is outside the scope of this course.
As the goal of this course is to get you started in a short time,
there are several things that I'm not going to cover.
First, Spring and Java knowledge are a requirement for the course.
I won't be going into explanation of how the Java language works
or how aspects of the Spring Framework behave.
If you need to learn more about these topics,
please visit one of the many Pluralsight courses already covered.
I also won't be diving into more advanced Spring Batch
concepts like asynchronous processing, restarts,
and performance considerations.
If you need to know more about these, please visit the documentation on the Spring Batch website.