With the Spring Batch plumbing configured,
including the JobRepository and JobLauncher,
we have everything we need to support creating and executing a job.
I'm going to create a job as a Spring bean in a Configuration class.
Note that I'm adding the JobConfiguration in a new
Configuration class named BatchJobConfiguration.
To create the job, I'll be using Spring Batch's JobBuilderFactory.
The JobBuilderFactory class is a factory for getting a type of builder.
In our case, we're going to use a simple JobBuilder.
There's also a JobFlowBuilder; however,
flows are outside the scope of this course.
The SimpleJobBuilder class then provides a DSL for
defining how the job is constructed.
We're going to use two methods on this builder.
The first will define the starting step of the job,
and the second will perform the actual construction of
a job bean that can be executed.
Here I'm showing the code that will be implemented to return the job bean.
I'm using the JobBuilderFactory to create a job
builder using the name of the batch job.
Note that the JobRepository I defined earlier will
also be configured for the builder.
Next,
a validation check is included for checking the validity of the job parameters.
I'm going to cover that next.
Then the start method is called on the job builder.
This defines the starting step for the job.
I'll define this step a little later, but for now,
I'll just assume it's available and inject it into the method call.
Finally, the build method is called on the JobBuilder to construct the job.
Let's look closer at the validation call I made.
When you start the execution of a job,
you define any number of input parameters you need to support processing.
For the demo, I want to load patient data in batch from a file.
As you know, any number of things could go wrong with this scenario.
The file may not exist, the directory for the file may not exist,
the file may not have the right permissions,
heck, the file may be corrupt.
Spring Batch provides a JobParametersValidator interface where you can
define any validation logic you want for your implementation.
Let's look at the implementation for our demo.
Here's the logic for the validator method.
It returns an implementation of JobParametersValidator.
First, I check to assure the input FILE_NAME parameter is not blank.
If it is, I throw an exception and fail the job execution.
Next,
I check the path and file to assure that they exist
and that the file is readable.
If the file doesn't exist on the server or the file is not readable,
I once again fail the job execution.
As this is a demo, I'm doing the bare minimum; however,
you should expect this validation check to include
several other additional checks.
There's one last piece of code we'll be adding.
Let's cover it briefly.
I'm going to define a JobRegistryBeanPostProcessor.
The goal of the PostProcessor is to register all jobs with
the job registry as they are created.
Now that we've discussed configuring a job, let's actually do it.
I'll be following Demo 5 that's found in the DEMOS.
md file in the root project directory.
With Spring Batch configuration in place,
the next step I'll demonstrate is the configuration of a Spring Batch job.
Make sure you've expanded the src folder to the package com.
Pluralsight.
springbatch.
patientbatchloader.
config.
In this folder, I'm going to create a new class called BatchJobConfiguration.
Again, I'll add in the class name as BatchJobConfiguration.
As this will be a Spring Configuration class,
I need to add the Configuration annotation to the class definition.
To create the job bean, we're going to use a Spring Batch job builder factory.
We simply need to autowire it into the Configuration class.
Let's add the JobBuilderFactory as the first member on the class.
The JobBuilderFactory will provide the DSL for configuring our job.
Next, let's add the definition for the job registry BeanPostProcessor bean.
Again, this will provide support for registering our job with the JobRepository.
I'll go ahead and drop that in now,
and here we can see we're just simply creating this BeanPostProcessor.
Now we can start to define our job bean.
Let's start by creating the method shell.
This bean will return the definition of our batch job.
It accepts a step, which will be created in the next demo.
I'm going to use the DSL for the JobBuilderFactory to define the job.
Let's drop that code in now.
First, you'll notice I'm using a Constants field for the JOB_NAME.
Let's define that now.
Open the Java class Constants in the same config
package as batch BatchJobConfiguration.
I'm going to scroll down to the bottom,
and I'm going to drop in the constant for our JOB_NAME.
This is the name we will use when referring to our job,
such as when retrieving information from the JobRepository or execution.
Let's open back up the BatchJobConfiguration class.
And after the JOB_NAME, I've defined a call to the method validator.
Again,
the purpose of this validator is to validate the job
parameters that are input to the job.
I want to add a check to assure that the FILE_NAME is valid
and that the input file it refers to exists.
Let's add that validator method now.
The method returns the JobParametersValidator instance.
In the validate method, I look for the JOB_PARAM_FILE_NAME.
As I'm using a constant for that, I'm going to have to drop that in as well.
Let's open back up that Constants class, and I'm going to drop in the constant.
And now we have a constant for the JOB_PARAM_FILE_NAME.
Let's open back up our BatchJobConfiguration class.
After obtaining the JobParameter for the fileName, I first check if it's blank.
If it is blank, an exception will be thrown when executing the job.
Next, I validate the file referred to by the JobParameter Exists and isReadable.
Again, if it's not, an exception gets thrown.
Note I'm using the application property that we defined earlier.
I'm going to need to autowire it into the Configuration class to fix this error.
Let's add that member now, and scroll back down to our Validate method,
and that fixes the error.
That also covers the validation for our job.
Now look back to the job method.
After the validator method call, we have the call to the start method.
This accepts a step, which will be defined in the next demo.
The start method creates an instance of SimpleJobBuilder for you,
which will then execute the step.
Finally,
the build method is called to complete creation of
the job based on what was defined. That completes the demo for our job.