You want to dress for success as well.
I know it's a cliché,
but you want to dress the way a person at a level above you,
just above you, tends to dress.
I know it sounds strange, but you want to think of yourself
as being adequate enough eventually to be in that position where you get promoted.
So, it's also a reflection on your attention to detail,
especially when it comes to meeting with clients.
So, you always want to dress for success.
I'm humble enough to know that I've got an awful sense for clothes.
I ask my wife every morning, "Does this match?
This match?" And I figured that – she told me,
by the way, black matches with everything.
That's why I'm wearing these black shirts. So, you always want to dress for success.