[Autogenerated] Welcome to this module on tune ML models In this module,
we get a detailed look at how sage maker automated hyper parameter
tuning works before looking at the tuning process.
Let's clear the basics on understand parameters and hyper parameters.
A model parameter is internal to the model on.
It can be visualized as a conflagration.
Variable whose value can be estimated,
are derived from the data that we feed in these values.
Error not set manually by the model developer,
but they're required by the model while making predictions.
The predicted value is saved along with a trained model on the accuracy off.
The predicted value determines the optimal prediction off your model.
The weights in an artificial neural network.
The support letters in SPM, the coefficients in a linear regression,
are some of the examples off a model parameter.
Hyper parameters are external to the model on the values of hyper
parameters are set before starting the training process they error
independent to the data that is being trained on.
These values do not change during the training process,
since his values are not part of the final model.
These values are not saved along with the model.
The K values in Kenya's neighbors,
the Learning rate for Training and URL network,
the value off Lambda in lasso regression are some of the examples
off model hyper parameter Tuning a hyper parameter is a process of
finding the right combination of hyper parameters that delivers
high position on accuracy.
There are multiple strategies used in hyper parameter tuning,
but grid search on random search are two popularly used methods.
Another common strategy that is gaining more traction now is beige.
In search in grid search,
all the hyper parameter values are set up in a great fashion on.
The model is strained for each combination on the
accuracy of the model is direct.
This is a resource intensive process on all the
combinations of hyper parameters.
Error evaluated before the model that performs the best is determined.
The complexity of great searching increases as the number of hyper
parameters increases in number in random search methods.
The hyper parameters values are set up in a great fashion,
but random combinations off hyper parameters are used to find the best solution.
The number of iterations is set based on time on resource
availability on this method has shown best results when the
hyper parameters are fewer in number on,
The underlying assumption is that not all hyper
parameters are considered equally important.
The problem with great on random searches are they're
completely unaware off the results from the past.
Evaluations on might end up spending valuable time on resource in
searching for optimal hyper parameter values in wrong ranges.
Base in Search, in contrast, keeps track of the past results,
and it treats hyper parameter tuning like a regression problem.
After testing the first set off randomly chosen hyper parameter values,
the tuning process uses regression to test the next set off
values while choosing the next set off values,
The tuning job chooses a combination that resulted in the previously
best trained job to improve performance incrementally.
Let's look at the automated model tuning resource
limits enforced by the sage maker.
The number of hyper parameter tuning jobs that can be
run parallel E is limited to 100.
The maximum number off training jobs.
Perl hyper parameter tuning job is 500 on the
number off concurrent training jobs.
Perl hyper parameter tuning job is limited to 10.
The maximum number of hyper parameters that can be searched
during a specific job is limited to 20 the maximum number
off metrics that are defined.
Perl hyper parameter tuning job cannot exceed 20 I'm.
Finally, the maximum runtime off.
A hyper parameter tuning job cannot exceed 30 days.
Sage Maker recommends few best practices to follow during the tuning process.
Those sage maker a loves you to use up to 20 hyper parameters in a tuning job.
The recommendation is to use a much smaller number of hyper parameters.
The range off the hyper parameters that you choose will also have a
significant impact on the resource consumption.
So it's recommended to use a much smaller range than a larger one.
Converting a parameter scale from a linear to a log rhythm
IQ is a very time consuming process.
So if you know that hyper parameters should use log rhythmic scaling,
you can convert it to yourself on mention it.
During the configuration set up,
a curing job improves one Lee after every successive rounds off experiments,
so it's recommended to limit the number of training
jobs that can be run concurrently.
Sage maker also recommends enabling distributed training by
training the jobs in multiple instances early,
stopping is a process off terminating a training job when the
object to metric computed by this job is significantly lawyer
than the best training job.
It helps reduce the compute time and helps you avoid the over
fitting off the model to configure early stopping.
You need to set the variable early stopping type to
are two to during the conflagration process.
After each epoch off training, sage maker gets the value off.
The object to metric computes the median off the objective metric for
all the previous training jobs up to the same epoch.
And if the value off the object to metric is higher than the previous job,
sage maker stops the current job to conserve computing resources.
Some of the algorithms that support early stopping our linear learner x g boost.
He made declassification object detection sequence to sequence on i p.
Insights.
Warm start to hyper parameter tuning job is a process off.
Leveraging are reusing previously controlled training jobs.
The results off the previous jobs are used to inform which combinations off
hyper parameters are effective in the newly starting job.
With the knowledge off previously tuned jobs,
every current job don't need to start from the scratch,
and it helps fast in the time it takes to identify the
best hyper parameter combination.
One starting help save significant time effort on computing resources and
eventually save cost tuning jobs with Warm Start usually takes longer to
start than standard tuning jobs because the results from the parent jobs needs to be loaded unstudied.