[Autogenerated] Welcome to this module on evaluate ML models,
we will be covering some off the performance metrics that are used to
evaluate both classifications on regression models.
If you are a beginner, I encourage you to understand this concepts clearly.
But if you're already familiar with these,
next few minutes are going to be a quick refresher for you.
Let's begin with the metrics for classifications problems.
If you have bean in the world of machine learning,
you may have heard about confusion Metrics.
Though Confusion Metrics is not a metric by its own,
it forms the basis off multiple other performance metrics that are used for
evaluating binary on multi class classification models.
Let's consider a business case where you want to
predict if the email is spam or not.
This is a typical binary classification problem where the
output label is a simple yes or no.
Let's try it two by two matrix with rows in the confusion matrix
representing what the machine learning predicted on the columns
representing the actual values.
The value in the top left quadrant represents the actual spam emails
that are correctly predicted by the algorithm.
This in machine learning language is called us true positive.
The bottom right QUARANTE represents the non spam email that
are correctly predicted by the algorithm.
This is called true negative.
Bottom Left Quadrant represents the actual number of the spam
emails that the algorithm didn't predict,
and it's also called is falsy Negative.
On the top right is where the algorithm predicts it has a spam email,
but in reality it is not.
This is also called us a false positive.
Now let's consider a multi class classification problem
where you like the algorithm to predict if a particular
fruit is apple banana are orange.
Since there are three possible outcomes,
the confusion matrix will be a three by three matrix on along the same lines.
For a classification problem with n possible outcome,
the confusion matrix will be end by in metrics.
Now that we learn about the confusion metrics,
let's look at the performance metrics that can be derived from this.
First one is accuracy.
Accuracy is defined as you overall correct predictions performed by the model,
and here is a formula used for computing accuracy.
Accuracy is the answer to the question.
What percentage of predictions were correct?
Next one is precision are positive predictive value.
The formula to compute position is the number off positive
predictions out off all the total predictions.
A model with a higher position means that it will
identify a higher percentage off.
Positive class are a higher percentage off truthy positive.
You can think of position as the answer to the question.
What percentage off __________ predictions were correct?
The next one is recall.
Recall is also known as sensitivity and is computed with the formula.
As shown here.
Recall is the answer to the question.
What percentage off positive cases did the moral catch?
Specificity is computer with a formula that has shown here,
and it helps in answering the question.
What percentage of negative cases are correctly predicted?
Let's say your organization goal is to capture maximum number of spam emails,
and that means we need to increase the positive
cases that the model is sketching,
which means we need to increase our recall score.
Now.
As we increase this, our position score might suffer.
That is another metric called F one score,
which is a harmonic distribution between precision and recall.
And here is a formula to compute JSON score an important
visualization chart in the field of classifications is a
receiver operator characteristic curve.
Also called us a rows seeker.
It is a curve that plots the relation between true positive rate.
This is a false positive rate.
PRA positive rate is also known as the sensitivity are
recall on the false positive rate is also known as the false
alarms are one minus specificity.
A rows SQL summarize is all off the confusion matrices
possibilities that each threshold produced.
It doesn't provide us with a numerical value to compare model,
but the metric area under the curve, also known as a U C,
certainly does.
Referring to the chart below,
you can see that choosing the threshold a provided us with better error.
You see value than choosing the threshold to be higher.
The year you see better than model is in distinguishing between the spam email on non spam email