[Autogenerated] Let's take a look at the dataset that
we're going to use in this demo.
This is a bank marketing dataset that's used for predicting if a
customer is going to sign up for a term deposit or not.
Right away,
you can see this dataset is a combination off numbers bullying and text values,
and it shows the profile of customers with details like is age,
job, marital status, education on so on.
The column campaign indicates the number of times the client
was contacted during this campaign process.
P days indicates the number of days passed by after the client was
last contacted during the previous campaign.
The column previous indicates the total number of contacts performed
prior to this campaign and API outcome shows the outcome off the
previous campaign on the output variable deposit indicate if the client
subscribe to the term deposit are not.
Let's launch into Jupyter notebook and begin our exercise.
This piece of code gets the current execution role from the Sage maker package
on the current region from Bo to three session like we have seen multiple
times in the previous model we're using get image.
You are a method to get the image off.
X G boost algorithm from the container registry.
These container registries whose these algorithms,
in a highly available,
secured on scalable environment each arable is account is
provided with one container registries and you need to be
authenticated before you can pull on, push images from the repositories,
Click run and you will see the success message being printed.
Now,
let's go ahead and create a S3 bucket where we will
store the training on validation data.
We're using the create bucket app a call to create the
bucket with a bucket name Globomantics.
When I run this cell,
I'm getting an error since I have already created this bucket
and if you're creating it for the first thing,
you would not be seeing this center.
Now, let's use the URL retrieval method to download the banking dataset.
Once the data is successfully downloaded,
we're storing it in a raid iFrame named model Underscore Data.
Let me run this cell on we can.
See the success message being printed.
I would like to check the top few rows and check the
structure of the data from the output.
It is very evident that the data we download it is a pre process
data because you don't see their strength that we saw in the raw
data anymore on the number of columns is very more than what we
saw in the actual data.
You can see one job column is convert OData Multiple bullion
column Checking if the customer is an admin,
are a blue collar, are an entrepreneur are two housemaid.
Let me list all the data columns,
and you can see similarly one Marital status column in the raw
data is converted to four bullion columns.
Marital underscored Die wurst,
marital underscore Married marital underscores single on marital under
school Unknown on all these columns carry Boolean values.
Let me check if any off the columns have null values in it,
and if so, they need to be filled with proper values. And as I expected, all the 61 columns have no null values.