After we have discussed different techniques for analyzing and
understanding our data, you might think that Globomantics data
analysis team tasks are done and it is time to hand over to the
machine learning team.
Mm, really?
The bad news is that no, that's not what we expect.
Our data will most likely have many issues that prevent using it directly.
Let's examine some of these issues.
Firstly, our dataset might be imbalanced,
which means that we might not have representative samples
from all real cases of our problem domain.
This is particularly important for classification problems.
Secondly, our data might use different scales,
which definitely means that we will have to make sure that we are
using the same scales everywhere so that we compare apples to
apples. Or even corruption, in some sensors,
we read the data from. Our data might not be straightforward
numerical data that the machine learning models can directly
consume, it can be audio files or even categorical data that
requires a special processing.
We might have missing data due to optional fields or even system failures.
Or even worse,
our data might contain some outliers that are not
representative of the real problem domain. Or even it could be
that our data is highly dimensional, that is,
it has too many features which make it difficult for us to
visualize and train. Our data might also expect what
so‑called features with high correlation,
which are features that add no value to our machine
learning model, or even worse, it can make our regression tasks perform worse.
Also,
our data distribution might be malformed and not what the
machine learning algorithms expect.
As you have seen the list of the challenges we might face
with the data is a very extensive list,
so we will discuss these challenges throughout this module, but before
discussing the specific challenges with our dataset,
let's try to understand first,
what is the root of all evil with the data issues we discussed earlier?
Let's reflect and think. First and foremost, user and system errors,
which can be narrowed down to human errors. Human either as a system user
or even system developers are not perfect creatures.
We make mistakes in data entry, we forget to add validation to our systems,
or we might even develop a buggy systems that corrupt
the downstream systems. For example,
it is quite common to see systems that use a string type to store the
date, instead of the native datetime construct,
thus opening the door to many date formatting related data quality
issues, such as missing data, duplicate rows, and so on.
The second reason would be the usage of heterogeneous systems that
have different business rules and this is quite common when it
comes to the units of measurements. Different units of measurements
are used for different cases in different cultures and surely for
different systems.
System A might have a human weight that's using pounds because it's
developed in the US while system B from Sweden uses kilograms.
Surely, we would not be comparing apples to apples,
and we need to adjust to a single scale.
Finally,
sometimes we are having difficulties just because it's
the nature of our business problem.
We might want to do machine learning on new system,
and it's a hard fact that we don't have enough data, or even we might
be processing a video data with too many dimensions. I'm sorry, life is not ideal.