Another common challenge we are going to discuss is the high dimensionality.
The high dimensionality challenge,
or what is so called the curse of dimensionality,
occurs when we have too many dimensions in our dataset. A
common example would be a video stream.
Having too many dimensions in the dataset is extremely bad,
due to the following reasons: Your data will become more difficult to visualize.
Visualizing three dimensions is hard, let alone hundreds.
The more complex your dataset,
the more complex your model, and the more complex your model, the
higher risk of overfitting. The machine learning training phase will
be more expensive since you will need to tune more parameters and that
will take more time. And let's now discuss the common techniques to
reduce dimensionality.
The first technique is feature engineering, and this consists of creating new,
useful features from the currently existing ones.
For example,
transforming the death year and birth year to a single
feature column called Life Span or Age.
The second technique is called feature selection, and this
consists of selecting a subset of features from the currently
existing ones based on certain criteria.
The third technique would be what is so called dimensionality
reduction, and this technique consists of creating new dimensions (not
necessarily from the existing features) that better capture the
underlying relationships in the dataset.
A detailed discussion of each technique is outside the scope of the course.
But we will discuss one technique of dimensionality
reduction called principal component analysis.
Let's see what principal component analysis is.
Imagine that we have the following dataset distributed across the Y and
X axes, two dimensions. Let's assume that the green line is the
best‑fitting line we found to fit our dataset.
As you can see,
most of the dataset variation is across that line. And here, we have the same
dataset as previous. And this time, we will make the best‑fitting line we
found with what is so called principal component,
which means that we will make it our new dimension.
As you can see,
we have not lost much information by removing the two dimensions and
introducing the principal component across a single dimension.
So in practice,
what we have done enabled us to convert a dataset that's
described in two dimensions to a dataset that's described in
terms of one dimension. This is big.
Since we did a dimensionality reduction,
we reduced the number of dimensions while maintaining useful
relationships in the dataset. And, in fact,
that can be generalized.
It would be possible to convert a 3D dataset to a 2D dataset or even 1D
dataset. And the same goes for 4D dataset and so on.
And from here, we are at an excellent position to
define the principal component analysis.
The objective of principal component analysis is to reduce the number from
n‑dimensions dataset to a k‑dimensions dataset by finding k vectors onto which
to project the data so to minimize the projection error.
The k vectors are called principal components,
and they are ranked by their explained variance.
Think about the best‑fitting line we've seen in the last slides.
I have borrowed this definition from the lead machine learning scientist,
Andrew Ng. And if you are interested to read more around mathematical
derivations of principal component analysis,
feel free to hit the following Bitly link.
One word about PCA is that you will end up with two or three principal
components within your machine learning model that are often just
mathematical vectors and are not explainable in logical terms.
Therefore,
PCA, or principal component analysis, makes it difficult to communicate your data to an external nontechnical machine learning audience.