Hi, everyone.
My name is Mohammed Osman, and welcome to my course, Exploratory
Data Analysis with AWS Machine Learning. I am a software developer
and machine learning enthusiast at Smarter Code. Machine learning is
booming everywhere; however,
machine learning is not much useful without careful data analysis
where we understand the underlying data trends and patterns and
data preparation where we fix the issues we found in our data using
data preparation techniques.
In this course,
we are going to follow a hands‑on approach to learn how to do
exploratory data analysis using AWS, a very important domain of
the AWS Machine Learning ‑ Specialty exam.
Some of the major topics that we will cover include what are the available
exploratory data analysis techniques in AWS, how to analyze your data using
descriptive statistics and reason behind it, how to use different types of
visualization techniques to understand your data distribution, what are
different challenges with the data, and how to fix these challenges using a
hands‑on approach. By the end of this course,
you will know how to analyze,
visualize, and prepare your data for machine learning tests,
and you will gain the required skills in the exploratory data
analysis domain in AWS Certified Machine Learning ‑
Specialty. Before beginning the course,
you should be familiar with basics of Python, basics of
AWS, on some basics of machine learning.
From here,
you should feel comfortable diving into machine learning modeling with
courses on machine learning model training and evaluation.
I hope you will join me on this journey to learn exploratory
data analysis with the Exploratory Data analysis with AWS Machine Learning, here at Pluralsight.