And now, let's discuss the high correlated features problem.
The highly correlated features are in short,
multicollinearity happens when the independent variable, in this case,
features are linearly correlated,
which means that changing one of them means changing the other.
A valid question would be why this would be considered a problem. In
particular, why is it a problem for regression models?
The simple answer would be that multicollinearity by
definition violates the definition of regression.
The main goal of regression algorithms is to separate the relationship
between each independent variable and the dependent variable.
The definition of a regression coefficient is that it represents
the average change in the dependent variable for each way
changed in the independent variable when we hold all of other
independent variables fixed.
So the idea is that when we change a single independent variable,
it should not change the others.
If that happens, and that some other independent variables change,
that would be very tricky for our algorithm since other variables
will be a moving target rather than fixed one.
If you want to think about it from an intuitive point of view,
we can claim that a variable that's highly correlated
is unlikely to provide more value.
For example,
if I take our dataset that we talk in the demo and I
clear that, for certain home, the garage is too large and
the garage can hold many cars.
I had the same statements implicitly mean the same thing.
Let's now discuss the possible solutions for the
highly correlated features challenge.
The first approach would be to use the correlation metrics. From the
correlation metrics, we will identify the highly correlated features
and remove them. The disadvantage of that approach is that it will be
limited comparison between one feature to another feature without a
holistic view and how this feature correlated with other features, in
general.
And that is why various inflation factor was introduced.
The variance inflation factor is a value that tells us how
much collinearity a particular independent variable has with
all other independent variables,
which means that it provides a holistic view we
lacked in the correlation metrics.
To understand that,
let's assume we would like to create one independent
variable, call it Xj. From other linearly independent
variables, we add regression techniques.
After doing the regression on Xj, we will calculate its R squared value,
which is the accounted variability.
In other words, how much percentage of the variability was accounted for?
If you are not familiar with R2 squared,
you can learn about it in my Building Your First Machine
Learning course in the shown link.
From that, we calculate the various inflation factor as 1 over 1 ‑ R squared.
If R squared is one, which means that all the variability was accounted for, the
variance inflation factor will be infinity since that variable will be perfectly
accounted for from other independent variables.
However, if R squared is 0, it means that the variability was not
accounted for. The various inflation factor will be one,
which means that the variable cannot be linearly
constructed from other independent variables.
In general,
we can use the following rule of thumb when
analyzing the variance inflation factor.
If the variable has a variance inflation factor value of one,
that means it cannot be linearly constructed from other variables,
and hence, it's not correlated at all with them.
A value between one and five indicates that the variable is moderately
correlated with other variables. A value higher than five would indicate
that the variable is highly correlated and we usually want to remove values that are higher than five.