Let's now see how we can remove the features with the
highest variance inflation factor,
or with the high multicollinearity, as we discussed earlier.
As you might remember,
features with large variance inflation factor than value five are
candidates to be thrown away since they will be considered highly
correlated with other features.
I got this function from here.
Let's go through the code together.
In Section 1,
the code imports variance inflation factor and add constant
helper function from a stats model package,
which have useful statistical operations such as
calculation of variance inflation factors.
The code also defines a function to calculate the variance inflation factor.
The function takes a pandas data frame and a threshold value.
The threshold value is defaulted to five.
In Section 2,
the code calculates the variance inflation factor across all features.
In Section 3,
the code identifies all features that have a variance
inflation factor larger than five.
And in Section 4,
we print out all features with a variance inflation index larger than five.
And now, let's run the function on our code.
We will drop the sale price column on only get the
numerical features since the variance inflation factor is
only defined for numerical values.
And as you can see,
the function identified many variables as remover candidates, among them,
Garage Cars and Garage Area.
We expected them earlier already when we calculated the correlation metrics.
And we have dropped all the features with variance
inflation factor larger than five.
Let's have a look at the shape of our dataset. As you can see, we have now less columns, around 69.