And now, the next step we perform is one‑hot encoding the categorical
variables thanks to pandas, which makes it very easy using get_dummies
function. Get_dummies will check all categorical variables in our dataset and
expand each categorical future to a certain number of columns equals to the
number of categories in that feature.
We have already explained one‑hot encoding previously. And
let's see how our dataset now looks like.
As you can see,
the categorical values has been expanded according to the
one‑hot encoding technique, for example,
the sale type column, which is Sale Type_New, Sale Type_Oth, Sale Type_VWD,
Sale Type_WD. And we are done with handling the categorical features.
Let's see now how many columns we have. As you can see, the number of columns significantly increased.