Let's now discuss the major types of visualizations we have.
The first type is the comparison visualizations,
which help us compare values across a certain dimension.
The second type is the relationship visualizations that help us detect
potential cause and effect relationships in our dataset.
Composition visualizations consist of multiple graphs of the same
type with a goal to convey complex information.
Finally,
the distribution visualizations help us understand
the underlying data distribution.
We will discuss one type of the comparison graphs, which is the bar chart.
A bar chart consists of different categories on the x‑axis,
say, for example, countries,
and the corresponding value from the characteristic from that category,
say, population.
Therefore,
a bar chart serves as a way to compare different
values over a certain dimension.
In the data analysis context,
it helps to compare a specific attribute over observations.
Another type of comparison visualizations is the line chart,
which is usually associated with the progression of time.
For example,
the following graph shows the progression of sales over a time period.
On the x‑axis, we have the time as a number of days in the week,
while in the y‑axis, we have the amount of sales.
Interestingly, we can see a trend that sales tend to increase over the weekend,
so line charts are essentially trend lines,
and in the context of data analysis,
they help us identify the impact of time on a specific feature.
The second category of the visualizations is the relationship visualizations,
which help us identify potential cause and effect
relationship between two or more variables.
One example is the scatter plot.
For example, we have this graph where the x‑axis contains the first variable,
which is the temperature in centigrade, while the
y‑axis contains the second variable,
which is the amount of sales. Each dot represent the
amount of sales on a specific temperature.
Notice that the general trend is that as the temperature increases, ice cream
sales increase. This is usually emphasized via a trendline,
showing the direction of the relationship.
So, scatter plots help us understand the relationship between two
variables, and in the context of the data analysis,
they are used to understand the nature of a linear
relationship between two features.
Another relationship visualization is the heat map.
A heat map simply consists of a correlation matrix of two variables.
But rather than putting correlation values in the value field,
a color is used to designate the strength of correlation.
Generally the darker the color, the stronger the correlation.
Let's take a look of the heat map shown over here of a schedule of a
clinic. In the x‑axis, we have the hour and the day, while in the
y‑axis we have a specific day of the week.
We quickly spot that Monday at 10 a.m.
is one of the busiest times at the clinic, while Saturday,
2 p.m. is among the least occupied times. So, a heat map tells us the
strength of relationship between two variables.
Therefore,
it makes it easy for us to identify correlated features that we
believe are most important for our training purposes.
The nice thing about the heat map is that it is more readable than
the plain number presented by correlation metrics.
The third type of visualization is the composite
visualizations that makes it easy for us to combine
things. A common example is the pie chart.
The pie chart, as the name indicates,
represent different categories in percentage in a
proportionate size in a pie with different colors,
usually, and each color represents a different category.
For example,
we have the following pie chart describing expense distribution across
different sectors in the country budget. We can see that agriculture in the
orange color takes 8%, while the health in purple takes 19%.
So, pie charts make it easy to understand percentage distribution and
makes it easy for us to understand how different values for a specific
category is distributed on our dataset.
The last category of visualization is the distribution visualizations,
which makes it possible for us to understand how our dataset is
distributed across different ranges of values. The most common
example for this is the histogram that tells us the frequency of a
specific value or range of values.
For example, we can see that values between 300 and 10,300 occurred 8 times,
while values between 10,300 and 20,300 occurred only 1 time.
So, the histogram is useful to understand the overall data
distribution and to find out where most of our values lie. It is
particularly useful to detect outliers. Let's now do a quick
comparison between bar chart and histogram.
Bar charts show different values for different categories,
while histograms show the frequency of the values.
A bar chart doesn't have to be ordered, while a histogram should be ordered.
As I discussed earlier, there are many types of visualizations.
If you are interested to know more, I have attached a link for a PDF summarizing them.