And now let's proceed with a demo and see how these
visualizations can be implemented in AWS SageMaker.
Here I am continuing on the same Jupyter Notebook we created in the last module.
As you can note that we have imported Python package called seaborn.
Seaborn is a high‑level packaged library,
and it makes it easier for us to draw interactive visualizations.
You can read more about seaborn here.
To start the visualization process,
let's start by first drawing a whisker and boxplot for the sale price to see
the overall sale price distribution trends in Globomantics.
And for that we,
use the seaborn function called boxplot and give it the
SalePrice column to display it vertically.
And you need to assign that as our Y parameter.
As you can see, we have a box and whisker plot with many outlier variables.
This could be assigned that we need to do some work on outliers,
such as observations removal.
We will discuss that more in detail in the next module.
Also note that we would expect the distribution of our data to be
skewed as the median is not exactly in the middle.
A symmetric dataset shows the median roughly in the middle of the box.
Let's verify this assumption by looking at SalePrice distribution.
And for that, we use the seaborn function called distplot.
And, as you can see, the distribution is skewed as expected.
This would warrant that we might need to do some
data processing to fix this skew.
After we have understood the shape of SalePrice data,
let's try to figure out which features could be a
good predictor of the sale price.
And for this, we will need to use heat maps that help us to detect correlation.
Here, I am telling matplotlib I want a larger figure.
Remember, seaborn is based on matplotlib,
and whatever we do there impacts seaborn drawings too.
Let's now draw the heat map.
And here I am drawing the heat map for the correlation
metrics we calculated in the last module.
And I am setting the annotations to True so that we see correlation values,
and I make it nicely colored with a cmap parameter.
As you can see in the last row,
we have a correlation for SalePrice across all features.
Also, as you can note in the legend,
the dark colors refer to strong correlations,
while the brighter colors refer to weaker correlations.
For example,
we can note that the following features are highly
correlated with the SalePrice.
The Overall Qual, which has a value point of 0.8,
Gr Liv Area with a correlation value of 0.71.
Let's try to create a smaller correlation heat map with a
smaller set of the most interesting values.
Here we are choosing the highest seven correlation values from the
correlation metrics based on the SalePrice column.
And we are only choosing values on the Sale column.
Let's print that and see.
As you can see, the following interesting facts.
SalePrice correlation with itself is 1, which is obvious.
Overall Qual, which is 0.79,
which makes sense since the higher overall quality of the building,
the more expensive it would be.
Gr Liv Area, which is the above‑grade living area,
and the correlation is 0.706, Garage Cars,
0.64, Garage Area, 0.64.
Note that it's most probably that Garage Cars and Garage
Area are highly correlated features, since if you have more cars,
you would need a bigger Garage Area, right?
We can validate that by checking their values in the heat map.
And as you can see,
the intersection between the Garage Cars and Garage Area in the heat map,
it's dark, which indicates that it's a high correlation.
Highly correlated features would warrant removal,
as we will discuss in the next module.
Also, there is a Total Bsmt SF parameter,
which is the total square feet of the basement area.
It has a correlation of 0.632, and 1st Flr area, which is 0.62.
Let's take a closer look at the relationship nature between
SalePrice and some of its highly correlated variables.
And for that, let's use a scatter plot with a trend line.
First, let's examine the linear relationship between SalePrice and Overall Qual,
and for that, we will use a seaborn function called regplot,
which is a scatter plot with a trend or regression line.
Hmm.
We see that the general trend is an increase of the price as
the overall quality increases (makes sense,
right?) with a few values that could be potential outliers
and the very big numbers of SalePrice.
Let's also examine the linear relationship between
price and above‑grade living area.
We can also see that the overall direction is an increase of the price,
with a grade living area increase with a few outliers prices
and the prices between 100 K and 200 K, which would also deserve some attention.
That's it for data visualization.
If you are interested to do more,
you can check seaborn documentation that covers all categories of visualization we discussed in this module.