Let's now discuss an important topic, which is the data distribution.
The importance in data distribution is that to make
machine learning algorithms happy,
simply put. Machine learning algorithms make specific assumptions on our data.
For example,
some machine learning algorithms assume that data
should be normally distributed.
We are going to discuss that soon.
Therefore,
we will need to do several steps on our data to make our machine
learning happy with it, and that's what we will do later when we
reach the feature engineering module.
Let's now introduce the most common use distribution called
normal distribution, or Gaussian distribution.
The first thing you can note here is that the distribution looks like a
bell; hence, it's also called a bell curve distribution.
Notice that it is symmetric around its center. On the horizontal axis, we
have the data points in a standard deviation scale, one standard
deviation, two standard deviation, and three standard deviation and four
standard deviation, both in the positive and negative sides. On the
vertical axis, we have the probability of each point. The average, or the
mean, of the normal distribution is on 0, which is the center of the
normal distribution.
It is also possible to have a normal distribution that is
centered around another point than the 0.
The special thing about normal distribution is that 68% of the data points are
within one standard deviation from the mean, while 95% of the points are within
two standard deviations from the mean, and 99.7% of the points are within three
standard deviations from the mean.
Let's now discuss few characteristics of the normal distribution that
makes it a role model for distributions in data science.
The normal distribution is considered a good fit to describe
everyday events, like rainfall rate per year,
number of accidents per year, and so on.
The main reason behind that is something called the central tendency theory,
which says that in some situations,
if a fairly large number of random variables are added together,
they tend to sum towards a normal distribution. Many machine learning
algorithms assume that the underlying data follows normally distributed
fashion, so it is good to have your data in that fashion.
Finally,
the normal distribution is considered mathematically resilient in the sense
that applying certain mathematical operations on a normally distributed data
will still result in normally distributed data,
which makes it very handy for data science purposes. And now,
let's discuss two metrics that are used to measure the
distribution of the data, skewness and kurtosis.
The first measure we are going to discuss is the skewness, and it's a
measure of how symmetric our data is. A distribution can be either
symmetrical, as shown in the diagram in the middle, or positively
skewed, as shown on the left, where we see that the distribution has a
sort of tail in the positive direction and hence the name positive. The
skewed value will also be positive or negatively skewed, as shown on
the right,
where we see that the distribution has a sort of tail in the
negative direction and hence the name negative.
The skewed value will also be negative. If we want to quantify the
cases of skewness, we can describe three cases off skewness. If the
absolute value of skewness is between 0and .5,
we see that our data is fairly symmetrical.
However, if the absolute value is between .5 and 1,
we say that our data is moderately skewed.
If the absolute value is greater than 1, we say that our data is highly skewed.
The importance of skewness in data analysis and especially in machine learning
tasks lies in the fact that skewed data needs to be transferred if we are
going to use certain machine learning algorithms.
Therefore, it's important thing to detect.
Another measure we would like to discuss is the kurtosis, and it
is an indicator of how pointy our data is,
whether our data tends to be sharp or flat.
Usually, this is measured against normal distribution,
which has a kurtosis value of 3.
Let's now examine the possible cases of kurtosis. A kurtosis value of 3
indicates a dataset that is closed to the normal distribution pointiness. An
example will be the black‑colored distribution.
While kurtosis value more than 3 indicates a very pointy distribution.
An example would be the red‑colored distribution.
While kurtosis value less than 3 indicates a flat distribution.
An example would be the blue‑colored distribution. In the next
clip, we are going to see these concepts in practice and use
statistics to understand our data. Be ready.