And now let's proceed with a demo and see how we can do
statistical data analysis using AWS SageMaker.
We are back to the Jupyter Notebook,
which we created in AWS SageMaker in the previous module.
The first thing we are going to do as data analysts at Globomantics
is to apply what's so called statistical data analysis on our
dataset to understand its characteristics.
To do that,
we are going to use pandas built‑in method called describe that
does descriptive statistics over dataset.
And now we can see some interesting data.
Let's try to reason over what we have got.
The count of sale price element is 2930,
which is equal to the total number of rows we have in the dataset.
It's an indicator that we don't have any missing data.
Sometimes we might have observations that are missing certain value due you
to user entry errors or lack of validation in the front‑end systems or even
faulty sensors that they didn't supply some data.
If there is a missing data value,
we will need to apply certain techniques to deal with them,
and this is something we are going to discuss in future modules.
The mean of the dataset is around 180,000.
The mean itself alone doesn't tell us that much,
but it becomes really powerful when we join this
knowledge with other descriptive statistics.
The standard deviation is around 80,000, which is somewhat high.
This tells us that we should expect considerable
differences in the prices in the dataset,
as the dataset is spread out.
The minimum value of the dataset is around 13,000.
Notice that this is while the average is around 180,000.
This gives us a hint that there are really large numbers in the dataset
that are causing the dataset to tend towards the average.
The 25 percentile is around 130,000.
If we remember that the minimum value was at around 13,000,
it tells us that there is a wide range of small
numbers at the first quarter of data, while the 50 percentile,
or the median, is around 160,000.
If we compare it to the mean, which is around 180,000,
we can say that they are close enough.
In simple words,
the average value of the dataset is close to the middle value when we
order the dataset in ascending or descending fashion.
The conclusion would be that the dataset is fairly symmetrical.
The 75 percentile is at around 214,000, while the max is at very large number,
755,000.
We can withdraw the following conclusions about the dataset.
There is fairly prices with large number between the 75
percentile and the maximum value, in other words,
the top 25 percentile.
If we calculated the difference between the maximum value,
which is 755‑214, which is the 75 percentile,
we will find out that the difference is around 541,000.
Compare it with the range with the minimum value at the 25 percentile,
in other words, the lower 25 percentile values,
you will find that is 130‑18 which is around 112,000.
And this range is way smaller than the other range
we found on the upper percentile, which was 541.
The conclusion we can draw from that is that our dataset is skewed.
Moreover, the maximum value, 755,000, is likely an outlier,
since it is more than 3 standard deviation difference from the mean.
We will discuss how to detect outliers later in the future modules.
That's it.
You can notice how much time we spent to explain these seven numbers
and what conclusions we were able to draw from them.
This should be a good hint for the value of descriptive statistics.
Let's now calculate other two metrics, skewness and kurtosis.
Luckily, they are also built in into pandas.
The skewness value is around 5, which is much larger than 1.
If you remember,
an absolute value of skewness larger than 1 is an indication of a high skewness.
And this is another confirmation of our analysis we did with mean and median,
and from that we also found out that our dataset is skewed.
Notice that kurtosis is 1.74, which is larger than 0.
This indicates that the shape of our data is pointy.
You might be wondering that I mentioned previously a kurtosis
value more than 3 indicates a pointy distribution,
but now I am saying that our value larger than 0
indicates a pointy distribution.
The reason is that pandas is using a different definition.
Rather than considering kurtosis of the normal distribution being 3,
it considers it as 0,
which means that it's deducting 3 from it for mathematical convenience.
You can read more about that here.
The final thing we are going to explain in this demo is the correlation.
I will take it here in a very brief manner,
as the correlation matrix we will create will not be very readable.
A better approach is the heat maps which are easier to deal with,
and we are going to discuss that in the next module.
To calculate the cross‑correlation of a dataset,
which means the correlation of each element with the other elements,
we use a pandas function called corr, as the following.
As you can see, the values we are getting are not very readable,
and they are just another complicated matrix of numbers.
So let's not analyze that now, and let me jump to something interesting.
As you can see, the dimensions of the correlation matrix are 38 x 38.
How comes that while our original dataset has 82 columns.
It should be 82 x 82.
Hmm, you need to remember one thing.
Correlation is defined for numerical variables,
and hence all categorical variables are not calculated during correlation.
Let me show you the dataset to remember that.
As you can see, we have some columns that have categorical values,
for example, the Utilities column.
Also, luckily,
pandas corr function is smart enough to exclude the non‑numeric values.
And that's it for this demo.
I hope that you now understand the value of descriptive
statistics for us as data analysts at Globomantics. Thank you.