Let's now recap what we have learned in this module.
We started by discussing why we need data visualization.
It is mainly because of the powers of the picture.
Remember, a picture is worth 1000 words. Then, we continued
discussing the usage of data visualization.
We have seen how it helps on summarizing our data,
assisting machine learning algorithms performance, and
finding interesting patterns in the data.
Then we discussed the different categories of the visualizations.
Comparison visualizations help us to compare features across a specific
dimension, while relationship visualizations help us locate potential
cause and effect relationships. Composition visualizations to compare the
composite situations. And finally,
the distribution visualizations that help us to see how our
dataset is distributed across a range of values.
Then, we proceeded with a demo for Amazon SageMaker to do visualizations.
After that,
we introduced a specialized visualization service called AWS
QuickSight and discussed its features. And then we concluded
with a demo for AWS QuickSight.
That's it for this module.
Now, take a break and come back to learn about preparing and feature engineering our data.