Hello everybody and welcome to the section where we make an animated lamp similar to those famous ones
you've seen in the films but not quite.
And this is gonna enable us to focus on first of all bringing your models to life whether it's an animated
object like the lamps being or whether it's a camera moving around a scene is going to add the extra
dimension to your renders that we've never had before.
We'll learn some key skills and how to manage the exporting of all those different frames and also focus
on lighting.
I'm going to delve into the cycles rendering engine in this particular section as well as eevee and
we'll switch backwards and forwards between the two and you will see that there is a stark difference
depending on what the outcome is that you want.
So let's dive into this section and start off by mocking our past scene and we'll start back in the
next lecture.