Hello everybody and welcome to this lecture now.
This is the end of the 2.8 remaster as it is at the moment.
I am busy in the background just prototyping the next couple of sections making sure they're working
properly in Blender 2.8 and I'm going back to some of the early elections as well because some of the
terminology is you guys have thankfully pointed out has changed.
I'm going to go rectify that.
Now I've got a few other notes here so I just want to make sure I don't miss anything.
The next lecture to this one is going to give you access to the old course.
Now that's important because if for some reason you can't run blender 2.8 or just want access to the
archive information before we remove it from this course you'll be able to do so following the link
in that lecture.
So that's important.
If you need access to the old 2.0 seven x that's by 7 7 8 and 9 content.
Not much has changed during that side but when we got to blender 2.8 a lot changed in fact a lot more
than I thought had to change which is why some of the earlier lectures now are somewhat different from
what when they were before.
But it's so much better now playing with eevee as well.
We get much much better results right from the word go rather than using the old blender render which
is much more involved to set up now.
Feel free to join in with the old content if you need to but do bear in mind the old content since it's
been deprecated is no longer being supported by us.
And if it's still in this course at the moment of course we'll be supported.
And as we roll forward we'll start removing some of the other lectures out to the old content as we
go so so far the first second third and fourth sections will be removed over the next week or so so
that's all the way up to the old chess sets.
But of course all the new content is right there waiting for you as well.
If you've got any questions of course fire away be happy to help and more content will be coming soon
well we'd be hopping back on over into blender 2.8 take our.