Hi guys.
Welcome to this section.
And we're going to be focussing on two main topics here.
We're going to be first of all focussing on getting the mesh really nailed right.
Good message topology right from the very beginning starting with a very low detail model and then adding
detail as we go.
And we will the second stage is actually making sure the materials are right.
It's all very well having an ultra realistic mesh but it's a bit lifeless and we can make that come
to life with excellent material use.
So we'll go through how to apply multiple layers of materials that make up our skin or human skin or
a dragon skin or a grape skin there's lots of applications that you can take from this entire section
and will also be playing with the cloth physics as well which would be great fun.
So of course before you crack on just a couple of notes of course the lecture notes themselves if you
want to follow along with the lecture notes they actually attached against this lecture and any assets
that you will need during this whole section are also against this particular lecture.
So have a look if you want to download them please do so right now.
And of course I will see you guys on the course in the next lecture.