Hello everybody and welcome to the section where we're going to create game assets.
Now it's not just for people who want game assets it's for anybody who wants to be able to export their
model and understand what you can and cannot export from blender.
We start off with the very basics we'll do some modelling as we've done before but we'll model in such
a way that's good for game assets and not necessarily good for maybe 3D printing.
There are two different requirements.
So we looking very specific Lee at game design document what we wanted to get out of it.
We'll talk about how we can mesh things together properly making sure you have modular assets is key
to creating environments quickly.
You don't want to have to build your entire environment and have it unique having your level designer
be able to pick up components and put them together to make an awesome level.
That's just what you want to have.
Now you may be your own level designer in which case is going to save you a ton of time.
Of course game engines wouldn't be great without some texturing so we're going to throw that in there
as well not just the standard color map but we'll also talk about normal maps.
There were a few maps is the color map.
We'll talk about glossy maps or speculum maps or metal maps.
It does depend on the workflow you're going for but that will all be unveiled as we progressed through
this section.
I'm really looking forward to it.
And this is one of these sections where you will have the opportunity to actually diverge from the course
content itself.
I'm going to be focused on making a gothic style church.
Now if you don't want to do that then by all means take the lessons that we that we go ahead and learn
and apply them to something that you like perhaps you like more of a steampunk or cyberpunk or whatever
sci fi environment then apply what we learned to those type of worlds rather than a Gothic church.
That's absolutely fine.
And you will get the most out of this course when you do things like that.
Anyway enough of me rambling on.
Let's dive into the first lecture.
See you soon.