Welcome to g.p you rendering in this section.
So in this video you'll understand that even with a dedicated GP you may end up with an out of memory
issue.
If your car doesn't have enough RAM and also that some a n d cars do not render hairs correctly.
So if you are experiencing these problems you will have one of two options.
Will even have to optimize the scene so it fits into your available RAM and that usually just means
less particles so bear that in mind.
And then if that's still not working or you have an m.d. card and it's not actually working then you
will have to switch over to see p u rendering.
I know some of the modern cards will work apps that you find but some of the older ones may not.
So now we've got that out of the way.
Let's continue on and move on to the next lecture.