Hello everybody and welcome back.
Let's jump straight into a challenge.
Now this is going to test some of your basic knowledge here shouldn't take you too long to do this and
we're not looking for anything super high poly unless you're really going down that route.
You need to decide on a scale at this point is a good time to finalize what you've been working on with
your planning.
Now I am going to go on a four by four meter basis for my pieces.
A church is a rather large building.
I think if we make the pieces much smaller than that it's going to cause an issue when it comes to fitting
them all together and create a blank wall piece.
This is gonna be are so template piece that we're going to use for other parts in our scene and create
a doorway as well.
Now I'm gonna go ahead and use the boolean modifier to make my doorway and it's just gonna be a cutout
and archway in my wall piece.
Now you may not go that approach and if you use a different approach that's absolutely fine.
In fact sometimes using the building modified can create horrible geometry just remember there's no
right or wrong here but I'd like to see your first modular pieces.
Remember we're trying to make things that we can stick together here finally.
I'd like you to go ahead and move the objects origin to the lower corner of your pieces.
So by default when you add a default cube it's right in the center.
If you were to lift that default cube up in edit mode it would be at the middle of the bottom which
is fine for some game engines.
But when we're snapping things together we can snap them together really quickly if they're actually
on the origin point itself where we wants to do that snapping.
So if you put it in one of the lower corners then all of our pieces that we generate from the template
piece will also inherit the origin placements who don't have the FAF AROUND TOO MUCH.
OKAY SO GO AHEAD pause video now and I'll see you back in about five or ten minutes okay.
Everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead and hop on over into blender and create our doorway okay.
So let's start building our doorway.
I want to start with you probably guessed it the default cube.
Here we go.
Okay.
Let's at this end and I'm going to go into edit mode so don't have to apply those transforms or you
scale on the y axis by point 1.
Make it nice and narrow and then we have to consider the origin.
Now most game engines you won't want the origin being in the in the middle like that maybe at the bottom.
So if we went GZ 1 we've now got the origin at the bottom but that's in some game engines is going to
be what you want or for a particular component.
However for modular pieces especially with unity and unreal you'll typically wants your origin of your
object being in the same corner on all of your pieces.
And I'm going to pop it on this corner here.
So we've vertex select selected.
I'm selecting that lower vertex.
I will go shift an S and move the cursor to selected go back into object mode right click on our object
and set its origin to a 3d cursor that's fine.
And then if you've not got this window open you can do it over in the object properties as well but
I'm going to set that to zero.
Now this is basically positive x positive y going off here at the top of the screen.
So all of our pieces that fit together should be like that and then we won't have any or even many problems
when snapping them together externally.
Okay.
Final issue here is it's called cube let's call it a wall which is fine and it's currently two meters
by two meters.
I think I'm going to want it larger than that so I'm going to go into edit mode.
Now we could scale it from its origin point.
So we go out and scale it and you see there it's going to actually scale from there which is exactly
what we want.
We could just get it by 2 and apply that but I also want to take this opportunity to show you that I
could go and change the pivot point to the active element which is that lower corner and scale it and
then select everything making sure that's the active selected and then scale everything as well.
So two ways that do exactly the same thing.
One of them keeps you in edit mode.
Okay.
This map of what we want to create I'm going to scale it up by a factor of 10.
I'm going to apply that scale and then I'm just gonna hide it out of the way with the.
OK.
We have a wall piece here.
Let's go ahead and duplicate it and then our duplicate let's call it a doorway.
Absolutely fine.
And we see here that we've got two objects in our scene.
That's a part of the same category but not collected together into that category.
So let's create a new collection with the doorway selected.
I'm going to hold down control and select the wall over in the outline.
Once we've done that we press the M K for mother on the keyboard and a new collection and I should call
this building so a window will go in there and other pieces as well.
Okay brilliant.
So the next thing that I want to do is make a cutout in this doorway and to hide my wall to do that.
And you may notice as I go ahead and click the icon I've missing a few icons that I had before.
I've recently done a little upgrade on my computer so we've got the standard installation here so I'm
going to go into my filters and just turn back on whether or not it's showing in view ports and the
camera icon there for the render whether it appears in renders in fact the image that I've got I never
want it to appear in a render so I'm going to turn that's off.
Now there are plenty of ways we can make a doorway.
You could use the mirror modifier and just literally put together a series of edges and faces together
to make that objects.
That's absolutely fine.
I'm going to go for the boolean modifier.
I don't think I'm going to have any issues with it making a mess of my mesh.
Now there are a couple of ways of doing this.
I'm going to add a cylinder in as my base cuts and then I'm going to do a bit of manipulation so that
cylinder.
So let's go ahead add in a cylinder.
I'm going to have to rotate it round so rotated on the x axis by 90.
I'm going to place it in the middle of my objects which is which is on the x axis too but not the y
axis too.
Let's make that zero.
Okay so that's cutting all the way through.
That's absolutely fine.
And we can just check what we're doing with the doorway selected.
I want to go to my modifiers boolean modifier and a different object will be the cylinder and we can
see it's cutting through absolutely fine.
Let's grab the cylinder and I'm gonna select all of the top edges there.
So I'm going to use control and plus to expand my selection and that failed miserably from there so
let's go ahead and manually select all of these.
Now you could use the circle select tool with the C just whizzed down there but we don't want the one
that's at the bottom there because we want to pull this up before we do anything else with it.
So we've got a straight bit of our door first.
Okay I'm gonna go g.
Oh I need to right click to get rid of circle selectable GZ and I'm just gonna lift that up.
There we go.
We've got some street corners that's what I wanted so no lift out by one to begin with and then I'm
gonna grab this top bit and I'm gonna scale it up from there and I want it to go to about three meters
tall I think.
Okay let's go G.
Z and pull that up and we get a spike.
Do we want that.
No we don't.
Let's use proportional editing.
So at the top here we've got proportional editing.
I'm gonna leave it's set to smooth.
I think maybe inverse square we can play with these settings and see what we get but smooth usually
is pretty good for this type of thing there we go.
And I can just bring that out.
So I'm going to put in three.
Oh no I don't want it to go up by three meters.
I think it's just one meter that is going up.
Yep.
There we go.
And then it's a matter of using the mouse wheel to just adjust how Archie are archway happens to be
I think that looks pretty good.
Okay.
The final thing I'm want to do here is apply that modifier.
We could just hide the out the way so we can edit it later.
It's a good way to check it first.
And I think that looks that looks absolutely fine.
Now one of the things here is if you have vertices that are lining up between your boolean cuts and
the final piece you end up with it being hollow.
We're going to have to fill that in in a moment so that select this apply a boolean modifier.
Get rid of our cylinder.
You may want to keep yours if you've come to this approach.
I'm quite happy getting rid of it and carrying on.
Now in order to fill this in I'm going to go into edit mode.
I'm going to select this lower edge.
Oh no I can't do edges first.
I'm going to go to vertex select and select the four vertices that make up this area.
Here I want to fill in and fill it in.
Then I can go ahead and select this edge and watch how cool this is.
If you just press the f k it will just continue to fill in.
Perfect.
Okay.
I'm almost done with my archway here.
The final things that I wanted to discuss with you are the fact that this looks pretty symmetrical so
there is an argument to be said that we should cut it in half.
Certainly this way a mirror modify it.
And here as well.
Now I'm not going to do that at the moment there and I can't cut it in half because there's a big end
gun here says a topology we might need to sort out in a bit but we can cut it in half.
Both along its x and y axis and then mirror it.
But first of all let's have some more detail to mirror.
Otherwise there's no point at this point in time we're just doing extra work for nothing.
Okay.
Brilliant.
How did you guys get on.
What did your archways look like.
What sort of sort of scale have you gotten for be interested to see.
Please show your work over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.