Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to focus on the camera position in our scene.
Now you may already have the camera pointing directly at the objects and all you need to do is render
out.
But as we can see here there are a couple of issues.
It's firstly badly lit and secondly it's not even in frame we can't really work out what it is.
So there's a couple of things that we need to do first with the camera to make sure that we can render
something out successfully.
Let's go have a look now and hop on over to the camera settings in Blender.
Hello everybody and welcome back.
Right.
Let's get rid of our cube and press the X key and delete it.
I'm going to add in Suzanne, Suzanne the monkey because we need to make sure that we've got a direction
to our objects just to demonstrate that we are in fact moving around it.
Okay so now that we've done that let's have a look through our camera.
How do we do that.
Well we can go to the View menu cameras active camera or numberpad zero.
Now at this particular point you may say Yeah that's absolutely fine.
But look how little Suzanne is taking up of our frame.
You can see here that when we're in camera mode you can zoom in and out.
But the framing does not change at all.
So how do we change that.
Well there are a couple of ways of doing it.
If we go to our outline and left click on camera we will select the camera.
You can see the camera now has an orange border.
This means we can go ahead and either transform its location or indeed we can open up the properties panel
of the 3D view and change its location X will move it along the X axis Y along the Y.
Of course Z on the Z axis.
Now when it comes to X Y and Z with rotation it can be a bit more confusing because you think well that's
not rotating the way I thought it was going to.
And that's because it's just pointing a different way.
If we scroll down this what we can also do is lock the camera to view which means that as we move the
view around the camera moves along with it.
I do not like this personally and I don't use it a lot of people love it but I don't because I always
forget to untick it and I go and rotate around my view expecting to come out of camera mode and I
end up moving the camera and sometimes it can be a real pain because you've set up the camera deliberately
in this in a very very special position let's say we're here and we move it's along the Y axis it gets
closer.
Oh let's make sure pick the right one.
Once he gets his hand there we move it round we go yeah that's perfect and then I go and think oh I
need to do something else in the scene boom and I've ruined it and you can't just do undo all the time
and get back to where you were before we can see it's taken us back to some point but not exactly where
we were.
However my favourite way of navigating around in blender in general and especially with the camera is
going to first person mode.
Now you can do that with shift and the character next to the one on your keyboard if you don't have
access to that and they won't come up on my screen capture my keys you can go to the view menu and go
to navigation and I'm gonna have to scroll down a little there's walk navigation there if you want to
set it's your own shortcut key you can right click and assign a shortcut I'm not going to do that at
the moment or you can add it to your quick favourites which is probably a better idea I am going to add
it to my quick favourites and we'll get to those quick favourites later on so I'm gonna go shift in the
number next to the also the key next to the one key and now I can move around as if I was in a first
person shooter so I can press W to go forward S to go backwards A and D to strafe Q and E to go up and
down, Thats really quick at the moment I'm gonna use the scroll wheel to calm it down a little there you
go this is a very easy way to manipulate are seen to get it looking exactly how we want it to.
There are a series of other options whilst in first person mode and you'll notice at the very bottom
of the screen there are some shortcut keys that show so you can press the space bar to zoom into a certain
area of your model very useful you can turn gravity on and off as well which is always an interesting
one I'm going to do at the moment because all I will do is fall because there's no ground underneath
but it does give you the ability to walk around buildings if you do that which is quite cool I'm happy
with that view of Suzanne and now if I go ahead and press F 12 to render we notice that we've got her
looking pretty swell and not cut off now before we move onto a challenge you can also go into the camera
view by just clicking this camera icon at the top right to the 3D window I sometimes forget that's there
because it's brand new but that's another way of getting in if all of these controls have said this
before are brilliant if you're on a laptop because you don't always have the control that you do when
you're at a full desktop with a full blown mouse with a scroll wheel and a full size keyboard.
Okay now it's time for your challenge.
Okay so your challenge I'd like you to go ahead and position the camera so that it frames your model
or scene.
Well now don't worry about getting absolutely perfect at this stage just make sure you can see what
you want to see of your model.
Secondly feel free to alter your model or your scene.
If they aren't quite right yet I know that I'm gonna go ahead and alter my scene and make the ground
plane a bit larger.
But if you do spot something with your new framing of course go ahead and alter it.
And finally remember you can move it again later so we're not setting a final position here.
We're just setting it up ready for our first render.
So go ahead pause a video and give that a go.
Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go and hop on over into blender and sets up our camera okay.
Everybody welcome back.
Right.
The first thing I'm going to do is go ahead and open up my file.
I want to work with.
Okay.
So now that that's there I'm going to press the zero key to see what we can see go into first person
mode.
And I'm going to come around this side probably a little lower down could make it look a bit wider and
the position over here that's looking pretty good so far.
I'm liking that now.
The ground itself.
I wanted to go out of frame so I'm literally just going to scale it up.
Instead it forms horizon in the distance.
That's house that you find in this case.
Now I can think about carefully where it positioned the camera in relation to the horizon because that
does change things slightly because obviously if the horizon is there that gives a completely different
look to it than if it's up here.
In fact this is a great way of testing a view for a game if you think about it if you've got the viewport
set up well is it a top down game like this.
Is this the scale of your model.
If it is the probably wasted your time with all the detail that you can't see.
However in this case I'm going to fly back round Oops.
Make sure you're in the camera mode when you start flying.
Otherwise you'd just literally flying around the screen.
Okay.
I was trying to use a shortcut there from an old version of blender but there we go on the sets top
like that.
I think that's a relatively good framing of my model.
It sets up on one side we can see the detail underneath the detail on top.
I quite like that.
I hope you've managed to frame your subject really well and in the next lecture we'll learn how to light
our subjects.
Just a basic three point light setup and I'll see you in the next one.