Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we are going to learn about selecting edge rings.
We already know about edge loops that flow around our model but these ones running down we can select
them by selecting edge rings.
Let's find out more in this lecture.
Of course we're going to select these edges running down here.
Now you could do it manually like I'm doing here and then dissolve and just work your way round.
But there is a quicker way of doing it if we have a look under the Select Menu selecting loops.
It's kind of a part of that we also end up with edge rings and you can see there with those edges selected.
It's selected all of the edge rings running round.
Now that is pretty awesome and we can go round and deselect the ones that we don't want.
The first thing that I thought when it came to this is ooh I could do.
Checker deselect and just change the amounts.
That would be quite easy.
So again I went to select went to checker deselect and it didn't do what I thought it did.
It just went down on this original one and did nothing else.
However when I selected an individual edge ring going round which I can do by selecting one edge going
to select going to select loops and edge rings it will select everything around that.
Now there is a shortcut for that whereas edge loops you hold down ALT and it does the edge loop if you
hold down alt and control at the same time.
It will do the edge ring.
So now that we've done that we could go in and go select checker deselect and you can see it's turned
off every other one.
So if we have 32 edges running down here I can now reduce that to sixteen and I can change how many
are being checker deselected in the operator panel we've got how many to go round so we can change
that we can tell it's a skip a couple and you can see here it selects a multitude of them.
So unfortunately you can't just select all of these and go round but you could select them individually.
However with what we've got planned with cutting this down it is quite easy to go round and just select
the ones that you want to dissolve by holding down alt and control and selecting the edge loops you want
and of course as you're going round and doing this you realize you need to add to your selection.
So if you hold down shift as well as control and alt you can add them in.
And once you've done that you can hold down shift and alt to turn them on and off as you want.
Now if we were chopping this up into smaller pieces say every other one what we could do here is
deselect them every other one going round.
Now what I would recommend is that you align any of the ones you decide to keep with some of these axes
if you make them off center that can cause some issues later on.
If we start using something like the mirror modifier so make sure if you do cut things up that the geometry
itself aligns with the world axes it just makes your life a lot easier if you can do that.
So you can whizz round and you can take these out as I'm doing now and it doesn't take much time at
all and you'll be writing saying or even suggesting oh how about just starting afresh because we seem
to be doing a lot of deconstruction work here.
Well part of that is because I want to teach you some new skills not necessarily a workflow and I would
agree with you if you suddenly realized that you'd made something really high poly and it needed to
be low poly perhaps starting again would be an optimal solution but since we've got the opportunity
here to learn how to cut down geometry where that might not be possible in reality.
So if you had already made a high polygon model and you wanted to come back to it later and just cut
down the amounts of geometry this may be the only way of doing it because you're not creating it from
scratch at that point.
So now if I press X and dissolve those edges we end up with 16 separate segments instead of 32 and it
looks a lot sharper now.
So there we go that pretty much covers all we need to know about edge rings which is a series of edges
are not directly connected but share the same face.
And now it's time for your challenge okay.
So your challenge is to create a base with eight segments.
We're already at 16 so eight shouldn't be too hard to do whether you're starting with 32 or the 16 that
we've just made.
You should end up with eight segments so the profile will be octagonal and there will be a lot easier
to work with a base that is that simple.
Pause the video now and give that a go. Okay everybody, Welcome back.
Let's hop on over into blender and create that base with eight segments.
Okay.
So for this challenge I'm going to assume I had not already gotten halfway there.
So I'm going to revert back to how it was previously and so I need to keep these vertical edges that
run along the axes and it could be just as easy to select all of these edge rings as we've been doing
before and then just remove the ones I want to keep.
So they'll be eight to remove.
That's a better way of doing it than adding the other 24.
So we'll do it that way round for speed.
So I'm going to hold down alternate shifts so I can start these selecting.
So we want the ones that lie on the axes that will make ourselves a square if we just dissolve them.
Now let's just try that dissolve edges.
We get a square and that might might be the type of piece that you want to do.
That is probably as low polygon as you really want to go and preserve the shape.
I'm not doing that though we're doing octagonal so we need to do three.
And then one three and then one three and then one two three.
There we go.
And then the final one is there.
So now that I've got all that sorted out I can just go X and dissolve edges and we should have an octagonal
finish which we do.
Perfect.
How did you guys get on.
Can you see the power of being able to take a high poly mesh and drill it down to its basic components
and then the next lecture we will actually have a look at some alternatives to the bevelling that we've
just undone and ultimately having this low poly model as the base for that makes our workflow so much
easier because we only have let's see how many of we gotten down.
So we have 92 polygons to play with and 48 vertices.
That's a lot less geometry than we had before.
And that gives us many many more options and flexibility when it comes to controlling it.
But the downside is we don't have such precise control as we might do if we can control each individual
vertex.
So of course like most things it has pros and cons it will be quick to work with but won't be so bespoke.
That's it for this lecture.
Show your work so I can see how you guys are getting on and I'll see you all in the next one.