Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to do one last profile modelling.
But this time using mesh objects enables us to have a much more detailed surface on our model.
So let's go ahead and hide the archway once again.
Now this time I'm going to do some sort of block work and it's going to be really simple once again.
So let's go ahead and add in a cube.
It's going to be added in completely the wrong place.
But again I don't care at this point in time because we're going to manipulate it.
So I'm going to go into edit mode that there have to apply anything.
And let's pop that there and what we're going to aim for is some alternating Block works just to give
ourselves a bit of variety.
I'm going to scale that on the x axis and get a lift that's up.
So it's approximately in the right place there.
I'm going to duplicate that scale it's on the x axis by point five which will halve it and I'm going
to leave a little bit of a gap there and then just place it on top like that.
Now what I can do is get that to follow our arch way around which should be pretty awesome by itself
and hopefully what we'll be able to do probably get it up to the top and then mirror it's coming down.
I don't think I've measure that perfectly.
If it does work out really well like that even better.
So I'm looking at this here going perhaps I should scale it down just a little bit more.
Otherwise those are going to be some pretty big bricks.
Excellent.
I'm going to Bevel all of those edges as well just to give myself a bit of variety.
I don't need that many segments however chunky block like that.
I'm fine with now it is pretty uniform but I'm quite happy with it.
But I am going to push it into the floor so I'm going to line my camera up zoom in because it's just
above the floor at the moment I'm going to go GZ and push it slightly into the floor.
Okay so we've got our our objects that we want to move around our doorway so to speak.
So where has that gone.
Let's call this archway bricks or something along those lines because that's what we're going to use
it for archway bricks.
And it's part of the building.
And in fact we've got a bit of a hierarchy problem here.
I'm going to use the parenting I'm going to enable all of this.
I can definitely select them.
So the door mirror all of these archways as well I'm holding down shift walls that do that and whilst
I've still got shift height held down I'm going to click and drag it on the doorway and it will set
the doorway is the parent for all of those objects.
That's a much better hierarchy to look at and all of these are to do with the doorway.
Okay.
So I'm going expand that again and select my archway bricks that we've created.
I'm going to hide the other ones there.
Okay.
Now we go to the modifiers tabs we've got a couple of options that we can use here.
There's the option of a curve.
So we're going to deform the bricks based upon a curve.
Is that what we want to do.
Kind of.
Because that won't repeat the bricks.
Now what do we need in order to repeat something you remember.
That's right.
The array modifier.
Now if we use the array modifier what we can now do is fit type.
We can fit it to a curve.
We've already got the curve going round that's the curve direction so we can go ahead and select that.
So now this is the appropriate length apparently to go all the way around our curve.
Now of course we can just half that later on absolutely fine.
But it's not bending around the curve at all.
So what we can do now is we can go and add another modify and deform this array so it fits the curve.
And once again we can pick the curve direction as the profile that we're going to be following.
Now this doesn't look right.
It kind of works and it's completely the wrong way.
So this is where you can have a look at your defamation axes and see if you can find one that works.
But it's not a defamation access in this count it is the means tilt of the archway curve.
So there's a couple of options that we can do here.
We can go back to the curve direction.
So that's what we saw in that showing that's unlike the archway curved direction and then with that
selected go into edit mode I seem to have lots of objects selected let's just select the archway itself
the curve direction go into edit mode.
And now if we adjust the mean tilt look the bricks move round for us as well.
But it changes the other curve extrusion that we've got going on.
So we don't want to destroy that.
So we can even duplicate the curve direction and use it specifically for the brickwork which would be
absolutely fine or we could just rotate our bricks round again both of them are absolutely fine.
I'm going to hide my curved direction and just to demonstrate that if I go into edit mode on my archway
bricks you'll notice that it hops around and that can be quite annoying if we can't see what's really
going on.
So we can turn on this option here on the curve modifier so we can see what's happening in edit mode
and then we can rotate things around to our heart's content.
So let's try rotating on the z axis.
No on the y axis well maybe on the x axis.
There we go.
That's what we need to do.
We need to rotate it round so it looks flat by the looks of it.
So let's rotate it round 90 degrees.
That looks very odd doesn't it.
And then I'm going to just move it around so g z up and down seems to work.
Oh no I haven't quite got it the right way round.
Let's continue rotating it now at this point in time I'm looking at that going.
Actually that doesn't look too bad in terms but it's not what I intended.
So let's go back into edit mode make sure everything selected and rotate it once again until we get
the right fit.
Now that's pretty cool.
I might just keep that you know that is pretty awesome.
That's not why I was expecting.
Here we go.
Let's see these rotating around a little bit more.
Let's do it by whole numbers.
Ninety is not bad.
Minus 90 is probably what I was looking for.
That looks spot on right now.
It would be entirely up to you which way you do.
I would actually recommend a different curve direction and follow round because then it's more intuitive
what this object is actually doing.
But ultimately your end result is what matters.
Okay.
Now where this is around the arch is a little bit problematic.
So let's go in and sort that out.
What's the reason for this.
Well if you remember with curves it matters where it starts.
So our issue here with it going up and down again this distance here is probably the same distance as
it is to the origin of our world.
So once again in edit mode if I grab all of that remembering that a curve only perceives the world in
to day and move that along the x axis all the way back to the origin look at that.
It matches however as it goes around here we can very easily see that it doesn't do what I would have
hoped it would and work all the way round and end perfectly.
You might want that type of look for your game or for your assets for your game.
I don't want that look I want it to end.
So one of the best things I can do is go back half way around and then just mirror it.
So what we can do here is go into the array modifier itself and at the moment we're fitting the curve
which is absolutely fine.
We can play with relative offset constant offsets going to be a bit more picky.
So I prefer relative offset of let's say adding a bit more or a few more gaps inside the brickwork.
Absolutely fine.
I'm going to leave it as one though because I like that nice tight brickwork.
But what we can do here is instead of fitting the curve we can go ahead and just fit a certain length
at the moment.
There is nothing there but as we increase that we can see it builds up in fact it's going backwards
in this case and that's about the middle.
Just up there.
Perfect.
Can I get a negative with my length.
No I can't.
So let's work with it like that.
That's absolutely fine.
And what I can now do is add another modifier right at the bottom.
A mirror modifier it's not going to match but we've already got a mirror point in our scene our door
mirror.
So let's use that now that's almost perfect.
You see how they grouped together like that.
And again you've got a couple of options we could solidify at this point and then try and merge so we
could apply the array and curve modifier.
However I like the option of our geometry here being non-destructive giving us basically infinite variability
later down the line the moment we solidify this to a mesh we lose quite a bit of control.
Little things like maybe not the defamation axis there but maybe adding a little bits of relative offset
which should merge the two top like so we can continue pushing them together.
So let's try a relative offset of that looks pretty good I'm holding down shift here to get a smaller
value but yeah it looks like a nice Keystone.
I think they call it at the very top.
I like that.
And of course you can use this technique with more mesh detail or less.
Just bear in mind the more you put in if you added another brick in here you'd have to rejig how this
merges together.
Yeah I really like how that's come together.
And of course now what we can do is go back to that mirror modifier and repeat on the y axis as well.
Look at that.
Awesome.
Now one of the things I will finalize here by saying is that if you really wants to make an impact with
these bricks you may want to solidify as I was talking about actually applying all of these modifiers
maybe taking a copy first so you can always rewind.
And then what I would do is make sure that some of the edges were a bit more worn or a bit less uniform
so it doesn't look quite new.
The other thing that I do want to do here is look how shallow these are.
So I'm going to go in if I already am in edit mode of these these bricks here and I'm going to go g
and Y.
Remember this works on two axes.
So I want the Brooke Block words come out a little on that direction so I can actually have the edges
of the bricks coming through but it not be too deep.
That's really good that way but I want the brick work this way to be much deeper so like a g x.
That's the up and down that we've talked about before said g z is going to be backwards and forwards
and then we can have massive block work.
Something about that I should imagine.
Excellent.
Wow.
Yes.
Brilliant.
I'm loving how that's coming together.
Now this is giving you a lot of scope for variations on your doors.
Really looking forward to seeing what you come up with.
Please share your work over in the discussions and I'll see you well in the next lecture.