In this video where vertex painting our head and adding a layer of detailing these layers so to show
you how to blend the various layers so that you can tweak and shoot in a non-destructive fashion when
it comes to painting your models.
Okay let's get started.
We're back into our head sculpt file I'm going to start you off with a challenge to get everything set
up for painting vertex painting our head so get the point where you're ready add some lights I'm gonna
add three point light to my scene make sure you have a material there might be a material at the moment
but make sure you do have one rename your vertex color layer to base or something similar main that's
it's gonna be the main color of of your model and then setup your shader Ed so you can see the base
layer in render view remember how we did that in the previous video how we can see it by plugging in
that base layer so that we can see what's going on there when we're in our render view and then to create
a palette and to select main skin color to so find a color that you think represents what you're going
for in your painting so there's you challenge posed a video take that on and then I will jump in when
you come back right I'll start off with setting up some lines I'm going to object mode I'll do this
very quickly just a three point lighting we've done this before so I'll do it super quick sticks for
you shift a at a light g to move it out I think I need to have it more powerful I've got it currently
at 10 let's make this rule go 200 nice and big point.
There we go.
And then shift to move over to the right shift team move to the back on just a little bit of finessing
of this
I'm going to change my view so in viewpoint shading click on the little selector instead of having the
mo cap lighting I'm going to click on just the first one basic lighting so that we're not looking at
clay and then when I go into my render view let's move the lights around a little bit to get what we're
looking for we'll have this be our main light pump up the power on that little bit more
Okay next up click back on head and jump in a vertex paint Moz I'm good and ready over there let's find
whether we have a material at the moment I do have a material if you didn't then just click plus and
add in a material rename this make this head material so it's nice and clear.
Excellent.
What's up next on our list of tattoos rename our last so click down on our object data properties open
up vertex colors I'm gonna rename this to base it's all about the bass no treble.
Next we're looking at our shader editor so up in the very top left in our second window I'm going to
select shader ED From here you can see because we have a material set up we're ready to go I'm going
to shift a inputs vertex colors base let's hook the base into the base color it's not going to do much
over here and then the final step on our list was to select a color that we're gonna have as our main
color back up to our active tools scroll up scroll up we're going to scroll around there and say oh
yeah near enough is good enough for that color but I to get a little bit more precise so I've searched
for skin color hex values in the Google and I Okay this is roughly the color I'm looking for f f DFC
for it see if I can remember that and I will click on my color select.
So underneath the color wheel I'll click on the color we currently have selected and or created I guess
click on hex and it was f f d something's up or something f before for FC 4.
Okay so make yours whatever color you think is relevant.
I'm going to shift.
K Well master over it.
There we go.
That's kind of a general Clay look and color specific kind of whitish yellowish pinkish it's near enough
is good enough I think for the moment because we're gonna be doing a little bit of painting and then
as I said a new color palette and we'll add this to our color palette so we don't lose it.
Okay.
Great we're ready to go.
So on the base layer we're going to add a little bit of detail.
I've gone in swapped out my reference so every now and again I guess we'll go have a look at our reference
the lighting in my image is pretty crummy.
Not very good at all it's very blown out very very overly exposed I think.
So I can do a little bit of poetic license when it comes to painting my character.
But you can see there's a pink color around the mouth.
It's a little bit darker on the nose in between the with a mono brow would be in between the eyeballs
and I've got a little bit of stubble action going on there.
So bearing that in mind I'm going to change the color a little bit more over to the right side to get
a bit more pink going on in what we're doing.
Decrease the strength six point six ish decrease my brush size just a little bit of painting over areas
where we want the color to be a little bit different little bit Pinker a little bit more blood vessels
going on if you will around the mouth definitely my computer starting to hemorrhage a little bit so
my apologies if the recording goes a little bit wonky or a little bit fuzzy it's saying to me Rick it's
time to get a new computer because Blender is a greedy beast okay paint is a little bit with this pink
color just putting in some accents are going to increase the brush size and just a little bit of splurging
around on the head so it's not one big old solid color.
I think skin it's good to get in some.
I was gonna say texture it's not really texture per say it's just some difference some some variations
so it doesn't look quite so flat.
And then I'm going to get these the Blur tool and just do a little bit of blur.
Make sure it's not there's no harsh lines were saying you won't have it so it looks like it's a little
bit more blended a little bit more natural.
We didn't talk about this much in the last video but there's a little bit of a question why on earth
would we vertex paint why wouldn't we do texture painting texture painting we can get a lot more detail
we can putting all the freckles and moles and dots is a lot more power is going on we're not constrained
just by how many vertices we've got nous in our scene or on our model it's because of the speed we don't
have to do the UVA unwrapping we don't have to read apologize we can just paint straight on our models
so if we do have a lot of vertices then it helps from that perspective so that's why we're doing this
it's probably not as good in terms of final quality as if we unwrap and paint right onto our texture.
But from a speed point of view we can get lots of really great results without having to go through
that step.
Our base not too bad and I just realized why my computer is struggling it's because I'm painting in
render view I'm going gonna go back into my solid view now everything's gonna go much much more quickly
it's not going to hopefully anyway.
One thing you might consider doing that I often forget to do is you can click on symmetry so that we
can just be painting one side and have it mirrored at this point.
I often like to get a little bit of variation so it doesn't look exactly symmetrical symmetry saves
a lot of time but faces aren't symmetrical so I think it's good to sometimes have symmetry turned off
if you're not doing a lot of work I'm gonna jump back into my shader editor view because what we'd like
to do here is add a second layer scroll back down to our object data properties open that up you can
see on a vertex colors I'm going to click on plus add a new layer here this layer is going to be called
see dark because I'm gonna be adding the dark patches under the eyes and so that we can visualize it
over in our shade.
Ed I'm going to shift input vertex colors and dark now dark.
I'll connect that color up to the base color so that should be what we're looking at in the range of
you click on the render view now it's going to show what we previously had which is nice of it which
is cool.
Okay now I want to start from a blank canvas the way I'll do that is to jump into selecting White and
the quick way to do that is click on RG B and make sure the values are set to 1 someone white here shift
K so now we have no color information at all on our sculpture I'm going to choose a bluey kind of color
add that to the palettes not super dark I'm going to turn the strength down down down down although
it doesn't matter so much if you have the strength a little bit higher because we are going to blend
these two together we'll go put the splotches under the eyes here if you keep your mouse held down then
it's not going to build up the color on top of each other so you can get into the spots that you want
if I let go and then hold down again it's gonna be adding more dark on top of dark so just bear that
in mind as you putting things down and I could have added symmetry and this would have made things a
little bit easier but as I said before I'd like to get some variation so that it's not exactly symmetrical
so long as it doesn't take too much time so I get these dark colors in here we're gonna blend it so
that we get the right amount of darkness not too much it's currently looking like a raccoon superhero
axe I'm going to jump back over into my solid shading just in case that's going to speed things up a
little bit so we're not sitting there rendering back over to our shader Ed we're going to shift a and
search for mics are G.B. that will mix our RG base on mix our colors drop that down that'll speech things
around a bit color is automatically hooked to base color the color of the actually read here instead
of hooking into color one just to make things easy I'm going to have that hook to color too and our
base hooked to color one just so the lines aren't overlapping not that it matters just I feel it's a
little bit tidier and now we look at and say Oh that really didn't really do much.
That's because I'm not in my render view so jumped out a round of you prematurely.
Now that will blend the two together and you can see very subtle dark underneath the eyes here if I
drag to the right it will make it dark it basically say bring more of the color information from the
dark attribute if I drag to the left as I bring more of the color from the base however you can see
that as we move to the right our whole guide becomes like a ghost that's not what we once I'm going
to change the blending properties from mix to color and drag it back down again get it to the point
where it's subtle you can see there's a little bit of yucky artifact thing going on there if you're
getting that pronounced on yours you can always go back to your light reconnect color to base color
form so that's what we're visualizing in here and then jump back up to you tools have a little paint
round in here see if it needs more detail more down the bottom see if it needs to be blurred.
See if that's because you don't have enough vertices in there perhaps or it could be that our base is
white and it would be better for us to have our base as more of a pink color so we can experiment with
that just giving you a couple of solutions in case things have gone astray when you you're merging so
if we do.
Back to this that will wipe all the information we had Poppy now blue again and it is symmetry this
time just to speed it up
OK.
Now let's plug the colors back color to color so color of our mixed into color and that'll show us what
the mix looks like okay that's fixed a little bit of that problem it's made our character more on the
kind of base color than we might want so it's a process a process of experimenting how much you want
it makes how much you want to blend if we move all to the right then we've got these kind of very pronounced
underneath if we drag more to the left then they go away and our base comes through sir.
And about there I think just have a little bit of that subtle blueness in there.
But the cool thing is we can easily jump back in and dock in that up in our actual painting on our layer
which if I paint now that's what's happening where painting the darkness and it's being blended as we
want it to.
And you know I think on this layer on this dark layer I'm also gonna do some detail for the lips.
I think that is a good place to do it.
So let's find a color that looks a little bit more lippy and darken it and see if that is giving us
the result we want again.
Make sure we're on the correct layer.
Make sure that our layering is coming through just dark and out the left I might make them a bit more
purples dark okay.
Because we have that underlying tone to it and then I'm going to give it a little bit of pink color.
Now you could do these as two different layers the eyes and the lips that's a totally perfectly cool
way of doing it.
I'm going to do them on the same just to speed things up a little bit but feel free to have as many
layers as you want.
You can blend them all together a little with this pink little bit apprehensive when I'm creating my
own mouth my own lips.
Because when you put a whole bunch of pink on your lips it makes you look a little bit more feminine.
I find some guys apprehensive about making my lips look too pink they probably needs to be a little
bit darker in the pink area.
I think
remember that we've got our blending going on here so I've got it at point eight strength but it's also
being blended at point four.
So it's not coming through super super strongly.
I'm going to add this color to the palette just one of the colors I've been using because I realize
I've gone and painted lipstick all over the side of my face.
Let's go and recalibrate away.
Not too bad not perfect you get the point I'm showing you the technique here even if I'm not showing
you the best artistry on how to create these things but as we get to the end of the process things are
going to merge together a lot more cleanly so keep them reasonably contrasting at the moment so you
can see them in a pronounced way.
The thing I'm not digging is that I've lost a lot of my bass pink coloring so again while I found this
good blend between the two I'm going to go back to my first base level.
This is what we can do.
Jump between the layers it's totally okay to do this.
Jump back to base click on my tool just find the pink color and just get some of that pink back in the
nose and go to this other view so it's nice and easy and you can see here I'm looking at just the layer
that I've selected on when I do this and I'm gonna have to make this a little bit stronger for it to
show through that's what's what it's telling me here when I go to this base layer caucus when I go to
the rendered view you can see that's the amount of color that's coming through so it's great to jump
between these views if you want to paint okay now I'm painting just on the layer getting more of that
kind of redness around the mouth around the nose on the ears and then jump back into the range of you
to see how it looks after we've blended them together you can see a little bit of that's coming through
probably a little bit more up on the for head up here and then as I did before just a little bit of
coloration it sneaks through on the rest of the head.
Okay.
And then the last layer I'll do the super quickly.
I think you get the point by now as I'm gonna put a little bit of kind of dark a bead mark here I might
put some hair on that at some point but while we're just focusing on painting my goal here is just to
get a little bit of darkness for the beard.
So let's jump down to our object outer properties click a another layer we'll call this I'll call this
hair.
I think I might do hair on the top of the head as well we'll see how it goes up to you for how you want
to do yours if you're doing a lady you might not need to do these steps and over on the left let's open
up our Shada editor again shift a input vertex colors and hair.
I just made a little bit of mistakes I've undone a few things and edited that part of the video because
I accidentally put in another layer of dark and it looked really weird.
OK let's plug.
Actually no.
I'm gonna mix all these together and do this on the fly rather than just doing the hair the facial hair
and then merging them later let's do this all the same time to do that I'm going to shift a search for
mics are G.B. we'll plug this into base color then we'll plug the previous color that we'd mixed together
into color one and we'll head into color two instead of being mixed I'm going to changes to multiply
let's just do a quick experience ceremony to make sure we're doing what we think we're doing will do
a big dark patch in here paint that on on multiply if we turn that to the right it gets dark it's in
that to the left it gets lighter Yeah that's pretty much what we want to do now if I change out how
much we're multiplying here we're getting a pretty extreme effect on the rest of the body at the arrest
the head not just on the bit that we've painted down so let's undo that painting hook things back up
of gangs we did our undo.
We'll see if we can look at just that one layer so I'm going to drag hair into our base color of our
principal be SDF and this is what we're seeing we've got all of this information for that's been brought
in from our other layers it's copied it onto this layer the pinks and the the yellows as well as this
we'd kind of facial hair that we've painted down so I got to choose my white color now if I shift K
they'll make everything white I'll go back and grab my color plug it into my mixture where I'm multiplying
and then color from my multiply mix into base color so our first colors are going to multiply we're
multiplying this factor if I change it up and down we're not seeing a different look.
So that's why it's often good to recalibrate typically the color when you go to a new layer to make
it all white or to make it something that's relevant to the sort of mixture you're doing so make it
all white.
Now if we paint on hair make sure we're painting on hair we'll go and find a bluey kind of color tend
this strength down a little bit we should see the result of painting this and then if we think it's
not strong enough we can increase or decrease it
okay if I look at that light on that to be a little bit darker then we can just drag it up and we make
that facial hair kind of look a bit darker you know as a last step I will paint some hair this is gonna
be really different if you're working with a reference it does have hair there's different techniques
for us to do that you could have sculpted out the hair and then color the hair or we could add use hand
modifies will play around with later on but for now I'm just gonna paint a little bit of hair over the
top of my character just so it makes sense
one final thing I'll show you here just to illustrate the point of how cool this is using this system
is I've looked here it looks like my hair goes down too far and like I don't like that if I get back
into my solid view and click on object data properties then select hair you can see it just shows me
there's hair layer layer I can see where I've painted I know that it's this kind of bluish smudge I've
put around I've missed a couple of bits here that's good to see that I can for example go in and blur
that and smooth it down.
Good to know but also there's this bit here on like oh how did I do that.
Don't like that at all because I've got this white under color here if I go and grab White from my color
palette I can paint up very cleanly very accurately to remove that and get the precision that I want
for that particular part of my coloring and then when I click on my shade of view you can see that it
has nicely merged them together.
That's a good way of working just on a layer and to see the impact.
I like to work in a way or I can see what the final result is going to be but it's also really nice
to be out to see what the raw layout just on its own is doing okay.
So that's all I wanted to cover in this video.
Great stuff.
I look forward to seeing what you've come up with please do post in the discussions if you've got something
you would like to share and I'll see you in the next lecture.