Hello everybody and welcome to this special lecture just on the outline.
Now the outline if you move your eyes to the right hand side of the screen is this area at the top here
we're going to use it lots whenever we're working in blender.
It's great we can select objects by just clicking on them we can double click in order to rename and
we could also hide and show items from our scene with this little icon.
Now as blenders evolved we've actually lost some icons on the right hand side here that some of you
might have been used to up until this point.
And where are they.
Well they're hidden under the filter options at the top.
So let's just make this area slightly wider so we can see everything.
And let's go along the top and what it's all about.
This first one at the top that is all to do with the editor type so we can change it to any other window
type within blender.
We're not going to do that.
We'll play with the next one along later on.
And this allows us to change the outline to look at different parts of Blender.
Typically we'll be diving in between scenes and view layer by default it comes to view layer which mainly
focuses around collections.
However scenes is something that you may also be interested in as it breaks things down slightly differently.
Let's switch that back to view layer for the moment.
This search box you probably guessed allows us to search for the item we're looking for.
Now when we've got three items in our scene three objects a camera a mesh object called cube and a light
it's not going to be too difficult to find things however later on when your scenes get more complex
you will definitely be making use of the search function.
Now the filter that I was alluding to earlier if we click on that it gives us a series of options and
it's just not disappear from it.
And at the top here we've got our restriction toggles now blender in the past used to have selectable
there rendering which is the camera icon and this little object here that looks like a screen.
So if we turn those four items back on and then have a look we see that they're back here.
Now we'll delve into more details later on on how you're going to use these things.
But a quick run through of these four items we've got this cursor here which allows us to make sure
we can turn off selections.
So when you've got a quite dense scene with many many objects in it being able to not select certain
items is really really useful including the lights and camera.
So often it's useful to turn those off because if your view goes round in front of an object you can
accidentally have a tense selection for the light back on.
You can actually end up selecting the lights rather than the cube which in some cases would be really
really annoying.
So you can turn off the selection.
We can hide them from our view.
However with things like the lights and camera that can be a bad idea because it also removes their
effects on the scene as well as the icon being a temporary disable.
We have the screen icon which is a global disable is very similar but it will make it disappear from
all view ports and then the final one here is one that I'll catch you out later on if you've inadvertently
clicked and it's got a cross there rather than the normal camera icon when you go and render out your
scenes later on you just won't have anything there which is useful if you've got something that you
wants there when you're modelling but not on the final render.
Now all that we've gone through here we will have another look at with more detail later on as and when
we need them.
But I know this is going to catch some of you out straightaway early especially those that have been
used to blender for a while.
So thought I'd include it nice and early in the course.
That's it for this quick tip and I'll see you all in the next one.