And this video we're talking about subsurface scattering and we're going to create a new layer that
will plug into the subsurface so we can get some subsurface scattering going on so let's talk about
what this is all about.
But first couple of quick points I did a little bit of fiddling with my character off screen made the
hair a bit darker.
And the second thing I'm at the point now where I'm annoyed with how shiny my character is.
Skin has a little bit of shyness but not that much.
So I'm gonna go into my main node and just turn speculum all the way down so the character now doesn't
have that shiny penis.
We can go and put that back in later on but now I just wanted to get a consistent flat not speculative
feel like you only have a little bit in your if you felt that makes it feel natural then you can pump
it up just a little bit to get a little bit of that greasy oil back on your face if you wanted to.
Okay now let's talk about subsurface scattering.
I've got an image here which I'm sure you've done yourself.
You've put the flashlight or torch up against that your hand and you can see that the light shines through.
Now it's not shining directly through what's happening is the light is hitting your skin and then being
dispersed or scattering amongst your skin.
So some materials the light hits it and just stops it's not scattering it's not spreading throughout
that material that you can see here very clearly particularly thin skin.
Like in the ears or in the nostrils the light is is penetrating through the skin but not just being
shown through the skin but also it's spreading around and getting that effect.
And that's what we're going to be simulating in blender.
And the first part of this exercise is to jump back into our properties and to for our vertex colors
add a new layer this layer we will call subsurface scattering or SS s for short.
And then within our shader Ed shift a input vertex colors SPSS drop this down the bottom here.
Now going to go back to my solid shading view find SPSS which we're on.
Once again I will make sure I'm clicked on my brush.
Start off with white.
So shift K The whole thing's entirely white.
Now if I plug the F A C the factor on my attribute you can see you've got f I see the step and we plug
that in to sub surface boink like that subsurface.
Now go back over to our render view.
You can see are crazy it's crazy for me because I've been playing around with this subsurface color
it's red.
If we put this back to its default of white if I can do that properly right in the middle of White what
do we get we get this kind of really weird but cool but not weird more than anything else.
Wax figure which is great.
That shows when we have one hundred percent.
So it's completely black.
We've got this really weird crazy thing going on.
That's not what we want.
Note a ball with the surface and subsurface color is I put it all white I could have said well let's
make it pink and so we get this kind of pink waxy kind of figure we will make it a little bit pinkish
a little bit skin color.
If now put it back to white so we can illustrate what's going on.
Now I'm gonna go back into where are we back into.
Yes we're still on SPSS I can do my solid shading view grab my paintbrush and instead of white I am
going to go and paint with 100 percent strength blacks I've just dragged the line all the way down to
the bottom on the color I'm going to just paint paint paint paint across the frontier paint paint paint
all of black full of black along the front and I've still got my mirroring on in case you're wondering
about that pink paint paint paint up to that point then let's see what's happened when I've done that
we've got regular on the bottom and wax we'd wax figure on the top in a way this is kind of a cool effect
but not what I'm going for in this particular instance you can see that when it's 100 percent black
it doesn't apply any of the subsurface scattering when it's 100 percent white it implies a whole bunch
of it.
So what we're going to do is back over into our solid view make sure we're on the right layer.
Okay.
I'm gonna undo that painting yet call me to undo it now I'm going to do is jump up to paint and so click
on dirty vertex colors it's gonna take a moment to calculate that hopefully my computer doesn't crash
come on blender you can do it you can do it.
What's that showing is that from Napoleon Dynamite.
No I think I'm thinking something different.
Okay.
And that applies a little bit of it's trying to go around and find the edges the sharper bits and make
them more white make the other areas more dark I find that when I do this I get Okay results.
However for some reason my subsurface colors come back to red again I don't have that shock as we had
last time we go ahead and have a look at how this is I still find it's too waxy we're getting too much
of that waxy effect in this particular instance so that might have worked perfectly for you but I find
we need to do some tweaking on top of this I'm going to go and select a fairly dark ish brush make it
pretty big and just go and paint nice and dark the areas that I don't want to have too much applied
too so remember we'll get more of that subsurface scattering when we have white and less of it when
we have darker.
So let's see what happens if we go around and just a little bit of I'm gonna make this even darker I
think and pump up the strength
Oh it's the airbender paint up the middle so make it fairly dark ish OK now I'm going to switch it back
up to white strength down a little bit low I don't want it to too strong I want to overpowering definitely
on the ease the ease is where we really have this subsurface scattering come to the fore because they're
quite thin quite thin fleshy bits of our body got a little bit of bleed there that shouldn't matter
but we'll see how it goes just take note of that and then definitely on the nostrils nostrils nostrils
nostrils I know you can do that too low definitely on the nostrils leave it on the nose you might need
to come back and repaint that someone are getting too high but we'll see how it goes.
Little bit on the lips but I'm going to turn the power down the strength down that is going to go a
little bit of blurring so it's a bit smoother.
We don't want sharp edges when we're doing this because your skin tends to not go from one sharp bit
to another sharp but it's more smooth and curves organic after all this is organic modelling that we're
doing at the moment so make sure we get that organic look by doing lots of smashing and smudging.
Okay.
Now let's just go and have a look at what we've got here.
Change the render view.
So I'm gonna change the color dramatically so we can see where it's popping.
If I make it very red then you can see we're getting this sort of pinkish is is are often pinkish when
we get that going on and a super important point as we saw in the other are the live examples where
we're doing it.
It depends a lot on what you're doing with your light.
So if you're finding that you're getting the not getting the effect you're after just play around with
where your lights are positioned object mode move it around a little bit here often if you put one right
behind the character's head you can see what's going on in those is super clearly back in the vertex
paint.
Make sure I'm clipped on the head.
Yes okay.
So I don't want it to be quite as pink as that so just bring it back up into the middle.
Okay.
And then you can see these is have a little bit more of that kind of fleshy see through feel to them.
And so it's up to you you can go and paint a little bit more do a little bit less.
Make it more pink.
Sorry.
This is the way you can make it stronger less strong.
You're on a scooter a little bit more orange you can.
That's totally cool if you want to get that feel to it.
So if you look here on this eyebrow I've got it more strongly lit.
The E has more definition to it.
There's a there's a tiny bit of that see through it kind of feeling to it vibe to it.
So play around if you want to put a little bit more speculum back in here so you do get a little bit
more of the shiny you can do that play around with your color so that you get the color that you think
is naturally shining through when you've got the inner parts of the skin and obviously play around with
how much you paint how much you unpainted when it comes to the color you put in here.
Okay.
I've just been doing a little fiddling around off camera to say you haven't have to watch every brush
stroke.
This is what I'm going for at the moment with my final layout just for head nose cheekbones round the
mouth eyes et cetera.
I'm also going to just have a little bit of a play with the subsurface radius and the moment it's set
to 1 so if I click on subsurface radius it brings up these three little boxes here and I drop this down
and see you can see if you lift it up it really balloons everything out it makes it glow a lot.
Very impressive so I'm going to drop it down I think to a very low point point three I think second
they point to if we increase that you can see.
Likewise we get a bit of a glow.
I'm going to drop that one down quite a bit.
Just mouse off it.
Two point one and then the last one I found doesn't do a great deal if I if I change it up and down
doesn't do a lot so I'm just gonna leave that pretty low pretty much where it was.
So the challenge I have for you is to apply subsurface scattering to your model and then do a final
pass with tweaking all your different layers and how you've painted them the colors the lights you've
gotten this you're seeing the strengths of the blending between the different layers and get it to the
point where you're happy with it and render it.
And please do share it with us.
I think that's enough for now in terms of our playing around with the human head and the texture vertex
painting so in the next videos we'll move on to something a little bit different.
So put a little bit of love into it now and let us know what you've done and what you've got.
And when you've done that I will see you in the next video.