Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to have a look at making this Mayan pyramid type shape in front of us.
Now the moment this is all the Fidelity we need so we're not going to go full blown Mayan on this was
simply setting up the base structure so that we can add more details later and you'll find this is common
when you're making models in general.
You don't wanna go straight for that high fidelity go for a low poly simple version of your model first
and then add the details later.
So let's hop on over into blender and use the inset tool to create this object.
Hello everybody and welcome.
So let's have a look at the setting.
I'm going to go into edit mode and it's a face operation so I'm gonna make sure we've got a face select
turned on.
Now if I select this top face here extrude it by nothing.
Which is something you can do even that creates geometry on top of itself.
We're not gonna leave it like that so that's okay.
Now we can scale that in and when we do we get an object like this.
And if we extrude and extrude by nothing and scale it in we get a similar sort of step shape as that
pyramid.
So that's pretty good.
We can get in and then just make a final edit there to make it look a bit more interesting.
Okay.
So now we've tested that y about this inset tool.
So let's select the face closest to us over here.
Now the inset all can be gotten from this tall shelf.
If I press the T key to bring that's up we have inset faces and we can see those shortcut key for it
is I.
And that is predominately what I will use I will often use the shortcut keys because over time you learn
that using them is going to be far far quicker than finding the right buttons of press.
However this man you can also be very useful if you have a touch screen for instance you can scroll
down and tap the one that you want and then carry on with the operation.
And I will upset because it's a face operation we can also find it in the face menu under inset faces
pretty awesome.
So let's see what inset faces does.
Oh it seems to do that extruded by nothing and scaling altogether.
Okay let's have a look at the operator panel this produces.
So let's open it up.
And there we go.
We've got lots and lots of options.
Some of them only apply if you've got neighboring faces selected when you perform an inset.
Some of them do something completely different.
So let's go ahead and extrude this face out and scale it in.
So it kind of mirrors the top one over here because we're going to play with both of these.
We'll start off with this one at the front that we're already working on and I'm going to insert it
again and just click now because I haven't done anything else.
The operator panel will still be there and then we can start having a look at some of these options.
The first one is the opposite of in the setting which is our setting.
So instead of moving the geometry inwards here I was to click that you can see it's moving the other
way and the thickness is pushing geometry back away from that face.
So that can be incredibly useful if you do need to add a little bit of extra geometry underneath.
There are other ways of doing this as well.
There are always other ways of doing things in Blender now going to these select outset for the moment
and I'm going to tweak this thickness here until I get a relatively good size for me.
Now we've got this depth slider here as well so we can automatically push things out at the same time.
Now that's really cool because you can do multiple operations all in one go if you wanted to.
Often I would insert and then move things manually because that to me feels like more control.
However if you know exactly what you're doing and you're just tweaking these figures here then that's
absolutely fine.
Now because I've clicked away when I was trying to show you something.
I've lost the in setting I've done something else.
There's nothing I can do to get back to the operator panel has questions asked the lot and unfortunately
you've done another operation you no longer have access to the previous ones.
Let's select this top one at the top here and do some other stuff.
I'm also going to hold down shift and select these other faces as well under pressure the insect key
and see what happens.
Okay.
That's interesting.
Hmm what's going on there.
Well there are a couple of things that you will notice as you go through these options and I do encourage
you to play with them.
Not only can you hover over the top of them which gives you a tool tip but it's good to play it's how
you discover things.
So these two seem to do absolutely nothing compared to what we've got at the top here.
OK let's see if we can just tweak this number here to a lower figure because occasion it can get a bit
too large no offset relative that makes very little difference to this as well edge rail does make a
little bit of a difference it keeps these edges in line rather than bending them out a little further.
Okay.
So I quite liked the fact that it's keeping the edge rail in line it saves me having to reach scale
and tweak it about later on and the offset relative I'm going to turn off outset we've already played
with select outer.
So that selects the new part of the geometry that's being created that's quite useful sometimes I'll
show that again in the bits.
But the one I'm getting to is individual look how much different that is compared to that it's completely
different.
Individual is something I use quite a bit especially when you transport holes or windows in an object
is a good way of doing so because then you can do something to this additional geometry and depending
on what you're trying to do this always going to be another way of creating holes or a window within
your object like this.
Let's go ahead and select this other one and inset it in because I wanted to show you these select outer.
So once we've done that we can click on select outer and it actually selects the border.
So that does mean that you can go in straight away and maybe extrude that out to make more of a tunnel
going on.
And of course because we've done that we've lost the operator panel.
So once again there's a little hint there that make sure you finish the current operation before doing
something else whether it's moving scaling rotating extruded et cetera et cetera.
Any other operation will get rid of the operator panel.
Okay so that's a good play with in.
And I've got some sort of I I know command module for a spaceship or something exciting like that.
So do play with Blender and come up with some weird and funky shapes you'll be amazed at what actually
turns into a good idea or certainly sparks something.
Then you can develop into a good idea.
And now we've played around with in setting it's time for your challenge Okay everybody it's time for
your challenge.
Now this is gonna be the first time I'm gonna be very specific.
Quality design brief imagine a client to come to you and said I want a pyramid that's 20 by 20 meters
on the base and has seven steps so let's run through the specification.
I want you to scale the default cube to 20 meters by 20 meters by two meters.
Once you've done that create steps of one meter in and one meter up so you'll be inserting by one meter
and then extruded by one meter as you go.
Now this is critical as we want a 45 degree angle for later on.
And of course if you're looking at reference material of a mind pyramid you'll notice that it isn't
quite as crude as that.
But for the purposes of this exercise we do want it to be a 45 degree angle so we need to go in by one
meter and up by one meter and we're going to create a total of seven steps including that first one.
So that will be counted in the first step.
When you've done that we're going to create a little room in a building on top which is going to be
two to four meters high so you're going to inset it's two meters from the last step and then extrude
up analogue.
I'll give you a bit of freedom here two to four meters I'll probably go smack bang in the middle at
three meters.
Hey guys.
Mark hey at some point you're going to see Mike in when they 7 step pyramid and sometimes it's gonna
be a nice step pyramid.
This is a little bit of an overhang from the Old Course where we used an eight step pyramid.
It doesn't really matter which you use and doesn't really matter how many steps you put in that we can
leave up to you but when you get to making these stairs later on you may need to use different values
to get the right angles.
And with that back to Mikey.
So go ahead pause video now and we're aiming to have something like this by the end of this challenge.
Give it a go and I'll see you back in a few moments.
Let's go ahead and make up my own pyramid or suddenly the base mash for it's in front of us.
We have our default cube and it is of a size two meters by two meters by two meters.
So we just need to scale this by 10.
Now we have two options we can do that in object mode and apply or we can do it in edit mode.
I'm gonna save myself some work and do it in edit mode.
Everything is selecting the bigger scale things by 10 but not on the z axis.
I'm going press shift in Z to do that.
To press Enter to confirm.
So the next thing we need to do is in set.
So let's go ahead and select the top face.
Press the eye key and I'm gonna move in roughly because we really need to look at what's going on in
the operator panel.
Now the thickness itself I'm going to set it as one and then I'm going to look at our model from the
top and just zoom into the top corner that looks like we've got the right amount.
And the reason why that's work is because let's just um take these other things here.
We need the offset even which is fine we don't need boundary enabled now offset relative would base
it upon the scale of our object.
So in this case here if I was to go offset relative it would it would go right into the middle and through
itself but I could probably get away with points 1 so it's not quite there yet I think we need to offset
even at the same time.
There we go.
So point one of 20 is to blender units and there we go we can see that's two by two that I'm not gonna
do that I'm going to lever off and I'm literally going to type in the distance I want it to be sorry
I need offsets even turned on.
So there we go.
Now that I've done that I can go ahead here and extrude on the z axis by one inset by one extrude by
one.
Now you will notice that I can just repeat those two letter combinations.
I 1 e 1.
Now how does it know which direction I want to extrude on.
It's just remembered previously right.
I'm losing count of how many steps I've got here and we want seven in total so the first one two three
four one two three four five six seven perfect.
So now we just need the building on top somewhere inserts it by two in this case and extrude up by two
three.
There we go about three.
Perfect.
I'm liking the look of that.
Excellent.
Have you guys gotten on this is a very repetitive task but some tasks in Blender are repetitive.
I'd love to know if you found an easier way of making this mind pyramid without those two repeating
tasks.
There is a way in code to do it using the python console but that's not working in 2.8 just yet and
we'll cover things like that a bit more detail later on in the course.
But for now we've got our base my in pyramid shape sorted.
I'd like you to share your work over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.