Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to focus on creating a base for our lamp.
You can see.
Well let's get rid of the lamp itself so we can just see the base.
We're going to create a shape like this and we're going to use curves to make hits.
So this generation of data here this mesh that we can see is actually just a series of curves and bang.
Suddenly this comes to life.
Let's go ahead and find out more okay.
So let's learn about curves now and use a default scene in which to do it rather than our complex or
starting to become complicated scene.
And the other reason for doing that is because I can show you exactly with whole numbers.
Whereas I think our lamp is not going to be a whole number.
So the first thing we need to do is give it a path to follow around.
And so first of all we're going to add in a curve and we're going to make it a circle so you can just
follow around.
So this is a kind of profile modelling we're going to make the side of our lamp.
And it's going to follow that around.
So this is going to be the path.
So let's give it a path.
There we go.
And in fact in many ways this is although it is the path some it's also going to be the base itself.
So I'm also going to put path forward that's a really bad spelling a path we.
So that's the base.
That's the path that the curve we're about to produce is going to follow.
And let's go ahead and add in another curve and we're going to use a busier curve we had in a busier
curve and I'm going to call this one the profile curve some profile curve.
So what we're going to do here.
Oh dear my curve curse I must be cast anyway.
So we have a path and a profile for this to follow.
Let's see what happens if we plumb these things in so selecting the base and then going down to the
curve properties when we're in the curve properties we're going to scroll down much further until we
come to this area called geometry when we're there we open that up scroll down a little more and we've
got these Bevel options we're going to select and objects and in this case we're going to use our profile
curve that we've constructed and boom straight away we've got a 3d surface that's pretty awesome and
very quick we've got to that point you can see immediately that all you could probably do the bowling
pins like this or you could do the chess pieces like this or in this case the lamp base like this as
well now using curves is a good way of making sure that things are infinitely editable and we can change
the better year handle type in a moment and make Richard Sharp changes.
And it's great being able to define a curve and it automatically translating into a 3D shape.
Now one of the things you're probably asking here is well how do I control that curve underneath.
Well what I'm gonna do is I'm going to go into wireframe mode so we can see stuff.
I'm going to select my profile curve and move it around and you will notice that as I move it's around
this doesn't change.
Now from that we can understand that it's to do with the origin of this object and the circle that's
underneath.
So how does this work then what's going on.
And this curve obviously looks right this way but it's been projected round this way.
Really what is going on.
So the best way of looking at this is from a quad view.
So we're going to do that would control alt and Q It's going to split the viewport into four different
areas.
Once a 3D window is still the others are locked into all graphic perspective and the good thing about
this is I can zoom in here and we can see the profile from two different sides and because it's a circle
these two will be essentially the same and we can see our curve itself.
Now if I position the curve you probably if I zoom in here you can see the two lines that are running
around just here.
One of those is the circle.
The base path that we originally drew and you will find that if you line up the origin with the original
circle that we made which should be roughly around there any way it matches perfectly.
Now if we go into edit mode and start editing this you can see underneath the profile matches perfectly.
So if I was to grab this particular vertex point here and move it it will make this the base larger.
If I was to grab a hand or one of these bits at the top.
Press g a move it's around we can change the overall shape of things.
We can even have it come out slightly first.
Now if I change this just to a rendered mode for a moment you can see that we're starting to generate
quite some unique sets of geometry.
Now I am going to move it to this slight angle here and just demonstrates you that where this is on
the z axis doesn't matter at all.
All that does matter is where it is on the x and y axis.
So what does that mean.
Well that means that our curve itself when it's being used like this is a two dimensional object with
X and Y being the only coordinates that we worry about X in this case being its width and Y being its
height which is why if we move this point here this vertex at the very end across slightly we can produce
a hole in the middle.
Now I'm gonna rough out a rough idea here for a lamp base and of course we can tweak it in the challenge
itself.
Now you may want a sudden drop into that hole.
How do we do that with curves.
Well it's quite difficult when it's set like this but what we can do is select the whole curve right
click and subdivide it.
This will add a control point right where we want to.
In the middle it should give us a few more options for moving things around.
Now that we've added that you'll see that there are twice as many arrows going round.
So what we should really do is keep the level of detail or the resolution of the entire curve consistent.
So it was at 12.
Before we go over to the busier curve properties we lower that down to six it will now be consistent
with the amount of data that we had before.
So if we move this control point over here and move this one down slightly we've still got this curve
going round.
But what we can do is select the handle at the end we can move it round or we can try and gets it's
looking like it's 90 degrees or we can just go ahead.
Press the V key and change the handle type from automatic to vector vector is simply a straight line
and we do that to both of these.
What we will find is that it becomes a straight line which is really really useful.
That means we can then go g x move this back and have it in line and this will now go straight down
and you can see that over here in the viewport as well if we go back to wireframe mode for a moment
so we can see a bit clearer what's going on.
You can see here how we're able to form this particular shape very very easily just by manipulating
this curve.
The other thing that we can do if necessary is say we wanted to move this up a little and then extend
this particular line.
Well if we wanted to do that we could just select the control point that we want to extend.
Press the E key to essentially extrude new geometry and I'm going to scale that one in so that we don't
have control points overlapping.
Now the obvious issue here is we've got a lot of extra geometry really close in at this base point.
You can see here there's loads loads more.
So once again what we can do here is we can just lower the resolution of all of the lines ever so slightly.
But if you try and keep your basic curves as we've experienced in the past two points of inflection
that often helps massively.
But here we go we've got a shape coming on this one here looks more like a donut maker a bagel maker
or maybe a trifle dish.
I don't know it's not looking quite like a lamp base at the moment but I'm sure we can get that sorted
over in your challenge okay.
So this is a really straightforward challenge using curves creates the lamp base pulls for the year
now and give that a go Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's hop on over into blender and use curves to create our lamp base OK Okay everybody so we're over
it.
Now seen at the moment I'm going to clear my render border and I'm going to select my lamp and I want
to hide everything else in my scene as a caveat when you do this to undo it will bring back even other
things that you've had and I'll show you that now shift and H solos that one object.
So that's one way of hiding everything from your scene and bringing it back.
Alton H Moore brings back cover stuff as well.
So let's go ahead then and hide everything from our scene.
So we've got our lamp here that we're going to work from now unfortunately our lamps origin is all the
way over here rather than where it was with the original drawing that we did.
There's a couple of ways that we can go ahead.
I am going to fix that right now I'm going to find the lamp sketch select that we can see the origins
there and I'm going to go shift an S cursor to selected it then I'm gonna go back to our lamp itself
and then select it right click set.
Origin 3d cursor.
There we go.
And we've got the 3d cursor in the right place to make our circle which is going to be our lamp base.
In this case I'm going to put in a path because that's what it is at the moment.
Now thinking about that path itself and remembering what we were talking about and the profile following
it round I really want this path to be a lot smaller because that's essentially where we're going to
end our profile and drop it down.
So I'm going to scale that in by maybe points one point one looks about right now I'm going to bring
up the properties panel here.
Notice I've got a scale on my curve throughout this section and you will find to your detriment if you
do not apply your scale or do your edits in edit mode it will cause a problem later on.
So it's really really important that you're mindful that you either do your edits in edit mode or after
you've done something like a scale control an A.
Apply that scale then we know it's got a scale factor of 1 it's not going to cause anything weird later
on I'm going to put the profile that I'm going to use actually back at the World origin it makes it
easier to work with.
As far as I'm concerned so busy a curve and I'm just going to move on the y axis downwards.
Okay let's look at this from the top.
Let's select how busy a curve this is going to be the lamp base profile.
Here we go.
So we got the lamp based path we can go there go to our object data properties our curve properties
I'm going to lower this down straight away the resolution preview because I don't want that gets in
the way I'm gonna go to the geometry and select my lamp base profile.
Brilliant.
So now we've got an idea of what's going on.
And as you can see here it's tiny at the moment but that's fine.
We can go ahead go into edit mode here and start tweaking these about remembering the X if I go in g
x it's going to pull it out.
Now you can see here it doesn't seem to be conforming to the scale that we wanted.
So let's just check and make sure there's nothing funky going on with scales here.
So this has got a scaling factor of 1 which is fine and the base has also that's absolutely fine.
Okay.
So we've got the base at roughly the right size.
I'm going to hide this out of the way for the moment our lamp that we had there.
Press H to hide it.
Let's go ahead grab this.
Now remember that that circle is where this origin is going to be.
So what I can do is whilst I'm in edit mode I can grab this anything to the left of that origin.
Now we go we start getting a circle.
So it's place it in the right place and at the origin we've got the circle in roughly the right size
that we want.
Okay so this is starting to look pretty flat but it's got a good start to it.
I'm going to select all of my curve right click and subdivide to add a little bit of extra geometry
in a little bit of extra control.
Let's select these two handles here.
Press V and changed into vector because I do want these lists to basically be straight down so I'm going
to make that all the way up and fortune I can just set the x value here to be zero then I know it's
all the way up and let's move first x equals zero as well and it's definitely all the way up and then
g z or not GZ sorry G Y left it up depending on how high we go.
Let's have a look here.
We might need to bring our lamp reference back in.
I think that's probably the best we can do here.
I want to look at that from the side and was it still so let's just continually lift it up so about
there.
Okay.
That's high.
That's out of the way again.
So that's starting to look pretty good but it's not got quite the shape that we want.
So we can even add more information or we can adjust these handles to get the right sort of shape.
Now your lamp might be slightly different if it is.
Don't worry about it.
It'd be nice to see different types of lamp.
Now I'm moving this in a 3D world which is going to move it and make it look a bit odd.
So when you're doing this I still even know it doesn't matter that if your handle disappears up in the
z axis if you're looking at it's straight down in auth graphic projection you know that at least it's
going to remain pretty consistent.
So I think I want a little sort of lip in the middle so I'm going to select these two again and subdivide.
And then also I should be able to do is have a little bit of a lip just there we can see it's coming
into effect.
I'm going to lower that down to about there.
Let's have a look.
Yeah.
So I'm liking how that's looking.
Of course we can go ahead and render that see what it looks like and not very good at the moments that
bring everything back in.
So bolts and H whilst we're not in edit mode ult and H brilliant we've brought everything back in now.
The lamp doesn't actually have a material on it.
So that's not the end of the world.
And of course my computer is fast enough to render this out.
But if I wanted it to be a bit more high definition not as in resolution but in terms of the number
of samples that we're using let's say we set this back to 32 which is its default I can pop that render
border in and just check.
Very quickly how it's looking.
The other thing I might want to do here is a little bit of cleanup as well.
Now one of the things that you'll notice is after we've moved the origin of this.
Yes.
What's our lamp and lights have also moved position which is well which is right because they were linked
to where the origin is.
So let's go g y and pull those back into where they should be.
Excellent.
There we go.
We've got the lamp all sorted now.
As we start working on these and moving them around we are going to have to pay attention to what's
going on in the outline.
Because otherwise we end up with things on top of one another and our renders will end up horrible.
But we'll deal with that as and when it comes up.
So there we go.
My lamp has a new base.
It's not quite solid yet it's you can see through the bottom of it et cetera.
He says not not moving it around.
There you go you can see through the base of it.
If I hide the world you can see all the way up into the base not necessarily a bad thing if that's the
look you're going for.
But in this particular case that's not ideal.
Let's bring back to the world base now there are a couple of things here that I can do to tidy up.
I don't need that drawing any more we've got that and the other drawing that we started with the lamp
sketch that can also go.
We're not going to use it again at this point so it's pretty safe to delete and hide my lamp.
And if we just click the little eye in the outline it doesn't hide each children.
If we wanted to do that we press shift at the same time and it hide that.
So we've got our base just here looks a bit low resolution at the moment but we can sort that out in
a bit.
We've got the lamp profile stuck out here and in the height that's out of the way we can't hide the
lamp base path that is that object there.
That's fine.
OK.
Brilliant.
That is a nice little set up there and we can have a look at it all by itself as well to see how that
looks when it's rendered.
Nothing really exciting going on that we need to give it a good material at some point but we'll do
that later on.
How are your lamp bases coming along.
Please share them and show them off over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.