Hello everybody and welcome back.
So we're going to jump straight into a challenge here and that is to create a window.
So I'd like you to go ahead and create a window in the same style as the door.
Now if you've gone off on a different style then make sure you're matching that and not the one I'm
making.
You can use any techniques at your disposal.
I am very likely to just replicate exactly how I make the door but in a window for now what I would
like you to do especially if you've used different techniques is write down the major steps you used
to create.
Now I'm going to say here the window or windows you could have more than one and share how you made
the window over in the discussions.
I want to see how many variations of construction you guys actually go through Paul's video now and
give that a go Okay everybody Welcome back.
As hop on over into blender and create a window.
Okay so for this challenge it's almost a repeat of what we've done already.
In fact I'm going to see if I can reuse my block work that I've got here.
One of the great things about building up a any any scene is having some sort of common features across
your models.
Now this is something that I can reuse again and again these big blocks small block and perhaps pop
some other blocks into my wall in various places.
However what would be really cool is if we can now use them in an archway perhaps a smaller variety
or smaller variance of them for Iowa window itself.
So let's go ahead I'm going to hide everything here for the moment and go and grab a copy of the wall
itself.
So I'm going to duplicate the wall and I'm going to call this a window so WMATA Mary Kay and I'm obviously
going to need to cut a hole in it.
Let's hide the doorway for the moment.
Now we have to decide whereabouts our hole in is going to be.
And you know this is part of where I perhaps should have kept the door cutout.
It's not a difficult thing to make but it would have been consistent if I'd gone and grabbed the cutout
shape that we had made and just made it into a smaller version of itself.
But we can't do that so let's learn from our experience not adding EUV sphere definitely circular.
But I do want to add a cylinder again 32 vertices might be a bit much actually for this particular window
but we'll stick with it for the moment.
I need to rotate that's around on the y axis by 90.
Oh I do apologize.
It's going to be the access is rotate exorcist by ninety and gonna pop it roughly in the right place
now its execution is gonna be to Z location too.
Yeah I think that's a pretty good start in the y locations zero is absolutely fine it should be cutting
everything into.
Okay so how high is our window going to go in fact let's get the basic shape working first.
So we're basically going to delete the lower half of our cylinder here.
Now you can you circle selects if you want as well as that half way.
Yep.
That is we don't want to select the halfway point excellent so let's go ahead deletes all of those words
sees that leave us with an archway that we can fill up there and also fill up fill up along here.
It does need to be a solid object for the boolean modifier to work for is important.
Okay that looks really good something to lower this down.
So going back to object man I'm going to slow this down to just one meter off the floor looking good
I'm going to have an archway coming up but I don't want it that wide says go ahead and skeleton on the
x axis.
C is already taking on the arch shape which is awesome.
I'm going to try.
Point five Yeah I think that's okay.
I'm gonna have to have a bit of a window sill there or a lip at the bottom.
I'm going to not quite go that find the skeleton by point seventy five instead.
Okay that has lifted it up ever so slightly.
So let's make sure that the face at the bottom is selected and then selects everything else and then
we're going to scale around the active elements are changing a pivot point to the active element.
Now let's scale by point seven five and it won't change its height.
Okay.
Let's grab this top edge.
Turn on proportional editing
and I'm going to look at this front on press g z and lift up and I'm just going to turn down some of
the options and set that two meters.
Now it's not quite the shape I wants at the moment.
I think what I'm going to do is select all of these edges but that bottom one and then what I can do
is pull everything up.
So with this mega g z one well without proportional I think turned on G said one excellence that's lifted
it up who have pushed it back along the y axis.
Let's try that again GZ 1.
Okay.
Is that a little high.
Yes.
Probably I'm not going to get the Arch Way in with that height so GZ point five.
That's a good start.
Now let's try pulling that up GZ gonna need proportional editing turned on that looks much better.
And songs that don't make that too big.
I have my arch way.
Where do I want it going up to well.
Choices choices.
I want to go all almost all the way up and go to about 2.5.
Something like that.
That looks good.
Okay.
So I'm going to cut that out straightaway so I need to select my wall.
This is still called war.
I want my window and I add a modifier on it.
I'm going to use the boolean modifier with the difference being the cylinder do you see this looks a
real mess if we're not careful.
Has that actually come to town.
Let's hide our cylinder and also our wall so we don't need that anymore.
Yes perfect.
Okay let's go ahead and apply that and then have a look at the damage what's it done to our mesh.
That's a pretty clean cut through actually I'm I'm pretty impressed with that.
Okay.
So now we can go ahead and I'm going to grab the window arch so let's go into edit mode on that should
be a lot easier to select.
There we go.
It's a lot easier to select because there is no edge loop down there are actually terminates because
this three edges meeting so it just doesn't know where to go.
Excellent.
So I'm going to duplicate that.
I'm going to separate it.
I'm going to immediately convert it to a curve.
Here we go.
And we don't want to keep the original in this particular case.
And what should we call it.
Let's call it window curve.
Okay.
So the window curve.
Let's see if we can just have our block work following it.
So I'm going to lean back archway bricks again but this time it's gonna be window breaks.
So that's go ahead enable it so I can see them let's go ahead and select just the archway bricks itself.
I'm going to duplicate those.
So we get archway bricks.
I'm going to call it window bricks.
I'm going to hold down shift as I nest under Windows so that's drag set it's as a child of the window
as the curve should be as well.
And I think really the bricks should be a child of the curve gives an idea of the hierarchy it's following
the curve.
It's important.
Yeah.
I like that.
And we don't need the 0 0 one here.
Okay.
So it's not following the right curve at the moment so we can come in here and pick the window curve.
Ah look at that.
It's amazing it fits.
Straight away I'm going to hide my archway bricks and I think this is going to be the wrong way round
when we have a look.
Yes.
So this is an opportunity here to just follow the curve precisely and because we haven't rotated the
curve you can see here that these bricks can actually now face the right way.
So we can go in in edit mode and rotate them I'm going to turn off proportional editing for my own sanity
or take them on the z axis to bring them to the right way round and then rotate them on the x axis put
them the right way around this way which isn't 90 degrees probably minus 90.
There we go.
And it's a bit of a mess at the top.
So what can we do here in fact.
Yes it's a bit of a mess in many places a g y will now move it backwards and forwards which makes a
lot of sense g z will move it in announced just like it did before and I only want it going through
ever so slightly but this is where we get an issue here because if you remember we play with the length
and now the length is probably far too much.
So let's play with this until we get it meeting up in the middle which is about right there and then
we can play with the relative offsets as well we can bunch them up together or commit them.
Asked a little looser until we get the merging at the top.
Aha.
Look at that.
Perfect.
That works out really really well.
It looks very similar to the door.
The only thing we don't have at the moment is something along the bottom and there's a couple of ways
of doing that as well.
What I'm going to do in this case is I'm going to d select everything to do it by block work here and
I'm going to go ahead and just select one of the blocks using the L K will select everything all the
geometry that's linked there and I'm going to duplicate that look I can stack bricks in random places.
I'm going to separate that's by selection I'm just going to call that one brick because it is a lone
Brick.
I'm going to remove all of these extra modifiers that are attached to that single brick and the mirror.
I'm going to keep the mirror on for the moment.
Let's go back to this individual brick wall which one was I deleting.
Oh no I was deleting window bricks by mistake.
Let's hope the undo buffer serves me well let's make sure I only have window bricks selected this time
so make sure you are an object mode otherwise we can't swap out that's called this brick.
Delete the array and the curve Phew.
Okay let's look at our window straight on and then we can move this to the appropriate location.
Okay.
And let's go ahead and rotate this not in object mode because it's gonna be very difficult to manage.
So let's go into edit mode first and rotate and let's set that to a bog standard 90 degrees.
Now how we manage this is entirely up to you.
But I do think that it needs to be here slightly.
It's going to need to come out further so let's scale on the y axis so intersects I think because our
mirror modifier provided we got clipping turned on.
We'll merge those vertices really well.
Okay.
And I'm not sure shall I keep it like that.
Push out a bit further of choices here are big.
So that scale that in the x axis and then just play with it for a moment move on the accesses to here
duplicate that's g.
Z No G X g x I can probably merge those together whilst still keeping a decent sized slab on each side.
K That's D select everything.
Press the L kits that's here in scale that on the x axis as well.
And that looks pretty neat.
Not sure if I should have an extra one in the middle or I like it like that.
I don't like the big gap though that needs to.
That needs to be solved.
So let's go ahead and just go g x and push one into the other.
Ever so slightly search just showing a tiny bit of the scene where they join together.
Yeah that's much better.
Yeah I like that.
I'm not sure about this plane area inside at the moment.
I think once we've got some texture on it that that will go away and people are really going to be paying
a lot of attention to the window.
Maybe maybe not.
But you know what we can start doing very soon after of course you name your objects.
So what I call that Brick I'm going to call this windowsill.
This is no longer just a brick we should look at that we've got an inside and an out which is really
useful.
I really like how that's coming together okay.
So we've got an option here instead of just pushing forward and modelling more and more pieces.
We should really see how these would be.
When we start fitting them together and we'll do that in the next lecture.