Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to go through a quick tip.
We've already discussed this tool once and it's the to sphere tool.
It also works when it comes to flat faces as well as the entire objects.
In fact it will circularise.
Our mesh.
So in this case let's pick somewhere that's not uneven one of the advantages of where I've picked to
place these particular faces these new faces here.
Well they are perfect as it is if I try and go F3 and to sphere and I change the value of to
sphere to one to make it circular as possible.
It just works so I can't demonstrate it on my geometry I've currently got here unless I pick somewhere
that's going to deliberately give me something uneven.
So we have a look at this area here it's a hexagon that borders our Pentagon just here.
So if we were to use these set of triangles when we had bevelled Oh I didn't mean to do that.
Great example there.
So let's put this back here and there we go.
So we've bevelled this you can see that it's uneven it's slightly lopsided I'm just going to reset my zoom
there so I can actually zoom in without clipping too easily if you're finding when you're zoomed in
and it's clipping like this.
This is the viewport clipping here will happen from time to time and you can change over in the view
we can see that our clip starts and our clip and we can change the options just here.
So if I was to lower my clip starts we can see that then I can get in closer before it starts clipping
the camera also has a similar option as well.
We'll delve into that later but there we go.
I can Now zoom in a bit closer and show you this lopsided hexagon here.
Now if I go f3 and to sphere what we find is if I just type in the value of 1 which means circularize
it we can see actually changes and it makes it is circular as it possibly can.
We try and do it again.
It might push it a little further.
So occasionally you can do this to sphere a couple of times.
And there we go.
We have got as far as we can possibly go and that's going to make sure that this new face is as circular
as it can possibly be.
And in this particular case I don't need to worry about it but it is good to know that that option exists
for those of you who have decided to place your holes where it is slightly uneven.
But we should now find that this is pretty much a perfect hexagon and that's as close to a circle as
we're going to get with that.
OK.
So there you go.
There's your quick tip that not only to sphere works on an entire object itself but it also works down
at the face level.
So if you've got something like this that you need to circularize you can do it with two sphere and I'll
see you all in the next lecture.