In this video we're gonna stop playing around with the hair particle system and I'm going to be coming
up with something that I think could look like a bit of animal fur and I'm gonna be challenging you
to come up with your own interesting kind of hair experimentation.
So let's get started.
Okay.
We might be coming back to our sculpture in the future but for now we're gonna save say thanks very
much.
Jump up into new general start a new scene here our new project I'm going to remove the default cube
and I can hit shift a at a mesh.
This will be an icon sphere down in the bottom left you can see an icon sphere open up that little a
menu I'm going to increase the sub divisions to I think 6 we'll see how 6 looks can looks pretty good.
Sona enough detail that this is all going to work.
And just to emphasize here that we're just having a bit of fun don't worry about creating something
that looks exactly like a thing.
Just go crazy be creative.
Now we're gonna be playing around in the particles property tab so click on particle property over on
our right here and I'm going to click plus to add a new particle system hasn't really done much just
yet.
You can see one little blob this there it'll really turn to magic when we click here you can see we've
got a here button click on that and one.
There we go.
Job done lovely.
Now first thing I do is just reduce the hair length so that it's not quite so crazy on the screen.
There we go.
Now what this has done is it's adding a certain number of hair so it's adding 1000 over my object.
If I reduce the number Berber proper you can see that it reduces the number of his that we've got that
may increase it back up to say 500 just to see how it goes.
Okay.
So to get some fullness on this hair what we want to do is scroll down within our particle properties
tab and find children open that up and click on interpolate and there we go.
We get a whole bunch of extra hair that we can see.
Cool.
It's looking a little bit ferret them out if you scroll out it looks more fairy is growing it's a little
bit less free now is something in here.
If we look at the render amount and the display amount you can see the display amount is 10.
Let me just give us more real estate here.
We're gonna render it.
We'll see a hundred.
I'm just gonna increase my display amount to 50 so it makes it a lot fuller it's a lot more similar
to what the render amount isn't you know I'll put the render amount at 50 so I should be getting if
I render I should be getting what I'm seeing at the moment rather than seeing something this very sparse
like that and then you render it like whoa it's a lot more busy than I thought it would be.
So I'm gonna leave mine at 50/50 can put it whatever you want I'm just playing around with numbers at
the moment we can also now change the length from them from one which was the maximum that we determined
previously in terms of our hair length up here point for one all the way down to zero.
So we can change the length of our children and we can start to add some randomness and some variations
and cool things.
One cool thing I do to scroll down scroll down you can find we're still under children.
I'm going to change the clumping so open up clumping and I'll increase the clumping As I increase it.
Guess what happens.
The hair clumps to the extent where we get our spiky little clumpy Spike ball thing there which is pretty
cool and is reduced I live it.
Have a little bit of clumping and if I want to have some clump noise You see there's a little bit of
randomness going on in there.
I can also open up kink which is how it's going to bend and change kink type from nothing to will say
curl.
And there we go.
That's an interesting kind of curly ball effect that we get.
Or I could change it to radio what's going to look good here radio or maybe a wave or braid wave.
You know live on wave at the moment.
Again we can change all of these values amount of clumped the shape the fatness of it nice and fat and
amplitude would too.
Okay cool.
Lots of great things we can play around with here.
What I'm looking for at the moment is what sort of effect would be good for animal fur.
Because we we want to have a couple of settings we say yeah that looks like an animal it's not quite
there at the moment.
That's something I've kind of got my eye on as I'm playing around with this.
And then the other main thing I want to show you as part of this exercise is how to make it look different
from a color point of view and from a rendering point of view.
So I'm just going to jump up into my material previews so we can see the colors that have been present
at the moment we have no color or just the default color.
Now there's two colors going on here one from the emitter which is our now ball that we put our icons
fear we put in there and one is the hair itself.
Let's go and change the color of the ball first of all the way I'm going to do that is by clicking on
material properties click plus and then click new material.
I'll call this skin just so it's clear it's the underside will change the base color to what am I making.
I'm making an animal kind of thing so I'll change it.
So it's darker sort of brownish and you can see because the particles.
In other words the hair don't currently doesn't have its own color.
It's just taking the color of the skin that's underneath.
I'm just gonna make it a bit clearer by reducing the amount of hair that we've got in here.
Actually I'm gonna go to nothing in the kink type reaction that you can see the color of the actual
skin itself.
Now let's change the color of our hair that sits on top of the skin the way we can do that is by the
game within our particles.
Particle properties let's find render.
So you can see we've got a tab here called render it's just above viewport display render excellent
and leave it as path yes instead of the material being skin we want to create a new material currently
on and have one in there so I'm going to jump back down to my material properties scroll back up the
top click on plus this will allow me to click on new I will change this to hair and the hair itself
let's make a what color show and make this just to make it very clear what's going on I'll make it a
pink just to be super clear.
Now back to our particle system particle properties fine we've got render and then render is path material
we are going to change to here.
Okay now we've got a very beautiful pink hair on top of a brown base and as I said before I'm looking
to make this look a bit like an animal so instead of pink I'm going to jump back to my material properties
make sure that I'm selected on hair seems like you're on hair base colour I'm going to change to more
of a brown kind of color to get animal look and stuff.
OK.
There we have it now it looks okay but not great.
And one of the things we can do to have it make a little bit more impressive is to add or to turn on
ambient occlusion the way we do that is find your render properties within range of properties were
looking for ambient occlusion so open that up click on that to apply it and immediately it looks a little
bit different because we've got the hairs are providing some of that occlusion and it's making the light
more interesting what I'll do is just play around with this distance I think I need to put that up to
about one that it's looking good let's play around with a factor that just makes it darker or lighter
I like the darker effect.
OK so there you go that's feeling a lot more hairy I think the clumping makes it look a little bit not
exactly what I'm going for so I'm going to go back down to my particle properties scroll down scroll
down find let's see clumping gonna turn off clumping I think just turn it down well but clump noise
turn that off and there must be something going on here.
Shape sorry for clumping in minus one not zero is what I want.
Okay now I don't have any clumping you can still see through the hair as I move back then it's starting
to look a little bit more like an animal mind I just wanted to do one more thing because it's too it's
too uniform there's not many rabbits out there that have exactly that sort of hairdo is there so I'm
gonna find roughness this again is under the children tab fine roughness and I'm going to have a look
around here get some randomness what happens if I increase the random value.
OK.
We do get it looking a little bit more squiggly.
Wow.
There we go.
So that definitely is looking a bit more like animal fur size is going to change the size the randomness
threshold so you can see is a lot of science to seeing what looks good is pretty much just twiddle the
roughness and see get it to the point where you're happy with it oh there we go.
I think uniforms giving me the sort of look I'm looking for.
Wonderful.
There we go.
There's a furball and you know as one last thing I'm going to find the display amount and just crank
that up to say one hundred so it's looking a little bit more lush and I'll put up the render amount
in case we need to render it just so we couldn't see those gaps that were going straight through into
the the skin of the object unless we're really close to it.
And it's good time for me to give you a challenge create something very add some hair to a simple objects
as I did was just to an echo sphere or you could do it to a cube or whatever you like.
Play around with that and be kind of cool color the hair and change its shape using clumping or kink
and to share your creation.
Just a quick note we're going to be doing some more hair in the next video or two so just do something
that's throw away something it's a bit of fun something Zeke's experimenting that will continue to work
on a different thing in the next video.
So jump in take on that challenge when you done please do share it and then I will see you in the next
lecture.