Hello everybody and welcome to this lecture where we are going to get the chance to play with origins
and position things exactly where we want them.
If we have a look at our three pawns in front of us here.
The one on the left hand has its origin smack bang on the bottom.
This one has its in its center of mass.
And this one is over here in the head of another pawn or almost there.
So there are various reasons why you might want origins in different places.
And it is important to select the right one for what you are doing and trying to accomplish at the time.
And also knowing that you can move the origin around to your heart's content depending on what you're
trying to do.
And this is especially important.
For instance if you're working with someone else or yourself and exporting to a game engine you may
need to have your origin in a very specific place.
That's not where you'd naturally have it's when creating your model.
Let's find out more.
OK.
So let's start off with our pawn that we've got here because there's lots of things that we can do.
The first thing I want to show you.
We've covered it briefly going past it's in the past but this time I want to really hone in on it.
If we select an object and right click on it it brings up the object context menu which has in it the
set origin and we've got a series of options as to where we can place that which is really awesome.
And we've covered these before.
The important thing to realize here is that the origin is not only the position of this object in the
world but it is also used for physics calculations as well.
So you may have it in one place when you're constructing your model and move it to another.
When you start calculating physics and being able to interchange between the two is important.
So at the moment we know that we've set this up at the very beginning to have its origin at the center
but perhaps you've missed that step and inadvertently made your model with the origin elsewhere.
I mean for instance let's look at this from the side.
You could have built everything around there so if I go into edit mode I can move the mesh data independently
and let's just say I move it down on the Z axis to roughly there.
Now the downside of this is if we were to make several pieces, let's duplicate this object a couple
of times and duplicate it once more.
Okay so let's say this one here was going to be let's scale it up by one point three three.
Just like we did before then scale on the Z axis by one point two or something.
So that's our place holder Bishop for instance.
Now you can immediately see one of the issues here.
How do I align all of these bases.
Sure you can go up here and use the snapping tool, we can turn on the snapping tool and go to face select
and then hope that as we whiz around here if I've got this selected and go G and Z just lock it in the
Z axis and snap it to there hopefully aligns faces that are closest.
Looks like it does but there's no way of testing if these are actually lined up now other than optically
because if we select this object we get a different location for the object than this object.
In fact I do lie.
There is one way of testing and that's to go into edit mode of one of these objects and select and an
individual vertex and remember that says two point 2 6 3 5 and then go into edit mode on this one and
go to three.
Okay.
Vote two are aligned or certainly those two vertices are aligned.
And the other thing you can do is if you've got multiple objects selected we could have hopped into
edit mode of both of them and quickly switched between these two.
But that's a bit ambiguous having to do that across two models is a pain enough if you had to do across
multiple models.
That's a real pain in the backside and would ultimately lead you to not doing it.
You just line things up visually so let's have a fake board.
And of course it's added it where the 3d cursor is on the center around our scene.
And now if we wanted to align these at the moment the easiest way of doing that without knowing about
moving these objects around is to just lift them up and kind of place them roughly in the right place.
I'm going to delete this I one for the moment we don't need it for our purposes.
And then of course we look at our scene and we go well let's turn a bit shading on so it can see some
shadows and then we realize we don't have a light in our scene so we can't test that and let's add a
lamp real quick.
So at Lamp point lamp source wow that's really bright.
Not surprising these objects are tiny that shift shift the lamp all the way over there.
Of course the lighting at this point because it's so small we're going to have to tweak this later we
don't see any shadow so I'm just going to quickly switch across to cycles so don't have the FAF around
with those settings and we can see here.
I want to switch it to GPU as well.
Otherwise I won't be able to record this properly.
Now we have to come back here and we start moving around we see that there is in fact a gap underneath
both of them.
And before you know it you're just faffing around with things would be much easier if we could just
say at the moment we want the bottom of the model to be where the origin is and it's to be in the center
so we can align things perfectly with our board.
Of course if we just type can zero here our bishop or place holder bishop here just disappears into
the floor which is kind of fun but not the look we're going for.
So the simple way of getting around that I'm just gonna go G, Z and lift this back up again until roughly
the right place so there we go roughly that.
So how would we go ahead and do this.
Well I'm come on come out of rendered mode for a moment.
The first thing that I would go ahead and do is go into edit mode and select the face that we want to
position our origin on.
Now of course we've got this make believe board in the ways I'm going to go to the outliner.
And where it's as plain I'm just going to click the icon it will hide it in our viewport for us and
let us go ahead face Select and Select the face itself once it's selected we can move the 3d cursor
to that position.
Now the origins position didn't have to be in the middle of our object which I want it to be at this
point.
We could just select the 3d cursor and click on this surface and we will know that it will have aligned
perfectly and then we could come out and right click and set the origin to the 3d cursor.
Now that's definitely on the bottom.
I can say Z equals zero and it will be flat to our plane that we created.
But if I wanted it smack bang in the middle with that face selected I could go shift and s and cursor
to selected.
Now in this particular case the middle of that face because that's what is currently selected.
So there we go.
It's moved the 3D cursor just a little bits across and then we can go ahead, come out, right click set
origin to the 3d cursor and now we know it's smack bang in the middle of the object.
Now if you wanted to use the object menu you could also do that and set the origin to the 3d cursor
there and the radial menu the shift S cursor to selected that we had done earlier.
You'll find that when you're in edit mode under the mesh menu under SNAP and then we go we've got the
same set of options that we've never had before.
Okay.
Armed with that knowledge it's time for your challenge Okay so hopefully a very straightforward challenge
for you.
I'd like you to check your pawn, your bishop and your base piece.
All have their origins at the center bottom of the piece itself.
You may have already done this in which case I do want you to still check.
That is the case.
Pause the video now and give it a go okay.
Everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead and check ourpawn, bishop and base piece before we make any others because they're all
going to be derived from these pieces or have their origins at the center of the bottom of the piece
OK so we're back over in Blender here.
I've been playing around with my pawn file so let's go ahead and revert it back to normal.
Now I'm pretty certain that all of mine are already set up but it does only take a few seconds to go
through and check so I can go ahead here select this bottom face with the face selected.
I can go shift S, Cursor to select it and we can see that the cursor has gone to the appropriate place.
Then I can come out right click to open up the context menu and then set the origin to the 3D cursor
and we can see here for whatever reason it was slightly off.
That is probably a rounding error heh i'll make sure now the object is sat on the bottom and save that
file and I'm gonna do the same now for my bishop.
Let's go into edit mode select the bottom face.
We go shift and S, move the cursor to selected, come back out and we can see here the cursor, 3d cursor
is also off by about the same amounts and again that is probably a rounding error.
I'm going to also apply my scale whilst I'm here as well so let's go ahead right click, originto the 3D
cursor set the Z value is 0 its going to have moved it a very very small amounts I'm going to go control and A
to apply and apply the scale that's on this model that's going to be important for the next lecture
let's go ahead and save that file and the final one of course is the chess piece base so let's go and
find that and once that has been opened up hop into edit mode, make sure we select the face shift S,
cursor to selected, tab back out into object mode, right click set origin to the 3d cursor again, adjust
the Z position correctly and then save our file.
All done.
How did you guys get on.
Did you have your origins already at the center or had you made your pieces with the origin elsewhere.
Well they are now all in the right place and I'll see you all in the next lecture.