Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we are going to focus on making these holes in our sphere itself so that we can have
some finger and thumb holes.
Now you may notice that it's turned on flat shaded again.
And that's because if we go to shade smooth we've got this horrible artifact and I can't really show
you the holes that we've made.
Now we can resolve that and we will do in the following lecture.
But for the moment let's focus on those holes. Hello everybody and welcome back so.
This is where we were before.
We've got a little task to make these holes now.
First of all I'm going to change my view mode to wireframe the reason for that is so I can see what's
going on inside our model.
If I go ahead and select these three faces it's the problem with wireframe sometimes you can select things
behind and we extrude you'll see that it's going inwards.
They're all going the same direction which is great.
We can see at the top actually says normal.
But they're not going correctly.
Now the reason why I say correctly is because this bottom one here looks horrible.
And that's because it's assessed all of these faces and picked a normal relative to all of them rather
than individual faces.
We get around that very very easily I'm going to press undo to go back there and then I'm going to change
this and be explicit.
So at the top here we've got this option for global.
And once you've clicked on global you see that this is the transform orientation.
So that applies to whether you're moving scaling or rotating something which is what a transform basically
is.
And we can do it locally, globally, normally, gimbal, view and cursor. The gimbal, view and cursor.
I don't really use that often but it is possible to use them for that.
And there will be specific use cases.
Global well.
And the best way I thought about the difference between local and global.
Imagine if you were stood up your local and global z axis the way that you think is up is aligned.
However if you lay down on your bed or on the sofa on the floor now your local is going sideways whereas
the global has stayed up.
The only way that you will get your local facing up again is if you were to apply that rotation.
But we want normal.
I'm going to be explicit in this case and then we want all of these to move together.
I could do them all individually and it would work now but we want it so it'll be together in order to
do that.
We're going to have to use individual origins under the pivot point menu.
It's quite easy to forget about the pivot point if you're not rotating something you often don't think
about pivoting but scaling is one of those things as well as extruding.
We're talking about using the individual origin.
So we're looking at this face here this face here this face here and now that we've set it up to normal
and individual origins we should get three blue lines which we do representing the normals of each of
these faces.
And with that you can finish this off now with your challenge.
Okay.
So your challenge is to extrude the holes for the fingers and thumb.
Make sure are all equidistant so they go in the same depth.
They should all be extruded along their normal also none of them are going off wonky inside the ball.
If you have any overlap points you extruded in scale the faces at the bottom of the hole accordingly.
So it no longer overlaps and I suggest you do that on all three for consistency.
Finally remember wireframe mode to see what's going on inside the model.
Pause the video now and give that a go. Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and create the holes for our fingers and thumbs.
OK so now that we've got our bowling ball loaded up let's go ahead select these three faces.
Brilliant let's go to our transform orientation switch to normal so we're explicit about it.
I'm going to select individual origins and then I'm going to switch over to wireframe mode after I've had
deselected not before.
Who would do that.
Silly.
OK.
About there may be a little bit more so I can now move these but I'm gonna have to press the Z key again
to move them.
So there we go.
And it's picked up because I've got normal selected here and individual origins.
It's allowed me to move them as well along those individuals.
Now it's not quite half so I could probably scale it by point five and get away with it but that's still
not quite there.
I don't want it to be too small at the bottom.
Okay.
Looks good, I'm going to tab out into object mode.
Switch back to shaded mode.
Oh it hurts my eyes seeing that you know.
But there are various ways of sorting that out.
Are you starting to think Oh I know I'm going to I'm going to try this to make sure that that's shading
artifact thing that's happening around the holes doesn't look horrible.
And that could be a mini challenge for you before we actually get onto the various ways because there
is more than one way of sorting this out there.
How would you approach this at the moment with the knowledge that you've currently got more geometry
is definitely one way of approaching it whether or not it's the quote unquote right way.
That's entirely up to you.
But we've we're going to sort this out in the next lecture and look at the various options as well.
So there we go.
There's my bowling ball coming along great.
Not quite sure of the color we're going to have to add a material to it soon.
I'm looking forward to seeing your bowling balls as well.
And I'll see you all in the next lecture.