Hello everybody and welcome back.
By the end of this lecture we're going to add a bit of color and we're also going to generate some geometry
using the new geometry that we've created.
This is especially useful when you got parts that fit together because you can make sure that the parts
is the right size from the word go.
So let's find out more.
OK.
So back over in a default blender file what we need to do is just experiment with separating out parts
of an existing model.
So let's use this cube as a good example go into edit mode get the face on top perhaps inset that and
extrude down.
So this is similar to the whole we've got in the top of the lamp.
Now the good thing is we've currently got this bottom face selected.
So what we could do is we can duplicate that face through the shift in D.
We've now got another face that exactly matches the one that was there before the press escape that's
going to place it back as if we had never moved it.
And then press the p key to separate and we do by selection or indeed at this point by loose parts because
it's not connected by anything but by selection we're being explicit here.
We've now got cube in cube 0 0 1.
If I tap out into object mode select cube 0 0 1 I then can go in and extrude out and we've got two pieces
here that are perfectly matched together.
Now at this point she may be saying well nothing in the real world a slow that it has tolerances we
need to give it a bit of space and your rights and we can do that in a couple of ways.
One of the easiest ones is to simply select it and scale it in ever so slightly giving us that gap a
little bit around it the other way that we could do it is we could start Beverly edges.
So one of the reasons why this doesn't look quite right here it just looks like one piece is because
this edge around here is not beveled and it's just completely flush.
So an example of that would be selecting this one around here and then selecting the edge loop control
and B and just baffling that edge.
That gives you the impression that it goes in and that's one way of managing that.
And finally if you didn't want to do adding actual geometry to our model we can undo that.
And as a whole object level we can go to our modifiers and actually add in a level modifier for instance.
The downside of that of course is it applies to the entire model in this case rather than just the edge
that we wanted unless we do some vertex painting which we'll learn about later on but for the time being
we could bevel and edge we could leave it as it is or we could just make sure we get everything roughly
the right size to begin with.
And so tuck it in ever so slightly select this one that's get rid of that and there we go.
It does look like two separate bits at this point or indeed make the other one slightly larger.
In general you probably don't want to make the other one larger and you want to keep things as tight
as possible.
And there we go that's that's sorted in the terms of an artistic sense.
You do have to take more care if you're doing this for a 3D printed part for instance you couldn't just
ad lib it all the time because you've got tolerances often that you have to adhere to.
But with that knowledge it's time for your challenge okay.
So your challenge is to create the stem coming out of the base.
Now use the existing geometry to create that STEM.
Now do also refer back to your reference materials that you gathered earlier on and make sure that you're
still following along with the design of your original lamp.
You're going to need to delete unnecessary geometry at some point and you may do it as you transfer
mesh data from one object to another.
You may not need all of the data that comes across.
And that was also true of your modifiers so check your modifiers because in general when you separate
mesh data into a new mesh object it inherits not only modifiers but materials and a few other things.
So I'd recommend also doing the materials at the end because what I'm going to ask you to do is add
some basic materials to your model.
Think about what things are made of how you want it to look overall pause the video now and give that
a go okay.
Everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead create the stem and make our lamp base look a little bit prettier OK so we left off here.
Let's go ahead and open up our animated lamp.
You can get rid of that.
So where do we start here.
Well let's start by going into edit mode of this object and having a look at the area that we're going
to create our model from now as a couple of areas that we can create it from.
I am going to use this base area I'm going to select the individual vertex and expand the selection
twice.
So I'm going to use control and num pad plus to do that and we can see we've got this circle around
the edge.
That's perfect.
So also I'm going to do here is I'm going to duplicate that and then separate it straight away by selection.
Perfect.
So we've got here lamp based path 0 0 1.
I'm going to call that lamp stem I think.
Oh dear.
Caps lock is on lamp stem.
And of course I'm free to change that name in the future if I come up with a better name for it.
Now the first thing I'm going to do is just have a look of this and I can see that this bit of data
because it's not being curved round is actually a slightly too big.
So I'm going to go scale that in ever so slightly but in edit mode.
So let's select it lost an object mode go into edit mode select all and scale it in ever so slightly.
Okay that looks good.
The next thing I'm going to do is select all of this in inner geometry and delete the vertices that
leaves sort of the ring around the outside that we can select and press F to fill in.
Now this point in time of course we've also got the subdivisions surface modifier still on and I'll
show you what happens if we leave it on.
Let's extrude this up.
We end up with what I can only describe as a missile or something that looks like a lemon squeezy.
I'm going to get rid of that for the moment.
I don't think I need it.
I'm not starting to look pretty good.
We could tab out of that is still looks pretty faceted.
So we're going to shade smooth now.
I'm not going to worry too much about this top edge for the moment because in the next lecture we'll
be talking about making sure that these edges are nice and sharp.
I could have add a bevel to it as discussed before but I'm not going to do that at this moment in time.
The next thing I want to have a look at is the material.
So you've got everything sorted out.
Let's go ahead to the materials tab creating new material.
I'm going to call this stem.
It's important that you name your materials appropriately.
Now this is going to be a rod of metal coming out of the base.
So I'm going to turn up the metallic setting of the principal shader.
I'm also going to lower the roughness not completely but down to around nought point one ish.
And we can test that by going in to rendered mode and having a look.
Now the rest of the scene and lighting isn't here at the moment so let's bring that back.
Alternate will bring stuff back.
Now I select that bits of lamp and hide that's out of the way.
And this really jacket one as well.
Okay.
Excellent.
And you can see here because this is metallic it's reflecting the world around it.
It's worthwhile bearing that in mind.
Looks pretty good looks very shiny.
How about this base.
Well let's go ahead and give.
That's a material.
And of course it's going to be lamp base at this point.
And I'm going to jump back to this one and call this lamps.
Them be really explicit.
Now the base itself.
I can have it any color I want but I think I'm gonna go for something quite vibrant maybe a deep orange.
Yeah I like the look of that but it looks a bit plastic key at the moment.
I want it to look like painted metal.
So I'm going to decrease the rough and everything is going to end up shiny in this scene isn't it.
I don't want it to look completely reflective like that and let's increase the roughness little bit
more about that.
Okay perfect.
That is looking really nice.
Let's go back to this rod here.
Increase the roughness a little bit more as if it was a brushed.
Bits of metal perhaps even lower the metal a little.
Yeah that's looking a bit better.
I'm going to darken this color as well.
There we go.
Yeah.
I'm liking the look of that.
How are your bases coming along.
I think it looks much better now we've injected a bit of color into it.
Please share your work over in the discussions look forward to seeing it and I'll see you in the next
lecture.