Hello everybody and welcome back.
Now before I give you your final section challenge this is something that you guys can already make
with the knowledge that you have.
Now you might doubt that with its complexity but it really really is that simple.
This whole church is made up of little blocks I can go and pick them up and literally move them about
you can see here I painstakingly put these together.
Now there are better modelling methods in order to do what you just saw in front of you there.
However none are quite as therapeutic as stacking blocks on top of one another is going to be a lot
harder to get that aesthetic.
But there is some smoke and mirrors and this is a really important thing.
A lot of people when they first start making 3D models go down the route of trying to do too much.
Now if we zoom out look the rest of the world isn't modeled it's just the square.
But from the camera's perspective you don't need to know that that moon in the sky.
I'm just going to I'm going to fly.
I'm just gonna walk over there and speed up a little as I go round.
So we have just a plane on the ground and oh what's this ah ha.
How about that our moon is just a circle in the sky place behind.
What about the background.
It seems to be blue rather than that horrible gray.
Well let me show you how to change the color of the background in blender.
So that's come out control and space.
And if we go down the properties panel you'll see there's a picture of a world and in fact it says world
if you hover over it long enough if you click that we've got a color and we can literally change the
background to any color we want.
So since it was a night time scene I thought a dark blue would be ideal for it.
Now there's one more file that I want to show you.
And how I'm going to open it I'm going to go to my files and I'm going to find the blender file and
I'm going to click and drag it in and drop it click open.
And there we go.
We've got a rocket.
Let's go and render that and see what it looks like.
Awesome.
Let's go to fully rendered mode.
So once again what you're seeing in front of you here is a very simple shape it's a series of cones
and cylinders stacked on top of one another.
In fact if you have a look at wireframe you can see that the cone here is stuck inside itself in order
to produce that's effects and that's a cylinder here.
And they've just been colored in differently to give us this overall effect.
And I've got these sky bright blue you might think no.
If we come out of that there is no sky.
It's just the plane in the background.
So that's another way that you can go and make yourself a background is simply by putting a plane which
is just one of the primitives.
We can go shift an A add a plane in scale it's up color in whatever color we want in this case I'm just
going to grab another material that's do oranges and orange sunset in the distance then it's just a
matter of rotating it's around I'm going to rotate it around 90 on the axis and then 45 on the Z axis.
And I think that's all I did actually in order to put it into the appropriate place G not Z shift it
forward slightly make it really big.
Now go back and we've got an orange background.
It's as simple as that to create backgrounds.
Remember anything that's not within the border of the camera it doesn't matter if it's not going to
be seen then don't waste your time on it.
Focus on the model that you're making all the parts of the model or the parts of the scene rather than
trying to do things that the viewer or what you're going to render at the end of it is never going to
see. Hello everybody and welcome to the challenge.
We're going to put our knowledge together in this end of section challenge and I do encourage you to
have a look at other students work for inspiration as well.
So start with a simple model and make a couple of different models to practice your skills and a big
tip here.
Look at the real object and reference material as well that really really helps.
Now before we jump into the challenge let me give you a couple of examples of what you could do.
Here we have a very simple speaker that's sat on my desk in front of me very low poly very simple but
it's just to get those skills honed in.
Then I decided to put some squares and cylinders together squares some cubes and sentences together.
And before you know you've got this lovely tractor next we can go a little bit on from that.
I've stacked some cubes together you can see I've gone ahead and made this castle with a couple of hills
around a blue background and some trees.
Very simple very straightforward and they're much like the tractor if you stack a few more of those
cylinders and cubes together you can end up with something like this train.
Yes this is just manipulating primitives and no other modelling techniques.
And finally here are another couple of examples to give you an idea of where you could go make yourself
a couple of models basic if you're new to this little bit more advanced if you think you already know
blender and remember to share your work over on the forum.
So go ahead pause video now and give that's a go. Okay
everybody welcome back.
Let's go hop on over into blender and see what I came up with.
Hello everybody welcome back.
OK.
So I'm not going to cause myself too much grief by trying to redo that church.
I did take over an hour to do with those blobs.
But what I am going to do is I like space travel so I'm going to make myself a rocket.
So I'm going to do the main body first and I'm going to cheat a little.
Well now that's the thing I wouldn't say it's cheating that's it's important to get through that.
Being efficient is not cheating.
There's a difference.
So I've got myself a booster cone there.
In fact I'm going to scale that down by point five so it's half the size.
Maybe point two, the look from the top.
I can't see the grid so I'm going to go over to the plane itself.
I'm going to call it ground so I know what it is good practice to get naming in early.
Even I sometimes forget especially when I'm doing you know simple for simple in quotation marks things
like this.
So let's lower this booster down and I'm going to turn snapping onto do this.
So let's gets it says flush on the floor.
Perfect.
OK.
I'm going to let them move this across the head duplicate it and move it over here and then look at
it from the other angle and just move both of these to one side going to highlight them both duplicate
them again and move them here and then go into add in a cylinder going to the scale that cylinder down.
It's going to be about that big in total now.
So if I scaled it by point five that's going to be about right.
I think, I'm going to go G Z and just lift it up until it's within.
So there we go.
There's the booster looking good so far thats the lower parts and I'm just going to duplicate and press
Z to lock in the Z axis.
This is the second part and I can start color coding them now so this is going to be a booster.
So it's going to be a darker color isn't it.
So let's make it a dark color go to LookDev mode as well so I can see that it's a dark color.
ExcelIent, I'm going to call this booster ... nozzle.
I think a nozzle then I'm going it's just going to select these other three that one at the end and
make a link to those materials.
I could have gone in and manually selected them and I'm going to call this one here rockets white and
actually make it a little lighter.
And this one I'm going to call it rockets black.
Now some of you might be thinking Well Mike if you're just using colors why don't use set the boosters
and this section to be the same color.
And the reason for that is because then I can't just change those things without affecting things that
well really they shouldn't affect.
Now what I'm going to do here is I'm going to scale that cylinder on the Z axis by point of five and
G Z lower it down.
Now it's not quite clipping to the right place.
So going to hold down shift to do a gradual lowering down to about there.
And we can see some intersection there so I'm going to go into orthographic view and zoom in a little
and go G Z left it up to the right place.
Grab this lower one duplicate it G Z.
I haven't given myself much room to get that right maybe a G Z let's bring that back down
okay so this point I want a tapered off but I don't want it going all the way.
So I'm going to add in a cone and open up the operator panel for the cone.
We still want 32 vertices because that's what the cylinder underneath has but note it has
radius 1 and radius 2 so us at this is point five and then go G Z to lift this thing up aha scale
by 0.5.
He said lower it down.
We're almost there we just need to align it's a bit better.
Here we go.
Starting to look pretty good.
Now once again we can take this one here.
Duplicate it, Go G Z lift it up and then scale that by point five.
Look at it from the side, scale it by two on the Z axis and then go G Z and lift it.
Oh it was right.
Perfect I'm now going to go G.
Z lift it up to there and I'm going to add another cylinder going to duplicate one and just scale it
down on the Z axis.
By point 1 I think I'll fit in this gap.
I'm going to make this one rocket black and go G Z and lower it down to the right place.
She's about there and then I just need to check that it fits properly.
Oh it does.
Perfect.
And I might do the same here.
So I'm gonna grab both of these areas go G Z and lift the two way up.
Grab this one here.
Now I'm starting to repeat myself lots.
I think you guys are getting what I'm doing here.
So I'm going to fast forward the video now because I'm just going over the same stuff repeatedly getting
that sorted.
The final thing here is going to be a nozzle on the end and nozzle on the end.
Why am I thinking a cone on the end of the nozzle.
Okay so let's go ahead.
I can't duplicate that because it doesn't have the right end but what I can do is create a new cone
K were almost there.
I'm gonna go for a very sharp cone go and there's a very doddey looking rocket.
Let's see if we can make these boosters a bit more boosty, I'm going to put these all in a collection
called rockets just so it's easy to manage.
That's looking good.
So all of the rockets together bring back the ground give the ground a material.
I'm going to call the material ground.
I'm going to still make it portray in it's aspect ratio by going to the output properties and changing
these around.
So this will be 1080 by 1920.
There we go.
And we can do a quick render just to see how things are looking.
Excellent.
So the final thing that I'm going to fake the sky is one of the things that can happen with a lighter
sky which I'm sure some of you have now discovered is it will contribute to the light.
So if you just change the background to a bright blue it changes the entire scene which is not great.
So I'm going to keep the background a darker color of gray and then we just need a fake sky.
So let's go ahead and pop back in.
Going to put a plane in rotate it's on X or Y by night.
Then rotate by 45 degrees on the Z axis and put it behind the rocket.
Usually it has to be far enough away that it's not to cast a shadow on it and we'll break the illusion
and let's call this one sky and I'm going to make this a very light blue and we'll render that out.
Awesome.
And the great thing is because it's being lit up we've got this lovely fall off across the image as
well so it's lighter on one side than the other creating that lovely little gradient on both the ground
and the sky element.
That's pretty awesome.
And it's going to name this sky as well so I know what it is.
I really liked how that worked out.
Well there we go.
Just using some very fundamental skills were able to make some quite convincing models straight off
the bat.
And of course the more time you put in you can create some really intricate objects and houses and vehicles
just by slapping together primitives and maybe scaling them and stretching them.
Okay so there we go.
Well done.
I'm happy with my rocket here.
I hope you're really happy with whatever you've made as well.
I'm really looking forward to seeing them so please do share them over in the discussions and really
looking forward to it.
I can't wait to see what you guys have managed to make up from just primitives and sticking them together.
Did you make a castle or a fort perhaps a train a vehicle please do share your work and I'll see you
all in the next lecture.