Welcome to multiple cameras in this video you will add another camera to the scene change the primary
camera.
Learn how to quickly move the camera around and change the camera's properties.
So let's hop straight on over into blender.
So we're left with our bunny here and we're going to hop back from the image ed which you were in at
the moment over to the 3-d view.
Now we're over in the free TV.
I'm just going to move this across just a little.
And I'm simply going to take a duplicate of our camera.
I'm going to zoom out a little selects my camera in the 3D view.
It's highlighted orange and using shift ends.
Make a duplicate and place it over there.
So we've now got two cameras in our scene.
If we go down to view and view from the camera view it'll go straight back to camera.
Well the one that's just cool camera and one called cameras 001.
So I'm going to name this camera over here camera wide and we'll make that a wide angle lens in a moment.
So we've got our two cameras here.
But how do we how do we actually view it from the camera or this wide one that we've just made well
down once that's selected.
Down on view and cameras.
You can set the active object as the camera.
You can see the shortcut.
There is control and no pads zero just switching to the active camera is no pad zero is very straightforward.
Your cursor does have to be in the 3D window control and zero will switch the camera over here.
So we've got these two cameras that we can select and go backwards and forwards between.
Have to be over 3D view.
Mary Kate so why would we want to do this.
Well there will be times in your scene where you don't want to keep having to move the camera about
between certain positions where you can just have it set up.
Another reason would be if you had different styles of camera so a wide angle where you can see lots
of a scene or a close scene shot there's a lot of theory on the size of focal length as to what you
require.
But this isn't a camera course it's a call some blender so are only touch on it very likely.
Focal length is measured in millimetres.
And basically the lower the number the wider the angle will be.
So the more you'll be able to fit in your scene and the closer your camera will have to be to any object
and you also get that very wide angle look a lot of state of videos and things like that have that fisheye
lens.
Now a fisheye is an extreme wide angle it pretty much encompasses everything in front of the camera.
But it's a bit distorting as well portrayed tends to be around 80 mm something like that telephoto if
you're taking a photo of a bird or an animal in a distance you may have 200 300 400 even higher mm lens.
Now if you were replicating something in a blender that you wanted to do in real life then of course
you would have to make sure you'd also set up your camera appropriately by default.
And we can have a look at these settings.
Now we've got the camera selected at the top here in the propertys window.
There's a camera.
And when we click on that we can see the focal length here is set to 35.
And that's great.
That's a great standard size 50 mimics the human eye.
That's a good number to remember there.
But of course it all depends on what you want to do if you're doing a wide open landscape.
You probably want a wide angle lens.
You're zooming right into the eye of an animal you're probably not going to be right up next to that
animal.
So I'd look really odd if it was wide angled apart if you're looking for an odd type of view then it's
a perfect way of getting there.
So we've got our focal length here we can lower that and raise it and if we set that down to something
like 10 it looks like it's just moved further back from the Rabbit.
But in fact hasn't.
But I want to move my camera now towards that now is selected at the moment.
One of the great things you can just do is open up your properties tabloid press the nke and up here
there's a button that says Lock camera to view.
Now the great thing about this is as you move around the camera moves too which is very powerful when
your having to position a camera.
So now we're at this silly wide angle.
You can see that the rabbit becomes much more distorted.
And if we take that down to something crazy like five.
That's not what the Rabbit looks like anymore but we can fit the whole rabbit in the scene.
If we come out of the camera view for a second to see that the camera is actually there it's really
really close to our rabbit.
Now if we set that back to let's say 50 like the human eye all that might not actually work.
Oh yeah.
There we go.
We're right up against the rabbits.
There's a big difference between 50 and five.
As you can see and if this was a real rabbit we'd probably be taking a photo from all 300 mill lens
or greater.
And yet we would be very close to grab at that point so we can move the camera out of just present twice.
They're to move just backwards.
And now to fit the whole rabbit in view you can see it's also not distorted as much.
Well here's a good thing to watch here we've were reaching the clipping point of the camera so I will
just leave it about there.
So the heads in shot but let's go see where that camera happens to be.
I'm going to remember to turn off lock camera view because now when I move away I'll be able to see
the cameras all the way over there as if you were hiding in the bushes taking a photo of this rabbit.
So there we go if change some of the camera properties we can move around.
Control and no pads zero or down here in the camera's menu under the View menu here cameras.
You can set an active one so if we want to go to this wide angle lens here and I go over the 3D view
and the control in 0 There we go back to that when I can lock the camera it's a view and just rotate
it round and move it about.
So that then I get it back in shot absolutely fine.
Now the active camera is the one that renders as well so if we go ahead and render here it will be using
the camera wide in order to render our shots.
However if we then set the active camera to this one here the just the one that's called camera.
So there we go that's Camera wide rendering that one now if we go back over to the 3D view and get a
camera and go view cameras set camera say active objects as the camera.
There we go that's that done.
Now if we go and render again we're now going to be rendering it from that camera viewpoint.
So if you're playing about this make sure you've got the right camera when it comes to rendering the
shots that you want to do.
Okay guys it's Challenge time.
I'd like you to create another camera so create a couple of new cameras.
Play about with the settings that we've just done.
Gets used to how the camera handles and sets one of the new cameras took a wide angle break quite close
to the Bunny and I suggest about 18 mm pause a video now and give that a go.
Okay guys.
Welcome back.
Let's hop straight back over into blender.
So I've already created a couple of cameras here and I'm going to call this one here camera 35.
And the other camera up here and then record it camera.
Three hundred eight not three thirty three hundred and I'm going to duplicate another camera.
So the easiest way I could add a new camera to a scene if I wanted to but I'm just going to duplicate
this camera 35 with shift Andy.
And unguaranteed was all the way over to espy control in zero so I can see what's going on with cameras
zero zero zero.
I mean we call this camera 18 so I know what it is.
Down in the lens properties of the camera.
I'm going to set that to 18 and see what the views like.
And I'm going to position the camera and lock the camera at two of you.
And let's just zoom in just a little bit more.
Probably about there and to rotate round a little.
Let's look up on the bunny Let's make the bunny huge in our scene.
Sue me out ever so slightly.
I'm not quite happy with that.
I want to see more of the is in the scene.
This way a little over a take rameau course.
This is all artistic licence has no right or wrong way of doing this.
There again let's render and see how that looks because that's the active image.
It's always a good idea to render things out or at least have a small part of the scene rendering.
X. And so that's what my Rabbit looks up like when it's got an 80 mil lens pressed against its face.
I'm just going to make sure that I've got on here go back to the 3D view can uncheck this lock camera
to view because the last thing I want to do is actually move the camera after I've set it all up.
One thing you will notice is that when you zoom in an ounce that's obviously the view the cameras got
there when you click lock camera to view.
Well now the cameras zooming in and out so as before you probably saw that it was like that on my screen
and I was zooming in and I could see enough on my screen.
Sorry if you couldn't see much going on there but you could zoom in and reposition it from there and
get a much better feel about what's going on.
Brilliant.
How did you guys get on.
Love to see your wide angle rabbits.
Please share them in the discussions.
And I will see you in the next lecture.