Hello everybody and welcome back in this lecture.
We are going to have a look at linking across multiple blend files so referencing other blend files
is incredibly useful it means you don't have to repeat yourself which when you have maybe an arsenal
of materials that you can access or a series of measures there's no point in repeating yourself time
and time again if you have the information available to you.
And the great thing is that any change in the source files will update the link theta.
This also means if you're working in a team so you're working on a character and someone else is working
on the gun or a backpack or an ax something that the player will be holding in your game.
Now the great thing about this is they can be modelling those other objects and any of the changes will
update when I read load my character or suddenly when I save it and then come back again and that is
really really useful it separates the actual parts from one another and enables a team to work on one
project.
So there we go it enables multiple people to work on components of a scene.
Now we can use a relative or an absolute file structure.
These are very simple concepts.
Basically in general you're probably going to be going for a relative file system.
That does mean that if you've got everything stored in a certain directory structure it doesn't matter
what computers it's on.
However an absolute file structure doesn't make much sense if you're working in a team unless you all
share exactly the same file structure that's so prone to falling apart.
So I would avoid using that.
Now one of the things I will warn you about nice and early on when you're linking breaking a link can
be an absolute pain to fix.
Now what do I mean by breaking a link not breaking it within blender but say you go ahead and move some
of your files out on the desk.
So you go into File Explorer and you decide to rearrange some stuff that will break and it can be a
real pain effects.
It's very difficult to just find all of those things again.
Now I say difficult because I'm assuming your projects rather large if you've only got two things in
there of course is going to be easier to read link them all but obviously we need to avoid doing that
if possible.
So in general this is why when you've decided on a file structure and we'll talk more about that in
a couple of lectures time it's important actually stick with it and you'll find that sometimes there
are legacy file structures in larger organizations and bigger projects.
And that's because changing something will break the projects.
It's better that it doesn't look quite right as a file structure if you're not going to spend hours
re linking things now linking should also be one way.
So let's say we've got our master seen here that we're building up I know I've got all of my files within
one blend file at the moment which is great.
Solves a lot of these linking issues but if I wanted something else this I wanted my chess set to be
within my scene itself what we would want to link it and I wouldn't want to have to recreate it in the
scene itself.
And of course any updates I make so I may want those to come across as well OK.
So let's go over into blender now and have a look at the different ways we can link our blend files.
Okay so now that we're over in Blender let's go ahead and create a fictitious object with some materials
on it that we could bring into another file.
So I'm going to call this cube here cube to link because that's what we had to be to link to link because
that's what we're talking about here we're going to link this cube into another blend file.
Now of course you can go ahead and grab any of your other projects that you've worked on but I'm just
going to very quickly create something that's make it red so we can see it.
Let's turn the roughness all the way down and if we have a look in the shaded view is a very shiny cube.
Excellent.
Let's add in one modify and make a very shiny ball.
Here we go.
And I'm going to right click on it and shade it smooth.
Would you look at that.
I'm going to go ahead here and add one more subdivision just to smooth s so that all looks good.
Okay let's go ahead and save that and I'm going to call this.
Make sure I'm in the right folder.
Let's call this cube to be linked and it's actually a ball rather than a cube.
There we go.
So we've set up that blending file with the material in it that we can bring across.
Okay.
So now let's go ahead and craft selves a new file and I'm going to get rid of my default cube as we
always do.
Now let's go ahead a file and we've got two options.
We've got link and append now append is one form of linking that takes a copy but it does not link back
to the previous file we're focused on linking.
So go ahead and click on link.
Let's go to where we've sold our file and go to the cube to be linked.
Now it doesn't open it up at that point it actually opens up a series of data blocks that we can go
ahead and access.
Now we could go into material and just get the material.
Now we didn't name it.
So it's not a particularly good name but that's okay for the moment for our practice.
We've got material here.
Let's go ahead and grab that ad Suzanne the monkey into the scene and then under my materials I can
select that and we can see here it says l 0 material and so is this where it is.
Now when it goes in again extra icon we can see we have the chain icon there.
And if we hover over that you can see you can actually break the link and make it local.
At that point.
But we'll talk about making it local later on.
And now we've got Suzanne the monkey with that material on which does mean and I want to demonstrate
this for you.
Now we're going to save this and I'm just going to call it Suzanne linked and now we can go ahead back
into our cube to be linked.
Change the color on that.
Let's change it from this red to a green just for an example file save.
Then when we go back into our other file Suzanne linked it automatically updates what we had before.
Pretty awesome being able to do that.
Now notice that the material is great out.
It means that we cannot edit it at all.
We try and rename it.
We cannot do that as well.
Now interestingly the warning I gave you about breaking links earlier if we renamed our cube to be linked
file then it would definitely break it.
I'm not going to say if I want to come back in here.
However if we go ahead and change the material and call this shiny green paint which could be a valid
name save our file and go ahead and open up Suzanne linked are it also applies.
So this is one of the things that you need to be careful with because that's broken that link.
So I wanted to get that in there nice and early because it's really infuriating if he didn't realize
that renaming it will break the link of course that's a very straightforward fix.
But if he did that to many things it'd be a real pain to do so so I'm going to close that down there.
I can go straight back into here file link and this time instead of the shiny green paint you see it's
updated there we can go.
Upper level and go to the objects.
Now what the object would do if we select the cube to link is it would also inherits all of the extra
bits below it.
So not only the mesh but the material as well.
Now over on the right there's a couple of options here we've got relative path.
This is important I think in general you're going to have that text.
It just means that when you have a certain file structure on a disk it's not reliance on it being exactly
like mine is up here.
It'll be all based upon the relative path based on where you've stored your data.
So let's go ahead and select link.
Excellent.
We've got our ball in the scene but we can't move it out there and look our cube to links come in with
the chain icon there as well.
Now let's go down to Suzanne and go ahead and add on the shiny green paint.
We've got another material in here are material to be linked.
That's not going to happen at this point in time.
So a couple of things we can do we know it's got a zero on there which means if we go ahead and save
and revert it will disappear
there we go.
It's gone.
And so's the other material that we had in our scene so we can move Suzanne around because she is local
to the scene.
However the bull that we've imported we cannot move at all.
And if we go to our modifiers tab we can see that we can't add any additional modifiers to this either.
That's locked out.
We cannot rename the match data the object eight.
We can't add new materials on either.
This is completely locked and completely linked to the original object including its position in the
world.
So if we were to go ahead and go to file and open up a cube to be linked which is now really a ball
and shift it GZ for Clay sits for units on the z axis up save our file and go ahead and open up Suzanne
linked it's moved there as well so you can see this is incredibly useful if you're bringing something
in all the parts in a certain position and you don't want the other person working on your team to be
able to move things around.
Perhaps the sets up as a very intricate system and by moving them you could break things.
That's especially true later on when you have perhaps drivers changing how another object is working.
Being able to move things around can screw around with that setup.
Now one final thing I want to talk about before we go and start being able to edit some of the properties
of our objects that we've linked to is that even though the chain exists here and it says it's a direct
library link it's a block that we can make local.
We cannot actually make that local at the moment because the material is further down the hierarchy.
We'd have to make everything above it local first so there we go.
That's how we go ahead and link to external data blocks.
Now you may be thinking well this is great Mike but I can see the use of importing materials I can have
a materials library and a blend file that I can keep referencing to and storing more and more materials
in.
That sounds fantastic.
I can just append new materials into that whenever I want.
But what use is this when I can't even move it and with the exception of that very specific case where
it has to be in a certain order.
Well in the next few lectures we'll talk about how we can make this editable and how we can go ahead
and use it in Blender and we'll start by talking about proxies and I'll see you in the next lecture.