In this video we can add more of a textured look to our hair by adding color variation within our hair
so it looks a lot more like hair actually looks rather than just one uniform color.
And we'd be using this simple material set up to do that.
My computer's been really struggling to do the screen recording and to do this exercise so I'm going
to reduce the numbers.
I'm in my particle system clicking on head hair I'm going to reduce the number of display for the children
down to say 10.
And also the render amount to 10 so I can be in cycles mode still see the hair but there's not quite
as many children here as many hair strands hopefully that'll make things go a bit more smoothly and
very briefly before I forget we've talked about this nearly talked about a couple of times I was going
to one of my other views here the material view you can see that our hair strands have a curve to them
and you can see there's quite a distinct edging to it.
So it makes the hair not quite as polished.
If you want to get some more detail and there go into your particle properties look for viewport display
strands steps instead of two let's increase that to three or four or five you can see after all it doesn't
really make any difference the difference between two to three was the most dramatic.
Let me see if I can zoom right in here on my hair strands because of the length of hair that I've got
in the way that I'm using this from two to three that looks a bit smoother and from three to four.
That's when we get a much more smooth line and I reduce this back to to just so I can have a look in
this view and have my computer not misbehave too much.
Suddenly my render at four I think I will say five.
That's right smooth skin maybe take a little bit longer to render but that's gonna make the hair look
nice and smooth while or in the viewport even if I'm in rendered view you can see that it's a little
bit angular.
Okay.
Now let's talk about color so I'm clicked on a head hair you can see when I'm looking on my shader editor
which I'm on at the moment shader editor we still have the material from our head instead of head we
want to create a new material head hair I think we'll call it so open to material property Tab I'm going
to hit minus or delete or get rid of remove that's what I'm after the head everything goes white as
it should.
We need to click new and I'm going to rename this click then rename it hair now within the material
properties you can see we have the surface which is currently principal B.S. The F we want to change
that to be hair.
The SDF so it understands that this is hair that's going to rearrange my shader edit here a little bit
so it's easier to see now we need to plug something into hair base there be SDF to give us variety and
that's gonna be a color ramp so shift a and search for color ramp puppet to the left the hair B SDF
we want to connect the color to the color.
Now we have a standard color slider so I can move the black node up and down and that will give us more
black as a proportion of the hair and less white.
So we now have black strands we have white strands.
If I scrolling around a little bit actually you know let me change the colors to make it a bit more
pronounced if I click on the White node and then click on the large white area below that then we can
change the color to say we'll make it green so it really stands out makes it very obvious and you can
see that we've got some black and we've got some green really pops let's change the black to make it
even more obvious so it stands out a lot so click on the Node click on the color just drag the wheel
drag the slider up so that we get more color in there and I'm going to change it to pink and you can
see that it's black and white why is that.
Well it's not giving us the full range of the colors when we try to go from color to color we need to
add one more note so give ourselves a bit space over on the left here shift a and I'm going to search
for hair info that will let our material know that what we're doing is hair info grab the random slot
and drag that over to the factor the f I see now you can see that we've got lots of pinks and lots of
greens within our hair because our note our color ramp feeding into our hair be SDF understands that
this is hey we're working on looking a little bit nasty at the moment because I don't have a lot of
hair strands in there I've reduced the numbers and my computer behaves a little bit more it kind of
looks like a punk rocker who's lost all his hair it's very thinning isn't it but we can go on create
more sensible colors so if I click the color slider drag down to a Brown a darker kind of brown now
we've got brown and green still looks a little bit wrong click on the green click on the green again
and then do something more in the White area that's starting to get into what actual hair is going to
look like where we have some varieties some texture again so it's thinning so I do need to add more
children pretty soon but for now it is looking at the color I can drag down the slider to give different
proportions and I can also click the plus button here on the left hand side of color click the plus
button I can drag that slot or that color slot up and down whatever I want it and I can change the color
so now I'm putting in a third color make this more of a pure white or a gray kind of white color.
Then you can see that we've got these three colors being represented so you can have two or three or
ten colors that are being represented and with variety throughout your hair and the positioning of the
slider.
How much space it occupies within the slider is going to determine how frequent that hair strand appears.
So it is going to increase the display amount for my children and my particle system just so we can
get a bit more of a fuller look.
And he doesn't look quite so old and decrepit.
There we go.
So it's a full kind of look we've got the texture there's some light hair popping through it's overall
it's kind of got that darker brown color with a little bit of the lighter brown in it.
And that's the foundations of how we get variety into our hair.
Now I've clicked on F 12 just to do a quick render so we can see how this looks when it's properly rendered
out.
I'll just speed up the video a little bit here so I can show you the output of this render.
OK.
That's how I expect it to be some texture some different colors represented in the hair look and how
I wanted to.
So let's just close that out OK.
Let's have a look at the material here so you can see the nose hair info into color ramp.
We can change our colors and add more in if we want if we want more colors.
And then into hair BSD.
And then finally into the material output.
This is all the material that is applied to our head hair.
We can also change the roughness roughness you and roughness V to see if we get a different look that
we like in terms of our color on our hair not gonna play around with this too much because my computer
is really unhappy at the moment with the screen recording and with Blender doing a lot of this high
intensity work.
But that's something that you can fiddle around with if you want a slightly different look.
Now let's get you creating it's time for a challenge add some color randomness create a new material
for your hair switch to hair BSD f add a color ramp node and then change the color as in the current
node add more if you want add Hey info node and link random to factor so that knows that we're dealing
with here and then to tweak the roughness in the hair BSD f if you'd like to get a slightly different
color and of course please share a render with us in our discussions so we can see what you've come
up with then we can celebrate how cool your particular head looks so I'm going to leave you with just
on screen here the material set up so I know that's the most important thing to look at as time's going
on so there's your challenge take that on and please when you come up with something cool please share
it with us in the discussions and I'll see you in the next lecture.