Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to focus on actually getting our animation design document nailed down.
It's important that we don't have scope slip and end up doing things and going off on a tangent.
Now much like every other project that we've done so far we need to have a design document so that we
can stick to it and know that we've succeeded.
And these are recommendations when I say 10 seconds or 30 frames per second later on.
These are examples probably close to what I'm going to stick to as I go through.
You can feel free to modify these and we'll go through the impact that might have in this lecture.
So first of all the length the longer the animation is the longer it's going to take to make.
Ten seconds is a nice sweet spot.
Five is probably a little on the short side and 30 is probably the absolute limit.
We want to do here.
Unless you've done animation before and you really want to stretch your legs the frame rate itself 30
frames per second is a relatively good frame rate for what we're going to be working on it's going to
show smooth animation it's not going to be jerky but also it's not going to take too long to render
out our animation.
The higher that frame rates coupled with the longer the animation will be the longer your render times
will be regardless of using eval cycles.
Something to bear in mind also frame rate may be dictated outside of blender so you were making assets
that you wanted to use in a game engine you would need to make sure that all of your assets had similar
frames per second because it's really really a pain in the backside if you're importing assets into
a game engine and they've all got different frame rates that can really slow down workflow when it comes
to exporting and importing assets.
So for this project we're going to find and set a certain frame rate.
And again it's up to you what you set.
I'm probably going to go with 30 frames per second because that's a nice intermediate frame rate.
It's not gonna be too jerky was that the same time.
Not taking too longer to render the number of cameras.
Now you could have multiple cameras in a scene it's only 10 seconds long or roughly around there.
So I'm going to focus on just having one camera we're also going to animate the camera and move it through
the scene itself.
So we don't want too much confusion there.
The number of characters so in this scene we have our animated lamp.
That's the main character again introducing more is just going to make it more complex and we want to
focus is the first time we've done animation on one individual character and just get them right now
the number of props I can imagine the scene at the moment where the animated lamp jumps onto something
perhaps knocks another thing off and then jumps off again.
So that to me means there's going to be one or two props.
Again we want to keep the scene as simple as possible rather than complexity at this very early stage.
Finally we need to set up blender with these settings in mind so we don't forget to do that.
If you don't have these settings done right at the very beginning it can be a real pain to try and correct
them later on because your animation will be locked to certain frames with in blender.
So we changed the frame rate it will look too fast or too slow so let's hop on over into a blender and
actually have a look at where these settings would be Hello everybody and welcome back over into blender.
First of all a few things have changed with the blender interface recently we've got a couple of extra
icons at the top here and I will go back and amend the early videos to reflect what those are but also
there's a bit of extra color and I really find this sort of thing useful as when they were all gray
it was quite difficult to differentiate all of these different icons but now they're color coded as
well which draws your eye to the appropriate one.
Okay.
So first of all let's have a look at the number of frames within the scene and the frame rates.
Those are the two that are going to make up the length of the scene.
Now never we go over to our output tab click on that in the properties and I'm just going to open this
up just a little there we go and scroll down.
We get this frame starts frame and the number of steps now that can be useful as I was saying earlier
you can change the apparent frame rate especially when rendering something early on because we don't
need all the information and the frame rate is just here.
So for instance if we wanted to set up 30 frames per second and it last 10 seconds.
So we changed the frame rate here and we can select 30 frames per second but that won't last for 10
seconds.
What we need to do is set the total number of frames here starting at 1.
The end would be 300.
That is a total including one and 300 of 10 seconds worth because we simply divide the number of frames
we have by the frame rate.
And that gives us how many seconds it's going to last.
So this is how I'd have it set up if I wanted a 10 second clip running at 30 frames per second.
If you wanted a twenty four frames per second and it lasted 10 seconds this would be 240 and if we have
a look down at the very bottom here and bring this area up we see that we have a start and end here.
And when we've been changing this area here whether we've got the start and end frames you notice that
this area here was also changing.
So you can change things as usual in multiple places in blender.
So now what I've shown you those two places it's time for your challenge.
Okay.
So your challenge Write down your animation specification now and you're going to stick to it for the
remainder of this section.
So think about the length the frame rate the number of cameras.
Characters number of props that you're going to have in your scene.
And then once you've decided on those factors what you will need to do is set up blender accordingly.
Even the default settings won't match up unless you specifically pick 25 frames per second.
That of course because you don't want to lose those settings.
Save the blender file as whatever you like I'm gonna call mine animated lamp.
So go ahead pause a video now and give that a go Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead now.
Hop on over into blender and set everything up.
So it's right for my specification of course if you're following along exactly you can follow along
here as well.
OK so this is where we left over in Blender.
Now I'm going to have a length of 10 seconds and a frame rate of 30 frames per second so I'm going to
set this to 300.
And so we've got a start and end frame yet that's fine and set the frame rate to 30 frames per second.
OK.
So let's have a look at the rest of our scene we've got one camera one keep one light.
Now the light itself.
I'm gonna get rid of that at this moments in time.
We can set up our own lights later on we may even only use the lights within the lamp itself that could
be quite interesting see how that works out.
The camera I'm going to leave one camera in there and I'm gonna get rid of the default cube whilst it
could act as maybe a prop within our scene the place hold a prop I'm gonna add in things specifically
ASM when I need them.
So there we go my basic scene is all set up.
I'm going to leave this area at the bottom called the time line down at the bottom as well.
If you don't have that remember any point you can click towards the very top of any of these blender
windows and drag down to create a new area and we can change the edit to type by clicking in the top
left and then we can change that to timeline itself if yours doesn't have that there you can see there's
this bit that you can pull out as well which should give us a summary of what we're changing but we'll
get to that soon.
Okay.
Everything there sets up apart from I've got multiple ones of these.
There we go.
That looks good to me.
I'm going to save my file into the animated lamp now whilst I'm in here I'm going to click the plus
key next to favorites.
So adds it to my favorites list if that area isn't there remember you've got this little hidden area
here that often likes hiding important places.
We got animated lamp in there and I'm going to call this animated LAMP AND THERE WE GO WE'RE ALL SET
UP AND READY TO START WORK IF YOU'VE GONE FOR SOME DIFFERENT SETTINGS I'd love to know why perhaps you
are planning on exporting to a game engine or you're using the footage with in something else that requires
the frame rate to be set that way please do share how you've set up your file over in the discussions
and I'll see you all in the next lecture.