Hello everybody and welcome to empties in this lecture.
We're going to introduce the concepts of an empty itself.
It is a null object.
It has no geometry is mainly used for control and organization and it can also be used in modifiers
as well and we can do really funky things with the array modifier if we use an empty, they can use be
used as a handle to control objects.
So later on when we get to animation we can set up an empty to make sure that a piece of a model tracks
to that empty.
And of course when we go to render it means that it will not be in our scene at all which is very useful.
It can be used as a parent object for a group of objects.
So much like you can shove everything in a collection.
Well if you need to move a whole lot of objects at once you can assign them to one empty and then just
move the empty.
And of course they'll have many other uses as well.
So let's hop on over to the blender and explore empties.
Okay so we're over in the default blend file here the first thing I'm going to do is add an empty so
you can get to it via the add menu or shift and A.
And when you do that we can go down to where it says empty and you will see that there are loads of
different types of empty that you can use.
They are all the same.
That's something that's very important.
This is just their appearance.
That is how they look in the 3D viewport.
Which one you actually pick doesn't matter at all.
I'm going to pick the plane axis for the moment and I'm just going to move over here.
Out of the way to show you what it looks like.
So it's got an origin just like every other object does and then it will have a certain shape as you
can see here it intersects the origin.
If we were to add a different type of empty let's say a single arrow this could be used to donate the
direction of something and how it should move.
And that's the purpose for having these different empties it's just to infer a different type of movement
or different use case.
So I'm going to delete that empty from there.
So what we can do here is we can select tile cube shift and select our empty go control and P and parent
it.
Now that means that when we move around this empty much like when we move the chessboard around all
of the associated pieces followed.
Now just remember over in the outliner.
Everything is in one collection at the moment the scenes collection.
However if we wanted to see the hierarchy of how things are parented we'd need to switch from view
layer to the scenes and then we can break everything down into the objects and their hierarchy itself
and that's useful being able to switch between those two because depending on what you're doing you
may find one view more informative than another.
And it's certainly when you start getting things piled on top of each other much easier to open up your
outliner.
Maybe stretch it out a little here and select the item by just clicking on it here.
So empties are incredibly useful they just go in your scene.
You can use them to control.
So at this point we could rotate the empty you can see that the cube will rotate from this point here.
Now that's really really useful because that means we could also use it as a pivot point.
So if you've got something that opens and you need to use this elsewhere in order for it to work that's
what you can do.
So now we've had the overview of empties.
I'd like you to use them now in our challenge.
Okay.
So your challenge sets up an empty for the black and white pieces and also add another empty for the
pawns themselves.
Now where you store the empty in the scene.
Just think about it logically and where you would want to place that she may wants the whites and black
pieces to be in certain locations and obviously dumping all of your empties on top of one another might
not be a great idea for selection.
Also you're going to have to add those black pieces into our scene and give them an appropriate material
as well.
Parent the pieces to the appropriate empty.
You may have a different hierarchy from me at the end you may have the white pieces being a parent of
the empty for the pawns.
That's entirely up to you how you structure that.
There are a couple of ways of doing it my way is not necessarily the right way.
It would just be an alternative way.
Now use collections for grouping as well.
We haven't used collections in a while.
I'd like you to practice the skill of adding things to collections for the grouping as well.
So we're going to have a hierarchy with parenting and children and we're also going to have a hierarchy
of collections as well.
So for the white pieces maybe for the pawns it's up to you how granular you want to be but certainly
for the whites and black pieces and then check your reference material is your board the right way round?
I know mine isn't so I'm going to have to sort that out. Pause a video now and give that a go okay.
So with our chess scene loaded up the first thing I need to work out is selecting everything at the
moment is going to be a real pain to go along and just hold down shift and select things is perfectly
possible because what we have here isn't too difficult to do.
In fact what I would do here is I'd highlight everything and then hold down shift and just click the
board twice to make the active selected and then deselect it.
Now I think we've got all of those objects selected and first of all I'm going to move them into a collection
because when we move them into a collection then these will be black pieces.
Initially when we move them into this collection what we can then do is whilst we're in the scenes view
in the outliner.
You can open up scene collection and just click on black pieces or just click on selection and it will
automatically select everything.
If you are in the other view the view layer when you do that.
Let's go down to black pieces if you click on it it doesn't select the black pieces.
You'd have to right click and select objects to do that.
So I'm going to go back to the scenes layer so everything's both got the collections there so I can
test them.
And it's got a hierarchy that we have.
So we've got a chess board and then we've got everything else underneath it.
And of course this will change in a moment when we start adding our empties.
But the first thing I want to do is select my black pieces duplicate them move them on the X axis by
I think it's going to be minus 30 or sorry the Y axis.
There we go.
And whilst they're all selected I am going to have to select these two notches because they're not, there
we go and then move them once again to white pieces
okay so now we have the two collection the two main collection set up.
It is now a matter of selecting everything else here and G Y.
And I think that's going to be twelve.
Yes minus twelve.
Okay so we've got the basic set up there.
These all need an appropriate material on them.
So let's go ahead with just one of them selected for the moment and go to our materials have going to
add a new material and I'm going to call it black pieces because we may have a different material for
the black squares certainly worth bearing in mind.
And I'm just gonna make it a dark gray for the moment.
There we go because it's a linked object linked duplicates all of the other linked items of inherited
that which is really awesome and that's the purpose of doing that.
Now I can just select black pieces from there.
Same thing happens now.
These don't have a material at the moment so I'm going to create new material and call it white pieces
and that's fine that's now applied to all of the linked.
And finally here we can just select it from the dropdown white pieces.
Excellent.
So now everything has got the appropriate material.
Everything is in collections.
It's just a matter of thinking about ordering things naturally.
So we'd need to add in a couple of empties.
So I'm gonna select all of my pawns here.
Now there's a couple of way of selecting all the pawns.
What we can do here is just select all of the objects that share the same object data, the same mesh
data I'm going to press shift then L and that also select linked.
So we want to select things that are linked by object data and then we go we've got all of those selected.
I'm going to go shift and S to move the cursor to selected which is smack bang in the middle.
And I'm gonna go and add an empty it's going to be a plain axis which is absolutely fine.
I'm gonna make the radius a little bit smaller maybe five centimeters because our scale of our model's
quite small rather than a meter across and I'm going to call this object black pawns.
There we go.
So that's the black pawns one done there.
And I can do the same thing again.
Shift L select all of the linked objects.
Now it may be difficult to select the empty without clicking on the board so I'm going to go over to
my outliner to find the black pawns empty and parent all of them to it's excellent.
And now we need another empty.
And I'm gonna go to my 3D cursor here and just move it's using the field over on the right and I'm going
to place.
Let's see.
Yeah probably they're going to add in another empty plain axis I'm going to call this empty black pieces
and now we've done that.
I can select everything that shares the same material.
So shift and L, select material.
There we go.
We've got everything there.
Find the black pieces and parent it.
Now you can see here there's going to be a backwards and forwards coming here.
So at this point I am going to not have the pawn selected actually I'm going to select the bishop shift
and L object data.
I'm going to make sure these notches are selected as well and I'm going to link those and parent them
sorry to the black pieces individually so making sure that the empty is the last thing to be selected
and then the black pawns empty.
I'm going to parent that to the black pieces empty.
So you just have to think carefully about the order in which you do things.
And now I'm going to repeat the same process on the other side.
Now rightly thinking you could actually just duplicate everything we've now got here and move it over
to the other side and switch that piece color out and then do a bit of renaming.
And I think that might actually be a good idea.
Yes I'm going to give it a go.
It may fail but I think that's actually going to be the better way of handling this particular operation.
So I'm going to delete all of those pieces.
I'm going to select all of these ones and it looks like I've managed to capture everything but concern
that we've we're missing a notch over here.
So something's happened to our notch at some point I think.
Yes.
So when we've applied the parent at some points there we go.
When we parented in our bishops here so control and P we need to keep the transform.
Otherwise it moved the notch away.
Okay.
And then I think we need to go back and do the black pawns and parent it to the black pieces parent object.
And there we go it's not moved anything else.
Perfect.
So now we've caught that one out.
It's important to check your work as you go not just blindly blunder forward like I just did.
We can delete all of those select all of these including that empty there.
I think they're all selected.
Perfect.
Let's duplicate those and then move them on the Y axis by minus 30.
Again that didn't move quite right did it.
Let's just continue moving it on the Y axis.
So that's roughly right and we can place things perfectly in a moment.
In fact let's just have a look at their world position.
If I said that's a minus twenty one we should be good because everything else has been pulled along
with it and then we can go ahead and grab these bishops I can do that but just aligning it like so and
moving them on the Y axis by minus twelve, I move them to the right position.
Now we've got a slightly different position now for all of our pieces.
So I'm just going to undo that and rotates all of these pieces around.
So I'm going to select this one here rotate everything on the Z axis by one hundred and eighty and then
move it forward and then we should have everything in the right place.
So we're moving it forward by nine centimeters.
Here we go.
So that saved me faffing around with everything else and that's a great thing of actually using an empty.
I couldn't realistically done that operation as easy if I didn't have everything linked to it.
So the final thing here is to call this white pieces and then find this one and call this white pawns.
So this is the downside of doing it this way.
There was a couple bits of renaming to be done.
Now the pawns themselves they are obviously a bit different than they have been duplicated not linked
duplicates so they even though these are all linked duplicates of one another because we duplicated
them from here.
They've lost the association with the first low load so we can go along here and set it to white pieces.
This one.
Also to white pieces really quickly.
Okay.
And now it's time to test our hierarchies.
So you've got white pieces.
Doesn't select anything.
Perfect.
So let's go and make sure we've got things in our collection make sure we've got everything selected
looks good.
Move it to white pieces and I'm going to do that.
Oh did that actually move things.
Yes it did.
Hey sometimes when you click off it's not so easy to get select this lot here move them all to black
pieces here we go.
So that's good.
We should now be able to select the white pieces and the black pieces really quickly.
Excellent.
We should have black pieces and then white pieces individually.
We can just pick up everything by selecting that or selecting this one here and there's one last parent
to do all of these pieces.
Should be parented to the board so control and P parent it to the board itself.
That means if the board moves everything moves.
If we move the White pieces everything moves.
Excellent.
I think we're done and dusted.
Just gonna check my hierarchy once more so we've got black pieces white pieces chess board so a nice simple
object hierarchy and then our scene collection.
I'm just going to call this board for the moment because that's all that's within there.
There is a camera and lights as well so I'm going to call it board camera and lights.
Of course that may change later on as well.
Hey it's Mike back from a few lectures time I was about to go brilliant we're all done.
Please share your work and I just realized that just moving it to the side of the board doesn't put
a black square in this lower corner.
So there is one final thing to do here.
I'm going to select both of these empties and so the middle point will still be accurate when I go and
rotates it on the Z axis everything will swing around perfectly.
And I only need to do it by 90 degrees and then we've got the black square in the lower corner.
There is of course another way of doing it.
I could reassign black to white and it would flip all the colors around but simply rotating it around
the central point of these two empties is all we need to do.
And there we go.
Brilliant.
I can finally say it we are all done.
I'm really happy with how this is working out so far.
Hope yours are coming along really well as well.
If you did decide on a different hierarchy I'd love to see what you've done so please to share your
work over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.