In this video, I'm going to show you a slightly different technique for creating the geometry that
we can emit our hair from will work on the eyebrows.
I'm going to put in some facial hair as well, a beard, and we'll do a little bit of coloring, as
we've done before.
Now, I'm not going to show you the whole process of me making the hair and combing it and putting it
in the right place, because we've done that a bunch of times before and I know you know how to do that
by now.
So switch over into material view so we can see things more clearly.
Everything becomes black because we lose our coloring information.
We need to be in render view to be out to see that.
See my eyebrows.
They're just following the contours of the brown just above the eye.
And if I turn everything off, let me to show you the geometry that is emitting the hair.
And to do that just up into edit mode and edit mode, scroll in a little bit here.
You can see there's just two strips that I've got and not a huge amount of pulleys in this I don't need
at all.
The main thing is that we get the outside line and you've got good tight control over where the outer
aspect of the eyebrow is a little bit different to when we're doing the head where it didn't matter
quite so much.
But we want to really finesse where the positioning of the eyebrow is now going to hide my eyebrows
that I've created already in order to show you the process of creating new eyebrows.
So first of all, we want to do shift a at a mesh and that mesh will be a plane.
Just move the plane around a bit.
It comes in pretty big.
We're going to reduce it down in size, just hitting G y to move forward.
Then we'll rotate it and then X 90 to rotate that scale as to scale it down.
We're gonna put it over on one side of the face and then we'll mirror this so that it's we just have
to create it once, which would be nice and efficient, just getting it in the right spot here.
Now, there's a technique that allows us to get it positioned exactly where we want.
And that's going to be by adding a modifier and the modifier will be a shrink wrapped modifier.
So it's head over to modify properties first.
I'm going to add a mirror modifier so that we are just creating this once and click the pipette and
then we want to select our head big four head there as our object that we're mirroring on Mary on the
X axis.
Obviously, we don't need to worry about clipping at the moment because we're not going to be getting
our our two eyebrows right next to each other.
Well, I guess if you've got a mono, you might want to put them all the way in the middle like that.
But for me, thankfully, at this point in my life, I don't have a minor brow just yet.
So clipping doesn't really matter.
You can leave clipping on or off, just going to close up that mirror modifiers away.
I've got more space here and look for shrink wrap as our new modifier.
We're going to add underneath deform shrink wrap.
Click on that and a side note.
This technique is the same as you would use if you were doing re topology on a character, particularly
a character's head and the sort of thing that we talk about a lot more now.
Blender character, create a course.
So if you haven't had a look at that and you're really interested, interested in getting deeper into
creating characters, it's a great course.
Check out the next first.
Here's to click the pipette once again and will select the target as the head.
Just click straight on the head.
Head or head hair.
They're pretty much the same for us, aren't they?
And you can see now that we should be the plane or better rename this from plane and I'll call my new
eyebrows because I've already got eyebrows there.
So you can just call those eyebrows if you want.
Call my new eyebrows.
And after we've done that, back to what I was saying before, we can now click on our geometry.
We've got G to move as we move it around, it will glue to the face and a quick insert.
You also need to have snap turned on up in the middle of your screen.
The little magnet makes sure you've got snap turned on.
And there a couple of settings that we need to look at here with you now modifier itself.
So if you have a look within the shrink-wrapped, modifier down the bottom here, you can see on surface
we want to have this above the surface and then put an offset so that it sits away from the head so
we can actually see it.
If you don't have an offset, then it looks like it often is underneath the skin and it's hard to see
as you're working on it.
Sanghas set mind to, let's see, point zero zero one.
That might be a little bit too low.
Let's set it two point zero one.
I think that's nice.
Yep, that's pretty good.
Happy with that.
And the other thing we want to do is click on this page button or uncage.
And when we click on that, we will see the end result of where I've gumtrees going to end up.
So we just see what it is that we're interested in the final result, which is cool.
Let's get this first piece in position.
And the next step is for us to enter into edit mode from edit mode.
I'm going to click to so that I mean edge selection, select this outer edge, hit E to extrude and
then as I drag it, it's creating a new face and it's gluing to the side of the head exactly what I
want.
Looks pretty good.
I'm just going to create another one, a two extrude and then move along, rotate a little bit r to
rotate and you can see there's a little bit of the head poking through and that's easy.
We can solve that by adding a loop cut just to add a little bit more geometry.
And as you know control are to add a loop cut.
So I'd say if you add the amount of geometry that makes sense so that it's mostly in the same position
as the head.
But don't stress about it too much because remember, we're going to push this underneath the skin a
little bit at the end and we're also going to hide the emitter.
You'd want to make sure you don't have any floating heads, any floating eyebrows that clearly aren't
touching the actual head itself.
Now, going to move the vertices around a little bit.
So one to get into vertex selection mode.
And I currently have proportional entity on its O on the keyboard to turn that on and off.
And I forgot to mention as well, we want snapping turned on and I tend to do snapping snapped to face.
So you can see a little magnet is snapping on off and then we can click on Face to make sure it's snapping
onto the face.
I find this little bit cleaner than snapping two vertices.
Yeah.
That seems to be working.
So one to get back into vertex selection.
And I'll just move these around a little bit.
Like I said before, proportional editing, I've got on when it is on, it allows you just to get a
little bit more control.
I think just control the size of it with your mouse will up and down.
So I'm going to do a little bit of finessing here.
I'll just turn the speed of the video up.
You just want to get it.
So the obviously the eyebrow geometry is where you want your eyebrows to be coming out.
Back now into object mode, and I'll go over to my modifiers and make sure that we have applied the
mirror modifier first so that it mirrors.
Click on apply, and then, as we've done before, into our particle properties, click.
Plus, I'm going to rename this to be new eyebrow's.
You could just call yours eyebrow's if you so desire.
And then we want to click on hair.
And from here, you pretty much know the process.
You want to play around with the number of hairs.
I've put mine to 100 to see how it looks.
Also, the hair length, probably a little bit too long at the moment.
I'll try.
Point to them from now.
Just kind of finesse it down a little bit.
Just so it's in the general ballpark.
And we need to add children, make sure that when you are looking at any rende of you that you turn
off show emitter or when you're trying to look at it, how it will look in object mode.
And I'm just going to do a little bit of brushing and grooming.
Again, same process as we've done before.
So I'm not going to go into too much detail on this.
And at this point, I'm just going to switch over to the eyebrows I prepared earlier so you can see
what I've done.
There are important thing.
Make sure you turn off the show emitter when you're particularly when you wanting to render it just
in case you don't want to see that hanging around there.
We've done that before.
And another thing that we want to do here is if you go back into your modifies, looking at shrink wrap,
modify, just make sure that the hair is below the surface.
You can do that a couple of ways, either by making a negative offset, which is what I've done here.
I've got an offset of minus point zero zero five.
While it's above the surface, or you can just set it to a different positioning such as inside.
So it's below the surface.
So you can play around with those values then.
And we've talked just recently about strain size.
I found with the eyebrows.
I need to have them a thicker strand than I was expecting.
So just playing around with the let's see, scrolling down here.
Where have we got it?
Okay.
Here shape.
I ended up going with a diameter root of two and a tip of two as well.
Just so it was a little bit thicker.
Again, something for you to play around with in conjunction with how many children you've got.
For me, I've got around about value of twenty using interpolated just clicking into Rendi View here
so you can see there's a thickness to the eyebrows and it's not too thin and too, you know, too tiny.
Okay.
Enough about eyebrows for the moment.
I'm just going to click on beard and jump over an edit mode so you can see what I've done here.
Now if you've done any retail apology, it's really a similar process.
Don't worry about having it perfect for mine.
I wanted to create reasonably clean geometry, but again, it's about the edges.
Get the edges in the right position and have the geometry hugging the face.
So create yourself a new if you've got any facial hair you working on.
Obviously, if you don't, then don't worry about this.
But create yourself a new object, a new plane, as we did with the eyebrows.
Rotate it.
Scale it.
Get it into position.
Mirror it.
And then go through the process of extruding and joining everything up and so everything else, you
know how to do in terms of the grooming and the positioning and the coloring of the hair.
But I just wanted to show you in this video a different technique for creating the geometry, using
the shrink-wrapped modifiers so that we can glue that geometry to our existing head and then we can
get a lot of control over the exact edges for where our hair is being admitted emitted.
So the challenge I've got for you is create your eyebrows, any facial hair, if you've got some or
need some, and then please do share with us, render a final render of what you've come up with in
the discussions, because I'd love to see it.
Okay.
Great stuff.
I'll see you in the next lecture.