Hello everybody and welcome back at some point when you've linked to file you may want to make parts
or all of it local.
So let's talk about some advantages and disadvantages of doing so.
The advantage of course the big one here is you will have more local control.
In fact if you do everything you've essentially appended rather than linked in which case it's just
like a duplicates a copy of that data in your file without any links to the original external files
moving a project can stay together.
This is a very important one because if you're dealing with a large project having everything all in
one file as I'm currently doing in mine is really really useful.
The problem of course is it can balloon your blend file and make it much larger than it necessarily
needs to be.
However if you need to share your project with someone else actually appending everything into the scene
which is having everything local then that that might be the way to go and we'll talk about packing
into the blend file as well which is incredibly useful.
It means that any textures you don't need to make sure they're linked to specific places on drives.
They can be baked essentially into our blend file although caution you can get your blend file very
large which may take some time to open if you're not careful.
Disadvantages Potentially more work involved.
So one of the issues of course is as you probably guessed or talked a lot about how you can bake things
in and then you can share etc. When you have everything local it means that if you make one change you
may have to repeat that elsewhere whereas if you've got something linked in externally that one change
should affect everything where that particular data block has been linked.
Any edits you make on the original as you're saying their effect all linked data blocks but not the
ones made local.
So that goes for materials it goes for mesh data and it goes for particle systems as well and anything
that is a linked data block.
So when do you localize.
This is a great question and there's not going to be a hard and fast rule unfortunately it's going to
vary depending on your circumstances.
So a basic one he would just simply be when the link is not required anymore.
That's that's quite a common one.
Yeah.
I want to take this and just make it unique and not worry about the other file over there when you want
to make the asset unique so that moves on from this but in this particular file so maybe that you want
to make it completely unique by altering the mesh data and of course if you're using that file in other
places what you don't want to do is edit the original and then find that it ends up slightly wrong style
for instance all the wrong colors or the wrong materials in all of the other files where it's linked.
Of course if you're just working on small projects you may find that this never becomes an issue but
it is something to be aware of when you want to make changes irrelevant.
Other potential projects.
So that again goes on what I've just been saying you don't want to change your source file and have
it changed loads of other projects just for the one that you're working on.
OK.
So we have a couple of options when we come to making something local.
There are four in total will run through each one and then we'll go play over in Blender selected objects.
So this close the object data blocks to the new blend file.
Now this won't allow us to edit the mesh data.
It won't allow us to edit the material so it does bring across and it's almost like creating a proxy
at this point in time.
The all the other data blocks themselves remain linked to the original file.
So this allows changing of anything in the object data block but it won't allow any changing for the
rest of the hierarchy underneath option to selected objects and data.
So this will clone the objects and data block into the new blend file another data block is in this
instance when we're talking about an object like a like a cube that will be the data so be the mesh
data.
So now we can edit that file but it does mean that any changes to the mesh data will now be broken so
we no longer have that link going back to the original file.
But the materials and other data blocks will be linked to the original object.
So it means that if you update materials then of course they will update in this file that you're working
in as well option 3.
You can probably see how this is going.
Selected objects data and materials.
So this clones the object data her materials data blocks and that means that allows editing of the object
data and materials data blocks and breaks those links making them local to this file and that's pretty
much almost all of the things you will generally be working on.
And finally option for this is basically appending at this point just with an extra step involved.
So there is an option here that's all.
And as it sounds this is pretty much the same as pending the object into the scene is now entirely local
within your new blend file with no links to the original file and we will see that as well because an
icon will disappear when we do that sort of thing.
Let's go and have a look at this now and hop on over in the blender Hey welcome back.
Okay so we're about to experience some weird behavior so I've gone back into my Susanne linked so we
can play with making things local.
I'd like to show you some quirks as well as we go okay.
So to make something local we basically have to go over to where we've got the chain itself and go ahead
and click it.
That will remove the links and it doesn't really matter how many times we go ahead and click this chain.
However the ones that we duplicated earlier on they don't have the same issue notice here we've got
our shiny green paint so I can come in and change this and look how about that.
These are updating and these ones aren't which is very confusing because looking at the naming structure
and let's just pull these out here and have a look at the data within the cube to link proxy was the
one that we made first of all.
And yes it looks like here we no longer have with our cube the mesh data is no longer linked and the
shiny green paint is no longer linked either.
However this one still has it.
We're in edit mode this pair here this cube to link proxy.
They'll still have it.
So we're kind of in this deadlock at the moment we're trying to work out.
I mean at first glance you think oh OK.
Mike's talked about the hierarchy so if I look at the cube here or perhaps if I go down to the mesh
data perhaps I can release it there.
They just won't work with the selected.
You can go to object relations and make local selected objects.
It just doesn't like it.
So with this first proxy or proxies that you make you just cannot make that change to them.
They're not designed to work like that.
So what you can do instead I'm going to get rid of that proxy.
This is no longer a proxy.
So it can lose the proxy suffix on it.
If we go back to our original linked date to this cube to link it's just they're hiding behind the other
two bulbs every Go ahead.
Now is the time where we can go and make this local sense linked at the moment.
If we come in and get objects relations we've got a couple of options selected objects much like a proxy.
But without all of the caveats a proxy come along comes along with like the inability to change some
of those settings we were having a problem with objects and data that will mean we're able to edit the
mesh as we've discussed before data and materials.
Now we can adjust the materials or we can go for all.
Now when you select all as I've mentioned that is the same is just appending at this point so you can
come in.
Press all we're not quite there just yet and I believe that's currently not desired behavior.
I think that is a bug.
The easiest way at the moment may be object to local is to go to the object Data tab and then go ahead
and click.
And there we go we've now got the queue to link and we've got two instances of that we can see.
And when you click on though and when you click on the changing click on there we get the cube to link
comes back into fashion.
We can name it here and call it ball finally.
And it's got two users we can see there are two users of that particular data in the scene and then
we can come in we've got our cube here and we've got some material and we can't free up the material
yet it's an indirect library data block we cannot change it because it's based upon the mesh data and
the mesh data is linked.
So we can go ahead and free that up.
And once we've done that we can come in because of that hierarchy and make local our green paint swap
it out the other shiny green paint which is red so much better and now everything's all updated.
Now none of these now have any links back to the original.
That's one thing to bear in mind and be careful with when you're making anything local.
So how about a live example of that when we've been playing with it.
Let's go and put that to the test so let's go ahead and open up our proxy church that we've been working
on.
OK.
So now we're in our proxy season or let's say we want to modify this window that we've got here.
Obviously anything object related we can do.
The moment that we make ourselves a proxy or indeed use the library override we are in control of the
object data which can be really useful.
But one of the underlying issues with changing the scale or even even the rotation or position of an
object in the scene is it can affect modifiers it can affect particle systems and physics in ways that
you didn't conceive it might have done.
So just scaling this up might be brilliant.
And then we can put particle effects on it and it doesn't behave as you'd expect it to.
Because when we try to apply our transforms we can't do it.
It's a multi-user object.
So sharing match data is something else.
So we can't just apply it because it would change everything down the chain.
That's a safety mechanism to protect yourself.
And the reason why you might want to either make something local or make it unique.
So this point we can come in and make this mesh data here unique.
The moment we do that we should be able to apply all of our transforms multi-user objects.
So the windows are as you want mesh cube.
Eleven is multi-user.
In fact we didn't have to even have an error come up to see that it sees as two uses here.
So go ahead click on that.
It's now unique user.
And then we can go ahead and apply all of our transforms which means that this is really this big now.
Of course we could go into edit mode and do that in the first place but we are still had to of unlinked
the mesh data in order to be able to do that.
Now that's an obscene size and I don't have any control over it which is something I don't like.
I don't know how that big how big that is now because I've applied it all in particularly paying much
attention.
That can go.
Let's go through the process again let's link that across.
There we go.
We've got two windows here and of course the other way of doing this is with this window selected again
if I went shift in day rather than alternate day we've effectively made its own unique object with its
own unique mesh data that we can go in and edit straight away.
Now remember that will now be unique to this file which may be what we want if we want this to be the
end of the churches and we want the big window but we didn't want to keep modelling all of this extra
stuff we could come in and perhaps scale it on the z axis by two and knowing us that's probably not
quite right so let's undo that for the moment and scale on the z axis by four or three.
There we go.
That's pretty good.
Let's scale it on the x axis by 2.
Yeah.
There we go.
It's pretty good.
And now we could surround it with stuff if we wanted to.
Does the floor piece fit in still.
Or do we need an extra floor piece if we do that the floor piece also fits in.
Absolutely fine.
That's one of the things you've got to bear in mind if you go ahead and scale things.
And of course the bricks are now all the wrong size.
That's the downside of just scaling randomly.
But you get the idea how we can mockup a building and sort out all this incidental detailing later on
if necessary.
Okay.
Awesome.
I'm going to leave that information with you so you can play with it and make your building your own
and that's really where I wanted to go at the end of this lecture I want you to think about any extra
pieces you need.
Are there any special objects like perhaps this big window here that you can make do with just scaling
one of your existing Windows if necessary now.
I'll be honest at this point in time I'm not particularly planned mine to be this particular scale at
the moment and I would encourage you to just be experimental at this stage while you're still putting
things together.
You never know you might get one of those happy accidents happening and I really love it when those
two.
So go ahead make sure you fleshed out your your parts pieces and anything else you need to do.
Have fun and experiment with your building and I'll see you all in the next lecture.