Hello everybody and welcome back.
This will be the last of these very heavy lectures for the moment but I do want to whilst we've been
talking about managing our files.
Talk about managing our actual files themselves.
So a place for everything and everything in its place and the great understanding here is that there
is no one way of setting up your filing system.
I've been in a team where the programmers wanted it one way the artists wanted it another.
In the end we just had to settle for a compromise between the two that made sense.
Ultimately it will come down to whoever whoever is handling the data the most.
It makes more sense for the artist to have the say where and how textures and materials are configured
than the programmers who eventually just end up using them.
Because often there's a hierarchy that you need to have in one system that you don't necessarily need
in another and trying to merge the two together.
Sometimes it's just not possible.
So understanding that there's no one way of setting up your filing system and seeing the pros and cons
from both ways perhaps you can find a way of setting up your workflow.
So it's kind of independent of anybody else.
That's great.
Watch out for overloaded folders so I'll try to keep folders.
Less than 20 assets.
The problem is if you have too many things in a folder it becomes impossible to navigate sets.
And heaven forbid you have rock 20 which means you've got 19 other rocks in your folder.
I hope you have a better name system than that.
Or of course the folder is just going to be called rocks at that point.
Have a personal style of filing if you don't like mine.
As we start going through the course use yours there's nothing to save any particular way is wrong.
Goes back to that top point there there's no one way of doing this.
You may find that the project you're working on suits a different type of filing than what I'm doing.
Now we've mentioned team quite a bit here and in inner team you'll often form guidelines from your own
needs.
So depending on what type of project you're working on you'll often find that you need to name things
in certain ways or you need to store them in certain ways.
And this is especially true when you're starting to work with a particular game engines some engines
love your files being named in a certain way or your objects named in a certain way which is a great
reason why you shouldn't just leave things named cube dot 0 0 8.
I mean what does that even mean.
I bet it's no longer a cube either.
I know I've caught some of you out there.
So let's take three game engines that I have worked with quite a bit.
We've got unity got unreal and Godot.
Any one of those game engines requires a different way of naming things with unreal for instance you
need to have a U.S. exe file if you want custom collisions but you need to make sure that the hierarchy
is right within your outline as well.
And Godot that can have a suffixes or prefixes that you put on your on your files and that means that
they will automatically do other things being able to understand that and use the documentation that
comes along with your game engine speeds up workflow no end to do form some guidelines write them down
so you can remember them and then you don't need to worry anymore you can just export things with those
guidelines in place and it should work really well where is it is something that happens a lot especially
as a project gets bigger so you can go the Google approach as I like calling.
You can have all the files together makes it difficult to navigate potentially easy to search.
Now there is an argument here to say if you've named things appropriately you should be able to find
them with a name.
However it gets a bit awkward when you've got gravel Wang and Gravel two grand will three you really
need to see them.
They may be distinctly different and it does matter which one you pick.
Now all files for a particular asset together.
This is another way of storing your files so if you have let's say we're working on the church door
we could put all the textures and everything else together for that particular assets it's a pain to
find one file.
If you do that's because everything is all grouped together so that really doesn't help with share textures
but you could always start like this and float up.
So grabbing that say a wooden texture that you've got on your door then you find that you're using that
wooden texture as well on a torch or on a seat well you can just float up to a higher level.
But then again it does become a bit more difficult to track where things are.
So I would actually favor especially as a beginner if you're using that wood texture in multiple places
and you've got enough hard drive space.
Most people do these days then just duplicates it.
That also means that if you need to modify that wood texture that it won't modify everything that it's
linked to.
You can get yourself in a real pickle if you're not careful where things are linked together and it
be easy to lose track.
Trust me on that one.
Okay so another thing that you can do is store your assets by where they are used in the game so you
could have cemetery or office block or construction site or app wherever it happens to be.
You can store things logically in where they used and that also has the benefits of being able to have
a theme amongst your objects.
And it's really easy to see if something's not on theme.
However there's a possibility that if you're working with an artist and you're saying you need to make
these assets for me please they might not know the locations well.
So you can sort by categories so someone's focused on polishing an area of a game they're going to be
able to work on it.
Okay so let's talk about some external constraints things that we don't really have much say over we
we kind of do I suppose in some ways but ideally we should adhere to the standardization that makes
it a lot easier to communicate and work in a team game engines often have their own naming conventions
I've touched on that already.
Whether you need to name something with a prefix or suffix look at your game engines documentation and
work to that now meshes breaks and textures will often have different names depending on where they're
going to be used.
So in real for instance I'm working a lot and I'm real at the moment a diffused texture a albedo texture
the bass color whatever you want to call it the bass color of your mesh will have C as a suffix on the
end but it will also have a T at the beginning.
So naming things like that means that you know that they're going to be applied properly over in unreal
and that also means that you can filter things properly as well within the game engine when you're setting
up materials and it's not just unreal that that happens with it's with all external programs.
It could be substance so that you're working with for instance it doesn't have to be a game engine but
making sure you have things named appropriately so you know what it is you're looking at would be very
great.
So let's talk about a texture called bricks bricks doesn't mean anything.
Now you could type bricks normal or bricks bump map or bricks albedo or bricks or whatever.
Now the benefit of Isaac is quite generic.
You know what tests the downside of that is it's not in any specific format.
And again you will know what you're working with so named things appropriately OK so we've talked a
lot about external file management.
How to organize things.
But what about blender organization itself.
Well we're going to be making a much more complex scene than any we've previously made.
It's going to consist of many many parts.
So I would suggest you organize it as you go.
And this goes so goes through your file system as well not afterwards.
It will be a real pain in the backside trying to name everything afterwards or trying to put it into
collections afterwards.
Please remember to organize it as you go.
We're all going to fall foul of this.
And I've seen so many models that you look at afterwards and you just know that that's nearly impossible
to edit because nothing's named appropriately so you don't know what it is looking in the outline.
Okay.
Yes.
Use descriptive names.
Cube cubes are it was here one etc. is not helpful to anyone except of course if it is a cube then I
will let you get away with calling a cube but it is important it's not helpful for anyone you will know
what it is.
Now when you're working on it when you open up your file again perhaps even the next day you might not
have a clue what cube refers to if you looked at it.
You will have to go and have a look at it click it in the outline it come back to the 3D view look around
oh oh It's a door I better go name it door and that's why you can see why organizing as you go rather
than afterwards is a good idea.
So there are some no no's as well.
Never ever store multiple versions of the same asset in your master folder.
Now we've not talked really about a master folder but this is your current working directory.
If you've got a new iteration of something you're working on and it's to replace the older ones then
don't keep them all in the same place.
Push it into an archive folder so it's very clear that that asset is the one that you're using.
So one bit of advice here is not to rename that put it in your archive folder name the folder whatever
you need to but the asset itself don't go ahead and rename it renaming it will break any links to blender
files that you're using the assets in.
That would be a real shame and a pain in the backside to try and fix it or also break all the links
that you've got in your game engine as well.
Also not great.
Of course there is a kind of exception to this and that is when you're exporting let's say both unity
and unreal they both accept FP Xs see you probably going to be exporting into a specific directory in
order to overwrite a previous version and there we go.
That's it for me on this topic.
However this is a great thing to discuss amongst yourselves as well.
This is such a wide scope.
I'd love to hear how you guys organize your files as well.
The pros and cons of doing it that way.
Be open about it if you know that there's a downside.
Tell people about it as well as the good things about it and also if you've had some fun experiences
share those as well.
A good story of working in a team you can always laugh about it later can't you.
Anyway that's enough for me on this topic.
Please share your thoughts over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.