Welcome to combining shaders in cycles.
In this video you give the eye a material that is a combination of different shaders using the node
editor.
So let's hop straight on over into blender.
So I've got my two eyeballs here.
Remember they're a mirror of one another so one of these is real.
And one of them is essentially a reflection of it.
As I mentioned before make sure if you get a flat shading that the eyeballs are facing outwards from
your rabbits.
I'm going to go straight into this eyeball here using the number pad full stop.
That looks like it is the one.
Yes it is.
When I hop into edit mode it's just going to remember to turn smooth shading back on.
Eyeballs are quite smooth.
So with the whole eyeball selected we're going to assign it's a material.
So let's go to the materials tab.
To make this a bit bigger.
And I'm going to create a new material and just call it a ball.
Now we're going to see too much of this eye ball.
But it's still worth getting this bit.
Right.
And just leaving it as it is at the moment I'm going to set the colour to bright white and those who
assign it to the ball.
Excellent.
Now it's not going to be just a diffuse colours going to be a mixture of that plus a glossy colour his
eye balls are slightly glossy.
So let's go ahead and do that now.
So when he opened up the note editor so going to create a I'm going to go at the top here.
Well first thing we've had to do something here I'm just going to press the plus here and I'm just going
to name this something else.
I don't know I bought for the moment because that's what the workspace I'm using for I'm going to generate
a new workspace from here.
The reason why I've done that is I don't.
I know that going through this process I'm going to ruin my default layouts.
And of course this is going to be specialists for just this one case anyway so we're going to have to
open up the node editor.
There we go.
Wow.
That's small so I'm going to zoom in and we can see the way it's set up.
We've got a diffuse shader.
And the outputs is what it looks like something to turn on rended mode here.
So we can see what's going on and not so Lofts at the moment.
That's probably because there's no light in our scene some just going to turn the lamp on as well.
Much better.
So you've got this the fault shayler here.
I'm going to change the lamp type to a sun.
So we've got.
Ah I hear.
And let's go back to it.
We have a diffuse shader going into the output which is what it looks like.
Now I'm going to go down here to where it says add and go to another shader and it be a glossy shade
up and I'm going to place that here.
Now the next thing I need to do is mix these two shaders into one before they go to the surface in order
to do that.
Im going to use something called a mix shader.
Now there are two ways essentially of combining these shaders ones ever a mix shader or an add shader.
They have to be careful with an ADD shade because it literally adds the values together so you can end
up with something that is incredibly bright.
But in this case we want a mix shade because we want to be able to control the ratio between fuse and
glossy.
So I'm going to add this time in a different way with shift in a like you used to when adding a a primitivo
or something like that in the 3D editing mode.
And I need to add a shade of type mix.
Now another way of doing that is if you know the name is you can click on search here and I've obviously
previously searched MC shade up the moment you type in mix.
It's one of the options there so I'm going to click MC shader.
Now I can immediately place it on top of this line here and you see it goes orange.
And when I click it's going to link it in.
Brilliant.
The final thing we need to do is go from whereases be STF on the cross he showed up.
Plug it in to the shader down here.
And now we can see we've actually got a bit of speculative bit of gloss to our eyeball.
The final thing with the MC shader is of course there's this factor here.
And so we can make it 100 percent diffuse completely ignoring the settings we've got on glossy or we
can make it 100 percent glossy.
We don't want to either we want it somewhere in between and we can always go ahead and alter this later.
But the default value of about point two or thereabouts is perfect because it gives us a little bit
of a gloss to it.
Perfect.
So I feel a challenge coming on for you guys.
I would like you to create the rest of the materials so go ahead and create and assign the following
additional materials.
The iris and pupil use the eyeball material as the starting point remembering to make it unique for
each material.
Then finally use the reference material.
If you find that necessary to make sure that the eye has the pupil and the iris in the right proportions.
So pause a video now and give that again.
Okay guys.
Welcome back.
Let's hop over into blender and assign the iris and pupil materials.
Right.
So the first thing I'm going to do and you can do this in any particular order that you want so I'm
going to create the two new materials first.
Or at least the slots for them.
And I'm going to click here and pick up.
I bought.
And then I'm going to click the number two here to make it a single user copy.
And I'm going to call that Iris.
I want to do the same to this one underneath.
I'm going to click here select eyeball.
Make it a single user copy by clicking the number and naming that one pupil.
Now depending on which one we're on.
We obviously are going to be changing the materials.
If we had not made them unique when we change one material it will change the original eyeball mature
and we don't want that to happen.
So with the pupils selected I'm going to go down here to diffuse and change that to black and just going
to have my pupil completely black on both of these that the colour of them blacked out for the time
being I'm going to make my iris probably an orange brown colour to match the iris we were making earlier.
But that would just be for reference because shortly the colour itself would be overridden by a texture.
But that's in an upcoming lecture.
So finally we need to assign these new material some of them.
Squeeze this one down a little or if I pick up the right thing.
Let's pull this down.
Skip bring the head of barback with this little Plus down here and change this to solid Hopkins edit
mode and let's just have a look from about here.
So these select everything I'm going to you circle select because it's going to be the easiest thing
and of course I can make this circle bigger and smaller and I'm going to select everything here.
And assign once the select there in a sign that that's of course you won't be able to see these assigned
materials into urine material view.
So I'm going to leave it like that for the moment.
Now finally the actual pupil itself now rabit pupils are quite large.
So let's go ahead here and again.
These select everything circle selects bout that much I think.
Ang Let's go to pupil and a sign.
Excellent.
With that in mind I'm probably going to make the iris slightly bigger as well so I'm going to use a
loop select here.
So we got face in a select loop around there go to Iris and sign.
So we've got all of our materials now assigned to our model.
Of course we can very quickly check that and see how this is looking.
So let's go ahead and render the image.
I believe I've got it all set up to render correctly.
So what have we got here.
There we go.
So we've got our bunny.
It's looking good.
Excellent.
How did you guys get on.
Please share your eyeball in the discussions.
And see you in the next lecture.