Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to have a look at our model and go around it and just double check that
we've got things without transforms applied to them transforms are incredibly useful because they allow
you to scale rotate to model things very quickly.
However when you're animating what you don't want is some funky stuff happening which is unintended
in the way we can do that is to make sure that transforms certainly the scale and rotation of our models
especially our mesh objects are applied.
OK so let's go ahead here and have a look.
Our models are going to turn back on overlays.
Now the way of quickly doing this is to click around your model and just see what's happening.
And we can already see if we have a look if this if this panel isn't open this is the one you need open
or indeed you could use this one over here as well in the properties panel it's entirely up to you.
It's the same information on the Object data.
If we press the end key we can bring that open and it's under the item tab we've got location rotation
and scale.
These are the three possible transforms that you can apply to your models.
And it's incredibly useful because it enables you to as I was alluding to earlier be able to rapidly
model any parts of your mesh.
The problem is that things don't always act as you would expect them to.
It transforms aren't supplied.
We already saw earlier.
That's because there was a transform applied to this lower arm.
The moment we printed it to something else it had an offset immediately happen.
And that can cause issues.
So what I'd recommend is going round your model.
And in this case I've got my stems selected and we've got a scale of nought point eight eight five.
So we can go control in a.
Or go to the objects menu and apply and then we've got a couple of options we've got location rotation
and scale or we can do a rotation and scale together.
Now typically those are ones that you do need to do together all transforms though can result in your
model falling apart.
So it may sound like a good idea to do transforms but that's not gonna be a great idea.
For instance at the top here what it would do is it would take the origin point its location and move
that lower arm down to the center of our scene.
Well speaking of which I picked up a move that bottom bit so we can go here straight away.
I'm going to highlight all of that and put it smack bang in the center of our scene again.
Otherwise it's just going to confuse me when I look at it later.
Now that I've done that I'm going to go ahead select this stem see it's got a scale applied but nothing
else.
And then when we go and have a look at our transform information for our lower arm we don't have any
rotation applied to it that's fine.
But we do have location and scale.
Now if we were to go ahead and apply all transforms it looks no different.
You think a ha.
Brilliant but what it has done is it's move the origin all the way down here to the center of our scene.
That might not be desirable.
Origins are very useful for manipulating your models and of course if you export your models they are
often used as pivot points.
So you probably don't want to apply any locations.
However this one's got a horrible scale of points one applied to it which means we are going to have
problems.
If we were to add particle systems submissive we would seize the physics engine and we might even end
up with something quirky happening with animation which is what we're covering here.
So let's go ahead.
Go control a and apply the scale.
And there we go.
That's all sorted.
We're not going to apply location and there's no rotation to adhere to either.
So there we go.
I apologize for mentioning this repeatedly throughout the course but you'll be surprised how many times
that it's forgotten and it causes so many issues so many questions come up.
And often it's a case of.
Well have you applied your transforms.
That's almost the right answer.
90 percent of the time.
So of course I've got a challenge for you okay.
So here we go.
Nice and straightforward.
I'd like you to check your model over for anything without the scale and rotation applied.
Remember it's not just the mesh objects that you need to look at.
Do have a look at your armature as well because that can also have transforms applied to it pulls the
video now and give that a go Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead hop on over into blender and just check for all transforms are all applied okay.
We've done the lower on that's fine.
I'm going to select my armature because I don't want to miss that.
That's got everything absolutely fine.
Let's have a look at the empty.
That's fine as well the base.
Well it's also got a scale so going to go Alton a.
Apply the scale.
This has also got scales.
Alton I apply the scale.
Perfect.
Okay.
I don't think there's anything else that's important but I'm just going to zoom out to the wider scene
and see what we've got going here.
So we've got this backdrop here I don't think we would involve in the animation at all.
However just to be complete I think we should check everything.
Yep that's absolutely fine.
Okay.
So this platform or bench here.
Yes it does have a scale.
Let's go ahead and apply that scale save our work.
I'm liking how this is coming along.
There are a couple of other things if we just click through they will be selected because they're on
top of each other.
As I click through them I did see one point eighty five again.
So let's go ahead apply that scale we got something here.
No I think we're done.
I think we've gone through everything.
Of course there is a hierarchy here in the outline that we can quickly click through as well if we want
it.
So of course we're dealing with primarily mesh objects here and the armature itself.
And we can see here because the armature has the bones in and we're starting to parent things to those
bones.
That is why we now have our mesh objects being nested underneath the armature because the mesh objects
are now a child of the armature.
Excellent.
Now did you have many things to go through and clean up.
I'm just going to tidy up my scene here.
I think that looks pretty good.
I'm also going to move my camera for the moment into a better position.
So if we do decide to render anything soon Yeah I can see what's going on.
Perfect.
How did you guys get on.
Did you have many things that you hadn't applied the transform for so please do share your work over
in the discussion also let us know if you're having any issues at this point in time.
It's at this key stage that things can fly apart.
So this is why we're going through and doing things bits by bits rather than making a model adding an
armature to it and it just fly apart and be very difficult to solve iterating through your model building
it up piece by piece is going to make a big difference to that.
So go ahead show your work over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.