Hello everybody and welcome to this lecture where we are going to have a closer look at the roughness
property of the principal shader so you can start adding things like minor reflections you can see the
underside of this pawn here is lit even though it's facing down.
And of course we've got the reflections but only on the black squares.
Let's find out more okay.
So we will start with a simple scene here.
I'm going to lift my cube up slightly sits above the plane and then add in a plane and scale it up to
around 10.
We're going to add a color to the plane straightaway so let's go to our materials settings and add in
a new material.
And I'm going to make this a dark color.
The reason why I'm going to make it a dark color is because reflections show up much better on darker
colors.
So let's work with that.
I'm going to change my viewports here to shaded mode straight away.
And you'll notice that there are no reflections at all.
There's a shadow but there's no reflection.
And if we scroll down a little we get to the area called roughness and we can control that we can lower
it down and we can turn it up again.
However when we lower it down to zero which is 100 percent smooth it's not rough at all.
It means that this surface itself is pretty much a mirror.
Yet we don't see the cube in it at all, interestingly we do see the lights in it and that can be a
problem whilst we can see the lights I just want to show you.
We select the light itself and go to the lamp properties and the adjust the radius.
You will notice that it will get smaller and larger and you can hide it pretty much not completely but
almost completely by setting the radius down to zero.
That will affect the lighting in your scene as well we can see it here as I change the radius as it
gets larger it can dim out.
And that's because it's larger with the same power.
Anyway I'm going to say that down to nought point nought one.
And there we go.
That's pretty much as hidden as it can be.
In fact you can set it to zero.
So that gets that big circle out the way.
But why can we not see any reflections.
Well if we are in cycles we would see reflections.
But with eevee you need to turn them on.
So this is something I'm going to repeat myself lots with as we play with eevee you need to remember
to turn things on.
If we switch over to cycles real quick the cube is there.
We don't need to worry about reflections we don't need to worry about shadow quality but with eevee we
do.
So let's go down to our screen space reflections a tick in the box and immediately you see there is
something there.
Huh.
There's our cube.
Now we open up the dropdown for screen space reflections we've got a load of other options.
We're not going to delve into masses of details here refraction is to do with whether something is transparent
and its half see through does it refract the light going through.
You've probably seen that example with a straw going into a glass of water some something it seems like
the straw is at a different angle now half res trace is to speed up rendering if we uncheck that you'll
notice that the reflection itself gets a lot sharper and you'll also notice here as we've come in look
the reflection seems to come and disappear based upon the angle that we're at.
So do bear that in mind whenever you're setting up your scenes you may need to change some of these
other settings to try and get to say is fading off there.
Well we've got edge fading hints that bringing it back.
Well, No, it kind of just makes that bit there really sharp.
So there is a certain angle at which screen space reflections just do not work.
If we switch this over to the cycles rendering engine that wouldn't be an issue at all Let's go back
into the eevee rendering engine.
So that's something to watch out for whenever you're playing with that if you want reflections in your
scene turn on screen space reflections.
I'm going to leave my settings at default here and let's go ahead back to our material itself and
play finally with the options so that scroll down to our materials and we've got this roughness slider.
Now if you set the roughness to 100 percent as I've done here a value of 1 that means that the surface
is very very very very rough is going to reflect the light in a way that scatters it everywhere rather
than reflecting it back at the camera or the viewer and you can see as you bring this back down and
you decrease the roughness i.e. making it smoother around point three is where you start getting a shape
coming back and then we get 100 percent reflection at 0, 0 is very much like a mirrored surface usually
most materials have a little bit of roughness in even if they are highly reflective and it's it's up
to you to play with that and see what you get out.
Now later on in the course we'll be using different textures and different ways of controlling this
roughness value but for the moment we can just control it in the materials property window on the right
here.
Now you may be familiar with the term specular Now we're not using that type of workflow.
So in general we're going to leave the specular at nought point five sometimes specular can mean
the amounts of light reflecting from a surface it's specularity  but in this case we can control
that using the roughness and the roughness only.
Okay.
Armed with that knowledge it's time for your challenge, Okay.
So your challenge is to change the black square materials properties so that they will reflect the pieces
within them make them mirror like and then feel free to experiment with the pieces and perhaps even
the white squares as well.
Do have fun, pause the video now and give that a go.
Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go hop into blender and make those black squares reflective Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and open up our chess scene I'm going to switch straight into rendered mode as we are.
And let's have a look at our scene.
So we've got a lovely sunset appearance on here in a blue over here.
The first thing I'm going to do is go ahead and select my chessboard go down to the material properties
black squares and I'm going to make the black squares completely reflective initially.
Later on of course we can play with that.
Okay.
So black squares are reflective and we can see straightaway this light over here is being reflected.
So I'm gonna grab that light and turn the radius down to zero and whilst I'm doing it I'm going to do
that to the blue one as well.
It changes the lighting ever so slightly and of course you can still see a little bit of reflection
there but otherwise I'm happy with that result.
Now we don't see any reflections yet.
So let's go ahead to our render properties go down the screen space reflections, I'm going to keep the default
settings apart from the half res trace I'm going to turn off just so i get a higher quality view let's have
a look at that, nice so we can see are different objects being reflected of course if we go to shallow
we won't see all of those reflections at certain angles but I think that's starting to come together
really well and I like the difference I'm going to play for a moment with the white squares as well.
And remember you can set the objects themselves to be reflective in fact with these faceted items.
This may be quite fun.
I'm going to set the black pieces as well to be highly reflective.
This may completely fall flat on its face but I want to give it a go.
So the  black pieces.
Excellent roughness okay.
So we should be able to see other pieces in the reflections of those so they look like a highly polished
dark material, Of course you could add color to them.
I don't like them like that.
I'm going to set the roughness a little bit higher.
There we go.
To set them to point three.
Now the white pieces in the white squares.
I'm going to leave those as they are for the moment.
Okay.
There we go.
How are your boards looking.
Are they coming together really nicely.
I think we're going to end up using this board rather than going back to the original one and playing
around with that and for that we're gonna need to get rid of all of these other pieces to work on it
and we'll find out more about that in the next lecture.