Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture I'd like you to go ahead and create your remaining building blocks your modular building
blocks.
So create some extra ones if you have what you thinks are complete sets.
Perhaps there are a few other things you'd like to include bring them from across from your nice to
hams into your will have in your scene.
Now obviously there are other models as well that we'll get to making later on in the section.
But for the moment we just need to finalize.
For me it's going to be a corner piece and I'd totally forgotten to think about the roof.
Now I'm going to have two roof pieces I'm going to have a large one to go over the main area and then
smaller ones on the side.
Although thinking about I can probably only use the word get away with.
But I think I can get away with essentially our wool piece cuts from one corner to the other meaning
that it's just a right angle triangle I should be able to use that as a basis for the roof.
But we'll see how we go as I start stacking things together.
Okay so one final thing you'll hear me say there's lots.
But keep it simple at the moment.
You want some basic building blocks to flesh out your design.
Suppose a video now and give that a go
Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead hop on over into blender and finish off our extra modular pieces okay.
So I've gone ahead and I've opened up my standard church scene and I'm going to go from my building
scene here into my export scene so everything's together.
And so I can start putting a few of these pieces together and trying to work out what size corner piece.
Now I could make this really really straightforward and have it be a four by four piece and then I know
that my door and everything else will fit together really nicely.
I'm going to take that approach.
I think it will be fine.
We're going to start with the wall in order to do this and then work from there.
So I'm going to select everything in my scene and press H.
Now bear in mind if you do do what I've just done.
When you go ahead and look at things through a rendered perspective there is no light in the scene anymore
so it's not all really work.
Of course the camera is also hidden even though we can see through it still if we need to.
Okay.
So find the wool piece for me.
I'm going to duplicate that.
I'm going to call it corner.
Okay.
So this is the corner piece a couple of ways that I could approach this I'm going to go into edit mode
and duplicate my mesh again and I'm just having a look at how it's positioned in our world because ultimately
all of our pieces line up externally.
So let's make sure we can still do that with a duplicated let's move it.
So g x four minus four.
There we go.
Ah Z one eighty they're not.
1 1890.
Of course that's placed it somewhere completely random for me but I should now be able to bring it across
the right location.
Okay so the last thing we've got here is just to merge all of this together.
Now there are a couple of ways that we can do this.
The first thing I'm going to do is to select all and I'm going to search for merge and then select merge
by distance and that will have removed these two double vertices here and here.
So that's very useful it's just this last bit here too and there are a couple of ways that I could do
this.
I'm going to change snapping snapping he says snapping to the vertex select and I can go e to pull it
out and reluctance to snap it to a vertex they're now going to select everything.
And once again it will remember my selection when I press EF 3 remove two extra vertices.
But if we go into wireframe mode we'll see we've got an internal face just here which is no good.
Let's go ahead and delete.
That's only the face if we delete the vertices.
It will look rubbish.
Okay values good as a war piece.
Let's turn back on solid shade.
Yeah I'm happy with that as a basic wall piece and it should fit together really well with everything
else Okay so let's go ahead and hide that corner piece.
Excellent.
And then the wall I want to grab that again duplicate.
I'm not going to use this as the basis for my roof piece.
So I'm going to call this roof as you can probably guess 45 degrees.
I think that's the slope of the roof.
I'm going to end up creating.
OK.
So we need to decide on the size again I'm going to stick to my four by four grid.
And this part here I'm just going to delete these two vertices here or essentially that edge.
By doing that I can then reconstruct what I want to make and we can base everything else off of that
slope just there in fact.
OK.
So we want everything to be on the positive side here.
So I'm going to grab this as it's here set.
That's a four on the y axis for here.
And then finally for the top 0 it means that for although it was already out for there.
Okay.
So that's the rough shape that I want but I don't want the roof to be flat whilst I'm in there.
So it's a matter I think of getting rid of these two faces
that's pretty good.
And going ahead and just hopefully producing the right side so let's look at this from the right angle
that we need.
I'm going to go e to extrude the edge Z points to that's gone up which is fine I want to do the same
with this edge so e that point so I'm going to join those two together and then all being well I should
be able to do these as well.
Excellent.
I'm going to grab this lower edge here and I am going to extrude that not by much I point for recap
so that should match up and butts up against anything I need to rule 45 degrees.
Okay.
I think that's good.
Let's go back into our building see and start thinking about bringing those pieces in and essentially
where they are going to be appearing.
I can see actually a couple of potential issues so I need to put in my my corner pieces and work out
where there's going to be so where would the roof piece go here.
Is there going to be a piece going in the end as well.
So it's gonna be an extra piece needed if I'm not careful but the rest of this I think we can sort out
with our corner pieces.
So let's go back to our export scene go and grab our corner piece and our roof.
I'm simply going to copy those and bring them straight into the building scene making sure in object
mode I can paste those two pieces in.
Okay.
I'm concerned that one of them is just cold war but no it's not.
We've got our roof.
Let's go ahead and just have a look.
Okay so that's not going to work in our particular case.
Look at that slight issue.
But is supposed to be the other way around.
But regardless that's going to cause us a few issues.
So we definitely need to think about how this is going to be put together.
Anyway we've got a couple of corner pieces to be put in as well.
I'm I'm tempted here to go ahead and shift this out of the way grab all the slots and just move it up
and out of the way for the moment let's focus on the front door Let's rotate this round on the z axis
by 90.
Looks good.
Let's move it to the right location.
This is Oh I thought I had solved that perhaps I didn't.
Let's go in and sort that out.
So where should be over here by the looks of things.
Go ahead select the appropriate vertex shift an S cursor to select to come out right click set origin
to the 3d cursor.
Okay so now we can fix that up what we think actually it's here we want but one massive shift that's
just selected.
Easy to miss that comes through.
Okay.
Which happens to be zero so we've got this bit here.
Let's go ahead and duplicate that along the x axis to here and then rotate it on the Z by 180.
Now not 180 is just 90 again.
Okay perfect.
So our building is going to take on a slightly different look now but we can see that we can actually
slot these pieces together.
We are lacking a few fundamentals here.
I completely forgot.
And it was just very fortunate that these numbers worked out but completely forgotten that lines up
here.
We of course have this overhang just here.
And of course this front piece we don't have a 45 degree front piece here either.
So there's a few things we all need to sort out but they can certainly wait for a bit.
Now I'm just going to as normal go through and reconstruct a building based upon this of course is going
to take me a few moments to do
okay everybody.
So I've patched together this so far and I've come across a few extra parts that I am going to need
I'm going to need some sort of filler parts if I want to keep this current style.
We've got the issue that the roof pieces themselves when it comes to an end piece.
We may need to have a special end piece because the wall comes out and of course the roof doesn't.
We've got a problem with the.
Not there not being a smaller roof piece.
So we can't bring this together at the top.
I think leaving like this is fine for the moment.
We don't have an end window.
Not a big issue I've just stretched one for the moment and I think it's just a smaller corner piece
as well that we also need if we have a look at here I don't mind the styling that's absolutely fine
it adds a bit of interest to the building but obviously we're just making do with the pieces we've got
at the moment.
So when we go into first person mode speed up my movement turn on gravity and have a look.
Excellent.
I'm liking this.
It looks like a much better building.
The horrible Z fighting.
OK.
Let's also hop into rendered mode and just see how that is looking.
Z key rendered.
Wait for a few minutes to just refresh.
Now of course this is going to obviously take a while to get some information in there the lighting
information.
I think that's looking pretty good.
I think this could be a lot bigger.
Again it's a temporary piece.
Anyway what does it look like in eevee.
Probably a bit rubbish at the moment.
Yeah that looks very rubbish for the moment anyway.
It's definitely working better in cycles for me with the lights.
But we can talk about lighting and things like that later on when we make the scene look a bit better
in blender.
I remember things like lighting there actually handled by the game engine itself the things that we're
doing in blender with our lighting.
Well it will she transfer into any game engine.
It's really to give us a feel of how the buildings coming together how lights might interact within
the building as well.
Anyway I'm liking how miners coming together.
I'm probably going to have to make a few extra pieces but I don't want to commit to those just yet because
I certainly have a few extra things to put in our scene like the pillars etc. So the overall layout
may change again but I'm liking how it's now coming together really looking forward to seeing what you've
done with your buildings.
Did you have similar issues to me as you start building up your pieces and again.
Oh no I needed a few more I might need an end piece or a corner an extra corner piece.
It's amazing how all of these suddenly starts appearing as you puts more detail into your model.
That's it for this lecture and I'll see you all over in the next one.