Welcome to using source control resetting in this video you will go over how to extract a previous version
of your files and become aware that blend files are made up of linked files need to be accessed and
restored in a slightly different way.
So first of all let's have a look at source tree.
Okay so in front of us I have some uncommitted changes.
Now I have some unstaged files down here now this might look slightly different to how it looked before
and that's because I've gone for a flat layout.
So on the top of this particular section there is a little button that if you click you can change the
view type.
So I did have it on treeview like this but I was getting fed up of having to open these folders up in
the hierarchy to see what was going on.
So I've changed it to a flat list single column is absolutely fine.
Tells me exactly what's going on and where things are.
Although I can break it out so the path is separate to the others.
So I've got I've changed the scene.
The Gothic church I have a note that is a test for this lecture.
This particular lecture that so that's been added to the working directory that we were in at the moment.
I've got a couple of tests some in Dune stained glass windows few guys and a glass test blend file.
I've been working on.
Now if I want to go back in time I have to go to the next layer up and I've got all of my commit history
going here.
Going back and back and back in time.
Now if I want to pick up a file from with in any of these historical events see this as a time line.
If I want to go back in time to that say Here we go.
G A P E 16 linking blend files I created a version of the Gothic church at that particular point.
If I go and right click on that I can open the selected version and that will open up that particular
file and we get a big long error message.
Now this is because it contains linked items.
If this was a non linked item so let's say the doorway or the archway the the items which were linking
then we wouldn't have this error message but because we got linked items it causes us a problem so we
just have a look at the blend file.
Once the error message is gone we can see that pretty much everything has gone.
Every bit of linked information and it's been replaced with empties.
So you'd have a couple of choices at this point.
You could relink formal by reimporting them into the scene and then replacing the appropriate empty
with the right mesh and that would be a real pain if the scene well even with this relatively straightforward
scene would be a real pain to do so we don't want to do that so what we need to do instead would linked
files is actually go back in time completely and we can do that by the following notice at the top here
the name is complete gobbledygook this is assets seeing Gothic church before and then a serial number
that's coming from the database that everything stored in.
But because this is existing within that database and not within the actual file structure itself the
current file structure it doesn't know where anything else is.
And this is perhaps where absolute links to our files would work better than relative links.
But that aside what we need to do now is basically close that down because that's of no use to us.
What we can do however is right click on there and check out this.
This basically this part in history when we do that it gives us a warning.
We can go ahead and click okay now.
My file structure is exactly how it was when this comet was made.
So if I go ahead and I can double click these as well.
If I go ahead and open that up we can see that it works.
Now that is pretty cool.
At this point I can go in straightaway and go file save as and call it.
I don't know it depends on what you're calling it recovered.
Say I'd made some major mistake during my model or added a load of nonsense to it and I didn't want
to go ahead and delete things and like when I could just go back to a previous happy state.
My model so recovered gough Gothic church and a save that blend file.
Now what I can do is go back to the source tree and go forward in time and go all the way back up here.
So then I go to the last comet and check out that comet that pushes everything back to how it was before
we went back in time to check everything else and when we go to are uncommitted changes if I just make
this area a little bigger we will see that now.
Waiting there for us is the recovered Gothic church blend.
Now will we make our new comet.
It will save that and we would have got back any potential date that we had lost or a model that we
now want to take.
Perhaps in a new direction.
That is brilliant.
Now I would like you to give this a go.
In a very small challenge.
I would like you to go back in time yourselves and restore a previous version of your interior scene.
Balls of the air now and give that ago.
Okay guys.
Welcome back.
Let's do that process again and I'll show you a couple of other nuances as we go.
So we're back in the file structure itself down here.
And I want to go back now.
At this point in time I can see here that I made a commit that can change that contained the Gothic
church.
So if I want to go back before just one step before that I never committed I never made any change to
the Gothic church so I can be a little confusing sometimes if I want to go back just one stage in that
scene.
I'd actually have to find when I change that.
It wouldn't necessarily be there.
What just going one back.
So I'd go back here and go.
No it's not in there.
This is where the flats lay out really helps you know diving in and out of folder structures.
So no it's not though I'm just looking for Gothic church blend.
And as we go down here this is looking a bit bigger.
And there we go.
So I didn't change the actual scene itself didn't save that scene change anything in its way back here
in gaap 20.
So at that point I could go back and check out that area click okay here the folder changes I can double
click and open up Gothic church.
It should work when it opens up.
I might need to tap into it.
There we go.
Just going to close that down and try double clicking that again.
So that is how it was before I started adding all of the portals the light portals in in the previous
lecture.
And I might actually want to go back to this state if I don't want all of those portals in because it
turned out that at the moment I've got enough light coming in that the portals are having very little
effect other than slowing my scene down.
So at this point I'm going to go file save as an unknown and go Gothic church before portals and then
of course I can fork that and go off in a different direction with it so let's save that as the blend
file.
Now remember at this point I'm going to have to go back to the committee that I made or the most recent
committee in this case and I should have in uncommitted changes a list of items.
And here we go rigi off recovered gough at church someone done and got it shown.
There he is back in camp and Gothic church before the portal.
Well before light portal's I could have been a bit more descriptive.
So then I can go and stage all of my file so I don't lose any of the recovery that I've just done.
And of course I'm going to call this one appropriately.
And there we go I'm going to make my commit.
And everything's done okay.
Brilliant.
I hope you guys restored a previous version of your interior scene and I will see you guys in the next
lecture.