Okay so this lecture we're jumping straight into a challenge.
It's the end of section challenge.
I'd like you to give a bit of thought to it and make it your own.
So I'd like you to go ahead and finish your mayan pyramid.
What do I mean by finish.
Well add some materials, add some lighting, add that camera to the right position.
So you're ready to render it's out add some additional features or objects to your scene as well that's
another thing you can do.
But most importantly play have fun and share your creations as you've gone.
So go ahead pause the video now and create your final Mayan pyramid
Okay
everybody welcome back.
Let's hop on over into blender and I will go and create my final mayan pyramid.
Okay so this is where we left off before.
Let's go ahead and make sure we save our work.
I'm going to save mine as 21 so we're ready to go.
So looking at it at the moment it's pretty plain and boring whether we're looking at it in lookdev
mode or even shaded mode and in fact in shaded mode looks kind of dramatic with the lights lower down
like that but that's not giving me the look for I want.
So a couple of things that this Mayan pyramid exists in nowhere at the moment.
So let's go ahead and I'm going to add myself in a ground plane and I'm just going to scale that up.
So there's something that this thing is set on I want to call its ground straightaway get naming in
there and I'm going to add a material to it straightaway as well whilst I'm here and I'm just going
to call that material ground okay.
I want to make it a green I'm going to make it a little darker and I'm going to leave it like that for
the moment.
The next thing I want to play with is my lights.
I'm gonna go for a three point lighting setup.
We have our rough camera angle here.
I think I want to help sort out the camera first so let's see what the camera can see.
Not a lot at the moment looks like we're zoomed in quite a bit.
Now I'm gonna go to view navigation and go down to walk navigation.
This will enable me to look around.
Ah yes I could get a really dramatic shot there but I'm not gonna go for that at the moment.
Let's just back up a little I want the whole pyramid like that so I can show it off to everyone.
So that's what the camera's going to see.
Looking at all scene from above.
Make sure your cursors over this the 3D editor when you try and do something like that I'm going to grab
our first light and when it's selected I'm going to press G and just move it somewhere else.
Now at the moment it looks like snapping still turned on something to turn it off and move it around.
Now the question is is that still at the right height.
Yes it is.
Okay.
So we got our camera which is all the way over here actually.
So I want a light around here.
I want a light back here and a light over there.
Now in this case I'm going to have the filling lights perhaps over here and a little bit brighter.
I'm going to pump the energy up to 30 because we're dealing with quite a large scene here that looks
pretty good and what I want is that even bit of lighting I do want shadows there but I don't want them
to be too overpowering as well.
I can lift lights up and down if I feel like this too you know too many shadows coming down from underneath
I can lift that up and light those surfaces.
And I think that's a good overall luminance lighting for our scene.
Now we have here a kind of a bland rocky type color I'm going to go in I'm going to rename the material
itself pyramid and once I've done that I'm going to change the base color to more of a sandy color.
It's going to make it stand out just that little bit better.
Okay so that's looking pretty good.
There's a couple of other things that I want to do here and that's have a lamp right smack bang in the
middle.
At the top here, as if something's coming out from inside.
So I need to move either a lamp to that position or if you remember using the 3D cursor so I'm going
to use the 3D cursor tool and I'm going to place it there.
Now we can also shift and right click to place the 3D cursor if we want.
So as well as using the 3D cursor option over on the tool shelf I'm going to add in another lamp so
a fresh lamp.
And I'm going to change it to a deep orange color.
Not going to adjust the end.
Yeah  i will wi'll knock that down to five for the moment.
Let's come out and look from the camera's view of what we've got that is looking pretty awesome.
Now the one thing you may notice at this point is that we've got lights bleed coming through our scene
so I'm going to press G and then X and move that slightly out.
So that's not happening anymore.
And that's always something to watch out for because if you put a light inside an object you may get
issues like it coming through like that.
Okay.
That is looking pretty good at the moment.
I'm happy with that.
How did you guys get on looking forward to seeing your work over in the discussions.
Please now render out your models by going to render render image.
Go head to image save as save that on your hard drive and then you're ready for sharing your work looking
forward to seeing it.
And I'll see you all in the next lecture.