Hello and welcome to this bonus lecture in the bowling section.
In this lecture, we're going to be animating our bowling scene using physics and the animation timeline
to produce a result much like this one.
Boom.
And with that in mind, let's get started.
Welcome back.
When I collect this pen and focus on it with the number pad zero.
So we've got a tumble round point case where all of these other pens are completely out of place and
no good for what we want.
We're going to select Paul, who's been using left click and shift a press, delete key and remove all
of those pens.
So we're gonna do a ball at the moment because it's in the way here.
So I'm just going to let the ball.
And the first thing I want to do is set origin to 3D caster.
Now select.
Geometry to origin.
There we go.
Back up a little bit, so.
We're not in the floor there.
Maybe go Doudou and move along the G.
Why access to get out of the way for now?
Well, some first thing we're going to do as well with a pen is something very similar.
If I can just select the pen.
Never go set.
Origins of the 3D cursor and then set origin.
To geometry, to origin.
And we've got to set that up a little bit.
There we go.
And if we go to three on the side view with an iPad, we can pull this up a little bit.
On notices when Mikey's made the pins, then look quite flat on the bottom.
So we have to go into edit mode using the tap.
Okay.
Press the number one key on the number line to change the vertex select and a pair.
I'm going to go into X-ray mode and change the viewport shading to wireframe the zoom in a little bit
and send to my day.
There we go.
I'm just going to box select from here.
This line here downward.
There we go.
Now press the X key and delete the vertices.
And because we had the x ray in transparent node on, we were able to select vertices all the way through
the model.
This pointing a press olt unless kleck to select that edge loop.
Press F to fill the face.
And just because it looks a little out there, I'm gonna scale it ever so slightly.
There we go.
I'm gonna go back into object mode and go g and sex and the origin point comes with us.
Maybe just a bit more to get that closer to that line, which is actually our plane.
And you can hold shift down to make it smaller increments to make it a bit more easy to place.
Excellent.
Let's go back into solid mode and we can turn off the x ray mode to get our pin and then we have a single
pin.
Brilliant.
That's right, click.
Put the origins, the center mass volume, just to make sure everything's working okay.
And that's our PIN, almost set up, ready to go for the moment.
I want to take a look at the bowling ball and our alley because we need to get our bowling ball down
to appends.
So.
So that bowling ball.
Gee, why move it back bit further as well?
Now, I'm going to pull this line up here and expose the timeline for you.
We haven't encountered the timeline and will account for it again in the animated lamp section after
the next chess section.
But I wanted to introduce it here to show the timeline and what we can do with it, with some with the
bow selected.
We're gonna select the physics properties here, which is just under the particle properties and two
down from the modifiers which you will remember from previous sections.
So let's click on this and add a rigid body.
And if you done game engine work, you'll know what a rigid body is.
It's an object that's directly controlled by simulation.
So let's add one.
Now, we wanted to be active because we wanted to move.
So we wanted to be controlled by the simulation results.
And one kilogram is pretty light for a ball.
So let's give it 10 kilograms.
Let's just play it, see what happens.
Odia.
The ball fell straight through the floor.
And the reason being is Brender has no idea of the moment that the plane is supposed to interact with
the ball.
So that's other ruddy rigid body.
And instead of being active because we don't want it to move, we want wanted to be passive so that
we'll just sit there and interact with the physical objects in the world.
It will naturally move, repress, play.
Now you find the ball just kind of rolls off the plane, but it doesn't feel free because it's interacting
with the physics body, physics, rigid body, sorry, on the plane, which is our coming out bowling
alley.
So let's go back to our first keyframe here.
On one hand selectable again.
And what we want is to give up all some momentum, so that actually moves down those high down the bowling
alley.
So let's click the animated button.
This allows us to control the ball by the animation system.
And what we want to do here is we want to, first of all, press.
And this will insert a key frame to our timeline.
What we do is we can set a key frame for location, rotation and scale and pull that up a bit just a
bit further.
And you can see this four points here on the timeline and that designates that at this point.
This ball is here.
What we're gonna do is we're also going to hover over the animated checkbox to make sure it's on press
eye.
This tells the timeline because we're using the animation timeline system now that at this point we
want the ball to follow the animation system and not the physics system.
So we're going to move this timeline forward now to about frame 10.
I can do this by dragging there or I can clicking here and change this to whichever frame I want.
And at this frame, I'm going to key.
Why why move the ball forward to probably about here to get some really good momentum and we're going
to I keyframe location, rotation and scale.
And then we're going to turn off the animated checkbox and keyframe it there.
Now last week, because it's gone back to the beginning.
But if we go back, it will run the animation and we will get everything we expect.
So let's just play both.
There goes the ball.
But what happens at the other end?
It's got back to the beginning of the animation and you'll notice when I chase the pen down here.
If I can selective about selecting the camera, the time line is gone.
This is because each object has its own timeline.
So when we press play, what happens?
Wow.
Ball comes down.
It disappears straight past the pin boom gone.
That's because, again, we have no roof physics, rigid body on our pin.
So let's add one.
We can't keep active.
And what we want to do now is watch the pendants.
We press play.
We are going to animate it or anything.
We're just going to give it some physics.
Both call.
That happened quite quickly.
So a pin hit it.
But normally what you would see is a better jittering here and it's probably going to be better to see
it when we've got more pins on the board.
But for now, what we want to do is checkbox the animated box, animated box again and press IJA keyframe
it, because we're going to have this only be animated.
At the beginning, so it doesn't move.
It just stays there.
And then when the ball comes in, we're going to run the timeline forward.
And here comes the ball.
And just at the point, just for his.
I think it's about 17.
I turn off the animated system and press eye to keyframe that it's off.
And then the physics system will take over for the pin.
So let's get back to the beginning again by hitting one.
Well, by hitting that button and then press play and boom, it knocks the pin flying.
So now we can set up our scene and what we can do is go through the top to you, the number Pad seven
K.
A reminder, we're looking down a bowling alley.
So we want to I'm going to place these rather roughly to shift day to duplicate place that roughly about
their shift day and on the X-axis.
Bring that over a little bit.
Now, these are probably too close, but you can measure the dimensions like we did in the previous
lectures.
I'm just doing this to show you quickly and control easy and undo that because he has managed to select
the.
Bowling alley, as well as the pennant deeper case, a shift day, that's better.
We've only got the bowling pins now.
It's going to grab that middle one and shift.
They move it across again.
Again, this is very rough and ready just to show you that his existence 50 over there and you'll notice
we've caught that plane again, bane of my existence, catching the plane when I'm clicking.
What's actually happening is it's copying the animation data over.
So anything that has been on this first pin will be duplicated and all of the pins will react the same
at the same point in time.
So let's get that one done.
Click this.
And I think that's tenpin.
Yep.
That's 10 p.m. and we don't need another line.
So let's just get that in position roughly where we want it.
Brilliant.
Let's tumble around.
And that we're all set up, so let's press play and see what happens.
Boom.
We have a strike.
Brilliant.
You noticed the pins are just rolling around and we really don't need an animation this long.
So let's have a look.
Most of the animation is done by about a hundred frames.
What we do also want to do.
Is to good times of frames, because everything seems to be about finished their.
Again, if you are in trouble in title number in here, or you can use the arrows to change that.
And also we want to change the end of the animation to be a 100, which will become important later
when we render to make sure that we are actually only rendering frames one to one hundred.
And so that's all set up.
OK.
So with that done, what we wanted to do now is we want to check our render settings to Pagode to here
and our output properties.
You'll notice I've deliberately left the frame right at 24 seconds, 24 frames, four seconds.
We press play.
I'll say now animation plays.
But what happens if we change it to the 30 frames per second?
Pressplay.
It does speed up higher animation a little for this purpose.
It really doesn't matter.
But for most animations, you'd want this to be 30 frames per second.
Now, if you need to adjust it, you can remap the timing so you can adjust it so that it's a it's a
bit better with the speed.
But we won't go into that in this lecture.
Maybe we'll cover that in a later lecture.
So how do we run out?
Well, if we scroll down from our render options here.
We can say that we have an output folder now currently is set to the tent folder.
I really want the tent folder.
Let's go put it in documents for a minute.
We just put it in documents there, except now what I recommend you do is you can go and use the compositor
and render out two images and you can go into the compositor up here and then put it into a timeline.
We're not going to do that with the modern technologies we have today.
Mostly, you're not going to crash doing a video.
So we don't change this Panji down to a FSR MPEG video.
And it's as it's the most common one everybody has.
We're going to leave this alone as a MKC file.
I did try earlier to do other versions, but it didn't work for me.
I think it's possibly because it's a driver's issue.
So when we're encoding, we want to encode a video in.
It'll go straight out to this soda.
And all we simply do is we've checked our Framestore is one frame and is one hundred, which matches
our animation and the frame rate is 30 frames per second.
And what we do is we go to the rendering tab just so we're in the rendering tab.
We go render and we want to render the animation like that.
And that will start to render your animation out to a video frame by frame.
Now, I'm going to leave this to play for a moment and I'll pop back when it's done.
Okay, so welcome back.
The animation has finished running just pop open blender here so you can actually see that.
There we go.
I've got it set to a different frame as I was checking something.
So let's ask about to frame one again.
Can enter one there.
Let's just press play.
Everything works perfectly fine in blender.
So stop that and come back to my file system and double click the output of the video.
And there we go.
Boom.
We have a strike.
Awesome.
I'd love to see what you have created.
Don't forget to share in the discussions on the community forums.
I'll see you in another lecture.