Okay everybody before we get cracking with this lecture what I'd like you to do is grab a couple of
textures.
Now one of the places that I will recommend is textures dot com.
Now you will have to sign up for an account on here and it will give you permission to use those textures.
And what I'd like you to do before we start this lecture is go ahead and go find something that looks
cool to you.
Now I'm gonna go ahead and just show you a couple of textures so you get the hang of what's going on.
Not difficult at all.
I'm gonna be working with tiles so let's just find a tiles example.
I can't see one on the home screen hits probably under floors but I'm just going to go up to the search
box at the top right here.
No I don't endorse textures dot com at all I'm got no affiliation with them.
It's just a particular site that I found very useful.
I've typed in tiles that scroll down.
These are all HD RS that we've talked about in fact.
And then we scroll down a little further.
Okay that's interesting.
Did I actually type in tiles or oh I types and texture I am super silly.
I do apologize.
Okay.
If we search for tiles look at is fantastic.
So we have here a series of tiles that we could pick from.
This one's quite shiny.
This one's got a bump on it.
This one's all breaking this one's broken.
That's a very interesting one.
Now these are all high resolution as you can see here and you don't get the full super duper resolution
as part of a free setup.
All of this if you want super high high definition you're going to have to pay for.
That's just how it is when it comes to textures.
Someone has to take the time to make these things and they're really good so I'm just going to pick
one now I'm just scrolling down so you can see what's going on.
And I picked this one here every scroll down a lot further you'll get to your standard textures that
are much more flat and not represented in this ball fashion.
Here we go.
These ones here.
The difference here is these are substance designer materials already set up perfectly.
If you wanted them and these are just your standard images.
However when you select any of these you will often find that though this one here just comes with the
diffuse what we want to make sure let's go up to these balls here.
Just select any one Oh I like that circle and so I'm going to go back that circle on there with the
impulse so to get the actual substance material that is not something that comes free.
But what is down here is the flat maps and this is a one with one two three four five different maps
so you can only usually get up to 1024 by 2024.
For this example you don't need to take up a lot of space on your computer by all means if you want
the higher resolution one go for it and you don't have to use textures dot com.
You can go elsewhere to get textures or use some of the textures provided as part of this course.
And I will make sure that there's a link against this lecture where you can go and grab those textures
there are free packed by picks are not super duper high resolution but they will get the job done but
you simply click that will download that to your computer and you can use it straightaway over in Blender.
OK.
So now you know just one resource where you can get textures from there are plenty of others out there
as well.
All you have to do is use your favorite search engine and search for free textures and off you go.
You're bound to find something that suits what you want to do.
I would always encourage you not just to download exactly what I've got but experiment and have a look
at different textures there's plenty out there.
If you find a great one share it over in the discussion so others can use it as well.
That's it for this lecture and I'll see you all over in the next one.