Hello everybody and welcome.
In this lecture we're going to create the surround for our chess board and apply our first textures
really exciting because this is the start of making our objects look so much better than they've done
before.
Let's go find out more.
Okay so we're going to start off with a much more simple scene than just having the chessboard here
and we've got some construction to do.
And I want to dive straight into these materials.
So we're gonna go ahead and create a new blend file just the default cube but we're going to make a couple
of modifications to that cube I'm going to add a couple of loop cuts around it and then perhaps scale
it out.
So it's a bit more ornate than it would be before.
And the reason for doing that is our chess board is going to be very much like that it's not going to
be a default cube.
So here we go we've got a I suppose a small Mayan pyramid whatever you want to call it but that's the
object we're going to texture and I suggest that you also do something similar.
Rather than sticking with a default cube the next thing we need to do here is go ahead and add a material
to this.
Now it will already have a material assigned.
I'm going to call it wood.
And now that we've got that they are going to click the assigned button and make sure is in fact assigned.
It won't be assigned to anything in particular at the moment because we don't have anything selected.
There we go the entire object now has that material assigned to it.
And if I go to our base color I can change that and we should see it change making sure that we're in
the appropriate view mode.
I'm going to change it to look Dev.
There we go it's gone green I'm going to come out of edit mode for the moment and we can just change
it once more.
There we go.
Definitely confirmed that the base color is pink or thereabouts.
OK.
So we need to define the base color using a texture rather than a single color.
We can do that with the little circle next to base color and then we can select on the second column
itself.
Image texture.
When we do that the color will disappear for the moment.
In fact it will end up going black color but later on we'll start applying a texture to that and it
will change again.
So let's go ahead and click open.
You may not see this saying open so let's make this a little wider so we can see what's here.
I'm going to click on open and navigate to the wood textures.
That's a part of this lectures resources.
Let me go ahead.
There you'll see we've got lots of different types of maps in here.
And I'm going to focus on these color ones.
There's heights maps and normal maps as well.
And we're not going to deal with these particular types of textures in this lecture.
I'm just going to focus on the color itself.
Now for the actual board itself I'm going to probably pick something dark like this Brazilian rosewood.
But for the moment I any of these will do.
So I'm going to pick the American cherry at the top and hopefully Yep.
Here we go we've got some textures applied.
And this is what I was hoping to see by changing the model we've got this vertical stripes coming down
here.
Why is this happening.
Well there are a couple of reasons why.
First of all if we scroll down a little we've got this area here where currently it says flat.
And this is the type of projection that this texture is being applied to this model via.
So flat basically is like we're looking from above.
The texture is being projected down onto our model from both sides.
So we should end up with a good texture of this side and a good texture this side.
But when it comes to any surface that's completely vertical like this straight edge here we get these
vertical lines and that can end up looking horrible.
We can get around that by changing flat to a different type of projection.
Now as you're doing this you may find blender at the moment may crash in fact for anything to do with textures
and rendering that can happen and has done plenty of times in the past.
So what I'd recommend is as you're working on this particular model you save your work in this play case
I'm just going to call it a test piece it could be whatever you want to call it.
And I'm going to save my blender file and then before I make a change I'm going to make sure I save.
And that's just a good thing to do in general.
See here if I change it from flat to box.
Now its as if the object itself has a box around it and you may be now looking at it and going
oh Mike it looks worse.
Why is that.
Why is flat working and box has gone worse in theory should be better because these textures are being
projected from all angles at this point so we shouldn't end up with these vertical lines.
So we need to have a look at this area here where it says vector.
At the moment it's set to default which is why this is looking pretty horrible.
However if we click on that we get lots and lots of options.
And we can also make it disappear the ones that we're looking for are under texture coordinate we are
telling the texture which coordinates it maps to.
Now later on in the course we'll cover UV unwrapping and mapping and that's what you can say precisely
where the texture will appear on a model for the moment though we don't need to worry about that we
can even use generated or objects both of them tend to work really well.
Let's try.
Object first and we can see here the texture is repeating itself a lot as we go through that doesn't
look ideal does it it is repeating the texture lots and not in an ideal way so let's see what generated
it ends up looking like.
In this particular case generated is going to look a lot better.
Excellent.
And we could see here that it's mapped it as if it was being projected from multiple angles which is really
really useful.
Now if you do find that it's not making much sense what you can do is increase this blend level and
then when you have two separate areas and that's this slope here it's a mixture of the front and the
side you can increase the blend there to try and blend between the two different projections and that
can make things look a lot better.
I think in this particular model it's not going to make too much difference.
And there we go.
That is our first texture applied to our model in a very very simple way.
And now it's time for you to apply your texture to your model in the form of a challenge Okay so your
challenge will come in two parts.
Firstly I'd like you to go ahead and make a surround for your chessboard at the moment.
It's just a 64 squares we really want something around it and we can to apply a texture to it.
So go ahead pick a texture from the provided wood pack so you'll find that over in the lecture resources
and then apply the texture to the board using what we've learned in this lecture pause video now and
give that a go
Hello everybody and welcome back.
Let's go ahead now hop into blender and make our surround and apply the texture to it okay everybody
welcome back.
The first thing that I'm going to do here is go in and edit my chessboard.
So let's go ahead.
I'm going to tab in and I've been playing with this and you may want to check this yourself as well.
When we're in face select mode.
If you select one of your faces.
Look at that it detaches from the other.
In fact if I press the L key to see what's linked it happens to be groups of four.
So the first thing I'm going to do here is select everything and press F3 and search for all doubles
and remove them.
And here we go.
We've removed 63 vertices and we should now find that the whole match is linked together.
Excellent.
The next thing is about this perimeter here another a couple of ways of working on that.
The first one is to actually duplicate the board and then just leave the perimeter around the edge dissolving
the multiple edges that you would have in between in order to get there.
Now I'm not gonna take that step because I know the dimensions of all of these squares.
So all I need to do is go shift and S moving the cursor back to the world origin and add in another
bit of mesh data a plane.
And I believe it's going to be forty eight centimeters across.
Boom straight away.
Now we've got this horrible effect going on.
And this is something that catches a lot of people out.
This is called Z fighting.
This is where two things are trying to display at the same time because they're literally on top of
each other.
They're occupying the same space.
If I was to press the Z key and go into lookDev mode we can see it looks absolutely horrible.
And sometimes this happens if you do have a place holder in place and an actual model and especially
if you forget to turn off the rendering option over in the outline itself that can cause these type
of issues.
But for the moment with that surface selected I'm going to go G Z minus one centimeter and because I've
got the scene sets up in centimeters that's all sorted.
I can now extrude just the edges up.
I don't want the face selected I just want the edges.
This is go round to the bottom.
And this is a bit awkward having to work around this board on top.
So what I can do is just clear all selections and I'm gonna go ahead and pressing the L key select all
linked surfaces on the top and just like before where we could hide an object.
Well you can hide faces as well as the H key that saves us a lot of time because now what I can do is I
can select these edges very quickly.
I'm going to extrude them up on the Z axis by one centimeter and then I'm going to delete the face that's
there by deleting that face I can now select the edge loop very quickly I'm going to extrude it by nothing
and then scale it outwards.
Now at this point you can completely ad lib what you're doing.
Again I'm going to extrude by nothing, scaling outwards and then move it down on the Z axis.
Then I'm going to extrude on the z axis by maybe minus two centimeters minus three.
Yeah.
And then fill in the face with the F key so we've got all basic board we can now go round and add a bit
of detailing in if you wanted to do that you could do that would loop cuts this bottom face by the way
I want to move down so I'm gonna go G Z and just move it down a little bit further because then I can
add in some decent loop cuts around the edge.
I didn't want to add one in there, Let's undo that let's add in two.
Excellent.
With the S key we're going to scale in.
Okay that's fine.
I'm going to set this face loop running around the edge extrude by nothing and then scale that in, Of course
we could scale that out if we want it as well and it's up to you how you embellish this and then we
go Alt and H and make sure that we can see the board as well and how it looks all.
Now I think that's probably alright.
I'm going to lower this edge here just a little to select the edge the running round and go G,G and
bring that down looks good.
Longer run a little edge loop around here and lift that back up again.
Perfect.
Okay.
The other thing that I want to do here is make sure there's a little bit of a recess around the board
itself.
So once again I'm going to clear my selection press the L key and hide the board itself and grab this
and scale it out ever so slightly not by much.
Then I'm going to go alt and H and see how that's looking.
I think that's about right.
If we go into rendered mode we should see that gap in full effect.
Yes I can see the gap running around the edge.
So the final thing to do here is extrude the board itself down.
So going to make sure I've only got the board selected and then extrude down.
Now you remember we extruded by just a centimeter before so minus one and
there we go.
We've got the board itself extruded down so not going to end up with some horrible floating artifact
around the edge here.
So there we go we've got the base layer all sorted.
The next thing we need to do is add an appropriate material.
Let's make this a bit wider here and bring this bit up.
So we've currently got the material white squares that looks like what the surround is made from.
I can just press the L key and select all of that.
Now I didn't clear my selection first.
I don't trust that I've actually got everything selected that I wanted selected I'm going to add a new
material called it wood I'm going to assign that and then just quickly check with the base color that
that is in fact right.
Okay.
So we've got those bits all done and I'm just looking around my model and this extra loop cut that we've
added in isn't adding anything to our model at this point.
So I'm going to go G.G. and move it down slightly and then scale this out.
There we go.
So I think that's probably a bit big as well so I'm going to hop into wireframe mode from the side so
I can select everything and I'm going to select all of this and scale it up on the Z axis and then move
this all up on the Z axis as well.
And that should look a bit more in proportion now than it did before.
Yes I'm liking that.
OK.
So our base colour we need to replace with an image.
I'm going to go into my images I'm going to open up the Brazilian rosewood I think that's what I'm going
to pick.
So make sure I've gone to my recent folders here kind of go to thumbnails so I can see what's going
on this Brazilian rosewood is really dark all the other Rosewood here is quite nice as well.
Mm hmm.
Lots of choice.
I'm going to stick.
I'm going to go for the figured rosewood with this time round.
So we've got our texture applied before I do anything else I'm going to save my work I should have saved
it before I did that.
So that could a crash blender the next thing I'm going to go and do is go to my vector and set it is
generated for the moment and just see how that's looking.
Okay.
Textures looking a bit large on the board itself but we'll find out how to sort that's out in the bit.
We've got the straight lines going down here so I'm going to go from flat to boxed and then we should
get it flowing better around the model.
Now I know objects didn't work before on our simple objects but let's see how it looks.
On this board itself that looks a bit better how it's flowing the texture around.
Let's just go back to generate it so it doesn't flow as well on generated as it does on objects.
This does flow around the model much much better awesome.
So I'm pretty happy with how that's works out as I say this textures is a bit big we can learn about
mapping in the next lecture where we can start changing the size of our wood texture and finally what
we can do here is quickly turn on our pieces and see how it looks now.
I did pick the dark wood so you could see reflections and that is what we should be able to see if we
just go to our roughness tab and there we go it's going to need to be quite low maybe point 1 or so.
And there we go we can see the reflections in the wood itself.
Perfect.
How are your boards coming along.
Please share your work over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.