Welcome to introduction.
T you've V unwrapping in this video you will no longer ask what you ve stands for.
We'll do an overview of the mapping that in the upcoming lectures and understand that will be creating
these maps from scratch and then using them a gain to speed up further work flow.
So we've had this section so far where we've looked everything emack crow how the pieces are all fitting
together what the overall building or interior is going to look like.
And now's the time to start zooming in on a bit of detail.
So what does it usually mean.
Well X Y and Z are already used for the Cold War donat system with the in blender itself and you and
V are like the x and y coordinates of an image.
So you v mapping is the process of projecting a 2D image on to a 3D model's surface and the U.S. map
itself as we'll soon see has so as the geometry as the map and it's placed upon the picture.
So let's have a quick look at something we're all familiar with.
A map of the earth.
And if you're interested in seeing more images like this of our wonderful planets and indeed some other
wonderful photographs I've gotten this from the nassr website.
All of their images are free to use so if you actually want to make a planet Earth a model of that and
will be doing something very basic like that in a few moments then of course that's the place to go
to get these wonderful textures from and remember the word texture or image is interchangeable when
it comes to blender.
Now one of the problems with a map of the earth is Antarctica really isn't that big.
And those Greenland Greenlands actually tiny.
So the South Pole is Antarctica right at the bottom there.
Now obviously that is a 2D representation of the earth.
So one of the dramatic things to highlight here is mapping can cause distortion in image because that
image then has to be compressed onto a 3-d shape.
Now we all know that the earth is flat like this it in fact looks more like this a sphere or spherical
in nature.
So you ve tells that texture how to apply itself to a 3D surface.
So what do these maps do.
Well they do lots of things what we looked at a few moments ago could be called a diffused map which
is creating the illusion of colour on the surface.
In fact it is adding colour on the surface in this case but they also create the illusion of surface
detail by mapping parts of an image to the geometry on our model.
They could be applied automatically which is great for your basic models and that generates a U.S. map.
But generating euv map yourself does give the best results.
So two of the basic maps that will be colour coming up in the near.
So two of the basic maps now that are coming up in the next couple of lectures we've got a diffuse map
which is the base colour of the geometry itself.
So up until this point we've really only dealt with making either individual faces of a certain colour
or applying a certain material to them or we've been dealing with the whole model having the same material
applied to it.
Now the great thing with a map is it allows us to only use one material but use a texture or an image
in order to control the diffuse colour.
Another one is a bump map.
Now that tells the shader how to react with light.
So a quick example here we've got this rough moon.
I'm going to call it a moon and we've got this one.
Now apart from the slight lighting differences they're almost exactly the same but you can you tell
which ones which.
Probably not unless you start looking at some of the micro details in the shadows.
So we have this one which is the high polygon version in fact it's one million triangles just over one
million.
It's rendered with a thousand samples and rendered a full ten ATP.
So it took a little while to render.
In fact it rendered at seven minutes four seconds in terms of its render time.
Now instead we go down to the low poly model.
If you look around the edge you can see that it's a bit jagged around the edge.
In fact this whole model is only a thousand triangles again rounded with a thousand samples and rendered
at 10 80.
Now that rendered in five minutes four seconds.
So that reduced our render time by around 20 percent.
Now what that means for us in blender is that we can make a highly detailed model bake that detail down
to an image.
Apply that image back to the model and save a shed load on our rendering time.
Now on the one off image it wouldn't be worth it if we were rendering that image over and over again
like on an animation then suddenly it becomes werefor instead of spending 10 hours rendering you'd only
spend eight or maybe less who knows.
Depends what you're rendering on.
Now of course this has the added benefit if you will rendering diffuse maps and normal maps and bump
maps and all these other type of maps.
We can then reassemble our whole model externally to blender as well so this has a benefit both within
blender and when making assets that you're using elsewhere.
So let's now go make a very basic U.S. map over in blender.
Okay so go ahead and open up a brand new blend far making sure you've saved and committed the work you're
currently on.
So I'm going to start off with a default blender seem like this.
I'm going to remove the cube from it and add a u v sphere.
The name may sound familiar I don't know if there's any direct link between Eevee maps and Yuri spheres.
But here we go.
Now in order to make this a bit more easy to see I'm going to lower the segment count quite significantly.
And the same with the ring so it's going to be a very low poly globe.
Now I know this is a bit abstract since we're working on an interior but I think a globe is a great
way of representing a map and then applying it in 3D and understanding how the relation works between
the two.
We're have more detailed interior models coming up soon as well.
I'm going to make the size of my globe just a little larger than four.
So make it five.
Going to make it a little larger than one has.
One is boring for a Globe five.
It's an epic globe.
And under the tunnels smooth shading So it's as smooth as it can possibly be.
Now this is currently got a default material on it which is fine.
I'm going to add new material and call it Earth because that's the picture I'm going to use.
I'm currently using nodes which is great.
Now become apparent why that's important in a few moments at colour.
I'm going to set the colour to use a picture for the colour so I can go here and use image texture.
Click on that little dot and then Image texture.
And I'm going to select from the game asset pack sections the world diffuse Naxal map.
And there we go.
This should now be showing.
He says the map of the worlds going to go to material and it's not.
And why isn't it.
Why.
Why can't we see it.
It's because blender doesn't actually know how to map that image to this object.
So we need to tell it and we tell blender by unwrapping our 3-d objects.
We go from a 3-d object to a two day object.
So let's drag out and create a u v image editor.
Hop into edit mode over here on our globe on our 3-d object in the 3-d window and we can go meche and
unwrap and we get a series of options you see the shortcut key there is you know we just go ahead and
unwrap now there isn't an image properly applied yet but it's also managed to grab that because it's
using the image itself and it knows it's a movie mapped image.
We can see that it's mapped to every face and that's not what we want and that is essentially what this
square in front of us is showing showing us that the whole image whatever the image happens to be assigned.
You map it to every single face and that is no good for this example.
So let's go ahead and open up the Emmy so we can see what's happening and because it's already loaded
into memory we can click the image drop down or drop up in this case since it's at the bottom and select
the image you are going to have to scroll out a little here and we can see the aspects of the race image
is quite wide.
It's got quite a wide array.
And now and you may need to do this a few times during doing any unwrap we're just going to reset the
unwrap by here in New ingoing reset.
And that means that any of the previous settings stored when unwrapping will have been white.
Now I'm going to speed things up here when I'm going to go into too detail about altering the you v
map but actually the generation we can get away here with going a sphere projection because ultimately
we're mapping it to a sphere is not a complicated object like a face or something like that.
Now we can see that it's not got it right not straight away anyway it's truncated half of the America
and the Far East and Africa has gone really wide on us.
That is no good.
So what we can do here is go over to the U.S. image enter and use the controls much like we would if
this were a mesh that we were altering.
So what we can do there is literally scale it with the ESC key making sure that this area is selected
and hitting the esky of course.
And remember we can it accidentally invert it will.
Which will make it all upside down.
But here we go we can scale it out as the right sort of height and then we can scale the width as well
with S and X so X is across an y is up when it comes to your pictures.
And then we can use the G key and move it about so all of these are very much like we used to.
You can also grab the individual vertices representing this 3-d object and move them as well to straighten
out the u v map.
If you wanted to now remember we're telling lender at this point which one of the faces is represented
on the image so we can move things about and really skew up the image.
If we're not careful so we do have to be careful when we're moving these about.
A time you'll be mapping to an image like this or even generating your own image in which case the alignment
with it doesn't matter because you're creating everything.
Now we don't have to worry about this disappearing into the aether over here.
Is she going to warp around to this side of the image and continue.
So I'm happy with that.
Now let's have a look at our globe.
How is that turnout going to hop out of edit mode so I can look around.
It's a little jagged around the edges.
The polls seem to be roughly in the right place which is not bad for a rough unwrap.
Occasionally these things can go completely adrift and look horrible.
But that's not bad.
Unwrap for such a low poly model.
OK I remember earlier I said that using nose was important.
Well it is if we don't want to create a separate material when working with cycles and blender render
because sometimes you may want to hop between the two.
So here's a little tip for you because psychos uses notes by default when we switch over to blender
render.
We can turn use notes off we see at the moment so is earth material node and then no nodes are associated
with the blender end.
And that's fine if we turn used nodes off this button next to the material name.
We say you shade those to render the material.
If we click that it disappears we can't see the image anymore and that's fine.
We can also turn this off by the way under the node editor itself as a little thing on here on the IMI
on the node Ed header that we can tick and untuck use notes.
Now what you want to go back to cycles you need to remember to read tic that or press this button again.
Now blend a render we can assign a picture to the few straightaway we need to do it by the form of a
texture.
Now we've already unwrapped our model so it doesn't need anymore unwrapping a special done.
All it requires is a texture applied we need to create a new texture.
Add to that texture.
Apply that image that we've already got in memory so we can click on.
Drop down or in this case drop up a hand click on mean nassr world diffused image and there we go it
straight on a couple of things I would do to change this straight away is the lighting itself is not
very good since going to the lighting properties and put sun on it is the planet Earth after all.
But we're not going to mess around with any of the settings for the sun.
And equally if we're in that cycles render of course the image now goes white because we haven't selected
use nodes but we don't select use nodes on the lights we select on the material.
If we start our are not sure about this but I think if I use nodes here and I go back to a blender render.
Oh it does still work.
Okay that is good.
I thought it might not if we switch the lighting across sphere here.
We need to go to the materials option and click use nodes again and the object is back again.
Brilliant.
I think it's time for a small challenge for you guys.
Okay I would like you to add a wall texture.
So use your own all the wall texture in the asset pack.
It doesn't matter which one you use.
You ve unwrap your basic wall so it's gonna be that basic wall piece without the window in it or anything
else CAN START.
Nice and simple with this unwrapping apply the texture to the wall.
In both cycles and blend a render.
If you find your texture is 90 degrees out.
Try rotating the UV mesh.
Now I must emphasize at this point as long as there is a texture on the mesh in both blender render
and cycles you have succeeded.
This challenge will nail down the actual quality of the unwrapping later on in this section pause the
video now and give that a go.
OK guys welcome back.
Let's go map our wall texture to our wall and hop on over in a blender.
Okay so I've opened up my wall my elodie a wall and we're going to start adding some detail to it.
So this is just going to be text to details so still gonna remain an elodie wall or at this point and
melody a wall.
So no extra geometry involved.
So I'm going to go straight to my materials tab and add new material name the wall.
Following that I'm going to not colour it in white or slightly off white.
I am going to use an image texture to define the colour.
I'm going to go ahead and open up go to the asset pack and open up this one called cinder block.
Now that that's opened it needs to.
We need to tell blender how it's mat.
So I'm going to close down at my tool shelf and properties of the 3D editor.
I'm also going to add I've moved across switched my viewport rendering to material so the lighting doesn't
matter.
We will need lighting by the way to see in blender end.
Otherwise it will be black.
So before I hop into edit mode I'm just going to plonk a sunlamp in the scene and sunlamp.
The direction doesn't really matter where it's placed as a matter only the direction counts.
I think that will be okay.
I'll literally hop into rended both quickly.
Yeah that looks absolutely fine.
So let's hop into edit mode on this.
Everything is selected by default and I'm going to just do a basic unwrapped nothing special and we'll
see how that turns out.
So that's looking pretty good.
We just need to go to the picture down here at the cinder block.
Also looking pretty good.
How are we in material mode.
No we're not.
Let's have a look.
Our AK So we've got vats at 90 degrees.
How's the side and this side is right.
How is the edge.
Okay that's good.
We can see here looking at the edge on the u v not on TV Surrey on the 3D view here.
It's compressed because the whole edge has been compressed so this whole image has been compressed onto
the edge itself.
It looks so surely because of the way the more time line is still pretty much aligned in the right place.
Not a great alignment but that will do for this initial initial go at it.
That's really good.
Well it doesn't require much in the way of fixing.
Now down this is a bit wonky here are not happy with that.
And of course what we can do here is select that face making sure in face select and then we're not
going to rotate the face in the 3D view that causes all sorts of horrible artefacts but because that's
now selected in the U.S. image too we can actually rotate it and we can see it's kind of granular granulated
at the moment so we can go round in notches.
I'm just going to type in 90 because it is 90 and press centre that should have sorted that out.
Perfect.
So we've got our first wall piece absolutely sorted.
I really don't care about this bottom piece am at the moment.
I don't care about it.
I might have to make it a separate piece actually because these are stacked on top of one another.
It's going to make a line.
Now whether or not that line makes it look odd.
I will have to see later on.
Be lean about it and check that it works.
So that's that texture.
Applied in cycles and it's looking pretty good.
If we go into the full view port rendering we can see that that is coming across really well and that's
just a diffuse texture.
We now need to make sure that it's working in a blender and a and a switch across the blender and in
the middle cereal's propertys.
I need to make sure it's not using notes.
So there we go we can now see our objects and make a new texture and then assign an image to that section
because it's still in memory.
I can just select it there and there we go.
Now obviously with Blender render the spec clarity is automatically applied as well so we go to the
materials and go down in there so we can see that the intensity is quite high.
If we go and turn that down we'll end up with a much lower sheyna to the wall.
What was on generally shiny unless they've got gloss paint on them or they are wet.
And in this case I want Neve so often the intensity is going to turn it right down to nothing.
It's a fall diffuse texture.
How did you guys get on.
Did you manage to map a basic image to the wall.
Did you use your own texture.
I love to see what you guys come up with.
And as always please share your work in the discussions.
And I will see you guys in the next lecture.