And this lecture, I'm adding some hair to my animal and doing some tests renders to see if I can find
something that's generally in the direction of what I'd like from my animal.
I'm just going to experiment with the hair first before I start grooming and placing it properly, because
you can often invest a lot of time in having the hair perfectly in position, only to find that, oh,
it's too long or too short or there's too much of it, or I wish I did it a different way from the start.
So let's find the look that we're going for.
First of all, gonna start off by creating myself new particle system.
Click on my cat first, finding the particle system click.
Plus, I will call this particle system.
Body hair.
Cook on the hair and then change the hair length, I'm going to make my point, too.
That might be a little bit too short.
This is the part that when they go and add children and stop modifying their hair, we'll lose the ability
to increase the handling.
So I spent a little bit of time trying to figure out how long the hair should be.
Maybe even point to five.
Don't do a lot of work until you're happy with the length of the hair.
I think what I'll be doing in the next video probably is white painting.
So for now, I'm going to totally ignore how terrible the head and the feet and possibly even the tail.
Look, I'm just going for the overall body hair structure.
That's fine.
Children interpolated.
And we've got a starting point to put mine up to 30 and 30.
Now, once again, if your computer is not enjoying having too many, then play around with it when
you've got a lower value and then see how it looks when you render.
Speaking of which, let's do our first render.
That's how we're looking so far.
Again, this is Eevee.
This is without hair just sticking straight out.
We've got patches in here that whether the Catholic a little bit bold, I find that happens when you've
got the hair just coming straight out from the body.
There's a lot more likelihood that you'd be looking directly into the skin or the body of the animal.
So just pop that down.
Let me say I'm gonna adjust the color a little bit at this stage so I can start to get a feel for that.
So I'll go down to my material properties, click on new I'll call this body Serial.
And then just change the base color.
I think I said in my previous video I was going gonna go for black, which was really enjoying the look
of the black cat.
But it's just quite difficult to see, I think, on video when I'm starting to look at strands of hair.
So I'm gonna go for a lighter color, probably more of a brownie ginger color the body.
I'll go brown.
And then I think the hair, I'll get a little bit more ginger in the hair.
Now create a second material plus and click on new.
I will call this body hair and for the moment I'll leave as principled B.S. the F, but I will change
that to hair shortly.
I just want to see generally how things are looking at this point.
I change the base color to make more of a bright orange.
If I can find a bright orange color for my ginger ninja, it's going to be strolling through the undergrowth.
Excellent.
Over to the particle system.
And can you remember where it is that we tell our particle system, use that color?
Yeah.
It's within render.
We find material and we change that to be body hair.
Now we've got to orange kind of looking.
Can't let's do another test.
Render again an Avey.
So she'll be pretty quick.
Okay.
And you might like that.
Look, you might like this kind of e.v. spike.
You look like I said before.
Ignore the fate.
Not gonna worry about those for now.
And the face gonna go in and do a little bit of grooming.
Just random type stuff to make sure that it's looking generally the way I want it to.
And I think what I'll do is modify just the tips of the hair particles.
Go for pretty big brush for the moment, jump on a calm and push everything a little bit back.
So we'll keep the the fullness of the hair.
I sound like a hairdressing ad, don't I?
Like by this shampoo.
Keep the Faunus in the full rich body of your.
You can tell I haven't had hair for a long time.
I don't even know how the ads go.
Anyway, we'll keep the fullness and thickness of the body.
We'll get a little bit of the hair pointing in the direction that the Kate the cat is kind of moving
or facing.
Okay.
Don't put too much time into this.
Just doing it for enough so I can go and do another test render.
See how that looks.
Okay.
That's all now looking in a orderly direction.
And you can see a lot of the the B on a C straight through and this part has been resolved.
Couple of patches, empty patches.
Ouch.
We'll have a look at those just now and see what's going on.
Okay.
You can see that we've got this big area where there's nothing in there, if you've got any of that.
You can go and click on ADD.
Make sure you do interpolate or click on Interpolate.
Sorry.
I will change the count down to just to count down the boob and just pop a couple.
Well they're not really going where I want them to go make my brush smaller.
And you know, I'm just gonna put down a one so I have all these double headers everywhere.
Okay.
And you can say they're following the shape from what we have because we're on interpolate.
So just doing this to show that we can fill in the gaps and make sure we can fill in the gaps.
Another test, render lots of tests, run a F 12 to do a test render in C have mostly filled in a little
bit more to go.
Very, very uniform with our hair here.
It's not looking realistic as an animal would.
So let's have a look at what we can do.
There's a couple of options.
First of all, we can scroll down within our particle system and find roughness and play around with
the roughness.
You might want to change the randomness to say point one, get a little bit of randomness in there.
I'm just going to jump back over into my object mode so I can see what's happening when I do this.
And as we go for that randomness, we've got every single thing has got the randomness of Benice to
the hairs.
And we do have you can see hopefully you can see in here that the hairs are looking too low.
Poly scroll up to render, whereas render and find the path and increase these steps to four, five.
Now we'll do a render X.
I'll do that in the viewport display as well.
Let's see Strand's steps.
Three, four, five.
I might even go higher here if your computer is not enjoying.
Then feel free to stop at a lower value.
I'll put mine, although after seven to so I can get the strands as smooth as possible.
Do another render.
See if that's changed much.
Okay.
It's got a little bit fuzzier.
So this is an interesting look at the fuzzy look.
And it's really cool to experiment.
If you want to do something that's more like a poodle look.
Or more like a frizzy animal local, more of a clomping hair look than you can play around with these
values.
I mentioned Clomping put clomping the value of, say, point five.
That will give us a little bit of the hair clumping together and then shape.
I'll put that 2.5 as well just to see how that's looking.
Okay.
Hit F 12 again.
This is looking really interesting.
If you wanted to make a an animal that was a like a stuffed toy that had what looks like cotton or wool
attached to it.
Is Frogmore Cotton then?
This is a really cool look for that.
Looks like little strands of cotton, doesn't it, particularly when you're scrolling.
So that could be the toy teddy bear if you wanted to make that look really cool.
Make sure you don't follow exactly what I'm doing.
Come up with your own interpretation of this whole exercise.
I'm gonna put the clomping back to zero, the shape back to zero.
I want my cat to have reasonably smooth hair.
But let's have a look at the roughness value.
I'm going to increase the randomness.
Actually, know what the threshold I was saying before that I've got too many things that are kind of
squiggly when I have some of them squiggly and some of them not.
So if our threshold is at zero, everything is gonna be squiggly.
If I put my threshold to one, then nothing should be squiggly.
So put my threshold to say point eight, then we'll have some of them.
Some of the strands of hairs will be squiggly if the squiggly is actually a word.
Okay.
Cool.
Nearly time for me to have a look at how this looks in cycles and it's going to change to slot two.
This means we can render to the other slot, jump up two cycles in my rendering tab, switch on over
cycles, hit F 12.
It's going to take a little bit longer.
I'll probably speed up the video each time I do my renders.
So it's not accurate indication of how long these things take.
If you're wondering why is Frick's Renda going so quick at the moment, getting super slow but are speed
up each time I do the random?
From now on.
Okay, I like that we've got a little bit of the randomness in there.
I think what I need to do with mine is to increase the number of children, which I will do now just
so I can feel like I'm getting an accurate indication.
60 and 60.
Like I said before, if your computer is struggling with this, then don't push it.
Let's just do another quick render on that.
For me, it's a lot of tweaking.
Render it, tweak it, render it so you can see how it's looking until we get to the point where we're
mostly in the ballpark and then I'll move on to the next stage of grooming.
Okay, so here's my render.
I'm looking at this bit on the top that I've actually paid attention to.
Not so much down here.
And generally I'm happy with it.
I'm happy with the length.
I'm happy with the the style of grooming.
When I push it backwards, it makes sense, you know, when I groom it backwards.
So I'm pretty happy with this look.
As I mentioned before, I need to change what I'm going to do for the feet, change what I do for the
face and head and whiskers.
But I think I've settled on a general approach.
Let me just try one more thing to make sure I'm happy with the look of this, which is to switch up
what we're using for our shader.
I'm going to if I can grab my other window delicately, drag on out a second window, switch into the
shader editor, just move that over.
Blinks.
We don't need it.
Scrolling, scrolling, scrolling.
Currently, we're using a principle B SDF for our hair, going to jump to my material properties.
What are we looking for here?
B, the I'm going to change that to be either the hair B SDF up yonder or the principled hair B SDF.
I'm not going to go into the full power of these things, I'm just gonna tweak them a little bit to
see if I can get the result I'm going for.
So go principled hair, the SDF and you can see when we do that everything goes pretty dark even when
I'm over in my render view.
Give it a moment.
I've got the color in here, which is quite a dark color.
So I'm going to change the default value color to be, let's see, something a little bit brighter so
we can actually see what's going on in the general orangy range, similar to the color I had there before.
We can see an okay kind of representation, but to see how this looks as a proper render.
So once again, I'm going to do a proper render and speed up things to see how this looks and then jump
back in and tweak some of the values.
OK, I still have some patches where I can see the skin of the animals so long as the hair and the skin
a similar color.
It's not gonna be too much of an issue.
I can just go on patch those those in later on.
I'm pretty happy with what I'm seeing around the mid area, a little bit flat on top.
So see if we can do something a little bit better there as time goes on.
But generally, I'm happy with this direction that we're in.
And I like the fact that when we do this, we've got this natural variation in color where the light
shining on it more brightly.
We've got a lighter color.
We've got a darker orange on the chest of the animal.
So it makes it look like we've got tons of hair type variation in here.
I said not super happy with what's going on on top, but we'll deal with that as time goes on.
Generally, I'm going to call this good enough for the moment and start getting into the next phase
of grooming my animal.
So quite a challenge for you.
And that is to add here to your animal's body.
So experiment with different styles of fur or hair that might suit your animal.
Try clumping.
Try having it longer.
Try having it shorter.
Try having it grooming.
Sorry.
Try grooming.
Try having it spiky.
And then to change a shader if you like.
You don't have to.
I've changed.
It made little bit of a difference.
I quite like it.
Use cycles rendering if you like, but you don't have to.
By all means.
You can absolutely use Eevee if you want.
This whole process to go more quickly.
You're not so worried about also precious about having it look absolutely perfect.
Or if you just like the style that Eevee gives to you, which often can give you more of a stylistic
cartoony look as well.
And once you're happy, head to the next lecture.
Well, we'll start to put a little bit more attention into the hair coverage and the feet and getting
the body looking the way we want the body to look.