Okay in this lecture we're going to dive straight into a challenge.
So what I'd like you to do is create the upper arm of your lamp.
When you've done that at the appropriate bone to the armature parent the upper arm mesh objects to the
upper arm bone constrain the upper arms movement we don't want it just twirling in circles or just going
off to the side check your naming and check your transforms as you go.
The video now and give that a go okay.
Everybody welcome back.
It's happened over into a blender and create the upper arm of our lamp Okay everybody Welcome back into
blender.
The easiest way that I think we're going to go about doing this is to select all we need to reset some
stuff here by the looks of it it's gone slightly askew or we've got it in a pose in pose mode.
We have I'm going to switch this so we don't lose any sets that we've got at the moment.
I'm going to go to my pose itself and set it to its rest position because then when I go into edit mode
everything is where we want it to be.
I'm going to select this part of the tail rather of the tail point of the bone and I'm going to go shift
an ass and move the cursor to select it.
Now we can go ahead or want to add a new bone in there.
I did however want to add something.
So I'm going to come out and add in a cube.
I'm going to go into edit mode and scale it.
You don't have to worry about applying transforms later.
Let's look at this from this angle here.
Move it in.
Okay that looks good.
That's a big enough gap there.
Now I am going to rotate this.
Looking at it from the side by 45 degrees looking good so far I'm going to grab this face here crosses
the three key to get there and just extrude up again I'm going to look at this from the side probably
pop it about there.
Now I'm going to make this deeper so I'm going to grab this lower face and I think if I move that's
obviously it's just going to move out randomly here press the Z key once Z key twice that's not moving
out.
Normal to the face even though I'm asking it to do that.
Okay.
So since it won't let me move to the normal I will simply extrude to the normal.
And then I can select the edge loop running around our model and finally dissolve those edges.
Brilliant.
Okay.
So that's how it's done and dusted.
We can add more detail to it later.
I'm going to go ahead hop out into object mode select my armature and go into edit mode here.
And look at this exactly from the side and we can see here that this needs moving.
So I'm going to press G and move it down ever so slightly says approximately in the right place and
then move or create rather a new bone coming up here and we'll probably end up tweaking that as well
with that bone selected.
I want to come out.
Select my new upper arm selects my bone and then control and P parent to the bone.
Now before I do anything else naming etc. I do want to make sure that that is with the rotation post
mode enabled.
There we go.
It is moving things around as we wanted to.
But it's also not constrained yet.
But before we do anything else I'm going to go to the bones properties and call this the upper arm and
I'm going to do the same for the mesh object itself.
So I'm going to go into object mode again so that the upper arm is just called cube at the moment.
I'm going to call it upper arm.
Okay.
Brilliant.
So let's go back into post mode.
We need to make sure we've got our arm just selected first and we need to go ahead and add in some constraints.
So let's do that.
Let's add in a limit rotation.
Now looking at this I want it moving on the 0 limit rotation.
There we go.
I want to keep it local space which is fine on the x axis.
I want it moving so I can limit it's on the set and Y.
And again I don't know.
I do want it limited on the Z and let's try minus 30.
Oh yeah.
Minus 35 plus 35.
And see what happens when we try and move it it's limited to there and we'll go up straight at the top
here.
Okay.
Perfect.
Up and down.
Excellent.
So that's everything.
There they are.
Let's go through and just check our naming.
There's only two things to really check here.
That's the bone itself.
I'm pretty sure we named yet.
The bone is called upper arm.
Our mesh object is called upper arm.
And when we go ahead with our arm which are selected and get a pose mode and start moving that it's
moving as we'd expect to perfect.
I'm gonna select all of my model and just clear those rotations so everything is back in line as well.
Brilliant lumps coming along really well we're only a few steps away from having this looking really
nice with the top bits of the lamp on.
I hope your lamps are coming along brilliantly.
Please share your work over in the discussions and I'll see you well in the next lecture.