Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to create our lampshade and we're going to use curves again and you will
find that the process that we're about to use is very familiar because we've used curves before to make
the base.
But this time we're going to use them in a slightly different way and you'll see how you're able to
not only make this particular part of the lamp but you may also be able to make other detailing that
would be very useful for this type of object.
Let's find out more.
Okay everybody so what we are going to use here is the modifier.
So let's go to the modifiers tab and we're going to be generating so the second column and we're going
to be using the screw modifier.
Now the moment you do that you'll notice that we end up with a very horrible looking mesh.
And what you're seeing here is the cube being spun or screwed around its own origin.
Now what we can do is either give it an access object much like we can give a mirror a mirror object
or we can simply go into edit mode and just move the cube out slightly so it's not going to intersect
as it goes through and we can see as we play with some of these options the effect it has.
So let's just make this a little wider so we can read everything the axis.
Well that's switch access is going to be screwed around.
So we've got a couple of different choices here.
And you can see we get different results depending on how it's happening.
Let's go back to Z for the moment and we'll have a look at some of the other options.
The angle.
Well what happens if we change that.
Well then it doesn't become a complete screw all the way around or maybe several screws going round.
It's entirely up to you how you do that.
Now typically it'll be a 360 doesn't have to be and then you can use the iterations later on to just
repeat that.
So for instance this cube is two meters tall.
So if we set the screw at two meters then by the time it's completed one whole revolution it will be
bang on top of itself which it pretty much is.
Now we can adjust the ever so slightly so it looks nice let's say from the side or the front.
That's looking pretty good.
And then we can just up the iterations and it will just repeat that consistently going up.
Now what does this remind you of.
Well hopefully it reminds you of some fun the helter skelter or perhaps a car park.
Some of them have or suddenly I had a toy car park when I was little it was like rats but also a spring.
This would be a useful model for our lamp.
Often the type that we're designing to have springs in them.
Let's just make this a little bit simpler again.
And I'm going to set the screw high back down to zero.
So basically creates a circle.
Now the next thing we can change here is the steps.
Now let's just this render steps and steps if I position my camera.
There we go.
And zoom out ever so slightly.
Or rather just pull the camera back.
There we go.
If we adjust the steps that say we adjust this down to five steps we'll end up with a messy pentacle.
Let's see if we can do six.
Yes six looks better.
So we've got six steps running around here.
But if we render it it will look like it's got more.
And it has because the render steps is set at 16.
We have an option here for smooth shading.
It's entirely up to you whether you go for that or not.
And it will depend on the type of object you're modelling merging vertices that can be incredibly useful
but you can see here if you do merge vertices your screw offset must be zero.
So that's what we were playing with at the top here when we've got the option to adjust the screw offset
that has to be zero to merge vertices and that just makes it a much cleaner mesh.
If we were to solidify this when we clicked apply now object screws currently grayed out because we
don't have an object that was screwing around.
But that basically means we can venue something like an empty much like he would do with the mirror
modify to change the objects offset as you lift up and down so you can change this using an empty which
is useful if you want to have a spring stretching and closing rather than just setting it manually like
this.
And I've already covered the iterations on there.
So brilliant.
There's lots to be done then that's really useful.
But how does it work with curves.
Well it works almost the same.
So we've got our curve laid down here.
Let's have a look now at the moment.
If we rotated this around its origin it would look a tiny bit silly but let's have a look down on it.
Let's go into edit mode because we want to leave the origin where it is and let's say we put that there
and left this part of the handle up slightly.
Oh sorry.
The control point and then move the handle down to something like that.
Okay.
So in this curve we've got a lot of information as we know when we made the base.
Now do we need that much information.
Well let's go into our curve data and lower the resolution of the curve.
Now ASP at 1 It's just a straight line and at some point we will lose the amounts of data that we need
to convey that line and it looks like it's five or six.
So I'll leave it like that.
Now let's go ahead to our modifiers and add in the modifier that's the screw modifier OK that looks
not very good but we can see it starts and ends exactly where the curve data is.
So how about the X if we look at this and we've kind of set it up to rotate around the x axis.
So let's try but look at that we've got a lamp coming together.
Now look at this edge.
It's pretty jagged.
Maybe we can increase the steps.
Maybe we don't want to do that.
You could also lower the number of steps and then add in a subdivision surface modifier and increase
it that way.
There are many ways that you can go ahead making your model look better.
There's no right or wrong here.
But do keep an eye out.
If you've got your objects selected.
See we've got 5000 triangles here.
If we have it set that high.
So from one subdivision it's 320 1002.
Oh blimey it goes up so so quick.
But if we turn that down again or even turn it off and then just say increase the steps to 32 looks
pretty smooth now.
And we're at 320 without adding any extra information along here.
That's the curve resolution if we then for a little bit jacket.
On this side we can just increase that independently.
And that's basically changing the overall topology of our model if we put it into wireframe we can see
exactly what's going on here as we increase and decrease.
And of course as we talked about earlier we want to try and make this is balanced as possible rather
than having large you know large changes in the surface of our geometry like that.
So looks like perhaps around six makes all of these nice and uniform also.
So with that comes your challenge okay.
So this is going to be a relatively straightforward challenge because I simply want you to create your
lampshade using the screw modifier.
Now one of the things that I'll say at this point in time is there's no need to add a bone yet or link
it to the armature in any way because we're not quite at the stage.
There are a couple further modifiers that we're going to use to finish off the geometry of our lampshade
first and then come back and we'll rig it later.
And then finally I'd like you to add some materials to your model so far so I know certainly my lower
arm and my upper arm that have any materials applied.
And of course this lamp I'm going to think I think I'm going to make it match the base itself.
So go ahead pause video now and give that a go Okay everybody Welcome back.
As hop on over into blender and create a lampshade Okay so this is where we left off with our lamp before
let's go ahead and get a view from the side turn on my overlays at the top here and we'll come out into
object mode.
Tape brilliant.
Let's add in a curve a busier curve.
I'm just going to move it to an appropriate location.
I'm going to go into edit mode rotate it.
I think it's gonna be on the x axis.
The y axis.
Yes.
K Well that's pretty big.
Let's go in a rotate.
Bring it round.
I'm just gonna scale it in for the moment.
Bearing in mind we're within edit mode so that's absolutely fine.
Now where the origin is is kind of important.
It's going to dictate where things are moved when we end up using the screw modifier.
Okay.
Let's go to our modifiers.
We're generating new geometry and let's go to the screw modifier.
Oh that's not what we want.
Let's try a different axis.
No that's not what we want.
Well let's try y.
Boom.
Look at that.
That's an almost perfect lampshade without doing anything.
Popham it's in the wrong place.
Because if we just move the data's here it's going to move.
That's why we need to come out and just place it in roughly the right location.
Looks like we're going to have to build up a joint here of some description but that's okay.
We can do that in a bit.
But before we do anything else let's have a look at the detail here compared to the base.
Now we've got this really low poly middle section which could just be metal arms.
You know it's very straightforward to make those into something that looks pretty reasonable for that
but this base and this this low poly ring around there is not undercuts sets.
So there are a couple of ways of obviously sorting this out.
We can add in a subdivision surface modifier.
We've played with that before what happens if we do that.
Yes it's moved out quite nicely.
Of course we've got these two settings here render and viewport so we can just add that in.
That's entirely up to you.
And we can go back to the screw modifier and lower this down perhaps eight steps.
Now obviously gets a bit smaller when you do that.
So that's something to bear in mind but 16 steps produces on this particular item we can have a look
down here.
Seventeen thousand triangles.
That's a lots of information although there's also the curve resolution here that we can bring down
as well so we can have a look at this from the side.
Have a look at the curve resolution and perhaps bump that out to get the rough curve that we want in
here maybe five.
Well we start to lose detail very quickly so let's come back three's too low.
Five or six.
I want to go for six there.
We're down already to 8000.
But then we've got to think we've got this balance here between what the modifiers are doing.
So let's say eight steps.
They're still pretty smooth and little bits of Jack goodness around the edge.
But we've lowered it down.
All we can do the subdivision surface modifier.
It's a tough choice which when we want to go for I'm going to set this up at 32 six relatives relatively
smooth anyway and it's down to 5000 triangles or five thousand eight hundred.
Now that may seem an awful lot for this amount of geometry here but this is absolutely fine.
At this particular model if this was a model that was sat far far away in the scene.
But yes you would want it a lot lower than that.
However this is our main character.
So having them relatively high resolution absolutely fine.
Right.
I'm pretty happy with how that's worked out.
Going to save my work that perfect.
Let's have a look at what it looks like.
Haven't switched it out into.
Look Dev mode for a while.
I think what we can really do here to bring this whole thing together here is a sign our materials as
well because that is part of the challenge.
So let's go ahead.
Let's pick the lamp base here.
Interesting.
So I'm going to call this lamp paints instead.
And then we've got this arm here which we can do lamps them on.
And this one here as well excellent.
So now these all have the same color to them.
It's much easier to see can turn off my overlays here and then I can have a look around my model case.
There's a few details to sort out here but that is looking pretty good now.
I think yes I do want this here to be larger all about proportions and all that is only slightly larger.
I'm going to make sure I apply my scale.
We can just make sure that it is applied by opening up the side bar properties there and then just save
my work.
What does it look like in or in cycles that looks pretty much the same.
There we go.
And as they look there for the moment and work there SAVE MY WORK.
LET'S SEE HOW YOU GUYS ARE GETTING ON please show your work over in the discussions and I'll see you
all in the next lecture.