A guy's welcome to problem solving in this video.
You will realize that starting again is sometimes the best option.
So a little background story here.
I was busy reorganizing my parts.
I accidentally did something and the whole scene just fell apart on me.
And I had a choice at that point do I try and fix the problem or do I just put all the pieces back together
again.
It turns out that after I made my changes to my nave that I had a problem with the scale and position
of a lot of the other bits of my model.
So in essence starting again was actually the best option because trying to move everything else subtly
in between was just not an option.
So we're going to see that even the well prepared scenes can be broken by subtle changes.
Now we're going to get help with problems that you may have run into when making your building as well.
So what we'll do now is hop on over into a blender and just go through some of the annoyances that I
had during the construction of my building especially with modular parts.
There won't be a specific challenge in this section but I would like you to share the challenges and
production methods that you've gone through so we can all share our group knowledge and help each other
out when it comes to constructing more complex items from individual parts.
So let's hop over into a blender.
Okay so I have started a brand new blender far here and reimported all of my pieces.
What happened that made it go horribly horribly wrong is that at some point during the construction
I had hopped into edit mode on my pieces and the origins had moved and the alignment was no longer working
as it should have done.
And when you hop in to edit mode and move your piece you're moving it in it's own local space which
of course means that when you hop out of edit mode all of the other pieces that are linked to that one
also move and your whole scene falls apart rather than trying to fix that problem.
I'm going to build myself a new church with my new pieces and put it all together whilst we're thinking
about how it's constructed.
One of the things we need to take into account is how the pieces actually interact.
You can see here yes they are still only linked models haven't made them proxy yet but we can see where
the corner piece intersects with these other pieces.
We've got a graphical glitch going on.
Now one of the ways of making sure that you avoid graphical glitches like the one in front of us and
tiling problems in general is to either create parts as a whole which is difficult because I like the
idea of having modular.
One of the other things we can do is force the issue.
And what I mean by that is making this corner piece an action bigger slightly.
Then the pieces joined to and that introduces a natural break in the image in the actual geometry itself.
And we don't end up with any overlapping which means if we do need to push apart inside another part
for whatever reason that it's not going to cause a graphical corruption.
So for instance this one here has this funny hash here some scanner save the file that I'm working on
now in the corner pieces of I got a short cut to it.
No I haven't.
Let's go to the corner.
What I can do here.
Is hop into edit mode and actually pull these faces out slightly.
So I'm going to extrude.
I want both of those faces and group strood here by point one doesn't have to be much.
Now this is speculation of how it's going to look but I'm going to be mean about it and try to extrude
this way by point one.
Okay so now the kormos ever so slightly bigger than anything that surrounds it.
I haven't changed the origin or anything else of this model.
Hop out.
That looks okay so far.
And let's go ahead and save it.
Now when we hop back in to our Gothic church in new we see that it's all somatically creates this little
ridge.
Now I can see straight away of it matched up in that way it's going to ruin the door because we got
the door in the window on top of one another there.
But this piece itself is now if we push another bit of geometry into it like a plain wall piece is not
don't complain at least not on this side.
Now we've got to think about the other side which is also going to have some graphical corruption.
Of course we want to make these changes subtle and not make them so they stand out too much.
So one of the other things we can do here and it will vary from model to model is opening up our corner
piece again this is one of our structural pieces is actually taper these outer edges in.
So it's.
So there will be a slight warp in me in the surface itself.
So if we grab this edge here and we're snapping turned on let's and merge vertices turn on and all.
If we snap to a vertex I should be able to bring it all the way in and then that will look like that
from the top.
This is its profile and I'm hoping that's going to look at and again this is all about lean production
We've spotted a problem.
We're going to try and fix it in creative ways or useful ways.
So we've also got the issue on the inside as well.
Now I am going to grab the face here extrude by point one I'm using Point one here as an example it
doesn't have to be of course.
And I'm going to push that corner back into itself so I'm going to move it to there and do the same.
This face here in the extrude it will have hit by mistake and then extrude it by point one and then
push this edge that we can't see if I can select it even through a model.
Note the Happer hop a wire frame to do that and then try and get the right one so that one there.
All this is this is more tricky when you've got it are going to have to do the whole operation in wire
framed so that sume in here and see if we can find the right one.
We're going to move it to that point there.
Okay so now let's have a look around our model in object mode.
It looks okay looks slightly wonky from the top but that's okay.
It will be slightly one key and that should help us when it comes to corner pieces.
Now I don't know how it's going to look it might look absolutely atrocious in which case back to the
design board and we'll remodify it but this will stop me having too many artefacts.
Of course if I push something in into this model so I want a shorter corner piece.
The issue will still be there be there that there will be a tiny ridge here so that doesn't quite solve
that issue.
So anyway enough of me speculating let's see what it's like in action.
So back into here and that looks fine from the outside.
And looks fine from the inside as well.
It's no longer going on top of one another in fact that way it looks like I've skewed it the wrong way.
I wasn't thinking Oh no this is why hopping backwards and forwards is very powerful.
I've put a lip in when I didn't want to let.
I've moved them in the wrong way.
Silly my silly silly silly.
So of course we can go back and correct that and I'll go and do that now and then I'm going to reconstruct
my model because of the fatal error I did earlier where I moved one of these in edit mode and it caused
the whole scene to fall apart i literally destroyed my church in a few clicks.
The other thing that changed the fundamental design of the church was the vault itself.
I didn't realise quite how this would modify the scene that I'm working on.
As you can see here it's slightly wider than the other one.
This is where the pillars of the church are going to be sat.
And because of the width of it's changing ever so slightly it cause the rest of the model to need to
be have a rebuild anyway compounded with the problem that I created last pose I created the vault as
well.
But compounded with that problem it's going to be far quicker to just reconstruct my church in a very
similar manner to how it was before.
So welcome back.
And I'm in the middle of constructing my tower piece at the moment I just want to show you a really
quick way probably already know about this but might not be doing it.
So I'm going to hold down g and Z and then hold down Shift and move that up to a micro blender unit
so then point ten of a blender unit and I'm going to duplicate this again and move it up on the said
axis and then up another two and obviously I'm doing some micro adjustments here as I go just to make
sure that everything is aligned properly or it's got to duplicate it to GZ up to their GZ.
I didn't need to do that twice.
So I'm happy with that being four stories here.
I can select this and move it down so it's covering up the right.
There we go that's roughly in the right place.
Okay.
So now that's constructive.
But that looks well silly.
So now I've got all the basic pieces in place and you can do this not only with these are used blank
walls and then put wind where I used blank walls I could put a door in here and windows down here.
But now I have done that I'm going to select my blank wall piece which is over here and make sure it's
the active object and of course go control L and make links to the object data and they go replace all
of those parts very quickly.
So you can build up a basic building block very quickly and then just substitute the parts in providing
they all match.
Brilliant.
Now just got to make the rest of the church.
So you guys in a bit.
Okay so finally after moving lots and lots of bits about and making sure they're looking nice in this
hierarchy over here.
So then I can turn off individual parts of the church as I am when it's necessary.
It's all come together rather well and much better than the first attempts at it.
And it's taken a couple of hours to get to this point with all the tweaking and moving and the additional
parts I've utilized a right angle triangle to make a roof section going along there and here and over
on this side.
I've got a right angle triangle just there so that when we're inside the church let's go to fly around
mode.
We can actually have a decent line coming in and not a square like it was just using a wall piece previously
and it just looked absolutely horrible.
Okay this is coming along really nicely.
What problems did you come across when you start adding level of detail to your model.
Did you have to remodel only think.
Did you have to read skaer let me think.
Did you accidentally destroy your model and have to start again.
Don't worry.
We all do it.
It gave guys remember to show your work in the discussions and I will see you guys in the next lecture.