Well, again, in this video, we're working on whiskers and eyebrows for our animal.
Let's start straightaway with your challenge to add some whiskers.
This is a good one to take on on your own before I go through it.
So you can see if you've remembered all the steps in the process and add some hair, some eyebrow hair,
if you like, as well.
Some cats do have some pretty pronounced eyebrows when you have a close look at them.
Some hints if you'd like, some hints if you don't, then pose a video and dive in.
Now, if you want some hints, then be sure to create a particle system first, then set, create your
particle system first, then set the emission to zero.
And hand place each hair as opposed to having the hair randomly spawned by the particle system.
There's no need for children in this particular instance.
We're going to be, like I say, hand placing each individual hair.
And you might want to tweak the hair strand thickness to get the right kind of thickness for the hair.
Maybe it's a bit thicker, maybe a bit thinner than usual.
That's up to you to have a play around with and figure out.
So pause video and take on that challenge.
And after you've done that, I'll go through my approach.
First, they've got to do is just turn off my other particle systems from the viewport here so I can
see more easily what's going on.
And second thing I need to do is create a new particle system from within our particle system tab.
Click on.
Plus, I'm going to rename this to be Whiskers and I'll also rename it within the actual execution of
the particle system to be whiskers as well.
Dishonouring get confused.
Click on hair change.
The hair length down two point three I think might be a good size.
Now, as I said, the challenge going to change the number to zero.
There they were young, we have none.
Excellent.
Good job.
Next up, we will hop over in to particle edit click on plus to add more particles.
I'll turn off interpolate for the moment.
I'll turn that back on soon.
I'm working with the middle the point selection mode, the middle of these buttons here so that I can
see all the points.
I think that works better.
Now where do we start off our heads.
I'm going to be starting off.
My hair's kind of not right on the outside of this face area, but a little bit more on the inside so
that then we can see the hair going across.
Let me show you what I mean by that.
Add one down there.
Pretty good.
Now I will comb comb to the side and the hair generally at the top is more heading straight out.
And then as we go down, it curls more and more downwards.
So we'll add a few of these initial hairs.
Click on plus add another one.
Just drop the size of my brush a little bit.
Plus loves having turn on interpolate.
Let's click on Interpolate.
So that is heading generally in the right direction.
Yep.
Yep, yep.
Okay, I'll start off with four.
I'm going to do each side independently rather than trying to mirror this.
I think that's gonna work best.
I will need to comb this one over there.
Karl, just quickly add a few more of these.
And I think I need to make them a little bit longer.
Going to my lengthen brush.
OK.
Lincoln Lengthen, lengthen.
Now, little bit of grooming just starting off with these four.
And then I'll probably end up with about, I think eight or nine on either side would be nice.
Caven, grab this one.
It's gonna be going.
Atwood's straight out.
Straight out.
And then droop down.
Drew down.
Tore down.
The middle ones tend to be a little bit longer than the bottom ones and the top ones I find okay now
and repeat the same process on the other side.
Like I said, you could mirror this, but I think I like to have a little bit of differences as well,
a little bit of uniqueness on each side.
I don't want them to look exactly like they've been cloned, which is check the forwardness of them.
I'm not exactly sure.
Or a little bit leaning backwards.
Yeah, that's right.
So that requires a little bit of readjustment of these.
So once again, imagine that your cat is running through a wind tunnel and we want to have all the hair
systems behave appropriately.
They're not gonna be pointing forwards because that would not be very aerodynamic, would it?
Now, dropping another couple interpolate on.
Yes.
Good.
One more at the back there.
One more front the side.
Little bit of messiness in there is a good thing.
That last one is going to overlap.
They tend not to overlap hair.
The whiskers on cat, they tend to have their own lane that they swim in, if that makes sense too.
So we don't, we don't cross the streams.
This is very Ghostbusters where the hair just sits in its own lane and one or two that just sort of
tend to dig right down.
OK, now let's get our color figured out for this, so I will go to a different view.
Back over to object mode.
Okay.
Looking pretty thick as well.
But let's get the material sorted first.
I click on material.
Click on plus add a new material, new to create it being new.
Rename this to the let's see whiskers going to change it from principled b.
B SDF to principled hair.
B SDF.
Give ourselves a little bit more room on our shader editor.
And I'll change the color to be a pretty light, very white ish kind of color.
Little bit of gray in there, so it's not too popping and back to our particle system.
We need to under render change the material to be whiskers.
Excellent.
Also going to within here in render increase the steps up to seven.
Seven.
And in the viewport display as well, the Strand steps.
I'm going to increase to seven.
Okay.
I think some of these down the end aren't curving downwards in us.
I need a little bit of work on that.
And you can see it's looking very kind of translucent See-Through through.
So if you play around the roughness and the coat to get to the point where you're happy with that,
you could go just regular BSD.
If we go the hair BSD.
If you don't go, have to go principled here.
The SDF.
But we do get a lot of controls this way.
You can see this is a great place to see actually just with a few strains and not much else going on.
If we increase the roughness all the way up then.
It's a little bit less See-Through.
If we reduce the roughness all the way down, then we do get that translucency, which is kind of interesting
look, but not exactly what a cat's gonna have for whiskers.
And then again, radial roughness.
You can see that gives it a much flatter look versus if we have that all the way down to zero.
Then once again, it has a very See-Through look.
So play around with those values until it gets the point where you happy with the relationship between
the See-Through hardness or the transparency, if you will.
And the opaqueness, some reasonably happy with that, what I do need to do is change the thickness,
I think, because the cat whiskers are very long and thin.
So let's scroll down, scroll, scroll down and find hair shape.
I think I'll change mine to values of point six and point two sets a little bit fatter at the tip,
but a little bit thinner at the root.
And just do a test render on that.
OK.
They're looking very white.
Kind of looks like a spider is jumped on the face, looking little bit fake at the moment.
So we'll see if we can do a little bit to that.
It could have to do.
I've got a bit too much roughness going on here.
I might decrease the brightness of the color a little bit.
Well, just have them blend in a little bit more.
And I'm going to do a little bit of tweaking to the positions.
OK, I'm reasonably happy with this.
You can see there's a lot of Faid over in the outer area of my whiskers, but that's okay.
I don't mind that whiskers tend to do that if we look at this cat over here.
There's a real kind of dark whiteness when it's boarded or when when it's backed up by the face.
But then when it's got the green grass behind it, hopefully you can see that on your screen.
It kind of fades out.
It comes out more translucent.
So I'm happy with that general direction.
Next, I'm gonna put some eyebrows on my cat.
Let's get a little bit of inspiration from our reference images up in the top part, right above the
eyes.
Just got a few strands poking out.
What about this guy?
Bit hard to see in that image.
What about this guy over here?
Our guy kind of scraggly, pointing forward and with the high brow hairs, are they eyebrows when they're
that long?
I whiskers, whatever they're called, similar size.
So they're similar size and shape to the whiskers.
So that's why I think I'll do exactly the same particle system, if not create a new particle system.
So I going gonna place a couple of eyebrow hairs.
So this is the end result of what I've come up with.
I could probably make the eyebrow whiskers a little bit more prominent and you can see there's a little
bit of kind of white and then not white throughout.
If we zoom in really close here.
But that's the general texture.
If we have a look at our reference images, the eyebrows and the whiskers tend to jump in and out of
being visible and not visible.
In particular, when you can see the whiskers with some body behind it, they're a lot whiter and they're
a lot more see through a translucent when it's just background behind it.
So I think we've hit that reasonably accurately and looking pretty good, pretty happy with that overall
look of the whiskers, so.
Great stuff.
I'll see you in the next lecture.