Hello everybody and welcome to this quick tip on the blender model scale and what do we mean by that.
Well put simply if this cube here represents in a building but we had everything set to millimeters
that would be bad.
That would be the wrong scale to have set up meters would be much more appropriate if we were making
a,
An oil tanker working in millimeters would be the wrong scale to use.
Now I'm obviously interchanging here millimeters and meters.
You can use inches and feet if you want and we can do that over on the side panel here.
So if we go to the properties panel and go down to the scene view.
So we're setting the units for the entire scene.
That's important because you can have multiple scenes within blender with different units.
So no go ahead and click on the scene here and we'll see that we've got an option here for units if
we click on that it gives us a couple of options.
The one that we're mainly concerned with at the moment is the unit system at the top.
So if we go ahead and click on that we end up with Imperial metric and none.
Now if you use the blender in the past it used to come with no units and by default it would translate
those in the background one blender unit would have essentially been one meter so you can switch between
imperial and metric.
And once you've done that you can change your length settings here.
So micrometer's, millimeters, centimeters, meters, etc
Or if we're in imperial you can switch between thousandth of an inch,Inch,Feet
Miles and adaptive which is an interesting one.
Now in general you want to pick this for your project and work on it.
Now in general I would recommend working in S.I. units.
It just means that everything is uniform and the majority of the time you'll be working roughly in a
metric scale of around 2 meters the human body sort of size.
And so everything is a good starting point from that.
And that's what I'm going to do throughout this course I'm going to be mainly focused on the metric
and under the imperial system of course you can have your pound just stone.
I've never heard of a centum weight.
There we go.
I'm learning something.
But here we go this is where you get to this area here and to be quite honest it will probably depend
on what you're used to working with but what's really important is if you're working in a team you will
want to make sure that you're all using the same units.
And remember what you've set here because you may think you're working a much larger scale than you
actually are.
And that will cause you some issues you can see here that this cube that once was two meters across
is now six foot something across because we've changed it to feet.
So the uni,
The units that you create your objects in.
In this case it was a to me to buy two meter cube by two meter.
We can see if I switched back to metric.
It fits perfectly in that meters.
If I switch to centimeters again it sits perfectly there but the numbers that i then type in would
default to centimeters if I go to Imperial you can see it changes the scale along the side here and
the scale of this underlying grid and then if we go ahead and go add new mesh objects a cube and here
we put two in.
You can see this two foot cube is significantly smaller.
I've just clicked away or hid it.
There we go.
It's significantly smaller.
So if you thought you were creating another two by two meter cube and you weren't when you went and
imported that into another scene you'd have loads of conversions.
So make sure ever you've selected you stick with for what you're working with.
Don't mix up imperial and metric stick with either one or the other.
Now when it comes to actually picking say you wanted to stick with Imperial for the rest of the course
that's absolutely fine and working in feet.
What you can then do is go to file save your start up file and then you don't have to worry about setting
it to Imperial every time because by default it will be a metric.
And of course I'm going to be working in metric as I've mentioned.
So I don't need to do that.
But if you do want to make sure that any of the settings that you've got a permanent every time you
open up blender for all new blend files you can go to file and save your startup file just a word of
warning.
If I saved it with these two cubes in the scene well those two cubes will be there every time you start.
So make sure you've got a bland scene a basic scene that you want to start with.
So I often play about go load up General again tweak the settings that I want to tweak and then save
my start up file from there.
So occasionally I've removed the default cube from the scene because I haven't been using it much but
it always seems to come back.
I love that default cube anyway that's the end of this quick tip and I'll see you all in the next lecture.