Welcome to good meche topology.
Now first of all what is meche topology.
Will two objects can have the same shape themselves yet have a different mesh construction a different
arrangement of polygons making those up topology can determine how easy it is to edit or animates an
object.
If you've made something out of triangles it's going to be a lot harder to edit if you've made something
out of quads and we'll go through why in a bit.
Now in general you said this before used quads wherever possible end ons and triangles would typically
cause pinching.
In your model.
Now that's fine if it's hidden out of the way or on something that doesn't move or indeed where pinching
is desired but often it's not desired we want to avoid it whenever possible.
So let's go have a quick look at different apology's with the same shape and hop on over into a blender.
So here we are in blender and I've got three layers all with three spheres on it.
This is this simple example as I could possibly think of to demonstrate this.
I've got Layer 1 2 and 3 as you can see the ball changes slightly in its shading etc. There may be a
scaling issue there but they all look the same and you can't tell their construction by just looking
at the shape.
Now if I were to go into edit mode on this you see that this one is made up of quads all the way around
it and what that means is if we're in face select mode I can start selecting rings around it very easily.
These face loops going round without any problem whatsoever and that has a great impact when editing
because you can edit a lot at once.
If we have a look at perhaps one of the other spheres we have here the same on the second layer.
By hop into edit mode.
On this you'll see that it's a uv's Sphere.
It comes to a pole at the top so similar to the last sphere.
I can still select some rings going round.
I can select the all these face loops going around here and the face loops going up and down but you'll
notice that I can't reach the top or go all the way around so that one is almost as useful as the previous
one.
However you will notice that the squares themselves the quads aren't particularly.
Even they change in size quite dramatically from these small narrow ones at the top to pretty square
ones in the middle and if we hop over to the previous one you'll see that pretty much all of these quads
are the same size across the entire model.
And that also makes it nice and easy to model with.
To work with.
Especially if you're sharing files with other people.
It's very important that we get topology right so someone else can pick it up and work with it.
The final example I have here is a nother spear and you probably already guessing it is sent IKO sphere.
Now this would be an absolute pain in the backside to try and work with.
Because if we try and select any loops there aren't any because every single join is a pole and if we
remember going back a pole is basically where edges joined together and we can see here there are 1
2 3 4 5 6 joining this particular vertex here in the middle and Ideally we just want quads so the flow
of edges goes round one way and round another.
Now occasionally we can have five or three joining together will discuss that further along in this
section.
Now it's not all about quads now.
Quads are very important but it's topology that defines a Faces key shape or any objects shapes the
edges.
In face loops will follow the general features around one's face or any particular object that your
modelling loops will help with the editing and we'll see that in great detail coming soon and loops
will help with defamation an animation so if you wanted to make your character smile or frown if you
were trying to do it it was a triangular mesh.
It would be a lot more difficult to do.
Now I've got a couple of examples here all made with quads.
Now on the left we have bad even though it's all made up with quads in general.
None of these air edge loops or face loops follow the actual features of the face.
If we have a look over on the right hand side we can see that the eyes are defined with a loop going
round them.
So is the mouth.
In so is the whole face itself.
And there's one on the ear as well.
If we have a look at going a bit further from this so we're going as a very low poly model there.
If we then go to the next step up you can see that these features are defined even more.
There's a ring running round the nose.
You can definitely see that in this second example here you can see the ones going Rammy eyes.
There's one big one going around the cheeks and round the face.
And of course the mouth is as a well is well defined by these rings or loops going round.
And that is what's really important now can be quite challenging to do that and will go through the
construction of each part of the face in detail and giving you some tools as we go but it's very important
to realize that it's not all about quads.
It's also how you arrange them.
Okay guys it's Challenge time.
I'd like you to go ahead and plan your topology.
Now knowing how you're going to create your model is very important.
So that's what this challenge is all about.
I'd like to go and get your reference material and mark out the key features and draw on the main face
loops running around your model balls a video now and give that a go.
Okay guys.
Welcome back.
Let's go have a look at my reference material and let's have a look at where the facelifts will be.
Okay so in front of us we have a photo of me.
Now one of the key areas will be around the mouth.
So let's go ahead and draw a loop around the mouth.
Now there also be a loop around each eye.
Now those are pretty well-defined and easy to spot.
So there we go we've got the loops running around there.
Now of course we've got another loop that defines the entire face itself.
So we go all the way around.
And we're mainly focussed on the front of our face at the moment so we've got one that runs around that
area.
There now because of planning these things it helps us work out how we're going to construct our model.
Now the is we can't really see from this angle so I'm going to focus on those.
There are a couple of loops that run around because it's in intertwining loop and the is quite complicated
and will go home for that in more detail.
Now the nose itself is going to be a loop that runs around the bottom around there around that sort
of area.
And there's one more loop as it runs along the top of the bridge of the nose around there and then runs
down to the chin and back up again.
And that helps us control our model because that encompasses all the areas where the muscles would be
moving the skin underneath.
Now this is our only one way of doing this if you weren't moving certain parts you wouldn't have to
do all of this in the amount of detail you include.
Again it will vary depending on the model you're doing going to make it quite a basic model to begin
with.
So then we can develop past skills without getting too deep and complicated and time consuming.
Remember from the last section the more detail you need to do the longer it's going to take.
And I would rather go through six or seven models and it take me a day or two to do than do one model
it take me a week and I haven't learnt all of the skills by the repetition going through making these
models.
So don't be afraid to make more than one.
So those are my loops that I'm going to concentrate on when I start making my model.
How did you define your loops.
Did you get all of these in here.
Did you miss a couple.
Were you surprised about the one that goes across the bridge or around the tip of the nose.
Please share.
As always in the discussions and I will see you guys in the next lecture.