Welcome So quickie explode.
Well what is Kabuki explode.
Well this may be all you need if you want something quick and explosive.
Of course now it can be used also as a starting point especially if the type of explosion it gives you
is what you want.
Now we will explore what it is actually doing for us in the background as well.
So without any further do let's hop straight on over and explore the quick explode in blender.
Okay so I've opened up a brand new blender file here and one of the first things I'm going to do is
I'm going to create another window and I'm going to change it to a time line.
The reason for this is it's going to give us control over the start and end frames and some playback
buttons as well.
Now it's kind of like an animation.
But usually physics is involved.
And physics has to go from frame to frame to work out what is going on.
And later on you'll see that this can be incredibly computationally heavy if you decide to do too many
things at once.
So you do have to be careful when it comes to doing anything with the blender physics engine just like
you have to be careful if you subdivide too many times.
It just really taxes the computer.
It will look like you've locked blender up.
But in fact it's just busy thinking about stuff anyway so first of all let's go ahead and use the quick
explode function.
Now you can get to the quick explode function through a couple of ways.
My favourite is by hitting space and time burning quick.
Explode as you can see I've been practicing.
So if I go ahead and typing quick you can see that it.
We also get quick smoke quick fur and quick fluid as well.
Now we're just going to pick quick explode.
Now what's happened.
Well I can see over in the outliner that's a spanner has appeared or a wrench which means to some modifiers
have been applied.
We see that a particle system and then explode modifier have been added to our scene.
Okay that's that's a good start.
Now let's just go along to the particle system okay.
It's a hundred I don't know whether that's going to make a difference.
Probably not physics and no physics is enabled at the moment.
We'll get into physics in another lecture.
So looking at these modifiers we can see that it's going to cuts the edges for a nice end nice as shrapnel.
Okay.
So this can give us an idea of what it's going to do.
And it looks like it's cutting edge along here.
I don't know how many pieces it's going to explode into.
Let's go ahead and press play.
Okay.
And it seems to break into two pieces.
And also after 50 frames we can see that's there's really nothing else to do something to change.
My end point to 50 frames now looking at the time frame itself here the timeline.
Now we've got this red bar moving along here and that is cached information.
So when we go and change something what blender does is actually play it through it caches those changes
it caches the movement of what's happening when the thing explodes.
It happens in a similar way as well if you use the physics engine which we'll see later on.
Now what is happening is it's not remembering so it doesn't have to do the calculations again and again
and again as it plays through.
Now as you can see up in the top here we got frames per second at twenty four which is great because
I believe that's what the whole scene is setting.
So we've got it just breaking into two pieces.
Now that's not very exciting.
Now we really want it to break in to lots and lots of pieces.
And of course that lines us up now for a challenge.
I would like you to go ahead and make some smaller pieces please.
So use whatever method you'd like to make the cube explode into smaller pieces.
Pretty straightforward.
Give it some thoughts.
Pause the video now and give that a go.
Okay guys.
Welcome back.
Let's hop back over into blender and make it explode into smaller pieces.
Okay welcome back.
So we've got our cube here just really splitting into two are not doing anything exciting.
I've got to stop that animation because it's a wee bit dull and I'm going to go back to frame one.
Well we'll see.
Frame 1 it's already broken apart.
Let's go back to frame 0.
So if we wanted to go in too many pieces it wouldn't be logical.
If we had many pieces for it to go into.
Okay so let's go ahead and go into edit mode.
And I'm literally going to enable the tool shelf go to the specials menu hit subdivide specials with
the W key and hit subdivide elam is going to increase the number of cuts I'm going to go all the way
up to 10 which it will allow and of course you can go in and type the much higher number if you wanted.
And I'm just going to leave it at 20.
Now hopefully that's not too many we can have a look up here.
It's generated 5000 Triangle's that's fine if you sargen here up into millions you're probably going
to slow the computers down massively.
Okay guess now we've done that let's hop out our into object mode and let's go ahead and play back and
see what happens here.
Now that looks a lot lot better.
The pieces seem quite big vote.
That's interesting that the pieces do seem quite big.
Let's see subdividing it any more makes a difference.
Also see if just using a subsurface division modifier would have done the same thing because I do like
to keep things so that you can edit them are much easier.
And of course with 20 subdivisions that's not going to be easy to edit.
So let's go ahead and explore a different way of doing this now.
It's going to hit the UNDO key.
In fact I'm going to hit the UNDO key so we get rid of the quick explode around there where it's broken
it in two.
And let's go ahead and go to the subdivisions.
Surface modifier over in the modifiers tab now where it happens to be in the chain.
May make a difference.
Some just gone up the view counts to four.
And let's see if anything happens.
Okay so it literally breaks into what looks like a burger bun in two.
Let's shift this up.
To the very top hat.
Excellent.
So we can see here that we can go back to the simple as well so it remains a cue ball.
We can do the cat mould Clark and.
Well that's doing something.
So I think there's a much better way of doing it without cutting things up.
Now we ski we can see here that as we increase the subdivisions all the frames per second is dropped
right down.
10.
You see that because we've added a lot more information.
But there does seem to be a finite amount that the explode will cut these up into pieces so if we go
back to one or sarino subdivisions it pretty much cuts in if we go to one subdivision I can't count
all those pieces.
I don't want to but it's less pieces than if we go to every go the 3 We seem to get even more pieces.
But after that it doesn't seem to get any more finer It doesn't get into space or dust or the very small
debris.
So it's worthwhile knowing that we'd have to play even more of the settings to get that sort of effect
going on.
Okay.
Brilliant.
We've just done a quick explode.
It's useful for certain things.
Obviously there's a lot more to be done with this and we can explore that later on.
Until then I will see you guys over in the next lecture.