Hello everybody and welcome back in this lecture.
We're gonna have a look at Non planar geometry is not something that you're going to come across that
often but when you do it can be a real pain to try and sort it out.
If you didn't realize what was going on and to really accentuate what's going on in solid shaded mode
I'm going to use the drop down on the right hand side and turn on cavity.
What this will do is it will add a ridge and a valley to some parts of our model really emphasising its
shape.
I'm going to delete the cube and since we're talking about planes let's just add in a single mesh object
that's a plane and scale it up.
So we shouldn't see any shadows or anything special to do with a plane.
So what does non plane the geometry actually mean.
Well at the moment all of these four vertices that make up this single plane pass through this same
plane which means that we get a nice flat shaded quad.
Now if we wanted that to be a slightly different shape I could go into edit mode grab of one individual
vertex and start moving it.
So if I go G, Z the moment that I move it it is now non plainer.
So the quad exists but how does this shape come about.
So I'm really emphasizing it at this point and we can see we've got this diagonal line going across
it now and it's it's kind of guess that that's kind of the shape that it's going to have interesting
what happens if I grab this one and lift it up even higher.
We can see that it's created a valley between the two so it's decided blender has decided that that's
where it will bend it will fold it will cut and you will get that horrible line going down it.
Now it may be a line that you want.
However I've seen scenes or so especially in a game engine where this has happened where you've got
non planet geometry and it's supposed to be a flat surface and you end up with this horrible Triangle.
This shading artifact running across the surface of your model.
Now obviously I've lifted this up quite an extreme amount.
However if it was lower down you can see also has that issue and that's something that is important
to be aware of when you're making anything that's flat shaded.
Now one way around this is to use the edge split modifier but something that I found a lot easier to
manage is to actually have all of your models smooth shaded.
So if I come out into object mode and shade smooth this line will still be here for the moment because
we're deliberately emphasizing the cavities.
So we'll turn that off if we go into rendered mode.
It does look like it's shaded smooth but let's zoom out a little bit further.
Let's not have a single plane but a real object.
So we have a cube in our scene now.
Let's go into edit mode and grab this top page and just lift it up ever so slightly.
Now if we turn on smooth shading we get a horrible looking cube because we're trying to smooth shade
something that isn't smooth.
It's got these sharp angular edges.
If you do have something like this what you can do is go down to your mesh data properties go down to
the normals dropdown and turn on the auto smooth feature.
This will solve not only that horrible shading artifact that we have when we're doing this low poly
modelling but also this will help cover up any non plainer geometry.
And since all of our models are made up of quads like the top of the queen's crown we want to make sure
that any triangles that do appear are deliberate ones not ones that actually spoil the look of our model
completely and that's it for this quick tip on non planet geometry.
If you do end up having triangles appearing on your quads shading your object's smooth and then going
to the mesh data properties and setting your normals to auto smooth and you may have to adjust the angle
the special on some of the pieces but that should solve any extra artifact that you do not want in your
final model.
That's it for this lecture and I'll see you in the next one.