Welcome to reviewing your work objectively.
In this video we will take an objective look at our model and see what is missing.
Hopefully not too much.
It's just some tweaks that need doing but we'll find out.
So first of all will be any improvements to the modelling itself.
Now modelling is important that we cover this one first because the second one.
Any improvements that need to be made to texturing Well it's reliance on the model itself if we change
the model dramatically the UVB map or change and if the UV map will change well the textures will change
as well.
Or will need to be changed to match the V map.
So that is something that needs to be considered before making any major changes.
If you decide to put in some creases here and there just to accentuate form that's probably not going
to make too much difference to the overall you v map so don't worry about that.
However if we decide to move an eye socket or the nose Well that's going to probably need another U.S.
map creating from it and the texturing update it.
Now finally the lighting and environment.
Now we've got a three point lighting set up at the moment and that is working really well.
However if you wanted to experiment with different lighting which can dramatically change the overall
feel and look of your model remember to take a copy of those lights and then move those around and then
you can switch between those two lighting groups and see the different effects it makes rather than
moving your current lighting and losing the position of it.
And finally the environment.
Well in this particular case we can go with a plane or graduated environment.
I mean I'm going to work with that plinth that we have there.
But to be quite honest we just want the focal point to be our bust.
We do not really want to have a messy environment or at an exaggerated environment's going to be plainsong
and it probably stick with the black background.
Just so the model stands out from it.
So let's go and hop on over into blender and take an objective look at our model.
Okay so I've gone ahead and rendered out my model to see what it's going to look like.
Once we start doing that so once we start getting to the full details and I'm quite happy with the skin
colour and everything but there's something that strikes me.
First of all there's a really harsh shadow down this eye and I don't like that something I have to move
my lighting around slightly.
Perhaps having the main light directly in front of the face and then feel like slightly to the side.
That's that's the first thing I'm going to try in terms of the lighting.
Terms of the modelling.
Well I am pretty happy with the overall model here.
There's nothing that stands out as horrible and there's a little dimple in here but again that's an
under under here that's absolutely fine because skin is not smooth.
And that leads me on to something that's very very glaring.
Is this paint brush working.
Because I'd like to be able to draw on this if possible.
I've got you on soft and at the moment I'm going to go to drawing so I can actually draw what's going
on in my mind.
So these particular highlights I think are about right but they're really telling us a story of how
smooth the skin is.
And certainly this person that I've modelled here in myself I don't have baby soft skin anymore is not
super smooth so the cheek here should have a bit of texture to it.
And I think what's missing from our model is a nice normal map now going in the modelling all those
creases is quite time consuming that's one way that you can do that you can go ahead and model in all
the little dimples and creases and that might actually be the fastest way of getting around this particular
issue.
If there's a texture that um I can apply to the surface and then use a another map like I've done with
the specular map or the glossy map to say where that texture applies and where it doesn't.
That's another way of working it.
Now of course I need to be careful with the node set up and everything else there.
So there are a couple of ways of doing that.
Now whether you go the sculpting route and then baking the Normal's or whether you go the texture route
and then converting it to a bump map or a normal map from there you can get pretty similar results you'll
have more control obviously if you manually sculpt in than if you just use textures.
So there's a time penalty for doing it one way but there's a realism penalty for doing it another.
So it's time now I've had an objective look at this particular model.
Is there anything else before I go on.
Well the lips themselves are quite smooth and lips aren't smooth if you have a look at reference material.
They have lots of fine lines in them.
Certainly there's even I've added freckles here it turns out on the full render they're not coming out
too well.
I mean there's someone for head here.
And to be quite honest they just looked like smudges.
So there's work to be done on that diffusely there as well.
Perhaps just bringing them out that little bit more imp maybe even being a bit more prominent with them.
I was thinking Oh I don't want them so bright badgely we mix everything together like we've done.
They're not quite as prominent as I thought they were going to be.
So it's time for a challenge.
I'd like you to go ahead and assess your model so use reference material I know have said this a lot
but it is important.
If you are unsure or if something doesn't look right you're going to be able to see and compare from
that and take a close look now at the level of getting detail right.
You really do need to see where the skin folds where it changes in texture and how it changes in texture
as well.
Share your work with the community and get their feedback.
We've got a whole course of wonderful people we've got the community site as well that you can just
come to post to staff and ask for feedback and people will gladly give it as well.
Now remember to go ahead and make the changes you want to do.
I know mine at the moment looks more like a plastic doll than it does a human.
And that's because it's too smooth.
That's the major issue I have with my model at the moment so I'll be working on creating a normal map
or certainly a bump map and using a normal node to make the skin more textural.
And remember do one thing at a time and assess the change has it done what you thought it would.
So that's very important if you if you go make 20 changes and it doesn't work out how you wanted it
to.
We don't know which one of those 20 changes might have been the one that caused everything else not
to work the 19 beforehand might have been perfect.
So it very important that you take things one step at a time.
Now as on doing the normal map for instance I'm going to be looking at handing it stage by stage.
I might just.
Do the cheek or the fore head or something along those lines.
Just one area of the face and then seeing if it's made the right effect.
If it has brillion I can get on with the rest of the model as well.
So go ahead pause a video now and give that a go.
Okay guys welcome back.
Let's go ahead and make those changes to the models.
Okay so I've started going through and adding a bit more detail to the inside of the eyes.
I've literally just been sculpting for a while.
Hot Hand then what.
Let's make this fit my screen properly.
There we go.
And then I've also started adding some micro detail to the lips themselves literally.
Again just sculpting.
Well the approach I'm going for here is I believe it's going to be easier to sculpt this detail and
have much more control over it then trying to use textures and masks because I can literally use textures
in a moment.
Well let's do a live example here and hopefully let's save my file before Heidi it is experimentation.
Let's go to the textures themselves and go to a brush mask.
Well let's go to let's say Clay strips and then texture.
Go to the brush or the brush mask it doesn't matter.
Depends which way you want to go about it.
And here the type I'm going to set of or annoy.
Now I don't know what scale this is going to be at the moments and no good.
Let's make sure it's applied.
So in the tool shelf texture Yeah and texture is there and it doesn't look to be working just yet.
Let's try a different one let's try not inflate and deflate.
Let's try all whereas it sculpting draw no texture of air yet that's shoes the foreign texture.
So let's make it a little while let's make this bigger.
Okay so we can see the size of it there is that's going to be quite a skin graft or an alien skin.
So if you'll go in for that type of effect you can and obviously the bigger and more pixellated or the
the chunky that texture is going to be.
So what we need to do here is scale it down now.
I believe there's a scaling here so this is one of these things where you actually increase the size
to make it smaller.
So let's try a hundred and see how that turns out.
Bear in mind that this will change depending on how Zumas you are you mean so something like that will
be completely different to something on those lines.
And that's getting there although the strength of that is far too strong we can see it's really pulled
the skin quites are lots and we don't want that.
So let's zoom out.
Let's try just a little bit higher than that.
Try five hundred five hundred five hundred Okay.
And then finally up here.
Let's lower the strength down to maybe 20 percent.
Okay.
I'm starting to like Fats.
Quite a bit.
And of course you can make things wrinkly.
And then of course smooth out the detail as well if necessary to make it not so wrinkly in place.
It's a case of us actually working out relatively well obviously resumes and but we get the whole face
looking very horrible would happen to me if I stayed in the sun for too long.
So obviously you can go for an extreme effect like this.
And in fact whilst we see this extreme effects I'm going to go ahead now because we're actually altering
the model I don't need to bake this into a texture.
Obviously if you were now exporting this you would take this as a normal texture.
So you it can be reapplied to a low poly model but since we actually have a well it basically alive
and ready to go under the rendering settings because under render under the vomity rez it's also air
force so we get the full benefits.
Let's just have 12 and see what that ends up looking like and I'll see you guys back once this is rendered
out.
So as expected it has had a relatively extreme result.
We just saw my windows out here.
Let's bring this one across.
Can I do that.
Yeah.
There we go.
So we've got a relatively textured surface to a model now.
In fact it's been so extremely in places with that taste.
You can see by its casting quite a deep shadow on are particular mesh has also taken a while to render
that took nearly six minutes to render So this is where doing the sculpting and working out and perhaps
making a normal mat from it.
We should see a render time improvement because it's not having to handle all of the geometry.
So in this particular scene itself there's one point four million trying goals which is quite a bit
there's 700000 births he so as to render all of those out the less vs. It has to do the better and having
a look at the lips.
I'm quite happy with those.
They've got the the right texture obviously they've been hammered by my silly use of this particular
texture brush but otherwise I'm really happy with how the lips turned out.
So it's time to work a bit more delicately with these particular wrinkles and folds in the skin.
Well I'm going to go off and do that now and I'll see you guys back in a few moments.
Okay so this is the render how it stands at the moment.
It's not a complete render and there's still some further diffused texturing to add in I haven't added
in my wrinkles yet but I have fleshed out my face.
So it's a lot more representative of me.
In this case.
So I noticed when looking from the front if I move round my model here and certainly just put it into
orthographic projection.
My ears dont stick out quite as far from my face as they do normally.
I I have made them in fact so I have had to puff out my cheeks a little as you can see here I've added
in my little double chin.
Well if you're doing something realistic you might as well get there.
So there's just a few.
I'm happy with all the indentations that I haven't made it in my face.
There's a little bit skin texturing to do in terms of the gloss map I just need to refine that where
things are glossy and where things are not.
And another thing that I have done and I almost forgot about when setting up my nodes is that skin is
also translucent so I just take you to my node set up as it is at the moment so we've got these layers.
If we think about them and how much of them come through starting with the deepest layer of the skin
and working up and as we go down this list I have added in a translucent B s the f shader which is also
using the same colour the base colour in the model.
And if we just isolate that self the translucent slits isolate that we see that with the colouring there
it makes it obviously much better than if it is just a plain old white but with the colour there we
can actually see it adds translucency to the areas that need it and when that's mixed in with everything
else that gives a slightly more realistic feeling.
If you don't have the translucency in your model you lack that one fundamental thing about skin.
And that's the fact that it is translucence you need to make sure you tell blender or certainly in the
nodes that is translucent.
So I've done that here and I'm very happy with that so the final thing to do for me at the moment is
just to work on the diffuse textures so I start getting some of the freckles that are through and just
bumping up where things are slightly shiny and where they're not because that's not coming through quite
as well as I'd want it to.
And I'll see you guys back in a few moments.
Okay so after some final tweaks and rendering this is what I'm going to class as my final mesh for the
moment and final textures.
I've worked out what was going on with the gloss shader just in have the right one attached.
For some reason during my creation I had Let's just see here.
I had a head glossy which was just blank and his glossy PRNG and only that one was applying the Course.
Black will mean that that's not there.
So that's why that was missing.
No matter what I tried that should disappear now it's not being used on anything after I've saved and
reopen.
Let's have a quick look at the no set up anything else that I've added since we've last seen.
We've got this bit here we've got the translucency that I've added in.
That's absolutely fine.
What I have done is art the image texture itself.
I've used a hue saturation and value just to tweak my mesh ever so slightly to see if we can see it
in action.
Okay so the bass is here.
Now I've just boosted the colours slightly and given it a slightly more yellow cast to it.
I mean I could boost that up even more to maybe one point.
So if you go to high of course you just look sunburnt as it goes up to a maximum of two.
There are maybe and stretch to 144 and have slightly darkened the model as well.
It was slightly too light.
Okay so after doing those the next thing that I did was I literally plugged in a very annoyed texture.
And made it with a bump note and then plug it into the diffuse the translucent and the glossy notes
and then that gave us a very little bumpy surface across the entire model itself giving us a slightly
textured feel.
But it's never that strong so it's not really seen across the model because we don't colour we want
the the factor there.
So it's is is kind of one of those things that's not seen but is seen.
So you won't see it directly but it does have an impact on the render.
I tried different scales I found that thousands seemed to work for my particular model.
One is obviously you can be big and blocky and won't work at.
And why aren't we seeing it at the moment.
Be a preview that for an I text ulrich's in to almost every went into rendered mode.
Let's boost that up so I tried 10 and obviously it out then work till it tried a thousand and found
that when I zoomed in that gave me the right sort of level of detail around the thousand mark pumped
into the bump and obviously I wanted to make sure here that it wasn't too strong.
I had to play several times.
Checked out the glossy individually because I saw one that would really sparked off and that's a nice
little textured feel across there.
I didn't map that at all I found that once everything was all plugged in it worked rather well.
Brilliant.
Well how did you guys get on How's your head coming along.
As just a few final things that are obviously missing from this model but we can sort those out in good
time.
Of course I'd love to see how are you getting answered.
Do remember to share your work.
And of course as always I will see you guys in the next lecture.