Hello everybody and welcome to another challenge.
Yes it's time to make the last piece the king.
Now I suggest starting from something like the Queen as it's a good starting point although you can
also just start from just the base if you want to.
Now look at your specifications.
Is your king bigger on the base.
Now mine is going to be 4.5 centimeters across the bottom rather than the four for the rest of the pieces
except the pawns which were three.
So with that in mind pause video now and give that to go
Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's hop on over into blender and make our king.
Okay Welcome back.
Let's load up our queen to begin with.
Go file save as king.
Unlike last time.
Okay so we've got a good starting point.
Need to turn on my previous image and then to delete and add back in making sure that the 3d cursor
is in the center of the scene.
Image as a plain pick for King.
Scale it by a lot.
To begin with roughly there and then press s followed by holding down the shift key to move it slowly
into 4.5.
Now it's gonna be relatively easy with this to scale it up to 4.5.
Since we just need to scale it by and I already know this one point 1 2 5 Ah look at that is a rounding
error.
And now to scale it and hold down shift just to get that final bit of so close.
Anyway I'm going to grab this.
Rotate it around on the X axis by 90.
It's just a matter of moving it up.
Now one thing to note here if I go G, Z it will look like it's coming towards and away from us.
That's because at the top here it still said the transform orientation.
Last thing we do is playing with the queen.
Let's remember those settings.
It's going to set that's a global.
And then when I go G, Z guess what it will go up the global up.
OK.
The next thing I want to do is a bit of a tidy up around the top here.
I'm going to go ahead grab all of these faces and what that should do with all of those faces selected
is remove when I delete vertices pretty much all of the spikes the entire top basically so we go extra
delete delete vertices.
There we go.
We end up with something resembling a crown almost there.
Those two areas on linked.
We can do that now with a bridging of edge loops and of course this might all be undone later anyway
but I'm gonna go G, Z and just lift that up.
So we've got the rough shape at the top.
Perfect.
I'm also going to select everything from the top going down so I will select the top vertex there hold
down control and press the number pad plus until we get a little bit further down and just go G ,Z
and lift that's up to roughly the right height.
Looks like we're going to have to do a different amount for different pleat pieces.
So about their analysts lift this up G, Z lift up to about there and scale it out.
Now one of the things you'll notice here is this image is wonky so I'm going to correct that as well.
Well as best I can.
Now if we rotate is rotating about his midpoint which is okay but it's mainly wonky from the bottom
so I'm going to set the pivot points to the 3D cursor before I start moving this from side to side then
I want something that's roughly equal either side which is going to be something like that give or take.
We could argue and pixel peep all night if we wanted to.
Okay.
So all of that is set.
We don't have this called a king yet.
So let's do that.
And modifiers are it's got the boolean.
So we use the bishop to create the queen and that modifier still sat there.
I don't get rid of that and whilst I'm dealing with it hopping to my queen and do exactly the same because
otherwise that might come back to haunt us later.
Back to the King before I start modelling the king itself.
I'm going to apply its new scale.
There we go it's never scaling or scaling transform of one which is a good place to be it's roughly
the right height as well about nine and a half centimeters.
It's probably going to be a little bit taller by the time we put the cross on the top.
So let's go to our object properties scroll down display as wire so we can see through and then providing
we go ahead and select edge loops we should be able to edit our model also going to change this back
back to individual origins.
No no we don't want individual origins that's going to cause a problem.
Let's go for the medium points.
Individual origins when we start scaling things we could quite easily end up in a bit of a pickle.
So I'm gonna start at the bottom now.
This is one of the one pieces that actually looks like he's got a lip running around the bottom so making
sure we're in edit mode.
Let's add in a loop cuts around the bottom and we go scale that out slightly before coming in.
Now I do want to be careful it's very easy at this point to add in too much detail at certain levels
and when I've been when I have been practicing this particular model it was very easy to run into the
case where it looks different from all of the other pieces because is it's the most important piece
it's the king's are you you tend to find you focus on it's a little bit more and when you do that you
end up with much much more detail in all the wrong places.
Let's go G, Z and lift that up so I'm just hyper aware of that's being a possibility which I don't want
to be honest I want to keep it is low poly as all of the other pieces in fact this area here pretty
neat.
I'm going to come out of it now.
So I've been playing lots.
Has it gone all wonky.
No it hasn't.
Brilliant.
And we select everything and lower the mean crease as well.
Okay.
Now the bottom.
I don't know if there is a face on the bottom it looks like there is.
It's highlighted.
Perfect.
So there would be a hole at some point I'm sure that we'll have to fix looking good.
Okay so it's almost worth adding another loop cut in at some points on here because it's a very tall
piece compared to the others.
It can have a little bit more geometry not too much more but it's a little bit more proportionally more
scale that's in.
And what that will enable us to do is come in and out again.
Okay G.G. good and live up and then scale that in.
And here is one of these examples where I could round off the edge a little bit more but I think it's
going to cause us a bit more pain than it's worth doing.
It's going to end up meaning that our model itself has too much geometry in all the wrong places.
So here I'm going to come out and then straight back in again so I'm going to imitate the fact that
there's something there but not with too much detail.
Again this is a low poly model.
It's very easy to get bogged down with the detail.
This top area here lets, I am going to select the top one and just go control and plus come down and
I'm going to go one level up and just delete the bits at the top there.
Okay.
G, Z lift that up to here.
G, Z about there? That looks pretty good.
Okay.
The next thing here I'm going to scale that all.
Oh no before I do that let's go E, Z.
Lift it up.
Scale that in.
Scale this one in as well add a loop cut to about here and scale that out.
Now this is an area that will have detail and it won't be disproportionate detail because it is still
going to use the octagonal form that we currently have but we're not adding extra curves in.
Now there are loads of ways that we can do this topic her, I'll press the W key instead of the E key, what
I'm going to do is I'm going to go up a little come out and check my model looks good.
Okay.
Let's go back round to the front.
Now focusing on this very blurry image we can extrude all the way up to the top and stop now what we can
do is add in a couple of loop cuts and I'm also going to add in one to begin with and bring it all the
way down so we get a very sharp transition and these two top places are going to be this one and this
one are gonna be all the way over here in a bit.
So we want an odd number so we've got a cut in the middle.
I think that many he's going to be others try it with three cuts I know I tried it with five.
In the example I think I am going to need five tries three not going to need five keep going backwards
and forwards indecision.
Now I can grab this one and this one and just scale it on the Z axis I bring them closer together.
Perfect.
Now I can grab the top edge loop and not quite the bottom edge loop and scale them outwards on oh X
and only X then we can have a look at what that looks like.
Almost there.
But it comes out just in one plane which is pretty useful.
Okay now we need to select these four faces here and to the other side and here and here.
That's a lot smoother than I thought it was going to be.
And I need to extrude by nothing and then scale them out on the X axis.
I was going to do that a different way but because I'd already selected them I couldn't do anything
else and I'm now going to have to select them individually.
Any way to scale them by X, 0 and that should flatten them.
Yes it has.
Okay.
And the same here.
Got a bit of a clipping issue going on I might play with my camera settings if that caused me any issues
again.
Scale X, 0.
Excellent.
So that's flatted those two edges.
And now of course what I can do is scale them up so I need them all selected to do this back round to
the front.
And just scale on the Z axis we get and exaggerate ever so slightly so it fits in with everything else.
Scale them out as well so flares ever so slightly and that should look pretty good.
Yes excellent right.
Right the next thing to do is this bit's on the top.
Now it is a ball.
So one of the easiest things that I can do here is add in a UV sphere and work from that.
Or I could start doing some scaling and other bits and bobs.
I'm going to add in a ball at the 3D cursor roughly where it needs to be and then sets the or the X
value here.
I'm just having a look to 0.
And the Y to 0 because it needs to be smack bang in the middle UV sphere.
That is point 1 radius r.
That's almost spot on.
I did not know how big that would be.
That was a pure guess eight segments.
Six.
Four.
Yeah I think it's gonna have to be four at this point and I'm going to go
G, Z and lift it up go into edit mode.
Yes sorry I'm in edit mode.
It wasn't a new object.
Go back to the selection tool select this bottom one and delete it.
Select this edge loop and this one and bridge them Ooh! I had some extra selected that I didn't want that one
and this one and bridge them.
Excellent.
So now let's just have a quick look Oh what's going on there.
Something where it's brigdged it's cross bridge them at some point which isn't great.
It's very hard to sort out.
So let's hide the image for the moment so we can see what's going on.
I think what I can do here instead is perhaps fill and merge that way.
I do need a bit more camera room so the clip starts I'm going to put down two point one and I should
be able to get really close.
Perfect.
So here we go.
This top bit here.
I'm gonna fill this in and then I'm going to inset on the scale only on  X and bring it back in line.
Now these two should bridge properly.
Excellent.
So the final thing to do here is ooh that's still going to have an interior face.
I want to get rid of that if I can possibly select through this model that's hide that and select the
face on it.
No it doesn't.
Perfect Alt and H to come back out so that looks alright.
It just needs to be a much much more squat now.
So once again select everything here perfect go G, Z and bring it down.
Then this very bottom edge loop here.
I'm gonna.
No not that one.
Not that one.
This one.
Now we go.
I'm just going to scale that in so inside and go G, Z and left.
That's up Excellent.
Now this cross on the top.
I'm going to go G, Z and bring the top down ever so slightly as well.
Give it a bit of a smoother appearance.
I quite like how that's come along now I can play with the rest of this and make it a bit more like
the other one so for instance I can grab the these vertices here and here and go G, Z and just lift them
up ever so slightly giving it a similar appearance to the top.
And again here and here just to give it a bit of a visual consistency G, Z pull it down again it's
only a little and the bottom bit is fine how it is.
Again if you wanted to keep that sort of flaring consistency this one isn't so bad because they are
both in line so it's easy to do with one little tug and there we go.
So there's the cross on top.
Now there is a lot of detail but in the grand scheme of things it's not that's come out save my work.
How do I think that looks.
I think that looks awesome I can't wait to see all of these pieces together.
And I'm also looking forward to seeing your King as well.
Perhaps you approached it in a slightly different way maybe a completely different way.
Make sure you share your king's over in the discussion and how you created them as well.
Have you gone for a slightly different look.
Did you use a completely different modelling technique to share your work over in the discussions and
I'll see you all in the next lecture.