Welcome to a painting in the image ed in this video.
You will create your own image using blender become more familiar with the image editor.
We're about to use it quite a bit in the upcoming lectures will realize Blender's limitations when it
comes to image editing and I understand that you may have to use external packages for better control.
This isn't as powerful as Photoshop nor gimp or any of those other type of packages but it does still
have some great versatility.
So let's go explore this now and start painting over in blender.
Okay so before we go and hop into the image editor and start work out want to show you this set up but
I've got at the moment now I don't have a whack stylus or a cinti or anything fancy like that.
I do however have an iPad and a Mac which means I can use a program called ashtray pad to use the iPad
as a second screen.
Now when I do that I can literally start doing things on the screen itself and it's just mirroring the
other screen.
And this is going to become quite useful for me when I'm sketching now.
By all means you do not need a stylus in order to do any form of graphical art on a computer but it
does make it a lot lot easier.
A bit like having a three button dormouse have make Splender and the 3D viewport so much easier to use
than trying to use a trackpad or a lot of other control interfaces.
My stylus by the way is not pressure sensitive or anything along those lines so I'm not going to be
able to do some of the fancy tricks where if you press harder the lying gets wide or something like
that.
So let's now hop into the image editor and start doing some painting.
Okay so I've just changed my 3D editor to a movie image editor and this is what it looks like.
Pretty boring so far and not much to do.
So let's go ahead straightaway and add a new image.
Now you can do that in the image menu using the shortcut keys.
Oulton n or of course hitting the big new button there and it gives us a couple of options so I'm going
to give my image that I am about to create a name and I'm going to call it test image.
Underneath we have width height colour Alpher blank and 32 bit floats.
Well the width and height.
I'm going to leave those as the phone I suggest you do too.
At the moment.
Later on we'll go in to texture resolutions and what size to pick on where to pick them etc. and what
size to pick them as well.
The colour will just be the cut the base colour that appears in this case it's going to be black I can
say that anything I want and not really important at this point in time either the generated type but
it gives us 3 different types who got blank which is just that solid colour you v grid and colour grid
and we just want it left on blank and click.
Okay now you will see that image now has a star against it which means that it's not saved.
But before we go ahead and save this image I just want to have a look at the properties of the image
editor.
Someone hit the N key to bring up the properties tab.
Now this gives us an option up here to rename our image.
Change the type of image is et cetera et cetera it allows us to change what aspect ratio we've picked
so we can go ahead and change the x and y coordinates.
Now do bear in mind if you do an alter any of.
Do bear in mind if you go and edit any of those after you've started doing some paint with the image.
It will wipe the image because you're essentially overwriting your default settings for the image and
therefore everything will go that you've done and there's no one do that.
Here we have the unique grid and colour grid that we could have selected before and the colour down
here.
We can go ahead and pick any colour we choose on the colour well that's all we going to do in the properties
for the moment some of them are closed down.
I'm going to go and open up the tool shelf because we're going to be using that lots in a few moments
now at the moment we cannot actually do any thing painting wise because we're not in the paint mode
so we need to switch the image editor to paint mode and I'm going to do that where it says view.
I'm going to change that.
Not this view over here.
Keep going all the way over here for the mode selection so much like you've got edit mode sculped mode
and object mode in the 3D editor.
There are three modes here.
We've got view paint a mask we want to switch it to paint.
Okay now we've done that.
We still haven't saved our image so let's go ahead and do that.
Now the first time you save the image you're not going to be able to quick save it as you can and once
it has safe because at the moment it doesn't really exist anywhere except in a blender which is dangerous
because it blender crashes your work that you've been doing will go.
So make sure we off that to a place on our hard disk straight away so I'm going to save azimi And I'm
going to use test image and click save.
Now that this star has gone it's been saved if I make any other changes to this file so I'm going to
literally click and draw something on here.
We see that it's got the star there and I can now use the shortcut key Oulton S and that will save the
file and once the asterisk is gone it means that it is safely stored on the hard drive.
That change I've made.
I can now pick up the file and use it in any other program including blender.
So let's go through the tool shelf now and we're going to focus only on this paint section.
There are a couple of other sections and we'll get to those later on.
But just this top paint section for the moment.
Firstly.
The top one is the brush type and when you click on that you'll see six brushes and wonder why are we
trying to do anything with only six brushes.
Well they're quite versatile brushes and they can be edited and changed quite significantly.
So much like most things in blender.
We've currently got text draw and if we click the two next to it that will create a unique rush.
And now I can call that my brush.
Now the problem with the name mind brushes it means nothing.
So of course you would want to name your brushes appropriately based upon what they do at this point.
It's a demonstration brush so my brush is absolutely fine.
Underneath we have a colour wheel and we can go and move this little white dot around and basically
pick any colour that we want.
There's a little slider to the right of it which enables us to make the colour lighter or darker.
Now you will notice that the left hand little panel underneath the colour wheel is the only one that's
changing.
So these are your two colours that you could pick from very quickly.
So we got our brush colour there and our secondary colour.
That's what blender calls them.
Now you can switch between them very quickly using these double headed arrow buttons just here.
In fact it says when we hover over the foreground and background brush covers that's what you will see
in a lot of image editing packages as well.
Now we've played with radiosonde strength before when we were weight painting the particle system over
in the bunny and that basically is the same here so we've got radius and strength and we can control
those with EF 4 the radius can shift an F for the strength with it being stronger when you move towards
the centre.
Okay so underneath we've got a blend and there are lots of different options and are not going to go
through them at the moment they basically change when you lay things on top of one and other colours
how they mixed together and accumulate is something that is very important under certain circumstances.
If I set the strength down to let's set it to point two.
If I said it's a point to start drawing because accumulate is off until I decide to click again or start
drawing over the same.
Part of the image but starting a new stroke.
Only then does it apply.
The next level of.
Colour if accumulate is turned on.
It doesn't matter if I stay over the same place it goes.
White Very quickly because whites the colour I've got we're not gonna use use gradient at the moment
does it change lots of the different options that you have here is very powerful but were not going
to use it at this early stage.
Now this is possibly the most powerful feature of all and actual palates because at the moment you've
got no way of storing your colours after you've selected them.
Sure you can click on the let's say the foreground colour here and go to the little pet and go and pick
up.
Let's say this lighter mauve at the top pair or purple or pinky colour whatever it is and that's great.
We've picked that up again and we start painting with it.
But that wasn't the original colour that cause that whatever the original colour was was a lot stronger
than that and we were just painting with it at 20 percent.
So we would want to store that colour.
And how do we do that.
Well with a palette so I can go ahead here and under the new option go ahead and click that and we get
a plus and minus symbol appear next to the colour wheel.
If we go ahead and click the plus it adds the currently selected colour to a palette.
If we hit the minus it removes it.
If it was the one that was selected.
Now if I go ahead and name this palette warm and let's say go in add some warm colours so yellow is
just going to be orange and red and things like that.
So I've now got four colours there that I can use and go back to at any point and continue using.
And the great thing about building up a palette like this that has a style to it like whether it's warm
or cold or nature or water or whatever you've decided to build up it means that you can then access
that colour palette from another blend file.
So this is a way to block some of these brushes.
So if you linked this data block in a new blend file.
When we went to this drop down here we would see that there would be zero L. warm at the moment in this
particular blend far as say f warm if you appended it it would just probably say zero warm.
Of course if you don't do anything with it at that point you will end up with it being lost when you
saved your file of course and you can do the same.
Here we see that all of these got f next to them because if they didn't the moment we so saved blender
and shut it down and reopened it.
All of them would disappear.
So there are more options underneath here as well but they're more advanced than we're not going to
touch them at this moment in time.
But I do have a bit of a painting challenge for you guys.
I would like you to create a quick image.
Remember to have some fun paint a couple of simple pictures.
I'm not asking you to be artists at this point.
I'm asking for some simple pictures.
Like very very early on in this course you remember when I was asking you to draw things like simple
cups and simple planes in there a picture of a boat and they're not real in terms of how they're asking
you to be a super artist at this point.
And it also does not have to be related to the current project.
It's more important at this point this is to make sure you're familiar with how the image editor works
when we are going about painting.
So have some fun scansion things simple things.
As I said depending on your skill level and make sure you're having fun as you do it.
Balls a video now and give that a go.
Okay guys welcome back.
Let's go create a quick image over in blender.
Okay so in front of us I've got something that's not that great at the moment.
Let's see what we can do with it.
So I'm going to zoom in just a little bit more so I can work on my image.
I am going to probably clear this down.
And one of the quick ways that I can do that is clicking any of these colours and dragging it over the
top it will actually replace everything if I do that.
So let's click here and drag and drop.
There we go.
What are white canvas to start with.
So I am going to do something really dull probably.
But here we go.
So I've got a radius I'm going to increase that and in the sky I'm actually not using my stylus at the
moment I'm using the mouse.
Turns out when I'm recording it's actually more awkward to use the stylus because it's well it's in
the way it's I'm tryna look at something that's directly beneath a microphone which is quite difficult
to do.
So there we go we've got some basic stuff in there and let's do that.
I am going to do a house I think so let's make this radius a lot smaller not too small.
Yeah about fair and let's have an orange house I might as well utilize what I've got there and then
zoom in.
Zooming is very important because it does allow us to have some more control over what we're doing.
Now at this point in time I need to increase the strength of that brush well undo the stroke for I just
did and just do that again.
There we go.
That's much better.
I'm using the stylus for that square.
By the way.
Oh okay.
I thought I zoomed in a lot more than that.
Okay.
Losing reference with the rest of the image can be quite critical.
So there we go.
I will put a roof on my house that's not too great.
I'm going to change my fill time brush to a fill type.
Oh only to select for colour that I want only a slight The slightly lighter orange and using a couple
of different brushes.
There we go it's looking pretty good.
Even if I do say so myself.
What else can we do here.
Let's give this house a car swap that's a round.
And I was going to draw a.
Carb there.
Nice simple can't like oh.
My children a.
Now obviously joking aside here if you spend the time you can actually get some really nice images going
here.
I'm being as simple and as straightforward as possible with my drawings here.
I hope you are having fun doing yours remember to share your work in the discussions and of course there
goes and smoke.
I will see you guys in the next lecture.