So that concludes this section of the course.
We've had a good time.
Hope you've created something you're proud of.
And if, like me, look at your creation and you see there's still a lot to improve and oh, I wish
I did that better.
And there's more that I can work on this particular part.
Then take as much time as you like.
Really finesse it to the point where you're happy with it.
But don't be too hard on yourself.
If you're not quite there yet, it's all about practice with these things.
And if you've been interested in the character creation side of things and want to create more than
just the head, maybe some arms and legs in a body, then be sure to check out our blender character,
create a course where we do go into creating those arms and legs and body.
And we work on rigging and animating and texturing and all the good stuff that comes along with character
creation.
So great work in this section.
I look forward to seeing what you've come up with and I will see you in another section of the class.