Welcome to using images for control.
In this video you will learn how to use images to control your materials with better finesse.
I understand why these control images are black and white and create a simple stage far building.
Once we've understood all of this so why black and white.
All these greyscale images define values on a per pixel basis.
Now the reason why I say values is it does depend on what you're applying the image to what you are
having it control whether that be the factor in a mix between two shaders whether it be something else
that you want to control that basically black represents a value of zero and white a valuable one.
So black means that there is nothing to do with it.
And white means there's a hundred percent of whatever it is you're applying it to and you map this image
to your model like you would any other image.
So let's go explore this now and hop on over in a blender.
Okay so we're over in blender and I'm going to add some materials to this cube.
So the first thing I'm going to do is I'm just going to lift it off off of this plane.
This x y 0 plane and just add in a plane.
And that will give us some ground to work on if just inverted that there we go.
So we should now when we hit the render button up here or indeed just switch to rendered view it looks
like it exists somewhere which is very powerful.
So let's go ahead and add a material to this cube and underneath use nodes.
Among them a set the colour to an orange Why not.
Okay so now we've got that there.
We need to have an image to control something.
So let's go ahead and open up an image editor and create ourselves a quick image and create a new image
and I'm going to come call it control texture because essentially that's is what it's going to be.
Let's stick with one two for as always and click.
Okay.
Now that I've created our image I'm going to now go into paint mode.
And yes it is working.
Earlier on this wasn't working for me I had to save my file restart blender and it suddenly started
working again.
I think the graphical interface just stopped responding or updating or something along those lines.
It was very confusing but saving my work restarting blender and opening up seemed to have fixed it.
Anyway that aside I'm going to crank this up to a strength of one because that means the centre of the
dots or dots or whatever you are doing is going to be pure white or pure whatever colour you've got
selected.
And I'm going to make sure that this is white.
Now that I've done that I don't want that size I want slightly larger sun than the blow it's about there
and hits it smack bang in the middle.
Perfect.
That's going to be my control limit so it's white in the middle so everything 100 percent of whatever
we apply it to will be in the middle and the outskirts will be black.
It won't apply to us at all.
So I've got that texture made I just need to go ahead and save it.
Oh that's make sure I save it in an appropriate location.
I'm gonna pop it in my resources.
Now I'm gonna pop it in my texture's just in case I do decide to use that control texture.
Excellent so now I've got my control texture ready.
I can just get rid of this screen altogether.
In fact I'm not going to get rid of it.
I'm going to convert it into a node editor.
Okay now we're in the node editor.
We can do a couple of things here.
First of all let's make sure that that image is applied correctly to this particular model.
So I'm going to add in an image.
So let's go.
Texture image texture and will link it to the colour to so I can test it it's not important that it's
there at the moment.
Of course that is working and the reason it's not working is because we've not told blender how to map
the image to the model so we can go about that by unwrapping the model.
But let's go and make sure we set up the node structure so that is implicit so blended knows how it's
doing that.
So this vector inputs here we can add something to that.
So let's go ahead here and add an input texture.
Call Ward an act that is explicitly telling blender how that is mapped and we can try these out we can
pop generated in and see what we get.
We get one dot on the very top.
Number might be what you want.
Brilliant.
Done.
If we go normal.
Well it's not going to do anything.
We actually want you v..
How we can get around this very quickly because I don't really mind how this cube is unwrapped at the
moment.
Just the fact that it is unwrapped and if we just do a basic unwrap without being conscious about it
we're likely to get as we can see here.
The image on every single face that exists and I'm happy with that.
That's absolutely fine for this test.
So now we've got our image loaded up we know it's work and we've plugged it in and it's on our model.
So what can we use it for.
Well we can plug it into other parts so we control certain aspects of our model.
Now at the moment or of our material that we've made so at the moment it's just controlling the colour
which is useful but not in this case.
So I'm going to unplug that so we get our orange colour back.
Now I'm going to use it to control the difference between two different shaders.
So I need to add another shader.
Now you can pick a different one from me if you'd like.
I'm going to pick a glossy shader.
Add that in there.
And of course because we've got to shaders.
I need to mix them together.
So how am I going to mix it together.
That's right.
We have a mix shader.
Now let's think carefully about the way of linking these two together which order do we need them in.
Well let's just play with these from one side to the other.
So in this configuration when the factor is set at zero we get gloss okay when it's 0 percent we get
lost so it means 0 percent of the bottom one.
And when we turn up it's 100 percent off the bottom one.
So in this case if we were to plug in the image texture into the factor what do you think it would do.
Remember where the black is the black is around the outside.
Now I would want gloss to be 100 percent in the middle.
So we're controlling 100 percent of the bottom one is like this.
We're going to have to flip these around so that the gloss is on the bottom because it's white in the
middle when we go here.
Colour and plug it in.
There we go we've now got a gloss shader on the middle bit and diffuse on the outside.
Very very powerful.
There are some other ways that we could go about fixing that.
For instance if we unplug both of those and we plug them back in how they were before obviously we'd
get the outside being glossy which may be desirable but in this case it's not.
So what else can we do.
Well we can invert this image texture so we can add in a colour in Verts observe to search for it.
And the moment I put that into our model we can see that inverts the image and therefore where it was
black on the outside it's now white on the outside and black on the inside which gives the same effect.
The great thing about Add in the inverse is it does give it does actually give us another degree of
control between those two states.
That is powerful in itself as well.
So now we've added all of these bits and bobs in.
There's one final thing to do and we haven't told blender that it is explicitly not a colour channels
not colour information on the image texture it's non colour data and then it it does actually make a
difference to our image.
We go here to colour.
We can see that it's not actually applied the entire black and white realm.
If we go to non colour data it has applied it properly.
Now the technical reason for this is it stops blender from applying colour spaces to the image.
And that basically means that instead we want blender to interpret that image as a numeric value i.e.
that zero to one that we were talking about earlier rather than a perceived colour value which can be
different.
We can see it similar in this swap around.
We switch it from colour data to nonkosher data.
But the actual non colour data gives us exactly what we want because if the value is zero is definitely
black the value is one it's definitely white.
But the steps in between are going to be accurate on a pixel by pixel basis.
Okay so now we've experienced that.
I've got a small challenge for you.
I would like you to create a simple stage.
And by that I mean that previewing your models is best done with them on some sort of stage not in nothingness.
A lot of the time we end up producing a lovely model and it's kind of sad.
They're in limbo nothing round it.
So it's good to have it having some sort of presence and a ground beneath the objects is one of those
things and we can use a controlled texture to make that ground a little more interesting.
So what I'd like you to do is create a plane under your building if you haven't done already and using
a controlled texture make it have a circular fade and just see no.
Here's an example of the kind of look that I'm going to be going for with the Gothic church that I'm
working on here of course your building might be slightly different from mess and we've got this fade
going around it whereas that used to be quite a jagged square plane it's now nice and smooth towards
the edges at that that white that you can see there that is simply the environmental light.
I've just got it's set up white at the moment that could quite easily be a sky box or something else
if I wanted.
Anyway enough of that.
Possibly now and give that a go.
Okay guys welcome back.
Let's pop back over in blender and make ourselves a simple stage.
Right so we're back over here blender and the first thing I'm going to do is hop over to the Gothic
church.
Okay so now I'm in the Gothic church.
Mine's coming along quite well that's my chosen interior slash exterior that I've been working on.
Now I believe that I haven't updated.
And no I haven't.
As you can see here some of the textures have been applied and come across for the detail that I was
adding.
It come across quite nice.
I think it needs to be a little lighter than that but that's something I can sort out later.
But I do need to make sure these other bits are set so let's go ahead and complete the challenge and
then come back and just make sure all these other ones have inherited the right material.
Right the first thing to do is well it doesn't really matter in this case which order you do this in
England to select my plane and just unwrap it that's that done the next thing I need to do is give you
the same material.
So let's go ahead bring this out for the materials tab.
I'm not going to call it plane I'm going to call it Ground going to be good name things properly.
I'm going to go to the mesh data and also name it ground object data enmeshed data now called Ground.
Okay that's good.
Now I'm going to select the materials added new material and I'm also going to call that ground.
Now it's entirely up to you.
You could assign a grass texture if you've got something here that's absolutely fine.
I'm just going to go for a basic sort of a green dark green first like a fake grass and then I may apply
a texture later if I do any outside shots.
It's just for the moment to demonstrate this technique.
So I need to now bring in that texture and use it.
So I'm going to go into the image editor first of all and see if it's in our scene already know it's
not something to go ahead and open and go and find that control texture that I've already made.
Okay that's looking good.
That's in our blend file now and ready to be used some going to go ahead into the node editor.
And I'm keeping these full screen with a rough idea of what's going on in the background.
Now I'm going to want some transparency so I'm going to need a transparence B.
The F that's fine and I'm going to need a mix shader.
So let's go ahead and shaders mix I could search for that probably quicker than finding it.
Okay.
So let's plug them in.
Is this the right way round.
Let's think it's white in the middle.
And so we want 100 percent of the diff use where it's the bottom one hundred percent of the bottom one
when it's in the middle.
So these are the wrong way round so that's plugged it in there.
Now swap them over.
Now we need to bring in texture coordinance and that you've he needs to be plugged into a texture image
or an image texture.
So let's go you ve to vector colour to factor.
Colour to non colour data.
And then finally the control texture.
Let's go into the 3-d view and that is looking almost there but not quite.
If we view it from the top you can see that with non coloured data where the values aren't zero we still
end up with information there.
So we need to recreate this image.
Now I don't mind overwriting the image that I've already got so I'm going to go into the U.S. image
editor bring open the tool shell switch the mode to painting and we drag this black colour from the
secondary colour on top of the image that makes everything black and come up the strength and this time
I'm not going to make this circle so big and make it roughly there.
I'm going to click a couple of times to make sure I've got a nice white area in the middle.
Now that that's done I need to make sure a save my image.
She's now done.
And if we hop back to the 3-d view that is looking much much better apart from its position.
So there's a couple of things here.
I don't think it's large enough for the scale of our church.
So in that case I'm going to scale it by two and I'm going to also move it's I think why is that direction.
Yes to us.
So it's roughly in the middle.
Okay so that's that part of it sorted and looking pretty good.
What I am concerned about here is not all of my texture's have come across as I had expected them to.
So let's go ahead and have a look at these wall pieces.
First of all so I'm going to save my work fair and open up recent.
There's my wall.
So we've got this is it applied to our model over here.
No it's not.
Okay so I've got all old and ball and I'm going to get a sign that's come across I'm going to save and
how I'm going to make sure I enter the other models and actually assign them this material in here.
So if I go ahead and change this material it affects every one of the other ones rather than just the
model itself.
So we'll just test that first of all.
We hop into a rendered mode that's done so I'm going to need to do the doors and the windows.
By the looks of things so let's go and do that now to open up our meshes door front door and here where
we've got arch blockwork.
I'm actually going to remove those altogether I'm just going to remove them completely.
Those materials and link in.
The worn material wall.
Then a sign it's so wall.
Have a look and hope for the best.
That is looking pretty good.
I don't think I wanted to delete the one around the edge.
There are deal with that bit later.
Okay so File Save and let's go ahead and open up the window as well I think whereas window window window.
There we go.
So again here let's have a look at the materials window wall.
I'm going to remove that completely.
I'm going to go in link in adults or remember the wall before give it a link in that wall.
I think from a library going to assign it to my model and I quickly hop in and make sure it's there
it's not quite there something it's not gone to plan.
Have I selected the wrong one.
Probably not.
Ah here we go.
That was the problem I didn't undo the right material.
So that's go ahead link in wall has remembered.
And then assign it's.
And there we go we've got our textural loaded Let's go ahead save.
That's hoppin to our we all got a church there we go.
And well I should just be able to hit renda and see how that's looking.
That is looking pretty good.
How's yours coming along.
Breathe share in the discussions.
Oh that's the wrong file that's the wrong Gothic church.
That's the old one which I accidentally destroyed.
I should really just get rid of the file now.
Or no.
Got attention.
Here we go.
Look for the camera.
Or it looks like I need to set one up that is looking pretty good.
I long ago set up a camera and render it out.
I'd like you to do the same.
Make sure you're sharing in the discussions.
And of course I will see you guys in the next lecture.