Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to have a quick look at a review and a recap and a bit more knowledge on
the timeline itself.
Now the timeline is currently hidden down at the bottom here.
You may have already hidden it away.
Let's say you have and you've made the window disappear.
You can come down to the lower corner drag up a new window preferably in the horizontal plane because
that's kind of what a timeline is it's going to progress from the left to right.
Show us when things are happening and we can click on the other window type and find myself a timeline
now conveniently it's under the animation column and we'll be having a look at some of the other types
of edits a window that you can use when animating in a future lecture.
So here we have a timeline.
It starts of frame 1.
That's quite common.
And it goes all the way through to whatever frame that you have happened to senses your end frame.
So currently we set this right at the very beginning and we're going back a few lectures here.
So we have starting at 1 ending at 300.
If for some reason we wanted to change that say we wanted it and 200.
We could use the type that indirectly here or with the playback head let's say over 200.
We can go to playback and set the end frame.
And there you go.
It's as simple as that.
I don't want that.
I want it at the end of 300.
So that's really useful being able to play left click and drag along here.
Now you're going to find it quite useful as we start developing our animation to be able to click and
just scrub backwards and forwards a particular area whilst you may not get it.
Playing back at a smooth rate is very good to see if there is a problem at some point.
I'm sure there will be as we start moving it around you may find that one of these frames that suddenly
the lamp flips to a different direction.
And that's a key point where you may have to add in a key frame to prevent that from happening or indeed
look at the animation overall our timeline is going to be quite simple but you can zoom in and zoom
out as well.
That's incredibly useful knowing that you can do that for our simple animation of only 10 seconds.
That's not a big issue but on larger projects that may be something you need to be aware of.
Speaking of larger projects I would always suggest breaking things down into smaller subsections of
animations rather than trying to do one big thing at once.
And that's typically the case.
That's why whenever you watch a film whether it's animated or not it has short scenes you very rarely
have a long long scene with the camera looking at one thing for a long time it often switches and changes
about.
That gives you more flexibility as an editor you can swap things in and out.
It also gives you more scope if you make a mistake that you don't have to re render an entire hour worth
of render where you only need to do a few seconds in between.
But since our lamp let's say jumping onto our box over here is pretty much the whole animation is only
going to last 10 seconds.
We don't need to worry about switching things up like that.
Now one of the things that's incredibly useful on the timeline is you can add markers and that's this
end column here.
We've got the option here to add a marker we can jump between markers and I find these markers incredibly
useful.
So for instance if by frame 150 we wanted the lamp to have landed on the box we can with our cursor.
That's the important thing with our cursor over the timeline press the M key.
Now unfortunately f 150 frame 150 is what that stands for isn't a great name.
We can go ahead and we can select markers and drag them left and right.
And if we want to rename them control an M so we can come in here and say landing and click Okay.
And of course we can go let's say at frame 40 we might want the jump to happen so we go m control an
M jump.
Now these are only place holders for the moment.
I have no exact plan of when things are going to happen but if you start to plan out your main scene
like this it can be incredibly useful because you start to have an idea of when things need to happen
by.
So if we know that at 240 I really want my lamp falling off.
So 240 I've I want it to.
That's a marker here.
Control M straight away.
Oh did I hit the right keys.
I'm not sure I did with the cursor over the marker.
There we go.
And I'm going to call that the crash landing.
I think it'd be quite cool to have our lamp jump up here.
I'm going to do a quick animation way and when we're up there for it's grass blocked and hit the ground.
Now obviously at the moment this is rotating around something the 3d cursor no doubt change that back
to medium points and then Yep way splat.
There we go.
So that's why animation in a nutshell.
But as we start putting it together let's reset all of those movements as we've put this all together.
It's going to start to feel more and more like an animation.
Oh I think I undid too much.
My marker here has gone back.
Let's call this crash landing again.
There we go.
Ah perhaps I didn't click okay or press enter.
Occasionally when you're renaming something.
I think if you don't press enter twice it's not going to accept it.
Now I like the frame numbers themselves.
Some people may prefer the time along the top.
So if you go to view you can show the number of seconds that you don't see the frames and the seconds
at the same time.
So as you can see here we carry through an after 30 frames so go up to 29 30 becomes one second and
so forth.
So this is frame count and then total seconds.
Personally I'm just happy with it showing the number of frames.
I know we're working at 34 in a second and then unless there's something you really need to key in and
get perfect then this will be absolutely fine.
Now I'm not going to give you an official challenge for this lecture but what I would like you to just
practice is moving about the time line making sure you're comfortable with that.
Make sure you're comfortable with creating some markers.
These may or may not turn out to be useful during this particular section and the other thing is just
double check that you have the right number of frames and you have the right frame rate that's going
right back to when we started setting our animation specification under the render tab.
Sorry not under the render tab under the output tab.
We have a start and end frame and our frame rates.
So that is still how we had it set before.
Now one of the things I will do whilst I'm in here actually is the resolution of 4 k.
I'm going to put it in as just back to 100 percent for the moment.
Otherwise I'll be wondering why my renders are taking far too long.
Okay I'm going to save my work.
This was important save your work often.
Brilliant.
So go ahead pause this video now play with the time line make sure you're comfortable with it because
we're going to be using it quite a bit over the next couple of lectures and I'll see you all in the
next lecture.