Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture I want to show you the benefits of grouping things in collections.
When it comes to exporting and importing in-between blender files so we have are seen at the moment
looking pretty good.
If we go ahead and go to a new blender file and go to append and then go to the file that we've been
working on I'm going to pull them this hidden area here.
I hate the way that that's hidden and there's no division.
Hopefully they'll sort that out soon.
And now that we're in here I can see that the chess scene and now starts to become the the questionable
how do I get the models that I want across into the scene.
If I go to objects we get a load of objects so I can bring them in all individually would take quite
some time.
What else can I do.
I could bring the whole scene in so if I go and select the scene we can then switch to the very top
scene 0 0 1 and there are entire scene has been brought across.
But once again this has brought everything else.
So this was a much larger scene that set us in a coffee shop and there are many many more elements and
we just wanted to pull this one out.
How could we do that.
Well if we go and just highlight everything here and delete sets we've got an empty scene again go to
append.
Now we will remember where you were previously so let's go.
Upper level if we go to collections we can group all of our items that we would typically export in
there.
So we got our black pieces white pieces board camera and light.
So be good if our pieces and board were all in one collection.
Otherwise we can't bring everything through.
So let's go ahead.
Let's cancel that.
Go into our chest scene file and start grouping these things together appropriately so very quickly
we can select the black and the white pieces straight away on the left hand side here.
Now the scene view is currently in scenes mode.
We could switch it into view layer.
It's exactly the same at this point.
Now the chessboard itself I'm going to bring out of the collection.
So currently in the view layer rather than scenes I'm going to control and left click on that and that's
going to select the board and all of the pieces underneath and then I'm going to press the M key to
move them and I'm going to move them into a new collection called chess models.
And the reason for moving them into a new collection like that is now we have the camera and light sets
up brilliant.
All those and then we got the black pieces the white pieces and we've got the chess models themselves.
So what we should now be able to do is save our work go and create a new file and I'm going to delete
the default cube and then I'm going to append what's remembered where we were before.
Now I can go ahead and pick up the chess models and there we go.
Everything has come across but it has come across with out all of the extra gump.
So we've now got the camera that exists in this particular blend far and this is incredibly useful if
you're setting up your scene with lighting and everything else to demonstrate the scene and what it
can be or this particular model.
And then you go ahead and export it to a brand new blend file perhaps you're now using this chessboard
as a set on a table somewhere in a coffee shop or something along those lines then you won't want to
bring the lighting and the cameras that came with it necessarily.
And that's how you'd export.
This is also how you might export it's ready into a file that you might want to then get ready for game
engine exports as well.
So you've got you're showing off file and you've also got your game export file although an alternative
to that would be to have different scenes within the same blend file.
Okay.
That's it for this quick tip.
I hope you find it incredibly useful.
I have always found it difficult to manage the export of multiple objects within a blend file and when
collections came along here was a really really nice thing to work with.
So I would be families useful and I'll see you all in the next lecture.