In this video we're experimenting with sculpting and I'm creating a hideous of Franken Caterpillar and
I'm going to challenge you to do the same.
So let's jump in and get started.
Then except first is to convert our minerals into mesh so that we can edit individual vertices and start
to do sculpting on our objects.
So while clicking on our parent level amble I'm going to go to object scroll down convert to mesh from
curve metal surface text.
Excellent that allows us if we go into edit mode you can now see all the edges and vertices and faces
so I could click on three and then g to move this around so you can see we've got individual faces that
we can manipulate.
Excellent.
Next up I'll do the same for just hop to actually into object mode.
I'll do the same for our eyeball eyeball.
We will go to object convert to mesh.
Excellent.
So anything that you've got in your scene that you individual elements you converted to mesh.
Now just gonna rename from M bowl to cat to the pillows so it's nice and clear and from I amenable to
just straight up.
I.
What I'm going to do is set up my object so that I can mirror it so I'm only working on one side and
that gets mirrored onto the other side.
If you've created your creature so that it's not mirror a ball not a problem you can do everything else
we're going to do in this lecture with all the sculpting without mirroring.
But if you do have something that does have symmetry to it then let's go through that process while
clicked on Caterpillar.
I'm going to go to edit mode so I can see everything that's going on hit one on the keyboard to get
my vertices actually jump straight on that's from behind jump straight on I'm going to hop in a wireframe
mode just so I can see nice and clearly highlight all the way down to get everything that is up to my
middle line.
Hit delete delete the vertices just hopping make sure I've got all the little vertices that there's
no stragglers and I do have a couple of stragglers here.
One more straggler I believe.
Delete and I don't think I hit the delete button delete vertices excellent and I'll hit one of these
or select one of these and hit El G and then X just so I can move my object right up to the line that
screen back into my other shading mode back into object mode because next I'm going to mirror.
Now I have auto mirror set up so I can easily get to it from my menu at the top here.
If you don't have auto mirror already you can go to preferences and then search for auto mirror click
on the tick box and then save preferences and then up in the very right next to our transform widget
you will see on the edit we have auto mirror auto mirror allows me to select my object and then just
say click auto mirror and it will mirror.
Wonderful.
Now we have used clip turned on which is important.
If I go back into edit mode and highlight grab one of these hit L to select the whole thing now I'll
go right on my front view.
Now when I move x.
Now when I move these you can see due to do if I move it into the middle it gets absorbed it clips doesn't
go over the top of my other side of the object and if I move it right up close and let that go because
I have used clip turned on that should hitting g x I can move it again merge or Weld my vertices together.
So that is now stuck in the middle which is exactly what I want.
Back in object mode I'll do the same with my eye.
Let's select one of my eyes.
Okay I want to keep things consistent on the right hand side so I'm going to highlight click L to get
all the linked vertices delete delete the vertices there or didn't do a good job on that.
And El again delete that should get all the vertices this time.
Excellent.
Just check this eyeball.
El again.
Move it over a little bit.
Now one of the problems you can see here is that our origin point is way over on the left hand side
so if I mirror this it will mirror the equal point of the origin.
Over here as things are set up at the moment so I'm going to do back into object mode I will click on
my eyeball.
I'll click on the three day cursor.
Put that right in the middle right on the y axis you can see my blue line running there and then up
onto objects set.
Origin we want to set the origin to the 3d cursor nicely the little yellow dots in the middle of the
cursor.
I can click on auto mirror and blink.
It should put it in the right spots.
That was just a matter of changing with the origin point is okay.
So we now have our caterpillar.
It's been mirrored excellently.
Now we're ready for action.
Before I start sculpting I just want to do one thing to make a little bit easier to see up in our shading
view.
You see little Right Arrow or the arrow to the right click on that.
Make sure that we're in the correct view which is the solid view.
Click on the arrow to allow cavity and I'm going to change type to be both and increased all of the
values of ridges and valleys and you can see now that we get more detail.
You can see the white lines that are showing up so that you and so that I can see what we're doing as
we go.
It makes it a lot more pronounced.
Now let's do some sculpting what we need to do is jump over into office where we'll click on Caterpillar
won't really be doing much for the eye click on Caterpillar and change from object mode into sculpt
mode.
I'm gonna be showing you how to use some of the brushes but what I encourage here is you just experiment.
I'm going to be turning my caterpillar into Frank and Caterpillar.
He's gonna be a monster by the end of this.
So let's just stop playing around with things if we click on draw up over onto our caterpillar.
You can see that that's just adding vertices it's pulling things out in the direction we're waving.
If I hold down control then it will slip things back in again.
So usually control does the opposite of a particular brush.
We move it around wherever we like it will change things as we go.
You can see that we've got a circle.
If I hit F then that allows me to increase the circle.
This is the the area that we're affecting so this will be a much bigger brush.
If I hit shift F that allows me to change the strength within that brush.
So if I make the strength full I might actually just reduce this pressure.
I don't make a mess.
Just check.
Yep it's on full and then as I go it's a smaller brush but it's making a big impact.
You can see I'm already already breaking my caterpillar but that's fine.
We're gonna be doing a lot of that in this video.
Now this is a good time for us to talk about something which I think sounds like an evil super villain
which is dying Topo dying Topo allows us to dynamically change the topology.
What I mean by that.
Well let's have a look at the top ology if I jump back over into edit mode I can see a lot more clearly
here the mesh of my object and you can see it's a real kind of mess.
There's this weird sort of circle thing we do have some good loops but we've got a lot of just mess
throughout as well.
And that's not a problem because this stage of our project where being creative and we're just getting
the shape of things later on we can have the choice of Rita apologizing if we've got way too much topology.
That's not a problem.
Our point here our main goal is to have it look good and you know let me just show you very quickly
the flow that you typically go through with an organic modelling workflow.
Block out your model which we have done convert to mash which we've done start sculpting which we're
doing right now.
The point here is the the creative juices flow.
And then to read apologize if mesh is important for animation or texturing.
That's why we clean this up we would get the right amount of detail and we have the right shape so that
it makes it easier for us to put our textures on there and makes it easier for us to for animators to
do what animators need to do for us to animator object.
And then we might unwrap you v unwrap and map and then to paint or texture.
This section will be adding hair to objects which is a little bit cheating but we still need to have
some reasonably nice mesh or reasonably nice topology so that the hair behaves the way we want it to.
But for sculpting we're not worrying about that we're looking at detail.
So how does that relate to Dian Topo.
Well let's have a look at what happens at the moment.
If we back into sculpt mode if I'm sculpting you can see we've got a point a point a point my my mouse
is snapping on my cursor snapping a certain vertices as I draw it's pulling them out or pushing them
in and just modifying the existing topology or the existing mesh that we have now.
I might want to have more detail say around the mouth where these two vertices is just not going to
cut it.
I'm going to have a lot more detail so I don't get these sharp pointy edges and the way we address that
is with Dian Topo to turn Dian Topo on.
We got to our top settings tab just here and we find scroll down scroll down we find the setting of
Dian Topo clicking that on you'll get an error message or a warning message saying Hey this is going
to break and modifier that's breaking our mirror which is not a problem because as we break that we've
lost our mirroring but what we can do under Dian Topo is we find Ramesh and then we I believe for me
it's going to be from plus extra minus X and we click symmetries symmetry right some tries seven tries.
That's the guy who fights nine Topo.
I think Silver tries.
Now what we've caught with time Topo is the ability to add more detail to our mesh if I go back to the
wireframe Modus Libre easier to see as I add you can see it's adding a lot more detail to our mesh it's
going to undo that.
How much detail is it adding.
Well there's one sitting here which it defaults to which is relative detail.
That means if we get really close then we'll be adding tons of tiny little detail whereas if we scroll
out scroll out it will be adding much less detail more bigger sized faces if you will which is great
if you're getting into the habit of okay.
If I want little details and lives here I'm moving very close in on bigger details I move out a little
bit more.
That's good.
If you get into that habit until then what I like to do is set this to constant detail and then we can
change the resolution at the moment it's three let's set it to six and see how that feels.
Which means no matter how far we scroll in and out it will always add the same amount of detail.
Now of course our brush size is going to change the way scrolled all the way in our brushes little.
So it's just impacting a little area and we're scrolling out our brushes big but the amount of mesh
that's being added is is consistent no matter whether we're scrolling or scroll down it's just how much
of the area is affected by the size of our particular brush.
Okay.
So let's that's in Topo.
Let's go through some more of the brushes we have draw sharp which similar to draw but it's gonna draw
a much sharper line.
This one it's digging in as opposed to pulling out something to hold down control and that will push
up above If I go back to draw and drawing a little bit more detail you can see that drawing is adding
more detail whereas the draw sharp wasn't adding when I've already got that detail in place.
It can manipulate it but when I've got these fatter kind of detail it wasn't doing as good a job of
responding there.
So interesting that draw is adding with Don top I turn on is adding more of that detail.
Okay.
And as we just go through clay that will have things behave as if it's lumps of clay which is really
handy Clay strips you can chuck down some strips like that again.
This is from more of the traditional clay sculpting.
So if you're familiar with that this is kind of a cool way to get those similar tools.
We have layer which allows us to put a layer on top of our existing geometry which is really handy.
So let me see if I can illustrate this more effectively if we put it over the top of there.
You can see that it's putting it over the top in a consistent manner it's layering it over the top in
flight does exactly what we expect it to do it puffs things up.
So if you want to inflate your tail down in here let me f make it bigger.
Inflate inflate inflate.
We can kind of inflate it like a balloon like a marshmallow blob is similar.
Just make my bra size a bit smaller.
But the strength a little bit more adds just adds a blob to things blob blob blob.
Excellent crease which is handy for us to literally add creases off us to go inside the mouth.
Yeah I wanted to create that up.
It's going to pull my vertices together to make a crease smooth does what we expect it smooth things
down smooth out some of our detail flatten which is great so underneath my caterpillar if I want to
flatten you to make it look like he's on top of some sort of surface make it less round that has a flattened
feel to it feel good for filling up particular spaces we might want to fill inside the mouth here scrape
that's going to be like scraping along clay with a scraping kind of tool if you make this tool quite
small then it's going to scrape just a bit of a line if I can do this correctly there it goes great
great great scrape and obviously bigger is going to do more I have a bigger scrape okay multiplying
scrape allows us to do a really cool kind of pinching scraping maneuver I quite like this too particularly
if you've got something where you want to have some sharp angles to it.
Speaking of that for all of these tools all of these brushes you can go through the right hand side
click on your top tab and then change the brush settings so the plane angle if I was to make the plane
angle very small then it's going to be a much flatter effect that I'm getting if I was to make that
plane angle bigger then it's really going to dig into it that might be something that I'd want to go
into my antennae and kind of dig around to make an outside edge to it it's a little bit of a clunky
way of going about doing it but I've sort of got what I wanted.
Similarly I could do this along the mouth to give them mouth a little bit more and more pizzazz and
then pinch as expected it allows us to pinch pull things together a little bit like crease but it's
more about pinching particular areas together grab is good if you wanted to grab an entire area and
kind of pull it up or modify it or stretch it out allows you to grab a lot of the mesh at one point
in time.
Similar with elastic deform snake hook is very different actually and show you snake is one of my favorites
I'll make the brush smaller.
This allows us to yank out of the objects I'm going to grab and pull and make these little kind of caterpillar
leg things Caterpillar leg Caterpillar legs I'm gonna go in and make a few of these Caterpillar legs
you might want to do something similar to yours.
It's also this tool is really really good for making kind of evil horn bump type things on top so leverage
is if we make this bigger then I can get a larger sort of hunchback a lump type thing going on with
my evil Caterpillar if I make it smaller then it's going to be more of a narrow lumpy type thing okay.
Out of the other ones is a few to play around with which are kind of cool.
The other one that I wanted to show you was two masks so if you click on mask and find an area where
you say Okay I want to mask out this area just here.
That means that my brush won't apply.
The area that I've got mask and then I can go and grab say the draw tool and you see as I go draw draw
draw draw doesn't do anything during the mask.
And then on the backside of the mask it starts drawing again.
So that allows me just to apply to specific areas and it's cool for doing this kind of took effect.
So this set setting a mask allows me to paint things on if I go to the box selection that allows me
to grab things quickly mask out that entire area if I hold down control and then select the mask.
It undoes that.
So as I said before control is usually the opposite for each of these things.
And if you haven't been playing along and if you haven't already jumped into the challenge the challenge
I've got for in this video is to flex your creative muscles go crazy with sculpting create something
that is hideous like I'm doing beautiful it is totally up to you and once you finish please share with
your your creation with it we would love to see it jump in take on that challenge now when you come
back I'm just gonna show you a little bit of extra tweaking I've done to my hideous Caterpillar so I
start off by inflating making my caterpillar look a bit fatter a bit more grotesque puffing it up just
grabbing the hook tool the snake hook tool and pulling some more bits out making some eye sockets giving
some ridges lift it fairly kind of bumpy and skimpy but later on I'll smooth that out just again going
along with my Ridge to trying to make a layer of detail on the outside trying to make it look like got
a bit of a bigger mouth to it as well I masked out the inside of the mouth because I found I was accidentally
grabbing it gives them spiky TV kind of things more of those sort of bumps just pulling it out played
around with the the antennae a little bit trying to grab it and pull it apart of stretching the head
I didn't really like the effect that was getting there more bumps just bumpy bumps snake hook pulling
things out the grab tool and I try to tie Oh but I didn't really like it so I changed my mind on that
okay.
There we have it my somewhat hideous of Franken Caterpillar beast.
So I look forward to seeing what you've come up with and I will see you in the next lecture.