Hello everybody and welcome to importing your reference material.
By the end of this lecture you'll be able to input your pen as you can see here in a position where
is not only transparent but you can see the objects behind it as well.
Really useful for any reference material.
Let's find out more.
Okay.
So as you've guessed it there's more than one way that we're going to be able to do this.
The first wave I'm going to show you is to simply go to your file manager find your reference and drag
and drop it in.
This will generate an empty with our image attached to the empty and we can move it around we can move
around in the scene and you notice that is aligned with the view.
So as soon as we've added that into the scene is aligned with the view itself.
And that can cause problems because if you weren't expecting that or not quite in the right view you
have to undo and go backwards and forwards again.
But that's a really quick way of getting us to the position of having an empty with an image associated
with it.
I'm going to highlight that and delete it out of the way because the next way I'm going to show you
is a bit more controlled.
We're going to go to edits and preferences and under your add ons tab.
So if you're not there go onto the add ons tap on the left hand side and start typing in the search
box image and you'll see an option hits.
Import export import images as planes.
Make sure you've got a tick in that box.
And if you want it to happen every time you open up a brand new plan to file from now on make sure you
click on Save preferences.
Once you've done that you can go ahead and close that down.
Now what will happen is when you go ahead to add a new object into the scene we've got this new image
option and we've got three options reference background and images as planes.
We'll start with images as planes.
This is the one that it's it seems to be indicating that we want straight to wait and see we've got
a load of options down here as to how it's going to import.
Okay I'm going to scroll down here it's not apparent by the way that you can lift this up and down this
catches a lots of people out that you've got things hidden behind this invisible area.
So I want to go to my bowling ball and pins folder my pin reference which is what I downloaded in the
previous lecture and we're gonna open that up.
Hey where's it gone.
What I'm going to go ahead and hide my cube is imported a plane with the right aspect ratio with the
texture of that pin applied to it.
So we won't see it until we're either in look there mode.
There we go.
Or we're in shaded mode.
Now of course the issue with this is it's not very good as a reference image but it is very good as
maybe a background image if you wanted to see some trees in the background of a scene that you're working
on very similar to how we introduced just having a billboard in the back a bright blue one or an orange
one.
If you cast your mind back to the first ever lectures that we did where we were we just want a blue
sky Well it's just a big blue thing behind the camera.
So we don't see anything else beyond that.
This is how you can do that but with an image let's have a look at the other options.
So let's go ahead delete that and add in an image as background and this time if we go into the pin
reference we can see that it's added in just as we had before just as if we dropped it in so we can
see here that it's aligned perfectly with the view as it was.
And then of course we can move around the scene that's got these grab handles that we can grab on and
you can see that it locks to the aspect ratio of the objects.
So that's another way of getting to the same point that we were on before.
However the key one the important one for us is a reference.
So once again if we add in reference it will align to your view.
So that's the first thing to bear in mind.
So before we do any of this what we need to do is make sure we're on the right view.
So either the right or the front of the graphic projection I'm going to go ahead and add in an image
reference and I'm going to go pin reference now with this here.
I'm not going to worry about scaling at the moment.
We'll talk about that later on but for the moment we just need to make sure that we can see it and it's
properly aligned with our mesh objects.
So the Bring Back our cube.
So the first thing you'll see here were in shaded mode.
I'm going to go back to solid.
We cannot see our image when there's an object in the way it's just buried in between.
So let's go round to the front.
What can we do.
Well only the empties properties.
If we scroll down on the object properties to where we've got all viewport display.
If we open that up and scroll down we've got a couple of options.
The first one that you may find very useful is having it in front.
Hey guys.
Mark Hare the update for you as blender seems to Earth either broken something or updated something.
So this no longer works it's cast your eyes over to the right under the viewport display of the object
data.
Sorry.
Object properties panel if you click in front you'll find that the image will no longer appear in the
front.
Also if you try and change the outcome from this panel that no longer works either.
The only thing you can do to see from this way round is to select the cube itself and then change the
display as to why if remote
if we switched back to solid mode for a moment what we can do is if we switched back to the image go
to the image properties we can come to the depth and change it to front.
I'd also like to draw your attention to the use Alpha checkbox just as a reminder you can use this slider
to change the opacity.
And with that in mind.
Back to Mike now that is incredibly useful as then we can see our image no matter where.
But the problem there of course is well we can't say our object which puts us in a bit of a conundrum
is better if this image was slightly transparent.
Well we can do that if we go to our color options.
Not only can we color this if we wanted to send it back to normal but at the bottom here we have an
A.
Now we've got RG B A H S V A and A hex value here if you wanted the RG B's red green blue this is hue
saturation and value but the H stands for Alpha on all of these.
If we turn that down our image becomes see through which means that we can see both the image and the
object behind and that's what we all want to make sure that we have when it comes to actually doing
anything with our image in Blender.
As a reference image.
So there we go multiple ways of importing an image into blender.
And now it's time for you to give it a go in the form of a challenge okay.
So your challenge is to set your view to even the front or a side or a graphic view.
Once you've done that import your pin reference image in the blender then set the image to be in front
of everything else in the viewport and make sure your image is exactly nought point four on the viewport
alpha channel.
We may change the later I just want to make sure you're comfortable with actually tweaking one of those
settings as well.
Paul's video now and give us a go OK.
Everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead and impulse hop in reference.
OK so welcome back over in supply and I'm going to press one on my number pad to whiz round to the front
view and I'm going to go shift an eight add in and because I made sure that I've saved my user preferences
I have these options every time I started either half those after creating a new blender file or perhaps
coming back to blender later on remember that in your preferences if you don't save your preferences
it will only apply to the blender file you're working on which is sometimes beneficial by this point
we want it to apply to everything that's really useful one to have turned on if I want to make sure
I close my user preferences down as well.
Okay so we're in the front view I'm going to add in a reference image I'm going to go and find fortunately
I've already bookmarked it but I'll also be in my recent as well.
Remember this little hidden area here bowling ball and pins pin references the one I wants to import
now I have included this against this lecture as well if you want to use exactly the same reference
material that I have of course I would always encourage you to use your own reference material so you
can really tweak and so you're not just doing monkey see monkey do work as we go forward.
Okay now that's imported.
I can scroll down here whilst I mean my empties properties the object data properties I'm gonna go to
viewport display open that's up and I'm going to say that it's in front of everything.
That's exactly what I want.
Now the color I'm going to go to Alpha I'm just going to tie pin point four and there we go.
Everything sorted.
It looks like it's probably a little large at the moment but we'll get sorting that out in a bit.
Okay.
There we go.
Hope you found that's pretty straightforward to do if you did struggle a little let us know where you
struggled over in the discussions or of course if you'd found a different way of doing this I'd love
to hear about it as well and I'll see you all in the next lecture.