Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this quick tip I'd like to show you how to add in key frames automatically.
That sounds like a great thing to do.
Unfortunately I've been caught out by it so it comes with a warning.
It's very straightforward to do.
Let's go and head back into our main interface.
Let's pause the video and in this selection of control these playback controls here there's this circle
automatic key frame insertion for objects and bones.
So it's not going to add in as it used to previously add an extra bits and bobs.
This is specifically for bones and objects what does it do.
Well if we have a look at the moment we're on frame 122.
So let's pull this back and hold down the middle mouse button.
There's no key frame currently at 122.
If I press record nothing happens at the moment.
So let's say we did want to do something so let's turn on our overlays grab the control bone here and
really hide the other one so far.
I'm not risking move selecting them or moving them and I rotate this around the z axis to there.
Suddenly some key frames get put in and if we have a look at the sidebar properties under the item we
can see that all of this has been keyed in including scale which is odd because we didn't scale anything
but it's automatically keyed in location rotation scale and similarly at the top here we'll go and grab
this and move it around.
We see that it automatically keeps it in.
Now this can be a real nightmare if you didn't realize that you were doing it and perhaps you were playing
it back and you thought oh maybe I'll you know move it around whilst it's playing back which at first
glance looks like a great idea.
But then when we look at it being played back afterwards you see that you've ended up with a very fidgety
lamp let's put it that way.
And that's not what we want.
And I've been caught out so many.
He looks like he's trying to pull himself along there.
I've been caught out so many times when it comes to having this on I prefer being explicit telling blender
Yes I want this to have a key frame in it.
Some people will get on fine with this I'm forgetful I'm going to forget to turn that off and it's going
to cause me this sort of mess.
Now if you did accidentally create these sorts of mess and didn't realize you might be square out of
luck that might be impossible to fix especially if you'd saved your file and opened it up enough day
and with your undo you can see.
Yes you can get it there and undo it back again.
In fact I'm going to keep undoing for the moment so that we get rid of everything that we had there
previously and yes there we go we started off putting key frames on 122 is not there anymore.
I'm going to save my work.
Make sure I've got everything as I want it and that's it for this lecture.
This is an incredibly useful tool but I'm going to turn off and save it.
That's what I meant to do there.
But use it with caution.
That's the main thing to take away from this lecture.
Of course you might also have one of those happy accidents where actually using the auto key frame ended
up in a brilliant result.
If you do share it with us over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.