Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to animates our camera so that gives the whole scene much more movement
Hello everybody.
So let's first of all think about what we want to do.
This is more of a refresher we played with the camera animation over in the chest section so a quick
refresher on how to do the camera movement.
First of all make sure the camera is the selected item when you go ahead and animated.
Let's bring out our key frames.
So I'm gonna go ahead not only make the timeline appear let's bring this up but also the property side
bar so we can key things in.
Remember one of the first things you'll need to do is key in the original location so we have a look
through the camera so we know what we can see and then we can go ahead and we can key in the position
and the rotation and maybe the scale as well.
I'm going to play with the scale myself but also walls to here it's a good idea to play with these settings
to understand that.
Okay.
Z's going to move the camera from the left and right.
Y is going to make everybody feel sick and X is going to lift everything up and down.
Now if you've done this your your actual fields themselves will turn orange to say it's different from
the key that you've made clicking back on any other frame will reverse it.
And if we go back to frame one you can see it is as it was before and then it's just a matter of going
to a new frame say here frame 50 shift in grave to move the camera I am fully in for this type of movement
more than anything else it allows you to move around your scene very quickly and set things up and to
press the IV key to key those in and then it's just a matter of going backwards and forwards to making
sure what you've done there look at that as we pan out is consistent and what you want it to be not
only in its speed in its transition but where the overall position of your characters and scenery actually
is one of the things you'll notice here and we will see this in the challenge it happens to me as well
is as we're panning round the objects is no longer center to our scene now we can use constraints to
control the camera as well but the other thing we can do is midway through so we had out to frame 50
is unlit she going to adjust the z value to bring it back in line now you don't want to do this too
much it can be incredibly annoying adding unnecessary key frames much like geometry but now when we
go ahead and play it we'll see that it will maintain more or certainly be more in the middle of our
animation as we go through whereas before it was sliding out into one side which is fine if you're trying
to convey movement but we're just panning around an object that is one of the ways that you could do
that.
Now one of the other things you'll notice here is that you're going to say Mike Where where are my key
frames.
I can not see them at so now this sometimes does happen if you want to see them again we can go to our
summary we notice here that nothing is actually on the summary itself which means we don't have anything
selected we need to select the camera again just because we are looking for it doesn't mean it was selected
here we go now selected we can see our key frames.
So that does happen.
That's one of the things to watch out for.
So rearmed with that knowledge.
Here's your challenge
okay.
So your challenge is to animate your camera having it follow your lamp now I'll leave this up to your
creative decisions how you want to follow your lamp through the scene you'll see how I do it in a bit.
So go ahead pulls a video now and give it go okay everybody welcome back.
Let's hop on over into blender and animator off camera.
Okay everybody so it's a matter of animating the camera to make the whole scene look a bit more dynamic.
Now at the moment we can't see anything else in the hierarchy because we've still got a look filter
applied at the top here.
So on the click of a little cross make that disappear.
Okay.
Now we can go ahead and find our camera or we can search for it.
I think getting in the habit of searching for things is a good habit to have.
It means that you're going to be able to find things naturally rather than having the habit of searching
for them manually.
Let's go ahead selects our camera and have a look through the eyes of our camera.
So at the moment if we were to go ahead and render this video it would look something like this we would
see the camera looking at the lamp and then the lamp would leave the frame and we wouldn't see anything
else.
So just like the bones themselves we can animate all of the properties of the camera if we wanted to
including its field of view.
So what I think I want to do here and of course we can tweak this and refine it as we go is I want to
make sure that I've only focused down here on the camera's position itself and of course I can move
it around with the shift in the grave key and we can use that to actually align our camera.
So the first thing we need to do is go right back to frame one and then we can go to its position information
and the rotation location information.
Now we're in pose mode at the moment and we've got our overlays turned off and so we would know that
was the case if we had our overlays turned on.
Now I can select my camera as the active item then I can key its position in.
So that's fine with its starting position but straight away we can see that as we start progressing
by frame well wherever we are here by frame 40 is pretty much left.
So let's just reframe our camera let's move it out to let's say here in Key that's in.
Now this might be horrible by the way.
And it's going to leave there.
But as we move round for I think we need to modify the why didn't I.
Anyway so about here it lands parts on the way to there.
We want it probably seeing how high it's getting so it's landing about there and then slipping off.
So again we can shift in grave key and move this around slightly and key.
That's it.
And remember now we can transition between the first one and the second.
And this is where you start pulling up your issues so we can see here that this is pretty good.
We pull out now.
This is bad framing.
By the time we're jumping in the right place which is nice we're losing most of the frame there so we
can do some things to mitigate that.
But look here as we pull the camera back we're not leaving much space to the left hand side which is
a type of methods that you can use to infer the movement of your character.
Much like if you were taking a photo of someone running you wouldn't put them up against the side of
your frame you'd leave space in front of them to run to.
And we really want to do the same thing here.
So it might be worthwhile at this point as we pull back actually shifting the camera around and we can
just play with the rotation here thinking about the camera's rotation.
X is up and down.
Why is it makes you sick.
And Z would be from the left to the right.
So what we can do here is once again click on the frame and pull the camera across more to infer the
movement and then we can key that rotation in so now it pulls back as we would expect it to.
Perfect.
Then we're jumping.
He's out of frame and he's landed and then we need to decide what we're going to do as it comes around
here.
Now the major movements are ones to do first hit and bounce and end so he really wants to be close to
our character at this point so I'm going to move the camera in nice and close and we may even wants
to add a bit where he's looking at us.
But let's leave it something like that for the moment and keep those positions in and let's see how
it looks.
Not in frame for some of it now here where he's looking at us.
He's no longer looking at us.
So might be a good idea at this point to move the camera to a position where he is looking at this as
at this point we're being looked at.
Let's move the camera into the appropriate position which is about here.
Now this may to be too fast to transition and you've got to watch out when you're moving the camera
around that it doesn't look too jerky.
That kind of feels okay.
Let's go to full screen mode with everything off and zoom in a little bit to get more of an appreciation
of what will be happening.
I do think he should look at this at the end as well.
That's one of those tweaks that we can do yeah.
I'm I'm liking that that's not too quick in its movements.
I'm liking how it works as a bit to fix there but otherwise that's pretty smooth.
Brilliant.
How did you guys get on.
I hope you'll get your camera animations all sorted out.
He didn't have any issue moving around just scene and keeping things in frame.
Get ready to show your work.
We're almost at the stage now where we can start rendering out our animation and I'll see you all in
the next lecture.