Hello everybody and welcome back.
In front of us we have our lamp laying on the floor.
We go ahead and hit F twelve.
We can start the rendering using cycles.
Now I know that this is going to take a few moments to do but critically we've got 300 frames doing
this.
So what we can do is a rough calculation if we look at the time taken.
It says 14 seconds Unger rounded up to 15 seconds just to make sure we've got everything covered.
And times it by 300.
So I can tell you roughly if I was to render this out in the same quality you can see right here it's
going to take 4500 seconds or seventy five minutes.
Now we're at the prototyping stage at the moment that's just too long.
Now I know some of you out there really want your renders when you're showing off things to look spot
on every time we're not focused on that the moment we are focused on making sure when we're rendering
out we capture the movement the lighting and everything else can come later.
And so there are plenty of ways of doing this.
So I just want to run through a few options for you to make sure that when you're rendering out we can
render things nice and quickly so you get a feel of the scene both on movement and lighting.
We'll start off with the movement OK so the elephant in the room here is Evey render engine.
So the first thing I would always recommend is that you switch over to using eevee for the movement.
And then when we go ahead and render that's out it takes less than a second with car render time down
significantly.
But of course our lighting isn't correct.
So that's one of the things to bear in mind.
The other thing that you can do perhaps your computer is in a fast as easy or the scene you're using
is quite heavy and eevee still takes some time to do we really want to test out our animation we don't
want to worry about things.
So the other thing that we can do here is switch this over to a workbench.
Then when we go ahead and render we get something that's a lot like the viewport in solid shape mode
and it's taken even less time orders of magnitude less.
And this does mean that if we wanted to we've got our animation there let's just go ahead and click
render animation and you will see here that it's counting up very very quickly which is a great way
of being able to preview your animation.
The other thing that does make a difference occasionally is the resolution that you're trying to output
as.
Now we've not set any of the options yet when it comes to rendering will go to that's in a in a future
lecture but as it is at the moment this is going to take well no time at all essentially just looks
like a jerky animation and one of the great things about previewing it at this speed is I can see that's
gone off a frame.
Of course I knew that already that's something I've got to fix in a bit but we've already got ourselves
to a point here where we've got an animation rendering incredibly quickly but it doesn't have any of
that important lighting information.
So we'll let this animation render out and what we can then do is have a closer look at including lighting
information as well okay.
So the majority of the movement is done that want to press escape we we escape out of the rendering.
But what we can then do is preview that really quickly by going to view animation or control and therefore
11:00 and we'll see what we've got so far.
So we're jumping up landing and we're off again.
So a couple of minutes we've got a preview and it's looping around quite happily.
So that's a great start but what about lighting how can we get lighting information out.
Well there's going to have to be some sacrifice of quality in order to do that.
So we're going to go back to cycles because that's where our lighting information is.
And of course it's going to take a while to compute.
Now one of the things that you can really really do to help speed things up.
We've already had a look at light paths before.
So we could lower the light paths.
Let's do the retina the render if I remember was about 14 15 seconds if we'd set the total number of
light bounces down to one.
It's going to look really odd it's going to look different.
Let's switch it.
We can see that it renders out very quickly and very rough.
Now let's go ahead and render it the last one was around 14 seconds.
Let's see what that change has made to our models and see round there it's doing some dinner poising
as well remember we've had the option turned on so we can have a much smoother image.
We're down to 12 seconds so that has made a difference to the render not significant enough.
I want to see a lot lot quicker if I'm going to have the lighting information.
So we've got a way of having the movement information the lighting information what we can then do as
I'm going to put that up to maybe four or so so we're not losing too much.
The first thing I'm going to do is go back to our day noisy scroll down to the bottom here.
I'm going to turn that off.
We turn off the noise zing.
Yes the image will look worse but it will be quicker.
Let's just see what that looks like.
Now we've played with those settings we can see it's whizzing around.
And of course your computer is going to be different.
I must emphasize the fact that you're going to have to play of the settings yourself to see how quickly
your computers can render animations out.
Now this is down to seven.
So if half the time.
That's a great start.
I don't care if it looks ropey.
This is 10 ATP.
One thing that will impact your render time is the resolution of your final image.
So let's come out again go back to our render tab.
Oh I did mean the output tab but whilst we're here I'll render samples.
We've talked about this before as well.
We set that down to one sample and render it out.
It's very quick but we will lose quite a bit of information in the process if we set this up.
Maybe let's have it 16 or eights let's do eight.
Let's see how quick is that.
It's going to be slightly longer.
So we're down to two seconds.
Now let's do the final thing that I wanted to do which is lower the resolution I with the quality that
it is.
Anyway I don't need to render out at 10 ATP so this is full high definition.
Then if you wanted four K you could bump that up 200 percent or type in the pixel count.
I'm just gonna set this at 50 percent for the moment.
That is that's less than 720 P and we've rendered it very very quickly.
That's nice.
How about if we set it down at 20 percent.
There is a point at which it just becomes silly.
I think that's enough as well if you was showing that or with someone on their phone that's that's about
right for the size of a phone screen.
Obviously I know some of you want real quality outputs.
I want to set this down to 1 percent just to show you a certain point.
You just get a junk load of pixels.
So I'm going to set this I think at 25 percent and go ahead and render the animation again.
Now you can see it's going through.
I think there might even be a tiny bit quicker zoom out here.
Now we're not going to get to see the render output.
So this is going through incredibly quickly and then leave it to go through and we'll review the animation
in a few moments on the floor for quite some time.
I think I do need to adjust the render length of my animation.
I can then close down the preview and we can simply go to render render animation.
Ah then want to do that.
It doesn't matter because it's the same information as we have before I'm going to view the animation
and there we go.
That's the animation as is I can make it full screen is going to be ropey because it's low quality but
we can see here the light itself.
Now I'm not sure if that lamp is bright enough because I can only really see it lower down or whether
the light samples coming from it are too little to get the impact.
And I think that entire scene can be slightly darker as well but this is what I mean by testing the
lighting information.
We can test out the overall scene by doing one single frame render which is just an image like we would
normally do but when it comes to animation and changing view Well we've really got to render out the
entire animation to make sure it's behaving as we would expect it to.
Okay.
So in summary we can tweak our settings when it comes to rendering out remember you have to turn them
back against and make a note if you're unsure in order to get the lighting information coming across
and into our scene.
The other thing that we can do is we can render out either with eevee or workbench on much more complicated
scenes in order so we can see the movement much more clearly.
So that's it for this lecture your challenged to take away from this is to test your individual setup
and see what's working best for you.
You don't have to share that with everybody else but if you do choose to it will help others as well
decide how to set up their system.
So I'm running as we can see here I'm running a Intel Core I 770 700 K at four point two gigahertz energy
force GTA x 10 80.
So I would expect anybody with a similar system to mine to have a similar setup to me.
However if your settings vary from this if you've got a more powerful processor or more powerful graphics
card or a less powerful processor or graphics card your settings will vary.
And it's up to you to test that.
But as you do please do let us know over on the forums so that people can cherry pick solutions that
have already been made just to speed up the workflow for everyone.
So there we go your challenge for this lecture is to test your settings.
Let us know what works best for you.
And I'll see you all over in the next one.