Welcome to copying meche properties in this video you will learn how to copy attributes of a mesh object.
See that this is actually really useful when you have lots of components for example that need the same
material apply to them and understand that it is a destructive operation that is copying materials from
one mess to another will overwrite a meshes current materials.
So let's go explore this now and hop straight on over into blender.
Hey welcome back over into blender so I've noticed as I open this up that's I've got a warning and that
warnings just disappear.
But what I can do is expose the window associated with the info header and we can see what's going on.
So not much has happened here we can see that it's brought in its red library for the meche data and
loads of other things.
Oh got this red line here so we got a warning.
That was the box that appeared a moment ago that the wall is missing from this particular file and I
think I've read rename that and it's ended up being bald 0 0 1 now.
It doesn't seem to have any impact on my 3D view so let's just have a look.
Quick Rick look around our model and see if we can work out where this has gone wrong.
So a wall pace for instance.
And while all these blank areas here are war pieces Incidentally I have noticed that the wall pieces
I've not applied the texture to both sides so it looks good here.
But if that piece is flipped round it's still rather plain and I can see that on the inside of the church
as well.
Okay so I suspect that it's this roof area here that prehaps causing the problem.
I remember that having a texture on it and it doesn't anymore and I can't remember removing that and
it does say wall in the materials properties here.
So in order to select linked materials i.e. other objects that may use the same material way as you
probably already guess it's in the select menu.
If we go down to the select menu and go to linked at the very top there we can see we can select anything
that's got the same object data material data texture data et cetera.
So if I go ahead and click on material we should find that that selects everything else that uses the
same material.
Now that it's done that I can go ahead and change the material for all of those so I can use the dropdown
here and just change it.
Let's say two linked wall.
One that does work.
One that's enough.
Just going to save the file before I do any rendering and let's render that out.
Now it's got a similar colour to the rest of the world in fact probably got a text on it.
Yes it has.
Okay so that's one way we can go about selecting everything that has the same linked property everything
that shares something similar.
But what about the ones that we want to make the same.
So what we can do here is I can select.
And then we go out of rendered mode against That's a bit quicker.
I'm going to go ahead and select this roofline here and then go ahead and select the new roofline.
Just here this silver arch way into the into the model itself.
So then what I can do once I've selected them both holding down the SHIFT key there.
There we go.
Got them both selected.
I can go ahead and go to object and make links so I can make links to the materials.
Okay now all of this overwrites what they were using before so let's go and see what's just happened.
So it's gone the other way round.
It has taken the last selected items of the active selected and applied that to all the other selected
objects.
Everything that did have it has now gone backwards on both sides there so need to be careful about which
way we select things.
So if I wanted this material the top to share the same material as the wall for instance I would need
to select the wall last.
So could I go ahead and select the roof and the do it so I can see one selecting and must select these
areas here.
The little bits sticking out still don't know the name for that.
And then finally I'm going to select a wall piece.
Now I'm going to use a shortcut key which was control in L and select materials.
Now when we go into rendered mode or material mode we can see that it's now using the same material
as the wall piece.
We can also see areas that are not using that so this area here for instance is a little triangle in
the top corner here.
We can go ahead select that select the wall pace and again control an L and select materials and now
it will share the same material as before.
So it's the last one that you're selecting the active selection that is going to be the source for the
material to be copied to the other selected items.
And that is incredibly powerful especially when working with a large object like this where otherwise
I'd have to go round and select each one individually and that would be a real pain in the backside
to do.
So this is coming along really nicely now.
I'm still not too sure on the roof pieces here and I certainly need to change the colour of that.
But this is just a demonstration of how you can move those about.
I think the roof does need to be a different colour than the set of the walls Otherwise it does look
a bit odd.
But of course now we have explored linking these objects.
I've got a challenge for you.
I would like you to explore different material choices.
So just as a reminder here make sure you save your farm before exploring with any thing you do in blender
that's potentially high or highly destructive such as changing materials about willy nilly.
You may want to make a backup of your file or even you save as and progressed from there and give your
file a version number.
Explore different material options for your models in the scene see if you can come up with anything
that's slightly different See how that affects your scene and remember to use the linking to quickly
change a large number of objects at once.
Pause the video now and give that a go.
Okay guys.
Welcome back.
Let's hop back on over in a blender.
So the first thing I'm going to do here is actually heed my own advice not divisive to save my work
and I'm with a save as and I'm going to add staddon material.
Exploration on the end.
And then when we save as we find that we're working on that brand new file which is very powerful we'd
say and don't want to make up our original far in list now opens up the realm for exploration and I'm
going to change to material mode here so I can see a bit clearer what's going on as I move around the
model without having to wait for it to render all the time.
So one of the things that I can do here is literally select absolutely everything.
Now when you do that it's the last selected object that becomes the active object.
So if you had selected let's say one of these volts on the top or whatever you're working on and then
pressed a twice it's still the active object.
The original one that you selected and then it has everything on it.
Now of course because of selected everything.
If I go and apply the materials everything has that one material applied to it and that is interesting
seeing that brick texture over the entire world itself.
Now the question is Have we lost all of the properties all together.
So these are sort of the explorations that you can do.
So the answer there is yes we have.
So even though we've not lost things like the displacement modifier and items like that we have actually
lost the fact that it sets the material to use another texture to Alpher it out around the edge here.
So it became more and more transparent my sky texture obviously hasn't changed at all that still the
default sky if I go off to my world to hear you see I've picked sky texture and I've just left these
as the faults here.
So that is looking a bit more grey scale than it was previously.
Obviously this doesn't change the geometry.
However we can use this to change the geometry as well which is incredibly powerful.
So let's undo that and our own blender has crashed.
Now I didn't plan this but this is a warning that when you start mucking about with things it's very
easy to crash blender.
Someone's going to click reopen then see where we were before.
Some will open up material exploration it's probably just where the save was before which was where
I was going back to anyway.
So let's say for instance I select this wall piece in the middle and then go ahead shift and select
the window on top.
I can go control in L and link object data and there we go I've got another window in place very powerful
for swapping things in and out as well as changing materials.
Brilliant.
How did you guys get on did you do any modifications to your model after exploring different materials.
If you have make sure you share your work in the discussions and I will see you guys in the next lecture.