Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to have a look at expectations see you know what's coming up and also how
some of these decisions affect workflow versus doing it just yourself.
Once you've gathered all of this knowledge because the methodology that we're using won't always apply.
Sometimes you will do the modelling first and then rickets and that would be typical in industry for
instance you'd often not even do the rigging yourself it would be passed on to the rigor if you would
just doing the modelling or as a rigor.
You may actually get a model passed to you that then you have to rig.
But in this particular section we're going to end up with the same results.
Whatever path we decide to take.
But what is really important is that we test things as we go.
So we're going to start off with a bit of a blender setup and explanations we've already set up the
scene ready to do some work in.
But because we're using cycles we need to understand how that works and how it works differently on
different computers with some with graphics card some with multiple use or try and cover the vast majority
of you out there so you know what to expect and how blender behaves because sometimes people get a bit
confused of why things are all noisy and or grainy and don't look very good especially since we've been
used to eevee up until this point.
Now we're going to do many iterations through to the end even though the lamp won't be fully belts.
So this alludes to what I was saying earlier where we would typically model something completely and
then go and rig it.
What we will be doing is modelling a part of the lamp then rigging it to make sure it's working as we
would expect it.
So rather than get to the end of the modelling stage only to find that we need to change something of
the model to make sure the rig works properly later on rendering times unlikely to be a lot longer than
the last section primarily because we're focusing on cycles and that does take longer to render than
evey does but throughout the section I will show you some hints and tips on to make sure even if you've
got a slower computer that you are able to get the best or the most out of your computer by only focusing
on areas that you actually want to see rendered and we'll be making the lamp and testing as we go.
That's the important thing.
So we wouldn't be necessarily following a typical workflow of making and modelling everything and then
rigging it and then animating it will be just testing things as we go to get the feel of everything
and then we'll loop background to the end.
And one of the things that we will be doing that is slightly different is we will be building all of
the components of the lamp as individual mesh objects.
And then at the very end combining them all together into one mesh objects.
The reason for making them separately is it just allows us to focus on the different parts of our model
individually make sure that they all work as expected and then finally put them all together into one
object.
The benefit of it being one object is then you can 3d printer then you can export one object and then
it will work in the game engines for instance if we leave a separate mesh objects it can be a real fast
to get it working externally in blender so we'll blend it all together at the end.
And of course if you wanted to after learning all of this knowledge you could create your lamp just
as one single mesh object.
But unfortunately because we'd be using things like the mirror modifier it would be best to build it
separately first rather than trying to do it in edit mode throughout that would be very confusing.
OK.
So without any further ado let's hop on over into blender and start setting up Arsene.