Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture let's export our animated lamp into two game engines.
But also let's explore what else we can do how else we can export our models.
So when it comes to exporting your model the first thing to think about is where are you exporting it
to.
So in this particular case I'm going to be testing the Unity game engine and the unreal game engine.
There are obviously plenty of other places that you could export you could be exposed to another 3D
program you could be exporting into another game engine there are plenty of different options now you
do have to bear in mind that those different options will come with different export settings so we
can't possibly go through everything at this point in time.
First of all we need to figure out what are we exporting because we could export absolutely everything.
In fact that's something a lot of people accidentally end up doing.
So here we have a look at our entire scene.
If we didn't have anything selected whatsoever.
OK if we go up to file and go down to export we see we've got quite a few options and we're not limited
to these options but these are the ones that are bundled with Blender.
Now we'll go through every one in detail but let's just gloss over some of the ones that I'm very familiar
with myself.
A collider you if you need something in Trimble sketch up colliders the way to go with that way front
would also work but way front tends to be very basic and doesn't often export everything that you want
it to.
Now the other thing to have a look at here and the one we'll be focused on.
You just saw unreal pop up there we're going to hop over to that in a moment.
And that's why we're going to focus on SB X in this lecture are both unreal and unity both supports
FBI X so we're gonna be using that as our example export formats.
The other one that a lot of you may be interested in is the S T L format that is traditionally used
with printers.
So when you actually put a file into your slicing program you'd typically export as an S T L first.
This final one at the bottom have a G.I. t f 2.0 standard.
This is an up and coming standard and I really hope it gains a lot of traction and hopefully unity and
unreal will start supporting this fully soon.
And it being an open standard means that everybody can contribute to it.
And we've seen what open software can be like.
Blender is absolutely phenomenal because of that.
Anyway let's just go to SB X export so you go ahead and go to export it.
Now it's come up with animated lamp FBI X surely we just click export FBI X and away we go well they
would export absolutely everything in our scene and really all we want is our lamp and its armature.
So we need to think very carefully about how we're going to do this.
A couple of ways that we could do this is we could create a new scene in blender with only those two
items in it.
But to be quite honest we don't want to flash around too much with that what we can do is select the
lamp hold down shift select the armature.
Then when we go to file an export under FBI X we have an option selected objects in fact most of the
export options have the option to Export selected objects and we've got a load of other options in here.
I'm not going to dive into the details at this point we just want to see whether this works outside
a blender.
There's a couple of tabs along the top here.
One thing actually before we explore those you will notice above the export there there's an invisible
bar here.
And I've seen this all the way down here and you've got this little up arrow that can be incredibly
confusing let's click it to bring that back up or I've seen this all the way at the top here covering
up the other ones not great UI but it's easy to fix as well.
The other options along these tabs then we've got geometry apply modifiers is usually a good idea so
we'll let that go.
And then we've got an option here about normals and we'll see in a moment the unreal will actually complain
when we go ahead and export.
So what we can do here is switch this from normals only to face and that will sort out some of the error
messages we will get armature.
Well we do want to export our armature.
I'm going to leave it as the fault here for the moment and the animation we do want to export that as
well.
So I'm going to export it into my animated lamp folder is going to export SB X and let's see what happens
when we first of all have a look at unreal.
So I've got a scene already set up here.
Let's go ahead and click the import button in the content browser.
It's going to go straight to the folder that I wanted.
This is so it's nice and quick and we get a load of options here.
Now you may not see this area just here.
There's the little arrow that you can drop these things down if you're doing this.
We don't actually need all of those details so let's hide them away.
So it's a skeletal mesh.
That means we've got a rig controlling it a Bowen based rig and we also want to import the match.
That's that's the standard here.
That's a given.
Now it may look odd that the skeleton is not coming through and we'll get back to that in a moment and
import constants like geometry and skinning weights is absolutely fine.
Well we want that we do want to import animations and the animated length make sure it's set at the
moment animated time.
What we can do is set a specific range that's useful if you need to import certain animations on a timeline.
Now just remember that at the moment our animation isn't one that would loop around like an idol or
a walking animation but it is an animation over a set time which might be akin to a death animation.
So let's go ahead.
An animated time is what we want.
Everything else okay.
And we're going to click imports all.
Now when it comes to things like materials if you'd set up something fancy we've got a couple of errors
or not they're not errors they're warnings they're warning us that something might not work as expected
or it's expecting something else to also be there.
I'm just going to ignore those for the moment though not important for us testing here.
Now if we double click in the content browser under our animated lamp in the top right we end up with
four separate areas that we can look at we can look at the individual skeleton and then we look on the
left hand side those we've got the base the look and the stamp.
Elvis is quite interesting.
These are bones what we've seen before that's the skeleton.
We have a look at the mesh we see the mesh and we look at the animation.
This is where it starts getting a bit weird.
It seems like it's playing something down here but I can't see anything going on and you might struggle
with this without even knowing what the issue is.
I do want to quickly look at the physics tab because I like pushing this button here and watching our
lamp go flop.
Anyway simple things as they say.
So what's going on here with the animation.
Well there's kind of a bug in the FBI export what it comes across from blender.
So the first thing I'm going to do is just click the cross at the top hits close and those extra windows
I'm going to hold down shift and select all of these things that are imported.
Notice it's imported some materials.
And whilst it has imported those base colors in general when you import any model into a third party
program you're going to have to set up your materials your textures again.
Then that's important.
We'll get to that in the next section where we start unwrapping our models because that will tell blender
specifically and external programs as well how to map a texture to a particular model.
Anyway let's delete those out the way and I'm going a forced delete them to get them out of there.
Let's go back up to blender.
OK.
So the problem here is that our armature is called armature.
You won't believe it's that simple.
Unfortunately it is.
So we go and change this to something like lamp rig and do exactly the same export.
Let's make sure that both of our models are selected.
So our model and our armature are selected and then go to export.
Now there is a warning here or rather that isn't a warning when we go ahead and try and export under
the same name and click export aspects.
It didn't say Are you sure that's something to watch out for if you've got a a series of models in a
folder.
It's very easy to accidentally end up overwriting something that you didn't mean.
So let's go over into unreal and repeat the same process we did before so I'm going to import our animated
lamp and when we do that I can just click imports all its can to remember the previous settings.
Now when we go ahead you will notice that some of these icons look slightly different which is pretty
awesome.
We've got less errors even better.
I should say I shouldn't say Error Sorry less warnings.
And if we have a look at our animated lamp underneath the animation tab there's now something there.
In fact it's our animation.
How awesome is that.
And even better if we go ahead and let's come out of this window for the moment and drag our animated
lamp into our scene there we go.
It's in the world live and we wanted to drag the animation in now we could do that as well.
We could go ahead and drag this next one into the scene and I believe if we're lucky they'll probably
jump out of our view off it goes there brilliant look you can see its shadow just falling away.
Excellent.
So that's some real covered.
Let's go dive over into unity and see what happens there.
So over in Unity One of the things that you may find interesting is that you can open up or what seems
like you can open up blend files within unity.
That's not strictly true but I'll show you this very quickly anyway if I go ahead here and grab my animated
lamp blend file and drag it across into the assets folder.
Give it a few moments and it seems to have imported it.
In fact we could click and drag it across and you know what.
That's pretty impressive that we can get a working scene over from blender into unity and it just comes
across like this.
That's pretty awesome.
But it's a problem.
And the reason why it's a problem in our particular case is if we were to go ahead and modify anything
in here it will update in this scene which is really awesome.
Apart from when you start getting very large files at that point if someone in a team let's say were
to modify blend file your Unity project would update immediately.
That's really annoying if you're trying to do something else at the time.
And it's also really annoying if you're trying to work on something you alter one model and it's just
a tiny change but it's a big model unity will have to open up blender in the background and redo all
of its fancy exporting and then bring it in.
So in general I would avoid doing this unless you wanted to bring in a static scene that you've already
made over in Blender.
Okay.
So what about importing and SB X so we go ahead and grab our animated lamp.
SB X which is kind of what unity was doing in the background and drag that in that looks a lot better
that looks like something we can use.
If I go ahead and drag that into my scene if I am just going to plop it's in the scene hierarchy and
then it's going to be at 0 0 0 in our world which means that if we have a look at the game tap we can
see it there.
Now it won't work straight away we can't just click play and do anything because we've not set up an
animation controller.
However if we go into the details with this little arrow here we can open up one of the animation files
and if I scroll out here and then press play we will see that it's playing the animation.
Now obviously this is jumping onto an invisible block we haven't brought that across.
And then it's landing on the floor.
And if you bear with me a few moments I can set this up so it does it in unity as well.
OK.
So I think I've got everything sorted out there and the camera I don't think it's in a good position
so let me move that okay.
So with everything set up I think the final thing here is to play our game and see if that works Excellent.
So there we go there.
In a nutshell is exporting from blender and seeing your work being alive in another program as phenomenal
now as I've mentioned before and I just want to repeat myself here.
When it comes to things like materials and setting all those up that is really done in the game engine
or in the third party program you're using.
So here for instance even though it's come across and brought across the base color that red in both
unity and unreal is not set up properly it's not quite any of that shyness that we'd set up and that's
because materials work differently in each of the engines.
Now unreal and even rendering engines are very very similar which is incredibly useful.
He can pretty much copy your settings across and almost the same hair as well.
And we're getting to some of these other things the albedo or the bass color metallic normals height
maps et cetera and they're all coming up in the next section.
So please share your work if you have exported your model into another program.
Let me know which program and share your results as well.
I'm really looking forward to seeing how you've brought your lamps alive in different places as well.
That's it for this lecture and I'll see you all in the next one.