Hello everybody and welcome in this lecture we're going to discuss making a standard asset so in front
of us here we have a very low polygon pawn and it's based upon the staunton chess set that we saw
earlier.
Now one of the things to bear in mind that all of the chess set has a similar base to it.
So if I was to take this top piece off we could place the bishop the king the queen even the knight
itself on top of here with a few modifications and of course the rook as well.
So we've got this standard asset that we can create once and use again and again and again and perhaps
make a few modifications obviously to its size.
And of course to how it looks.
OK.
So now a blender open we've got a couple of ways that we're going to do this.
The first thing to bear in mind is that you will have to have the add on turned on if you've somehow
lost the add on you go to edit preferences and under here we've got the add ons on the left here, If we
search here for planes we've got import, export, import images as planes.
This is the important thing here we need it as a plane and not an empty.
If we have imported as an empty then we can't do any scaling to it and we can't set the plane.
In this case to the appropriate size which is going to save us a lot of time aligning our reference
material.
So let's go ahead we can go file import images as planes once that add on is turned on.
Or we could add image images as planes.
So in this case I'm going to add my image as a plane.
I need to go to the right place.
We can't just drag and drop it in it that'll add an empty.
So we need to go to the appropriate location find look under recent we see here we've got models.
I'm going to go up a level down to reference and then find our pawn and what we should find if I go
ahead and delete the cube.
This is the important thing here we need to be able to see our plane.
Look at it from the front or side and then it's just a matter of organizing it and we can see here that
we've got ourselves in the properties panel.
This is situated around the origin being 0 0 0.
But we really want to lift it up and I want to see what I'm doing as well.
So I'm going to turn on lookdev mode so I can see what I'm doing.
Go into edit mode and just go G Z and lift it up.
Now by how much.
Well if we have a look at the size of the plane itself out in object mode we've actually got a dimension
here of Y is one metre an X is about 58 centimetres.
So the first thing that would strike you here is how's that X and Y there.
And that's Z didn't Y that we can see what's going on here.
Well when you're dealing with two the objects in Blender X is to the left and right and Y is up and
down it's as simple as that.
It doesn't respect the fact that it's in a 3D world it's talking about its local dimensions.
So in this case we can see that it's one metre high and it's 58 centimetres or fifty eight point seven
centimetres wide.
So at this point we can just go to our dimensions and think well a pawn is going to be three centimeters.
So we could type in nought point nought three or remember we can type in three centimetres or remember
that we can also.
That's a problem there of course that we just squished it lots.
We need to divide it by the same amount or of course we can go to our scene settings go to our units
and change it to centimeters and then we can just type in these figures normally.
Okay.
So let's undo that for a second because I want this as is.
And let's go ahead and change this back.
to centimeters then all the fields are correct.
Whilst in edit mode which I was in I'm going to go G Z point five.
Oh No, haha!
We're in centimeters that's gonna be 50 centimeters.
Now I know that sat on the ground.
That's a good start.
But the next thing to work out is how do I make this the right width.
Well in this case what we can do is we can press the S key to start scaling.
Remember you can hold down shift to move things very slowly and we will find as we scale down the dimensions
gets towards three centimeters, Let's scale that again and you can see it starts and get very very very
small.
And as we approach three centimeters we can hold down shift and just do the final few bits and there
we go.
We've got it at three centimeters and five centimeters high.
Now that is encouraging because we establish that a king is approximately nine and a half centimeters
high.
When we were doing our research so that is a good indication that we're around the right size.
I'm just going to apply the scale on this because that's just habit and we can see it's not exactly
five centimeters.
So now we have our image at the right scale and we can start constructing the rest of our model and
for that it's time for your challenge. Okay everybody it's time for your challenge.
I'd like you to go ahead if you haven't done already to import the Staunton pawn dot PNG.
Of course if you're using your own reference material then you'll want to import that and of course
set it to the appropriate size to help you judge the scale of your model I'd then like to add a cylinder
and get it to be the right diameter and height for the base not the entire model but the base itself.
Make sure the origin is at the base of the cylinder that's going to be important for later on we're
not doing physics or anything but it is going to be important so we can place it correctly on our scene.
And remember don't worry about getting the shape of the base right.
We're going to do that in the next lecture and then I'd like you to save your file as perhaps chess
piece base or chess piece templates whatever's easiest for you to name it.
I'm going to keep mine as chess piece base of course pause a video now and give that a go. Okay everybody
Welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and create our chess piece base OK so we have our pawn ready to go and the next thing
we need to do is insert a cylinder.
So let's go control and A.
And add in a cylinder.
Now I'm also going to make sure I name things as I go this is going to be huge.
I'm going to go straight away and change the radius from 100 centimeters.
Now remember the radius is only half the diameter.
We're going to set that's a one point five.
Which is fine.
There we go it's the right size.
And then the next thing we need to do here's the depth.
And we worked out that was going to be about five centimeters okay.
And the location.
Well we could shift up slightly.
I'm going to do that manually in a moment.
So there we go.
We've got the cylinder in there it's just in the wrong place at the moment.
So we could lift it up and apply the scale but that doesn't put the origin where we want it to be.
I'm going to do things in a slightly different order.
I'm going to go round to the bottom and use the snapping tools that we used before.
I'm going to select this face along the bottom and then go shift and S and cursor to selected.
Now that we've done that we can come out into object mode right click and move the origin to the 3D
cursor.
Now the origin is that the base.
We can just set our Z value to zero.
Now it may seem a little bit convoluted that we went that way round.
But this is an important skill.
We happen to know that it was going to be exactly two points five centimeters that we needed to shift
this pawn up but that might not be the case in all circumstances so it's better to learn the more advanced
skill knowing that you can just type in a whole value if it happens to end up that way.
Okay.
So looking at my transforms there's nothing I need to apply.
I'm going to go into edit mode and select this top face I'm going to bring it down.
Now I'm going to bring it down to one centimeter initially and let's look at it from the side.
Now that's not where the base ends so I'm going to press G and then press the Z key to lock it to the
Z axis and I'm going to bring it up to that base level.
And we can see it's around here.
Give or take.
And that is a one point three seven eight seven centimeters.
Now it's not important that we have that precise it's not a mechanical part that needs to mesh in with
anything else.
We could round it up we could round it down but I'm going to leave it exactly like it is there.
I'm happy with that.
I'm going to make sure I now save my piece.
Go ahead save this, Needs to be in the right place.
So in my model's folder we currently have the board and I'm going to call this chess piece base and of
course you can call it whatever you like as long as it makes sense as to what you're going to use it
for.
So this is my chess piece base.
And what that does mean is I can start from this position every time for all of my pieces.
And there we go with that saved we're all sorted.
And of course we can now use this as a template file we can open up this file and save as pawn or bishop
and modify it from there.
Now what we're likely to do is get it right for the pawn and then go ahead and re save it for the other
four pieces that will share the same base size.
So we're going to modify this template as we go but that's it for this lecture.
How did you guys get on.
Did you manage to get everything sorted out in the right scale and proportions.
I hope you did.
Share your work over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.