In this video we're gonna shape our head just to get the macro structure of it to get it blocked out
the nose the eyes the mouth the ears and to get the shape looking like our reference images.
I'll start off by showing you some options for tools to use and also the settings that I'm gonna be
using.
I'll be using the snake hook tool a bunch.
Now you can see the size of my brush.
I'm gonna make it a little bit bigger.
Pull about that size.
The benefit of having about this size is if I've scrolled out then I can grab large areas of my model
and move them around.
I can also scroll in and then grab more smaller areas and make more of a shot and movement rather than
having to go in and out of the brush the whole time it's good to use your zoom in and out through that
having a big brush you can do macro movements at the start and it's really important.
Just focus on those macro movements pushing shaping.
Don't get into the fine detail just yet.
We're going to be doing that after we've got our everything blocked out.
We want it to be the other main tool you could use his grab is very similar to the snake oil tool it's
going to grab and move things pull them along.
You hold down control then it will push things in.
The main difference let's have a look here if I get my brush reasonable size.
Now I've got the strength of this set point five.
If I grab a side of it with the grab tool grab grab grab grab grab grab.
You can see it keeps going and going and going going going similar.
If we were to hold down control and push it within the head.
However if I'm using the snake oil tool and do the same thing let me just check my strength Phillips
1.
I'll put it at point five as well if I grab it grab grab grab grab.
Then after all it stops pulling it it has an elasticity to it where it stops.
After a while.
So I find it a little bit more forgiving using the snake tool than the grab tools so I tend to use that
a little bit more.
And so the challenge I have for you you can do this at the same time.
I'm working through my model or you can wait and see how I do it and then go about it your way is to
get the overall shape that you want.
Don't go for the details yet block out the nose block out the eye sockets block out the ears and block
out the lips and to shape the chin and the jaw line.
Don't add any fine detail just yet.
And in terms of the chin and jaw line in terms of the neck I will be adding a neck to the model but
I'll be doing that after I've finished doing the general shape so I'll be doing it off until the bottom
of the jaw line and then later on we're just gonna yank out a whole bunch of neck from the head it sounds
really gross isn't it.
But we will yank neck later on it's going to start by pulling with the snake hook tool.
Make sure I've got my brush reasonably good sized just pulling into the shape of the head.
Looking at the reference a lot.
I'll start with a bit of a front view.
Just get the front view roughly how I want it pull the chin down the chin down.
Oh well I remember I forgot one last tool and that is I'll be using smoothing so you can see if you
add a little bit detail like I was playing around with the mouth here.
If I want to flatten that down I can hold down shift shift will allow me to use the smooth tool from
any of my tools have a hold down shift you can see it's flattening the surface back down now.
The strength of that is going to depend upon what our smooth tool strength is so if I click on the smooth
tool and then shift F if I have that it really small say point 1 and then I go to any of my other tools
like snake hook hold down shift.
It's not really doing very much at all.
If I go to my smooth Tool Shift F put that all the way up to 1 and then go back to my snake Coco grab
or draw hold down shift and you can see it's doing a lot stronger in terms of the smoothing.
So I will leave my smooth tool at around about point 5 I think is a good spot.
You don't have it too strong because you can accidentally just blast away things that you've done like
if you put on drawer and then you hold down shift.
That's not too bad that smoothing it down the right I won't.
But if it's pushing it too fast just remember you can always go and change the smooth brush value.
Okay.
I miss my I do it up a little bit here with a few smudgy bits but not to worry I'm going to grab my
snake hook tool and just go about the process of pushing it into place trying to get the shape of the
head as I want it pulling the top bits up to a pass from the front first of all trying to get the general
shape and this is why I like to have the grease pencil here so at this very very very start point I
can just get it roughly into the shape that I want now is where we need to start scrolling so we can
see that hasn't gone exactly to plan so I've got a little bit of a lumpy head there not a problem I
do kind of have a little bit of a lumpy head hopefully you've got a great reference you're using something
that inspires you could be yourself it could be a famous actor or a superhero or a movie star or any
of those kind of things because a famous actor would be a movie star wouldn't it.
OK so is yanking the headline off I want a more sort of solid front forehead type thing the chin is
goodness.
Why is the chin high back there.
Let's drag it forward ragged forward ragged forward make sure we're looking front sort of accidentally
lifting a little bit the lips in there but that's fine.
Drag the chin forward pull down the jaw line so my jaw line goes like that I'm not trying to recreate
my image perfectly here I'm just using it for reference in the end I don't think it's actually going
to look like me OK I'm not that's not my goal in this exercise I'm just trying to get ahead and I'm
using this big buffet it over here as an example of how to go about doing that so yank out the chin
a little bit you can see when was zoomed out and we've got a big brush everything's pretty macro with
how it moves around a little bit of a mess up here it's going to hit shift to smooth things down liberate
the top smooth it out a little bit drag in the head dragging the head and get up and get up so I'll
speed up a little bit of the video as I go if I think I'm just sort of yanking around bits of the sculpture
and I don't have anything new to tell you but each time I've got something that I think is noteworthy
I'll jump back and pause the video so just getting the shape in here it's flat a bit of a nose start
working on the shape for that so we'll just yank it out where my grease pencil marks are OK so you can
see the brush was either too big or I was too zoomed out Yank Yank yank on the nose yank on the nose
okay.
It's a good starting point a little bit too long my nose is big but not quite that big I know I've got
a little bit more of an arch going up there push push push push.
That's good.
And then we'll get some nostril action happening just drag to the side drag drag drag drag your drag
down a little bit of pushing up pain so the snake OK tools not just for pulling things out but also
pushing things back in again we can do that now I think with the eye I'm going to push the eyes in a
little bit getting a bit closer for this maybe the brush a little bit smaller push shooting push it
in and push it in nearly at the point where the grease pencil has served its purpose and I want to get
it out of the way but we'll leave it there just a moment longer push it and push it in I'm actually
pushing it in yep good starting looks like an alien perfect that's what we're going for so it's all
good we can fix all this later on if we don't get it exactly right we're just going for shape at the
moment I can see it's a little bit sharp there which I don't like but like I said before we'll fix that
a little bit later on I just want to get the shape let's have a look how is the general back of the
head
ok not super happy with the mouth let's see what we can do about that it looks like it's a little bit
too low what I put in there before.
Let's put it a little bit more properly I will turn the power down on this so I can go a bit slower
on the mouth than I did last time it's generally it hold down control this slurp that pot in a little
bit and shifts its smooth roll out a little bit more great and grab the K as the hot key to grab the
snake look to move all of the mouth up a little bit more a little bit more now I can see it's fairly
flat for me in between the lip and the nose and I've got this weird kind of indent so push the whole
mouth in a little bit more I think it's not gonna stick out quite so much.
Well you might want to do while you still are learning and practicing is to do a caricature.
So what that means is to exaggerate things for example make the nose really big and to make the forehead
for the fore head really pronounced maybe not horns but you get the picture and do something a little
bit more stylized so you're not feeling the frustration of a habit it doesn't look like what I'm trying
to have it look like OK the eyes.
I'm pretty happy with the spot there I'm not happy with the shape of them but we'll cross that a little
bit more later on it's going to smooth this out and you can see that my eye comes back down.
So at the moment going up to high again snake tongue and to grab all of that all of that and drag it
down drag it down another little technique if you find yourself wanting to grab a large area and drag
it down.
But as a result say you're dragging down this as well which we didn't want to do is remember that you
can go in and mask that so you just use mask paint in this area and so I don't really want to affect
that.
You might want to do it a little bit tighter than what I've done just there.
But you can mask this area out.
So then when you do go and grab K for grab a snake quick tool it's not going to be moving around that
particular geometry just below the then under the mask just control and box mask control grab the whole
area blink.
That should undo it all.
Cool.
Remember to keep rotating around your model very very important.
Keep looking at the shape from all angles look at the lines so at the moment I've got this fully straight
line down the front of my face I'm going to go exactly on the side angle how's my line doing there okay.
You can see the forehead needs to be pulled out a bunch more so I will K and then pull that forward
forward forward.
Make sure you grab a few sides and I'm going to swing around make sure I can give myself some lumps
yet I'm looking a little bit alien ish that's fine.
So push that you know I do kind of look a little bit alien with my full head as it is smooth it down
a tiny bit.
OK good.
Back on exactly the side few and pull this up a little bit.
And then from the front view I think I need to widen it all okay so the lines at the front you can see
down the right and the left it's fairly straight.
My model at the moment has a little bit more curvature to it than I'd like
and I'd just get rid of my grease pencil.
Now just click on the ice that's not there anymore.
I would do a tiny bit of fine tuning to the nose.
I think the bridge needs to go up a little bit higher it is grabbing and pushing it up and it's a little
bit round and bulbous at the moment.
I'm gonna pull out some nostrils.
Not a lot of detail here.
Just the general shape and a little bit.
Flatter on the tip and pushing the creases next to the nose you can see in here we've got fairly sharp
creases.
We'll use some tools when we get into the detail to make those creases pronounced but now it just getting
in the shape.
Okay.
The other thing is cheeks so where are my cheeks.
They're kind of opposite the bottom of my nose so I want to pull those out a little bit.
I tried different tool here and I try to inflate to to see if I can give a little bit of inflation just
to puff out those cheeks.
Not too much I don't have big O cheekbones Yeah.
That's a bit better.
Okay now let's do one of the tricky parts of the whole exercise which is the is now the ease you can
see here for me a little bit below my eyes or the top of the ear is a round about the eyes my eyes on
huge so you might want to do your eyes a little bit bigger and the bottom of the mouth.
So basically the years go from the eye to the mouth when looking at the side view the way I'm going
to go about doing this is just using the snake tool and just yank out a blob.
I can get the right angle here a little bit smaller on this tool so it's a little bit more pronounced
yank out a blob you get another another blob below that.
Yeah that's pretty good.
Now the blob just a little bit in front of it and then yank this out a little bit more my eyes don't
stick out some people's eyes take out a little bit more like a like an elephant's my ear certainly does
not do the elephant type here.
Okay.
Now that we've got this in the macro position let's have a look right from the side view.
I can see that the top of my ear is way above my eyes.
So make my snake or to a little bit bigger.
And this is where I'm going to mask.
Actually I will grab the mask.
I'm going to mass the area that I want to change around here I want to grab all of this.
Move it down I don't want to be affecting the eyes and the nose just within here I'll hit control eye
to inverse that.
Now K for my snake hook to scroll out nice and big.
Grab the top of the E..
Bottom of the spring the whole thing down and it looks like it needs to go backwards a little bit as
well so bring the whole thing backwards backwards backwards great little bit lower scroll around have
a look from front on looks yes looks right.
Okay cool unmasks sorry.
Box box mask control that will undo everything.
Now back to my k for snake hook tool to the delivered of E poking.
So getting nice enclosures push the era in a little bit up to the outside of the low push it in push
it in and push it down just to get the shape in there will do a lot more crafting of it when we get
to decent detail stage but for now just want to get the side of my head back to where it should be and
the ear a little bit sharper we can do just a tiny bit of let's see of pinching at the moment just to
give it that shape a little bit of pinching pinching around the ear not too much.
Don't do a lot of detail just enough so you can say yes that is officially an ear
okay so that's mostly what I wanted to get to at the end of this video is just blocking it in nose eyes
general mouth position the shape of everything.
So when we start to putting the details we're not worrying about is the year in the right spot we're
saying look at what should the air look like.
Okay so excellent.
Hope you went well with this exercise and in the next video we'll start putting in some more detail
into our head.
See you in the next lecture.