Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture I'd like to talk to you about version control.
Now there are various forms of this but I'm talking specifically about proper version control software
rather than just keeping backups.
We are embarking on a rather large project where if you make a mistake midway through it could haunt
you.
And this is the sort of work that can take hours of your time to do so it's great if you could just
step back a little so version control is kind of like zipping up your projects and giving it a specific
name only because we're working with models and textures and things like that.
It just tracks the changes it's exactly how I keep track of how my lectures are progressing.
And so if I make a mistake when recording I can just revert everything back to the end of the previous
lecture.
So version control is incredibly useful and when now at the point in the course where it's going to
really help a lot of you out now it's not mandatory but it's highly highly recommended.
And if you who have done coding would have had version control at some point in your teaching.
So what are the benefits.
Well it makes rolling back to a previous state incredibly easy.
It allows you to test and practice and just try things out without the worry of breaking your projects.
Now this is incredibly important to do because I've seen people inadvertently run out of un dos on blender
and I've done it myself where I've made the load of minor changes didn't like it and it turned out there
were two options I could ever work with what I've got or start from the previous save which might have
been a few minutes ago to have 30 minutes ago if you're really focused on something but what you can
do is you can commit your changes when it comes to source control and then you can just move on from
there.
Now you can share your repositories where your information is stored online.
So it's great for having a project if you are working on multiple computers.
That's how I'm able to work on all of my various computers.
I make sure that any of my information that I want to share is available and not only that it means
that the history is available on every machine so it's not just like sharing a blend file on Dropbox
it's much more detailed.
It's like showing the blend file on dropbox with every single change that you've ever done.
Now Dropbox has its own versioning.
If you ever did need to recover something you'd have to do it blindly.
Now this would be a great time to make sure we do actually have a course dedicated to version control.
It can become quite an involved process with lots of different options but the very basics of it means
that you can just roll back to a previous version.
Now software front ends I'd recommend source try and get crackin as those front ends.
Personally I use get crackin.
I really like the way that it works and I'm able to just commit any of my changes save those with a
name which I know I can go back to and then I can just continue working and it does mean that I'm able
to go back to previous versions of my work if I've made a mistake.
So that's my brief going over of version control and I wholeheartedly recommend it to people is the
next step home from backup.
It allows you to try out new things without the repercussions of getting something wrong because you've
always got the option to go back to a named version in history.
So if you're interested do check out our course on it to learn much more.
Otherwise check it out and see how you get on with it and I'll see you will in the next lecture.