Hello everybody and welcome to the section on bezier curves.
It's the first time we've played with curves so take it slow.
But by the end of this lecture we'll be able to make an outline of our pin.
As you can see here.
And if I turn on empty we can see it perfectly traces the outline of our reference image.
Let's go over into blender and find out more.
So we left off here before way of our reference material the first thing I'm going to do is add in a
bezier curve and I'm also just going to turn off my text inputs at the top here.
So we'll change it back to my outliner so I can use that there.
And I noticed that it's obviously obvious using a text field down here and now we have something in
it.
I'm going to reveal the header once more.
I'm just going to get rid of any text that's in there and then I'm going to right click header and toggle
the header off once more and you can see my keystrokes.
Nice and easy.
I will turn them back on right.
So we've got everything set up here and we're ready to work.
The first thing I'm gonna do is just hide the place holder.
We don't need it at the moment.
What we do need is the image so we can trace.
Now I'm going to go ahead and go shift and A and add in a curve object.
Now this curve object we got a series of options that we could pick.
I'm gonna pick bezier and you might go well there's an orange line that's appeared at the bottom what's
going on.
Well if we zoom out we see that a bezier curve has indeed been added.
And if we press tab was that selected we can see what a bezier curve consists of it consists of.
In this case a start and end point for the curve.
And these are both vertices.
And then you've got these handles and if you select to handle and press G here to move it we can
adjust the shape of the curve pretty easily.
Okay.
So there's is the simplistic view of a curve and we can go down here grab the other handle lift that
up and change the curve accordingly.
So there are many many options and curves we'll get into some more detail about them later in the course
but that is the fundamentals of a curve, you have vertices and then handles which control how the curve
flows.
Now we do have curve options as well.
If we go over to the property's view and scroll down until you find the one that looks like a curve you
can change the amount of steps within that curve by changing the resolution preview.
And if we turn up really really really high to 64 we get a super smooth curve.
But if we then converted that to geometry later on we'd end up with a very dense mesh I'm going to leave
it at 12 as the default.
And you'll notice as we start tracing around the outline of our pin sometimes we might need more or
less depending on how we're going.
So we just pick an average number that we can work out later on.
Now one of the first things that we'll see here is the curve is at the wrong orientation to our object
in fact instead of trying to factor around getting this to actually fit the right way round I'm going
to delete it so I'm going to press A to select everything to do with that curve whilst in edit mode
we're not in object mode.
The reason why we're doing this whilst we're in edit mode is it removes all the curve data and we're
going to remove all the vertices.
So we still if we have a look in the outline we still have a bezier curve object.
That's the key here.
We're still editing that object.
It just has no curve data at the moment.
That's whizz round.
So the front view and zoom in slightly so we can see what's going on now.
Let's go ahead on the tool shelf here.
If you don't have the tool shelf you can bring it out with the T key making sure of course your, your
cursor is within the 3D view itself.
And I'm going to go all the way down to the bottom where it gives us an option to draw a curve.
Now I could literally if I was a super artist kind of draw a rough outline around here and then tweak
things as we go.
That wouldn't be a bad start at all if that is pretty close to what I'd want it to be anyway.
So there you go there's one option if you're a super artist you could just quickly sketch it in, let's
say we weren't such a super artist and we wanted a bit more fine control.
I'm going to undo that and just click once.
Now the initial placement doesn't matter too much but you can refine it over on this control point here.
This vertex we can actually align it where X equals zero and then we know is exactly where the mirror
point is going to be later when we spin this around and the Z.
Well let's also make it zero.
Why not.
Now the next option is extrude and you can see here the shortcut key for is E so much as we've extruded
mesh data before you can move so extrude when it comes to curves.
That's really useful if we press E we can see we can move it and place it in a rough position that we
want and we can do the same again and again and again and again.
And there we go.
We're done.
But the problem here is when we've done this type of extrusion for some reason it's decided to make
our curve less curvy and more straight which is one of the options it's called a vector it just goes from one
point to another.
So now that we've done these vector points how can we make them a bit more curvy.
Well what we can do is we can press A to select all and press V and what V will do is it will bring
up the handle type and you can also find that under the control points menu if we're in this we get
the option to set the handle type back to automatic.
This is what we're used to seeing now that we've got it there.
It's just a matter of going in and tweaking.
And one of the things that you may ask yourself is do we need this many vertices and handles.
Is this too much data.
The answer may be yes the answer may be no I definitely know you cannot create this shape with just
two vertices because you can't get this inversion going on here and it coming back round perhaps you
can't make it three.
You'd thoug,think come out maybe here back in and then round again you might be able to get the rough
shape but remember at the top here what we really want is the curve coming to a complete horizontal.
And the only way of doing that is I'm going to go back to selection mode so I can select this handle
and this handle and this control point really need to be at the same height.
So I'm going to copy that value for the control points.
You can tell the control point is is highlighted by the way because both the handles are also highlighted.
We select just the handle only that is highlighted and I can paste that value in.
That's the only way of making sure you get a truly flat top that it comes in.
And then we'd also go back down and round and also X here its value is fine.
It's important though that the control points X value is zero because that's where it stops and we can
do exactly the same down the bottom here.
We can find well, Z equals zero.
That's that's all we need to worry about there so Z equals zero.
And you may notice here we've got global and local.
So the other thing that we could do.
Well let's whizz round to the top here.
The other thing that we could do here is select our control point and make sure that says point three
eight.
And there we go.
Now as we go through we can click and just press G adjust to make sure that line is flowing round and
down as you'd expect it.
So now if you have lots of control points down your model you will find that you probably need far less
a resolution.
So if we have that at six you can see that even though it's more stepped there are more control points in between
because this is going to be six steps in between each control point.
And as we whizz around here we can see that our curve is going round and down our objects.
We can see in 3D spaces going all the way down to the bottom there.
And that's important.
One of the things that you can end up with and it's worthwhile checking is that you have no tilt as
you go down you shouldn't do providing that you've set up your curve in an orthographic and looking
directly at your objects.
If for some reason you were slightly twisted you started adding curve data in there's a good chance
that you've either got a tilt to it or it's not laying where Y,
In this case equals zero.
Now if you happen to have created it from the side you'll find that maybe X will equals zero all the
time.
But what we should find is every one of these handles and control points in this particular exercise
with sitting along the X plane, the image along this X plane, we should find that Y is equal to zero.
If for some reason you've made it round this way you'd expect X to be equal to zero throughout.
But there we go that's all set up apart from the fact we need to make it just a little bit neater and
see if we can get away with fewer of these control points.
Obviously the fewer you have the less control you have but you may end up with a much better shape because
you're able to control it better having fewer.
So what I want to try and convey but when you have this many control points or even more it becomes difficult
to adjust the overall shape.
And remember we're not going for an exact copy around the outside of our pin at the moment we're just
looking for a good trace around.
And that leads us nicely on to your challenge okay see your challenge finish off your bezier curve.
Now one question more or less control points, I'll leave that up to you to decide.
It does depend on any nuances of the shape you want to convey and how detailed you want it
overall. I'd like you to adjust your handles to correct the overall shape.
Remember we're just trying to trace the outline of our pin and also remember its only one half that we're
worried about because we're going to rotate that profile 360 degrees to create our pin and I'll also
like you to think about adjusting your curves resolution so that you have an appropriate level of curve
detail.
Now I know you're new to this.
So what an appropriate level happens to be will vary but basically if you're looking at your curve
and it looks like a series of jagged straight lines you probably need to increase its, but increase it
until it looks like a curve rather than just whacking the number up as high as you can.
That's in itself will cause you problems in future if you just whack can number up as high as it can
possibly go.
You will find blender will crash or even lock up for a very long time, been there plenty of times.
Anyway go ahead.
Pause the video and give that a go. Okay everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and finish off the bezier curve. Okay.
So I'm just looking at how this is going around the model.
We definitely need one at the top and one at the bottom.
I'm not sure we need this one here I do think we need this one here.
Basically you always want a control point at the peak of a curve.
And because this is the top part of this curve we're going to need one.
And this where it turns around here we're going to need one there and we're going to need one here.
That's that's for certain.
I don't I'm going to try deleting it and just seeing if we can adjust this handle to compensate
ooo roughly.
This is what you always run into I mean at this point you need to increase the curve resolution as well.
But what we're really playing here we're trying to get a shape and it's really forcing it into something.
It doesn't really feel like going in.
So that feels much more appropriate in the level of detail we've got.
And of course we can just tab out and see the overall shape.
So here if I grab this handle and just move it around slightly it follows the shape really well, looks
good here comes in a bit too tight here what can we do.
Well what the first thing we can do here is just adjust this handle.
Now remember when you were just one handle it will adjust the other ones as well in fact this control
points really in the wrong place it really needs to be where it tucks in so I'm going to come out and have
another look.
Looks good to me.
And wear it bulges out here.
I'm just going to move this one up.
Okay perfect.
Now much like this top one and bottom one I was saying that they should really sit so that the control
points and the handle are level with one another.
I think that that rings quite true in other places like here.
So I think that the X coordinate of the handle and the control points itself should match.
I'm going to copy that and paste it into the handle because they are slightly different.
Now it is only a very very minor tweak is it important.
Probably not.
But I'm going to keep it like thats and I like the way that it's curving round.
Now the bottom here.
Later on in this section we're going to make sure that our pin can sit on the ground flat.
It's going to be nearly impossible to actually get this to be flat so we won't worry too much about
it.
So what I'll do here is I'll go G and X I'm only moving the handle along the X axis along there and
then we can come out and I think that matches it as close as I really care to make any more time spent
on this is probably not going to work out.
Now there will be some exceptions to this.
If you were trying to model something that you were going to 3D print and it was really important that
it was accurate then yes.
Spend more time on it and make sure it is accurate.
In this case that's as close as it needs to be.
So I'm going to call that complete.
I'm going to call my bezier curve pin profile.
Got caps lock turned up and it is important to get into the habit of naming things as your going so
pin profile is absolutely fine place holder lie empty.
So here we go here's one that we've missed earlier.
So this is not really an empty is it's it's our pin reference.
And of course you can shorten that's a pin ref or something along those lines.
And here I'm going to also append this with pin.
And the reason for having a pin place holder and a pin profile and a pin reference is so that's later
on if we add other things to this scene which we very well might or may not do well at least then you
can differentiate between the objects themselves because in this case liberal prefix with the name of
the object.
Okay.
So that's me done.
How are you guys getting on please share your work over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the
next lecture.