Welcome to the grease pencil.
Now a grease pencil has many many uses.
We're going to go through only a few of them here.
But of course feel free to play with them as you go.
So it's great for making notes on your model is good for sketching and planning ideas.
If you got an idea and you want to as I say quickly sketch it out you can do so with the grease pencil
roughing out shapes and I'll be doing that using the grease pencil to do that too rough out where the
eyes are going to go etc..
So converting two edges is well we can convert the lines we actually draw to a curve and then curve
to an edge because the grease pencil itself when you draw a line we see in a moment.
It's actually made up of a series of points and those points can be changed and edited.
Much like vertices and edges are connected together.
It can be used to also create 2D animations.
Just like most things in blender you can animates the grease pencil so I'm sure some of you have already
seen that some people have used the grease pencil to actually make some animated sketches.
Which is wonderful.
We won't be going into too many details with that but suffice to say you can do that.
So let's go explore the grease pencil now and hop on over in a blender.
Okay so we're back over in blender here and one of the first things that I want to do is just show you
where some of the options are for the grease pencil itself.
So at the moment we've got our head selected here and I've not named it yet so I'm going to go ahead
and name it head because just cool Cube isn't very descriptive.
Now on the tall shelf itself there is a grease pencil tab.
You may have to scroll down if your operator panel is quite high.
So those are the grease pen so we can see a couple of options on the tool shelf there.
We can also see the grease pencil options on the propertys panel so it's not open you can open that
would be in key.
I will if I can see it.
I've got my background image there is scrolled up a little ivory gate grease pencils even turn the grease
pencil on and off there so like showing it and hiding it again.
And we can see here that we've got layers as well.
So there's a couple of ways that we can add a grease pencil to our scene itself or to an object.
Now in general I would advise adding it to the scene.
However if it is to do with a specific object in your drawings are basically can get in the way.
Is it when you hide that object you can have a link to the object so that wherever you've selected it
we switch this now to objects.
We will see that the grease pens will be linked to the head so that when we start drawing in a few moments
we can see that it's attached to the head.
And if we hide the head it will also disappear.
So let's have a look and.
Well there's a couple of ways of starting new we can go and click on draw a line or arrays or poly at
the top here.
We can have a look at clicking new here as well.
Or you can hold down the key in the d key will start The drawing process.
Now one thing that I've always found useful if I'm looking for a shortcut key and I can't find it in
the menus and places like that.
But I know what the function is called I will go to the user preferences go to the input tab and search
for what we're looking for.
If I go and type in Greece it doesn't come up with anything that is not that useful.
It would help if I spelled Greece correctly.
Okay so we can see here we've got Greece pencil jaw now.
They're not defined with their names here but we can see that we've got the and the left mouse is going
to do something controlled day and the left mouse will do something controlled in the right mouse or
do something and control at the right mouse will also do something.
And when we open that up we can see that the and right mouse is going to switch on the eraser.
Every time I open up these other ones here is going to be full of stuff and I don't recommend you ever
go in and play with these but just for information.
Dean left mouse is going to draw freehand draw a straight line.
If you hold down control at the same time draw a poly line as well so there's lots of options and is
going to close that not save anything and that links to these four buttons at the top here so there
is a shortcut for that.
So let's give it a go.
Let's hold down the key and just oh there we go.
I've drawn a spiral.
Now the moment I've done that I am on the right hand side on the property panel a new layer has appeared.
Now we can press the plus key here and add another layer.
And of course once we've added another layer I can hold down the the key again and draw a smiley face
or whatever you happen to be during.
It's entirely up to you and the great thing about using layers it does mean that if you delete if you
want it gone you can just press the minus button and delete it.
You can name it what you need to name it as well.
There are some further options down here so with the this one squiggled the spiral that we've done.
If we change the stroke call the fill we can actually change the colour of the line itself so you can
make it green if necessary or red.
It would depend on the model because if you're a black might not always be a great colour to use if
the model you're working on is black for instance so we can change the colour there as we go we can
change the thickness of the line and it is pressure sensitive.
By the way so if I go ahead and hold down deep.
Now I'm using my iPad to draw here.
I've actually got a a stylus.
If I press lightly as you can see it's quite thin.
And then as I press heavier it gets thicker of fickleness.
If I can tell that off to a thin line it's by no means an artistic package.
Never using the mouse I just grab the mouse and hold down deep and start drawing.
It's going to be the thickness.
It that you've got set over here because with a mouse there's no pressure sensitivity.
So the final thing here is x ray and I'm going to go for you can turn on the points of course or ever
do volume but points.
Just turn the size down you can see the points that I was talking about.
It's me that's actually making up this line.
I'm just going to turn that back off again.
So we've got these three scribbles that I've made here I'm just going to turn the thickness slightly
back up again so we've got the thick and thin stuff so x ray can be very useful.
Here we see.
I've managed to draw inside our model so if I turn off x ray you won't.
Here we go.
You can see the bit that comes out the back.
So if you're drawing on certain things that you need to see through you can turn x ray on just like
we could with the bones and armatures.
Now you will notice that all of these are lying on a plane and I moved the 3D cursor So it's where the
3D cursor is will be the actual point that the plane passes through.
And then your view where you're looking will be the rest.
Now there are a couple of other things that you may want to do.
So if I scoot around to the front of my face here at the moment you can see if we look on the left hand
side under the grease pencil we can see that it's currently set to cursor.
So the one you're going to be during the stroke at where ever the 3D cursor is.
We can do the view now the views quite use.
If we KRIT go ahead here and create a new layer and I put a smiley face up the top here and must remember
hold down day as I go.
Incidentally you can just click on draw and draw away.
The problem with just drawing and without continuous ticked on the left hand side is every time you
start.
Basically stop clicking or holding down the left mouse button.
The drawing will just stop so you can actually turn on continuous click draw draw a circle draw and
then draw the rest of your smiley face.
It's whatever you do.
I personally prefer to just hold down the d key whenever I need to annotate But now we've done these
smiley faces here.
You can see because it's the view it's completely independent of where we're looking at our model.
That's great for making notes or whatever you need to do.
It does mean that when you move your model around that does not disappear.
And as I was saying earlier if I now hide the head everything goes because we're linked to the object.
I'm going to read or bring back the head angle switch the scene view.
And you'll notice Oh well where's all my stuff gone.
Where has it gone.
We need to have the head selected in order to bring it back.
So don't panic if you literally if you select something else it will disappear.
So that's another reason why perhaps having it on the scene view would be a good idea.
Of course once it's on the scene view it doesn't matter what you've got selected.
If I go ahead here with it in view and go out of a hole down the right key as well Aaron go.
So if I go and draw my smiley face that I had earlier it doesn't it now doesn't matter what I've got
selected that smiley face will be there because it's on view.
I can rotate round.
So the final one I think is very useful is surface.
So if we now move around the front of our model I am going to draw on the model itself.
I'm going to delete the layers that we've currently got on the scene so that one's gone and I never
delete these two layers as well.
Now with its sets on surface it literally draws on the surface of our model.
So I go ahead hit deep to start drawing and say I want an eye there and I'm planning on having the nose
being around there and the lips being about here.
Obviously I use reference material as well but it's a good way of guiding your well basically guiding
your drawing in your model.
He's looking quite evil you might want to put where the hairline is now because I've drawn light that's
when we scoot round to the side you can see is actually following the model itself.
And that's incredibly powerful.
Lots of fun.
Okay guys.
Now we've learned a little about the grease pencil.
It's time for a challenge.
I would like you to go ahead and sketch some details.
So using your reference image add some grease pencil marks defining where the major features of the
face will be and even go round to the side and just mark where the hair perhaps will be or V is as well.
There are some features that we often forget when we're just looking at the front of a face.
Now it doesn't have to be neat or detailed.
Think about them as construction or guide lines and that's the use that I'm asking you to do at this
point.
Of course you can go as detail as you want with the grease pencil at any point.
Suppose a video and give that a go.
Okay guys.
Welcome back.
Let's go get some details on our model and hop on over into blender.
Okay so I'm pretty sure that that will not be where the hairline is and those won't be where the eyes
are as you scan to make sure I do sketch my details on the correct side so you can see there.
This left hand side is the one that's mirrored.
I'm just going to get rid of all the rest.
And for the sake of transparency under there make sure that mine's on the scene.
I can't see my background image at the moment so let's just make sure that they are there are how I
did a bit of organising and I bet that's broken.
So Mikey front profile needs to be selected.
Oh I'm in the wrong folder as well.
That's a great start.
So there we go reference images making front.
That's looking good.
I'm back.
The other one down here Mikey right.
Let's see if that's there.
No it's not so.
Let's go here.
In here assets.
Oh no I want to go to this folder just in case I reorganize.
They won't be broken then there again.
So I'll actually start on the side.
So looking at the grease pencil options here I would like to make sure I'm drawing on the surface I'm
happy with that.
Now let's find the grease pencil options.
And then add a new layer.
So then.
And what colour.
I'm going to leave it black for the moment but I can see here Virts.
We've got some detail around here.
Again this is me drawing with the mouse.
So you can get a rough detail with the mouse.
Of course as I was saying it doesn't have to be detailed So in this point we could actually undo that
for instance and go ahead and put in perhaps some detail going there.
Here.
Really really quick stuff to try and define where things are.
Just to get a rough idea of what's going on that looks okay to me in terms of is where they are now
something weird has happened there.
It looks like it's gripped on to literally this lamp surface has been going around there.
So I'm going to hide that out of the way.
Turn it off and a turn the camera off as well to prevent anything like that happening again.
And then it was back around to the side and just get rid of those of course undone now hiding not great.
So let's pop it there and there.
Which looks good.
And then you've got this bit and then that bits as well.
Okay perfect.
So that's my ear differ almost defines going to put this in a bits in as well.
So there's my ear define and that's actually on the model itself it doesn't have to be any more details
than that at the moment where in fact it probably doesn't need to be any more detail than that could
because it's going to be 3D modelling brings the rest around.
Okay.
So around the frontier.
Let's zoom in and we'll get some details.
So we've got the nose which is going to be around here.
I'm going to hold down deep and just literally jaw around there.
We're going to have the eyes now the eyes obviously if you're working with your own picture they will
vary in size shape and eyes do vary depending on your race as well.
I've got a double eyelid if you're from the Far East.
People don't have double eyelids out there so there's lots of different variations in shape.
So and I'd love to see what you guys are doing in terms of making your model come together mean that
so cavour and again these are rough drawings.
They're not anything else.
Now I need to do the mouth area and actually looking at this and with the model behind I can start to
see the the face loops all coming together because I can see one that's literally runs all the way around
here if you look at how the muscles lay underneath the mouth.
That's a really bad circle or it's certainly not mirrored in any way but I can see here that that grouping
they can see as one object.
One group of muscles you've got the lips starting there and the bottom here is going to about there.
And again because it's mirrored I shouldn't really be concerned about the other side so I'm just going
to try out the Erase torso and click on that and get rid of anything.
Now as you can see as I'm going around in erasing it's being quite notchy as it goes.
And of course that's not a particular problem and that is simply deleting the points that have been
drawn.
So there we go if Gotz those bits there the top and bottom side of the mouth the grouping of running
around go up to the top end just sieverts the hair line itself.
If I decide to put a hair in will be somewhere starting around there and working its way down and round
and then I can move to the side view.
Well actually that's that's almost perfect.
And here I can draw down here.
To the back of their head.
And of course if I wanted to I could skip round to the back but there is no reference material for about
now.
This is one of these examples where an x-ray is not useful.
I do not want to see the detail round the front of the model when I'm working on the back so I can turn
off x ray so I can actually work on where this hair will go.
I haven't a clue.
Probably be about balser on those eyes.
And at the moment that isn't terribly important because we've and focussed on this part of the model
brilliant.
How did you guys get on.
Love to see your sketches and the detail that you've laid out.
The great thing about this now is I've got some detail to work with without having to be smack bang
on the front or side views.
And that is somewhat better than having a plane in your scene.
We could of course import an image as a plane and then view it from there.
That's great when you're using it as a literary to refer to this we are using it's a model too.
So it is is quite important that the details we have them in the right place.
Otherwise as we say if you don't make it look if I make it look perfect first time is going to be very
difficult.
But if you don't get it roughly in the right proportions it will look very very odd as great.
How did you guys get on as always.
Please share in the discussions and I'll see you guys in the next lecture.