Hello everybody and welcome back.
I'll show you a couple of examples.
But often when you say cycles vs. eevee or something versus something else is always a matter of which
one is better.
And I'll tell you what neither.
It does really depend on what you're trying to do there are some high level features that aren't available
in TV and there are some that you just can't do in cycles as quick.
OK.
So let's focus on eevee to begin with there are two main points here and there are hundreds of little
ones as well.
But eevee is generally quick and you get a very good result quickly so you end up with something that
you can present to someone and not have had to wait hours for it to render out which can happen with
cycles with more complex scenes.
Now eevee isn't always instant.
That's something that is a bit of a falsehood spreading around evey is something that sometimes takes
four or five seconds to render a scene even up to 20 I've seen in some more complex scenes.
But the same scene in cycles would have probably taken significantly longer now cycles is a physical
based renderer it is accurate but it takes longer.
It's designed for GP use but runs fine on CPD as well.
And we'll see later on how that differs depending on the type of system that you have.
But basically cycles sends rays out from the camera back to the light source and works out lots and
lots of different bounces eevee does not do that.
So cycles is good for reflections.
It will accurately represent them even uses something called screen space reflections.
So if it's not on the screen it's not getting reflected and that can be a problem if you're trying to
reflect something that's behind the camera.
Now we are going to be focused on cycles in this section because we're modelling a lamp never to a cross
compatible as well so we're able to switch from eevee to cycles to test things.
And that's very useful if you are testing out movement and things like that where you want materials
on your model.
But we will be looking at the lighting specifically from the cycles point of view.
But remember you can swap forward and back.
Now there are other renderings as well that you can plug into blender so cycles in the movie are just
two different rendering engines.
They count collate materials and lighting differently but we won't be covering any of those extra rendering
engines in this course render time difference is a big one.
I will just shown you.
Well let's bring it up now.
So here we've got two clips of the bowling ball physical animation that we've done.
So we've got eevee here and cycles eevee is on the left and cycles is on the right.
They both look pretty similar.
So in this particular case I would put forth the argument that whichever one you're using it's fine
but I'd prefer to use eevee in this case because it gives just as good a result and so much quicker
the render on the left took four minutes to do the render on the right took 40 minutes to do that significantly
longer for very very little quality difference now your machine specs can make a big difference as well.
Lots of different machines out there so you may be running a lower end machine you may be running a
massively powerful computer.
This will make a big difference to cycles and it will make somewhat of a difference to evey the more
powerful your system the quicker it's going to do things that's pretty standard.
But the thing I've noticed with cycles is that it scales.
So the more cores in your CPE the better the more powerful your graphics card the better.
You can even use your CPA and GP you together in certain circumstances with cycles and we'll look at
that in a bit and render out out even faster.
But in my experience if they're not balanced it's probably not worth doing.
So to sum that all up there isn't a better renderer.
It really does depend on what you're trying to achieve.
If you're making assets that will ultimately end up in a game engine you may want to focus on eevee
but as you will find out in later sections that we can't do all of our baking that's necessary where
we solidify textures and materials for export.
Some of that will have to be done in cycles.
So we do have to hop between the two depending on what we're trying to achieve but eevee is much more
on par with a game engine set up then cycles is cycles takes a lot longer to calculate because it's
more physically accurate and as we will go through the course you will see between even cycles.
There are some things that are just not possible on TV which are on cycles and vice versa.
So that's it for this lecture we've had a quick comparison between cycles and eevee will die off a bit
deeper as we progressed through this section and the rest of the course with the differences between
the two.
Just remember one isn't better than the other.
It really does depend on what you're trying to achieve and I'll see you all in the next lecture.