Hello everybody and welcome back.
This is a quick tip about clipping.
There are two types of clipping in Blender.
There's the viewport that we currently work in and there's the camera itself.
So first of all let's work with the viewport.
We've got a small piece in our scene so when we zoom in what eventually happens and this probably has
happened to you already is that you end up losing half of your object.
It's fine in orthographic projection because technically you never really get any closer to your model.
You're literally just zooming into it.
But when we start panning or rotating around our model we can end up with not being able to see it.
So we'll cover this viewport clipping straight away and we can see it's actually here in the view.
So you need to open out your side by your properties panel here with the N key.
Go down to where it says view and then we've got a couple of options and we can see here we've got the
clip starts at 10 centimeters.
And what it means is at the moment we are closer than 10 centimeters so we're seeing inside our model.
If I was to lower that down to one centimeter There we go.
We can see our model.
We can zoom in and zoom out and eventually it will start clipping again when we're really close.
And this is one of the things where you'll need to adjust this occasionally depending on what scale
you're working at.
And because we're working quite small at the moment you will end up with clipping issues.
Now if we were making it a model that was in the millimeters what I would advise at that point well
is to make your model larger than it really is.
And remember to scale it down at the very end.
That just means your work flow in blender so much easier to manage because if this was much smaller
you just it just doesn't work as well as you'd want it to.
Right.
So now we've got the viewport set up.
I'm just going to save that so those settings are saved in the blend file itself.
Now the next thing I need to do is the cameras because if we have a look at the camera itself.
Oh well I don't see anything here.
In fact the chest piece is very small so let's see what happens if we go ahead and press shift and
the grave key and start coming in and in and in and in and we can see everything pretty well.
That's awesome.
So the camera doesn't seem to affect us so much when it comes to small objects.
However the cameras nemesis is long distance when things get big.
So whilst we're talking about clipping I feel it's appropriate to do the camera as well.
And so what we need to do is click on the camera and then go to the cameras properties.
So once we're in the camera's properties you'll see there's a clip starr and a clip.
And so very much like we were experiencing before.
If I was to move this, Oo let's move in a little closer.
I'm going to use the scroll wheel to slow down the moving if I can.
Nope still going crazy quick.
There we go.
So moving slowly we'll get to the similar, similar sort of point where it starts clipping in.
So if I wanted to fill up my frame so that when I render my model it comes out that's the problem you
see if I was to go ahead and hit F 12 to render something it would look horrible.
It would not be right at all.
So let's close down that and adjust the clip starts again to one centimeter.
Then we see everything then we can go ahead and render it with the F 12 key or of course you can go
to the render menu and go to render image as well.
And that's much better.
That gives us the opportunity to share our models much much easier especially these small ones. Now
as we go out to the whole scale of the chessboard that won't matter so much anymore unless you were
to bring your camera in on an entire board to one corner of the board and then you might also experience
this clipping issue as well.
So there we go.
Those are the two places that you have to watch out for clipping and the camera.
Well when you're looking through the camera we use the camera settings when we're looking in the viewport.
Well that's the viewport settings.
Got to love the different options that you have in Blender sometimes.
So there we go there's the end of this quick tip remember if you've got clipping issues either a short
distance that should clip starts and if you've got something much larger we can see that the viewport
has 100000 centimeters right the camera only has 10000 centimeters so I believe that's a kilometer in
the viewport but only 100 meters when it comes to rendering and through the camera itself.
So that's something to bear in mind that you may be able to see a scene in your view ports.
Yet when you render it it doesn't look like it's all there and 100 meters isn't that far if your rendering
something much larger like a cityscape or even just a moderate scene.
So there we go.
There's your clipping distances.
Hopefully you won't be caught out by them in the future and they'll see you all in the next lecture.