Hello everybody and welcome back.
So by now you've got a big long list of assets that you want to make and you're probably a bit inundated
and don't know where to start.
So in this lecture I'd like to focus on how we can help you make those critical decisions on what models
you're actually making and what ones would be nice to make.
So working out the main ones that you'll need is key.
And then I'd recommend taking a look at something like trailer for organizing and if you've got other
suggestions once I've shown you what cello is if you don't know what it is then please to let everybody
know in the discussions what you use for organizing your artwork and your direction and your workflow
in general.
Because cello might not gel with everybody.
So let's take a look at cello for the moment and what I've done in terms of organizing and then I will
let you guys organize your work as well.
OK.
So over in cello This is a project management and it's very awesome the way that you can click and drag
things across.
So I've got a level of detail a sarcophagus.
I'm not going to put it any higher than that.
Well let's put it as B for the moment.
I've made one of those just as an example.
So you can click and drag and move things around and that's phenomenal and most project management software
allows you to do things like this but this is a very visual way.
So what I've done is I've listed everything that I can think of immediately down on my asset list.
All of these things I could create and some examples as well from the photos that I've taken.
Remember you've got access to those photos as well in the lecture that we talked about them over in
the resources.
OK.
So you can go and collect your own reference photos and drag them and you can have more than one where
do I have more than one in here this doorway for instance if I click into it I can see I've got two
different types of doorway.
It gives me an option of how I want to focus on it.
And of course it's called A Doorway.
I'm focusing on not only the door itself which is obviously the prominent feature but look all the extra
detail we have going around this particular door.
Not only that but the detail on it as well phenomenal.
So I've then dragged any of the assets that I think are needed over into my needed assets.
This is the key area that I'm going to be focusing on the last thing I want to do is focus on a rug
and not get to the main building done.
So there are a couple of things that are absolutely necessary.
The sarcophagus was a nice to have now anything that's nice to have leave on the assets list because
by nature if it's not needed it is a just a nice to have.
So doorways that's going to be important from our viewpoint it may not be that critical but I think
adding an extra element to the wall section i.e. a door is going to bring the whole building into what
looks like a lived in or in this case a used environment a large stained glass window.
I'm afraid I can't make a church without one of those going in there.
And later on in the section you can see that we don't have to model all of that.
It's great if you want to but we can also get around by using it in a different manner.
We'll talk about different techniques that you could use here.
A window is going to be really important not only a stained glass window but we can have some open windows
as well just may be playing glass in them or something about the roof.
Now the roof I was I was personally I was coming and asking about whether or not to include a roof.
It would depend on last seen and if we ever looked up.
Now if you were designing a game where you were looking down on your character all the time the roof
would be an absolute waste you wouldn't really need to make it the floor tiles.
I think having a pattern on the floor of some descriptions and test lighting tiles is really going to
help bring the whole thing to life.
A pillar is going to need that definitely for the archways which leads us onto the archways.
We're going to need some blank wall pieces as well.
Now a couple of things that I've left behind here I've not included a vault in this I don't think oh
yes it's right at the very top so I've not included a vault in there currently but I think I am going
to need that because when we get to the top of the archways and the arches there it's going to look
odd if we don't if we have just a plain roof without that vaulting there so I'm going to move my vault
across into my needed assets I'm going to put it down here now.
I don't really have an order of precedence at the moment and I think that's important as well.
Otherwise you can end up modelling things in an order where you can't put them together logically.
So I'm going to go off and reorganize these into a logical manner and now it's time for your challenge
and your challenge is to organize your Model S.
I want you to be very clear on what you're making and what you might leave to a later point.
So separate out the models you need from the ones you want.
And I would recommend something like Tarullo or any other organisational software in order to do that.
The nature of being able to click and drag and move things around is a lot easier.
You could also if you'd like a pen and paper in the past I've written this down on post it notes or
little bits of paper that scraps of paper that I've got and then I can organize it like that pin it
up on a board if you prefer that way of doing it.
Brilliant take a photo of that and share it with us as well supposedly.
Now and give us a go
Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead and I'm going to dive back over into travel quickly and organize those models and a bit
more of a logical how I'm gonna go ahead and construct them order OK so back over in Charlotte.
So at the moment I got my doorway up here we could start with a doorway.
That would be absolutely fine.
Launch window.
That's probably going to come after sit doorways windows roof.
I'm going to link a vault.
I'm going to rename that.
Because I've decided that it's not just gonna be a plain old roof.
Now I think we might have some plain old roofs in there so I'm going to call this a plane roof and this
a vaulted roof and we can focus on the vaulted roof later on as well.
There is an mirroring techniques we can use to really speed up the process of making a vaulted roof
floor tiles so yes floor.
It Be good to get that done early.
The pillar so from floor to pillar the large stained window we can leave to much later on the vaulted
roof that would come up here off the pillars and archways first.
So you can see here how thinking about how we construct in the building already is inform our decision
of how and which models we make first.
And a blank wall well a blank wall was so easy to make.
It's gonna be our base model that we base everything off almost like a blank template that we can build
our scene from and you'll see as we progress that the size of your items is critical for it being a
modular construction.
Now this large window down at the bottom.
I just want to throw in there.
I've knocked it all the way down to the bottom of my list which I think's fine because it's going to
be the the focal point at the end but you could also argue because it's one of the main focal points
of the scene.
It's potentially more important that we get in there sooner but I'm going to let my design language
of the rest of the building and then later on focus on the large stained glass window I'm going to put
right at the back of the wall.
Okay.
I hope that helps you guys out when it comes to organizing your work and making sure that you can remain
focused on the assets that you need really critical if you've got to make several assets being able
to put them in a priority order knowing which will take precedence over everything else.
Some of these extra ones over here I can see already a prop they're going to really help making a scene
feel more convincing however they're not essential for getting the overall feel of the scene.
So that's it for this lecture and I'll see you all in the next one.