Hello everybody and welcome.
In this lecture we're going to have a quick look at the terminology low poly because it can mean different
things to different people.
It'd be clear if I was to talk to you about what it means to me and of course I'd like to hear what
it means to you as well in the discussions.
So first of all in the last lecture we made a base piece and it starting to get quite detailed.
It was starting to look quite smooth and not what I would call low poly.
So we're going to go ahead and fix that in a moment but before we do I want to discuss what low poly
is is two things really.
First of all we've got the style now low poly is a kind of a retro look back to the days of old but
not only that it's also a way of rapidly generating assets to use in a game or perhaps in a scene itself.
It does facilitate much more rapid model making.
That's just part of it.
The less detail there is often the easier it is to make your models.
The other thing that it is, is it's a relative term.
So these two things can be used interchangeably as they are often low poly assets i.e. less polygons
in a simple mobile game for instance but low poly does change over time and that's something key to
understand.
So what we will call high poly back in 1990 would now be horrendously low poly and the same is true
now in the future.
I'm sure things will be different yet again.
So one of the things we need to first do is have a look at our model and make sure it's meeting the
criteria of being a low poly chess sets.
Now there's another reason for making sure things are low poly are that is low polygon count in case
you've been wondering and it just means it's a simple shape.
There are other types of workflow that ensure that the base geometry that you're able to edit and tweak
is as little as possible and as much as necessary.
So a couple of things that we can do and we'll look at very very shortly is alternatives to using that
bevel.
You may find that you want to use the bevel and it's ideal for your circumstance.
You need to make individual tweaks to that part of the mesh.
But if you can overall smooth out an object without having to use the bevel tool that could be a big
boon and there are a couple of ways that we can do that.
But for now rest assured we are about to make our model low poly again and we're going to do some subtracting
methods in order to do that.
And I'd love to hear what you think about low poly over in the discussion.
Do you like the style.
Do you loathe the style or always go for realism.
It's entirely up to you it's your choice and there is no right or wrong when it comes to it.
And if you're just going to cross your arms go Mike you know what I am going to do this a high poly
chess sets and I don't care I'm going to follow along the lectures I'm not going to make it really really
awesome that's also fine.
I encourage you to do so and I'd love to see them how they turn out.
So that's it on the discussion of low poly.
Let me know what you think it is over and the discussions and I'll see you all over in the next lecture.