The second problem I would like to discuss is the scale of features,
and that problem can take two forms.
Firstly,
we might have some feature columns that have inconsistent scales
across the dataset for different instances.
For example,
we might have some data entries that are in USD
while others are in British pound.
And even though if we have all instances of the dataset with the same scale,
there is another challenge,
which is that many machine learning algorithms are
sensitive to the data magnitudes.
And one common example is the K‑Means clustering,
which uses the Euclidean Distance,
and the Euclidean Distance is affected by variable magnitudes.
For example,
a dataset that's entered with a specific feature in centimeters would give
different results than a dataset with the same feature in inches.
It's an inherent limitation by design on some machine learning algorithms.
Let's now discuss the solution for data with multiple scales issue.
Let's assume that we have the following dataset with sales price,
where the first two items are in USD, while the third one is in British pound.
This is clearly a problematic case since the British pound is in
a different unit scale than the US dollar.
The solution would be to multiply the British pound with a correct scale,
in this case, the exchange rate.
Let's say that it is 1.25.
And here we have the new dataset with one scale across all features when
we scaled the 30 British pound to 37.53 US dollars.
There are several techniques to solve the feature magnitudes challenge.
We will discuss the most commonly used ones.
Standardization removes the mean and scales the data to unit variance.
MinMax rescales the dataset such that all features
are in a range between 0 and 1.
And normalization scales the vector for each sample to unit norm,
independently of the distribution of samples.
The core theory behind these approaches is that they are representing the data
in relative magnitudes greater than absolute magnitudes and,
hence, removing any scale effect from the dataset.
To sum up,
always remember to make sure that all feature columns
have the same scale across the dataset.
This is done by multiplying by the right scaling factor.
And always scale your features using a standardization technique if the underlying machine learning algorithm calculates distance.