I don't know if you have read the phenomenal book by Malcolm Gladwell,
titled Outliers.
In this book, Gladwell shows that completely random factors,
such as day of birth, can determine opportunities to achieve success.
For example, Gladwell found that in Canadian ice hockey,
most of the players who ended up in the NHL were
born in the first half of the year.
The reason was that the age cut‑off set for youth
teams was at the beginning of January,
meaning that kids who are born in December can compete with
kids who are almost one year older than them.
So, practically speaking,
these small age differences can have a lifelong effect on the
hockey player's opportunity to succeed.
Whether we agree with the author or not,
outliers do exist in our daily life,
and they have a significant impact on our long‑term prospects.
Machine learning is no exception.
Outlier data points are data points that differ
significantly from other data points,
and they can have severe effects on our machine
learning and data analysis endeavors.
The real‑world data is not ideal,
due to several reasons: Data entry mistakes either from
human or even instruments failure.
Data processing and manipulation errors.
A legitimate outlier in form of extremely rare events that are not
representative of the current status quo. For example,
a super generous millionaire who decides to pay 10 times the property price.
The risky thing about outliers, even though they are usually in small magnitudes,
even though they are usually in small amounts in our dataset,
is that they significantly damage the statistical properties of our
dataset by introducing skews and faulty distributions.
However, in certain scenarios such as fraud detection,
the rare events can be more interesting than the
more regularly occurring events.
And, hence, outlier analysis becomes important.
Let's now start discussing how we can fix outliers. In
this case, our solution will be two steps‑‑finding
outliers and then handling outliers.
Let's first discuss finding outliers.
The first technique that we can use is what is so called Z‑Score. A
Z‑Score is simply an indication of how many standard deviation
points a specific data point is far from the mean. A typical outlier
value would be a Z‑Score of 3.
However,
you can define a different value based on your dataset. Z‑Score
works better with normally distributed data.
The second approach would be to use the interquartile range we discussed
earlier and to consider everything outside it as outlier.
Also, the box and scatterplots are excellent tools to detect outliers visually.
To handle outliers, there are two general approaches‑‑to remove
them all together or to correct them if you feel that you know
their reasonable limits. An example would be to cap the dataset elements to specific value.