Let's now go through a demo and do data preparation using AWS SageMaker.
It's time to get our hands dirty.
And now we are back to our previous Ames housing price
dataset we visualized in the last module.
It is now that time to proceed with the data preparation steps.
Since our dataset is quite large,
the first thing I would like to do is to adjust pandas print settings to
change the maximum number of rows to display to a large number.
Let's now try to detect missing values in our dataset.
For that, we can run a pandas command called isnull,
and then we will sum the numbers of null values in each column.
You will notice that pandas detected certain null values.
For example, Alley column.
The reason is that this column uses the value NA as one of its categories,
while pandas' default behavior is to consider NA as not a number,
and, hence, it will be detected in isnull.
Let's look at what we have in the original dataset.
And as you can see, Alley column uses the value NA as one of its categories,
which indicates that pandas will be confused,
and it will consider it not a number.
We can validate that by looking at our pandas dataset.
And, as you can see,
pandas identified the NA values as not a number in Alley column.
The reason is that pandas is using a specific configured list of values as an
indicator of missing values whenever it reads a CSV file.
And you can see this list below.
So,
the solution to this problem would be to reconfigure pandas when reading
to exclude the value NA as a measure of missing values.
So I will replace the default setting of pandas by removing
the NA value to make it fit our scenario.
And I will load the CSV again,
and let's have a look at our pandas DataFrame one more time.
And as you can see, the Alley column reads the value properly as NA,
rather than not a number.
Let's now do some analysis over what we see in the dataset.
If you can see the PID column, it's not a really useful column for us,
and it's just used as a unique generated identifier.
We can drop that column.
Let's now have a look at the descriptive statistics we have in our dataset.
For that, I use describe and I call transpose.
Transpose will switch the rows and columns of our pandas DataFrame.
Here it will help us to easily read the descriptive statistics.
It would be worth time to check the maximum and
minimum columns for each feature,
because if we see a feature that has equal minimum and maximum values,
it would mean that this feature has no change across that column,
and we can drop it, since it doesn't add much information to the analysis.
And as we can see, there is no such case, so all is good, and we can proceed.
Let's now start reading our missing values.
As you have seen previously, when we call pandas isnull,
we identified some features with missing values.
Let's now try to calculate the percentage of the
features and see how significant they are.
In the first line of the code,
I calculate the missing percentage of entries by dividing the number of
missing entries in each feature by the total length of the dataset and
multiplying it by 100 to get it in the percentage terms.
Then,
I construct a new pandas DataFrame containing each column
and the corresponding missing percent.
Finally, I sort the values in a descending fashion.
And as you can see,
the feature with the largest number of missing values is the Lot Frontage,
with 16.7% missing values.
When dealing with missing values, you can consider the following rule of thumb.
If the percentage of missing features is greater than 80%,
you need to consider dropping that feature at all,
since we might not have much to do.
Fortunately, this is not the case here in our dataset.
Then you need to consider imputing the features using
different data imputation techniques.
And now let's see what strategy we are going to do
to fill in our missing values.
The first two variables, Lot Frontage and Garage Yr Blt,
have the highest amount of missing values,
which are 16.7% and 5%, respectively,
while the other variables have missing percentage less than 1%.
I will use median for numerical values,
and the most commonly occurring value for the categorical variables.
Let's see that in action.
And here for every numerical value I have with missing values less than 1%,
I replace missing values with the median of that feature.
This is accomplished using a pandas function called fillna.
And here, for every categorical variable I have,
I replace the missing values with the most commonly used value.
You can think about it as amount.
This can be obtained from pandas by using a function called value_counts.
The value_counts function returns a list of all unique values in the
column and how many times each value occurred,
and sorting them in a descending fashion,
which means if we take the index 0,
we will get the value of the most frequently occurred value that we
can use to adjust the missing categorical variables.
Let's have a look once again on how our missing values look like.
And as you can see, only Lot Frontage and Garage Yr Blt are with missing values.
Let's handle that.
The strategy we will use to impute Lot Frontage and Garage Yr Blt will rely on
estimating their values using machine learning techniques.
In other words,
we will consider the missing values as target unknown values that
we would like to estimate from a non‑value,
which are the other values in the dataset.
Fortunately, we don't need to develop a machine learning pipeline for that,
since already Python provides that functionality out of the box.
To use that functionality, firstly,
we will need to make sure that we updated our Python version,
since AWS SageMaker might load an older version of Python
while the imputer is a new feature.
And let's validate Python version.
Good.
Now we are using version 0.22.2 of scikit‑learn.
And now we will import the experimental imputer.
I have imported Python sub‑package impute,
which contains IterativeImputer method that we will use to fit
against our features and impute missing values.
Notice that I imported enable_iterative_imputer.
This is because the imputer is an experimental feature
and has to be imported explicitly.
The strategy for imputing missing values is by modeling
each feature with missing values as a function of other
features in a round robin fashion.
There are many details behind the scene regarding the IterativeImputer.
You can read about them in scikit‑learn documentation.
And here I am separating my features from the target predict,
as IterativeImputer expects only features.
I will only apply the imputer on the numerical features,
since the imputer does not support categorical features.
Categorical features can be detected by checking that pipe dtype of the values.
And I prepare the imputer with a random_state of 100.
This is just to make it easy for you to replicate the same results.
Then I will call imputer.fit, which will fit the imputer to our features.
In other words, it trains on the features.
And then I will impute the missing values.
Then,
I concatenate the newly imputed features with categorical features and
sale price to get the new fully imputed dataset.
Notice that I called reset_index on the DataFrames before concatenation.
This is to avoid a tricky behavior by pandas,
where it assigns not a number if there are two DataFrames that
don't have the same index during concatenation.
And now let's validate that we don't have any missing values.
All values are 0.
Very good. We are done with handling our missing values.