And now let's remove the outliers we have in our dataset.
Before doing so,
we had a discussion with a domain expert from Globomantics who
provided us with certain criteria to filter outliers.
You may choose a different criteria based on your
domain expert's recommendation.
Here I defined a Python function called Outlier_Mask. Then I calculate the
range between the 90 percentile and the 10th percentile.
Then I define a filter to detect the outliers.
The outliers have been defined as values smaller than 10th
percentile minus 1.5 the range or values larger than 90th
percentile plus 1.5 the range. Your definition may change based
on the domain expert's recommendation.
Then I filter out the dataset.
Let's examine it. And now notice that we have less number of rows, 2189 after removal of outliers.