As you remember, we mentioned that the machine learning algorithms,
in particular the ones that calculate distance,
are very sensitive to the feature magnitudes.
And, hence, we need to scale our features to an outcome within that.
To do that, we need to import Python preprocessing model first.
I will separate the features from the outcome as we
only need to scale the features.
Then I will prepare a MinMaxScaler from the preprocessing model.
Python also supports other scalers we discussed previously.
And here in the first line,
I fit the MinMaxScaler in my dataset and create a new
NumPy array with scaled features.
And in the second line,
I construct the pandas data frame back from the NumPy features.
Let's examine our features now.
And, as you can see, all our features now have a minimum value of 0 and a maximum value of 1.