And now, congratulations on finishing Exploratory Data Analysis with AWS
course. Let's review together what we learned across this amazing journey. We
started by understanding how machine learning is done in AWS. We recapped the
machine learning pipeline and discussed relevant services in each phase. And
we clearly specified the position of our course within AWS Certified Learning
‑ Specialty exam.
Then we introduced the housing pricing forecast dataset and
used our fictitious company, Globomantics.
Then we learned how to set up our AWS environment.
Then we proceeded with a module to understand data analysis in AWS. We have
seen how Globomantics machine learning organization looks like and clearly
identified where our roles as data analysts.
Then we learned how to name things correctly in data analysis, an important
thing to communicate effectively with other data scientists.
Then we reviewed basic probability and statistics.
After that,
we concluded with a demo where we did data analysis. On the
following module, we proceeded with data visualization.
We understood why we need data visualization, different types of data
visualizations and their usage, and then we did a demo using AWS
QuickSight and seaborn library in AWS SageMaker. And finally, in the
last module, where we discussed data preparation, we understood the
importance of data preparation.
It's mainly because our machine learning algorithms has certain
expectations on our dataset, and unfortunately,
our data usually is not what we are expecting due to
different reasons, such as entry errors,
differences among data sources, and just real‑life facts.
Then we went through a long list of common data challenges and
discussed possible solutions for them, for example,
how to handle imbalanced data using undersampling and oversampling
strategies, how to skill our data using standardization, min, max, and
normalization, and how to detect and remove outliers, and how to fix
malformed distributions, and many others.
And as usual,
we concluded with a demo where we illustrated some
of the challenges. And finally,
don't forget to rate the course from the options in the right and share
your questions and insights in the course discussion.
Thank you again for your time, and I hope that I meet you in future Pluralsight courses.