Let's see what will happen in the machine learning
pipeline from an organizational perspective,
which means how does machine learning teams operate and work in practice.
We will explain the AI organization Globomantics Real Estate Company introduced,
our fictitious company.
The housing sales data resides in many different systems hosted
in a real estate broker's office in Ames town.
The supplied data has different for months,
whether it's APIs, files,
or databases since each broker has its own unique system.
Thanks to our dating engineering team who decided to do all the
heavy lifting on bringing the data from different data sources and
making them regularly available to us.
At the end of the day,
they provided us with the finalized and consolidated data from many sources.
And now it is our responsibility, as data analysts,
to understand the underlying data and feature engineering to make
it good enough for the machine learning team.
You can think about this as the CSV file we uploaded in AWS SageMaker.
The machine learning team will experiment and play with the different
algorithms until they land a suitable algorithm that works best with the
business problem they would like to solve,
which is sale pricing forecasting.
Finally,
the machine learning team will hand over the model
to the operationalization team.
That will make sure the model works properly and safely in production.
Note that even though I have divided the machine
learning setup to different teams,
your mileage may vary based on the product criticality,
data volume, and the organization maturity.
Moreover, notice that the directions of the arrows are unidirectional,
which is over simplification.
In a real‑life scenario,
the interactions among the teams are usually bidirectional,
and there is a lot of ongoing communication and discussion across
the team as they understand the business problem.
Let's have a quick discussion about the specific
responsibilities the data analysts at Globomantics have.
Firstly,
the team will be responsible for doing data analysis using different
statistical techniques, such as mean, correlation,
median, quadrilles, and so one.
The team will be also responsible for doing data
visualization using different graphs.
This will help us to have an intuitive overview of our
data without digging into details.
Finally,
the team will also be responsible for feature engineering the data, which is
making it what the machine learning algorithm expects.
We will be taking these responsibilities throughout the course journey, so stay tuned.