In this section, we are going to briefly discuss some statistical concepts.
Feel free to skip them if you are familiar with them.
Univariate statistics refer to statistics over a single variable.
This is because there are many different statistical
measures based on the number of variables.
Let's assume that we have the following dataset.
Let's define the following statistical measures. Minimum,
which is defined as the least value in our dataset, is 1,
while maximum, which is defined as the greatest value in our dataset,
is 55.
The range,
which is defined as the difference between the greatest
and smallest value in the dataset, which is 54.
Count, which is defined as the number of elements in the dataset is 10.
Sum, which is defined as the sum of all dataset elements, is 161.
The mean, which is defined as the sum over the count or the average, is 16.1.
The median,
which is defined as the middle value in the dataset when
ordered in an ascending or descending fashion,
which is 7.5.
The mode, which is defined as the most common value in our dataset, is 5.
The standard deviation,
which is a measure of how the numbers are spread out in the dataset,
is 18.6.
A closely related measure is variance,
which is 347 and defined as the square of the standard deviation.
Quartiles are calculated when the data is ordered in an ascending fashion.
The first quartile, which describes which value is higher than 25% of the data,
is calculated as 5, while the second quartile,
which is defined as the value, which is higher than 50% of the data,
is 7.5, which is as same as the median.
Finally, the third quartile,
which defines the value that is higher than 75% of the data,
is 20.
The interquartile range is defined as the difference between
the third quartile and the first quartile,
which is 15.
The interquartile range is very useful to identify outlier data points.
The mean and median are categorized as central tendency measures since
they calculate value that generally tend to the center,
while standard deviation, variance,
and IQR are commonly referred to as dispersion measures as they tell
us to what extent the data points are dispersed.
This was a brief explanation.
If you are totally new to statistics,
I would recommend you to watch Understanding the Overall Data Trends
module in my course Building Your First Machine Learning Solution
where I discuss these measures in detail.
Correlation is one type of bivariate statistics.
Bivariate statistics refer to statistical measures
that are applied over two variables.
Correlation tells us to what extent two variables are linearly related.
Let's take the following example,
which is a table that describes the temperature,
ice cream sales, and jacket sales.
As you can note, the general trend, as the temperature decreases,
the ice cream sales also decreases.
That makes sense since many people don't like to take
ice cream during the cold weather.
However, as the temperature decreases,
jacket sales increases as people don't want to get caught with flu.
To quantify the type of relationship between temperature and ice
cream sales on one hand an the relationship between temperature
and jacket sales on the other hand, we use correlation.
There are a couple of methods to calculate correlation.
We will use a method called Pearson correlation.
Pearson correlation defines correlation measures between ‑1 and +1
with ‑1 indicating a high negative correlation,
which is inverse linear relationship.
When one variable increases, the other variable decreases.
While +1 indicate the high positive correlation linear relationship. When
one variable increases, the other variable increases also. The correlation
between temperature and ice cream sales is calculated as 0.92, which
indicates a high positive relationship.
When the temperature increases, ice cream sales increases.
The correlation between temperature and ice cream sales is calculated as
‑9.5, which indicates a high negative relationship.
When the temperature increases, the jacket sales decreases.
You can also read about details on calculating correlation on
Building Your First Machine Learning Solution course.
Before we conclude our discussion about correlation,
I would like to discuss something very crucial.
It is what's so called the correlation fallacy.
Let's assume that we are in the summer in the hot and nice weather. Because
it's hot, many people decide that they will buy ice cream.
Also, because of the sun, many people will get sunburned.
However,
the fact that sunburn and increase of ice cream sales happen together does
not mean that any of them is the cause of the other.
Even though this looks clear and obvious,
you cannot imagine how many people try to draw causation from correlation.
For example,
if one says sleeping with one's shoes is strongly related to waking up
with headache, this does not mean that necessarily wearing shoes means
that you will wake up with a headache.
We can summarize this discussion by saying correlation does not imply causation. It is also called with that therefore because of this fallacy.