This section will be a short introduction to probability.
While we don't need to know lots of probability for our data analysis purposes,
it would be useful to develop a simple background as to
set the stage for data distributions,
a topic that's inspired by probabilities and which we will discuss soon.
Let's start by understanding why it is essential to
understand probability in real life.
If you look at things around you,
you will find that there are many uncertainties out there,
whether it's something simple like rolling a dice, or the
number of people coming in a queue in a public service, or
in more complicated scenarios, they expected rain rate somewhere.
Given the probabilistic nature of many events around us,
it would be extremely useful to develop knowledge and the
skills to deal with these uncertainties.
Let's start diving.
A probability simply tells us the likelihood something that will
happen. It is expressed as a number between 0 and 1,
with 0 indicating impossible and 1 indicating
something that will happen for sure.
Let's now discuss how we can calculate probability.
The probability of an event happening is calculated as the
number of possible ways an event can happen over the
number of all possible outcomes.
A bit vague, I know.
Let's take an example.
Let's assume that you are playing with your friends and you roll the dice.
Let's examine few probability examples.
The probability of getting 4, given that its one dice, it is simply 1/6.
Why?
Because it's only possible to get 4 if we get a 4 facing face; divided by 6,
which is the number of all possible outcomes when rolling a dice from 1 to 6.
The probability of getting an even number is 3/6 or .5.
Why?
Because there are three ways that we can get an even number when rolling a dice,
either by getting 2, 4, or 6.
The probability of getting a number bigger than 6 is simply 0
since 0/6 is 0. Simply put, it's impossible to get a number
bigger than 6 when rolling a dice.
The probability of getting a number of smaller than 7 is 1 since 6/6 is 0.
Simply put, we are 100% assured that when we roll the die,
the number will be smaller than 7.
Let's go further and introduce an interesting probability
concept that's called random variable.
A random variable denoted by X is a mathematical variable that
describes the set of possible values of a random function.
Let's take the dice example we discussed earlier.
We can have a variable named X,
and it will donate the outcomes of rolling a dice. The possible outcomes of
rolling either a face with one dot, two dots, and so on.
Let's donate each face outcome based on the number of dots it has from 1
to 6. In probability terminology, we call X a random variable, and that
outcome of the dice face is a random event, and the possible number of
dots in the face as the possible values.
And now, after discussing random variables,
we are at excellent position to discuss probability functions.
Let's now discuss probability functions.
The first concept of probability functions is a probability mass function.
It describes the probability of a discrete variable
happening. If we take the example of rolling dice,
it can be described by the following equation. The
probability off getting around the value of X,
for example,
3, is defined as 1/6 if X value is between 1 and 6,
and 0 otherwise. On the other hand,
the probability density function describes the
probability of a continuous variable happening.
It is used as a mathematical modeling tool for some real‑life applications, and it usually has complicated equations.