And now we are done with the first module.
Let's recite what we have learned so far.
We went back to the basics and introduced the machine learning pipeline again.
We briefly mentioned AWS services relevant to the
discussed machine learning pipeline,
with Amazon SageMaker being the king of them.
Since this course in AWS Certified Machine Learning exam path,
we have put the course into context to the exam objectives.
This makes it easy for you to anticipate what type of knowledge is needed
in the exploratory data analysis domain of the exam.
Since this is not an absolute beginner course,
we discussed what things I would expect you to know before proceeding further,
which is mainly machine learning basics.
And I also shared a previous course I authored here at
Pluralsight that can help you to get up and running.
We also emphasized the hands‑on nature of the course to learn the most.
Then, we quickly defined data analysis and shared a small story
showing the power of data analysis if it's done correctly. It is
meant to be a teaser to your brain to perceive what sort of powerful
things we can do with stored data.
Then, we introduced our dataset that we are going
to play with across the course.
After that,
we introduced Amazon SageMaker in a more level of detail and its benefits.
Also,
we did a small demo where we set up our environment for
subsequent steps in the exploratory data analysis.
That's it all for now.
I hope I see you in the next module, where we will start analyzing our data in Amazon SageMaker.