Hello, and welcome back
to the course of deep learning.
today were starting the section on auto encoders,
so how are we going to tackle this topic?
Well in this section will learn the following,
auto encoders what are they,
what is the architecture and how do they work.
We'll talk about training of an auto encoder
and the steps that go into that.
will talk about a situation where
we have over complete hidden layers in an auto encoder.
And then we'll talk about three regularization techniques,
which are used in order
to combat some problems that arise there,
and these techniques are sparse auto encoders,
de-noising auto encoders and contractive auto encoders.
Then we will talk about stacked auto encoders,
and will finish off with deep auto encoders.
And what I wanted to mention here is that
the first part of this section
will be quite straightforward,
will be very simple
because of all the things we've already learned
in this course,
so you'll see that will breeze through this auto encoders
and you will be able to very quickly get up to speed
with was going on.
And then the final part of the section,
starting from over complete hidden layers
and all the way to deep auto encoders,
and these tutorials are more of a high level overview
as you can see there's lots
of different variations over complete hidden layers,
sparse, de-noising, contractor, stacked and deep
there's lots of different variations of auto encoders
and instead of going into depth
on one or two of these specific topics,
we decided to rather give you
a quick introduction to each one of these variations,
are these topics out of auto encoders
and then at least you'll be familiar with the terms
and at least you will know what is the reference to
when you hear them
or when you're encountering them in literature
and then whenever you decide
that you need to go into depth on one
or several of these topics,
for each one of these tutorials,
we going to provide additional reading
which you can look into,
find out more information
and up-skill yourself on that specific topic.
So that's how this section is going to be structured,
can't wait to get started
and I look forward to seeing in the first tutorial.
Until, then enjoy deep learning.