Hello and welcome back
to the course on Machine Learning.
In the previous tutorials,
we learned quite a lot about the K-Means algorithm.
We talked about how it works in the background.
We actually performed a manual K-Means algorithm
which was lots of fun.
Then we talked about the random initialization trap
and what the K-Means plus plus is.
And in all the scenarios we kind of work with
a predetermined number of clusters,
whether it was two clusters or three clusters.
And we talked about somehow finding out
the not correct number of clusters for a given
data science problem.
In today's tutorial, we're actually going to talk about
the algorithm behind finding out
the right number of clusters.
So we'll learn how to decide what number of clusters
to input into your K-Means algorithm.
So let's get straight into it.
Here we've got a challenge, or data size problem.
Again, we've got only two variables,
the x and y coordinates just for simplicity sake.
In reality it can be any number of columns or variables.
And here we've got the scatter plot
representing our data set.
Now if we run the K-Means clustering algorithm
on this data set with three clusters
or with K predetermined to be three,
then the result will look something like this.
And not just something like this, but exactly like this.
We've got the three clusters that have been identified
and we already know that
we would need to run the K-Means plus plus algorithm
just to avoid the random initialization trap.
But again, for simplicity sake,
we're just going to call it the K-Means algorithm.
So we've got the three clusters.
Now in order to understand, if for instance,
two clusters would have been better in this scenario
or maybe 10 clusters would have been better,
we need a certain metric.
We need a way to understand or evaluate
how a certain number of clusters performs
compared to a different number of clusters
and preferably that metric should be quantifiable.
So what kind of metric can we impose
upon our clustering algorithm
that will tell us something about the final result?
And there is such a metric.
It is called the within cluster sum of squares,
that hence the WCSS on the left.
And that is the formula how it's calculated.
This is an example for three clusters.
Now at first glance, this formula might look
a bit overwhelming or complex,
but in reality it's super simple.
So in line with our mission of making the complex simple,
let's break it all down.
What is going on here?
Well, we've got the three elements
and each sum, so this symbol stands for sum,
each sum is calculated for each cluster.
In fact it's calculated within that cluster.
Hence the W at the start.
So let's look at one of them.
Let's look at the central one for instance.
Here we're taking every point inside cluster two,
and that is exactly what is written out here.
And this is, believe it or not,
a valid way to write this sum.
So you just write P with the index I is inside cluster two
and we're gonna take a sum across those points.
And what we're summing is the distance between each point
inside cluster two and the centroid of cluster two.
And then we're squaring that distance.
So we're taking the sum of those squared distances.
So now if we have a look at our chart,
I'm gonna keep the WCSS on the left.
So for instance for cluster two there it is.
We're taking the centroid
and we're calculating the distance to every single point.
So to that point, then we're squaring it.
To that point, then we're squaring it.
To that point, we're squaring it and so on.
So we're taking the square,
the sum of all the squares of all these distances
and we're summing it.
And then we're doing that.
So we're doing that for the first cluster,
we're doing that for the second cluster,
and we're doing that for the third cluster as well.
And so as a result we get this total sum,
so the full sum.
And that is going to be our metric.
And actually it's quite a good metric in terms of
understanding or comparing the goodness of fit
between two different K-Means clusterings.
And how do we know that?
Well let's have a look.
Let's rewind back to when we had one cluster.
Let's see how that metric, WCSS is going to change
as we increase the number of clusters.
All right, so there is our chart with just the one cluster.
As you can see, that is our centroid.
And for every single point we have to measure the distance
between that point and the centroid.
Then we have to square that distance
and then we'll have add all those distances up.
As you can see, we'll get quite a large value,
because this centroid is quite moved away from
all of the points.
They all of to reach towards it.
So let's just visually remember what this looks like
and that will help us kind of remember
what that distance is,
not in terms of the absolute value,
but just what it feels like.
It's quite a large distance right now.
So I'm going to increase the number of clusters to two
and let's see how everything changes.
So there we go, that's two clusters.
And as you can see, now instead of having one centroid
in the middle, we have two centroids.
So each one of these points no longer has to reach
all the way to the middle
or the distance isn't that great.
All you have to do is just calculate
the distance to this centroid.
As you can see it's less.
And then for these centroids,
for all of them here as well,
the distance to this centroid is less.
They don't have to reach all the way to the middle
when you're calculating that distance.
So there we go.
That means that the total distance
or the total WCSS that we see here
is going to less than when we had one centroid.
Now one again, we're going increase the number clusters
so this time to three.
So just remember visually what two clusters looks like
and then we'll compare it to the next image.
So there we go.
Now we have three clusters
and as you can see, nothing changed in cluster one,
so this sum is gonna be the same.
These two sums have changed.
So now instead of one cluster,
these two groups of points are
recognized as separate clusters
and therefore they have their own centroids.
And the distance has again decreased,
because you can see now,
all of these points are closer to their own centroid
than they were to the centroid which was in the middle.
And again these point are closer this centroid overall
than they were to the centroid here in the middle.
So therefore as you can see the WCSS distance is decreasing.
And what is the limit of that?
How far will it keep decreasing?
Well let's think about.
Let' say we increase the number of clusters
to four, five, six and so on.
How many clusters maximum can we have?
Well we can have as many clusters as there are points
or elements in our data sets,
so as many points we see on our chart.
That's how many clusters we can have.
So if we have 50 points, we can have up to 50 clusters.
Because after you go over 50
or after you go over the number of points,
there's no more points to actually cluster.
Every single point has its own cluster.
So, and in that case, what will the WCSS equate to?
I'll give you a second.
If you want to you can pause this video
just to think about that for a second.
If we've reached the number of clusters
equivalent to the number of points in our chart
which is the same thing as the number of elements
in our data set,
then what does WCSS equate to?
And exactly right, the WCSS will equate to zero,
because every single point has its own cluster
and therefore has its own centroid.
And that centroid is going to be exactly where that point is
and therefore the distance between the point
and the centroid is gonna zero.
If you square that, it's going to zero.
And if you add up all those squares
it's still gonna be zero.
So as we can see, the WCSS will decrease
from a substantial value when we have one cluster
all the way down to zero
as we increase the number of clusters.
So it is good metric,
but at the same time, it's constantly decreasing, right?
So it's constantly getting better and better and better
and that's because as you can see,
the less the WCSS or the higher the number of clusters
the better the goodness of fit.
We're fitting our data better and better and better
and therefore the lesser the WCSS
the better the goodness of fit is deemed to be.
But how do we find the optimal goodness of fit?
Yes it keeps getting better,
but is there a sacrifice that comes with that improvement?
And that is exactly the case.
Let's have a look at this visual chart.
This chart represents how the WCSS changes
as we increase the number of clusters.
And as you can see at the start,
the WCSS starts at quite a large number.
It doesn't really matter what this number is measured in,
what the absolute value is and things like.
What matters is how it changes,
so the relative comparison between different
K-Means clustering methods
with the different number of clusters.
So you can see here that it jumped from 8,000 down to 3,000.
That's a massive change of 5,000,
let's just call them units, 5,000 units.
And then from 3,000, as we increased the number of clusters
from two to three, it jumped from 3,000 to 1,000.
Again, quite a large drop.
And then from three to four, what's going to happen
is going to jump from 1,000 to maybe 800
and then from 800 to 600, 600 to 500 and so on.
So as you can see the first two improvements,
or first two changes from one cluster to two,
from two to three, created some huge jumps,
or huge drops in the WCSS.
Going forward the WCSS drops not as substantially.
And this is our hint at selecting
the optimal number of clusters.
And the method we're going to use is the Elbow Method.
And it is actually very visual.
All you have to do is look at your chart
and look for that change or that kind of like,
it does look like an elbow,
and look for that elbow in your chart where the drop
goes from being quite substantial
to being not as substantial.
The improvement is not as great.
And therefore, that point in your chart
is going to be the optimal number of clusters.
In this case it is indeed three clusters
that is the optimal number.
And as you can imagine, this method is quite arbitrary.
So sometimes the situations are not as obvious.
Sometimes elbow might not be as evident
as in this case and therefore somebody might
pick one number of clusters.
Someone else might come along
and pick another number of clusters.
But that is a judgment call that you need to make
as a data scientist.
Sometimes you need to decide
on how your analysis is going to be structured.
And this is one of those cases,
because you are deciding what type of
K-Means clustering algorithm to run.
You're inputting that value of K.
And yes it can be arbitrary,
but if you're not really sure,
then you just need kind of run the K-Means
for instance with three.
Look at it with four, look at it with two,
and like see what the difference is
and make that judgment call on which K
you think is optimal for your analysis,
because ultimately you are the person creating this analysis
and you need to decide which number of clusters is optimal.
So the Elbow Method is just an approach
that can help you make that decision.
But at the end of the day, it is your decision.
So there we go.
Hopefully you enjoyed this tutorial
and now your arsenal of K-Means clustering
is quite broad.
You have quite a few tools in there
and I can't wait for you to jump into
the practical application of this method.
Adaline has prepared some very interesting
code challenges for you
and you'll be working with this method
both in R and Python.
It's gonna be very exciting.
So good luck with that.
I'll see you next time
and until then, enjoy machine learning.