Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
Alright, so today we're gonna train
our stacked autoencoders.
And this is going to be quite technical,
but that's for the good reason,
because this is only to optimize our code
so that you can use it on high dimensional datasets,
on higher datasets because we are gonna do this
with the 200,000 ratings,
but if you wanna use it for the 1 million ratings dataset
or even a larger dataset,
you need an optimized code
that saves up the memory as much as possible.
So we won't go in too much details about the technique
and besides this is some technique related to PyTorch.
So you just need to understand what the lines of code
will do and that I will make sure to explain.
Because then, the most important thing that matters
is that you understand how the architecture
of the neuron network works
and that you know how to manipulate this architecture
by changing the number of layers
and the number of neurons in the hidden layers.
With this structure here, that's very simple to do.
And after this section I'll give you a little homework
to teach you how to manipulate objects.
And this homework will consist of
manipulating the objects related to the activation functions
so that you can try different combinations
of the activation functions.
So the most important part of the code is here
and now we're gonna train the SAE
and we're gonna use some pretty advanced techniques
in PyTorch that are only PyTorch related.
So let's do this.
It's gonna take a little more than 10 lines of code,
but no worries.
We will do it step by step.
So let's start with the first step.
The first step is to defined a number of EPOCH,
because you know we're training our stacked autoencoders
on several EPOCHs, so that at each EPOCH
the weights can be updated.
And so we need to choose a number of EPOCH.
And the number I chose is based of course on experimenting.
And by doing that I ended up choosing a number of EPOCH.
So that's the name of the variable I'm creating to 200.
So we're gonna train our stacked autoencoders on 200 EPOCHs.
Alright, second step.
Second step is to make a four loop, of course,
because in each EPOCH we will loop over
all our observations.
That is all our users because
each observation corresponds to the ratings of a user.
So we're gonna loop over all our users,
all our observations,
but we're gonna make this loop in each EPOCH.
So we will have two loops,
one loop to loop over all the EPOCHs and another loop,
inside this loop, to loop over all the observations,
that is the users.
So we start of course with the four loop for the EPOCH.
And so we do four,
then we introduced the variable for the loop,
which I'm gonna call EPOCH.
Alright, in range, and now we define the start
and the stop of the EPOCH variable.
So the start will be one, we will start at the first EPOCH
and we stop at number of EPOCH.
Of course we stop at 200.
But remember the upper bound in a range in Python
is excluded, so we have to add here
plus one so that that includes 200.
Alright, exactly as before.
And then colon and now we go inside the loop
and now this is inside this loop that this other loop
over all the users that we are gonna make
is gonna take place.
But before we introduced that second loop,
what we need to do is initialized two variables
that we will need to keep the information over the EPOCH.
And so what is it?
That's of course the loss, the loss error.
So we're gonna introduce a new variable
that will be this loss error.
And so I'm gonna call it train underscore loss.
Because then we will make the test loss
for the loss of the test set.
So train loss equals, and so right now we just want to
initialize it because it will be modified at each EPOCH.
And so we initialize it to zero because of course
at the very beginning of our training,
there is no loss yet.
And therefore, train loss equal zero.
Alright, we're not ready yet to start the second loop.
Before I'd like to introduce another variable
and initialize it to zero as well,
which will be a variable that will count the number of users
that rated at least one movie.
And that's for the exact purpose I've just mentioned.
That is to optimize the memory
because we won't do the computations for the users
who didn't rate any movies.
That could have happened, and so we want to exclude
these observations, these users from the computations.
And to do this we need to keep track of the number of users
who rated at least one movie
and so that's why we're introducing this new variable
right now, which I'm going to call s and
which I'm going to initialize to zero.
And I'm even going to do more.
I'm gonna introduce it to 0. To make it a float
and that's because I'm gonna use s to compute
the RMSE in the end.
That is the root-mean-squared error.
And since the root-mean-squared error is a float,
then all the elements to compute the root-mean-squared error
should be a float.
And since s is part of the computations,
s should rather be a float.
It's not compulsory,
but that's just to avoid a warning.
Alright, then next step.
And the next step is of course to start the second loop.
That is the loop that will loop over all the observations,
that is all the users.
So this loop will introduce all the actions
that will take place in one EPOCH.
So right now what we're gonna do inside this loop
is everything that is, you know, we're gonna get
our predicted rating using our SAE class
with this object we created.
We're gonna also compute the loss error.
But this will be the loss error on one EPOCH.
And that's what we wanna see evolve in the training.
You know we want to optimize this loss,
so we want to compute this loss at each EPOCH
and see if it's decreasing over the EPOCHs.
So we will do that and we will apply our optimizer
that we created here and that we'll apply to
casting gradient and descent to update the weights
and lead to the convergence.
And as an optimizer we chose RMSProp.
Okay, so now let's make the second loop
which is four and so now we introduce the loop variable
that will loop over all the users
and we're gonna call it ID underscore user.
Alright and then same in range.
And inside this range we need to put all our users.
So this time we actually don't have to choose
a sort of one and a step of NB users plus one
because actually it needs to be the indexes
of the observations of our training set
and the indexes of the observations of our training set
don't go from one to 943.
They go from zero to 942.
So what we simply need to do is add here
just NB underscore users, which we created right here,
NB users that is equal to 943
but only putting NB users here,
Will make this range from zero to 943 excluded.
That is 942 which is exactly what we want
for the indexes of our training set.
So that's perfect.
And now colon and we go inside the second loop.
Alright, and so now basically we need to
make the action take place for each observation.
That is for each user.
So, what do we have to start with?
Well, we can start by getting the input.
The input vector, that is basically
the input vector features
that contains all the ratings of all the movies
given by this particular user inside the loop.
Okay, so let's do this.
How can we get this input vector features
containing all the ratings?
Well first, let's give a name to this variable.
We're gonna call it input equals.
And so now basically what we would be tempted to do
is to take our training set, alright.
Because right now we're in the training set,
you know, we're training our stacked autoencoders,
and then brackets.
And then inside these brackets we input our ID user
because this ID user corresponds to the index
of the observation corresponding to the user
with which we are dealing right now in the loop.
Okay, fair enough.
But as you might've guessed,
this is not only what we have to do.
And the reason is that training set ID user is a vector
and a network in PyTorch or even on Charisse
generally can not accept a single vector of one dimension.
What it rather accepts is a batch of input vectors.
That is that when we applied the different functions
of the network, like for example,
the forward function, while the functions will not take
simple vectors of one dimension as input.
Remember we already crossed that situation.
That was when we used the predict function
to predict if the image contains a cat or a dog.
Remember we had to add one dimension
and that additional dimension was for the batch.
We put our input image of a cat or a dog into a batch
and that added one dimension that then would make
the whole thing accepted by the predict method.
And here that's gonna be the same.
This is the input.
We're gonna use some functions on this input
and as in Charisse, the PyTorch network and its functions
don't accept a single vector of one dimension as input.
And so what we need to do is do exactly the same
as we did in Charisse.
We need to add an additional dimension like a fake dimension
which will correspond to a batch.
So we'll create a batch.
This batch will contain one vector,
but we will be into a new dimension
corresponding to the batches.
And so now the question is,
how do we create this new dimension?
Well, that's just a PyTorch technique.
What we have to do is use the variable function.
So I'm putting that first
because it will take training set ID user as input,
so variable then parenthesis, we put
training set ID user inside.
But that's still not enough.
To create this additional dimension, we add here a dot.
And then we're gonna use the function unsqueeze, like this.
And now the last thing that we need to do is
specify the index of this new dimension.
And that's exactly the same as in Charisse.
We are gonna put this new dimension in first position.
And so this dimension will have index zero.
So the zero here is the index of this new dimension.
And this, all this, will create a batch of,
okay, a single input vector.
The batch can have several input vectors.
Remember we called this batch learning.
But here we're gonna do online learning.
That means that we're going to update the weights
after each observation going to the network.
And therefore, we are creating a batch of one input vector.
But we have to create this batch,
otherwise it won't work.
Alright, so now next step.
The next step now is to take care of the target.
We have the input vector,
but we would like some separate variables
between the input vector and the target.
So basically the target is the same as the input vector,
but since we're going to modify the input,
we would like to get the original input
before the modifications.
And therefore, I'm gonna create this target variable.
And this will be a clone of the inputs.
Like a copy of the inputs.
But I'm using the word clone because
we're gonna use the clone function.
Okay and so to clone our input,
we simply need to take our input.
So input here and then add a dot.
And then use this clone function to copy our input.
So right now the input and the target are the same.
That's the input vector features
containing all the ratings of the different movies
by this ID user at the loop right now.
But then we will modify target.
Okay, then next step.
So in this next step we're gonna introduce an if condition.
And the only purpose of doing this
is to optimize the memory.
To save as much memory as possible
because this if condition will consist of
only looking at the users who rated at least one movie.
So if an observation contains only zeros,
which means that the user didn't rate any movies,
then we won't care of this observation.
This will not be part of what's gonna follow.
Okay, so let's make this if condition.
We start with if, then we add the condition.
And this condition is going to be,
torch.some parenthesis, and inside the parenthesis,
we're gonna input target.data.
So target.data will take all the values of target,
which is our input vector.
And therefore, target.data will be
older ratings of this user here at the loop right now.
So, target.data is just all the ratings.
But we wanna consider all the ratings
that are larger than zero, because what we wanna do
is check to see if this sum of the ratings
that are larger than zero, that is either
one, two, three, four or five.
We wanna check if this sum is larger than zero.
And if that's the case,
that means that the observation contains at least
one rating that is not zero.
Because then if that's the case,
this sum will be larger than zero.
And so in that way we consider the users
that rated at least one movie.
So perfect.
That's what we want.
And now we can start the computations.
So the first thing we're gonna do now,
so that's the real first step of the action,
is to get our vector of predicted ratings.
That is our output at the very right of the network
after the input, that is the observation
went into the network.
So basically that's nothing else
than a vector of predicted ratings.
Okay, so we're gonna introduce a new variable
to get this output vector of predicted ratings
and we're gonna call it of course, output.
Here we go.
And now how can we get this vector of predicted ratings?
That is our predictions.
Well try to pause the video and guess it.
Because that's important to understand
what it's gonna be.
It's actually very simple.
I'm gonna tell you right now.
We have to use our SAE object.
Because this object is an object of the SAE class.
And in this SAE class, the action of forwarding
the input vector into the network takes place.
And we besides, this function returns
the output of the network,
that is the vector of predicted ratings.
So since this forward function is part of the class,
then by applying our object SAE to the input
of real ratings, well the forward function will be applied
and will return x.
That is the vector of predicted ratings.
So basically that's very simple.
We just need to take our object SAE,
and then in the parenthesis we add our input.
That is our input vector of real ratings.
This input is going to be this x here.
So the forward function will take place with the input
right here.
It will do the action and return x,
the vector of predicted ratings,
which is going to be output.
So that's how it works.
It's very important to understand this.
You just need to take your object
and by inputting the input vector of real ratings here,
the forward function will take action.
The encodings and decoding will happen.
And this will return eventually
to the vector of predicted ratings.
Alright, so we have our real ratings
and our Predicted ratings.
That's the first step done.
Now let's take a short break
and we'll take care of the rest of the training
in the next tutorial.
Until then, enjoy deep learning.