Hello and welcome to the Part One of the
Creation of our Hybrid Deep Learning Model.
As you understood, this part one is about making
the unsupervised deep learning branch
of our hybrid deep learning model.
This will be the self-organizing map
which we'll use to identify the frauds
exactly as we did in Part Four.
So, this will be good stuff, but
then the challenge will be to combine the two
and so the tricky part of this challenge
comes afterwards with Part Two,
"Going from Unsupervised to Supervised Deep Learning."
But it's good that we can start easy.
This will warm us up.
Alright so, let's go to our
self-organizing map code template.
As I just said, now it is kid stuff
because we simply need to copy all this code
to identify the frauds and paste that
back into our "Make a Case" study
and now what do we have to do?
Well, first, we'll execute this part
of the code to get a map, the self-organizing map
that will contain the outlying neurons.
Here it is, and, as we can see,
we clearly get this outline neuron,
which is an outline neuron because
it is characterized by a large MID,
the Mean Interneuron Distance,
and besides, it contains both categories of customers,
customers that got their application approved,
and customers that didn't get their application approved.
So that's perfect.
We got the frauds for the two types of scenarios.
Now, selecting the outlying neuron is kind of arbitrary,
because it actually depends on the
threshold we want to get to select these neurons.
Either we want to take the whitest neurons,
and in that case we would only take this one,
or we can decrease the threshold a little bit,
in which case we could also include this one.
Let's do that to include as much information as we can
and you can even go further and take some more over there.
Well, let's take the whitest one and then,
all the rest of the neurons are regular neurons,
common neurons that follow the general rules,
and therefore look definitely like non-potential frauds.
The frauds are definitely in this class here,
and more particularly, in this neuron.
Alright so, now we have to get the
coordinates of these two neurons.
So the first one has coordinates five and three
and the second one has coordinates eight and three.
So five, three and eight, three.
So let's input that here.
The first one has coordinates five, three
and the second one, eight, three.
Alright and now we're ready to get
the list of the frauds, the potential frauds,
and to do this, we need to execute this code.
Here we go. Now let's go to variable explore
and we get 37 frauds, so that's pretty good.
That gives us, pretty much, information.
I still don't know if the best model is to take
only the whitest outlying neuron
that we identified or to take the two.
Well, I'm taking the challenge here with you,
but you're welcome to try other ways
and I'd be very happy if you get better results than mine.
So, feel free to explore and improve your model.
What matters is that you practice
and, if possible, succeed.
And that's great if you succeed making a very robust model,
even more robust than the one we're about to make.
Alright, so we identified 37 frauds,
and so now what we're gonna do
is use the results that we just got here.
That is, this list of frauds to go from
unsupervised to supervised deep learning
because to go from unsupervised
to supervised deep learning, what do we need?
Well, we need a dependent variable
because with unsupervised deep learning,
we don't consider any dependent variable
because it was trained on our features
without using any dependent variable.
But when doing supervised deep learning,
we need a dependent variable because we need
the model to understand some correlations
between the features and a result, an outcome,
And the outcome is in the dependent variable.
So now, that's where comes the tricky part.
There will be more tricky parts after that,
but that's the most important thing to understand.
How are we going to create this dependent variable?
As soon as we manage to do that,
we will have all the ingredients to train
our future supervised deep learning model,
which will be our artificial neural network.
So think about it and I'll give you the answer
in the next tutorial. Until then, enjoy deep learning.