Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
So in the previous tutorial we imported the data set,
and now we're going to prepare the training set
and the test set.
So the training set will be to train our encoders
and the test set will be used to evaluate
their performance.
So let's do this, let's start with the training set.
So we're first going to go to file explorer
to see what we are going to take,
and, as I said in the previous tutorial,
we are going to take the 1000 ratings dataset
which is in this folder, and in fact what we
are seeing here in the ml-100k folder
is five train-test splits of the whole dataset
composed of 100 thousand ratings.
So as you can see we have u1.base, u1.test,
u2.base, u2.test, u3.base, u3.test,
up to u5.base, u5.test, and so,
each one of those pairs of sets
are actually some separate training set
and test set, so base means training set,
and test means test set.
So u1.base and u1.test is one train-test split
of the whole dataset composed
of one hundred thousand ratings,
and the other pairs are other train-test splits.
And so what's the use of having several train-test splits?
Well, that's to perform careful cross-validations
manually afterwards, you know, to be able to train
our model on several training sets
and test it on several test sets
exactly as we did when we performed careful
cross-validation with ten-fold, since indeed
we were training our neural network
on ten training folds, and we were testing it
on ten associated test folds.
And here, instead of having ten train-test folds,
we actually have five train-test folds
and therefore that's to do five-fold cross-validation.
But we're not going to perform five-fold cross-validation
in this section, because I like to focus on
the auto-encoders themselves, and therefore
we will only take one train-test split
and we will take the first one
composed of u1.base, that is the training set,
and u1.test, that is the test set.
So let's import these two sets.
All right, so we're going to start with the training set
which is u1.base, and therefore we're going to create
a new variable training_set.
Here we go, and now we're going to use
the pandas library, still, because we want
to import u1.base, but then we will convert
this training set into an array because
by importing u1.base with pandas we will get
a data frame, and remember with Python
we would rather work with arrays.
So let's first import it with pandas as a data frame,
and then let's convert it.
So, the same, we're gonna use the shortcut pd
and dot, then the read_csv function,
then parentheses, and for the first argument
we need to input the path that will take
u1.base in this ml-100k folder.
So let's do it.
We have to put the path in quotes, like before,
and so we start with the folder that contains
u1.base, that is the training set,
and this folder is ml-100k, so we start
by typing ml-100k, then /, and then simply
the name of the training set which is u1.base.
So u1, dot, base.
And here we go, that should be okay to import
the training set, however, I pre-checked
the separator for this u1.base file
and this time it happens to be not a double colon
but a tab, so you can check it out by opening,
for example, u1.base on a text editor
and you'll see that the separator is a tab,
and therefore you will need to specify it
otherwise it will think the separator is a comma
because the default separator is a comma.
So we're gonna add the argument
delimiter equals tab, and to specify tab
we need to input \t, like this.
And by the way, the delimiter, tab,
should rather be taken with this delimiter argument
rather than this set argument.
So it's good to know that, and, actually,
now I think we're ready to import the training set.
So let's check it out.
I'm going to select this line and execute.
Here we go, yes, the training set is well imported.
Perfect, let's have a look in the variable explorer,
and here it is.
So, first of all, what is the split?
I mean, what is the proportion of the training set
compared to the whole set?
Well, we can already see that.
Remember, the whole original data set in this ml-100k folder
contains one hundred thousand ratings,
and since each observation corresponds to one rating...
Well, since we can see here that we
have 80 thousand observations that means
that we have 80 thousand ratings,
and therefore the training set is 80%
of the original dataset composed of
the one hundred thousand ratings,
so that will be an 80% 20% train-test split,
and I think that's the optimal train-test split
to train a model.
Okay, so now let's open the training set to see
what it looks like.
So, remember that's exactly the same
as in this ratings dataset that we imported
in the previous tutorial.
The first column corresponds to users,
the second column corresponds to the movies,
and the third column corresponds to the ratings,
and then the fourth column corresponds to the timestamps,
but that, as we said, we don't care,
because this won't be relevant to train the model.
And so here, for example, at the fourth index,
that is the fifth observation because it starts at 0,
well, that corresponds to the user number one
that rated the movie number seven and gave it four stars.
Then, if we take another example...
Well, at the 261st observation,
that corresponds to the user number five
that rated the movie number 373 and gave it three stars.
All right, and so, now what's gonna happen
is that we will train our auto-encoders
on this training set, and so it will try
to identify some patterns to find some groups
of movies that are liked by similar segments of users,
and so it will find these patterns,
it will find some specific features of the movies
which will be the hidden nodes in the auto-encoders,
and these specific features can be some genders,
some actors that are in the movies, or some directors.
For example, one hidden node can be a specific director,
like Tarantino, for example, or it can identify
some movies with a great actor that is liked
by the same group of people because they gave
the same high rating.
So basically it will identify some patterns,
it will identify some features,
based on which, in the future,
the model will be able to predict the rating
of a movie that one user hasn't seen yet,
and it will be able to predict that rating
based on the features that the auto-encoder's
detected, and based on the history of this user.
That is, you know the auto-encoders will take
the features that it detected,
and it will take also the ratings of that one same user
to predict the rating of the new movie
that the same user hasn't seen,
and therefore has not rated yet.
So that's how it will work, and you will see
how the auto-encoders will make a brilliant job
at identifying these patterns,
identifying these features, and eventually
predict the ratings.
Okay, so that is the training set,
it is so far imported as a data frame,
and therefore, as I just told you,
we have to convert it into an array
because then you will see that you will use
Torch sensors, and for this we need arrays
instead of data frames.
So, let's quickly convert this training set
into an array, that's very simple.
We need to take our training set variable again
and give it a new value, and so now,
basically what we're going to do is use
the function that will convert a data frame
into an array, and this function is, of course,
a non-bide function that is called array.
We take our shortcut np, because we're taking
this function from non-bide, and now we take
this function array and parentheses.
So that's the best way of converting a data frame
into an array.
Now, inside this function we have to input
our training set but the old one, this one,
that is a data frame, so training_set.
And, as a second argument we will need
to specify the type of this new array
that we are creating, and since we only have
user IDs, movie IDs, and ratings that are all integers,
then we will convert this whole array
into an array of integers, and to do this,
we need to use this argument here, that you see,
dtype, and that will specify the type of the array.
And so we'll add dtype equals, and then in quotes,
we will specify the type which is int for integers.
Perfect.
So, as you can see, if I select this line,
now we can see that that the training set
is a data frame of this size,
and if I execute this...
The training set is now an array,
that means array actually of integers, 64,
and of the same size.
So perfect, and if we open it, well we get
the same values, but this time into an array.
Okay, so now we're going to do the same for the test set,
we're going to prepare the test set,
and actually this is going to be very easy
because we will use the same techniques
to import and convert our test set
into an array, so I'm pasting that here.
I'm going to replace training set by test set,
same here, training set, test set.
And here as well, and of course, after that
we'll need to replace this u1.base by u1.test
because we're taking out the test set
which is u1.test.
Here we go, perfect, and that will take the test set.
The delimiter is also a tab, so basically,
we're already ready to import the test set.
So let's do it step by step.
I'm going to select this line first,
and, execute, here we go, test set imported,
we can have a quick look.
So that's the test set, and same, this is exactly
the same structure.
We have the users in the first column,
then the movies in the second column,
and the ratings in the third column.
And so what we have to understand is that
the training set and the test set
have different ratings.
You know, there is no common rating
of the same movie by the same user
between the training sets and the test set,
however, we have the same users, here indeed
we start with user one, as in the training set.
But, for this same user one, we won't have the same movies
because the ratings are different.
So here, we have the answers in this third column
that contains the ratings, but it's just to get
the real results on one's side, and so what
will happen is that we will make our predictions
using our auto-encoder's model to predict
the rating, for example, of movie 14 by user one.
This will give a prediction here,
so it will give, for example, four, and then,
we will measure the error between the real rating, five,
and the prediction, four, and that will allow us
to measure the MSE that is the Mean Squared Error.
So, we're just keeping this column
to measure the MSE in the end, in order
to evaluate our test set performance,
and I will tell soon where the medals are,
for the challenge of this section.
Okay, so, perfect, that's the test set,
but right now it is as a data frame,
and we need to convert it into an array,
so that's what we're gonna do now.
And actually we don't have anything to do,
the line of code is ready, so we just have to select it
and press command or control plus enter
to execute, and here we go, now the test set
is an array of integers 64 of 20 thousand ratings
that corresponds to 20% of the original dataset
composed of the one hundred thousand ratings.
Perfect, so that's done for this tutorial,
we prepared correctly the training set,
and the test set, and now in the next tutorial
we will get the maximum number of users
and the maximum number of movies in two separate variables
because then we will need these two variables
to prepare our auto-encoders.
So we'll do that in the next tutorial,
and until then, enjoy deep learning!