All right, let's do this.
Logistic regression intuition.
And you can probably already tell by my voice
that I'm pretty excited.
There's some very interesting slides coming up
and this is quite an important topic,
but at the same time it is quite challenging.
So a quick heads-up,
there will be some math and I've done a few
run-throughs of this presentation already
and I really,
I will try my best to convey everything
in the simplest way possible.
So let's get into it.
We already know about the linear regression.
We know that there's a simple linear regression
and it has this very short formula
of one independent variable.
And we also have looked
into the multiple linear regression
which has many independent variables.
So we already know how to deal
with this type of challenge.
So when we have a scale put like that
where on the horizontal axis
we've got the independent variable
on the vertical axis we've got the dependent variable
and this is an example, we've looked
at salary versus experience.
How do we create a model here?
So we use a simple linear regression.
It puts a line through our data
and that line is modeling our observations
so we can basically forecast things
and compare our actual observations to our model and so on
but so we know how to deal
with challenges like that or problems like that
but your company had hired you as a data scientist,
what they do is they send out email of first two customers
with like a proposal to buy certain products
it might be a clothing store or it might be a grocery store
or something like that.
So, what they do is basically they send out a offer
in email to a lot of customers to purchase some product
and here you've got a sample of those customers
that they contacted recently, you've got their age
and also you have a variable
whether (mumbles) not they took action.
So did the person take up an action, perform an action
did they take up an offer, did they buy a product,
did they open up an email respond to our email and so on.
So was action taken or not?
And the very black and white, very different
but at the same time like even though we don't know
what to do, we don't know what's going on here,
it's not what we're expecting
but at the same time intuitively we can see
that there's some sort of correlation.
We can see that the observations on the bottom,
they're a bit more to the left,
observations on the top are a bit more
to the right implying kind of
that probably older people are more likely to take action
based on this offer and younger people are more likely
to ignore it.
So, can we somehow model this?
How about we try the existing method in our toolkit
which is the linear regression.
Let's run a linear regression and that's what it looks like
as you can tell, it doesn't look like the best approach.
It doesn't look like the best method to solve this problem.
So, let's look into this in a bit more detail.
We're going to draw the other horizontal line over here.
Instead of trying to predict exactly what's going to happen
for any given person, let's imagine a person
and let's say we want to predict
for that person knowing their age
we want to predict whether they will
take up the offer or not
but instead of predicting exactly whether they're going
to take it up or not, how about
instead we will predict the probability,
we will stage a probability or a likelihood
of that person taking up that offer
and if you think of it in that way,
right away things start becoming clear.
Right away you can see that okay, so this chart is actually
from zero to one.
And I also know that probabilities are from zero to one.
Ooh, that's interesting.
So basically I could feed in probabilities
between zero and one.
The fact that the red dots, the red observations
are already either zero or one and nowhere in between.
Well that's simply because we already know the result.
We already know that they're either there or there
but for something we're predicting,
it kinda makes sense to say well, I don't know for sure,
I don't know 100% he will take it up or not
but I know maybe of an 80% chance he will take it up or not.
Right?
And when you think of it that way,
the linear regression line or at least
that part that's in the middle between zero and one.
It makes sense, right?
Or it makes some sense,
because that is basically it's telling you
that anybody between those ages of for instance,
where it's crossing the horizontal line
for the first time
or where it's crossing the horizontal axis,
it might be like 25 or let's say 35
and where it's crossing the horizontal axis for one
it might be let's say 55.
So those people between 35 and 55,
any person that falls in between that age,
there's a probability of them taking up this offer
and that probability is increasing as we move to the right
as we take more and more older people
that probability is increasing.
So the part of the linear regression in the middle
kind of makes sense and we can do something with it
but the parts that don't make sense at all are the ones
at the top or at the bottom
because probability can never be less than zero
or it can never be above one.
So what's the linear regression trying
to give us a hint about here?
Well, what it's probably saying, what we could interpret
as is that people above that age,
that nominal age we said 55, above that age,
they're very very likely
to take offer actually more than 100%.
So basically, they're definitely taking it up.
Anybody below 35 on the other side
on the left they're definitely not taking it.
So essentially what we're saying is
if we ever take that approach
then we would have to replace this linear regression line
for a line that looks like that.
So let's just cut those bits off
and replace them with horizontal parts.
And that would be a very basic
but it still would be an attempt
at creating a model for this situation.
So we would still be able to use this
to make some sort of predictions and assumptions
that talk about the correlation between the action
and the age of a person.
So, that's a very basic understanding
and that's kind of the start of our understanding
of intuition behind logistic regression.
So let's see what the actual scientific approach is.
So here we've got the line that we looked at
and it's described by this equation.
Now this part is gonna be, this is the most fun part
so bear with me.
If you apply to this equation a sigmoid function,
which looks like that, so you put the y
into the sigmoid function in purple
and then you solve for y from the purple box
and you put y back into the blue box,
then you will get the green box.
So basically, your linear regression
will start to look like this
and this is the formula for logistic regression
and what that will do
to your chart which is most importantly
this visual part, it will convert it from the chart
that we see at the top to this new chart
which is actually the logistic regression function.
So, if at this stage you're asking yourself,
what just happened?
Then you're not alone.
(laughs)
the first time I saw this or I learned this,
this was the expression on my face.
If you're totally comfortable for all that,
that's super great.
That means you'll thrive through this section
but if you're confused right now, not a problem,
I was the same when I was in your shoes.
So let's take this step by step.
Let's look at it step by step or exactly what happened.
So there's our graph.
There's our independent variable.
There's our outcome yes or no.
So that's the y, the dependent variable
and there are our observations in our data set.
Based on these observations and plus using this formula
which we're going to take as given.
This is the logistic regression formula.
Using this formula and these observations,
we come up with this line and what's important
to understand here it's not a magical line.
This line for the logistic regression is the same
as a slope or a trend line for a linear regression.
So basically what this line is doing
is it is using the formula, it's following the formula
and it's the best fitting line that can fit these data sets.
So basically we're doing exactly the same thing as of
for linear regression but it just looks different,
that's all.
So there are heaps of these lines
that you can draw that look like that
but only one of them is the best fitting line.
So the point of the logistic regression is
to find that best fitting line and this is it.
So we found the best fitting line that follows
that equation and fits these variables or these observations
that we had in our data set.
After that, we can forget about the equation,
we forget about the variables, we've got our line.
So this is our logistic regression function.
We've found the same thing as of for linear regression.
We've created the model.
We've built the model.
You can see it.
This is the model in front of you right there.
Now what can we do with this logistic regression?
Well, we can use it to predict probabilities
and we've already touched on probabilities
that they lie between zero and one
and that instead of predicting for sure
that something will or will not happen,
how about we predict the probability.
So, let's look at...
Oh by the way probability here is called p_hat
so that that little sign above the p gives us the name p_hat
and anything you see
with the hat in this section just basically means
that it's something we're predicting
so that's a way to remember it, that picture p_hat
so we're predicting this probability.
Okay, so let's take four random values
for the independent variable.
For x, we're going to say 20, 30, 40, 50.
Let's see what happens to these variables.
So let's put them on the x line.
Those are the dots and I specifically put dots
not x's or crosses because it doesn't mean
that they're on the horizontal bottom line doesn't mean
that their probability is zero
or that their dependent variable is zero.
No, they're just there because they're on the x-axis.
We just plotted them there.
It has nothing to do with vertical axis.
Now, what you need to do to find the probabilities
is you need to project these values onto your curve.
Once you project them,
you get these
blue dots or blue observations
which plotted basically so these are the fitted values
as you remember in red you have the actual
and in blue you have the fitted values.
So these are your fitted values
and now if you project them, if you want the probabilities,
you need to project them to the left like that.
And let's have a look at these probabilities.
So the person who is 20 years old,
the probability of taking this offer is very low,
perhaps 0.7% so less than one percentage
to take up this offer.
The person who is 30 years old, the probability is higher.
It's about 23% to take up this offer.
The person who is 40 years old,
their probability to take up this offer is 85%
according to this model
and the person who is 50 years old,
their probability is 99.4%.
So that's the first thing that you can get
out of a logistic regression.
That's what we're going to be using
we're gonna be using it very actively
when we're talking
about building geo-demographic segmentations
because you use this probability as a score
and we'll talk about this more.
So you can actually rank people,
who is the most likeliest to take up your offer
and who is the least likeliest to take your offer up.
So it's actually even better
than just having a one or a zero.
You have a probability so you can order people
by this probability.
Anyway, you might want to say
well, I don't want the probability,
I want a prediction as
(laughs)
because this is a regression, I want a prediction
for the y value.
So, okay, we can do that.
Let's get rid of those probabilities.
Now can we get y the actual.
Obviously we can't get the actual
because the actual is something we can only observe
in our data set or in real life.
We can only get a prediction for the actual.
So y_hat as the hat suggests is the predicted value
for the dependent variable.
How do you get y_hat?
Well, the approach is very arbitrary.
You have to select a line.
Let's wait for that.
Okay.
So you have to select a line.
In this case we're going to select 50%.
You can select it anywhere but 50% is usually selected
because it's in the middle and therefore you have symmetry
and anything below this line, so anything that falls
on the curve below this line will be projected
downwards onto the zero line
which makes sense.
So it's basically saying if your probability,
your predicted probability of taking
up this offer is less than 50%, let's say it's 40% or 20%
then we're just gonna say
that you're probably not gonna take up this offer
and so that's what's happening.
The person with 0.7%, the person
with whatever it was 27%, 23%,
their probabilities are not zero but they're below 50 so
if you do require a y_hat so a predicted value,
a yes/no value then makes sense
that if something is below 50%,
you're probably gonna say
that they're not gonna take up the offer.
so there you go both of them y_hats are zero.
Now, anything above the horizontal line
that we selected, the 50% line
is agreed that all of those values that fall
onto the curve above that line are projected upwards,
they're projected onto the yes line, the one line
so the person that had a probability
of 85% is projected outwards and the person
that had the probability of 99.7% is projected upwards.
Also makes sense right?
So if
you're predicting that somebody's probability
of taking up an offer is 85%, then if you have
to say yes or no, then you're probably gonna say yes.
You're gonna say yes this person would take up the offer
if you have to choose one of the two.
So those are our predicted y_hat values
if in this case, they're both one for those two variables
and those are the two things you can get out of
the logistic regression so you get
the probabilities which are important.
Also, you can get the y_hats, the predicted values
for the dependent variables.
Once again, it's important to think of it
as it's doing exactly the same thing as a linear regression.
It's fitting this line even though it's not a straight line
and the values are not scattered,
everything looks bizarre in its uniformity
or in its structure makes it look bizarre
but still, it's a pretty much the same way.
We've agreed on the line or a formula for the curve
and we're trying to fit the best curve to our data.
Once we've done that, we've got a model,
we've got the coefficients which will talk about later
and we can start drawing conclusions
or insights from this model and some of the insights are
we can get a probability of somebody taking action
or of the event occurring or basically
of the answer being yes, so it's not a yes/no,
it's a probability so 85% or 20% or whatever.
So that's when we project it to the left onto the y-axis
and also we can get a predicted value
for the dependent variable based
on where we select this arbitrary line 50%.
You can select it anywhere you like.
You can select it higher, lower, depends on your knowledge
about the problem at hand and as you understand.
Depending on where you selected,
that will significantly affect your variables.
So I really hope this explanation was trivial enough
and yet insightful enough for you
to gain an intuitive understanding of logistic regression.
I look forward to seeing you then
and until next time, happy analyzing.