Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
So in the previous tutorial we imported
the required libraries to build
our future artificial neural network.
And so now we're gonna start
building our deep learning model.
And we're gonna build this model in two parts.
Part one will be data preprocessing,
which I've prepared here.
And part two will only be about creating the ANN model.
So let's start with part one.
And you will understand in this tutorial
why it's so important to prepare the data correctly
to build a future deep learning model.
So, as you understood in the business problem description
explained by career.
We are in front of a classification problem.
So we have some independent variables
which are some informations about customers in a bank
and we are trying to predict
a binary outcome for the dependent variable,
which is either one if the customer leaves the bank
and zero if the customer stays in the bank.
So this is a classification problem.
And therefore, I've prepared here
our classification template
which is explained in great details
in the last annex section at the end of this course
get the machine learning basics.
So basically, what we're gonna do now
is take everything in this template
except the visualizing parts
because we know we have many independent variables.
We have more than 10 independent variables.
So we take everything from importing the libraries to here
because in the end we'll have a look at the confusion matrix
to evaluate the performance of our ANN model.
So we will take this whole section
and go back to our ANN model and paste everything here.
All right, so let's handle
each of the sections here one by one.
Let's start with the first one, importing the libraries.
So let's take this code section here and execute.
Here we go.
Libraries well imported.
Great, now second code section, importing the dataset.
So let's do it.
The data set is not social_Networks_Ads.csv.
It is now
Churn_Modelling.csv
All right, perfect.
So let's import it.
Great, well imported.
Now let's go to variable explorer
to have a quick look, here it is.
That's our data set.
So quick reminder, this data set
are informations of customers in a bank.
The bank gathered these informations
and at the same time observed if the customer stayed
or left the bank within a six month period of time.
And so the key thing to understand here is that
all these variables here are independent variables
and the last column here, exited is our dependent variable.
And so, we are trying to predict the results
of this exited dependent variable
from the informations of these independent variables.
And we're going to do that
within our artificial neural network.
All right, so let's press okay.
And now the next thing that we have to do
is to create the matrix X of features
and to do that we need to input the right indexes here.
So to have an idea of what these indexes are
we need to go back to our data set and see
which independent variables
we want to include in our matrix of features
because our matrix of features is nothing else
than a matrix containing the independent variables.
All right, so let's do it.
We have all our variables here
and let's look at them one by one.
First column is row number,
row number has of course, no impact on the decision
of the customer to leave or stay in the bank.
So we won't include this variable in our matrix of features.
Second variable, customer ID same.
Absolutely no impact on the dependent variable.
All right, third column, surname well that's the same.
It's not because your name is Andrews
that you have more chance to leave the bank
than if your name is McDonald.
All right, that has absolutely no impact
on the dependent variable and therefore,
we won't include the surname variable either.
Now next variable, credit score.
Well, credit score, yes.
The credit score is very likely
to have an impact on the decision of the customer
to stay in the bank or leave the bank.
If we think about it, we might expect
that customers with a low credit score are more likely
to leave the bank than customers with a high credit score.
So definitely, that's the first independent variable
that we will include in our matrix of features.
All right, then geography, geography, yes.
Perhaps customers in France are more likely
to leave the bank than customers in Germany.
So we'll include that as well.
Gender, yes, same.
Perhaps men are more likely to leave the bank than women.
We never know, we have to check it out.
Then age.
Age, well, of course, young people might be
more likely to leave the bank than older people
that not only have more stability,
but also might have been in the bank
for a longer period of time
and therefore, are more likely to stay.
All right, and tenure.
Tenure is how long the customer has been in the bank.
Of course, this might have an impact
on the decision to stay or leave the bank
so we include that as well.
Balance, same.
Of course, the customer with a zero balance has more chance
to leave the bank than a customer with a high balance.
Number of products, we never know
it might have an impact
we'll include that as well.
Has credit card, yes, maybe.
We might expect that customers
with a credit card are more likely to stay in the bank
than customers who don't have a credit card.
So we have to check it out as well.
Is active member, well, same logic as here.
If a customer is active,
then he might be more likely to stay in the bank.
And eventually, estimated salary,
well, that's the same logic as balance,
customers with a high estimated salary
might be more likely to stay in the bank
than customers with low estimated salaries.
So with our own logic, we are able to say
which independent variables might have impact
on the dependent variable but what we don't know is
which independent variable has the most impact
on the dependent variable.
And that's what our artificial neural network will spot
and we'll perfectly see by looking
at the correlations here and therefore,
it will give the bigger weight in the neural network
to those independent variables that have the most impact.
All right, so now we know which independent variables
to include in our matrix of features.
That's all the independent variables from credit score
to the last one, estimated salary.
And so let's see what the indexes
of these independent variables are.
So let's see indexes and bison start at zero,
so that's zero here, one, two, three.
Okay, so we'll go from three to three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10, 11 and 12.
All right, so we must include the indexes from three to 12.
So let's do it.
Let's press okay here.
All right, so we need to take the indexes from three to 12.
This takes the indexes two and three.
And so to take indexes from three to 12,
we need to add the lower bound here, index three colon
and then the upper bound, but remember,
the upper bound is excluded in a range.
So instead of putting 12 we need to put 13.
And that takes all the indexes from three to 12.
All right, good.
So now we're ready to create our matrix of features x.
And so let's select this line and execute.
Great, matrix of features x created.
All right, and now let's create
our dependent variable vector.
So that's very easy.
You know, remember our independent variables are taking
indexes from three to 12 and therefore,
the index of our dependent variable is index number 13.
And therefore, instead of four here we input 13.
AlL right, so we are ready to build
a dependent variable vectors.
So let's select this line and execute.
All right, here we go.
We can have a look.
Y contains the binary outcomes, zero or one
for all the 10,000 customers of the sample of this bank.
All right, so let's press okay.
We're done with importing the data set.
Everything is well prepared.
Now let's move on to the next code section.
The next code section is about splitting the dataset
into the training set and the test set.
But before we do that, we must pay attention to something.
We must fix something before splitting the dataset
to the training set and the test set.
Can you guess what it is?
Well, it's, of course, related to the fact that
we have some categorical variables
in our matrix of features.
And therefore, we need to encode them exactly as we did.
And in the next section at the end of this course,
get the machine learning basics.
And that is why, I've also prepared
the categorical data that PY file right here.
And therefore, in this file,
we will take this code section here
that encodes any categorical data
that you have in your dataset.
So by the way, our dependent variable is categorical,
but it takes values zero or one.
So it takes numerical values.
So we don't need to apply label encoder
to, you know, encode text into numbers.
But we have our independent variables
which have categories that are strings and therefore,
we need to take this code section here
that will encode the categorical independent variables.
All right, so I'm taking this,
copy and going back to my ANN file
and we will encode the categorical data before splitting
the dataset into the training set and the test set.
Because basically, when you do this split
your matrix of features x
and your dependent variable y must be already encoded.
All right, so I'm pasting that here.
Here we go.
I'm going to remove that.
That was just to make the distinction
between independent variable and dependent variable.
And now we will encode
our categorical independent variables.
So let's see what they are.
We will have a look
at our matrix of features from the console.
So I'm pressing X here and let's have a look.
All right, so these are all our independent variables.
We can very clearly and quickly see here
that we only have two categorical independent variables
which are the country which contains three categories
France, Spain, and Germany and the gender variable
which contains two categories female and male.
So these are the only two variables
we need to encode in our matrix of features.
So let's do it.
Let's take care of the first one, the country.
All right so, since we only need to encode two variables,
we will need to create two label encoder object here.
And therefore, we'll call the first one, labelencoder_x_1.
All right, so here we create the object.
And then in the next line, we apply
the fit_transform method to encode this variable.
That is, it will convert the strings here,
France, Spain and Germany into numbers zero, one and two.
So that's the first step of the encoding.
So let's do it.
We need to put the right index here,
which is not zero, but of course one
because indexes in Python start at zero.
So that's index zero and that's index one.
That's the index we want.
All right, great.
And same here we replace zero by one.
All right, good.
Let's not forget to add this underscore one here
to take this object created here.
And so I'm going to select these three lines here.
And this will convert the strings into three numbers.
All right, so well executed.
Now let's have a look at x, here we go and that's it.
So as you can see, France became zero,
Spain became two and Germany became one.
All right and now let's take care
of the second categorical variable, the gender variable.
So we will do exactly the same as we did here,
but only with a new object.
So I'm going to copy this, copy and paste it here.
And here, I will not only change
the name of the labelencoder object,
which I will replace by labelencoder_x_2, right?
And let's not forget to replace it here as well.
And of course, we need to change the index here
which corresponds to the index
of the independent variable we want to encode
and therefore, that's, of course,
the index number two, zero, one and two.
All right, so we replace one by two here and same as well.
All right, and that's done.
We just need to select this and execute.
All right, now let's have a look at x, x here.
Here we go and as you can see,
female became zero and male became one.
I hope the ladies of this course won't be offended.
But that's pure random.
All right, so now we need to do one more thing,
which is, of course, related to the fact
that our categorical variables are not ordinal.
That means that there is no relational order
between the categories of our categorical variables.
That is, you know, France is not higher than Germany
and Germany isn't higher than France, and same
between Spain and Germany and Spain and France.
All right, so exactly as we did in part one,
we need to create dummy variables
for this categorical variable.
And we will only do it for this categorical variable
of the country because it contains three categories
and this one contains two categories.
So since we will then remove one column
to avoid the dummy variable trap.
Well, it will be no use to create
dummy variables for this one.
So let's just do it for this one.
And we already have everything prepared here
with the OneHotEncoder class
that will create these semi variables.
We don't even need to change the index
because that corresponds to the right index
of the column we want to create the dummy variables for.
Indeed, that is index one.
All right, so basically, we're ready
and we can just select that here
to create the dummy variables.
All right, done, well executed.
Now we can have a look at x.
And actually, since now all the columns have the same type.
We can have a look at x from here
because the type is no longer an object, but float 64.
So let's have a look.
And we can clearly see all the independent variables
of our matrix of features.
All right, so we now have 12 independent variables
because we have our three new dummy variables.
I'm gonna change the format very quickly, zero, okay.
Alright, so these are our three dummy variables
corresponding to the country.
And then here we have the credit score.
Then here, the categorical variable
corresponding to the gender,
and then the other independent variables.
So that's great.
But now we will remove one dummy variable here
to avoid falling into the dummy variable trap.
All right, so let's do that right now .
It's going to be very quick and easy.
We take our matrix of features X and we will update it
by taking all the lines of this matrix
and all the columns except the first one.
And to do this, I'm taking all the columns
from index one which corresponds to the second column
until the last index of the last column.
All right, and that will do it.
I'm going to select this and execute
and now as you can see,
we only have two dummy variables for the country
which is great.
So no more dummy variable trap.
All right, so we're good.
We are ready to split the dataset
into the training set and the test set.
So that's exactly what we do in this section.
Everything is ready.
We will maybe change the test size to 0.2
to you know, train the ANN on 8,000 observations
and test its performance on 2,000 observations.
So let's do it.
I'm going to select these three lines here and execute.
And here we get something new .
We get a deprecation warning that is fine.
It's just because spider was a updated
to its latest version and in this latest version,
well, this cross validation package here
was replaced by model selection.
So basically, to avoid this warning, this is fine,
this perfectly created the training set and the test set,
but to avoid the warning, we just need to replace
cross_validation here by model_selection.
All right, and now if I reselect that
and execute as you can see, the warning disappears.
All right, so that's good to know.
And that can be useful to avoid future errors.
All right, and now time for feature scaling.
Do we need to apply feature scaling
to artificial neural networks and in general, deep learning?
Well, the answer is yes, absolutely.
That is thoroughly compulsory.
And that is because there's going
to be a lot of computations, you know,
highly compute intensive calculations.
And besides parallel computations,
so we need to apply feature scaling
to ease all these calculations.
And besides, we don't wanna have
one independent variable dominating another one.
So very important, we need to apply feature scaling
that's really compulsory.
So let's do it.
Everything's ready here.
I don't need to change anything.
So let's execute and all good, no warning,
features getting done properly.
We can have a quick look at x_train here.
As you can see, all the independent variables are scaled
and that's the same for the test set.
Everything is scaled properly, we are all good.
Our data is not well preprocessed.
And now I'm super excited because we are about
to start building the artificial neural network.
This is going to be something, we are now approaching
one of the most powerful tools in machine learning
that I'm sure will be very useful
if you need to apply them for your work.
So we're gonna do that in the next tutorial.
And until then, enjoy deep learning.