Hello and welcome to this new tutorial.
All right, so in this one, we're gonna tackle
the last step of the first part Data Preprocessing.
So this last step is about reshaping the data
that is adding some even more dimensionality
to this previous data structure we made
in the previous tutorial.
And this dimension we're gonna add is exactly the unit,
that is, the number of predictors we can use to predict
what we want.
Which is the Google Stock Price at time T plus one.
So in the scope of this financial engineering problem
where we try to predict the trend of the Google Stock Price,
these predictors are indicators.
And right now we have one indicator,
which is the open Google Stock Price.
And we take the 60 previous Google Stock Prices
to predict the next one.
So that's our only indicator, but thanks to this new
dimension that we're gonna add to our data structure.
We will be able to add some more indicators,
if you think could help predict even better
the upward and downward trends of the Google Stock Price.
We're not gonna do it in this implementation.
We will just use the open Google Stock Price.
But thanks to this new data structure,
this new dimensionality, you will be able to add
if you want, some more indicators.
All right, so let's make this happen.
It's actually really simple, it just takes one line of code.
And to add this new dimension, we're gonna use the
reshape function.
Anytime you want to add a dimension in a non pi array
you always need to use the reshape function,
that's your best tool for that, all right?
So first of all let's understand that we just need to
do this for X train, because X train actually contains
the inputs of the neural network.
And now we need to create this new dimensionality
of this new data structure, because simply,
that is exactly what is expected by the
future recurrent neural network that we're gonna build
in the second part.
So that's not only for you to be able to use
some more indicators, that's also to be compatible with
the input format, the input shape, as we call it of the
recurrent neural network.
All right, so let's update X train, then.
X train and as we said, to update it,
we're gonna use the reshape function.
And this reshape function is taken of course from,
the non pi library, which has a shortcut NP
because, basically, we're reshaping a non pi array.
So NP.reshape, perfect.
And now, in this reshape function, we need to input
two arguments.
The first argument is what we want to reshape,
that is the non pi array we want to reshape.
And that is, of course, X underscore train,
that's our non pi array we want to reshape,
that is, add this new dimension corresponding
to the predictor.
Or in our problem, the indicator.
And now in the second argument of this reshape function
we need to specify this new structure,
that is this new shape we want our
non pi array or X train to have.
All right, so we have to input this structure
in some parenthesis, because we're gonna include
three elements in these parentheses, and why is that?
That's because right now, our data structure
has two dimensions as you can see.
X train right now has two dimensions.
It is a non pi array of 1198 lines and 60 columns,
so two dimensions.
And now we're gonna add this new dimension,
and therefore, there will be like a 3D shape here
with a new dimension corresponding to the indicator.
So you have to visualize it in 3D.
It will be like we will have these non pi arrays
of two dimensions here, stacking in a new dimension
that we're gonna create, corresponding to the indicators.
All right, so make sure to visualize this well.
And therefore, in this parenthesis, we simply need
to add these three dimensions.
And now, to know exactly the order of the dimensions
we need to include, well I would recommend to go to
the Keras documentation, because it tells exactly
the dimensions we need to include here.
So I'm gonna go to Google and, so these are my
train and test data sets that I imported with
Google spreadsheet.
But now I'm gonna open a new tab in which I'm going to
search for Keras documentation.
First, perfect, now let's click on the first link,
Keras documentation, and now let's go to recurrent layers
in this layers section here.
So recurrent layers and actually we already found what we
want which is this paragraph here about input shapes.
Input shapes is exactly the input shape expected
by the recurrent neural network in Keras.
And as you can see, it's a 3D tensor.
Tensor is like an array.
The input should be a 3D array, containing the
following three dimensions.
First, the batch size, which will correspond to the
total number of observations we have.
That is the total number of stock prices we have from
2012 to the end of 2016.
Then the second dimension is the time steps,
the number of time steps.
And that is, as you understood, 60.
And now the third dimension, this new one that we're adding
is the one corresponding to the indicators, the predictors.
So I remind, these can be some new financial indicators
that could help predict the Google stock price trends.
So, for example, that can be the closed Google stock price
or even some other stock prices from other companies.
I'll give you another example that explains this well.
Take Apple and Samsung, you know that in an iPhone
most of the material is coming from Samsung.
And therefore Apple is highly dependent on Samsung,
but at the same time, Samsung is highly dependent
on Apple, because simply, Apple is their best customer.
And therefore the stock prices of Apple and Samsung
might be highly correlated.
And that's exactly what you could add as a new dimension
if you want to predict the Apple stock price.
Because simply the Apple stock price is very likely
correlated to the Samsung stock price.
Then for Google I wouldn't know exactly
but you see the idea.
So there we go, we have our three dimensions.
First the number of observations,
or the batch size if you do some batch training.
Then the number of time steps, 60.
And then the number of indicators we have,
which in our case, will be one.
All right, so let's go back to Python.
There we go, and now let's input these three dimensions.
So the first one, as you remember, corresponds to
the batch size or in our case, the number of observations.
And we have in total, well, 1198 observations
because indexes start at zero.
Be careful with that.
But in case you want to apply this code to any data set,
any stock prices that you want to predict,
I'm going to get this number here by taking
X train dot shape of index zero.
That will get me exactly the number of lines of X train.
And then to get the number of time steps,
which is exactly the number of columns,
well, I will get X train dot shape, as you can guess, one.
Because X train dot shape one gives me
the number of columns and the number of columns
corresponds exactly to the number of time steps, 60.
All right, so let's do this for the first one
and then the last one will be very easy.
It is actually one, we have one indicator.
I will just input one, but don't forget to change it
if you have several indicators.
All right, so okay here, the first one,
as we said is the number of lines of X train
that is X train dot shape, square brackets zero.
Then the second one is the number of time steps,
that is the number of columns of X train,
which we can get with X underscore train dot shape
of index one, and then last argument,
the number of indicators, the number of predictors,
which is one, the open Google Stock Price.
Wonderful, so now we have our final structure,
the right structure that is expected by
the neural network, our future
recurrent neural network that we're gonna build.
It is a structure in three dimensions.
One dimension corresponding to the number of stock prices.
The second dimension corresponding to
the number of time steps.
And the third dimension corresponding to
the number of indicators.
All right, so let's have a look at this new structure.
I'm going to execute now, there we go.
We have our new X train, and if we have a look at it
as you can see, we can already see that it now
has three dimensions, the exact same ones
as I just mentioned.
And so if we have a look at it now,
if we click on it.
Well, you can visualize it this way, of course.
You cannot see it in a 3D box, but the way you
can see it is by changing the axis here.
So this is the first dimension, axis U and you
will see three axis, zero, one, or two
corresponding to the three dimensions
of this structure.
And for example in this one we see, well,
our previous X train with the 60 time steps
at each time, T.
At each time T, starting from 60.
The 60th financial date.
All right, so I hope everything is clear for you.
This is very important if you want to,
I don't know, add some other indicators
or do some more, more robust financial
engineering prediction here.
And so if this is clear, I have some excellent
news right now.
We are done with Part One, Data Preprocessing,
and we are ready to move on to Part Two,
Building the RNN, where we will build the
whole architecture of our LSTM.
And the double good news is that it's not
only gonna be an LSTM, it's gonna be a stacked LSTM
with several LSTM layers and we're gonna make it perfect.
We're gonna make it robust because we're gonna add
some dropout regularization to avoid overfitting
to make sure we have the most relevant,
the most useful recurrent neural network model.
Keep in mind this general truth.
All models are wrong, but some are useful.
I'm not saying that the one we'll make will be 100% right,
but we'll make it as useful as possible.
Until then, enjoy deep learning!