Hello and welcome back to the course of machine learning to do it talking about Bayes Theorem.
Now our main goal for this section is naive and base classifiers.
But at the same time we can proceed to them before talking about base there and that's why we're going
to have this lovely tutorial devoted specifically to this topic.
So let's kick it off and get straight into it.
Today we're talking about spanners.
I know it's a bit weird.
We're always talking about spanners we're supposed to talk about Bayes Theorem but I'm going to be illustrating
the Bayes theorem on an example.
And we're going to be using spanners just because it's one of the things I found on the Internet.
One of the first pictures that came to mind and also that way you'll always remember whenever somebody
says Bayes Theorem you'll remember spanner and you'll remember what we talked about today so it's a
good way to anchor this into your memory.
All right.
So let's say we're in a factory.
We're doing some analytics for a factory and there's two machines and one machine produces spanners
and the other machine produces spanners.
Now the machines work at different rates and they have somewhat different characteristics but overall
they're producing the same spanners.
The additional information here is that the spanners are actually marked or tagged.
So we know which machine they came from so the top ones came from machine one.
The bottom ones came from machine 2.
And then at the end of the day we've got a whole pile of these spanners and the workers go through them
.
And their goal is to pick out the defective spanners here we can see that there's a couple of defective
spanners hiding among the pile.
Now the question we're going to be asking today is what's the probability.
What's the probability of machine to producing a defective spanner.
So if you take just a random spanner and produced by machine two so as it comes out of the from the
conveyor belt you pick it up.
What is the probability that that spanner is defective.
And the way we'll get operability is through some information that will already be given to us at the
start.
So we'll have a look at that information in a second.
But the rule or the mathematical concept that I'll be using to get that probability is called the Bayes
Theorem.
Here's a mathematical representation of it.
I know it is a bit complicated right now it seems like what are all these signs like we know that is
probably probability but then be a vertical line what would all the all of them doing here what is this
relationship telling us.
Well don't worry about it for now.
We will walk through it.
Very slowly step by step and you'll get to know the base theorem very intimately.
All right.
So let's get started.
What is the information that is provided to us at the very soon.
Well we know that machine 1 produces 30 or inches per hour.
Admission to 24 inches per hour.
By the way trenches and spanners I found out just now that they're actually the same thing.
A spanner is outside of North America.
A wrench is inside of North America.
So there you go you learn an extra additional thing today if you didn't know that.
I learned an excellent additional thing.
So we're was going to call them wrenches from now machine.
One produces 30 wrenches machine to pieces 20 inches per hour.
OK great.
Also out of all of the produced parts we can see that 1 percent are defective.
So after checking the parts that then they are thousands and thousands of branches we can see that 1
percent of them are defective.
OK.
So we know that they also know that out of all of the defective parts we can see that 50 percent came
from machine 1 and 50 percent came from machine too.
So here you can see that if you take all the defective parts or only the defective parts and you calculate
how many of them came from machine one and how many of them came from machine to.
You'll see that half and half that half of them are for machine one and half from from Washington.
All right.
So this is just the defective parts.
And the question is what is the probability that that apart produced permission to is defective.
So that's the same question which we assess really what is the probability that if I come on two machine
two and take the part that just popped out of Mushin to what is the probability that that part is going
to be defective.
So how do we put all that information together to get the answer to this question.
That's what Bayes Theorem answers or helps us do.
So let's have a look at how we can rewrite this information in more mathematical terms.
So the first line what does it tell us it tells us that machine one inches per hour machine to 20 or
inches per hour so in total out of all the range produced there is 50 ranch's produced per hour.
And also that means that the probability of any given range that you pick up from the pile just aini
whether it's effective or non-defective if you pick up a wrench from the final pile the probability
that will come from machine 1 is 30 divided by 50 right.
So if we're producing sutee from machine 1 and 50 overall per hour that means likelihood of any given
range to be from machine 1 is about is exactly 30 divided by 50 or 0.6 or 60 percent Similarly the likelihood
of that range being from machine to is 20 or 30 or 40 percent.
All right.
Great.
So we're going to write those down and keep them there for now.
Now let's see what we can get out of the second line so we can see that out of all the produce parts
we can see that one person a defect.
Well it's very simple to write this in mathematical terms or can just say possibility of a part being
defective equals 1 percent.
So so even though that was a simple transition.
Actually these sentences are saying a bit different thing.
So the one on the left says we can see that 1 percent are defective so that means that we took we counted
the number of defective parts and we divided by the total amount.
And that means that 1 percent effective on the right is saying the probability of a single part to be
defective with 1 percent.
So that means if I pick up a random part from the pile the likelihood of it being defective is 1 percent
.
Right.
So that is what we're saying here.
And here's a very simple thing to write in methodical terms there it is defective or that there's a
defect equals 1 percent.
All right and now we're moving on to part three.
Out of all of the defects of parts we can see that 50 percent came from machine 1 and 50 percent came
from machine to.
So how do we write that in mathematical terms and this is just about.
So let's start with the machine one part.
50 percent came from machine one.
Meaning that if we take only the defective part so if it's given that we're only looking at the defective
parts then the likelihood that any part of that we pick out that that part came from machine 1 is 50
percent.
And the way through in mathematical terms is this way of machine one vertical line defect equals 50
So the right part of it here the vertical line in mathematical terms means given.
So here is the P of part pure of machine 1 is the likelihood operability of a part coming from machine
1 here.
It's same thing.
But given some condition.
So this is the likelihood of a part coming from machine one given the condition that that part is defective
.
So you know priori that that part is defective because you're picking it out of the defective pile.
So what is the probability of that part coming from machine 1.
Well it's 50 percent and that is the mathematical transcription of this sentence.
We can see that 50 percent came from machine 1.
50 percent of defective parts.
OK so now is the same thing for the machine machine too.
It's going to look exactly the same but here is going to be machine 2.
So probability of a part that the part that we just picked up the billy ray originally was created by
machine 2 is 50 percent.
Given that we're only peeking out from the defective pile.
Right.
Because if we're picking out of our all of them it's actually 40 percent.
It's 0.4.
But if we're picking it out only from the defective file it's 50 percent.
So you can really tell from here from these two expressions are four expressions that the likelihood
of a POD come from machine to is 40 percent meaning that it produces less.
It produces less wrenches whereas the likelihood of a defective part coming from machine to is 50 percent
so that if you take any part or any branch you pick it out from the defective pilot the likelihood that
it was originally produced by machine is 50 percent.
So you can tell right away that machine too seems to be producing disproportionately more defective
parts than machine one.
Right.
So it's only producing 40 percent of the output but it's accounting for 50 percent of the defective
parts.
And the question that we want to ask is actually a bit different.
Right.
So the question to ask is What is the probability that a part produced by machine 2 is defective.
So here it's kind of reverse here.
First we're saying we're taking a part from machine to right.
We're only looking at parts that are produced by machine to what is the probability of a random part
taking out a machine to be defective.
How do we write that in mathematical terms.
It's written this way so probability of a defective part given that it came from machine to.
If you look at just the probability of a car being defective it's 1 percent.
But here we are given a condition that is machine 2.
So the way to think of it you can think of it as parts of coming out of machine too and you just pick
up a random one was the probability of it being defective right.
Or you can think of it in terms of quantities.
The correct term here is frequentist interpretation so you can think of it in terms of the frequentist
interpretation.
And that means instead of just picking up one part and thinking about what.
So what is the likelihood of it being defective if we know that it came from Ashin to think of it as
there's a pile of wrenches that only came from machine to so you have a pile of you know a thousand
wrenches that came for machine to what is the number of wrenches that are going to be defect.
Right so what is a portion of branches that are going to be defective.
So those are two different ways of thinking about probabilities and or the Bayes Theorem but they pretty
much the same thing exactly the same thing just different ways of thinking about it.
So it's either What's the probability of this one part that just came out of machine to being defective
or what is the portion of all of these pars that came out of a machine to what is a portion of them
that's going to be defect.
So that's the question that we want to answer.
And given all this information.
All right so let's start solving this problem and will illustrate how the Bayes theorem will help us
convert this information to this information.
All right.
So first of all we won't need the ability for machine 1 and the ability for machine 1 given defective
so we're going to get rid of that out of our information just to clean things up.
Now let's just move everything slide everything over to make some space and not just write down the
Bayes Theorem which we had a brief look at before and based theorem for this particular problem will
look as follows.
So the probability of a defective part.
Given that it came from machine to probability of a parred being defective given that that part that
that wrench came from machine to equals and here we go this is the fun part.
So you will take the proverbial star from right to left it will take the probability of a part being
defective.
Overall we will need to multiply that by the probability that a part came from machine to.
Given that it was defective and we need to divide that by the probability of the parts coming from machine
to.
All right.
So for now this might seem a bit better already than we saw previously at least.
Now we we can read these terms right and we know how we got them here.
So we actually discussed each one of these terms and they're pretty straightforward even though even
though the mathematical representation might look a bit scary at the same time they're pretty straightforward
terms we know what we're talking about.
At the same time we don't really understand where this formula came from and more importantly an intuitive
level doesn't really make sense at this stage.
But Sergei let's for now plug in the numbers and then we'll proceed to the intuitive part of this format
.
So if we plug in the numbers we will get is 0.5.
So we'll just take numbers from the top or if we start from right to left again the probability of a
par being defective overall is 1 percent multiplied by probability of a part coming from machine 2.
Given that we're only looking at defective parts or given that that part is known to be defective it's
50 percent.
So there it is.
And we're dividing that by the probability of the part coming from machine to overall and that is 40
percent.
So it goes over like that and we get a 0.0 4:59 so one and a quarter percentage is a one point twenty
five percent is the probability that machine two will spit out a defective part.
Right.
If you come up to machine 2 and you pick up my part then the probability of that part being defective
is one point twenty five percent or the frequentist interpretation is if machine to produced 1000 parts
then according to Bayes Theorem.
And a half of them will be defective so you can really say 12 and a half ranch's will be defective so
let's say it produced 10000 parts then the base theorem tells us that 125 of those wrenches are going
to be defective.
So as you can see we convert all this information that we knew about the process and about the results
of the process into exactly what we want.
Now let's move on to the intuition the fun stuff right.
So with this one point twenty five and so let's move this to the top.
That's our base theorem.
And let's look at an example and you'll see that it's actually very very intuitive what we just did
it all makes total sense.
So let's look an example let's say we produced a thousand ranges all total.
So in total we have a thousand wrenches after the two machines were working for some time.
So we know that 400 of them came from machine to.
Right.
So we know that machine 2 produces homier inches per hour does it PRI's produces 20 or inches per hour
.
And machine one produces 30 or inches per hour as per hour.
Get information from the very start.
And that means that out of the thousand wrenches 40 percent will be it would have been produced by machine
2 that means 400 came from machine.
OK.
So that makes sense.
Then we also know that 1 percent have a defect.
We actually see this.
The workers who look at the wrenches at the end of the day this is also given to us.
They see that 1 percent of a defect and that means out of thousand one percent is tenths of 10 wrenches
have a defect.
Okay great.
And so what's the next step next step is that we know that 50 percent of those 10 came from Mission
2.
So we know that exactly five of those defective wrenches came from machine to that is also given to
us because those defect wrenches actually have labels on them and we can tell by the labels labels that
five of them came from machine to.
All right.
So the question is what is the percent effective parts from machine to.
Well it's very easy now right because we know that how many defective actually came from machine to
five.
And we know how many wrenches came from machine to 400.
Right so all we have to do is divide 5 by 400 and we'll get one point twenty five bytes we get the same
answer.
Not only do we get the same answer.
We actually did exactly the same process.
If you think through what we did here we perform exactly the same process.
We had a thousand wrenches right.
And then we turned that into 400 so we multiplied a thousand wrenches by 40 percent which is the probability
of a part time machine too.
So this is our denominator.
Right.
So instead of probing the machine to what we have what we just did this 400 is P of machine 2 times
1000 right so we have machine two times a thousand in the denominator.
I sort of just piece of machine in what we're doing here.
Right.
And then one percent have a defect and that means 10.
So where did this 10 come from.
That's 1 percent times a thousand.
So instead of pede defect at the top we actually have the defect times 1000 right now.
So just visualize that for a second.
So instead of permission to have permission two times a thousand defect times a thousand.
And then this 50 percent the possibility of them of them 50 percent came from machine to right equals
five.
That's the last line is actually us performing this operation here.
We're saying the probability of card coming from machine to given that it's defective is 50 percent
.
So basically to get to this what we did is we took this part.
So we took 50 percent.
Multiply that by the 10 which is actually.
So 50 percent multiplied by 1 percent.
Times 1000.
So here we've got extra time thousand and here we've got the machine to what we did is we actually put
in motion two times a thousand.
So we just aggregate an extra part over here times 1000 and Pardoe here 10000.
And then we still divided that final result that five that we got by the 400 that we got.
So the logical steps that we took are exactly the same as the Bayes Theorem.
The only difference is that we looked at a specific example of the thousand ranges.
So as you can see the Bayes Theorem is a very intuitive theorem so we're not even going to go into the
mathematics of how it's derived.
This is about understanding it intuitively so as long as you remember the mathematical representation
of the base theorem it actually makes sense what it is helping us calculate it.
And in the steps that it is implied for us to take to calculate the final result.
So there we go.
Hopefully that all makes sense and we only have one final question left.
We only have one obvious question here.
So the question is why do we have to go through all this complexity.
Why do we have to go through all this complexity.
Why don't we just count the number of defective wrenches from machine to and then count the number of
total wrenches that came from machine to and divide one by the other and get that same result.
Why can't we just do that.
Why don't we have that input of the total number of wrenches that came from machine to right away.
So that's a question if the items are labeled Why couldn't we just count the number of defective wrenches
that came from machine to and divide by the total number that came from Washington.
So if you think about it that's exactly what we are doing so we are dividing the total number of.
So this is the total number of branches that came from machine to at the top.
If you multiply by the thousand at the top we've got the number of machine to add or so defective the
ability of a part for mission to see if it's given as effective tumbril really would be perfect.
So at the top as you remember we've got that five so the top is actually the number of defective parts
that came from machine to at the end of the day we were actually doing that exact thing.
The question is what can we do it right away.
Why couldn't the workers just go and count the number of defective parts that came from machine to and
divided by the number of parts.
That's the overall number of parts that came from wishing to.
Why not save some time.
Well the answer to that question can can be multifold.
First of all it might be very time consuming like in this example Zabol might be time consuming to calculate
the number of wrenches that just came from machine to for instance we might know it might be like a
standard metric that the factory measures how many wrenches produced overall.
Right so we know that number 8000 or maybe 100000 but to count them permission to add might take them
some time to sit and can through those wrenches in there for just fossil fuel based.
The other thing here is that sometimes you might not have access to that information.
Sometimes the problem might be such that you just cannot perform that and you have some inputs like
we had in this case and that's it.
And it's not as simple as in this example and therefore you just don't have access to that information
.
So there are numerous reasons why you could be in a situation where you can't just go through the straightforward
easy obvious way and you need to base their base for them.
So therefore it's a useful thing to have in your science arsenal.
And moreover now that we know Bayes Theorem we can proceed to the naive base classifiers and to finish
off terrestrial I've got a quick exercise for you perform the same calculational similar calculations
for this value that we use to calculate what is the probability of a part being defective.
Given that it came from machine 1.
So there you go.
It's a handy Couhig says this to solidify this knowledge.
And I look for an external until then in Germany in learning