Hi everyone and welcome to the intuition lecture linear discriminant analysis or LDI.
Now for those of you who are coming from the previous section on principle component analysis or PCA
this may seem a bit similar.
But there is a difference between the two and we're getting it started by taking a look at overall what
LDA entails.
It's a pretty brief and straightforward intuition lecture but we'll get to the main takeaways between
PCa and LDI LDA is commonly used as a dimensionality reduction technique and we've heard that before
with PCa.
It's used in the pre-processing step for pattern classification and machine learning algorithms.
And its goal is to project a data set onto a lower dimensional space.
Sounds similar to PCA but LDA differs because in addition to finding the component axes with LDK we
are interested in the axes that maximize the separation between multiple classes.
And that is the main takeaway or the main point is where PCA we are with that distinction and working
with the principle component analysis with the axes the principal components within the data.
But where as we're looking in LDA we are looking for the separation of those classes within the data
and to break it down further.
The goal of LDA is to project a feature space onto a small subspace while maintaining the class discriminatory
information.
And we have both PCa and LDH as linear transformation techniques used for dimensionality reduction PCa
is a unsupervised algorithm but LVH is supervised because of the relation to the dependent variable.
And we can see here from this visualization the main operations and main differences between PCa and
L.D. at PCA.
Again we're looking in that the subspace and the dimension reduction technique of the data to examine
how the principle KOHONA axes are in relation.
Whereas in LDI we're looking for that class separation and I think this visualization kind of makes
it the most clear between the two.
If you want some additional information you can always take a look at the following link.
But here we have the PCA and LDA and the main operations related to each again.
LDI supervised because of the relation to the dependent variable.
And I think when you start working through this in the upcoming lecture and the hands on part it's going
to make more sense but that's the main takeaway to focus on LDA.
And you can accomplish this by five main steps.
Similar again to PCA.
The five main steps for LDI include the following.
The computation of the D dimensional mean vectors the computation of the scatter matrices you have to
also compute the eigenvectors sort the eigenvectors by decreasing eigenvalues and use the D times K
eigenvector matrix to transform the samples onto the new subspace overall.
Very similar to PCA.
Two different types of dimensional reduction techniques one being unsupervised and one being supervised.
But the main distinction with LDA to take away is that we're looking for that class separation within
the data.
Overall if you're coming from PCA this should seem familiar for the majority of operations if you're
new to this I advise you to go take a look at PCA as well.
But when you are starting work through the next comp coming park it should make more sense.
But just keep in mind that the main takeaway for LDA is that class separation and it is a supervised
learning technique.
If you have any questions as always please feel free to share them and enjoy machine learning.