Hello and welcome back to the course of machine learning.
Today we're talking about random forests.
Let's have a look inside.
So first thing we're going to learn is a new concept ensemble learning.
What is ensemble learning and learning is when you take multiple machine learning algorithms and put
them together to create one bigger machine learning algorithms so that machine learning algorithm the
final one is actually using leveraging many different other machine learning algorithms and they can
be the same machine learning algorithm as we will see today.
We're going to be looking at the random forest method which combines a lot of decision tree method so
instead of running a decision tree method which we talked about earlier.
So running at once we're going to run it multiple times and that will give us a run of four.
So let's have a look at the step by step process to understand how all of this happens.
So step one is you pick a random K data points from the training set.
Then you build a decision tree associated to those data points.
So instead of building a decision tree based on everything you have in your daughter said you build
a decision tree just based on some of the data points that you have.
So kind of like a subset of ALL your daughter said Next you choose the number of trees you want to build
.
And you repeat steps 1 and 2 and then once you have all those trees and you have a new data point so
when you want to check where a new Torben falls how is classified for a new data point you make each
one of your entry trees predict the category of which the data point belongs to.
And then you assign the new data points to the category that wins the majority vote.
So that's how a random forest works.
So basically you start off with one tree and then you build another tree another tree another tree and
each one of those trees is being built on a randomly selected subset from your daughter.
And even though each one of those trees might not be ideal overall on average they can perform very
well and that's a major advantage of this algorithm.
It's kind of leveraging the power of the crowd so to speak and sort of just relying on one tree.
It's checking what all the trees are going to say and then just taking the majority vote and deciding
the classification based on that.
And that power of numbers can help get rid of certain errors and certain uncertainties in your algorithm
and make it more precise.
And in fact it's such a good solution that when Microsoft were developing Kinect on this device that
allows you to play games on your television that little device over there that attaches to X-Box and
then you can play games without any controller so here that device is using an infrared grid to understand
where the hands arms head and other parts of the body of these people are located and how they're moving
and is using machine learning to understand how the body parts are moving and where exactly they're
located in space.
So when Microsoft was developing Kinect they decided to go with the random forest algorithm over all
of the other machine learning algorithms that were available to them and use the rainforest to develop
this sophisticated piece of hardware or slash software.
And actually they have a interesting article about it so I'm just going to show it to you now if you
can find on the Internet.
So it's a burst of dot com.
This is from there.
And you can definitely find it there.
It's called real time human poser cognition parts from single depth images.
And here it explains exactly so you can actually see the random forest in action so you can see that
this is similar to what we were talking about before in the classification trees.
But here is actually using random for us to understand where body parts are and then based on that the
device finds what it needs to do in that computer game.
So that's how it works.
And so if I just search for the word forest you'll see that decision for his decision for his decision
for us and actually explain that they were able to achieve faster speeds faster processing with the
decision for us and therefore that you know reduce the cost of the hardware that they're required for
this tool.
Interesting article that I chickened out if you want to learn a bit more about a real life practical
application of a decision forest or a random forest and that's it for today's tutorial I hope you enjoyed
learning a bit about an ensemble type of machine learning algorithm definitely the practical side is
going to be quite interesting as well.
And I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then in Germany in learning