Hello and welcome to this art tutorial.
So in the previous tutorial we implemented Thompson something from scratch and now time for the moment
we've all been waiting for.
Let's see if Tompson sampling can beat UCB.
So in fact we are ready to execute this code section here and find out about the final results.
So let's remember the random selection gave us a total reward of 1200.
On average the UCB algorithm gave us a total reward of two thousand one hundred and seventy eight.
And now let's see if Tompson sampling can beat that.
Now let's select everything from here to the top because you know we have an important data set.
So we will execute everything on once to immediately get this final result that we're so excited to
find out about.
So ready.
I'm going to press command and to execute and let's see who is the big winner.
Here we go.
And it turns out to be Thompson said I'm playing because we got a total reward of two thousand six hundred
and two.
So we have some random factors so let's not scream victory yet.
We are going to execute that again to see the new we Wardwell we get 2600 almost.
We can do that again.
And basically it's averaging around two thousand six hundred.
So yes definitely.
It's being the upper confidence bound algorithm.
And by the way remember that with the UCB algorithm we almost doubled the total reward of the random
selection algorithm.
But now with Thompson sampling we're not only building the UCB algorithm but also we are doing better
than doubling the random selection total we want because we get this 2600 total reward on average which
is more than the double That one thousand two hundred.
That's what it's all worth.
The random selection algorithm on average so great definitely Thompson something is a big winner.
And now we have a last thing to check.
You know remember we need to check that Tompson something also gives us the best ad that has the highest
conversion rates you know on which the users of the social network we click the most.
And so we need to make sure that it's also the adversion number five which was the adversion found by
the UCB algorithm and to check that out very efficiently we can select this code section here and execute
to look at the histogram.
And here we go.
We also get that the version that was most collected is adversion number five.
And by the way Nusi we had some higher bars here if I remember correctly.
But here with Tompson sampling we can clearly see that this was this adversion number five here that
was most selected.
You know this bar here corresponding to the adversion number five is clearly dominating the other boys
and that's because Tomsen something quickly figured out which ad is the best you select.
That is it quickly figured out which ad has the best click through rates.
And so now we can congratulate ourselves because we clearly solved very efficiently this click through
rate optimization problem.
And the best algorithm that we found for this is Thompson sampling.
All right so congratulations for having implemented these two algorithms UCB and Tompson sampling.
That's the end of the section and that's also the end of this part reinforcement learning.
So I look forward to seeing you in the next part.
Natural Language Processing.
Until then in Germany learning