Hello and welcome to this art tutorial.
So in the previous tutorial we plotted our den program to find the optimal number of clusters and the
result was five clusters.
So now this new step since we have this optimal number of clusters we are going to fit the hierarchical
clustering algorithm to our data X with obviously five clusters.
OK so the first thing that we need to do is to create a new object of the age class class.
And actually this is something that we already did because if we go back to Step 2 here when we wrote
then program equals h Clast then the distance matrix and the word method we actually created enough
not ject of the H class class and we're going to do the exact same thing right now we're going to create
the exact same object from the class class.
So I'm going to copy this line of code pasted here in step three.
And I'm just going to change the name of the object just to make things nice and clear.
So let's replace here DENTRO from by age C..
And now we have the same object as before only with a different name.
And this actually makes sense because by building a general grum we actually do all the steps of hierarchical
clustering and among all these steps there is this step in which the algorithm found five clusters.
So that means that this object contains the information.
When we have five clusters and so now let's use this object to build our vector of clusters that is
the vector that will tell us which cluster each customer belongs to and to build this vector we're going
to use one of the method of the H class class which is the cat tree method.
So we're going to color vector of clusters y underscore H C equals.
Then we use the cat tree method of the H class class.
So let's type cat tree and then press 1 and then we see that this method requires three arguments.
The first argument is tree.
And of course it's our danger Graham that we just renamed H.C..
Then the second argument is k the number of cluster.
So here we can put five and we will leave the default value for the third parameter.
OK.
Now it's interesting to take a step back because actually this method is called Cat tree which is a
very well-chosen name because indeed we are cutting the tree to take the part of the tree that contains
our five clusters so that makes pretty much sense.
And now since we are actually done with fitting Hollioake who are clustering to our mothers that let's
electroscope section here and execute to find r y h c vector of clusters that appears right here and
now if we type in the console y see here and press ENTER we have all the clusters that the hierarchical
clustering algorithm assigned to each customer.
So for example customer number one belongs to cluster one customer number two belongs to Kuster to Customer
Number 1 0 6 belongs to cluster's 3.
And our last customer belongs to cluster 4.
Okay so congratulations.
We found the right number of clusters and we fitted correctly the hierarchical clustering to a small
dataset and now time for fun in the next tutorial we will be visualizing a hierarchical clustering results
.