Hello and welcome to this art tutorial.
So in the previous tutorial we got the exciting result of the total reward being two thousand one hundred
and seventy eight and therefore almost doubling the Total War we get with the random selection algorithm
which was around 1200.
So that was the first exciting result and we also got another exciting result which was you know the
best ad to show to the user given by this selected vector by looking at the last round here containing
only fives that showed us that the ad was the highest conversion rate is the version number five of
the ad.
So two exciting results.
And now to finish this section even better we will have a look at the histogram to have a quick look
at the overall strategy you know to see the number of times each ad was selected and how the selections
of at number five dominate the selections of the other ads.
So that's going to be very quick and easy because we simply need to use hest which is right here center.
And now as input we simply need to get the variable that contains the values you want to plot on this
histogram.
And that's of course the ads selected vector because you know this vector tells us which ad was selected
at each round.
And so this histogram method here will look at the number of times each add was selected in this selected
vector and that will plot the histogram.
So basically we're done and now just to make it better we can add a color.
So we type call equals blue in quotes.
If of course we want the blue color and then add a title by adding this main equals and then in quotes
we add a title.
And so let's say histogram.
Well adds selections.
Here we go and we can also add a label to the x axis.
So saying we use quotes we are here.
Right because you know basically what we all have on the x axis are going to be the labels of the ads.
So that's why I'm adding here ads.
And of course let's add a y label quotes and let's say a number of times each ad was selected great.
And basically we're done.
So now let's have a look.
Will select this code section here and press command control plus enter to execute.
And here is the histogram.
And wow we can clearly see that's the at number five is the ad that was most selected by the users.
That is the other has a higher conversion rate and therefore no doubt that's the ad we need to show
to our users for the marketing campaigns of this chip brand new luxury SUV.
So no doubt the fifth ad wonderful.
We completed our job as a machine learning scientist.
And so congratulations.
We implemented a great algorithm.
So now what we'll do is implement another algorithm to see if we can do better.
And this other algorithm will be Thompson something algorithm.
So let's see if Tompson something can beat UCB and we'll find out in the next section.
Until then in German learning