Okay, my friends.
So now we're about to have a very exciting tutorial because we're about to watch the demo.
You know, the demo of our A.I. being built first and trained and finally making our single predictions.
So this is where we left off in the previous tutorial.
Basically, all the implementation is done.
And now I'm going to guide you through how to run this on Jubran Notebook.
And therefore, the first thing I'll do will be to download and install everything we need to have Duplin
notebook.
If you already installed that you know, which contains Juber notebook.
And if you already have you bring a book on your machine, then feel free to skip the five first minutes
of this tutorial and start directly from minute five.
Okay.
This is when we will start using Juber in the book.
And for the rest of you, well, follow me.
I will guide you through the installation of an icon.
And therefore in notebook.
So let's open a new search tab on your favorite browser.
And in a search bar and its type and conduct.
There we go.
So anakonda then we're gonna go to the first link.
And I kinda has become so popular now.
And we're going to go to.
Well, get started.
And install an icon, that individual edition.
Then you can click download here.
And then you're going to choose the anakonda and steller for your system, whether you have a Windows
or Mac OS or Linux Imon macros.
So I'm gonna go with this and you're gonna take the graphic installer and not the command line and stutter.
All right.
Graphic installer.
And you're gonna take the Python three point seven version, not the Python two point seven.
Right.
So only this row here.
So choose your system.
Click the file and this will download Anakonda, you know, the installer.
And in a few seconds you'll get, you know, the installer on your machine, probably in your download
folder, which is done for me.
Good.
So let's just get rid of this download.
And now let's go to my machine.
There we go.
This is my download folder on which the installer was downloaded.
So make sure I find it and then double click it.
And this will launch the installation of Anakonda.
Here you can just click.
Continue.
Just click.
Agree and continue.
Can read that if you want.
And then install.
Then this will install.
And I condemn.
This will just take a few seconds.
Not more than one minute and you know.
Okay.
Less than a minute.
There we go.
Good.
So right now Anaconda's installing and let me tell you a few words about Anakonda.
So this is basically a platform that contains several ideas on which you can code in Python and even.
Ah, because you will see that it contains now or is to you.
But the Python idea is that it contains include in a book and also Spider Spider is another great idea
to code and Python.
But here we're gonna go with Jubera notebook because we have been used to, you know, the IP only format,
which was the format we used on Google CoLab.
But this time since we have a huge dataset which we can't import on Google.
Kulab Well, we're going to run this with Dupere notebook.
All right.
So let's see where we are.
So still installing well, you know, running the package scripts, but you will have anakonda on your
machine with no issue.
All right.
So here this is just given deed access to your downloads folder.
Of course, you click.
Okay.
And then it should progress now.
All right.
Let's see.
And dairy perfect.
So now we have an icon that you can click continue to and insulation.
Yes, close.
And then you can either choose to keep the star or remove it as you want.
I'll just keep it.
All right, good.
Now we have an icon then.
It's not over.
We still need to install a few things.
And these things are unfortunately the Tensor Flow Library and the Keris library, because I remind
that the beauty of Google CoLab.
And the reason why I wanted to code everything on Google Kulab was that we didn't have anything to install
because all the libraries and packages are already preinstalled except for the rare ones.
But here on Jubera notebook or Spider or any anakonda I.D..
Well, we have to install manually the packages, and that's exactly what I'm about to show you.
So for Mac and Linux users, please open your terminal Linux users, you'll find it very easily.
And Mac users, well, you can just press command plus space and then in the spotlight search can type
terminal.
And this will open your terminal.
And for Windows users, no reason.
I'm not forgetting you.
Windows users, please go.
You know, at the lower left corner of your monitor, please click that window button and then find
an icon that in your list of programs and in an icon tab, you will find command prompt.
Then please click it.
And this will be the equivalent of the terminal on which you can run commands to install packages from
the web.
All right.
So now we should all be on the same page.
No Windows users, Mac users or Linux users.
And we're about to install tend to flow and carers.
And you will see that it will be still super quick and easy because the simple commands that we have
to enter here in order to install tensor flow and carers are the following.
So we have to enter them separately.
US always Tenzer flow.
We simply need to enter Pip, then install and then ten sir flow.
All right.
And then we just need to press enter.
And this will download Tenzer flow from the web and install it on your anakonda environment.
All right.
So right now, as you can see, it is downloading it and installing it.
So sorry about all this.
This is totally fine, right?
See, installing connected packages, including, indeed, to flow.
So it is not only installing tens of low, but also some what we call dependencies which work with denser
flow.
But please don't worry about all this.
This will just install Tenzer flow, which is exactly what we need.
Okay.
Good.
So installation done, as we can see.
Successfully installed all these dependencies, including Tenzer flow.
And now to install carers.
Well, we're gonna do the same.
We're gonna enter Pip and then install.
And then carrots.
And then press enter.
And this will install carers on your machine.
There we go.
Successfully installed carers.
And that's the version that we just installed.
You might get a different version if you take this course way after I recorded it.
Good.
Done with the terminal.
No worries.
We won't have to deal with it anymore.
I hope it wasn't too traumatising for, you know, those of you who used it for the first time.
I know it can be a bit surprising at first, but indeed, this is the classic way of installing packages
when you're not working on Google colour.
So then you can quit the terminal and then there we go.
Now we're ready to finally open anakonda and mostly open champion notebook.
So we're gonna find Anakonda in either, you know, the list of applications from Mac users or in your
list of programs for Windows users.
And same for Linux users.
So on Mac here is an icon there.
So let's just double click it.
And this will open it.
I can just go back to my desktop here because Anaconda is now opening.
And in a second, we should see that beautiful platform.
Very user friendly, containing all the different ideas on which you can code with Python.
All right.
Loading applications.
And in a second.
There we go.
Welcome to Anakonda.
Good.
So, as I told you, you have several ideas.
You have this Oresteia for all, but you have several of them for Python, including Jubera in the book.
And Spider.
And as we said, we're going to run our implementation entrepreneur book.
So here we are going to click launch.
All right.
And this will launch jibbering a book.
And this will automatically open it on a new tab on your browser.
You'll see.
We should see pop up in a second.
There we go.
So welcome to Jubera notebook.
So this is your machine.
You will recognize the folders of your machine.
And of course, now you're gonna go to the folder that contains, you know, the data set.
Know, which you downloaded at the beginning of this practical activity.
So remember, mine is on my desktop.
And here is the folder, you know, Section 40, convolutional neural networks.
So within a click it.
And inside.
Well, as you notice, I only kept the data set.
I removed the two previous implementations which were in that folder.
Because now what I want to do is actually take or exact implementation.
We coded during this practical activity.
I'm going to download it by clicking fell here and then download that IPY and B, make sure that the
IP won't be because that's the format used for Jubera and Notebook.
All right, then I'm gonna close this.
And now we're gonna go to where this was downloaded, meaning in the download folder.
We're gonna put that into this folder, you know, containing the data set right here.
So you have to put it in the exact same folder.
That's important because you have to run this file on Dupere in the book within the same directory folder
that contains the dataset.
That's why it's important to do it.
So this is the exact implementation we coded together during the practical activity.
And now we're gonna check that it works by running each and every single one of the cells.
So let's do this.
Let's go back to Jupiter notebook, which is right here.
Okay, good.
And now, indeed, we have.
Well, our implementation.
Good.
So let's open it by just clicking it.
And welcome to our implementation of the convolutional neural network.
And now now is really the show time, because the only thing we'll have to do will be to click this
run button, cell after cell, even the text cell.
You know, we'll just start from the beginning and see what happens.
Okay.
So I already.
Let me just, you know, clear all the output, which were the output we got in Google.
Kulab So to do this, we can click kernel here and then restart and clear output.
Right.
We won't get these output.
We will just really start from scratch.
Okay.
Good.
So now let's do this.
Three, two, one.
Go, run.
OK.
That doesn't run anything.
Because this is a tech cell run again.
And now it is starting.
We're gonna click our first run for the first cell and this will import tensor flow.
This door means that it is running right now.
You know, the cell is running and when it is done running, we will see the first number one, meaning
that the cell is successfully run.
OK.
There we go.
Using transfer back in.
That's the output of this cell.
And in order for this to work this way, we'll make sure to have run like me, the PIP install commands
of tensor flow and cast.
All right, good.
Now, this sector version is still going to be you know, it's sensible to 2.0 2.0.
And then let's just run the rest of the sales.
There we go.
So now we're entering part one, preprocessing the training set and now running the cell.
We will get in the output that indeed we imported and preprocessed, you know, with data augmentation,
8000 images belonging to two classes, dogs and cats.
Okay, then let's click run for the next cell repricing the test set.
And now running this cell, we'll get indeed this time 2000 images belonging to two classes.
And of course, no image augmentation was applied, only feature scaling was applied.
All right.
And now entering part two, building the CNN.
There we go.
First, we initializes CNN as a sequence of layers.
Then we start the first step, step one convolution where we add a convolutional layer, then puling.
Let me just scroll down a bit, actually.
Right.
Then puling.
So here we apply.
Max, pulling through this first convolutional layer.
Good.
Done.
Then we add a second convolutional layer.
And at the same time, we play Max pulling done.
Then we proceed to step three where we flatten the result of all these convolutions and pooling into
a one dimensional single vector which will become in this new step for food connection.
The input of a fully connected neural network which will contain only one fully connected layer with
this cell that we're about to run.
Done.
And now let me scroll down a bit again.
Right.
Let's scroll down like that, OK?
And now in the final step of the construction process of our CNN, we will connect all these to the
final output layer, which will contain the final prediction.
Right.
Let's run this cell.
And there we go.
Now we're done building the CNN.
Everything looks good so far.
We now have a brain with some eyes that are able to see images.
You know, just like we humans do with our eyes.
And now now that we have this brain and these eyes will time to make them smart by training the CNN
to recognize cats and dogs in images.
So there we go.
We enter part three now.
First compiling the CNN with an Adam optimizer, which will performs to gas a gradient descent.
The best way than a binary cross entropy lost function because we're doing binary classification.
And an accuracy metrics.
There we go.
Now our CNN is compiled and now now, my friends, it's time for the training.
Are you ready?
This following cell will run the training for 25 books and at the same time, we will get the accuracy
on the test set.
So this will be very exciting because we will see the accuracy on both the training set and it's set
getting increased and increased over time.
Are you ready?
I'm not going to make us wait longer.
There we go.
Now the training is starting.
There we go with the first epic, one of 25.
And here you see the loss, the accuracy, you know, progressing, increasing.
So basically, the 250 here corresponds to the fact that, you know, the batch size is 32.
And we have until 8000 images so that, you know, 32 times 250 equals eight thousand.
So basically, you know, we have 32 images in the batch and we have 250 steps in each book to, you
know, reach the total amount of eight thousand images.
All right.
So first it Bogdan, let's see what we got.
We got an accuracy of 61 percent on the training set.
Be careful.
And on the set, we got an accuracy of sixty seven point seventy five percent, which is pretty good.
All right.
And now the other epics are running.
But as you can see, it's going to take some time.
So I'm just gonna do it.
Fast forward here with some exciting music so that we can observe and mostly admire the result and the
progression of, you know, getting higher and higher accuracies in accelerated mode.
All right.
Are you ready?
Three, two, one.
Action.
All right.
Here I am back in the game.
I'm super excited to see the final result here of the 25th epic.
There we go.
We end up with a final accuracy on the training set of eighty nine percent and a final accuracy on the
test set of 80 percent, which is great.
And I remind that if we hadn't done that image augmentation pricing, you know, in part one, well,
we would have ended up you know, you can try with an accuracy here of the training set around 98 or
even ninety nine percent, which clearly indicates overfitting and a lower accuracy here on the test
set.
Around 70 percent.
So that's why I insist image augmentation is absolutely fundamental.
OK.
So the training is done.
There you go.
You had your first advanced training.
Congratulations again.
And now.
Well, let's test our model in production by, you know, making that single prediction of a single
image.
All right.
So just before we run this, let's just make sure we know whether we're predicting.
So we're going to go back to our folder, which is right here.
We're going to go into our data set.
And remember, those single images are in this single prediction for there.
And we're going to start with this one.
Caradog one which concerns, of course, Doug.
And now we're going to check that our CNN can predict that indeed there is a duck inside this image.
You ready?
Let's do this.
Where is it?
It's right here.
All right.
So play.
Now we're gonna play this cell to, you know, get a prediction.
Make sure to have cat or dog one here, which corresponds to the image we just saw.
And now let's play this cell.
And now we're about to get the final prediction printed in the console.
And we're certainly hoping to see Doug in the output.
Are you ready?
Three, two, one, run.
And perfect.
Our CNN predicted that there was a dog inside the image.
Okay, good.
First test bass successfully.
Now let's see for it.
The other image.
This one, which contains, of course, a cat.
So let's deploy our model on this single image and check that indeed, our CNN returns a cat.
So to do this, we just need to replace this image name here by cat or dog, too.
Then we can just play this cell again by just clicking wrong again.
And now we're going to print this again to print a new prediction of this other image.
So let's do this and let's hope that indeed we get.
Cut in the output of the console.
Perfect.
So our CNN got all the answers correct.
But what if I make it even more challenging, you know, because maybe I was sneaky and maybe I chose
images in a test set that I checked was working well with our CNN.
You know, that our CNN was able to predict correctly so to make it more challenging.
My idea is to open a new tab here.
Then the search bar.
I would like to generate random number and we're gonna generate a random number using this, you know,
the classic tool by Google.
And we're going to generate a random number from our test set, you know, which contains the new images
on which the mole wasn't trained.
And we're gonna take randomly an image from this test set and tested as a final test, you know, for
CNN.
So let's see the images of the dogs in the test set go from 4000 one to 4000.
Well, 5000.
And the cats go from the same four thousand one up to once again, 5000.
Okay, so let's start with dog first.
Let's generate a random number, you know, between 4000 and 5000.
And let's generate this.
And we get four, six, eight, nine.
OK.
So let's get that image.
Four, six, eight, nine.
Which is a bit below.
Okay.
Right here.
Four, six, eight, nine.
All right.
So that's actually gonna be quite challenging.
Our CNN might not recognize that it is a dog.
Will it see?
So I'm going to take that image.
I just copied it and into this single prediction folder, I'm pacing it and I'm going to rename this.
You know, I'm going to rename this Caradog three.
All right.
That will be our third image.
And now let's generate a new number for the cat.
All right.
Four thousand five hundred and thirty eight.
And so in the test set, let's go into the cat folder and at stake.
Sorry, what is it again?
Four thousand five hundred thirty eight.
Yes.
Four thousand five hundred and thirty eight.
Which is right here.
All right.
Wow.
It's gonna be challenging again.
Let's see.
We only see a cat head here, so let's see.
Okay.
Well, I didn't expect such a hard challenge, but let's see how our CNN is going to do anyway.
So I just copied it and into this single prediction for the let's based it.
Let's, you know, copy the name of this and then paste that here to replace that by Caradog four.
All right.
So let's deploy our model on this single image first and let's hope that, you know, it predicts this
time a dog.
So here it is, Caradog three.
I'm scared.
And let's play run and then print prediction.
Doug.
Woo hoo!
Great.
I was really scared because, you know, is not that obvious for a machine that the dog in the image
is a dog.
But that's really good.
OK.
And now that special cat and this red gift wrapping thing.
Caradog for let us hope that our recognizes that it is a cat.
You know, it's obvious for us humans, but here we only see a head actually, you know, with the features
of a cat.
So yeah, let's hope that it will work.
So Caradog four.
And now let's play the cell.
I'm scared again and.
Excellent.
So 100 percent correct answers from our CNN.
So that's awesome.
I'm really happy that it worked 100 percent.
That's because, you know, we have, after all, an accuracy of 80 percent on the test set, which
means that indeed eight predictions will be correct out of ten.
So, yes, even if the images are quite challenging, you know, with not some obvious dogs or cats.
Well, our model can do pretty well.
So congratulations.
You just built a pretty advanced artificial wool network.
You know, the convolutional neural network is quite technically advanced.
So congratulations.
And not only you built it, but mostly you built it successfully.
It is now a really good cat or dog predictor.
And feel free to, you know, play the same game by generating a random number and test some other single
images you might be surprised by.
You know, the predictive power of the model you just built.
All right.
So we're making great progress here.
Now we're done with deep learning part.
So we're going to move on to the next part, which is about dimensionality reduction and which is super
important for you and your career, because, you know, you're going to work with huge datasets, with
many, many features.
So you need to have the right tools in order to reduce the dimensionality of your dataset without losing,
of course, the information.
You know, the information that allows to learn some correlations between the features and the dependent
variable.
So that's a super important chapter.
I look forward to seeing you in this next part.
And until then, enjoy machine learning.