Hello and welcome to this art Tauriel soon to be used to toil report the dataset which contains 1000
reviews of a restaurant and for each of the review we have information whether the review is positive
or negative.
So one when the review is positive and zero when the reviews negative and we are trying to build a machine
or any model that we'll be able to classify each new review and tell if this new review is positive
or negative.
So basically what we're led to do is something we already did that is classification in part 3.
But this time we are working on text and therefore we need to figure out a way to create a model where
we can have some independent variables to train a machine and classification model to learn some correlations
between the independent variables and the dependent variable which is of course the liked column.
So now the goal is simply to create some independent variables and what could be those independent variables.
Well the idea in natural language processing in the back of our model is to create a model which will
basically be a huge table a table with a rose or nothing else in the reviews.
So this table will have 1000 rows because we have 1000 reviews one row for each review and the columns
will simply be all the words that we can find in the reviews.
You know we take the 1000 reviews we look at all the words and those 1000 reviews.
And we're going to create one column for each word and then each cell in the table will correspond to
one row.
There is one review and one column that is one word in all these words and these 1000 views.
And then this there is going to be the number of times the word appears in the review.
So for example here is the first word wow.
Well there's going to be a column for this while we're here.
And so for the first line that corresponds to the first review.
Well this well column will get a one because the word WOW appears once in the first review but then
for all the other reviews that is all the other rows we don't see any Wow here so all the cells in this
first column for the other rows will get a zero.
And that's what will be our model in the end.
It's going to be this huge table with 1000 rows that are going to be the reviews and a lot of columns
that are going to be all the worse that we can find in this 1000 reviews here.
So now you might start to figure out why we would need to clean the reviews it's because since we're
going to take all the worst in these reviews here.
Well we're going to get a lot of columns because we create one column for each word but we don't want
to get too many columns because the more we get some Collins and the harder it will be for our machine
or any model to run properly to execute efficiently.
Not only our machine model will have more trouble to execute properly but also it will have more trouble
understanding the correlations between the presence of the words and the reviews and the information
whether the review is positive or negative because of course if we keep all the words in these reviews
Well we will get some irrelevant words some words that will not help the machine learning algorithm
to predict if is positive or negative because in other words that we can find in the reviews here.
Well some words give a much better hint in telling if the review is positive or negative.
Let me give you a simple example.
We have this Loved word here in this review.
This is the word that basically tells us that the reason was positive because there is this love word.
But then if we look at this this word or even place where these two words don't give the machine learning
algorithm a hint whether the reviews positive or negative.
It's of course this word loved by which the machine learning algorithm will understand some correlations
between this love word and the fact that the review is positive.
So that's the whole reason why right now we are going to clean the text.
It's not only to reduce the big table we're going to get to in the end because we want our algorithm
to run properly and not be saturated.
And the other reason is that we want to get the most relevant words to find the best correlations between
the presence of the words and the outcome whether the review is positive or negative.
All right so now we get the point.
So let's start cleaning the reviews and an important thing to understand is that's what we'll do here
to clean the reviews.
Well it's the same technique to clean any other kind of text.
Well I will give you the main tools you will be able to use these tools to clean any text you're working
with.
And of course if your text is a little more complicated like for example NHT pages that contains HDMI
tags.
Well you would need to add a little more tools but you would still use the tools that we are about to
use.
And the good news is that if you want to use more tools to clean more sophisticated text Well you just
need to ask me some questions.
Nick you and I and now help you at these tools to your problem and your text.
But what we'll do here you will definitely do it to perform natural language processing your text files
for your problems.
All right so let's do it let's clean the text.
So that's the next step in natural language processing.
We will clean all the text and then we will create our bag of words model which is this huge table which
is actually called a sparse matrix because we'll get a lot of zeroes in the sparse matrix and then that
means that we'll get a model where we have some independent variables and one dependent variable and
that's when we'll be able to use our machinery intensification morals that were built in part three
to predict the class of a new review that the model will not have seen yet.
So let's do it.
Let's start with the first step of cleaning the text.
And this first step is going to be about initializing a corpus because you know we will not clean the
reviews directly in the data set.
We will instead create a corpus which will contain all the reviews and that will be in this corpus that
will clean all the reviews.
So let's start by creating this corpus.
And in order to create this Corvis we need to import a package and you might need to install it if it's
the first time you're doing natural language processing.
So I'm going to type here the command to install this package this package is called the T.M. package.
It's a very famous package in our natural language processing.
So let's install this package by typing install packages.
Here it is.
And so the name of the package has to be input in quotes which is the tea package.
All right.
So if I go to my packages I will find the test package here it is.
So I already have it installed so I don't need to install it again.
So I will put that in comment.
Here we go.
And of course if you don't have the team package here you will need to install it by executing this
line and everything will run properly.
All right.
So of course after we install the package we need to import the package.
Well mine is already imported but we need to automate all this so as usual we are going to take the
library command and in parenthesis we input the name of the package.
So T.M. again not in quotes.
All right.
And now we are ready to build the corpus.
And so how are we going to call our corpus.
We're going to call it corpus.
All right corpus equals and then we're going to use the corpus function spelled this way the corpus
with capital V in capital C and then in parenthesis we need to input vector source this way.
And again new parenthesis and it's in parenthesis that we input the column that contains the text that
we want to clean in this corpus.
So this column is of course the review column of our dataset.
So here we will put this column which can be taken the following way by typing data set dollar sign.
And then as you can see we have the two variables here that we can pick and the one we want to pick
is review.
All right.
And that takes all the review column of our dataset and that's exactly what we want.
Because this column contains the text and we want to clean the text in the corpus.
All right so that's the first step of cleaning the text.
So let's attack this and press command and control press enter to execute and create the corpus.
Here we go.
As you can see it already says that it's a large corpus and we can even see here that our corpus takes
3.7 megabytes of space.
We will simplify this corpus by cleaning Step-By-Step all the reviews.
And that's what we'll do in the next tutorials until then and machine learning