Hello and welcome to this art Tauriel.
So in the previous two tours we imported the dataset and we started with the big first step of natural
language processing which is about cleaning the text.
We are working with.
So this first step consisted of creating a corpus that basically is a new data set.
Design only containing the reviews the text of the reviews.
And basically this is in this corpus that we going to clean all the 1000 reviews and we are going to
clean them Step-By-Step.
And in this tutorial we're going to do the first cleaning step.
All right.
So let's do it this first cleaning step will consist of putting all the reviews in lowercase s and what
is the purpose of doing that.
Well we are doing this or that in the final sparse matrix containing all the words of our 1000 reviews.
We don't get why the same word you know with one word starting with a capital letter and the same word
but not starting with a capital letter.
And of course we only want to have one version of the same word and therefore will keep the one with
lowercase.
So that's why right now in this first step of the clearing process we will put all the words of our
1000 reviews in lower cases.
So let's do it.
To do this we are going to update the corpus this way than equals because we are updating it.
That is it will contain new reviews which are going to be the same reviews but with lower cases.
And to put all the words of the reviews in this corpus we will use the T and underscore that function
that will do the job for us.
So functions that we need to add some parenthesis and then we need to add two parameters the first parameter
is actually the corpus itself.
But you know the old version of the Corbett's that is the corpus that we have here which contains the
original versions of the reviews there is 1000 reviews we have in our data set and this corpus here
will be the new updated version of the corpus that is the corpus containing all the reviews in lower
cases.
So that's the first parameter.
The old version of the corpus and the second parameter is a function that is some kind of a transform
function and that will simply transform each word of the corpus by replacing the capital letters in
lowercase.
So this function is content underscore transformer.
Here it is.
Let's press enter here and actually this content transform function can perform several transformations
as we can see in the yellow rectangle here.
The parameter of this function is fun.
And so we need to add the function that we want to put all the words of the reviews those cases and
this function is called to lower.
All right.
So that's the function parameter that we need to input in this content transform.
Which is like a transform function having several transformation possibilities as input here and the
possibility that we choose is this too long a function which will put all the words in more cases.
And basically this team that function is used so that we can apply this content transform into lower
function for all the words of the 1000 reviews of the corpus.
Great.
So that's actually done.
That's actually all we need to put all the words of the 1000 reviews in more cases.
So I'm going to show you now what it does.
So what we'll do before selecting this and executing this what we'll do is have a look at you know one
review of the Corvis at stake.
The first review and then we'll run this line of code and you'll see what it does to this first review.
OK so let's access to the first review and to do this we need to use the as that character and then
in parenthesis we end the corpus.
But then since we want to look at the first review of this corpus Well we need to add some double brackets
actually and one because this is the index of the first review because indexes are start at 1.
So this way we will have a look at the first review.
And you know since the corpus is kind of a complicated object we need to use these double brackets here
to access to the written review.
And besides we need to use this as character function to have this written review displayed.
All right.
So I'm going to press enter here and as I just told you we get the written review.
Wow.
Love this place which is of course the first review as we can see in our dataset.
Love this place.
All right.
So that's the first review that's the original version of the first review.
And now we are going to apply the first step of the cleaning process which is to put all the reviews
and cases.
So let's do it let's select this line and executes.
All right.
So as you can see it was very fast all the 1000 reviews were just transformed in a lot of cases.
So let's check it out.
Let's check it out for the first review.
So we just need to you know press the up arrow to get the previous command which is this one.
And you know since our new corpus is also called Corpus We just updated the corpus Well we can run this
and hopefully we'll get get the same review written in lower cases.
So let's check it out.
Let's press enter here and here we go.
As you can see the capital W became this little W and this capital L became this lower out perfect.
So first simplification now in the final big table the final sparse matrix we won't get two versions
of the same word one in capital letter and one in lowercase will get one unique version of the word
and therefore we did the first simplification of our future sparse matrix.
So that's a first good thing done.
And now we will proceed to the next step of the cleaning process which will be to remove all the numbers
of the reviews because indeed the numbers are not very relevant in telling you for review is positive
or negative.
Well we need to be cautious actually because maybe some reviews are you know on a scale of 1 to 10 I
give a 10.
Well that's definitely a number that is fully correlated to the outcome whether the review is positive
or negative.
So we should pay attention to that but we could have other numbers that are totally irrelevant like
you know some addresses that contain numbers or phone numbers well that would be a little weird in the
review but we never know.
Well in general when we are dealing with text when we're working with text we want to get rid of the
numbers because these are most of the time not very relevant.
And you know this could add a lot more columns.
So in general it's better to remove the numbers.
So that's what we'll do in the next tutorial.
And until then in Germany learning