Hello and welcome to this Arta Tauriel.
So that's it.
We did the big first step of natural language processing which consisted of cleaning the text we're
working with.
And now it's time to create the sparse matrix of features containing all the different reviews and the
rows and all the different words of the reviews in the columns.
So as a reminder what we're about to build is a huge table in which the rows of the 1000 reviews so
we're going to have one row for each review.
So we're going to have 1000 rows and then the columns are going to contain all the words we can find
in the 1000 reviews in this corpus that is the 1000 cleaned reviews.
And so basically what this means is that we are going to take all the different words in the 1000 interviews
in the corpus and we're going to create one column for each word.
So suppose we count in total 1500 words in this corpus of reviews.
Well that means there are huge tables going to contain 1500 columns.
And then for each cell in this huge table where then each cell will correspond to one review corresponding
to the row and one word corresponding to the column.
And so the value that will contain the cell is the number of times the word appears in the review.
So as we explained earlier since most of the words don't appear in the reviews.
Well most of the cells will contain a zero.
And then of course we'll get a few ones because each review is composed between five to ten words so
in each row we're going to have five or ten cells having a one and all the other cells will have zero
and the cells that have a one will be in the columns corresponding to the worst on the review.
And maybe sometimes but very rarely will get a two or three.
That happens when the word appears twice or three times in a review.
I can give you a simple example let's imagine that we have a super positive review saying I love this
restaurant very very much.
Well in this review the word very appears twice.
So for this particular review in the table that is let's say it's the row 100 well and the cell that
belongs to this row and that belongs to the column corresponding to the word.
Very well we'll get it to because very appears twice in this review.
So that could happen but it's very rare.
And what's most important to understand is that in this huge table we'll get mostly zeroes a few ones
and a very few twos or threes and we'll get so many zeroes that we call this table a sparse matrix a
sparse matrix is a table that contains a lot of zeroes.
It contains very few non-zero values and that's exactly what we're about to obtain because of what we've
just explained.
And you'll see in the information of the table we build that we have the word sparsity and sparsity
refers to that situation where we have a lot of zeros.
And speaking of sparsity let's also keep in mind that if we cleans all the reviews here in this first
step of natural language processing it's in order to reduce as much as possible.
This future sparsity that will occur in this huge table that we're about to build.
So that's the whole point behind this first step here cleaning the text is to avoid having too much
sparsity that is it's to avoid having a table too big with too many columns because remember one column
is created for each word in the corpus.
So by doing all these steps here we removed a lot of words and a lot of characters punctuations numbers
etc. so that in this final huge table we get the minimum number of words and therefore the minimum number
of columns.
And one last quick reminder we are creating this table in order to have the framework of classification
morals.
That is you know having several independent variables and one dependent variable we haven't created
the dependent variable yet it's actually in this dataset here we will just take the second column of
this dataset because this contains the outcome whether the review is positive or negative.
We can see that here it's the second column light.
One of the reviewers positive and zero reviews negative.
So that's the invariable column and the independent variables are going to be nothing else than these
columns corresponding to each one of the words in the clean reviews of the Corbis because for each review
that is each observation we can link their review to each of the columns because for each of the review
we can associate a value for each of the columns and this value is the number of times the word corresponding
to the column appears in the review.
So that's how we create our independent variables and then we'll create our dependent variable and therefore
we'll get the classification model as we use to work with and eventually we win because we will have
everything we will have our independent variables.
We will have our dependent variable and we already have all our classification models that's the models
we made in part 3.
So we will just need to apply these morals on our new data set that we are about to create that contains
the independent variables after words and that have been invaluable as the like to call them in our
original data sets.
All right so let's do it let's create this table and in our we can do efficiently using a function or
function that is called document or a matrix and it's super easy because this function will only take
one argument and as you might have guessed it's going to be the Corvis and that's it.
This will create this huge sparse matrix with all the 1000 revues in the rows and with all the words
of the reviews and the columns.
So let's do it.
Let's call this sparse matrix of features D.T..
And because the function we're about to use is documentor matrix.
So so far we'll call it DTN so equals and then we use the superfunction document term matrix.
Here it is.
I just need to press enter.
And as I just said we just need to input one argument which is our corpus.
All right.
And that's done.
Here it is Corgies.
This will create our sparse matrix of features.
So I'm going to select this line and execute and done the sparse matrix of features is created it appears
right here Deci and we can click on this button here to have some info.
And actually what's interesting to see now is the total number of words counted in the corpus to create
all the columns and we can see the stall count here 1577.
So that means that the number of columns indicated by and call here in our documentary matrix are sparse
matrix is 1577.
So that means that this huge table has 1000 rows.
So we expected this because of course we have 1000 reviews but we didn't expect the number of columns
in total because simply that was the total number of words in the reviews.
So we can count them but we can see this number here 1577.
So that's a really big table.
But be prepared if you're working with more complicated text or longer text like articles or books.
Well you might get a lot more columns here because you will get a lot more worse.
So what you'll have to do and you can ask me any questions about that in the Q&amp;A is reduced even more
to sparsity by filtering the words in your text.
And speaking of filtering that's what we're going to do right now.
We are going to apply a filter to clean even more the reviews by only considering the most frequent
words that means that it's like we're going to add a step in this text line process which will consist
of only taking the words that are the most frequent.
For example the words that appear in only one review.
Well they might be removed because they're not frequent.
They only appear once only one cell in the matrix contains one because these words only appear in one
review and these words of course are not very relevant because since they only appear in one review.
Well our machine learning classification model will not be able to establish any correlation between
this word and the outcome whether the review is positive or negative because indeed to understand such
correlations the word would need to appear in at least two reviews.
So that's the kind of words we're going to remove.
And again this is in order to reduce sparsity.
And speaking of sparsity I will show you something very interesting right now if we go to the console
and type here ditty and then we'll get other information about this sparse matrix of features and information
that I want to highlight here is of course this sparsity information.
And as you can see the sparsity is 100 percent right now and that's because there are a lot of zeros
in the Matrix.
And also because we haven't filtered and non frequent word yet.
So that's what we'll do right now.
We will filter all the words that appear only once we will filter other words that are not frequent
in the reviews.
All right so let's do it.
To do this we are going to update our documentary matrix.
So we're taking again DTM here.
All right.
Because we're updating our sparse metrics and equals and now we're going to use a function a very practical
function that will filter the non frequent words of our sparse matrix which so far is nothing else than
DTN.
So DTM will be one of the inputs and we will filter all the non frequent words by specifying a proportion
of non frequent words that we want to remove from the sparse matrix and this proportion of non frequent
words will be obtained thanks to the second input of this function because the second input is the percentage
of the most frequent words we want to keep in the reviews.
So let's say you want to keep 99 percent of the words in the review that are the most Rikan words.
Well this second input will take the value of 99 percent.
So let's use this function.
This function is remove sparse terms.
Here it is.
Remove sparse terms.
So pressing enter and ready to input the two arguments.
So the first argument is of course the sparse matrix on which one to apply.
This filtering so of course it did them all right and the second input is the proportion of words that
are the most frequent words and that will be kept in the sparse matrix.
So let's say you want to keep 99 percent the most frequent words well we would need to put here point
ninety nine and therefore we'll build the same sparse matrix but this unconsenting 99 percent of the
words that are the most frequent in this sparse matrix of features and therefore you know we're not
looking at the Corpus containing all the words and counting the most frequent words of this Corvis.
What this function remove sparse terms will do is to look at all the columns of the sparse matrix here
and then keep 99 percent of the columns that have the most ones in the columns because each column corresponds
to a word and therefore when there are very few ones in the columns that means that this word appears
in very few reviews and therefore these other words that are not frequent in the reviews and accordingly
not relevant.
And that's why we can remove them.
All right so let's do it let's apply the filter to be cautious.
Let's maybe take a higher proportion of freek'n words we keep because actually with 99 percent we might
remove a lot of words.
You can try it on your our studio to see.
But here since we don't have many reviews you know we have 1000 reviews that is not much compared to
other text we can work with in natural language processing.
Let's be careful here and apply.
And ninety nine point nine percent proportion of freek'n words are him going to add a 9 and you'll see
that it will already remove quite a lot of words.
So let's try it.
I'm going to select this and execute and indeed as you can see we now have 691 columns in the sparse
matrix that is we only kept 691 words.
So clearly we can see that by keeping ninety nine point nine percent of the words that are the most
frequent.
Well that already removes almost 1000 words because originally we had remember more than 1500 words.
So be careful with this.
Be careful not to apply a too low proportion of frequent words you want to keep and to choose that remember
to look at the total number of words that is counted when you build this first parse matrix.
And of course you can also choose this number by considering the total number of reviews you have in
your original data set.
And you know since we only had 1000 reviews.
Well that's why we take such a high proportion here.
And let's see by how much reduce the sparsity.
So we have two tight deci again because our documents force matrix that is our sparse matrix was just
a data with all these words removed.
So pressing enter here and the sparsity now became 99 percent so better.
But anyway that was fine because we didn't have too much columns.
You will see that if you work with larger text you will get a lot more words and therefore a lot more
columns.
All right so that will be all for this to Tauriel.
We built our bag over words.
Congratulations for that.
And now it's time to make the classification model.
So that's what we'll do in the next and final tutorial section.
And until then and let me see learning