Hello and welcome to the art of Tauriel.
So now we know how to implement to feature extraction techniques.
These are PCa and LDA But these feature extraction techniques work on Lynnie are problems.
That is when the data is linearly separable.
And in this section we are going to see one new feature extraction technique but this time adapted for
non-linear problems where the data is nonlinearly separable.
So this technique is called Colonel PCA.
Colonel PCa is a current life version of PCa where we map the data to a higher dimension using the kernel
trick.
And then from there we extract some new principal components and we're going to see how it manages to
deal with nonlinear problems.
So we're not going to work on the same problem as we did in the previous sections with the one dataset
but we're going to work on the same dataset as the one used in part 3 classification because now we
need visuals.
We need to clearly see what happens we need to see how current PCA manages to extract some new independent
variables the principal components even when the problem is non-linear or that is when the data is not
linearly separable.
And this dataset that we used in part 3 the social network adds data sets will remember it was clearly
a nonlinear problem because nonlinear classifiers showed much better performance.
So let's take this dataset and let's have like PCA to see how it will handle the nominee already.
So let's find this data set into our working directory folder.
So we'll get to our mission.
It is a folder and part of nine dimensionality reduction.
And here we are at the last section of this part 9 kernel PCA.
So that's the folder you want to set as a working directory make sure that you have the social network
at as well.
And if that's the case you really click on this more about near to set the folder as a working directory.
And now what we're going to do is take this logistic regression model because you know this logistic
regression model is a linear classifier therefore it will not be appropriate for our problem because
our data is not linearly separable.
So what we're going to do is take this linear classify here but we are going to apply kernel Pitsea
inside of it to see how kernel PCA will save the situation.
And so you will see that even if we apply a linear model.
Well thanks to Colonel PCa that we managed to extract new principal components adapted for this nonlinearly
separable data.
Well you will see that will get amazing results.
So right now let's copy the whole model here from the top down to the bottom copy.
And let's face it in our code PCA file.
All right.
And now basically the only thing that we have to do is to apply code PCa at the right place.
But before we do that I would just like to visualize again why this linear model is not appropriate
for this dataset.
So what we're going to do is take everything from here because you know this will visualize the trainings
that results by plotting the prediction regions and the prediction boundary.
So we're going to take everything from here up to the top to you know important data set apply the preprocessing
phase filter logistic regression to the training set and eventually plot the training that resolves.
So let's do it let's visualize this again very quickly and that will give us motivation to apply.
Colonel PICHETTE and here we go.
All executed properly so as a reminder the points are the real observations.
That is our real customers in the social network represented by their age and their estimated salary.
So that's our real observation points and our predictions are represented by these regions.
The red region here and the green region here.
And basically this red region is where our model predicts that the customer will not click on the ad
and this green region here is the region where a model predicts that the customers will click on the
ad and buy the SUV.
And so remember the problem was that this straight line here is actually the prediction boundary generated
by the logistic regression model.
But since the logistic regression model is a linear classifier then it has to be a straight line here
separating the data and therefore remember the problem is that it can not make some kind of a curve
here to catch these green users that should be in the green region right now they're in the red region.
And so this clearly represents the fact that our data is not literally separable because we can clearly
see that this prediction boundary here that plays the role of separator and that is supposed to separate
the two classes.
Well it cannot separate the two classes properly because as you can see these users are not in the right
region and so now what we are going to do is not make a nonlinear classifier like we did in part three
you know when we made Colonel SBM base decision trees around him for us.
Well what we're going to do now instead is a black Colonel PCA so that we keep a straight line as a
separator as the prediction boundary of a linear classifier that is still going to be the prediction
boundary of the logistic regression model.
But since we're going to apply kernel PCA Well this will manage to apply some trick where the trick
is actually the kernel trick to map the data into a higher dimension and then apply PCA to extract new
components that will be new dimensions that explain the most variants.
But thanks to this Colonel Treyc Well you'll see that we'll manage to get some new dimensions in which
the data will be linearly separable even by a linear classifier like logistic regression.
So let's see that right now.
I can't wait to show you this.
I'm going to close this.
And now let's apply kernel PCa at the right location.
So you already know what this location is.
It's actually not different than before.
We need to apply kernel PCA right up to the data preprocessing phase and just before fitting our classifier
like logistic regression to our training centers.
So basically we need to apply current PCA right here so U.S. here applying Kerno PCa and here we go
let's do it.
All right.
So first we need to install a new package that is called current lab which I don't think we'll install
before so let's do it right now.
So we use the command install packages.
Here we go.
And in quotes kerflop.
All right.
So I think I already have it installed.
Let's check it out.
So here it is current lab kernel based machinery lab.
So I will not install it.
But if you want to do it you just like this line and execute.
So I will just put this line as a comment.
Here we go.
But then since it is not imported I will import using the library command Kurla.
All right.
And that will import it.
Kurla will import it.
And now let's start applying kernel PCA.
So ask for PCa and LDA we're going to start by creating an object which will be the kernel object that
we will use to transform our original data set into this dataset.
After using the kernel trick so we'll call this object K PCa and then equals and then that's where we
use the function that will create this kernel object.
So this function is also K PCa then parenthesis and then lets input the different arguments.
So let's take it out let's press on here to have a look at the arguments.
So the first argument is X and this is actually the data matrix or the formula describing the model.
And here I'll give you a little trick to describe the model very simply and very efficiently we can
simply input here until the.
And that and that will be enough for the KPC a function to understand what the formula is because then
we will add the second argument which is data and that is actually the training set but without the
dependent variable because remember Colonel PCA is just a PCA technique where we use the kernel trick
to map the data into a higher dimension and then apply PCA because indeed in this high dimension the
data is linearly separable and therefore since we apply PCa in this higher dimension and PCA is an unsupervised
technique.
Well here for the data argument we just need to input the training set but without the dependent variable
and therefore asked for PCa we input here data equals training set in brackets to remove the dependent
variable which is indexed by 3 because we only have two independent variables.
All right.
And then the next argument is kernel.
So kernel is a kernel you want to use to apply your kernel trick.
Remember when we studied kernel SVM we saw that there were several kernels to use the kernel trick and
here we are going to use the most common one which is the gashing Colonel and that is called here RBA.
So that's our third argument.
And so here we can put kernel equals RDF dot.
All right.
And then what is the next argument the next argument is keep or we will actually not use this one.
But then we have a very important argument that is at the heart of dimensionality reduction that is
features which is the number of features the number of principal components you want to end up with.
So here of course who would like to visualize the trainings that results in the test results in two
dimensions and to have this in two dimensions we need to keep a number of two new extracted independent
variables.
So here the number of features will be to ask for PCa.
So we will input here features equals to.
All right.
And that's it for our PCA.
Object is ready to be created and to be used to transform our original data set into this new data set
with the new extracted features derived from kernel PCA.
So let's select this line and create the object.
Here it is.
You say well create it and now let's move onto the next step which is to transform our original dataset
into this new extracted dataset.
So now things are going to look like what we did with PCa.
But some things are going to change so we will do it step by step and we'll see where we need to make
some changes.
All right so first as we're busy we're going to use the predict function to transform our original trainset
into this new extracted training set.
So this new trainset with a new extracted features derived from Colonel PCA we call it training set
underscore PCA.
All right and then equals and then we use to predict function to do the transformation.
And inside this pretty function we first input our KPC object as we did for PCa.
And then the training set the original training set.
So let's do it training set.
The second one.
All right.
And as opposed to PCA.
And as with LDA this will return a matrix and we need it as a date frame to ask for LDK will use that
as that data thought brain function.
So parenthesis here and we close the parenthesis here to set this transform training said trining said
PCA as different and as a reminder we're doing this to give what the next function will use in the next
sections expect.
All right so far so good.
And so now let's select this plan and execute this and you're going to see what's going to happen and
you're going to understand why we called this new training set training said PCa with a different name
than the original training said trainset.
All right so let's execute.
Here we go.
Executed properly.
And now let's have a look at our training said PCa that we just created.
So I'm going to enlarge this so that we can see which one is strains that PCA that's the one.
So let's have a look at this.
I'm going to click on it and here is our trainset PCA.
So as we can see it is composed of only two columns we want and V-2.
So try to guess what these two columns are.
I'm going to tell you right now these two columns are the principal components that we obtained through
current PCA.
That is these are two new extracted features.
After all this mapping into this high dimension using the Caltech and then applying PCA to the data
set mapped into this high dimension.
But now the problem is that in this training said PCA we don't have to depend Roybal and we need it
for the next sections because in our code templates we need to have the independent variables and the
dependent variable.
So what is the next step now the next step is to add the dependent variable into this training set PCa
and sort of thing to understand here is that we lost the deep and Roybal but we kept the observations
that is this one here corresponds to the first observation we had in the original training set.
This one.
So this first observation here has the zero label that is that this first customer didn't buy the SUV.
This was the original independent variables.
And then if you go to our training said PCA Well this first customer is the same first customer as this
training sets.
So it will have the zero label in the purchase column.
But then these are new extracted features of course we don't get the same values as for the independent
variables of our original trainset.
So what we can do now is simply take the dependent variable call him purchased of this original training
set and add it to our training set PCA because these observations here are the same observations of
our original trainset.
And so what we need to do now is very simple we just need to take our training set PCa then we're going
to add a new column that will call purchased.
So by doing this you know I'm just creating a new column that I also called purchased because this new
column is going to be purchased dependent invaluable and then equals and then what I have to do now
is to take the real purchase that Ben Roybal call him from the original trainset and we can do that
because the training said PCA contains the same observations as the observations of the original training
set.
So here to take the purchase column of the original trainset we just need to take our original trainset
which is called training sets and then dollar.
And then that's where we take the chaste column.
So by doing this I will add this new column pre-Chase and this you can pre-Chase I will include the
values of the pre-Chase column of the original training set.
Let's check it out.
I'm going to select this line and execute.
And now as you can see if I go back to training that PCA this contains the pre-Chase column of the original
trainset.
So that's good.
That's the next step done.
And now we need to take care of the desert and so to take care of that said we're going to do exactly
the same as we did for this training said PCA.
So let's copy this copy and let's paste it here.
And of course what we're going to do now is replace this training said PCA by test set PCA.
And same here we take the original test set to make the transformation and then we're going to add the
purchase column of the original test set to this new test set.
That is a tested extracted from code PCA.
So test it here and that should be OK.
So I'm going to select these two lines here and execute.
Perfect.
Our tests tested PCA is created.
Let's have a quick check.
So that's the test set.
And that's our test said PCa with the two new extracted features and the purchase column.
And now that means that we correctly applied Colonel PCA.
So great we are ready to move on to the next section.
So let's go back to our current PCA our file and let's now fix the logistic regression to the trainset.
Now do we need to change anything in this code section.
Well yes of course we do because.
Be careful.
We called our new extracted trainset Chernin said PCA.
So here for the data arguments we need to specify training said PCA.
So that's the only thing we need to change here.
So we are ready to select the section and execute.
All right CAS very ready.
And now let's move on to the next section relating to test results.
And of course here that's the same we had to replace test set by test set PCA mean to an artist a little
bit.
Right.
And that's it.
We are ready to execute the section to predict the results.
And here we go.
We get our vector of predictions why pred for this new test set this year.
Right now let's make the confusion matrix.
We of course need to change test set by test said PCA.
Here we go.
And now it's ready.
Now we can execute this line of code to get the confusion matrix.
And here it is we can have a quick look and the council by person see him enter and we get 57 plus 26
equals 83.
And since we have 100 observations in a test set that gives us an 83 percent accuracy.
So that's pretty good.
And now let's get to the exciting part.
Visualizing the trends that results so very quickly what do we need to change.
Remember we need to change the names of the independent variables and call names here.
That's compulsory.
So as a reminder the names are the one and the two that's the name of the independent variables.
So here we need to replace age by one and estimated salary by V-2.
And that's not compulsory.
And anyway we already have two good names.
P.s. one NPC too.
So don't forget about that.
And of course we need to change the name of the training set because we got our training set training
said PCA.
So here I'm adding trainset PCA.
And that's perfect.
That's ready to be executed.
To visualize the trainset results.
So we will only visualize the trends that result.
But let's make the same changes for the test sets so that you can have a look at it yourself.
So same we're replacing age by the one estimated salary by V-2.
And here we replace tested by tests that underscore PCA.
All right.
Now let's have a look.
I look forward to show you what's going to happen.
So I'm going to select everything from here up to the top here that is the whole section to visualize
the trends that result.
And let's press command control us enter to execute.
Here we go.
The computer patients are being run.
All right.
So these are the results of Colonel PCA combined to a logistic regression model that we apply on a non-linear
separable data set.
And so we can appreciate the contrast between the simplicity of the obtained results and the complexity
of what happened behind the scenes because indeed we have this very simple result here with these two
classes separated by a straight line with what happened behind the scenes is that our original data
set in our original feature space was mapped to a higher dimension using the kernel trick to avoid to
highly compute intensive computation.
And then by mapping our data set in the original feature space to this high dimension well for us that
created some new dimensions.
And mostly that created a new feature space where our data was then linearly separable.
But by doing that we had more dimensions than the original number of dimensions.
So we still needed to apply the PCA dimensionality reduction technique to end up with a lower number
of dimensions.
So then PCa was applied to this new feature space where the data was linearly separable and through
some you extracted in the been available were created there are nothing else than the principal components
of PCa.
And eventually we obtain this new feature space formed by these two new extracted principal components
resulting from PCa in which now our data is linearly separable and much better separated by a linear
classifier.
All right so that's it for kernel PCA.
And that's also the end of this part dimensionality reduction and I'll see you in the next part part
and moral selection and boosting the last part of this courseware will cover a very exciting algorithm
in machine learning that is called Extreme boost.
So I look forward to seeing you in this next part.
And until then enjoyer machine learning.