Hello my friend.
Happy to see you again.
Now for this new section and mostly this new practical activity where we're going to build together
the random forest regression.
So this is our last model of the regression part and we're going to build it very quickly and efficiently
because actually it looks very much like the decision tree regression model.
So we will be very efficient and besides right after this section comes the most important section for
you it is the section where Kiril and I will explain to you how to not only evaluate your regression
models but also how to select the best one.
So right after we're done with the random forest regression we will actually have a new dataset with
you know multiple features you know like more real world data set and I will show you how to use your
regression code templates to quickly plug your regression models onto the dataset and quickly find the
best one.
All right.
So that will be very important for you to learn how to handle.
But now let's smashed our last regression model the random forced regression.
And before we start let's just make sure everyone here is on the same page.
I give you the link to this folder right before this material in the article.
So make sure to connect to that link.
And now we should all be on the same page.
So we're all going to go into part two regression.
Then we're going to go this time to the last regression model which is our Random Forest regression
and then we're going to start as usual with Python and this folder contains once again the position
salaries data set and of course the random forest regression implementation in the API and before match
which can therefore open with either Google collaboratively or Jupiter notebook.
And as far as I'm concerned as usual I'm going to open it with Google collaboratively.
So there we go.
Let's start implementing the random forest regression model.
Now it is you know laying out the notebook and in a second we should have it.
There we go.
All right.
So as usual this is an read only mode.
We're going to quickly create a copy so that we can re implement it.
We're not going to be implemented from scratch because it is really similar as The Decision Tree regression
model.
So you will see that we will only re implement one code cell and if you know you come here in this regression
folder for the first time with random force regression.
Well I encourage you to have a look at Decision Tree regression first because indeed all these code
cells were explained right.
But this time we're only going to delete this one.
That's where we you know train the random for regression model on the whole data set and then all the
rest of the same.
It is all the same as Decision Tree regression.
We import first the libraries then we import the data set.
Then after you know the training of the random force regression model on the whole there is said we
predict this new result which is the exact same syntax.
Actually I'm going to hide this now.
So this is the exact same syntax as The Decision Tree regression model.
And then here that's the same.
This is the exact same code that we implement visualize the random forest regression results.
All right so let's just keep this because we did it many times and I'm sure you're looking forward to
that final section where you know everything is going to make sense because indeed you will learn how
to use this regression folder containing all these code templates for regression and you will learn
how to understand which model to choose and you know select the best one for your data set.
I will explain everything in this last section.
But for now let's implement that only missing code cell to train the random forest regression model
on the whole dataset.
So let's add a new code cell here and now there you go you could once again totally do it yourself by
looking at some documentation online and actually well let's do it together this time we're gonna pretend
that you know we would like to build a random forest regression model and turn it on the dataset and
that I have absolutely no clue on how to build it or you know on which side could learn class to use
to build it.
So let's see.
Well what I would do as I said would be to go to Google or being.
So here is Google and I would type here in a search bar.
Well you know for example cited learn.
All right.
And then random forest regression.
This one right.
Even the suggestion helps.
That's perfect.
Then pressing enter and then I would go for the link cycle learn you know the cycle learn web site and
this will usually be the first link as it is the case right here.
So let's click this.
And normally I should find site the exact name of the random forest regression class and also the name
of the module that contains this class.
And indeed that is exactly what we see in big here.
This is the whole library cycle learn.
This is the module that contains the class we want and this is the name of the class.
So there you go.
Well let's actually take everything here and we will get this bitch because this is not exactly what
we have to write in Python but I'm sure you'll know how to adapt this.
There you go.
That's why I wanted to show you.
You know it's very very easy to find online the name of a class that allows to build the model you want
right.
I just had to type cycled learn and random forest regression and just go to the first link so you see.
Very very easy.
So let's go back to our implementation and let's start building this random forest regression model
and train it on the whole dataset.
Now I'm gonna based where I've just copied because indeed in order to import this class I simply need
to add here at the beginning of from right from cyclone and then from the end symbol module of psychic
return.
Well I'm going to import that random forest regressive class and perfect.
And now you know what the next natural step is.
Well it is of course to create a new object of this random forest regressive class and we're going to
call this object as usual right.
Correct sir.
Which will be equal to.
Well you know an instance of this class.
That's why I'm copying it and basing it here and adding some parentheses.
All right.
So this time do you think we have to input something in this class.
Well let's not fall into the trap of too much easiness.
Let's say remember that for a decision tree regression we actually did not input you know an essential
parameter.
We just input a random state factor in order to fix the seeds so that we can all have the same results
displayed in the output.
But this time there is actually a parameter that is very important.
I'm sure you guess which one it is.
And not only it is important but also you can tune it you know you can try several values of this parameter
to see which value leads to the best accuracy and therefore the best random forest regress.
And that parameter is well of course as you might guess the number of trees because remember a random
forest is a bunch of trees teaming up to output a final operation.
You know each tree makes its own prediction and then the random forest itself judges the final ones
output.
And so that number of trees is important and that's why we will specify we will choose actually a number
of trees here.
And I usually recommend to start with 10 trees.
So that's exactly what we're going to input here.
The name of that parameter is an underscore estimate or is just like that.
And as we said we're going to say equal to 10 10 trees.
Right.
Ten estimates.
Each tree is an estimate.
Okay.
And then as usual we're going to add the random underscore state parameter.
And once again we'll set that equal to zero so that we can fix the seeds and get the same output displayed
in our notebook.
Okay great.
And now final step you know this step by heart.
Now it is so obvious for you it is of course to fit the regress or object to the whole dataset.
In other words that means we are training the regress or on the whole dataset.
Right.
So here we have to add a dot and then fit applied to X and Y.
Perfect.
So and that's all we had to do you know for this random forest regression implementation all the rest
is the same as the decision tree.
So we can just execute all the cells here and observe comfortably in our chair.
The final result.
So let's have a look.
I just want to warn you again that it's not going to be pretty.
And that's of course for the exact same reason as decision trees a random forest regression model is
way better adapted to high dimensional data sets or you know datasets with multiple features which you
will see in the final section of this part to regression when not only learning how to evaluate your
regression models but also on how to select the best model for any dataset you know for a particular
dataset you're working with.
All right.
So let's do this.
Let's execute each of these cells starting with important libraries.
Then I'm not going to forget I almost forgot to upload the data set.
You know I was about to execute the cell but that were never returned to Nara because indeed the dataset
needs to be applauded.
So let's upload it now.
All right.
So as usual we have to go into our machinery is that folder.
Wherever you put it on your machine then part two regression then Section 9 and last section of this
part to random forest regression and python.
And there we go.
Position salaries.
This is still of course the same dataset.
Okay.
So that's all good.
Now we have the data sets and now we can import it inside the notebook.
Well actually inside our python program and now we're going to train the running for his regression
more on the whole data set.
So let's do this and this will output the running for its regressive model with all the parameters and
at this stage the only parameter that I recommend to tune is indeed that number of estimates which we
chose to be equal to 10.
All right and don't worry too much about the rest.
Now this will already give you an excellent model.
And then now let us predict the final result by you know just calling this predict method from our regress
or object and predict method just has to take as input.
Well that position level number six point five which remember you have to input in a double pair of
square brackets because the brick method expect a 2D array as its input.
Right.
So that's very important for you to know.
But we saw this many time.
I'm sure it has become also very obvious for you.
So let's do this let's get this prediction and we get while we get a pretty good prediction actually.
One hundred and sixty seven thousand dollars which is very close to you know that salary that this person
mentioned to earn in the previous company which was 160 K so that's very very good.
And now let's visualize the final result.
Oh I actually forgot to delete that output but that's fine.
Let's run the sale and we'll get that output again.
And here is the regression curve of the random for us regression model and of course it looks like a
lot the one of the decision trees although this time there are more steps of the stairs you know remember
for the decision tree regression model we had a step for each of the position level.
And here for example we have two steps between two position levels.
So that's of course because we have more trees this time and therefore more splits of you know the features
where you have the same prediction.
You know the average of the predicted salary.
So it only makes sense that there are more steps.
Right.
Same here as well.
And same here as well.
But once again this is not really relevant in 2D.
I just wanted you to see still.
Well the regression curve in 2D which is the only way we can see it unless we put something in 3D.
Well you know over three dimensions it's clearly impossible to visualize a regression hyper plain so
that's why I kept two dimensions here.
But once again don't worry.
In this last section we will have a real world data set with multiple features and we will try each
and every single one of our regression models on this data set and I will teach you how to figure out
which ones to select.
Indeed that's very often ask questions in the data science community.
You know you have all these models but which one should you go for you know which one should you select
for your data sets.
And that's exactly what I'll teach you in this last section of Part Two regression.
All right.
So congratulations.
That was your final regression model of part two.
You now have a complete toolkit of regression models which gives you a lot of different options and
solutions for your future data set and future machinery problems.
So I'm really happy for you that we built together this toolkit.
Make sure to use it the right way.
And now we will finish with this last section to teach you how to use this regression tool kit.
The best way you know by selecting the best model for any dataset.
All right.
So join me in this next section.
I can't wait to see you again.
And until then enjoy machine learning.