Hello and welcome back to the course on deep learning.
Today we're talking about a clue which is rectified in your units and this is an additional step on
top of our convolution step.
So it's not a separate big step it's a small step in step one be basically.
And what is going on here.
Well we have our input image we have all convolutional there which we've discussed and then on top of
that we're going to apply.
Wait for it.
Our favorite rectifier function and you're familiar with the rectifier function from the previous section
on artificial neural networks and in our So sometimes authors or instructors separate the convolution
and direct fire as two separate steps in our examples which is going to consider them the just one big
step for second evolution then the rectifier.
And the reason why we're applying the rectifier is because you want to increase non-linearity in our
image or in our network and our commercial neural network and our fire acts as that filter or access
that function which breaks up and you arity and the reason why we want to increase nonlinearity in our
network is because images themselves are highly non-linear especially if you're recognizing different
objects next to each other or just on background and stuff like that like the image is going to have
lots of nonlinear elements and the transition between pixels adjacent pixels is often would be nonlinear.
That's you know because its borders is different colors is different.
There's different elements in your images and but at the same time when we're applying a mathematical
operation such as convolution you know and running this feature detection to create our feature maps
we risk that we might create something linear and therefore we need to break up the narrative.
So let's have a look at an example here is a image and original image.
Now when we apply a feature detection detector to this image we get something like this.
So you can see here that black is negative white is positive value as well.
When you apply a feature detector to a like a proper image which has not just zeros and ones but has
lots of different values and you apply as we saw previously you Texas can have negative values in themselves
sometimes you'll get negative values.
And here are the black ones are negative white ones are positive.
And what a rectified linear unit function does is it removes all the black rights in anything below
zero it turns into zero.
And so from this it turns into this right.
And so it's it's pretty hard to see what exactly is the benefit in terms of in terms of breaking up
linearity.
I'll try to explain.
I'll try to show an example on this image but at the end of the day it's this is a very mathematical
concept and would have to go into a lot of math to really explain what is going on.
But let's let's try let's have a look.
So for instance let's look at this.
This building here.
Right.
So this is a building on its own.
Then you can see this shadow.
This black part this shadow over here well you see that it's white the reflection of the light and then
it's a gray and then it gets darker and then it gets darker again.
So and when we take it out we take out that black spot.
So think of it in terms of linearity right.
So the it looks like when you go from white to gray the next step would be black.
Right the next up would be black it's it's a linear progression from bright to dark and therefore this
is kind of like a linear situation.
When you take out the black you break up the linearity.
Let's try another one.
Let's have a look here.
And at the same time it's still that same building right.
It's not it's not like you or your like it's not like you're blending two buildings into each other
but that is secondary.
The main point is breaking up the linearity.
So let's have a look here same thing.
So you see white gray black gray white.
And when you break it up you don't have that anymore right.
You don't have that progression the gradual progression that you just have like an abrupt change.
And that helps introduce non-linearity into your image.
So it's a very rough explanation very kind of like on or on the fingers explanation rather than technical
but hopefully it kind of helps you understand a bit better what we're talking about here.
So here again you can see white gray is a better example even to bright darker darker darker and darker
darker.
So this part looks like it's thinner than you break it up like that again so this is a very rough explanation.
It's not absolutely perfect but at least it gives you some idea of what's going on.
But if you'd like to learn more there's a good paper as always there's always a paper.
This one is by CCJ corps from the University of California and it's called Understanding convolutional
neural networks who have a mathematical model.
And basically they're He answers to questions and you need to just look at the first one.
And the question is why is not a nonlinear activation function is essential at the filter output of
all intermediate layers.
So that kind of explains it in a bit more detail both in terms of intuition and mostly in terms of mathematics.
So that's an interesting paper where you can get some more additional information on this topic.
And if you really want to dig in and explore some some cool stuff here.
Then there's another paper that you might be interested in.
It's called delving deeper into rectifier surpassing human level level performance on image and that
classification.
And here the author is combing hair and others from Microsoft Research.
They propose a different type of rectified leaner unit function.
They propose the parametric rectified function which you see here on the right.
And they argue that it delivers better results without sacrificing performance.
So interesting read if you'd like to get a bit more into this topic.
And that's all for today.
Really you layer is pretty simple so for adjusting just applying the rectifier function and I look forward
to seeing you next time.
Until then enjoy learning.