Hello my friends and welcome to this new practical activity on support vector machines.
For clarification of course.
All right.
So we already built to classification models logistic regression and K and then we got the best result
so far with Ken.
And now let's see if we can beat it or even the one after that.
Colonel SVM.
All right.
So before we start as usual let's make sure everyone here is on the same page right before this tutorial
I give you the link to this whole folder.
So make sure to connect to that link.
And if that's the case then follow me into Part 3 classification and then Section 16 support vector
machine as VM.
And we're going to start with Python of course as usual.
And in this python folder you will get two files.
The first is the same data set.
Social network adds that C is v containing 400 observations where each observation is actually a customer
who but yes or no.
SUV that is advertised on social networks.
And for each of these customers you have the age the estimated salaries of these are the two features.
And with these two features you will predict the dependent viable purchased meaning whether or not the
customers but the SUV.
So one means yes the customer but previous SUV and zero means no the customer didn't buy any SUV.
All right.
So same data set.
And of course the second factor is this support vector machine implementation and the API and B format
which can either open with Google collaboratively or GP a notebook.
And as far as I'm concerned I'm going to open it with Google collaborator.
But feel free to choose your favorite ideas.
All right.
So let's put that out here actually here.
And right now it is loading the notebook laying it out.
And in a second we should have it open.
There we go.
All right.
So that's the whole support vector machine implementation.
And of course it is exactly the same as before.
In order to re implement this we will only have to change the code cell where we build and train this
model because indeed this implementation results from the exact same classification template that we
made when we built the logistic regression model and we saw clearly when implementing the Kenya's neighbours
model how indeed.
We only had to change one cell and how this template worked super well for that model.
So here for SVM we're going to do exactly the same.
We're just going to leave all the cells as they are as they actually were in the logistic regression
model and we will only re implement the cell where we build the SVM.
All right.
So let's do this let's create a new copy of this file because this file isn't read on mode.
Let's click here save a copy and drive.
And this will create a copy inside which we will indeed be able to modify the implementation and mostly
to re implement that could sell to be the SVM model.
All right.
Perfect.
So at the beginning of course we start with the data repricing phase with all the same outputs displayed
on the notebook.
So that's all good.
Then we apply feature scaling because you know it improves the training performance.
And anyway it's never bad to apply feature scaling.
And finally there we go.
That's the cell we have to re implement together because indeed it is the one that defers with respect
to the previous implementations.
So let's click this trust button here to you know read implement it again let's create a new code cell.
And now my friends over to you once again I would like you to please press buzz on the video and try
to implement that could sell yourself.
And that's because I not only want to train you in machine learning but also train you on how to be
independent with machine learning.
So right now the exercise I want you to do is to do some research in the cycle cyclone an API to figure
out which class allows to build the SVM model.
So you will find it very easily actually because there is no trap in the name of the class or the name
of the module.
So I trust you will totally be able to do this exercise successfully and mostly know which method to
use at the end to train that SVM or on the training set.
All right.
So please press buzz.
And now in two seconds I'm gonna give you the solution.
All right let's do this.
So I already have the cyclone API open.
You know that was for the nearest neighbors the key nearest neighbours.
Which we implemented previously in the previous section.
We used this class K neighbors classifier and now the next thing we would like to find in this API documentation
is the module that contains the class that allows to build the SVM model.
So naturally where could we find it.
You know here should we scroll back up or scroll down.
Well let's hope that you know the name of the module starts with an S..
Because here you know the modules are organized by alphabetical order.
So since here we are at n n neighbors.
Let us hope that the name of the module we're looking for starts with a net like support vector machine.
So let's scroll down and random projections.
Mean supervised learning.
And there we go.
Support vector machines.
Hello.
That's exactly what we were looking for support vector machines.
That's not the name of the module the name of the module is as the m the same.
That stands for support vector machines.
All right.
And then.
Well you know the hardest part is done.
Now according to you which estimated as you know because here you have all the basically support back
to machines based machinery morals and so according to you which one do we need to take here.
Well we actually have two options.
We could either take the linear as we see which will directly build the linear support vector machine
model or we can take this one as we see and choose a linear kernel.
All right.
And we will actually go for this option because in the next section we will study the kernel as VM models
which as you might guess allow us to choose some different kernels in our SVM including the linear one
and the nonlinear ones like for example the very famous one orbit.
Right radial basis function which is actually the one we used in as we are you know that's the class
you recognize it that we used to build the edge of your model in the path to regression.
All right.
So there we go.
Let's go inside.
And here is the name of the module as VM of course.
And the class that we must now import in order to build R as your model.
All right so let's start with this as usual let's get you know this path and let's adapt it inside or
coattail you know how to do this we need to start with from.
So from the cyclone library and then the SVM module of the cyclone library we will import the SBC class.
OK.
So that's a first step.
And then the next natural step you know it by heart it is of course to create an object of this class.
And we need to keep here the name classifier because in order to not have anything to change afterwards
so classifier which will be nothing else then the SVM model itself.
And so to create such an object we need to call this class.
I can just type it as V C and then add some parenthesis and now the question is what do we need to input
here as parameters.
Well I hope you have the reflex to think of course we need to input the kernel because as I've just
explained this as we see class allow us to build kernel as and models with either a linear kernel which
is the classic as your model or a nonlinear kernel.
So here in our parameters we'll have to specify that we want a linear kernel because we're starting
with the classic SVM model.
And then in the next section you know on kernel as VM will choose a nonlinear kernel like RBI for polynomial.
We'll see.
But there you go.
That's our first argument.
And indeed when we have a look at the documentation we can see that indeed the second parameter here
is Colonel and the default value is RBI.
So we'll have to specify that we want linear to start with and then as you can see you have many many
other arguments you know parameters and you can check out the description for each of them.
But no worries we won't change their default value we'll just keep their default value.
Like for example the regularization parameter for which we'll keep the default value of 1.
That's fine you'll see in the visualization that there is not much we can do in order to improve the
moral or to avoid or fitting.
So there we go.
The only parameter that we'll take is this one kernel equals not IBF but linear.
All right let's do this.
Kernel equals in quotes linear.
All right.
And then I know I've just said that we won't have to input any other parameters but let's add anyway
you know this one the random state parameter and set it equal to zero.
Just to make sure that we get the same results displayed on our notebook you know because there are
some run factors when we build this SVM model and therefore for teaching purposes it's better if we
all have the same results displayed in our notebook.
All right.
And that's it.
Congratulations.
That builds the SVM morale.
The classic one with the linear kernel.
And now you know how to finish this.
Of course our last here is to take our classifier from which we're going to call the fit method to train
our SVM classifier on the training set and we have to input that here in two parts first matrix of features
of the training set which is x train and then the dependent variable vector of the train set which is
why train all right.
So you know this perfectly well now it's like your native language.
Right.
Okay.
I hope I'm right but there you go.
Congratulations.
This implementation is now over.
Thanks to this very efficient code template.
And so now.
Well we'll just run everything and observe the final results.
Indian All right so let's do this.
Let's not forget to you know import the data set here you know upload it in the notebook so click this
folder here.
Then you will have to wait a few seconds because your notebook will be connecting to a runtime to enable
file browsing and in a second and we should see.
There we go.
The upload button.
So we're going to click that and well you know that's the data set but I'll show you the whole path
again.
So you'll find your machinery is at for code and data sets which you could download in the previous
tutorial in the oracle.
Then you're going to go to part three classification then to Section 16 support vector machine in Python
and social network at that.
Yes.
You click open and this will upload the data set inside the notebook.
There we go now.
Now you can run all the cells by clicking runtime here and then.
Are you ready.
Run.
Oh and this will run all the cell.
And perfect.
Now we have are as VM Morrow with a linear kernel with all the default values of the parameters here
except this one linear kernel and so there we go then we have the rest of the cells when we predict
the new result.
Indeed we get the right prediction remember it's 0 for that particular first customer of the test set
of age 30 an estimated salary eighty seven thousand dollars.
Indeed it is predicted not to by the SUV as is the case in reality.
Okay then when we predict the test results once again we see that we have many correct predictions except
some of them.
This one this one and you know this one okay but it looks very good.
However what we're mostly interested in and we're about to get it right now is to see the accuracy on
the test that you know the number of correct predictions or if you want the number of incorrect predictions.
Are you ready.
We're about to get it right now.
Right.
That code sell prints the computing matrix and display the accuracy and wow.
OK.
Interesting.
So it beat actually the logistic regression model right.
Remember the logistic regression model had an accuracy of 89 percent.
And here the SVM slightly beat it by 1 percent.
However it doesn't beat that low key and a model which remember had an accuracy of 93 percent.
All right.
So it doesn't beat it and now we're actually going to understand why why didn't the SVM moral beat the
K and then.
Okay.
So we'll actually figure that out in a bit.
Or actually you know I can just show it to you here on the original implementation of the SVM but you're
going to understand now why it didn't beat it.
Well there you go.
It didn't beat it because once again since we chose a linear kernel Well the prediction boundary or
you know the decision boundary is actually once again a straight line.
And therefore even if you rotate it either this way this way.
Well it won't be able to catch the right prediction for you know these green customers here which should
belong to the green regions.
And same for this one.
You know if we rotate it this way.
Well we will catch these ones but then we will get more incorrect predictions around here.
And if we rotate this way you know from here to here.
Well indeed we will catch these ones in the right prediction region but we will get more incorrect ones
here.
So that's the problem of linear models here.
Indeed it's much better to have a prediction boundary that does some kind of a curve here in order to
catch only the red customers who should be predicted not by the SUV and leave the green ones in the
green region.
All right.
That's exactly what we got with our K nearest neighbors right.
It is not a smooth curve but it did the job of selecting the right red customers here still leading
some green ones but here catching the right green ones in the right region the green region.
And here of course since we have the straight line it's impossible to do.
But no worries I'm sure you have the intuition that once we use a nonlinear kernel well we'll be able
to catch the right green observations here in the right green region and well that's exactly what we'll
find out in the next section when implementing the kernel SVM mode.
All right.
So let's see if we're done here.
Yes we are.
So it's finished to execute and of course we get the same results and let's see for the test set still
running but and Oh wow.
Okay so funny timing.
It just populated here and well you know still the same because of this straight line here.
Well we have some green customers and customers who but in reality a new SUV that couldn't be bricked
it correctly because they fell in the wrong region because of this brazen boundary that can not separate
well are two classes.
All right.
Same problem.
And you know you might guess that this problem will be fixed once we choose a nonlinear kernel for our
support vector machine model.
All right so let's find out about this in the next section on kernel as SVM.
And until then enjoy machine learning.