Hello and welcome back to the course and machine learning I hope you enjoyed the previous tutorials
and that today we're going to talk about the different types of kernel functions.
So the final thing that you need to know about the kernel SVM is that the radial basis function which
also called the Gaussian function is not the only Chornobyl function that is used in this method.
So let's have a look at a couple.
So here we've got the Galson or the RB of Colonel which we've already spoken about.
Then there's also a popular choice which is a sigmoid kernel and that's the former on the right it's
in a bit of a different notation.
But the essence is the same is that you still select a landmark and then then from there depending on
the distance a landmark different results will occur.
But in this case as you can see this kernel of function is directional so anything even like just looking
at in this two dimensional space is just a projection.
You see that anything to the right will be automatically right away will have a high value so will be
included in your classification anything till after will be excluded so sometimes you might require
these situations so maybe if you look at a two dimensional space just imagine those points where we
had points on one side are not in your classification on the other side.
Are you in your classification you want to somehow outline that decision boundary or highlight that
points.
Pauses certain points are should be in your classification then a sigmoid kernel is a popular choice.
Also we've got a polynomial kernel's which are also popular.
One of the more popular choices and here you can have like a pull in arm which dictates how your kernel
behaves.
And you can go into more detail on that.
So this tutorial is not for us to discuss the specifics of each one of these kernels but just to show
you that they exist and help you be aware of the different types.
And so these are the most popular choices.
Galson are B-F sigmoid and polynomial.
And now what are we going to do is we're going to actually go and have a look at them in three dimensions.
I found a really cool Web site where we can have a look at that and we'll go and check it out.
So what I need is here it is.
And so if you go to this Web site which is M-L kernel's dot read the docs dot I O slash and slash later
slash kernel functions that age HTML.
You'll see some wonderful pictures here so if you scroll down you'll be able to find some very interesting
different types of kernels in a three dimensional space so you need to read more about the way they
design them.
And you know how the formulas work so they're a bit different to what we discussed.
But nevertheless the kernel This gives you a good overview of the kernel functions that exist and that
you know sometimes are used.
Probably the ones the three that we highlighted would be more than enough for most scenarios that you
might come across but it's always always good to know that other types of kernels also exist and they
are available to.
So there's a sigmoid kernel which we talked about as well.
So hopefully that's going to be a good overview for you as well.
And now I'm going to wrap up this tutorial on that note.
Hope you enjoyed learning about the kernel SVM and I'll look for the next time.
Until then happy analyzing