Hello my friends.
So are you ready to visualize a linear regression results and the polynomial regression results to indeed
understand that the polynomial regression model is way more adapted to nonlinear datasets meaning two
datasets with non-linear relationships.
All right let's do this.
Let's create a new coat cell.
And now you actually know what to do.
I should've told you in the proofs tutorial to try to do it yourself first.
Because we're going to code exactly the same as.
Remember this piece of code we implemented to visualize the results of the simple linear regression
model.
But it's okay.
Let's do it together now quickly.
So remember the first thing that we have to do is call the matte plot lib dot by plot module which has
a shortcut P L T.
Then from this module we're going to call first the scatter function which will allow to first you know
display on a 2D plot the different points of coordinates containing the real results.
You know the real position level's going from 1 to 10.
And the real salaries.
So that's what we are planning first and then we'll plot the predictions.
And so while here we have two input for the coordinates of these real points containing the real position
levels in real salaries and on the x axis we have of course the position levels.
Therefore the x coordinates will be X you know all the position levels contained in X and then on the
y axis will have the salaries the real ones and therefore the y coordinates will be Y.
All right.
And then remember we need to add a color and we'll choose like last time red.
Perfect.
So that's for the real results.
And now we're gonna plot the predictions and to do that.
Well we're gonna call P LTE again motility type plot from which we're gonna call the plot method because
this time we're actually going to plot that regression line you know in blue like in simple in our regression
and then for polynomial regression you will see that it's not aligned but it will be actually a curve
and still we will use the plot function for that.
So again we have to enter the coordinates of the different points of this line and for these coordinates
Well first the x coordinates are still X the position levels but then the y coordinates will be of course
the predicted salaries you know instead of the real salaries and to get them well we simply to call
our line rank object Nuttall in red to you know Limerick to his for the polynomial regression model
Lynn regs for the linear regression model.
And so Lynn rank from which we're gonna call that predict method applied of course to X right.
Containing the position levels of the matrix of features X..
All right and then we add a color and like last time will choose the color blue.
All right blue and then we'll just improve or enhance our graph by adding a title and x level and a
Y label.
And finally displayed so you know how to do this.
We call first party then the title function.
So here we're going to add a funny title like in quotes of course truth or fluff.
Right.
This is the simple scenario I invented for this case study and then we're going to precise that it's
linear regression.
You know the linear regression model.
Okay.
Good good title now an X label.
So here again fealty that X label and we'll choose you know something simple like position level.
Okay perfect.
Then a y label.
So I'm calling the Y label function and we're going to enter salary because on the y axis are all the
salaries the real ones or the predictive ones.
And finally remember that we have to show the graph by using this show function perfect.
And there we go.
Where are you ready to visualize a linear regression results.
Are you ready.
I'm going to close this so that we can see it very well.
All right let's make sure I didn't make any mistake.
Yeah it seems all good.
So now let's press play.
And here we go.
This is the linear regression results.
Let's scroll down a bit.
All right.
So first of all to recap the red points here are the real salaries you know going from zero to I think
one million for the CEO.
Yes.
Okay so these are all the real salaries of this column.
Okay.
And then the blue line is of course the regression line containing all our predictions but the predictions
of the linear regression model.
So first of all we can see that indeed the linear regression model is not well adapted to this dataset
because indeed remember that in simple in our regression it was well adapted because each time you know
for each of the values of the features Well the prediction was close to the real result.
But here for many position levels you know for many values of the future.
Well the prediction is far from the real result here.
For example it is quite far from the real salary.
Imagine if we wanted to use that model to predict if someone is saying the truth or bluffing about a
salary that is contained here.
Well you know we would have offered a way higher salary than we would be supposed to.
So that would not be the best negotiation.
OK.
So that linear regression model is not well adapted.
And same here.
It is far from the prediction.
Same here far from the prediction here it's okay.
But you know that's only for two points.
Two salaries.
But then here it's super far from operation and here as well.
So clearly not well adapted.
And that's why I want to show you this because now you're going to see that the pulling the mere regression
results are gonna be much better.
And now I'm gonna show this to you right away.
I'm going to close this and we're going to visualize binomial regression results efficiently by taking
this code because you're going to see that it's going to be almost the same.
So I'm going to scroll down ask crawled back up to compare create a new coat cell basing that here and
now according to you what do we have to change here.
Actually something important.
Please press buzz on the video now and try to figure out before I give you the solution.
What you have to replace here in order to visualize polynomial regression results.
I really want you to think because it's not that easy it is easy.
But you know it's not like what you would think at first sight.
So please press pause in the video and make that change in order to make it work for polynomial regression
results.
All right.
Okay.
Now I'm going to tell you the solution.
Well first of course we have to change our regressive here because we want to use our polynomial regression
model which is based on Lin rig too.
So that's the first change Limerick to yes.
And now in the British method do you think we need to keep X or change that by something else.
Well of course we can't keep X because remember X is only that matrix of single feature containing the
position levels.
Remember that when we use the Lin rect to regress her which is the linear aggressor it has to be applied
to the transformed matrix of features X into this matrix of features at the different powers you know
position level then squared position level.
And then the other powers here we only chose N equals two so far so we only have the squared position
levels.
But that's exactly what you need to change here.
You can't keep X because it is the single feature.
So you need to input here that transformed matrix of features X containing the different powers of that
single feature position level.
And that's of course exactly this pulley rag veterans for method applied to this matrix of single feature
x.
So I'm copying this and that's exactly what we have to input inside this predict method.
You understand.
So that was the little thing not to forget.
And now you're all good.
You're ready to have a beautiful visualization of the polynomial regression results.
Let's just replace this linear here by Bob Lee normal.
And now 100 percent ready.
Let's visualize the polynomial regression results.
And there you go.
Now we have indeed a way more adaptive regression curve coming indeed much closer to the real result.
You know the real salaries indeed if we compare two.
I'm going to zoom out a bit so we can see both of them at the same time.
There we go.
So if we compare these points where we had issues previously with the linear regression model well we
can clearly see now that the issue is resolved because indeed the predictions on this blue curve come
way closer to the real salaries and this is only with N equals two.
I'm going to show you then that with higher powers and equals three or four.
Well we will get even better results and I'm going to actually show this to you right away.
So now what we're going to do is well we're going to keep this but we're going to remove this because
we're going to retrain the polynomial regression model with a higher degree.
Let's take for example you can try with three but we're going to directly try with four.
So there you go.
I'm going to remove the output retrain the pulling them a regression model on the whole dataset with
therefore this time a degree of 4 which means that the polynomial regression equation will be salary
equals B zero plus B one times position level plus B two times position level square plus B three times
position level all of the power of three plus before times position level the power for that will be
the new Polynomial regression equation And so therefore let's retrain its let's build this new Polynomial
regression moral by just running this cell again.
All right.
Now we have it and now very simply we're going to visualize the new Polynomial Russian results by clicking
this sell here and now as you can see now the polynomial regression model is perfectly fitting.
This data set.
So here we clearly have over filling but that's okay.
Only in this situation because we want to have a perfect prediction of the salary between position level
6 and 7.
Okay.
And now one final thing because I really want you to have the best results and best visualizations.
Indeed as you can see here what happened is that only some straight lines were plotted between each
consecutive points of the data set right.
And therefore that makes this curve not as smooth as we would hope for.
So I actually prepared another code but which we want code together because this is just for the sake
of having a more beautiful curve.
So we're going to get it from the original implementation.
It is actually right here you see visualizing the pulling them a regression results for a higher resolution
and smoother curve.
So I'm going to take all this code and then paste it in our copy of the implementation right here in
New Kotel and you will see that we will get indeed a much smoother and more beautiful curve as you can
see right.
And the trick to plot this curve I'm going to explain this quickly is just to instead of taking you
know the integer is zero one two three four five six seven eight nine ten.
Well we increase the density of these points by taking not only these integers but you know one one
point one one point two one point three one point four up to you know nine point one nine point two
nine point eight nine point nine ten.
That's what this 0.01 means.
That's what we call this step.
All right.
So you have to understand this.
You can if you want but this is something you will probably do only once in your life because I remind
that usually your datasets will have many features.
And here I only took one picture in order to show you the results on a graph because you know if we
had many features I couldn't show this to you because we would have way too many dimensions.
So don't worry too much about it.
OK.
But just appreciate the result.
Right.
We have a very well trained and therefore very well fitted but over fitted model for this data set.
But that's fine because then indeed we will be able to get an amazing and accurate prediction to figure
out if there is truth or bluff.
So that's what we'll do in this next and last tutorial we will first predict that salary of the position
level six point five with linear regression and then with polynomial regression I really encourage you
to try to do it on your own first because it's actually not that difficult.
The only new thing that you'll have to figure out will be to well figure out how to predict a single
observation instead of a whole matrix of features of the test set.
But really if at least you try well you will definitely improve your python skills.
So good luck.
And I can't wait to see you in the next material to find out about that prediction.
And until then enjoy machine learning.