Hello and welcome to this art Tauriel today we're going to implement support vector machine or more
commonly called SVM.
And after having implemented it on python we were going to do it on our.
So let's quickly set the folder as working directory machinary easy part 3 classification SBM.
And here we are make sure that you have this social network and starts your file and then you can click
on this more button here to set the folder as a working directory.
All good.
Now we're going to go to our classification template that we made in the logistic regression section
.
So let's take everything from here to the end copy and let's face it in our SVM file.
Here we go.
Now we need to change very few things.
So first we need to create or classify here which is going to be the SVM transfer of course and then
we just need to change the title here for the craft the training search results.
So we're going to specify that it's the SVM classifier same for the test set here as of yet.
And now let's move back up to create our classifier.
OK.
So as usual we are going to import a library and this time the library is going to be the most popular
library that is used for SVM which is the library.
It turned 71.
So there are actually two very popular library ads intensive anyone and current lab.
And actually I tried them both.
We had 10 kind of the same results.
So you can try the other one to her lab.
It's actually almost the same parameters.
You just have to press F1 to look at the parameters on to K SVM because the function for current that
is k SVM and you could check it out.
But right now we're going to do it with each 71.
So let's do this first let's have a look at the packages here.
Check out to see if you have the Eton 71 library it is installed on my arse because I used to do a lot
of times but if you installed our For the first time then you might not have it.
So I'm going to just write this command here.
For those of you who need to install it so install packages.
Here it is.
And then in parenthesis you put in quotes the name of the library which is named this way.
Ten seventy 71.
All right.
So if you select an exit to this line it will install the package.
I won't do it because it's already installed but it will do it.
I promise you.
So I'm going to put that comment there.
And now let's start creating or classifier.
Well first we need to know that this line library turned 71 and that in case you want to make some automated
script that select automatically your library here because this won't be selected all the time.
So you want to make sure that you select it.
And now we are going to create our SVM class.
So as usual we are going to call our classifier classifier equals.
And then here we're going to use very simply the function as V.
And so let's do this as V.
And then let's press F1 to look at the parameters F1 and here are the parameters the arguments.
So the first argument is formula.
So let's add it.
So as usual it's the formula that is the dependent variable expressed using Attila with respect to all
your independent variables which you represent by a dot.
So here we're just going to add formula equals.
So first we take our dependent variable which is purchased all right and now we used to still the here
and then a dot dot meaning that we're taking all the independent variables of our data set.
OK.
Now come up to go to the next argument then the next argument is data.
So of course that's the data on which you want to train your classifier on which you want your class
for you to learn the data to make the future classification.
And of course this data is our training set.
Okay perfect come to.
Let's go to the next argument the next argument is X and Y but we don't really care about that.
And however we do care about the time here and the kernel because the type as you notice there is two
types of as V.M. there is that as V and for classification and the as we are for regression which is
kind of the same support vector machines algorithm but there is one for classification and one for regression
.
So here with this argument type you choose the classification then the default type for classification
is see classification.
So that's the one we're going to choose for type.
So let's add here type equals C classification are right and now the last very important argument is
the kernel.
So we're starting with the basics we're starting with the most simple as V M which is the Linnie are
as V.M..
So here we're going to choose to a linear our kernel the linear kernel and then we're going to try some
more sophisticated SVM with some gaussian kernel.
So I will let you find out about the surprise you can actually try to practice by yourself and play
around with the different kernels if you want to you know do the course in advance.
That's actually a very good thing to do a course in advance and then watched a course to compare your
work with the content of the course.
But for now we are going to choose a linear kernel's so he will improve the kernel equals Linna.
All right and that's all.
With these four arguments our CROSSFIRE is ready as VM classifier is ready.
So we're going to select the different steps over our sections of our code.
So let's first select this one to preprocess the data.
Here it is.
OK so perfect we have a data set.
Here are trainset and our test set.
So dataset contains 400 observations which are informations about users of a social network including
the age and the estimated salary in this column purchased here tells.
If yes or no the user bought a car when the user got the ad that the car company put on the social network
for marketing campaign purposes.
And so our transfer as usual is going to try to classify the users into the two categories.
Yes they bought the car and no they didn't buy the car.
OK so let's go back to our classifier.
So the pre-processing is done and now we're going to create a classifier.
Everything should go well and I'll have to select this because mine was already selected.
So let's press command control plus enter to execute.
And here it is cast failure created.
All good.
OK.
Now we can make some predictions of new observations which are here to test that observation so let's
do it.
White bread white bread.
All right so let's have a look at why bread.
Why KRAD.
So these are all the predictions of the tested observations that is for each user of the test sets or
classify or predicts if the user buys the SUV or not.
So let's compare the predictions with the truth which are contained in the set.
So this column tells the truth about whether users but yes or no.
The SUV and this are the predictions there is are as VM transfer of predicted whether each user bought
one or the SUV.
So let's look at for example the Web.
OK.
So all these first guys here were predicted not to buy the SUV.
We have all zeroes until the 103.
But here as you can see we have some guys who actually bought the SUV in reality is the 18 19 20 and
22 there are classified predicted that they didn't buy it.
And the truth is that they actually bought it.
So that's incorrect predictions.
But let's look at the incorrect predictions in a more efficient way by looking at the confusion matrix
.
So let's select this line here and execute.
And now let's find out about the real number of incorrect predictions.
So let's stop C.M. here in the council and press enter.
And wow that's actually a quite large number of incorrect predictions.
And by the way we don't intend the same results as in Python because we have some random factors in
the model and here we didn't specify seat so you might actually have some different results.
But the ideas here.
So OK so let's look at now the graph to see how it's doing.
So for those of you who actually didn't watch the Python tutorial about as V.M. a good exercise is to
try to guess what's going to happen.
That is what we're going to be the prediction regions where what is going to be the prediction boundary
.
What do you guess you will see.
So I will let you think for a second.
You can pass on the video and right now I'm going to tell you.
So as you notice we chose a linear kernel which means that are as being classified as a linear classifier
.
So as I explained in the logistic regression tutorials on Python and are well a linear classifier in
2D dimensional space is a straight line.
So here I'm telling you this right now we're going to get a straight line not to get any disappointment
because I know we proved our model with a cane and before we obtained good prediction boundary that
cut you know those users on the bottom right corner that's actually but the SUV but who were incorrect
predations for logistic regression.
Well here it's also going to be some indirect protection for the linearize VM because it's actually
a linear classifier.
So let's look at the results right now.
Select this and press command control press enter to execute
.
And here are the results.
OK.
So as you can see that's exactly what I just told you.
You know those users here with a lower salary and higher age well they actually bought the SUV in reality
because the points are green the points are the real observations but they fell into the red region
here because since the Lynbrook testifiers a straight line it couldn't you know made some kind of curve
here to catch all the red points into the right place and therefore it caught some green points putting
them in the red region.
So yeah that's exactly the same as for logistic regression.
Sorry about the disappointment but don't worry in the next section we will introduce a new kind of Caspari
which will be well the kernel as VM with a different color than Lindauer kernel.
It's going to be a gaussian kernel or even we can try some more kernels where you can practice that
yourself.
It can be very good practice for you.
Let's hear yes it's a linear testifiers So basically it's the same as logistic regression.
And if we look at the test that result is going to be the same let's have a look.
And here is the test set.
OK.
So yeah same thing here we have some users of higher age and lower estimated salary but yes U-V but
fell into the red region again because our class very is a straight line and that's the best you could
do to classify those two points and place them into the corresponding category.
So a few incorrect predictions here a few incorrect additions here.
And if you want you can count the number of incorrectly actions that is the number of green points in
the red region plus the number of red points in the green region and you will count the number of incorrect
predictions we found in the confusion matrix which was 20 incorrect predictions.
That's great that we have this result because that gives us the motivation to improve our classifier
improve our model.
And that's what we're going to do in the next section.
So I look forward to seeing you in the next section and show you how we can substantially improve our
classification model.
So I look forward to showing you the next level.
And until then enjoy machine learning