Hello my friends.
All right.
How did you do with the little exercise here predicting the test set results.
So based on what we've just done in the previous tutorial you know in training the simple in regression
or on the training set and also based on the hint I gave you you know this predict method well you should
have been able to crack this.
All right now we're going to implement a solution together starting by creating this new code cell.
All right.
So first let's just expand what we want to do here.
We want to predict the results of the observations in the test set.
And so let me show you once again the data set.
So that's the whole dataset containing the 30 observations.
And we actually split this data set into the training set and it set the test size was chosen to be
open to meaning that 20 percent of all these observations went into the test set.
So 20 percent of 30 is actually six.
So let's say just to simplify the explanation that the observations of the test set are the last six
ones.
You know one two three four five six.
So let's say all these observations went into the test set.
Well what we want to do now is predict for each of these observations meaning for each of these employees
the salary.
Right.
So what we're going to input in that predict method is exactly the number of years of experience for
each of these six employees and our moral will predict the salaries.
So the salaries that we see here you know the last six ones are the exact salaries you know the truth.
We call it The Ground Truth.
And when calling the predict method on these six numbers of years of experience we will get six predicted
salaries.
And so what will want to do then will be to compare the predicted salaries to these real six salaries.
OK.
And we will do that in a less steps of this implementation when visualizing not only the test results
but also the training set results you you're going to see everything will be super clear.
All right so let's do this let's get the test results by first you know in order to call a method.
We first need to call the object itself which is regressive.
So that was the first step you had to do here then from our object we add a dot here and we call the
function we want.
Oh wow it's funny.
The Google could have actually guessed what I was about to call.
That's.
I never noticed that but anyway.
Yeah that's perfect.
We want to use the predict method of course.
Now what's the hint.
And this brick method you know as any function expects some arguments.
And so now according to you what does we have input in this predict method.
Well that's simple.
Once again you know we want to enter the features meaning numbers of years of experience and not the
salaries that were just for the training set.
Here we only need the numbers of experience because from the numbers of experience we want to predict
the salaries and the numbers of experience are exactly contained in x test.
Right.
Because we want the numbers of experience of the test set.
And so the only thing we had input here is access.
And there you go.
That was the solution.
OK.
So as you can see once again very easy.
That's the beauty of the libraries.
You can just do anything you want in usually one or two or three lines of code.
And here we just had to call the predict method to make some predictions from a model that is of course
already trained on the training set.
All right.
Now because we are going to visualize then the training that results in a test results I'm actually
going to put all these predictions because this returns actually a vector of predictions you know a
vector containing the predicted salaries of the employees in the test set.
So I would like to put all these British salaries in a vector therefore in a new variable and therefore
here I am creating this new variable which I'm calling why Fred you know as opposed to y test which
contains the real salary.
So make sure to understand why test here contains the real salaries and why bread here contains the
predicted salaries.
And now in the next steps we're going to compare white bread to white test and also we'll compare white
train to the predicted salaries in the training set in the last two steps of this implementation visualizing
the trains that results and visualizing the test results we will get amazing graph super clear super
simple to understand and we will clearly see how well our model was trained with this visualization
and how well amo was able to predict new observations with this visualization.
So let us do this in the next sartorial.
And until then enjoy machine learning.