Hello and welcome to this art tutorial Center following tutorials we're going to implement the a priori
algorithm and as you know we are going to make this machine learning model to create some added value
in some specific business.
And in this part this business problem is going to be about optimizing the sales in a grocery store
or grocery store in the south of France and you're going to perfectly understand how the a priori algorithm
is going to do a perfect job at doing this optimizing the sales.
Because recently a lot of stores considerably created some added value things to machine learning and
especially Association rule learning by using it to optimize the sales of their products.
And how did they do that.
Well they just used Association rule learning to know exactly where to place the product in the store
.
You know for example I'll give you a very simple example.
If someone buys some cereals Well the same person is very likely to buy some milk as well.
So by placing the cereals close to the milk the store is very likely to put these two products into
the same basket even if the buyer originally intended to only buy cereals or I can give you a more general
example suppose a person wants to buy a specific product.
Let's call it product A.
And this product can be associated very well to another product B and the person who wants to buy the
product.
A minor.
Think of this good association between the product and the product B.
Well if you place the product in the product be next to each other.
Well the association can suddenly pop up in the buyer's mind so that you know the buyer can tell hey
that's actually a good combination.
Why don't I try these two for my next lunch or something.
And so again even if the buyer was originally meant to buy only the product.
Well Judy this association that popped up in its mind thanks to the placement of product and product
to be next to each other.
Well the buyer finally buys a two parent A and B.
So that's the idea of how we can create added value for retail stores or grocery stores.
And so what we'll make in this future tutorials to optimize the sales can be also applied to any other
store that is selling some different products.
You can think of an online store.
You know these recommendations people who bought this also bought that.
Well these recommendations are based on association rules as well but not only it can be also the result
of recommendation systems like collaborative filtering or a custom based item based collaborative filtering
.
Association will learning has a role to play.
So now let's make our first association rule and an algorithm which is the a priori model for this specific
store in the south of France.
So let's do it.
As usual we're going to set the working directory by going to our new part folder which is the fall
of Part Five Association rote learning and we're starting with the a priori algorithm.
So that's the fall that we want to set as we can direct remission that you have the market basket optimizations
he has found and you can click on this more button here and then set as working directory.
All right.
We're on the rifle now.
So the first thing we're going to do is to import the dataset so the dataset is marking back at optimization
so as usual we were going to call it data sets.
And then of course we're going to use to read that as we function.
And now we simply put in quotes the name of the city.
So here we go.
Market Basket optimization dot CSC.
All right so let's execute that and let's explain what the dataset is about.
Here we go.
They said well imported it has seven thousand five hundred observations and 20 variables.
So let's check it out and clicking on dataset here.
All right.
And that is Dasent.
So the first thing that we can see here is that this line here contains some products.
These products here and of course these are not the titles of the different comps here.
So to improve this what we can first do is to add this Hetter argument here had are equals and then
simply false this way and that tells are that the first line of our data set doesn't contain the titles
of the columns.
So let's check it out now.
That's like this line and execute.
Here we go.
Let's close this and click again on the dataset.
And here we go.
We don't have any titles for the columns but you know this first observation is no longer seen as the
titles of the columns.
That's the real observation itself.
OK.
So better now let's describe the data set.
So as I told you we're making this a priori model for a store in the south of France.
And so we want to find out the association rules of the different products of this tour to see how the
manager of the store can optimize the placement of its different products to optimize the sales.
OK.
So the first thing to say now is that this store is located in one of the most popular places in the
south of France.
So a lot of people go into the store and so you know this place is a very convivial place a very friendly
place where people love to hang out relax talk to each other.
And so these people come very often to this tour because even if it's not by something it's a place
to meet their friends and therefore the manager of the store noticed and calculated that on average
each customer goes and buys something to the store once a week.
So this dataset here contains the seven thousand five hundred transactions of all the different customers
that bought a basket of products during a whole week.
Indeed the manager took it as the basis of its analysis because since each customer is going an average
once a week to the store then the transaction registered over a week is quite representative of what
customers want to buy.
So based on all these 7500 transactions our machinery model our a priori model is going to learn the
different associations it can make to actually understand the rules.
Such as if customers buy this product then they're likely to buy this other set of products.
So that's what we want to figure out and that's what our pre-read model will tell us.
OK.
So each observation line here corresponds to a specific customer who bought a specific basket of product
.
So for example if you look at line two here that corresponds to one customer who bought burgers meatballs
and eggs at a specific time of this week.
And that's the same for all the other observations that correspond to other customers.
Or maybe the same customer who went back to the store another day or another time.
So that's what today is about.
But actually this is not the set.
We're going to use to train our apriori model.
And the reason is that the package we're going to use to build our Priore model which is by the way
the Avril's package doesn't take a dataset like this as input.
It doesn't take a C as we felt that we import.
Thanks to the redone cxxviii function what it takes as input is called a sparse matrix.
And so what is a sparse matrix.
It's actually a matrix that contains a lot of zeroes in machinery and you will encounter a lot of times
the word sparsity that corresponds to a large number of zeros.
So a sparse matrix is a matrix containing a very few number of non-zero values.
So what we're going to do now is transform this dataset here into a sparse matrix and can you guess
what we're going to do.
Well what you're going to do is take all the different products of this data set.
And actually I already know that there are a hundred and twenty products and we are going to attribute
one column to each of these 120 products.
So that means we'll get a hundred and twenty columns.
So for example.
So for example we'll have to call them Shrem they call them almonds to call them avocado to call them
vegetables mix Karachi's energy drink tomato juice up to the 100 and 20th product that there is we're
going to see all the products then on a plot.
But in this area said there are a hundred and twenty products which are by the way the one hundred and
twenty products of the store.
So there is going to be one going for each of these products and that's going to be the columns.
And then the lines are still going to be the different transactions corresponding to each of the 7500
customers that bought a basket of products during the whole week.
But instead of having the list of the product they bought We will have in each of the 120 columns here
a zero or one.
And it's going to be a 1 if the product is in the basket of the customer during its transaction and
is zero if the product is not in the basket.
So for example let's take the second customer here.
The second customer bought a basket of three product burgers meat balls and eggs.
OK.
So in our sparse matrix we'll have one burgers call them 1 meatballs call and 1 x call them.
They're not necessarily going to be next to each other.
You know burgers can be the fifth column and meatballs can be Neyens call them an X can be 12 Scullin
that depends on how the Avril's package is going to make the matrix but we will have a column for each
of these three products.
And so in these columns since the customer number two bought some burgers meatballs and eggs there will
be a one in each of these columns that will be a one in the burbs column or one in the meatballs column
and the one in the X column and all the rest of the columns are going to have a zero value.
And that's because all the other products were not in the basket of this customer number two.
So you can guess you can imagine that we're going to have a lot of zero values and that's even more
true considering the fact that we have a lot of customers that bought baskets of only one product.
For example this customer number 10 here bought some French fries.
This one bought some cookies this one bought some mineral water.
So you know for these three customers who bought only one product we're going to have only one column
that contains a non-zero value and all the other columns that means all the 119 Collins will contain
zeros.
So you can see that we're going to have a lot of zeroes in this matrix.
And so for those of you who are discovering sparsity I'm happy to introduce you to sparse matrices so
let's build this sparse matrix right now.
You'll see that it's going to be very easy.
So let's go back to our code and let's create the sparse matrix.
So to create the sparse matrix we're going to use a package of course and this package is the Avril's
package.
So we are going to install that as important.
So as usual we're going to take the function install packages and then in parenthesis we just input
the name of the package in quotes and that's the Avril's package.
All right.
So let's check to see if I have it.
Well I already know I have it.
It's actually already here and already imported.
So that's the Avril's package for which the description says that it's Mining Association rules and
frequent item sets.
OK so mine is already installed so I'm not going to execute this line.
I'll just put in comment.
And so if you don't have the Avril's package here in the package just list you need to select this line
and execute.
And this will install the package without any issue.
And as far as I'm concerned I'm just going to put that in.
Right and to make sure that the rules package is well imported.
We need to add the line here library and in parenthesis Avril's already there.
Perfect.
And that makes sure that if you execute the whole script the Avril's package will be imported.
And now we were ready to create our sparse matrix.
So since our data set has no use here because we're not going to use it to build and train our printer
model we will call our sparse matrix again dataset again and to create the sparse matrix It's actually
almost the same as importing ACSU file because instead of writing here read that says we we simply need
to type read dot transactions read that transactions and then it's the same in parenthesis we need to
input the name of the CSP file.
So we'll copy that and paste it here.
That's the first documents but then we need to specify to this function that the separator of our CHB
file is actually a comma.
So we need to add here cept the calls in quotes comma.
And why do we need to do this it's because you know RACF we file if you open it with a text editor you
will see that the different products are separated by a comma.
And we actually didn't have to specify that the separator was coming here because that's the default
separator of the reductions V function.
But that's not the default separator of the reductions actions function.
So that's why we need to specify here.
So set equals come up and actually we could start here.
But since I promised you to give you real life data sets I added on purpose and reality in the data
sets.
And this reality is about having some anomalies in the data and these anomalies are actually some duplicates
.
Indeed when this manager register all the different transactions.
Well he might have been very likely to make some human mistakes to put some duplicates in the data.
So for example if we go back to our dataset.
So that's the whole data that's important that's his view with the readout function.
And so for example when this transaction of the 30 first customer was registered one can make some mistake
of putting twice like cream here for example and to train the a priori algorithm we need to have no
duplicate.
So there is actually a good way to handle these duplicates.
It's actually very simple because we just need to add an additional argument.
If we look at the readout transactions function here by pressing one you can see that our end of duplicate
arguments.
And as you can see it's a logical value specifying if duplicate items should be removed from the transactions
.
So since the a priori algorithm is trained on transaction data set they're supposed to have no duplicate
values.
We need to add this argument or and don't duplicate and set it to true.
And that will remove all the duplicates in each of the transactions.
Maybe your dataset won't have any duplicates but it's very common to have a few anomalies in dataset
such as some duplicates.
But here we will be fine.
Thanks to our end of the blockade argument.
All right so we're now actually ready to create our sparse matrix.
So let's do this let's execute this line and here we go.
All right.
So now the sparse matrix is created.
Unfortunately we cannot have a look at it as you can see if I click on these days here.
The new dataset sparse matrix is not appearing here.
That's actually the old one so we can close this but we can actually get some info about this sparse
matrix.
But before getting all these detailed information well we can see that we already have some information
about the duplicate itself.
When you execute this line to create your sparse matrix with the reduction sections function including
our end of duplicates arguments you will automatically have this message distribution of transaction
with duplicate and you'll see that we have 1 5.
That means that there are five transactions containing one duplicates.
And for example if in your dataset you have some triplicates duplicates there appear twice in any transaction
.
Well you will have two here and you will have the number of triplicates here.
So that just gives the distribution of transaction with duplicates.
And anyway now they're removed.
So we can actually get some more detailed info about the sparse matrix and to get this info.
We as we already did many times before need to use the summary function.
So summary.
And here we input data set.
All right.
And that will give us some info about the sparse matrix so let's execute this line.
And here we go.
So what do we see here.
First we reminded that this dataset contains transactions as I have a matrix in sparse format so that
exactly means that a sparse matrix and we can see that we have seven thousand five hundred and one rows
and we have 119 columns and we can see that we have a density of 0.03 in the sparse matrix and what
does that mean.
That means that the proportion of non-zero values is 0.03.
We have 3 percent non-zero values and 97 percent 0 values.
Ok then we have the most RIKOON items.
So the item that is the most bought is mineral water.
Yes it can be very hot in the south of France and it's a good French tradition to have a bottle of water
during meals.
OK then the French love very much eggs they love spaghetti French fries chocolate and that's all the
other products.
And then we have some interesting information about the distribution of the baskets of all the 7500
transactions.
So for example here this one associated to 1754 means that there were 1754 baskets containing only one
product and then we have 1358 baskets containing two products 1044 baskets containing three products
et cetera.
And we also have the quintiles of this distribution with the minimum value the maximum value.
So the minimum value is of course a basket of one product the maximum value is a basket of 20 products
and on average people put four products in their basket when they go to the store.
All right.
So that's interesting information.
But of course we'll get some even more interesting information afterwards.
And speaking of these more interesting informations we can already have one now.
It's actually going to be visual information because we're going to make a frequency plot of the different
products bought by the different customers in the store during this whole week.
And so to get this plug very easily we can use one function of the Avril's package which is the item
frequency plot function and in this function we just need to put two arguments which is going to be
the data set.
So that's the sparse matrix.
That's the first argument and the second argument is tough.
And and that's the number of the most solid products you want to have in this frequency plot.
So for example if I put up any calls 100 I will get the 100 most purchased product by the French customers
in this French store.
So let's check it out.
We're going to execute this line.
Here we go.
And that's the plug.
Don't worry I'm going to zoom on it so that we can see better the products.
And here we go.
So that's the first 100 products most purchased by the customers.
So that's kind of interesting and if you want to have less product in this plot you can just look at
the top 10 and you'll get actually the first 10 products purchased by the customers which are of course
the same first 10 products.
OK.
So this plot is actually going to be interesting for us.
What's coming next because we will have to choose a value for the support according to the Priory algorithm
itself and we will be able to actually use this plot to look at different supports of the product to
choose a good value for support.
So that's what we're going to do in the next tutorials.
We're going to start training our a priori model on our data set which is going to be the sparse matrix
here that we just built.
And so I look forward to building the a priori model with you.
And until then enjoy machine learning