All right my friends.
I'm ready.
Are you ready to build that dance program and use it to find the optimal number of clusters.
Here we go.
Us implement a solution together.
So let's start by creating a new code cell.
And now what will be the first step.
Well as usual you know we want to implement this efficiently.
So we're going to use a function but this time exceptionally this function won't be imported from psychedelia
and it will actually be imported from another very popular library in data science.
I would say you know it is in the top three most popular libraries I put Scotland first of course and
tend to flow for deep learning but that other library is side by side by contains a lot of great tools
when building machinery models and well for hierarchical clustering it indeed contains a function which
is called Ten program and which will return the tangible gram itself.
You know the plot of the DNA program.
So let's do this let's directly import that you know module first that contains this function.
And as we said this model is taken first from side by then from the module cluster and then from the
sub module High are key.
Right.
Google collab guess guesses it perfectly the other way to write this is of course to say from side by
import cluster that hierarchy.
So that's just another writing.
And then we're going to add of course a shortcut to this.
Otherwise we need to call all of this again and the shortcut will be as S C H right for site by cluster
hierarchy.
Okay.
So that's the module which contains the function we want to use in order to build our DNA program.
So now next step.
Well the next step is to use that function which we can now access from that hierarchy module which
we just import it.
And since this function returns directly the danger gram itself.
Well we are going to create a new royal here which we're going to call then draw grab as simple as that.
And this Daniel Graham variable will be the output of this Dan program function which we're about to
use from the hierarchy sub module by the cluster module from the site by library.
All right.
So let's do this.
Since this function belongs to all of this here you know the hierarchy module.
Well we have to call first the shortcut leading to that module.
SDH and from which now we can call this then draw Graham function.
Perfect.
Thank you so much Google collab.
And now indeed in the parenthesis we have to input some arguments.
And now you can't really guess what the arguments will be so I'm just going to write it and then I will
explain what this means.
So first we actually have to call s c h again.
You know the hierarchy module from the cluster module from the site by library.
So SDH from which this time we're gonna call another function which is the linkage function and this
linkage function will take as input to arguments first.
Well your matrix of features inside which you want to identify the clusters and that's of course X and
then the second argument is the clustering technique and in hierarchical clustering the most recommended
method and the one that brings the most relevant results and the most relevant clusters is the method
of minimum variance which is a technique that will result in having clusters inside which you know the
observation points.
DONVAN Right too much you know half among all of them a low variance.
And that's what it means you know the method of minimum variance consists of minimizing the variance
in each of the clusters resulting from hierarchical clustering.
And so this is really the method that I recommend.
And speaking of this method that's exactly the next argument of this linkage function we have to input
here and the name of that parameter is method and the name of that minimum variance method is not called
minimum variance but ward Ward.
You can actually check this on Wikipedia.
There is a whole page on Ward and you will see that indeed and consists of minimizing the variance inside
your clusters.
All right.
And that's it for the whole Daniel Graham function here.
It only expects one argument which is basically the method you choose for your clustering that you link
to your matrix of features X in which you want to identify the clusters.
So that's all you need to input here in this Daniel Graham.
And there you go.
This will already return the danger gram itself you know the plot of the Daniel Graham.
But as usual we want to make it nice.
So we're just gonna add a title an X label and a Y label and then we will show it.
And I will teach you how to read the Dan program to indeed find that optimal number of clusters.
Are you ready.
Let's do this.
Let's do this quickly.
We're going to first add a title you know with the title function by Matt pipelines and this time let's
say you know we're just going to choose a simple title like Senator Graham.
All right then let's add X label.
There you go X label.
And then in quotes.
Well you tell me what is going to be on the x axis.
Let's not fall into the trap of you know answering too quickly you know the x axis is neither annual
income or the spending score you know it's none of the features the x axis in the Dan program is actually
the customers.
You know the observation points basically the x axis are not the columns as I just suggested but the
rows because remember in this matrix X or even the state of set each row corresponds to a customer in
this customer is actually an observation point.
And that's what is on the x axis of Daniel gram.
You have all the observation points you know just given by indexes from one to 200 because we have 200
customers in this dataset.
And then on the y axis What will you have.
Well you will have the Euclidean distances between each pair of customers and then each pair of groups
of customers where the groups get bigger and bigger.
And then by considering bigger and bigger groups you get also the Euclidean distances between two of
these bigger groups.
Right.
That's how the general gram works it will become more clear once we visualize this.
So there you go.
I just wanted to get you to think on what is the X label and the Y label.
So now that we know well let's input here the X label which will be therefore you can either call it
observation points if you want to generalize this or if you want to stay in the context of this case
study well we can call it course Summers.
All right.
Customers that's for the X label and now for the Y label.
Well that will be always the same you know independently of whether we want to stay in that case or
not that's going to be always the you CLI D in distances.
All right.
That's always what is on the y axis in a danger gram.
And finally we end up remember with P LTE that show to indeed display the graph in the output.
All right so now let's check it out.
Let's see that Daniel Graham and I will explain again what we have on the x axis and the y axis.
All right let's do this.
Let's play this cell and we're about to get the Dan program in a second.
There we go.
All right.
So that's our beautiful Daniel gram.
And as we said in the x axis we have the customers listed from 1 to 200 because they're 200 customers
in the data set and on the y axis.
Well we have indeed that.
As you can see Euclidean distances first between each pair of customers that the little pairs you see
here.
And then as you see when you link to customers you know within a same group while this forms a group
and then with the group next to it linking to other customers well you link these two groups within
a new pair and you compute the Euclidean distance between these two groups by you know taking the root
of the sum of the squared distances between the customers inside these groups.
All right.
And you do this for then each pair of bigger groups as we see for example the two biggest groups that
we see on this General Graham are first.
This one you know that first group containing lots of customers.
And the second group is this one right which was linking these two subgroups and then all these sub
subgroups inside.
And so now the question is how do we figure out that optimal number of clusters.
Well it's super simple and to show this I will actually click these three dots here to view the output
in fullscreen but then it's still not enough where I would like to do is now save image as all right
I'm gonna call this image then drew Graham.
Gonna save it.
And now we're gonna go on to my desktop which is right here.
Yes.
I'm recording at night.
And here is the Daniel gram.
So let's see if we can zoom better now.
Whoops.
Let's me let me just.
There you go let me enlarge this.
All right.
Well still not that great but it's good because what I wanted to do is this horizontal line.
That's exactly what I wanted to get which I couldn't get on cola.
And the reason why I wanted to get this horizontal line is because it is what will help us figure out
the optimal number of clusters because very simply on a Daniel gram the optimal number of clusters can
be found where you have the largest distance you can move vertically without touching one of these horizontal
bar.
You know by horizontal bar this is a first horizontal bar.
Then this is the second horizontal bar the third horizontal bar fourth horizontal bar.
And then you know this one is the next one horizontal bar horizontal bar horizontal bar etc. and the
optimal number of clusters can be found where you can move that horizontal line you know the ones that
I'm creating with my mouth and then I'm gonna try to move that vertical bar inside the Daniel gram you
know starting from the top and we'll see where I managed to move the most vertically before meeting
one of these horizontal bar.
So let's do this together and you know we will very easily find where we have the largest vertical move
let's say and then the optimal number of clusters will actually be the number of vertical bars we have
inside that vertical move.
All right.
So let's start from the top.
We have to start from the top.
And so from the top it goes this way we start from here.
That's the first horizontal bar.
And when I move down you know move down like that.
There you go.
That's when I meet the next horizontal bar.
You know this one.
So actually we made a very small vertical distance here which means that indeed the optimal number of
clusters is definitely not too right.
Because here we have two vertical bars.
Then the next step is to start from this second horizontal bar.
And so let's do this with our mouth.
All right.
We start from here.
The second horizontal bar.
And we're going to go down until we meet the next horizontal bar which is right here.
This one right.
That's the second horizontal bar.
This was the first.
And from this first to the second while we made that vertical distance.
OK.
So that's pretty big.
Which means that maybe you know if it is the largest vertical move we can make.
Well in that case the optimal number of clusters would be one two three.
You know the number of vertical bars we have within this vertical move.
This one this one and this one so that would go for three clusters.
All right.
So maybe that's the optimal number of clusters.
But then let's continue let's continue from here.
Right.
So we're going to continue from here.
That last horizontal bar we met.
And now I'm going to expand over here and same we're going to go down until we meet the next horizontal
bar.
And there we go.
That's the next horizontal bar.
And here we made a small vertical distance of definitely it is shorter than the previous vertical distance
we made just before.
And therefore the optimal number of clusters is definitely not one two three and four.
It's definitely not four.
OK.
Okay.
Let's continue maybe there is a higher vertical move we can make in the next step.
And you know exactly that this is going to be the case because we already did k means but there we go.
That's next move.
We start from here that last horizontal bar we met and I'm going to expand this in order to you know
not miss any horizontal bar and actually I should even take the whole width.
You know I should take exactly this.
All right so that we can make sure we don't miss any horizontal bar.
So we start from here.
And here we go.
Let's move down let's move down move down move down move down.
Until we meet the next horizontal bar and here we go.
Right you see that's the next horizontal bar we met the one from that last cluster here and.
Well now the question is is that vertical move you know vertical distance which is made here bigger
than the one we made in the second step.
Meaning this one.
Well it seems to be the case right.
It seems to be that this vertical distance is actually larger than you know this vertical distance.
How could we actually measure this you know to be exactly sure.
Well have a look at you know the pixel here to 64 times 66.
I don't know if you can see it well but if I move up you know remember there were 66.
Well actually zero.
OK.
So that's very easy.
So there are actually 66 pixels here.
All right cool.
And now let's do this again here from that horizontal bar and up to here and wow.
OK.
So that was very short actually because here the vertical distance is actually 67 pixel you see it in
0 2 7 2 times 67 2 7 2 is actually the width of that rectangle I just made with my mouth and 67 is the
height and that's the height where interesting because that corresponds to the distance of the vertical
move.
So actually 67 versus 66.
So.
Well you know three clusters is actually a good number of clusters.
But you know since we already did it with K Means and on the Elbow Method we clearly identified that
the optimal number of classes was five.
Well we're going to take that one difference here.
In order to still keep well five as the optimal number of clusters.
But it's really interesting that we did this 10 program.
I actually didn't notice before that we were so close from my vision I had the impression that this
distance was larger.
But there you go.
This one was also very good.
Let's check in again because I just want to make sure Yes 66 but even 67.
Depends.
Down to where you go exactly in that horizontal bar actually you know to make it super thorough we would
need to start from here you know at the bottom of the horizontal bar up to the top of the next vertical
bar.
So here we have sixty five and here for that next distance.
Well you know I'm starting from the bottom of the horizontal bar and going here sixty five.
The same is the same.
So actually three clusters of five clusters is very good and so feel free to you know continue this
implementation with either three or five.
But since with K Means We identified five clusters as the optimal number of clusters Well we're still
gonna go with five here but there you go.
That's a very good example because indeed in some situations we can have two optimal number of clusters.
All right.
So I'm really glad I showed you this and mostly this shows you the importance of trying several models
whether it is for regression classification clustering because indeed having another Mauro can give
you extra insights when doing your missionary's task and indeed with hierarchical clustering.
That extra insight is that indeed three clusters actually makes a lot of sense as well.
So there you go.
Make sure to keep hierarchical clustering you took it in order to catch these extra insights in your
future data sets for your future clustering problems.
All right.
Perfect.
So let's close this and let's go back to our implementation.
Here it is.
All right.
So to close this well I just pressed escape and there you go.
We have our DNA program.
Everything is perfect.
And now for the next step we're going to train that Hari Aki cool classroom model with as we said five
clusters which you can totally do it with three clusters if you want it will still bring amazing results.
And so let's do this together in the next tutorial.
And until then enjoy clustering and machine learning.