Hello and welcome to this art tutorial.
So we already built two regression models.
It was that simple in our regression and the multiple you know regression and these two models were
linear models and now we are going to the next level because we will start to build non-linear our regression
morals.
So that means that for data sets where there will not be a linear relationship between the independent
variables and the dependent variable these non linear regression models will be very useful.
And speaking of problems with non-linear relationships this is the kind of problems that we will have
to deal with in the future sections.
So in the future sections we will be not linear regression models to solve nonlinear problems and today
in this Statoil we will start with polynomial regression.
So as usual let's prepare the workspace by setting the rightful as working directory.
So right now I'm going to my machinery Naisi folder for two regression then Section polynomial regression
.
And here's the right folder.
Make sure that you have the position satirises the file and you can click on this more button here and
then set as working directory.
And now let's start with the usual first step of making of machine or any model.
So this first step is of course the data processing step.
So to be efficient I'm going to go to my data processing template as we made in part one.
I'm going to select everything in a template.
Copy and paste it in my polynomial regression model this way.
OK.
And now we just need to change a few things.
So the first thing we need to change is the name of the dataset.
So it's not data here.
Data was the name of the data set in the pre-processing part.
But now in this regression part the name of the dataset is position underscores salaries.
So here all right position and the scores salaries.
And now let's select this line and execute to have a look at our data set.
OK.
Now let's see what will be our machine learning mission.
So we are a human resource team working for a big company and we are about to hire a new employee in
this company.
So this new employee seems to be great a good fit for the job and we we're about to make an offer to
his potential new employee.
And now it's time to negotiate negotiate on what is going to be the future salary of this new employee
in the company.
And so at the beginning of the negotiation this new employee is telling that he's had 20 plus years
of experience and eventually earned 160 K annual salary in its previous company.
So this employee is asking for at least more than 160 k.
However there is someone in the H.R. team that is kind of a control freak and always fantasized about
being a detective.
So suddenly decides to call the previous employer to check that info.
You know that info about the previous 160 K annual salary of this future potential new employee but
unfortunately all the info that this person manages to get are these info here.
The simple table of salaries for these 10 different positions in the produce company.
So does a church member of the team runs a simple analysis on Excel or a Google sheet and actually observes
that there is a non linear relationship between these position levels and their associated salaries
.
However And moreover this H.R. guy could get another very relevant info.
This other relevant info is that this new employee that is about to be hired has been a regional manager
for two years now in the previous company and that usually takes on average four years to jump from
being a regional manager to a partner.
So this new employee about to be hired was kind of halfway between Level 6 and level 7 and therefore
we can say he was level 6.5.
So now is a job guys getting all excited because he is selling to the team that he can build a bluffing
detector using regression models to predict if this new employee is bluffing about it sorry.
So at the beginning the team finds it a little weird but it's kind of curious to see what's going to
happen.
So here is the mission.
This new employee that is about to be hired is telling that its annual salary was 160 in the previous
company.
Let's use polynomial regression to build the bluffing detector to predict if it's truth or bluff.
All right.
And now that we get a problem let's see if we need all the data set to train our machine learning model
which by the way is going to be the polynomial regression model.
Remember the machine is the polynomial regression model itself and learning is related to the fact that
this polynomial regression machinery model will learn the correlations between the levels here and the
salaries to predict any new salary of new levels that are not in this table here.
For example we want to predict the salary level 6.5 Well thanks to what our machine learning polynomial
regression model learns on this info here.
It will be able to predict the salary of level 6.5.
Okay.
So we notice that in this dataset this position column is typically equivalent to this level column
you know it's like we already encoded this position column you know by transforming this variable into
numerical variables and therefore will not include this position column in the data set where we will
train our polynomial regression model and we will only use these to call him level and salary so that
the independent variable called in will be this level column and the dependent variable will be the
salary column.
So let's go back to our polynomial regression model and here let's select these two columns we are only
interested in.
So to do this we will reset the data set.
So I'm taking my data set here and again I'm taking my data set than brackets.
And then this brackets here will put the indexes of the columns who want to keep to train our machine
learning mode.
So let's see what these indexes are.
OK so we have three columns indexes and are start at 1.
So this column has an next one.
This column has index 2 and this column has next 3.
So since we want to keep these last two columns then we want to keep the indexes 2 and 3.
OK so let's put that to him.
Put this we can simply input to column three.
Let's check it out.
That's like the slide and executes.
And as you can see now our data sets if we look at it only has these two columns level and salary.
So as a reminder level is the independent variable and salary is the dependent variable.
So we will use the correlations between the levels and the salaries.
To train our non-linear machine learning polynomial regression model to predict some salaries such as
the salary associated to a 6.5 position level.
OK.
So let's go back to the polling regression model.
Our data set is well important now it's well prepared.
We have everything we need.
And now let's move on to the next step.
So the next step is to split the data set into the training set and the test set.
And actually this time and normally this time we will not do that.
And the reason is that we only have 10 observations here.
So this is a very small dataset and by the way I chose this dataset because we're still shaping our
intuition of machine learning we're still learning the basics of machine learning.
And therefore I choose the simple data set because we have two dimensions here so we will be able to
plot the form of the polynomial regression model self as well as the future non-linear regression models
.
OK so let's go back to the model.
And as I just said we won't need to split the data set into the training set in the test set.
So what I'm going to do now is I'm going to put all this section in comments.
So let's do this press command control plus shift plus C and that puts all your selected lines in comments
.
So no trainset and notice that will be created.
OK and the last step now is feature scaling.
And the good news is that we will need features game either.
And the reason is simple it's that because a polynomial regression model is actually a multiple in our
regression model with polynomial terms you know instead of having different features like features that
represent something very different we are taking a first feature which is actually the position levels
from 9:59.
And as the other independent variables that we'll be in are multiple in our regression model we will
take the squares and other exponents of these levels here.
OK so actually that's turned out was actually very simple.
No need for training set or test set.
No need for future scanning just some little changes in the dataset here with indexes and we're all
fine.
We're ready to build our first nonlinear regression model that is the pulling of the regression model
and that's what we will be doing in the next tutorial.
So I look forward to creating this bluffing detector with you.
And until then enjoyer machine learning