All right my friends.
Are you ready for the final steps of this implementation.
First we're going to visualize a training set results.
And second we will visualize the test set results.
So let's do this.
Let's start by creating a new code cell.
And there we go.
Now we just want to plot on a nice graphic the real salaries compared to the predicted salaries.
Basically we're gonna have a 2D plot with the x axis being the numbers of years of experience you know
from one to 10 and the y axis being the salaries you know in the range of salaries given in this dataset.
And so we will plot in red points the real salaries and in a blue straight line the predicted salaries.
Okay.
And we will do that both for the predictions and the training set and the predictions in a test.
Are you ready.
Let's do this.
So I didn't expect you to implement this yourself before you know doing it together because there are
actually a lot of new tools that we're gonna use here and especially Matlock lib.
You know you remember this library mad plot lib allows us to plot some nice graphics including the ones
we're about to plot.
So we're gonna first go mad plot lib as a reminder it has to shortcut P LTE actually what we're going
to call is exactly the PI plot module from the MATLAB library and this is what is having the p LTE shortcut.
So there we go.
Let's start by calling five plus P LTE from that plot line and then we're going to call a specific function
from this module which is go scatter and scatter will allow us to put the red points in a corresponding
to the real salaries in the two D plus.
Okay.
So naturally what we have to input here are the coordinates of these red points representing the real
salaries and these coordinates are nothing else than X train and Y train right.
Because remember the X axis will be the numbers of years of experience.
That's what is contained in exchange and the y axis will be the salaries.
And that is what is contained in y trains are here and scatter here we just have to input the coordinates
first X train for the numbers of years of experience.
There you go.
And then why train for the salaries.
Okay.
And then we can add another argument which is color and which will allow us to choose color of these
points.
And as we said we're going to choose red.
Perfect.
And that's the first thing this will just plot the red points corresponding to the real salaries in
a 2D plus.
Then next step or next step step is to plot the regression line.
So remember from the intuition lectures the regression line is the line of predictions coming as close
as possible to the real results.
You know the real salaries and therefore and that's why it is called a linear regression to predictions.
You know the points corresponding to the predicted salaries will follow a straight line right as in
a linear function.
And therefore here we're not going to use the scatter method we're going to use the plot method because
that's what we used to plot curve of a function.
And since our function is linear it will actually be a straight line.
All right.
So there we go.
Let's call first the p LTE module pilot.
Then from this module we're going to call the plot function.
There you go.
And in this function will same as in the scatter function we have to input the coordinates of the points
or line nodes corresponding to the predictions.
Actually you have all the descriptions of the diverse tools we use in Google collab.
That's one of the many beauties of Google collab.
And so you can have a look at more information here if you'd like but that's very intuitive.
We just need to enter.
Once again the coordinates of the predicted salaries and this will just plot the line following these
predicted points.
Okay so let's do this.
According to you what is the first coordinate of these predicted salaries.
Well that's of course X train.
Why is that.
It's because right now we're visualizing the results of the training set.
Okay so these corresponds to the numbers of years of experience of the employees in the training set.
That's the x coordinates.
Okay now we're going to input the y coordinates and according to you which ones are these.
Well it's something we haven't created yet.
You know we created actually the widespread variable containing the predicted salaries of the test set
but we haven't created a vector containing the predicted salaries of the training set and that stall
fine what will actually enter here as to why coordinate of this plot.
We're about to make are going to be exactly the predicted salaries of the training set to get them.
I'm going to copy this and paste that right here but instead of inputting here x test I'm going to input
actually X train because calling the predict method on X train meaning on the numbers of years of experience
of the employees in the training set will get me exactly the predicted salaries of the training set.
All right.
Just as before with predict x test so extreme.
Yes.
And then just as before we're going to choose a color which this time will be blue.
Right.
So that we can clearly see the difference between real salaries and the predicted salaries.
Okay so this will plot the regression line.
Now next step what can we do.
And that's just for the sake of the form.
I want to train you how to build a nice chart or a nice graphic with Python.
So here we're gonna add a title and to do this we have to call the title function and inside the parentheses
we just have to input in quotes.
Well the title we want for a graph and so let's say salary versus experience.
Okay.
You can choose any other title if you prefer another one.
So salary vs. experience and then we're going to specify the training set because indeed then we'll
do the same for the test.
Okay.
Salary versus numbers of years of experience in the train set right.
This is a very precise title.
Now we're just going to add a label to the x axis into the y axis.
And for this we have to use the x label function into which we have to input.
Well the label we want to display on the x axis and we're going to choose in quote of course years of
experience.
All right good.
Now we're gonna copy this because we're gonna do the same for the y axis and the name of the function
for this is why label.
That's why I just did a copy paste and for the Y label.
Well we will choose to display salary.
Okay.
Salary.
And finally in order to show the graphic.
Well we just had to finish here with BLT that show you know the show function.
And this will display the graphic in the Alps.
All right.
So good.
Now we're gonna do the same for the test results.
I'm just going to copy everything here and paste that in a new coat sale right here.
And so now we're going to do the right replacements and this code in order to visualize this I'm not
the change that results but the test results.
And so obviously the first thing we need to replace here are the coordinates of the real observations
because these are the coordinates of the employees in the training set and we want the coordinates of
the employees of the test.
Therefore here we have to replace obviously X trained by X test and then Y train by Y test.
Okay.
So these are for the real observations with the numbers of years of experience and the real salaries
of the test.
And now according to you do we have to replace something here in BLT plot x strain regressive that predict
X train according to you do we have to replace X trained by excess and the same x rayed by excess.
Well you know that kind of a trick question because remember that the regression line that we get is
actually resulting from a unique equation and therefore the predicted salaries of the test set will
be on the same regression line as the predicted salaries of the training set.
And that's why here we actually don't have to replace X trained by accessed here and here.
Okay.
You would actually get the exact same regression line whether you plot the coordinates of X strain and
the predicted salaries of training set or x test and the predicted salaries of the test set.
You can check but that's because the regression line in a simple in our regression model results from
a unique equation and we therefore end up with the same regression line.
Okay.
So no need to replace anything here.
And finally we will just replace your training set by test set and there you go.
Now we're ready to visualize the training set results and the test results.
So let's first run the sales we haven't executed before.
So remember we executed up to the training.
Now we have to execute this one to indeed get the vector whitebread of the predicted salaries in the
test set.
So there we go.
We now have white bread.
And so now we're going to first execute this to visualize the trains that result and we're going to
say now nice to the plot with indeed the real salaries in these red points here and of course are beautiful
regression line containing the predicted salaries.
And we clearly see that this regression line was calculated so that it comes as close as possible to
the real salaries and of course for each of the years of experience here in order to get the predicted
salary you have to project the Europe experience to this blue regression line.
So for example the predicted salary corresponding to eight years of experience is about you know one
hundred thousand dollars per year.
OK.
So that's how it works.
And so we can clearly see that our predicted salaries are very close.
The real salaries you know for most of them but that's on the training set.
Remember that's important because our model was actually trained with these observations you know with
these years of experience and salaries.
Now what we would like to observe is if we had the same result you know the same closeness of the regression
line to the real salaries in the test set with which the model wasn't trained you know we want to evaluate
it on new observations.
And that's exactly what this new graphic will tell us because now we're about to plot this time the
real salaries of the test set and the predicted salaries of the same test set.
So there we go let's run the sale and let's see if we're still close to the real salaries even for new
observations.
And yes absolutely our predicted salaries which are of course on the blue line once again are very close
indeed to the real salaries.
So our moral are simple in our regression model was able to do a wonderful job at predicting new observations.
So congratulations.
That's very exciting.
You've built a very successful first machinery model.
However just remember that the reason why we get such a good regression line here is simply because
there was a linear relationship in the data set between the features and the dependent variable of the
data set other words we had a perfectly linear dataset.
In other words we had a dataset with linear correlations and what I want to make sure you understand
is that these beautiful results won't happen for any dataset because of course you'll get to work on
data with non-linear relationships.
And for these data you will need a nonlinear model.
And that's exactly why in this part two regression we will also study some non-linear models which you
will see will be polynomial regression or as we are which will allow you to get amazing results for
data sets having nonlinear relationships.
But for this dataset we clearly had linear relationships and that's why linear regression more was perfectly
fine.
But I just wanted to highlight this.
Okay so congratulations once again.
I hope you're very happy and excited to have built your very first missionary model.
Now we're going to increase the difficulty a bit because in the next section we will build multiple
linear regression model meaning that instead of having one feature you know only one independent variable
we will have several of them.
And that's exactly the difference between simple in our regression and multiple in our regression.
Simple in our regression is when you have only one feature and multiple in our regressions when you
have several features.
So take a good break now and as soon as you're back with your energy let's implement our second machinery
model in the next practical activity after cubicles intuition lecture and until then enjoy machine learning.