All right.
I'm ready to do some cleaning.
Yes good because now we're about to do a deep cleaning of the text.
Right.
So far the texts have punctuation different characters other than letters that capital letters lowercase
the verbs are conjugated differently.
Well we're going to simplify all this and that's indeed an essential step when doing natural language
processing.
We need to clean the texts as much as we can in order to ease the learning process of the future machinery
model which we will train to understand the reviews understand English basically and predict if the
reviews are positive or negative.
All right.
So let's do this.
Let's first import the library's meaning the tools which will allow us to clean these decks.
So the first one and that's the main one the most essential one it is the library art.
Right.
So let me just import it first.
It's simply called R E and that's library.
You know will use to.
Yes.
This one the first one that the library will use to simplify basically the issues but this is not the
library that will allow us to do the stemming.
Which I will remain and re-explain later on.
OK.
So are you.
Then we will import of course that and LTE K library very classic library in natural language processing
which will allow us to download the and symbol of stop words.
So what are the top words.
These are you know the words we don't want to include in our reviews you know after cleaning the texts
which you know are words that are not relevant to help the predictions of whether a review is positive
or negative.
And these words include you know the simple ones like the you know all the articles like the.
And you know all these words which don't give any hint of whether a review is positive or negative.
So we will remove all these words you know all the words there are not helpful to predict if a review
is positive or negative.
And speaking of these stop words well now that we import an A.K. we can call an A.K. and from which
we are going to download.
Well oldest upwards.
And to specify this we need to enter here in quotes inside this download function from the penalty library
stop words and this will get all the stop words and you'll see later on how we use this to indeed not
include these non relevant words in our reviews.
OK.
So good.
Now we're not done with an A.K. yet because from an LTE T.K. And then from the corpus module of an antique
a library we will import all these stuff words that we just downloaded before.
There we go.
So basically this line of code downloads them and this line of code imports them into our notebook.
OK.
So all these top words and finally still from an LTE K and from the stem module from the N.A. library.
And then once again from the poorer sub module of the stem module of the end I'll take a library.
Well we're going to import a class which is the porter demo class.
Perfect.
And this is a class we'll use of course to apply stemming on our reviews.
So now let me remind what this is about stemming consist of taking only the root of a word that indicates
enough about what this word means.
So for example let's say there is a review that says oh I loved this restaurant okay.
And let's say we want to apply stemming to the word loved.
Well what it will do is that it will transform Luft into love just to simplify the review.
Because whether we say oh I loved this restaurant or Oh I love this restaurant.
Well you know that means the same.
That means that the review is positive.
So we can totally remove all the conjugation of the verbs you know just keeping the present tense so
that we can indeed simplify the reviews because remember at the end you know after cleaning the text
when creating actually the bag of words model we will create a sparse matrix where in each column we
will have all the different words of all our different reviews.
And therefore in order to optimize or minimize the dimension of this sparse matrix where the dimension
is exactly the number of columns well we need to simplify as much as we can the words.
And if we don't apply stemming Well you know in the sparse matrix we will have one column for love and
one column for Luft.
And since that means the same thing that would be redundant and that would make the sparse matrix even
more complex you know where the higher dimensions that would be wrong.
So that's exactly what stemming is about it consists of reducing the final dimension of the sparse matrix
so that we can indeed have not too much trouble to learn the text from our machinery model.
All right.
So that's what this poorest dimmer class will do.
And now there you go my friend.
We can start cleaning the text we have all the tools we need so the first thing we'll do is create a
new list which we'll call Corpus.
All right.
And we will initialize this list as an empty list.
And what will this list be exactly.
Know what will it contain.
Well it will simply contain all our different reviews.
You know all the different reviews from our data set but all cleaned and all into this list corpus.
So what we'll do actually is you know we will make a full loop to iterate through all the different
reviews of our data set and for each of these review we will apply a cleaning process you know by putting
all the letters in lowercase and removing the punctuation and removing the stop words.
All these things and we will do that one review after another and each time we clean a review.
Well we will add it to this corpus.
So this corpus will only get in the end all the clean reviews.
Okay.
And we do this of course because then the future functions will use in the next steps.
Expect our reviews in the list and all cleaned.
Okay.
So corpus and now now that we initialize this list well we're going to populate it with a clean reviews
through a for loop a full loop which will iterate you know with this classic looping variable ie in
the range from 0 to well guess what.
Guess what is the upper bound.
You know we will simply iterate through all the reviews and since we have 1000 reviews in our dataset.
Well I will simply go from zero to 1000.
Right.
As simple as that.
It will iterate through the indexes of the reviews which go effectively from zero to nine hundred and
ninety nine.
Okay.
So for loop ready and now we can go inside the for loop.
And there we go.
Now we're going to apply different steps to clean each and every single review of our data sets.
So first of all we will create a new variable which will call review and that variable will exactly
be that cleans review.
But you know we will clean it step by step.
So we'll update review each time we proceed to a new kind of cleaning.
And the first kind of cleaning will do will be to remove all punctuation.
In other words it will be to keep only the letters in our reviews.
All right.
And to do this we're gonna call r r e library from which we're gonna call the sub function which is
a function that can replace anything in a text you know in a string actually by anything else you want.
And what we're gonna replace actually is any element that is not a letter you know from it is that by
a space so that every punctuation like quotes double quotes commas or Collins or anything you want will
be replaced by a space and it has to be replaced by space because otherwise we can have two words that
stick together.
So we need to make sure we replace the punctuation by spaces so that we can indeed still separate the
words.
All right.
And the way to do this thanks to this sub function is to enter here in the parameters first what we
want to replace and the trick to say that we want to replace anything that is not a letter is to do
it this way.
You start with a pair of square brackets here just like that.
So that what's inside this pair of square brackets will be what will be replaced you know by the spaces.
And the trick to say that what we want to replace are anything but letters is to include a hat here
and I will explain what this means and then add a.
So have to do it like that actually double had a k a dash z so all the lowercase letters from a to z
but also then all the capital letters from a to z.
All right.
And what this hat means is exactly not you know this symbol in mathematics or computer science means
not meaning not all the letters from a to z in lowercase nor the capital letters from a to z which is
exactly what we want we want to replace anything that is not the letters from it is that in lowercase
or capitals by spaces and the way to specify that we want to replace all these by spaces is well exactly
what we have to enter here as a second parameter and which we will enter in you know quotes but inside
a space right what's inside these quotes is exactly what we want to replace those non letters here by.
All right.
So we're going to replace everything that is not letters meaning all the punctuation by this space.
Okay.
And then finally we have to enter one final argument which is of course where we want to do all these
replacement you know inside the what inside which review right inside which text.
And so very simply the third parameter we have to enter here is the review in which we want to do all
these replacements and to access to review Well that's very easy we need to take our data set.
There we go then we need to take the right column of the data set which contains the reviews and that's
of course the first column which we can either access with the eye log function and then specify in
the index 0.
Or I'll show you another trick by adding here a pair of square brackets and then just entering in quotes.
Well the name of the column which is read the view right.
If we go back to our dataset you will see that the name of the first column is review.
Okay.
So as you want.
I look works very well too.
And now do we need to add something here.
Well of course because this only gets the first column containing all the reviews.
But now we are dealing with a specific review the one of index i and therefore to catch that specific
review which we want to clean right now inside this full loop.
Well it's simply to add in a new pair of square brackets.
All right.
This will get the review of indexed I in this first column review of the dataset and that's exactly
what we want.
All right.
First cleaning done.
Now we will proceed to two other types of cleaning.
Then we will take a little break and then we will proceed to stemming.
Which will consist of you know simplifying the words in order to get only the root and therefore simplifying.
Eventually the sparse matrix.
All right so that new step will be to transform all the capital letters into lowercase.
And that's very easy to do this we just need to take our review variable from which we can now call
a specific function.
Because you know we created this variable as an output of this sub function by the R E library and therefore
like objects it now has some attributes and functions or you know methods that you can call in that
function we want now to simplify all the letters into lowercase is the lower function and that's it.
You just have to enter it like that review that lower.
But this will return the review with only lowercase letters.
And since we want to update our review variable Well we simply need to adhere review equals write equals
the result of applying the lower function to our previous version of the review.
Okay.
So very easy.
And then one final cleaning before we proceed to stemming in the next material.
Well actually what we have to do now is something to prepare for the stemming and that something is
to split the different elements of the reviews in different words actually because the different elements
are now words.
So we're going to split the review into its different words so that then we can apply stemming to each
of these words you know by simplifying them by their root.
Okay.
So the way to do this is very simple once again you know I'm gonna copy this and it here and instead
of calling the lower function I'm simply going to call the split function as simple as that.
This will split your review into its different words and now.
Now my friends we're ready for this Deming.