Hello and welcome to this are to Tauriel.
So in the previews tutorials we made our first two steps of building or pulling of the regression model
which were to preprocess the data and actually that was really simple because we just needed to import
the data set and select the columns of interest and then we fully to morals to our data set the linear
regression model and the polynomial regression model.
So we build that in our regression model as a reference of comparison of the polynomial regression model
that we also built.
And speaking of comparison and this tutorial we are going to visualize the graphic results of these
two models and therefore we're going to make two plots here one plot for each model where we're going
to see the real observations and the predictions.
And it's this toil that you're going to be convinced of how more powerful the polynomial regression
model is compared to the linear regression.
So right now let's write the code to visualize those results.
So we're going to do this with GG plus two in case you didn't follow the linear regression tutorials
on our.
I'm just going to write a line to install the GGP to package I'm not going to install it just in case
you don't have it and to check that you need to go to the packages here and check if you have the GDP
to package here.
And so if you don't find it in this list here you need to install it to install it.
It's real simple.
You just need to type here.
Install that package just press enter here and then in quotes you enter the name of the package which
is GGP up.
And then you just need to select this line and execute a Islamic person commander control plus enter
.
And this will install the G-G to package without any issue.
I'm not going to do it because mine is already installed but you can trust me it will work perfectly
.
So I'm going to put that as comment by pressing command shift policy.
All right.
And now we can start to visualize the linear regression results.
So as you can see in the packages here the Juji party package is not selected here so I'm going to need
to select here.
So either I can take care or the better way is to automate the selection of this package.
Thanks to the script and to do this we just need to add the line library and in parenthesis the name
of the package with no quotes.
So just gg plot to here this way.
And when this line will be executed actually we can check it right now.
As you can see G.G. but it is not selected.
I'm executing this line.
And now it's selected.
OK so now that our GOT library is selected Let's start building the plot.
So we're going to do exactly like in simple in our regression we're going to use the G-G plot function
and then we're going to add the different components in the graph.
So first we will add the real observation points thanks to the GM point function.
And then we're going to add the predictions component.
Thanks to the GM line function.
Then we're going to add a title to the plus things to Juji title and then a label to the x axis with
X lab and labeled the y axis with y lab.
So very simple exactly like before we are going to make this graph step by step.
OK so let's start with the first step.
The first step is just to type here DZIEDZIC plot with parenthesis and that will initiate the plot.
And now remember we need to add a plus here and that's where we start to add the different components
.
So the first component is the real observation points and we are plotting them with the GM point function
So let's add here GM point GM underscore point actually here it is.
And we can put the arguments in the parenthesis.
OK so the first argument remember is the aesthetic function.
So that's in this function that we will input the x coordinates of our observation points as well as
the y coordinates.
So let's do this.
He asks for a set function.
So it this a static function we need to put the X go tonight and the y coordinates of all or 10 observation
points.
So let's see what these coordinates are.
Let's have a look at our data set.
So our 10 observation points are characterized by their levels and their salaries.
The x coordinates corresponds to the independent variable that is the level column here and our y coordinates
will be our 10 salary's here associated to these 10 levels here.
So in short the x coordinates are the independent variable values.
That is the 10 levels here and the y coordinates are the dependent variable values.
That is the tensor is here.
OK so let's end with that.
So X here is level and Y is salary.
However since we did not specify that the data is dataset here our data set we need to specify where
we are taking the levels and the salaries and to specify that we need to add here dataset $ So that's
our understands that we are taking the levels of our dataset dataset here.
So it's going to be the same for why we're going to specify that we're taking the salaries of the column
salary in our data sets this way.
Perfect.
And now we can add another argument because it's a static function was the first argument of this geom
point function.
And remember we can add a second argument which we will add because we want to add a color to our points
then make distinction between the real observation points and the predictions.
And so we're going to pick the red color.
So here I'm going to add the color argument and set it equal to red in quotes.
All right.
And now let's not forget to close the parenthesis at the GM point function because this parenthesis
was for the aesthetic function and now we are all fine.
Great.
And now let's add the second component which are the predictions.
So I'm going to add a plus here and adds my second component here.
So the second component is as I just said predictions and we are going to add these predictions component
with the GM line function.
So exactly like we did in simple in our regression.
So Jim line here cheer him on the score line and then parenthesis of course.
And again we're going to take the a static function combined to a caller.
So I'm just going to copy all this right and paste it in my GM line function.
All right.
Now of course we'll change a few things.
So first let's start with the simplest let's change a color we're going to pick a blue color for predictions
.
Here we go.
And now what we need to change are the coordinates of our prediction points.
So the x coordinates of our prediction points are still going to be the levels themselves because we're
just predicting the salaries of the 10 levels that we have in our dataset.
So here we obviously need to take the ONLY levels that we have in our dataset.
So we keep here data set dollar level.
But then for the y coordinates of course something is going to change here because by taking data set
dollar salary here we're taking the real salaries of our 10 levels.
That is the salaries that are in the salary column of our data set here.
So of course we need to remove this and replace it by something else.
And what is this something else going to be.
Well of course it's going to be the predictions of the salaries of the 10 levels according to the linear
regression model and to get these predictions we are going to use of course to predict function.
And so actually that's exactly the same as in simple in our regression in this pretty function we first
need to specify the regressors.
So the regressors is called Lin rag because you know we're playing the linear regression results and
our linear regression model was called Lin rag.
That's our regressors leading right here and now the second argument I remember is new data.
So new data here.
And that's actually the data points we want to make predictions on.
So very simply that our data set because we want to get the predictions of the salaries of the 10 levels
of our dataset.
So here are putting the dataset there.
Perfect.
So we're good because we already inputted the blue color for our predictions.
Great.
And now let's complete this graph very quickly by adding a titles of plus here.
And then you know we used to G.G. title function to add a title.
Can you see how it's simple it's starting to get really intuitive now.
You know we were planning the real observation points with the GM point function then the predictions
with the GM line function and now a title with the DG title function well everything will seem easier
and easier for you.
So for the title we're going to add azen but truth or bluff you know just to get a funny name to our
problem.
And we're going to specify here that we are applauding the linear regression results so we'll just specify
here linear regression.
All right.
So that's it for the title.
And now let's add an X label and a white label.
So for the X label we're going to add something here X lab parenthesis in quotes and then level because
our x axis will contain the levels and then plus y lab parenthesis quotes and salary and done the linear
regression results are ready to be plotted so let's not wait anymore and let's immediately have a look
.
So I'm going to select all this.
I don't need to select this because plot is already important.
And now let's press commander control press enter to execute and hear other linear regression results
.
So let's zoom on it and let's interpretes great.
OK so what is the first thing to understand here.
Well the most important thing to understand is definitely that we need to make the distinction between
the real observation points are the red points here.
Each one correspond to one specific level and the real salary associated to this level on the y axis
here.
And then we have our predictions on this slide that is that for each level let's say for example the
level 5 when we project this level 5 here on this straight line here.
This point is actually our prediction point and we can get the predicted salary by projecting this point
here on the y axis this way.
And so we get a little less than $250000.
OK.
So that's the first thing to understand the red points are the real observation points and the points
on this blue straightline are the prediction points.
Okay.
Now the second important thing to understand is that our prediction results is actually a straight line
.
And the fact that it's a straight line is due to a particular reason it's that the linear regression
model is obviously a linear model.
Each time you build a linear model in two dimensions you'll get a straight line.
And I'm highlighting this because the next model we're going to visualize the results is going to be
the polynomial regression my role and this model turns out to be a non linear regression model and you
will see that it will not be a straight line anymore.
And now let's give some interpretation.
So first of all we can see that this linear regression model represented by this blue straight line
here is not fitting.
Our dear said very well because as you can see for some observation points the prediction is actually
pretty far from the real observation.
That's the case with this point and Zimpher this point as well.
And this point and especially this one.
Let's have a look at this point for example.
While this point is the real observation point it corresponds to a 10 level and a 1 million dollar salary
.
So it's definitely the salary of the CEO.
And so that's the real salary.
And now if you want to get the predicted salary for this particular observation points that represents
the CEO.
What we need to do is project this point on this blue straight line here that is our linear regression
model to get actually the prediction point.
And now to get the predicted salary of the CEO we need to project again this prediction point onto the
y axis that contains all the salaries.
And so we obtained that the predicted salary of the CEO is actually $620000 according to our linear
regression model.
So imagine we're negotiating with a future employee that is about to be hired.
And that was the CEO in its previous company.
Imagine how furious this person will be if we tell this person that we believe it's bluffing because
we think its salary is around $600000 whereas its previous salary was in reality one million dollars
.
The negotiation would probably turn really bad.
So that's a first example of how this model can give poor results that can have a very negative impact
on the situation like the negotiation we are having right now.
So let's see if the negotiation would actually turn bad for our real situation that is this future input
is about to be hired and that it has a 6.5 level and that is negotiating its salary by saying that its
previous salary in the previous company was a hundred and sixty OK.
Well let's see the 6.5 level corresponds to this level nearly.
And when we project this level to our regression model that is this blue straight line here and if you
project Again this point on the salary excess we get a predicted salary.
Well it's more than $300000.
Definitely so.
Actually we're way above what this employee said its previous salary was.
So actually in this situation in our real situation that negotiation would turn well for us but still
we want to get the accurate prediction and clearly to do so we need to improve the model and make a
non-linear model which will fit much better the observation point here that is that we will make some
kind of a curve that will approach much better all the read observation points here.
So let's do this let's close the linear regression results and lets start to visualize the polynomial
regression results and you're going to see now how easy it is to go from the linear regression results
to the polynomial regression results because what will simply do here is you know select this and paste
it here and now we will see how we only need to change very few things.
So as usual let's start with the simplest let's replace linear are here by polynomial OK.
And now what do we need to change.
OK so do we need to change something in the genome point function.
No of course because we want to keep the same real observations.
So that's OK.
And then do we need to change something in the genome line function.
Of course yes because here we were predicting the salaries of our 10 levels in our data set according
to our linear regression model.
So according to you what do we need to change here.
Very simply.
Well actually we just need to change the aggressor in the function and instead of taking DeLynn Raggatt
which is the linear aggressor we're going to take the pulling on the repressor that we call POLLI rack
and that's it.
That's actually all we need to do to visualize the pulling on the regression results and you'll see
that in the next sections it will actually be the same.
We will only need to change a regress or two plus the new graphic results of our future regressors.
So that's very nice.
We're actually ready right now to visualize the putting on the results.
So let's do this without waiting.
I'm going to select this and press command and control press and to execute.
And here it is.
As you can see this is not a straight line anymore.
Let's zoom on the graph.
All right.
So as I just mentioned the first reflex to have as a machine or any scientists is that this is not a
linear model anymore.
And by the way congratulations you just made your very first non-linear model.
We're going to see plenty of other non-linear models in this course.
But this is your first one.
So congratulations.
So as you can see it's not a straight line it's a curve and we can immediately see that the curve is
approaching much better all the read observation points.
And especially for the CEO here the CEO wouldn't get mad.
Now if we negotiated with him it's future salary in a new company because now the prediction is much
closer to the obsession point.
And let's check our employee that is about to be hired and that has a 6.5 level while 6.5 is around
here.
And when we project 6.5 on our Paul Newman regression model represented by this blue curve here we get
a predictive salary here I'm projecting the point on the curve.
Back again on the salary access and we get actually a salary that is coming much closer to the salary
mentioned by disputer employee which is around 160 k here.
Well we don't get the accurate prediction here because that's what we're going to do in the next tutorial
.
But definitely this model is getting much better the set.
And now just for fun let's add a new degree to see how this model can still be much improved and almost
passing by all the points very accurately as we add more degrees.
So let's check it out.
Let's close this and let's add a new degree.
So very simply what we're going to do is add a new degree here by copying this line pasted here and
we're going to add a new column in our data dataset level 4 that will correspond to our original in
the been invaluable level and the power for.
And so therefore here we need to compute it this way by taking the fourth power of level there.
And now let's execute this line to add the level 4 column in our data sets.
Now you can check to see it here level for perfect.
And now let's reset this to rebuild our new poll on the regression model with this fourth degree now
.
So executing new polynomial regression will all created.
And now let's have a look at the results.
So these are the previous results corresponding to a polynomial regression model with a third degree
.
And now let's look at what happens with fourth degree.
So I'm going to select this and execute.
And here are the polynomial regression results for a polynomial regression model with a fourth degree
.
OK.
So as you can see we can zoom on it if you want as you can see the line is actually strictly passing
by all the red opposition points.
And now this year would be even happier with negotiation.
Or should I say even less furious because the prediction now is actually almost the same as a real observation
point.
That is the predictive salary it's almost the same as the real salary.
OK.
And same for 6.5 level employee when we project this 6.5 level here on the curve.
And then projecting again on the y axis that is the salary access we get a value around what he said
that is 160 k.
And for those of you who are interested in having a more continuous curve here like within and by then
I will add the code for that job in the our file providing in the section you can check it out for fun
.
And this is them all over again to use to get the accurate prediction of the previous salary of this
new employee that is about to be hired and we will compare it to the salary that he pretended to have
in its previous company and eventually tell our final verdict whether it's truth or bluff.
So I look forward to doing that with you in the next tutorial.
And until then enjoy machine learning.