So if everything went fine, you should get
this sort of an output, like I got it here,
the one that I am selecting now.
You can see it on the screen.
So this is something that you
should get. It didn't last that long,
maybe five to ten more
minutes, something like that.
I really don't know,
I'm not sure, I didn't exactly time it.
That's just my approximate estimate, nothing more.
Now that that is done, we can
go ahead and clear the screen
and then go into the Downloads folder and
we will have something like this,
it says Kali-Linux-2.0.0-vbox-amd64.ova.
Let's go ahead and double
tap on it and see what happens.
Nice. OK, so it says
that it allots one CPU, 2GB of RAM.
I sincerely hope that you have
enough RAM on your Mac, if you have 4 gigs of RAM
I mean, it should work still,
you can always resize it later, it's no big deal.
If you just have 4 gigs,
you might want to resize that later.
I'll show you how to
resize it, but if you have like 6 or 8...
I don't think you're gonna have 6.
If you have like 8 or 16 or something of a kind,
then it is completely irrelevant,
you will be able to function like so
without any problems of whatsoever.
Just go ahead and click on Import.
And it says "importing".
Well, these downtimes and waiting...
this is murderous,
but you gotta wait through it.
While this is going on let me just tell you that
during the past few days I have not found
the MacBook Pro battery lacking.
It is fantastic. It does last
for quite a while, which is amazing.
Come on, my good man, come on.
Why are you giving me like
twelve minutes to just import the image?
It should be faster than that.
I guess I shall segment
this video and make it like,
make one tutorial of multiple
parts, so I will merge them together.
So let's just call it here and then
I will merge the next part with this as soon as
the 11-12 minutes have passed, most likely 15,
so you don't have to sit here
and hear me ramble until this is done.
Once it is done you will get a screen like this.
If you're wondering
where this is on the file system
I'm guessing it should be in the
same place as it is on a Linux machine
so let's go ahead and type in "cd".
Revert back to the Home
directory of the current user,
so that user's Udemy here.
And let's do "ls" from here and there you go.
You see how it says "VirtualBox VMs".
If you go to cd, VirtualBox, VMs,
you can see this Kali image.
It is here, it is functional, it is working.
Whether it's working or not
we actually have to check that.
Now, if you have only 4 gigs
of RAM available on your Mac
just go ahead and I go into...
right click here...
for me right click is just
two fingers touching the touchpad
and then go into Settings, you
can go into System, if I'm not mistaken
and then you can move
this pointer left to reduce it
and right to increase the amount of RAM.
You can only do this
while the machine is powered off,
and not while the machine is powered on.
And this is very nice.
I can actually use 16 CPU cores.
which is, I have four actual...
and eight virtual? No, I have four actual and...
that should be twelve
virtual cores, which is very nice
if my guess is right, because
this has a quad-core processor in it.
But 16 CPUs means that I can
run 15 virtual machines here at once.
I know, right? It would
probably overload the system
or load it to its maximum and
the system would be rather slow,
but I could actually run 15 virtual machines
in one actual, which is very nice.
So all of this, we're not gonna need it for now.
For the time being, I just
want you to go into System
and be able to adjust the size of RAM just in case
you have just 4GB available on your Mac.
But if you have more than 4GB
you can just leave it
at default and not touch it at all.
So let's go ahead and
power on for the very first time
our Kali Linux machine, just double tap on it
and pray that it starts and works.
So this is a first install.
I'm just gonna go ahead and select that one.
It says "loading, please wait".
I'm so hoping that this
prebuild version already has
the Guest Additions
installed, that would be so nice,
but if it does not, no big deal,
we will be able to install them ourselves.
It says failed to the vulnerability assessment.
Don't worry about that,
you can install it additionally
and configure it, but, I mean,
there's no real need for it at the time being,
this is just a virtual machine.
Boot, boot, boot. Come on. Any time.
Any moment now.
And there we go. So username should be "root"
and the password should be "toor".
Let's see if this is the same
set-up as the Live Kali Linux,
where the default password is t-o-o-r,
in case somebody didn't hear me spell that out.
The username is "root" and
the password is just the reverse of this.
So "toor", that's the default set-up.
Later on you can add in
new users, change the password, etc.
We've got Kali. Let's see
if we can get a full screen,
we can get a full screen! Voilà. Excellent,
so we don't actually need to
install VirtualBox Guest Additions,
which is awesome, as we
don't need to go through that process.
Let's go to the full screen like this.
It actually doesn't go
to the full screen all the way,
it could go a bit farther.
This is gonna be good enough,
I don't think there will be
a need to actually change anything.
Actually you can stretch it out
by half a millimeter more if you'd like,
feel free to do so, but there you go.
Kali is installed, Kali is
up and running, it is functional
and I don't see any problems here.
So let's see if I have internet connectivity.
I can type in "ping google.com", so this is stock,
I didn't change anything. Press Enter and voilà.
The internet does work,
I can actually successfully ping google.com.
Let's interrupt that with Control+C
because it's extremely
rude to leave the ping running.
They are kind enough to allow us
to ping them to test our connection,
so let's not waste the band
within their servers for no reason,
just use as much as you need and that's it.
And another thing I wish
to point out is in the Devices
you have Drag and Drop,
Shared Clipboard is more important, so
bidirectional is enabled by default.
Drag and Drop is also bidirectional
but I don't really care about that
as long as the clipboard functions.
Now, where is my Network settings? There we go.
Go into Network and then go into Network Settings.
It says "attached to NAT".
NAT will pretty much mask the activity
of your virtual machine
behind your physical machine,
so your traffic will appear
as though it was coming from your physical machine
but if you want Kali to be Kali
and not hide behind your
physical machine, or should I say...
I don't like to expose
but just kind of present your
physical machine to the rest of the world,
you can go ahead and set it in
Bridged mode. Both modes are really fine,
you shouldn't have problems with NAT at all.
Some people might have
a problem with Bridged mode
due to the drivers for the network adapters,
but nothing I can do about it,
you can either go into
the net and try to find the drivers,
if there are any existent,
if there are not, tough luck.
I mean, it's fine. You can
select NAT, it's going to work.
Let's go ahead and select the
Bridged Adapter and see if this works.
If you don't know which
adapter you are using on Mac
because when you select
Bridged Adapter you actually need to select
and specify which adapter you would wish to use.
Obviously, if you're connected to a Wi-Fi,
you're gonna select Wi-Fi (AirPort),
or if it's Ethernet, you're gonna select Ethernet.
If somebody has an adapter,
something like that, you can select this one.
But if you don't know which
adapter your machine is currently using,
there's a simple fix for this.
You can pop up your terminal.
Let's just get out of here. Clear.
And all you need to do is,
same as in Linux, you can...
Let's go and expand this across the whole screen.
I hope this flashing white
color is not gonna kill your eyes.
It probably will, I'm kidding. It's killing mine.
You can type in "ifconfig",
and then just search for the interface
because these are the interface names.
You have "en2", "en1" and you
can take a look at which interface has
in the sign ip address, so
we're looking for an "inet". There we go,
"en1" and we have "inet" and
then you have your LAN ip address.
This is the LAN ip address, this is most likely...
most of the people have pretty much the same range
of LAN ip addresses on
their home networks and it's fine.
I've noticed that some people in the discussions,
they hide their LAN ip addresses
I can't see a reason as to
why you should do that, but OK,
feel free, it doesn't really
matter that much anyway.
What I'm trying to say is that this LAN ip address
doesn't really leave your network at all.
And it most likely changes
when you reconnect the device,
as well depending on which ones are available.
For example, if I disconnected this device
and if I reconnected another device
that other device
would probably have this ip address
and then when I reconnected my Mac later on
I would probably get 192.168.1.4.
That's just your LAN ip
address, it's not your public ip address.
Public ip address is something different,
that is the ip address
that you use to go onto the net
through your default
gateway, and that is the public one,
that is the one that can
be used to basically trace you back.
But this one, forget
about that, this is just a LAN ip address,
this is something for communications
within the LAN network and that's about it.
Probably you didn't get
the best of explanations there,
but well, it's not that relevant.
This is how you'd identify
an interface which you are using.
So when you go here in VirtualBox
and when you select the interface,
you will select the one which
you are using to connect to the net.
Now, all of these connections, it doesn't matter
if you select a Wi-Fi here or an Ethernet here.
All of these connections
will be seen by VirtualBox as
wired connections, so none of them is actually
your wireless.
So virtual machines do not access
your integrated wireless
card. Let's keep that in mind.
They will not access
your integrated wireless cards.
In the follow up lectures
I do believe that I shall show you how
you can effectively
pass through a USB wireless adapter
so that you get Wi-Fi
on your virtual machine as well.
But that is for another lecture, so allow all here.
By the way, if you power your machine off
you can change your MAC address here
because MAC changes
don't work on a virtual machine.
So you can just change your MAC address here
by pressing this circle here. OK. Nevermind.
We've switched to
Bridged Adapter, saving settings, OK.
I'm in the software, let's type in the password.
Let's go and try to ping google.com. No ping.
It's not passing through, OK,
no big deal. Let's type in "ifconfig".
I do have already assigned an ip address
and I did not released the DHCP list,
I did not release this
ip address on this interface.
So let's go ahead and release it.
Several ways of doing this
but I'm just gonna go ahead and type in
"service network-manager restart".
And then type in "ifconfig" and you see
I have a completely different ip address now,
that one was from NAT
and this one is on the LAN network.
So I just go and type in "ping google.com"
and voilà, it worked.
So both Bridged and
NAT, they're working just fine.
This is a first install on a Mac from 2011.
That should be it for these
lectures. Now we're gonna move on to
continuing this set-up on a Mac and doing
everything that you need to do
to actually be able to sit back and relax
and follow through
this course as comfortably as you can.
Until then, I would like to bid you all farewell
and I sincerely hope
that this was extremely useful
to all the Mac users out there.