Today we're just gonna go ahead and see
how can we actually
pass through a USB to our Kali virtual machine.
Why do we need to do that?
The primary purpose of this
would be to be able to pass a USB wireless adapter
because, as I said before,
your virtual machine does not have access
to your integrated network wireless card.
If I type in the password
here and if I go ahead and zoom,
so type in "ifconfig" and you can see
that I have two interfaces listed here.
This interface, this is not a
wireless interface and even though
I am connected to the network via wireless,
I am not connected to the network with a cable,
I'm obviously using the wireless network
as you can see in the upper right corner.
That is a problem, because you won't be able
to go through the wireless part of the course
and you'll be able to see it and all that,
but if you don't have access to the wireless card,
that can be problematic. Now, I've stated before
that there are two ways of going about this.
One of the ways is checking
for the compatibility of your wireless card
with not only Kali Linux but Aircrack
and see if it's compatible on aircrack-ng website.
However, that procedure
has been somewhat frowned upon
as you can't actually
just use the model of your card,
you actually need to go
on the net and look for the chipset
which is used by your
card and then use that chipset
to go onto the Aircrack site
and look for that chipset number.
Let's call it a number,
demarcation, whatever you wish to call it.
Look for it and see if it's compatible.
If you wanna go through the process,
I mean, by all means, feel free to do so.
I will even help you out, if you like
but I have opted for a different solution,
I have opted to actually
get a USB wireless adapter,
pass it to a virtual machine and get
an extra interface here for wireless.
So the very first thing that
we need to do is power off our machines.
Just type in "poweroff". Let's shut it down.
The second thing that we will need to do is see
if we're actually capable of passing through a USB.
If not, we will need to install additional software.
And I will show you which USB do I have,
which USB wireless adapter do I have.
So if we go over to Ports,
and if we go over to USB, I have USB 1.1, USB 2.0
so let me just plug my device in
and let's see if it actually works out
and this thing only has
two USB ports, which is amazing.
If I say USB 2.0, invalid settings detected. Why?
OK, so we need an extension
pack in order to be able to do this.
I'm just gonna unplug
my device, I will show you later on
which device am I using as a USB adapter,
but we're just gonna say OK here and now
we will open up our browser.
I'm using the default one, Safari
even though I generally use Firefox
but I'm assuming that this is stock,
so we're just gonna use
whatever we can from the system itself.
Let's go ahead and search for
"oracle virtualbox".
And here we go. Oracle VM VirtualBox. Click on it.
Sure, we can get it from here,
but I was hoping to go straight to Oracle.
Actually, wait. Let's see if we can get from here
so I don't have to bother on their site.
Downloads. Extension Pack. There we go.
So I do have it here.
Actually I didn't notice it here.
Usually I just went over to the Oracle site
and then navigated my way through there to find
the page that was dedicated for VirtualBox.
"If you're using 4.3.30,
please download the extension pack here".
But we're using 5.0.4.
By the way, before we actually download it
we can check the version
of your VirtualBox in the Help menu.
So just press on Content, it should be there.
No. It is, actually it is.
It's version 5.0.4. There you go.
There are some slight interface variations
between VirtualBox for Windows, Mac and Linux.
But nothing too drastic, really, so no worries.
Let's go back to Safari and it says
VirtualBox 5.0.4 Oracle
VM VirtualBox Extension Pack,
all supported platforms.
So let's just go ahead and click on this link.
The download is in progress,
this should take a lot less time
as these things are not very big, it's just 16MB.
Let's open it up.
Are you gonna run?
Please? Yes, no, maybe? No? Okay.
So Downloads. Extension Pack. Here we go.
"You are about to install VirtualBox extension pack.
Extension packs complement
the functionality of VirtualBox..."
I'm just reading this because
it's probably too tiny for you to see.
Maybe it's not. I can see it
quite clearly from some distance away.
"...the functionality of VirtualBox
and can contain system level software
that could be potentially harmful to your system.
Please review the description below
and only proceed if you have obtained
the extension pack from a trusted source".
I sincerely hope that we
have obtained it from a trusted source.
This is science.
Safari is using an encrypted connection...
Show me the certificate.
VeriSign Class 3, OK,
so this should be fine, as far as I can see,
https seems to check out,
as far as I can see anyway.
There are never any 100% guarantees.
There's always that 0.0.0.00000something chance
that something will go wrong.
One more thing, if you are running anything else,
any other programs that are like VirtualBox,
so if you have VMWare
or if you have parallels or something like that
you might not want to
install VirtualBox alongside with them
because it's generally not a good idea to run
two instances of this
virtualization, softwares of this...
It's just not a good idea,
not only on Mac but on any other system
on Linux and Windows as well.
So if you have one, either remove it or use it,
do not install another one next to it.
I mean, you can and you have
a chance that everything will work out,
but, you know, just to keep it on the safe side.
Anyway, I'm gonna go ahead and click on Install.
There is a license agreement
here to accept from Oracle. Agree.
Now it's gonna prompt this
for a password, so let's just type that in.
And now it is installing the extension pack.
And there we go. It has
successfully managed to install it
without any difficulties. Now what we need to do
is simply go ahead and enter Settings,
go into Ports.
These are serial ports,
nevermind that. Go into the USB
and now you can select
2.0, 3.0, 1.1, whatever you wish.
We're gonna go ahead and
select 2.0 and let's just see if this works.
I can indeed see some of the things here.
Definitely Logitech USB Headset,
the one that I'm using to record this.
I have access to that.
I'm gonna go ahead and
say Ok for now and not add anything.
I'm just gonna go over
to the net to show you a picture
and a model number of the wireless
network adapter that I have next to me.
It is not mandatory that
you get this particular adapter,
you can get any other that is compatible
or that is accessible to you,
but make sure that it is compatible
with Kali Linux, that it is
compatible with aircrack-ng.
I'm gonna go ahead and see the model number,
it's a bit of a lengthy one.
OK, it's opening it up.
I'm sincerely hoping that
you can all see the model number here,
it's "awus036nhr v.2".
I need images. So there we go.
This is how it actually looks like.
This is what I'm holding in my hand now,
any of these pictures will do, they're all showing
I suppose, the same adapter,
and this is the one that I am using.
This is the one that I've
tested out, if you want to use anything else,
by all means, you are free to do so.
This particular adapter is not a must-have,
you can obviously take another one
that you have checked for compatibility.
Check for compatibility on this site: aircrack-ng.
And let's go ahead, select Compatibility
and there you go, you have the available chipsets
It says "supported by airodump
for Linux", "supported by aireplay",
"supported by airodump
for Windows", we don't really care about that.
But both, this needs to be
included "supported by airodump for Linux"
and "supported by aireplay for Linux".
You need to figure out
what is the chipset of your card.
How do you figure out the chipset of your card?
Write the model number and then
just write the question
in your favorite search engine,
"What is the chipset of
(the model number)", press Enter
and you'll be able to figure
it out, not a hard thing to do at all.
Then take the chipset number and go here.
Sorry, not the chipset
number, the chipset designation.
And then come here and
try to figure out, try to find it.
Even if it's not listed here,
it has a chance of working out.
But, you know, it can be a little bit dodgy.
Some features might work, some others might not
or it might not work at all.
Then again, you can just go onto the net
and look for the compatible adapters.
You know, if you can't get this one, this one is like...
I think I got this
for 20 bucks or something like that.
Fairly good one, from Ebay.
But you know, if you can find
something cheaper that works, feel free
but I have not tested anything else out.
I've just tested out this adapter,
I've also tested out the
wireless card in my primary machine
and some other things as well in terms of wireless
but as far as the USB
wireless adapters are concerned,
this is the one that I have tested out.
Anything else, I can't
make vouches that it will work,
but, I mean, make the
checks for yourselves and see if both,
if this part says Yes and
if this column as well says Yes,
then it should work. No big deal.
So just go with whatever
option you feel the most comfortable with
and keep in mind the cost,
so try to be cost-effective as well.
Anyway, let's go ahead and
plug it in, so just take the USB cable.
All that I'm doing is taking a USB cable,
I'm plugging it into the
adapter, that I got with the adapter.
And then I'm gonna
spin it around and I'm gonna plug
the USB adapter into the machine.
This is the second time
in five minutes that I'm plugging it in,
but I didn't really do
anything, I just tried plugging it in.
So I'm just gonna plug it in to the machine
and I hope that it's not dead.
That would be very nice if it's alive
at least, because
I don't see a blue flashing light at all.
I'm just gonna go ahead
and try plugging it into my laptop
to see if it's actually alive,
because I haven't used it for a while
OK, so it is functional,
definitely I see a blue lamp.
That part is obvious anyway.
Let's go ahead and
plug it in and see what happens.
Nothing, but well.
Let's see if we can
manage to pass it through anyway.
So I have the device
plugged in, all I did now is plug the device in.
I did not install any drivers prior to this.
I did not do anything other
than just plug the device into my Mac.
That is all. Via the USB port
with a cable that came with the device.
That is all. Nothing else.
And this is the first time
that I'm pretty much doing this.
Let's go ahead and
click here, Settings, go into Ports
USB, it's 2.0 EHC Controller.
Click on the plus sign and 11n USB.
Let's select that and click on OK.
Now let's power the
Kali machine up and see what happens.
OK, excellent, so my USB is now blue.
The blue lamp is on.
Notice that I did not install anything on Mac.
I did not install any drivers,
the Mac did not recognise this device,
Mac doesn't have a clue what this device is.
It's just passing it
through, just as if it was a USB
and it's passing it through
a VirtualBox to this virtual machine.
That is all.
Actually I couldn't use this device on
the Mac until I'd installed the drivers for it
but I'm not gonna do that
because I'm never gonna use it on my Mac.
What should I use this in a Mac for, anyway?
So Control Shift +++ to magnify.
I type in "ifconfig", press Enter, voilà.
You have Wlan0. I am not connected to any networks
but, I mean, it's
right there, I can use it, obviously.
If I press this, Not connected. OK, obviously.
Select a network. There we go,
so I have a tonload of networks
around me that I can use to connect,
and let me just go ahead and cancel this.
I go into Network,
I'm gonna go into Network Settings.
I'm gonna go into Network, and I'm gonna say,
you see, where it says
Bridged Adapter, I'm gonna say "not attached".
So it's not attached to any
of the integrated adapters in the machine,
doesn't care, doesn't matter.
This is gonna bring the
internet connection down completely
in terms of wired connection. I'm doing this
so that I can demonstrate
that this wireless adapter actually works.
And I'm gonna try to ping google.com,
now this is not gonna
work out, as you might imagine.
I'm just gonna Control+C to quit.
Now what I shall do is just
go into the Network manager here,
go into Wi-Fi, Select
a network. Select this network.
Click on Connect, type in the password.
Let it connect, I'm gonna
leave it to attempt of ping
to see when it actually connects.
Are you serious? Have I forgotten the password?
You know, when you don't use
your own wireless for a very long time,
you tend to forget the password, which is...
It can be very frustrating, to say the least.
Please, tell me it's this one. There we go!
So ping google.com
has managed to pass through successfully.
I'm still having some difficulties,
it could be the range on this thing
because I'm sitting quite some distance away
and this is a virtual
machine, so keep that in mind.
And the ISP router
is utter junk, I can tell you that.
But OK, the ping passed at least
once, so you know you at least have...
Actually it didn't pass.
I did resolve the ip address,
so that's something, right? Nope, doesn't wanna.
OK, no big deal, we'll fix it.
So it's pinged google but it's hilariously slow.
Let's attempt to open up the browser
and let's go to Udemy.
Is it gonna open this site?
No, it will not open the site.
This is good, that I've encountered a problem.
This is bad, because I will need to make
another tutorial on how to solve this.