So we're back.
The next portion,
the next step that I wanted to put
in a segmented section, not only
due to the time limitations but also
because this is the portion where if you do this,
you run a risk of basically damaging your system,
probably not in a physical sense,
but rather instead in a software sense because
you will most likely...
if something goes wrong
there is really little than you can do.
Most likely you will have to do a clean reinstall
and I have stated this
in the very beginning several times.
I have stated this is not the recommended set-up,
but here you go, here is how you can do it.
So, first off, we're gonna
go over to the net and
you can take a look at this site
but I will also give you a link and
or the file which you can download,
but feel free to take a look
at this site as well if you wish.
This is the tool that you're going to need,
it says that rEFit is a
boot menu and maintenance toolkit
for EFI based machines like Intel Macs.
And also it says "as you may have noticed rEFit
is no longer actively
maintained. Please check out rEFind,
a fork that is maintained
and under active development".
So you can also go with that one,
I've had some problems with it and I figured,
since I have an older Mac from 2011,
I'm gonna go ahead and use
this one instead, the older one.
You can also go and try with that one as well,
I have tried and had limited success.
I'm not going to download it,
but this is the one that we will be using.
It's a Mac disk image, rEFit, and
I'm gonna go into the...
No, it should be around here somewhere.
In the Downloads, you can see
that I have indeed downloaded this one
but this is a dmg file, so just double click on it
and it's gonna go ahead and open it.
Don't do this to me, please.
There you go, and this is what you need: mpkg.
Just double click on it
and it's gonna take you
through the installation procedure.
I already have it here,
but just click, click, click,
click through the end. That's it.
This might actually mess your...
mess your system up, so keep it in mind.
There's nothing special here, just continue,
license, continue, agree.
You can just go ahead and click on
Install here and then the
installation goes through and the rest.
There is no special options or
something like that that you need to select.
Here's basically click and go. No big deal.
Unless you wish to customize something,
which I definitely would
not recommend at this time.
So this file will be provided,
of course, but you can also go ahead
and check out the site and
download it from here if you wish.
OK, so now I am gonna go ahead and
basically minimize this and we're gonna go ahead
and switch to my phone
now, from where I'm going to
record the rest of the video
because I need to reboot the machine
and show you how it is...
how it is done. Let's go ahead and call it here
and I'll be back in a moment,
where we will do the stated.
Okay, so welcome back, I guess.
Now I've switched to my phone.
So I have changed
this a little bit. It's now Kali 2.
Completely irrelevant to you, I've just renamed it
to something more peacing
to my eyes, but it's not going to affect you
in any possible way.
So you can do that too, you can redo the procedure
and in the beginning you
can label it as Kali 2 if you want.
I've shown you where
you can relabel the devices with
the Disk Utilities in Mac.
But it's completely irrelevant, I would suggest
that you go ahead and
follow through. I'm a perfectionist,
so it was kind of just stabbing me in my eyes.
Anyway, let's go. So over here you have,
I have a power cord attached to MacBook,
something I advise you to have during this,
a USB that we've just
made, it's plugged in directly,
not through a hub or
anything like that, this is a USB hub.
I didn't use a USB hub,
I did try doing it via USB hub,
seems to work fine but in some forums
they suggested and advised against it.
Now that you have all of this set up
I advise you now to go
ahead and shut your machine down,
not reboot, shut it down, like, completely.
I'm pretty sure you can
see the letters, but even if you can't
all you need to do is shut
the machine down, quite literally.
Yes, I would like to reopen the
windows and, please, shut down.
Let the seeding stop.
I'm just seeding Kali Linux on download.
Anytime, anytime.
And here you can actually see me in my t-shirt
that I've been wearing for days now,
and behind me, the rest of my place, I guess
in the reflection of the screen.
After this I'm gonna go ahead
and answer all your questions on Udemy
and I'm gonna head to shower and bed.
Down here, you have Power button,
could be in a bit of a different place for you,
but basically all you need
to do is power the machine back on.
So Power button, very important, keep an eye on it
know where it is, you're
gonna need to press it again later on.
Let's go ahead and power the machine back on.
You can hear the CD and the boot..
You can see in the left corner,
where my finger is now, that the USB is blinking
and this is a non-standard Mac
boot, you can see that it says rEFit,
so let's go ahead and select what we need.
Let me just zoom in so you can read the letters
because they are a bit more important now.
So we've got Boot EFI. No, we need... Manager,
no, this is not gonna work, I tried it.
If it works for you, great. If not, just go ahead
and select the one that I have selected,
it says boot EFI\boot\grubx64.efi
and that is the one that I shall boot now.
So go for it.
You get this GNU GRUB version 2.0
I'm gonna go ahead and say boot persistent,
even though it's not going to
matter in a sense that it usually does
but we will still have a persistent partition there.
So let's go ahead and say boot persistent.
More me.
Take a good long look if you like.
Down here it's just reading, reading, reading,
loading, loading, loading. Fine. Whatever.
Just go for it, I mean,
you can feel free to read if you like
but doesn't really matter.
That's something that the
system is doing and that is informing us
of what it is actually doing.
Going through, going through.
Come on...
Oh man, there's a lot.
Okay, so there will be a
catch during the boot-up procedure
where we will need to play
around with the Power button a little bit.
Don't worry, you won't need to open up anything
or do anything like that.
So you see it just boots and,
well, doesn't actually boot.
There is a blank, there is a black screen
and then there is a flashing USB.
I'm sincerely hoping that you
have a USB that flashes, if you don't
after the black screen appears, give it ten minutes
and do the following. If you have a flashing one
well, just wait for it,
like I do.
The flashing seems to have stopped
and you can see that the machine...
See this light here? It's not in
stand-by mode or anything like that.
If you come close to the machine,
you can still hear the fan spinning,
and I'm gonna go ahead...
Maybe you can hear it here as well.
Look, the Power button. So, it's right here.
Do a short press on the Power
button, a very short press will do.
Don't hold it for long, if you hold it for long
you're going to mess it up because
you're going to power
the machine down, completely.
So keep an eye on this.
On the light and let's go ahead
and power the machine back on,
well, no, just wake it up, I guess.
Just press it once.
And you can see that the LED has turned on
and now it's slowly flashing, painfully slow.
Then press it again. So I did a one short press
and now I'm gonna do a second short press.
Second short press was done, and there we go.
It's going through the procedure again.
There you go, voilà!
Kali is here and running.
So we can go ahead and log in.
Password will be t-o-o-r, the default password
and the default username
will be "root" and there you go,
Kali is running.
It's semi-persistent,
you have the persistence partition
in the upper right corner here.
Let's open it up. So this is a
persistent partition and everything else
that is on the other partition
which we have created is not persistent.
So on this partition you can
make one small script and then...
bash script and then just issue a
set of commands which you want to run.
So when the machine boots
open up your persistent
partition and run the script.
All that is saved here, where my
mouse is moving and my hand is moving,
on this partition, casper-rw, is permanent.
You can also name it any
other way because "casper" is for...
the way I explained it
on a PC, so I just kept the name.
Anything that you save here will be persistent,
anything else, on any other
partition, will not survive a reboot.
So any actions that you take or something of a kind,
you can save them here
and then just continue from there.
If you want your configuration
saved, more importantly, on your Kali,
you can make a bash script with a set of commands
that you would type
in the terminal, exactly the same,
and just run the bash script and
those commands will execute one by one
and will configure your Kali every time you boot.
You run the script once and
it configures it to your preference,
you just create the script here and that's it.
If you need help with the bash
script, feel free to reach out to me
in the discussions section.
You know I'm always there to help.
I answer as many questions as I can on
pretty much daily basis.
But for these couple of days
I've been really stuck with this,
nearly an impossible job to create a boot on
MacBooks that are older than 2012.
2013, 14, something like that,
that's gonna work without any problems.
Just plug and play,
use that program that I've showed you,
create a USB and it's going to...
I mean, I've tested it out on a MacBook 2013.
It works with a Retina display, works
without any problems of whatsoever.
I do believe that's Retina, don't hold my word to it.
But doesn't really matter, just the year matters.
So it works without any problems, but on older ones
it's trully a painful experience.
All the files that you will
need for this will be on Udemy,
either in a form of a link
or they will actually be there
from where you can download them.
Anyway, this concludes this chapter with Macs.
If you have any questions
with Macs, in regard to Macs,
feel free to reach out to
me in the discussions once again.
Again, at the end of this tutorial
of this chapter, I'm going to say
that I do not recommend this on a Mac at all.
First of all, running the risk of
being forced to reboot your system and
basically, a high chance
that you'll encounter problems,
difficulties and so on and so forth.
That's it. I bid you all farewell
and I hope that I have helped
at least some of you achive your goals.