Hello everybody and welcome to this
tutorial.
Today I will introduce you to the Linux terminal
and show you some of its basic
functionalities so
So in Kali Linux, the terminal icon is located in the upper left corner
this black thing
So just click on it
and there you go.
You have the terminal up and running here by default
It opens up a root terminal in Kali
So if you want to
usually people want to configure it
but if you don't want to configure anything else
this is perfectly fine.
You don't actually need to do anything else.
However, 99% of time people will configure the terminal
to suit their own needs and purposes.
For example, I will always almost always increase the font size.
So that it's clear and visible
and that I have a better overview of what I am doing at the moment
and it also reduces eyestrain, according
to some articles
Anyway, just go ahead and right click anywhere on the terminal itself
not on the bar, but on the terminal itself
and then you have "show menu bar"
Now we can see it here
Go ahead and click on edit
You can click on profiles as well
and create new profiles here by just clicking on "New"
giving it a name and then configuring it in the preferences.
However, we're gonna be configuring the default profile
since there really is no need to create any additional ones.
Go ahead and click on profile preferences
and here you have a great deal of options.
One of the first ones you will see
is that you can use a system fixed with
font.
So this is not good.
You see this is very small
I always need to change that.
If that's fine for you, you can keep it like that
but I always change it.
I have monospace 20
If you click on it, you can change the
font size here if you wish.
You can change the font that you're using
and that would be it as far as this place is concerned.
You has some other very simple options here
It says "show menu bar by default in new terminals"
I generally take it.
I think it's a good idea
since you always need to do something like open up a tab
or something of a kind
but you don't need to
You have the cursor shape here.
It says "Block" "I-Beam" "Underline
I just want to show you how it looks like.
You can view the terminal as the changes are applied.
So you have a block and you have a underline.
I prefer a block
You can use whatever you wish.
It will not affect you in any technical
sense, that is.
I have "Title and Command' and we don't actually change anything there.
You can change the title if you wish
and we have colors.
So I think that this color scheme is appropriate and fitting for me
but you can change it anyway you like.
You can customize it to the point of extreme.
You can change the text color.
The background color.
You have the color palette here.
So you can do whatever you want here.
You have built-in schemes.
It says White on Black
I can say Green on Black
Oops, sorry...cancel
You can say Green on Black
Does it have Blue on Black?
Umm, no.
Oh, this one's bad
I wouldn't be able to work on this one.
So let's just leave it at White on Black.
This is the best color...
This is one of the best color schemes I use.
Personally, I use on Fedora Blue on Black
but I'm just gonna leave it as it is here.
No need to actually change anything.
Now in the background, you have three features here basically
You have solid color like this one here that you are seeing
and you can choose a background image.
You can download anything you want from the internet pretty much.
You can configure it to be transparent
or image background.
and also, you have the ability to have a fully transparent background
and if you click on "Transparent Background"
it's pretty much the same as having a background image
except in this case
excellent
I'm just gonna configure the transparency levels
and that's pretty good
except in this case
your background image will be your desktop image pretty much
depending on where your terminal is.
in "Scrolling", there's an important
feature here
It's "Scroll Back"
So you don't want to have 512 lines.
You want to go ahead and click on "Unlimited"
unless you're severely limited in terms of RAM
and unless you're typing in a large amount of commands
or something of a kind
but in any case, it's better to have unlimited
especially not only environment such as these
but rather instead
in cases such as these.
You don't need to do anything here in terms of compatibility.
I'm just gonna go ahead and close this
and I have selected a transparent background
and you see this only works for a desktop image.
It doesn't actually show icons or anything of the kind.
If I open up my web browser, it's not gonna show it in the background.
It's still gonna keep the desktop background image.
So the desktop wallpaper, should you wish to call it so.
There's a slight delay when it goes about in the update
but it's fine.
Doesn't bother us in this slightest bit.
Maybe I will change this later on during tutorial
see how I like it
but I just wanted to give you an option, so you can do whatever you want with it.
In any case, you can go ahead and click on "File"
and "Open Tab"
I'm just gonna go ahead open myself four tabs
three new ones and one I already had.
So here you can switch in between them.
It's very nice.
There are no complications.
For example, if I press "Open up a new terminal"
I gotta click here and then I gotta click here
and unusually you're gonna have...
I'm just wanna show you what it's like to have four of them.
So yeah, this is not actually manageable
especially because you don't know what you are doing on which terminal.
People sometimes split their screens into terminals.
I sometimes do that
It's very nice
but we will deal with that a bit later on when we get into some serious stuff.
When we actually need multiple terminals
but tabbing these terminals
it's very nice
primarily because you can actually see what you're doing
on each one of them in the headers.
See these things that I'm clicking on now
They are headers of the terminal
or so you can call them
and for example, in this terminal
I'm gonna go ahead and say
"I want you to go into home. Change the
directory to home"
Change the working directory, that is
If I change it here to "var"
and if I change it here to "var/logs"
and if I want to go here to "tmp folder"
Excellent
So on each of the tabs in the headers
I can see where I am.
So this this one, it's home
but this one, it's tmp.
I don't need to click on it to know.
This one is log.
So I can know what I'm doing in every particular terminal
and even though you could have a program running
or something like that
It's still gonna write it out in the header
and you're gonna get some extra information there.
It's very nice
It's very useful
and it's going to help you out a lot as we progress through this course
and as we get into more complicated
stuff.
Anyway, I just want to introduce you to the next terminal.
We have done some work with before
during the installation of VirtualBox and VirtualBox guest additions
but basically there, I just give you the
command
and you're gonna basically just rewrite it or copy-paste it
and that's gonna be it.
but here, in the follow-up tutorial
actually I will start explaining the fundamental Linux terminal commands
The most common ones
The most basic ones
and there you will be able to see the logic of things
and how this Linux terminal works and functions
because once you actually learn that
it gives you a huge amount of power.
All the power of the operating system rests on it's terminal
because it's a direct interface to the kernel of the system
and it's a lot faster then the graphical interface.
Now one more keynote that I would like to make here
Once I teach you how to use the Linux terminal
and once you get into the habit of typing in commands
you can use them for a wide variety of
purposes.
You don't necessarily need to use these things for pen testing
or something like that.
You can use these commands for network administration
or you can use them in order to troubleshoot problems with the system
and so on and so forth.
So you get a far wider spectrum options in terms of jobs
or something of a kind
as opposed to just learning something
that you can only use for pen testing
and nothing else.
In any case, I bid you farewell
and I hope to see you in the next tutorial.