Hello, everybody and
welcome to this tutorial.
I'm just gonna pick up from where
I left off in the previous one.
Anyway, in the previous one as
the last part, I posed a question and
you should have answered it before you
started listening to this tutorial.
In any case, as I said before,
you have a type of proxy here and
you always want to be using socks5.
You don't want to be using http,
because they are not really that safe and
socks5 doesn't support a lot of options.
Anyway, this is the IP
address of the proxy server.
We will enter a few of
them manually later on.
And this here is the port number on
which the proxy server is listening,
the port that is open.
And over here, these two words.
Now some proxy servers, especially paid
ones will always have a user name and
a password, so
you can just type them here in plain text.
Unfortunately, but
it is only assumed that you and
you alone have access to this computer.
And besides, this this file is not
everybody can read this file, anyway.
So if you just type in the username
here and password here, you will
gain access to a certain proxy that you
have chosen or that you have paid for.
Anyway, these are just examples.
We won't actually be using these
proxies or anything of a kind,
we need to go down below and
here is the end of the file.
So if I just press Enter
a couple of times, there we go.
So there's only one proxy active
at the moment, it's socks4 and
all traffic is being routed here.
So our tor, it says,
defaults set to "tor".
Now tor by default,
listens on this port and
our connections will be
going through tor now.
But just in case, I want to add socks and
you should really do this, socks5.
Press Tab and
type in exactly the same IP address.
By the way, this 127.0.0.1, this is
the loopback address of your computer.
So this is for inter-device communication.
And if you PNG this address,
it means your pinging yourself, basically.
And usually, people PNG this address in
order to make sure that the IP protocol
is setup correctly, even though they
don't have internet connectivity.
So let's just type in 127.0.0.1.
Same port numbers, space here.
No tabs, 9050.
There we go.
Press Ctrl-O to save a file, press Enter.
By the way, you don't need to
use nano to edit this file,
you can use VI or
some other text to edit it.
I like using nano, it's practical and
it's fairly simple.
It's a lot simpler than VI.
I know how to use VI as well, but
it's a bit more complicated, so
I prefer to keep it out of tutorials.
Anyway, do Ctrl+O to save,
as I've done just a moment ago.
It doesn't hurt.
You can press it as
many times as you like,
it doesn't really matter and
then press Ctrl+X to exit.
There we go and we have the files saved.
Clear the screen for, you always want
make sure that you are working in a very
neat environment, so to say.
Then go ahead and type in service
tor status, see if tor is running.
Tor is not running, so
it gives you an answer.
And what we want is to start tor up,
so service tor start.
Press Enter.
There we go.
Now tor service has started and
it is up and running.
So the next thing we need to do
is use proxychains in combination
with our tor and in combination
with our internet browser in
order to be able to access a third
party in order to verify that
all is working properly and
that we are anonymous.
A lot of people do the configuration and
they type in service toward start and,
yeah.
That's it.
They don't verify the settings.
They start to scan and what happens,
of course, they get detected,
because they most likely
misconfigured something.
So that's really a bad idea.
What you want to do is go ahead and
type in proxychains.
So proxychains.
Now this is, you do not want to
browse the internet as root,
we're just going to use it to verify
our proxychain's settings and
I'm gonna close the web browser.
So, I'm just using it for that purpose and
we will use proxy translator later on for
a different kind of purpose for
scanning and so on and so forth and
then we can use it as root.
But for a browser,
it's not a good idea for security reasons.
Anyway, proxychains and
then type in firefox or
you can type in any favorite
browser that you have.
I think Firefox works the best with
proxychains, as that is the default
browser of Kali Linux, even though
it says Iceweasel, it's Firefox.
Trust me.
So, type in proxychains firefox and we can
type in the website, if we wish to visit.
So let's just type in www.duckduckgo.com.
Now DuckDuckGo is one of those
search engines that is also
anonymizing you, so
they do not record your IP addresses.
This is a very nice feature that they
have and I definitely recommend using it,
primarily because you have a far
greater extent of anonymity than you
do when using Google or, and
the equivalent popular search engine.
As they do record your traffic, they do
record your IP addresses and that can be
problematic in itself, especially when
you're doing some sort of footprinting.
You do not want to be recorded anywhere.
Anyway, let's just go ahead and
press Enter and web browser is loading.
You can see that the loading time
is definitely not the fastest,
it's a bit slow, but it has loaded it up.
Just go ahead back to our terminal and
see, excellent.
So you see that the link has been
established here, there are some problems.
As it says denied somewhere, but that's
okay, you are bound to encounter errors.
Here a ton load of them, especially
when you're using custom chains.
You will see, there will be more
error messages than there will be
OK messages, such as this one.
But believe it or not, the connection
still manages to pass through somehow and
it still manages to
function in spite of that.
Anyway, I'll just go back and
open up our web browser once again and
you can use pretty much a lot of services
out there to do this sort of thing.
So just type in check for
DNS links and press Enter.
Whoa, this was fast.
So DNS Leak Test, excellent.
Lets go ahead and click there and
see what happens.
Hello, this is my public IP address now.
217.13.197.5.
It says that I am from Germany.
I assure you, I am not from Germany.
If you want to verify all of this,
you can type in,
open up a new terminal and
type in service tor stop and
then open up your regular web browser
without the proxychains command.
Do the same test again and you will
see that you will get a completely
different IP address,
which will be your real IP address.
So anyway, it says, hello,
this is me from Germany.
I'm gonna do a standard test,
I'm not gonna do an extended test.
Same thing pretty much.
This one does more rounds, but you get
the same information, more or less.
So it goes query one, excellent.
This is my ISP provider.
This is what they have
concluded in regards to my DNS.
So look, it's Level 3 Communications and
it says, Country, United States.
Makes no sense of whatsoever,
so I am anonymous now.
I can be effective,
which is a very good thing to have indeed.
Now this IP address will change from
time to time, but just go ahead.
If you'll remember it, 217.13.
Let me just copy it and I'm gonna go ahead
and show you that it actually does change.
So, Accessories.
I'm pretty sure,
I have a text editor here.
Excellent.
So, I'm just gonna paste this IP address.
And now what I'm going
to do is go ahead and
close this browser and
don't need this, so service tor stop.
It's stopping it.
Service tor start.
It's starting it.
So you don't need to write to
actually start stop start,
you can also do service tor restart and
it's gonna do the whole process for you.
So you can save a little bit of time
there and let's just repeat everything.
And go ahead, I'm just gonna go ahead and
type in proxychairs firefox and
I will request the same
search engine as well.
Will it open?
Now don't be disencouraged,
if it doesn't open it straightaway.
If it says, okay,
you don't have connectivity or
website is not available or
something of that kind.
Just try typing in service space
tor space restart command,
a couple of times over
again until you get it.
Because sometimes,
certain IP addresses are blocked and
you need to be assigned
the one that is not.
So just don't immediately jump to
a conclusion, oh, it's broken,
what am I gonna do?
It's gonna take forever to fix this,
how am I going to do this.
No, just try resetting it a couple of
times and you will resolve the problem,
primarily because a different IP
address will be assigned to you.
So anyway, let's just go ahead and
type in again,
check for DNS leaks for
center and here we go.
I'm just gonna use the same website,
it's DNS leak or whatever.
DNS leak test, that's the name of it.
Excellent.
So you see now,
I don't even need to compare the IP,
obviously, it's different.
So this one is 217.13, this one is 91.109.
So completely different IP address here
and from a completely different place.
Now it says that I am from United Kingdom,
apparently somewhere in London.
Now let's just go ahead
issue a standard test to see
what sort of resolutions will I get here,
this might take a while.
That's why I'm doing the standard test,
because it's a lot faster.
But you see the last one was rather fast,
this one is a bit slower,
depends on the distance.
I suppose I'm a bit closer to Germany
than I am to the United Kingdom.
I don't know.
I suppose this depends on the speed
of their server, as well.
Anyway, you can see my DNS resolutions
here, it's Level 3 Communications.
Again, I have stated
nothing from United States.
I am completely anonymous with this,
not likely to be detected
by pretty much anything.
Just to give you an example,
if you wanted, for
example, to use proxychange with nmap.
I'm not gonna go into great detail now,
I will show you this when
we get to the nmap section.
But before we do,
we can see some rebose output here,
how this is actually functioning.
So there are certain domains
which are being contacted,
you can see pretty everything
that is going on here.
No problems.
Not a bad idea to sometimes go
through this sort of information,
especially if you do not have connectivity
or you wish to understand better exactly
where is your traffic going, where it is
ending up and how is it spinning around.
Anyway, let's just go ahead and
clear the screen and
use let's say, proxychains nmap.
And this is all that you would
need to do in order to route
all of nmap's traffic through proxychains.
This is pretty much true
of any application,
just invoke the application as you would.
So normal nmap in the location would
be nmap and then so IP address here and
then a port over here and some arguments,
as well to go along with it.
But instead of just typing it like that,
you can use proxychains and hide yourself.
Also, just type in how would you evoke a
browser on a regular basis, you would type
in firefox, press Enter and that would,
of course, open up a Firefox browser.
So, any application that you can
start through your terminal and
you can start all of them
through your terminal.
Just type in proxychains in front of
it and all the network information
generated by that application will
be routed through the proxychains.
Now will it use a preset of proxies or
will it use tor,
that is up to you how
you have configured it.
And there will be a part three to this.
I will show you how can you import
custom chains of proxies and
how you can use those proxies
to access things on the net or
to hide your activity behind them.
In any case, I bid you farewell and
I thank you for watching.