Hello everybody and welcome to the continuation of this tutorial.
Anyway, today we're gonna do the actual cracking of the captured file
which is basically a follow up tutorial on the previous one.
Make sure you watch these in a proper order, as they are usually tied to one another.
Anyway, we have aircrack -ng
So I'm just gonna go ahead and type that in.
Anyway, we need the -w for a password or word list that we're going to use.
Either password or word list.
Anyway, you can find these online and download them
and I've seen some pretty good ones.
So it's 48 gigabytes or something like that
However, you need to keep certain things in mind.
First of all, the region where you're doing this.
So for example, if you're doing this in the US or Canada or English speaking areas
you'll be able to find some relatively good word lists that you can use
and they will most likely be able to help you out.
However, if you are in a region such as mine where people mainly
speak slavic languages those word lists
are not going to help you very much
orasure for example in russia or perhaps
some friends or something of a kind
there are specified word lists for
language areas but more often than not
they don't tend to work as I said if you
if you are in an english-speaking region
try it out with word lists there is a
good chance that it will be a successful
run for merely because people do tend to
repeat either repeat password or if they
tend to use fairly similar ones so the
likelihood of the password being in the
word list is pretty high
brute forcing method again what I just
said is not called
explained is called a dictionary attacks
who literally take a dictionary from
somewhere you type it in here you type
the name of the file hereafter download
and then you and then you start cracking
which is
a fairly difficult process to do over
over a certain period of time especially
if it's a dictionary it will practically
finished trying all the possible
combinations within the dictionary all
the list of recommendations within a
dictionary in a reasonable amount of
time so it might take a day or two or
something like that but again if you're
sitting next to a wifi you can spread
this attack out you don't actually need
to spread out or anything like that
perhaps indeed spread out for the
capture option or something like that
but for the aircraft option once you're
cracking the password it doesn't matter
you can literally sit in your house
without any sort of internet connection
or whatsoever if you have a few have a
capture capture file which you then
that's the end of it you will be able to
do it in your house without concern or
worrying about overloading the network
because this process is not conducted
over network this is conducted on your
local machine on a file this is very
important it is completely different
from an online attack or something of a
kind where you have the billion
limitations however as i said im in a
region where word lists are not very
useful and therefore I'm gonna do a very
different thing here I'm gonna see you
for a file to be ready in but I will
also tell it to reading from standard
output and now a duty to specify the
actual capture file so can test caps
let's just expanded to fullscreen
excellent so I have scant
dashiell one-dot cap and the final thing
that I need to put in a society which is
something and now in front of it all I
have shown in the previous tutorial
about crunch I mentioned it a few times
so I used for lunch
base and now each facet of arguments now
once you are when you start doing this
you want to have an idea of what the
past Ridley 12
to take a look around maybe specifically
a coffee shop maybe it will be a name or
something like that
of the place bid will have some sort of
characters of the name in it so make
sure to include them or something of a
kind if it's a company tried tried the
names of the officers tried the name of
the company tried the names of the of
the year of the different departments
and so on
communication with numbers and you may
think all well here's why why don't I
just tell us do all possible
combinations because it would take about
a billion years quite literally
regardless of what sort of hardware you
have it would take you like a billion
years you would basically need to have a
full power I don't know let's combine
Amazon and Google cloud hosting services
altogether and still it would take you
are very long amount of time in order to
crack a password because there are
literally death many combinations so my
twenties scouting and it also helps if
you know the length of the password so
if you see somebody typing in the
password in this is not just for
wireless cracking this is for any kind
of rude foreseen or dictionary attacks
if you are there if you are in the
environment or if you can access the
environment physically as a as I think I
mentioned in my first tutorial but I'm
not sure about it
somebody during class during one of my
classes he actually managed to see the
length of the past for the professor was
typing in because while she was taking
it in it was being projected onto a
projector screen was being projected
through the projector and nobody could
see it of course nobody could see the
password but hey he taught himself how I
at least have the link now and then he
passed a few times by her while she was
there to get in she obviously couldn't
he obviously couldn't see all the
cheapest taping in but the password was
like six or eight characters in length
and he managed to figure out that there
are many
of six or eight characters he managed to
figure out three or four something like
he didn't know their exact positions but
industry but he knew that they were one
after another and that is what I would
highly recommend otherwise this will
take for ever so for example I know the
password of my work
wireless router and I know the length
that's why I'm gonna give you this
option Sudesh and with that you can
actually specify what sort of characters
will be assigned to which positions so
for example I would strongly advise
looking at the man pages of crime just
show you a clear and an French
excellence we have we have a man paid
for grants and you have these arguments
so on and so forth and if we go down low
ok this is Jeff Carr said oars which
prove which we might actually uses well
I showed you that but we'll see whether
that is convenient for our purpose
anyway I'm just trying to find it should
be around here somewhere in the examples
down below this is definitely something
you should occur because they're
practically there's practically an
infinite amount of combinations that you
can use excellent so here we go this is
what sorry thundershower 5th St
excellence look at what he has done here
all these symbols present certain types
of characters for example the signage
preserves the lower case letters while
the exclamation
and this hash I have no idea what they
represent that I'm being percentage is
numbers irritating its capital letters
amateur about that but it doesn't really
matter is completely irrelevant you
don't need to know these things by heart
I don't know them what I do I take a
look at the man ages and I figure out
what is what it's not it's not really
that of course it's Dashti option there
we go desh the and here we have our
options to keep in mind it is an option
is an option percentage science is an
option carried signs an option and look
look at what it says the explanations
practically perfect specifies a pattern
an example of a pattern says your God
which is believe it or not people
actually use that in their best words
it's hilarious but they do and he has to
signs the front and 34 out signs
actually in the back look at whether a
designer 4 cents will insert lower case
characters so it will use this word and
it will insert lower case characters in
front and behind she said it would
insert uppercase characters in a certain
percentage sign somewhere in there it
would insert numbers that I care a tiny
percentage side and the carrots owners
down below it will insert symbols that
is why it is this i mean you have the
option obviously and that is why it is
very important to acquaint ourselves
with sort of password if you are
breaking you cannot just walk in and
break password brute force it without
knowing anything about it previously
that that that's just highly unlikely to
happen I mean even with the best of
machines out there it will not work as
well as you wanted to i mean i I'm
running a few virtual machines in the
box or perhaps my CPU usage will be a
bit lower but I've managed to turn
everything off and
Mehsud out it was on seventeen hundred
passengers per second I think I could
have gotten to 2.2 K if I overclock my
processor but i dont didn't have a
cooler here so I didn't want to do that
that is a very important aspect of this
you will need to watch the temperature
of your processor I mean if you're using
an Intel Core it will shut down by
default it will not allow you to
overhear adrienne arsenault destroyed by
overheating it but look here on the
right side I have each temperature
meters and they don't really have a way
of doing this in as the gadgets on the
desktop but you can see these you can
see do not necessarily the Celsius
temperature in numbers rather instead
you can see these charges basically
where scales however you call them you
will see the different temperatures like
61 degrees Celsius when I start working
with brute force air cracks method when
I start using the brute force method
with aircrack it will load the CPU
Nicholas 610 and you will see how the
temperature will just start jumping up
so when you're performing this attack
you might consider actually employing
some extra cooling systems in order to
basically reduce the temperature
processor because that will not only
increase decrease the chance of
something more functioning but also
increase the chance increased the amount
of tries it can do per second
anyway without further ado and just
gonna go ahead and move to celebrate and
terminal but more as well and I'm gonna
say crunch d I want you to you lose your
numbers in front and I know that the
word is under so
1234567890
also pipe Piper simply saying whatever
goes out this this and this argument
here is saying read from whatever is
faster than standard of press center and
there we go take a while and this is not
going to work because I am a genius
failed to actually passed the proper
length ones passing length in
combination with what we did hear you
absolutely need to make sure that it's
exactly the same late 2011 excellent
presenter and the scan is progress exxon
their ago so there we go
he found in such ridiculously short
amount of time primarily because I
already knew a good portion of it but
let's let's see what happens now let's
head and if I remember correctly what
was for capital letters I think it was a
coma
just check it out because I not all
knowing and come up with uppercase
letters yes it will
my memory still serves me well we will
remember to treat my brain with
something later I'm gonna see I'm going
to give it to you here I'm gonna give
your
something well it doesn't matter press
ENTER and still still the amount of
possible combinations is not large I
just wanted to make sure that you had
the opportunity to see the max out see
the maximum amount of tries here let's
just go ahead and close pretty much all
of my virtual machines and once I do dad
I will have more CPU despair more CPU
time here that I can devote to do this
forcing method just go back here and as
them as a virtual machines are getting
close and saved I'm getting more and
more attempts here but the still pretty
low I remember getting up to 1,700 so ok
it it sounded again within a reasonable
amount of time let's try passing II
think a character set so shush F ups
sorry that and what does it say what
character sets terminal at Cedis $1 his
name
caterer said Steve excellent so remember
to give a path if you're doing it and
some other folder but if you're doing it
in the folder down during it installed
this should be fine and paste said Alice
T and you know it will help you with
that I actually take a look at it myself
soldiers go back to the terminal
and this is not going to be very helpful
and need to go ahead and open CBE
stopped 36 excellent LSU and we have a
charset somewhere around here I'm pretty
sure scratch see make file management
want our civility so here we go lets go
to class versatility and here we have
the names stated before for pretty much
all the charts it's in existence we can
specify these manually but it's better
to use these drugs such as there is a
much smaller probability of the National
mistake so let's use mix alphanumeric
space and discuss significantly increase
the amount of possible combinations
probably gonna take through tomorrow to
actually get that but oh well I
compositor at any time and continue it
as well so no problems there
press ENTER and apps it's still giving
me a relatively small amount of
combinations primarily because like
12345 possibilities if you increase the
amount if you press Ctrl C tragically
started it will it will go until the
final threat because Linux systems
guaranteed it alters will be executed
and water so it's just this one say that
and this one as well
at center its seven hundred and
twenty-six year by the this will take a
significant amount of time let's see
what else can we actually closed in
which increase it
oh I know I know why it's so low because
I am recording at the moment as as I am
recording at the moment that is eating
up my if my memory and CPU time as well
now it's gonna show you something else
before iraq has tutorial up because
they're feeling I've already breached d
a lot of time if you have some sort of
temperature commuters on your computers
and a curse you do they're pretty easy
they're pretty easily downloaded from
the next you will notice after an hour
or something like that the temperature
will begin to rise the good news is that
you can spread this file that you have
interrupt this process now and the last
passport the last thread for password is
this one just gonna go until it's
reached exxon so what you can do here in
order to alleviate stress on a single
machine in order to increase your time
actually use this command and specify
either my list of characters so or you
can actually if you don't know the size
you can do the following for example you
can tell one machine ok I want you to do
all the combinations 499 of course then
this option would not be possible any
longer he would need to delete this and
another machine could do for example
1010 another one could do 1111 I do
believe that this is something that we
did long ago in school because we all
have laptops and pretty much we wanted
to brute-force ascertain password but
you know a single laptop doesn't have a
lot of processing powers Ashley not long
ago a lot of Sprint actually amazing so
we actually emerged not just a few left
off but also house home desktop
computers we basically merged every
single computer we could have scrapped
from anybody that was willing to help us
out and we had 10 or 20 computers
buckled up together and they were all
conducting a brute-force attack they
were all generating passwords of this is
something that you can do you can give
different parameters two different
computers
executed on the captured file because
this captured five kids portable you can
put it pretty much anywhere you want and
conduct
a attack there anyway in the follow-up
tutorials I will show you some other
methods how you can attack wireless
wireless access points and what you can
do with them perhaps a little bit of a
more effective method method in terms of
time that requires far less
reconnaissance any case I bid you
farewell and I hope to see you in the
next story