Welcome back, everybody.
Today we're just gonna continue
from where we left off.
I am going to do a couple of
things with Metasploit, and
those will include making our reverse
shells persistent on another system and
escalating privileges in order to do that,
because we do need an elevated
set of privileges to do certain
things on a system elsewhere.
Now, I can just see the question
in the discussions now,
can we actually do a remote desktop?
Yes, you can actually have a desktop
of another person being displayed on
your own screen but I strongly,
I strongly recommend against it.
Okay, if you're doing this in LAN,
fine, it can pass, but
if you're doing this over the net, having
a remote desktop is a waste of bandwidth.
I mean, complete waste of bandwidth.
I do not understand what it is
exactly that you would like to see
on their desktops.
You can take screenshots if
you want of certain things.
If you need passwords,
you can use keyloggers which
are embedded in Meterpreter.
You just need to issue a command
to log keystrokes, I don't know,
stuff of a kind, but I really don't
see the point of a remote desktop.
If you want to see if they're
browsing something on the net and
if they're watching something on the net,
you can obviously see the addresses,
you can see the IP addresses of
what they're visiting on the net.
Not the IP addresses but
you can also see the domains and
then you can just copy them
into your own browser and
have a look at whatever you want
to see almost in real time.
I know that would be a bit of a drag, but
believe me, it saves up on bandwidth,
and if you do a remote desktop over
the net, you are very likely to render
the other person's web browsing
experience practically inoperable.
They won't be able to browse the web,
I mean, they will, but
it will be very slow unless they
have a really good connection.
And unless you have a really good
connection, you won't be able to do that.
Try running TeamViewer and
you will see that it's not
the fastest of applications out there,
not because of the way it was built,
but because of the amount of information
that is passing in between two points.
Anyway, you should have pretty much the
same setup as from the previous tutorial.
You should not have closed anything,
I sincerely hope that you didn't.
It doesn't matter, if you did,
you can just repeat it.
Here, we're gonna go ahead and
open up our shell, so
just do the same things.
It's still running, I believe,
on my Windows 8.1 machine,
and let's see,
will it actually work out here.
Or, hold on.
Oh, I already have it running.
So it's working, and
let me show you how is it working.
I'm going to go over these commands
with you, don't worry about it.
I just want to get into Meterpreter now,
excellent.
So we are now in the Meterpreter.
Let me just prove to you that I
am in fact a Windows machine.
So cd.
There we go,
these are obviously Windows files, cygwin.
I even have that installed
on my Windows machine.
Amazing.
Doesn't really matter.
Anyway, now you can see that
I am in my Windows machine.
I've just closed the Meterpreter.
I've actually placed my
Meterpreter shell into background.
And that is something that you can do and
that you will be forced to do during
certain hacks, primarily because you will
want to do other things with that session.
You will want to open up a session and
then you will want to do
different things to that session.
You want to pass that session to different
exploits so they can use it as well.
And you obviously can't do that like this.
Now, what you would do is
put it in the background.
But before we do,
just go ahead and type in help.
This is going to give
you a list of commands.
This is a very nice command, getsystem.
Attempts to elevate your privileges.
But this doesn't really always work.
And here you have webcam commands.
I can't do this demonstration
on a virtual machine.
But this is only for physical machines,
unless you have a USB camera or
something of a kind.
It's not really that hard.
You just type in run and
then one of these commands.
You will see later on,
we will do something.
We will use some of the commands, not for
webcam, but we will some other commands.
I do believe that it is just run and
then this and
the rest will simply fall onto the system,
the system will be able to do the rest.
Anyway, so you have these things,
you can take screenshots,
you can start capturing keystrokes,
stop capturing keystrokes.
I don't know,
you can do pretty much whatever you want,
you can list accessible desktop and
Windows stations, well, that's very nice.
System information,
this will list information on
the current system, so not a bad idea.
Shell, we have already used shell,
drop into the system command shell,
which means you get the CMD in Windows,
practically, a CMD prompt in Windows,
although the tab does not work there.
I'm not sure if reboot would work,
I think I've tried it before,
but it gave me some errors.
You will need to use shutdown space /r
command in order to reboot the system.
ps will list the running processes.
And up here, where is it, so
I would suggest just taking
a look at all of these commands.
The text for them is not that long, just
go ahead and read through all of them,
if you can, go through all of them,
at least go through a few more
than we will use in this tutorial.
Just to get an idea of what
this thing can actually do.
Here, you can type in netstat and
it displays network connections,
so you can see what they
are doing on the net in real time.
Which is very nice.
As you can copy that, as you can pretty
much copy those addresses on to your
machine and you can see which sites are
they visiting or what they're doing there.
As opposed to having,
as opposed to running a remote desktop,
which is highly inefficient.
Here you have some simple
file system commands,
I'm pretty sure that some of
them won't work, but most will.
And up here is the background,
which we have started.
So, if you type in background,
it backgrounds the current session.
Let's just go ahead and do that.
Please, I cannot stress how important
it is that you take a look
at some of these commands.
They are very simple to understand.
You won't need to bash your head against
the wall to figure out what they do.
You just take a look at them and
type them in, so for example,
to background a session,
you type in background.
It's the same principle.
I don't think that you actually need
to use run, that was my bad here.
But just rather instead type in a command.
Before I type in background,
I'm gonna type in getsystem.
And this is gonna fail.
I have a bad idea.
Yep, there we go.
Operation failed.
The environment is incorrect.
For shell command, you just type in shell.
And it puts you into a CMD,
it gives you the command prompt.
And let's see,
do we have any elevated privileges?
Even though the getsystem command
did not work out to the best, but
there was still a better way to
check this, just to know for sure.
Because these things tend to bug out.
I mean, this is a reverse shell,
so don't expect perfection.
cd into Windows.
Tab doesn't work here.
See, if I press Tab,
it just keeps on jumping.
System32.
And, nope, cd Windows/System32,
am I right now, okay, there we go.
Now we're gonna try to make a directory
here, so mkdir test, does this work?
Uh-uh, nope.
mkdir test, Access is denied, I cannot
make a directory here, so proof enough.
Anyway, we're gonna now background.
And tab does work here
to finish your commands.
Backgrounding session 5, and
you see it exits out of the Meterpreter.
It doesn't exit out of Meterpreter,
but it puts into the background.
And in your foreground is your msfconsole.
Now, you can type in sessions dash help to
get a list of help commands for sessions.
You can also type in session -l to
get a list of running sessions.
You can have pretty much
as many as you want here,
as many as your system can handle.
To get back into a session, type in -i and
type in the number of the session, the ID,
press Enter, and there we go.
We are once again into
the Meterpreter session number five.
You can again type in background and
put it in the background,
remain where you are.
And the msfconsole from where
you can do various things.
Now, I have decided to use this one,
and you see,
I've described it here,
ask for privileges.
Now, there are numerous ways
that you can attain elevated
privileges on a remote system
upon opening a Meterpreter shelf.
The best one in my personal experience
is to simply ask the user for
the permissions.
If they don't give them to you
the first time around, I don't know.
Wait a while and then ask them again.
And if that doesn't work, I don't know.
Wait a while, ask them again.
Eventually, they will click,
more often than not, yes.
I don't know why, but
such are the things in Windows.
You don't need a password.
You can just click Yes or No and
you have admin privileges, which is
fascinating to me, to say the least.
Anyway, before I use that exploit,
I'm gonna type in use post, so
post exploitation, windows.
Yes, display all 149.
And anyway, you got here escalation, so
you can gather credentials,
different types.
But, okay, so
you can even have a keylogger here, but
you don't really need it.
If you have an Meterpreter session,
you can start it from
the Meterpreter session immediately.
Rather, instead, I want escalate.
So, there's more if you just
wanna take a look down there,
it's like 149 things there.
So use escalate.
Press tab.
Excellent.
So we got, like, drop link, getsystem,
golden_ticket, screen_unlock, kbdlayout.
Actually, I don't know what this one is.
Anyway, you can use getsystem as well.
That one is being used by your
Meterpreter if I'm not mistaken, but
that doesn't always work.
That's why I said it's
the best thing you can do.
I just wanted to show you some other
ways of escalating privileges, so
you can pretty much use any one of these
in pretty much the same way as I am going
to use this one.
There is little or no difference.
If you get stuck somewhere,
feel free to ask.
So use exploit/windows/local.
And what do we got here?
Still too many.
ask.
Excellent, so
now we have entered this exploit,
and for this exploit,
you type in show options.
And I have configured this to session one,
as that is what is was previously,
you only need to configure session one.
Payload options, that's already
configured, so you see, it's using
Windows Meterpreter reverse_tcp,
the one that we have used previously.
What you need to do is
just change the session.
You won't immediately get this, I think.
You need to set the session.
This is from my previous session.
So just type in set session 5.
Excellent, so show options.
Excellent, so it's session five, and
these things are loaded accordingly.
Yes, they are the same, but I was just
doing some testing before this, and
just testing out will it actually work or
not, and how it would actually work,
how it would look like,
just to bring you guys quality content.
Anyway, now that we have this done,
you just type in exploit, and
it's gonna transmit a signal.
[SOUND] There you go,
not sure if you heard that.
If we open up our Windows machine,
you see User Account Control.
So you're basically asking the user for
the control.
If you want it, sure, type it, Yes or No.
But even people sometimes by
mistake will click Yes, and
then they'll be too lazy to reverse it or
anything of a kind.
That's just one of the ways, but
there are others, as I have showed you.
You can use them in pretty
much exactly the same way.
Now it says Meterpreter session 6 opened,
it has opened up a new session, and
this Meterpreter has elevated privileges.
Let's see if that is true,
getsystem, what, get me help.
Yes, of course.
Exit.
Get.
Okay, got system via technique 1,
it does actually work, no problems.
And now we can do shell, and see, can we
actually make a file in Windows\System32?
Apparently, we should be able,
so mkdir test.
Test has been created.
A subdirectory or
file test already exists.
Okay, fine.
mkdir test1.
So it does actually manage to make it.
So if I type in del test.
Are you sure you want to?
Yes, I'm sure.
del test1.
Sure you want to do that?
Yes.
So we can manipulate files in System32,
which means we have
pretty much full control.
If we can place files and
run them from there,
we are omnipotent,
pretty much, on the system.
Anyway, let's go ahead and exit this,
clear the, not exit, but background.
Clear the screen.
Anyway, that was one of
the processes which we could've used
to elevate privileges, but there
are other ones that I've showed you, and
you can use them pretty much the same
way as I have used this one.
You just pass the session ID and
then just, if there are some other
parameters that are required,
just type in show options like this.
show options.
And it tells you here,
is something required or not?
So it says SESSION 5 is required,
TECHNIQUE EXE.
And this should be configured by default,
but you only need to have a session here.
So you can see what fields
are required and not.
You basically just type in set and type
in the name of whatever you wish to set.
That's it.
No problems there.
However, again, if you encounter problems
doing some other stuff in Metasploit,
please do not hesitate to post it
in the discussion section on Udemy,
and I'll be more than happy
to attempt to assist you.
In any case, I bid you farewell
until the next tutorial,
where we will actually do,
where we will make a persistent shell,
so every time a machine resets, we will
gain an open reverse shell over here.
Anyway, until then.