Warning this video may contain extremely frustrating installation instructions for experienced developers
only it's advise that you install use in cloud 9 to avoid moveless pain.
OK.
Welcome to this video on installing my as well on a Mac.
And again I'll warn you this can be painful.
And this lecture and doing this all these steps are 100 percent optional.
In fact if you don't have a good reason if you're not sure if you should do this then that means that
you shouldn't do it at least not until you get to the end of the course.
Of course if you're somebody who is an experienced developer and you know you want to get this running
locally at the beginning on your Mac then go ahead follow these instructions.
But I would definitely recommend that you go through the course for ninety nine point nine percent of
the people in this class go through the course of cloud nine and then install this on your Mac at the
end.
It just makes everything so much easier.
OK.
So if you're still here though the steps to actually install it are surprisingly simple.
The problem is once you install it you run into issues depending on your developer environment depending
on things like using bash or Z show.
If you have permissions issues and passwords and it just turns into a nightmare a little bit.
Well not just a little bit a lot.
So the first thing we need to do.
Like you said it's actually nice and easy just go to my office.
Q l dot com.
Goes to the downloads tab.
And what you'll see here are a bunch of the basically like the commercial services and Ms.
Q. Well enterprise software that is not free.
We want the community section and then we want the first thing here my Escudo community server.
Then at the very beginning this is kind of just a blurb about it some documentation instructions.
But if you keep scrolling down you'll see the download links.
So you'll need to select the one that corresponds to your Mac.
Depending on how old your Mac is how new it is what version of Mac OS it's running.
All of that you'll have to make a decision but for me it's for first one here so click download and
it looks like you have to type or you have to sign in or create an account but that's not true.
You scroll down and there's this link.
No thanks just start my download.
Of course if you want to you can sign up.
But most of you probably don't care.
So just quick.
No thanks.
Just start my download and I'll see you in just a second once I edit this download time out.
All right.
Now that's completed downloading.
So I'm going to open it up.
Might take a second to open but once it does you'll see a single file inside of this and we'll just
double click follow the steps continue.
Read every word.
This of course I've already done it so you know I know everything it says.
Click Agree tells you one point when 3 gigs of space needed to make sure that you have that available
then will click install.
Then it will ask you for your password for your computer.
Fortunately yes I can use my thumb finger that way you don't have to watch me type my password.
I don't have to edit that up.
It's always a problem.
I don't want people to see my passwords.
OK.
So here's an important part.
I mean this all important but this in particular it gives you a little pop up here that says a temporary
password is generated for root at the local host and then it gives you this password.
So I highly Well I highly recommend that you need to copy this.
Technically if you forget to lose it you can reset the password.
It's just another set of steps and complications.
So copy this.
Save it.
OK.
We're now done installing it.
Move it to the trash.
So we're done with the install but that's the easy part.
Just a couple of clicks.
Now we need to do a couple of things.
The first is startup the server so to do that we go to System Preferences and it should be down here
there should be a new icon somewhere at least depending on how you have your setup.
For me it's about muffed my as well.
Will click on that and we should see my server status you know blah blah blah.
It's the server instance is currently stopped.
There's a button to click to start it which will start it.
And then there's also this checkbox which will address.
Now depending on what you want you can have my s q all server startup every time you start your computer.
I'm not going to do that.
You have to type your password again.
I have like 6 or 7 database servers on here and I just don't want any of them to start up on this machine
at least this is not my developer machine this is what I use for teaching.
Totally up to you.
Just depends on how you're using it.
But if you're just learning my ask.
Well now it might actually be good to leave it on so you don't have to continually started.
But either way it's not that hard to start it's just a button here which will click now.
And there we go.
If you didn't click this or uncheck this you may have to type your password when you click that the
first time.
OK so now what we have left to do is open up our terminal and start interacting with this.
So I'm going to bring the font size up a bit and theoretically you should be able to type my well but
this is where we start running into issues.
So I'm getting this command not found.
And if you get this again this depends on how your Mac is set up in your developer environment.
And this is where it's annoying for me.
I'm using something called the show I'm getting command not found.
And that's because the my Escudo command is not it's not in my path.
So what I need to do now open up my dot slash dot S.H. RC file
and I'll paste this line in here just so you can see it or include this in the instructions for this
lecture.
You can find this on anywhere online it's very common error when people type in my school and you get
command not found.
In fact if we just did that right now and went to Google see depending on what version of OSX you're
running there's all sorts of replies that are basically exactly what I just did it.
In fact that's where I got the wine originally.
It just depends on if you are using bash and if you are then you can use a line like this but essentially
you know there's all of these possibilities depending on your environment.
So I can't cover all of them here but find the correct command for you to run.
And that's only if you're getting command not found.
All right.
So we need to save this file.
Close it down or back to a terminal.
Then the next thing I'm going to close the window and reopen it.
Or you can quit terminal or you can source your profile.
Now what I need to do is try my ask you out to get.
OK so now we have a different problem and this is a great problem.
This is a problem we should have access denied for user Culp's do local host using password.
No the problem is if you're a member.
Well first of all this means that my secure while the command is found it's running but we're getting
a result now.
And the problem is that I'm trying to start my as well and I don't have permission I need to log in
as the root user and remember we save that password.
So I went and copied that password that we were told to save.
It's on my clipboard Now I could paste it but that won't do anything.
What we need to do is run my as well dash you space route dash P and hit enter and it should promptly
for the password.
You can paste that in and we're in.
All right.
So if you get this far congratulations everything's working.
If you didn't get to this point it's likely because of a couple of reasons.
One is that you're still getting that command not found issue.
That one this is relatively easy to fix the problem is you have to be comfortable using your command
line and opening up you know hidden files like abash profile or yours the HRC file.
The other problem you could run into is this permissions thing.
And if you didn't save that password I told you you should save but if you didn't or you close the window
accidentally you can reset the root password.
All you need to do is go online and Google it.
There's a couple of posts online about it.
Basically what you do is you run my ask you about Dash you space route and there's something called
flush privileges commands and you can update your password with a new password.
There's a couple of things you can do like that.
Basically rather than me making a video for every possibility.
It's much better if you just find it out online.
And this is why I recommended that you use cloud 9.
Promise you're not paying me.
It's just that this is difficult especially in an online setting.
OK.
So you might think we could start running some miniscule code if you tried.
Here's something we haven't actually seen yet.
But if you tried this were actually about show databases this would show us databases and if there are
databases it would still show us something.
But instead we get this you must reset your password using alter user statement before executing this
statement.
OK.
So our final hurdle here what we need to do is have a command that I just had on my clipboard but it
looks like this.
Alter user in quotes root at.
And then in quotes local host identified by and then all you need to do is provide a password here in
quotes that you would like to use for the root user for your my s q will install for this server instance.
And so just type something I'm just going to make my own password.
There we go and hit enter.
Oh.
A Michael.
Now if we get the query OK things should be working if I try my show database's command this time we're
in.
I don't get this permissions problem.
Ok it worked out.
So again that command I'll also include in the instructions if you need to do that it's just alter user
root local host identified by password.
OK.
So then the last thing is if you want to close out by the way it's Kamandi which we'll be covering all
of this if you're going through the course of the very first time and this is how you decide to start
will actually go over these commands in the next section when we install everything.
Once we have everything installed and we start talking about mice.
Q Well but we need to be able to verify the install.
So there's a couple of comments.
OK so now if I wanted to try logging in again I shut it down.
It's my as well dash you route dash P and then we'll ask me for my password which I changed to password
to type that you won't actually see it.
But if you type it correctly you're in.
OK.
So that is our journey to installing my s.
Q On a Mac.
Great time.
Hopefully if you got to this point you made it through and everything worked out.
If not if you're just starting this course off I still highly recommend that you switch to using Cloud
9.
Avoid all of these issues and then come back to this when you feel more confident.
Otherwise if you absolutely have to use a Mac we'll try our best to help you out.
Anyway moving to.