A there it's me again it's time for yet another one of these videos.
This time we are diving into Section 3 a really important section.
And yes you could probably say that about everything in this course but this is where we really get
going.
It's really crucial in the last section.
It's true.
We did run our first my su command.
But if we're being honest they're a little bit underwhelming kind of lame.
They didn't do much in this section that actually changes.
We see our first commands around data.
So we'll be able to make a new database or do a database and then inside of those databases we'll start
working with tables which are kind of the fundamental structure in all of school and my.
So really important stuff.
And by the end of this section will actually throw out the entire section or sprinkled a bunch of exercises
around you know commands that will learn things like creating databases using and switching to databases
and then creating tables and describing tables.
So a bunch of challenges coming up.
But like I said this is a really important turning point where we actually get past all the garbage
around setting stuff up installing.
Now we're actually doing real my of stuff.
So let's get going.