Hey welcome to the next section.
So let's recap what we just saw in the last section.
We basically saw how to make databases and then how to create tables which are currently empty to represented
by this box here.
Let's say this is a catch table it's empty it has no data in it.
But in this section I'm going to show you the tools to insert data into the cat's table.
Thank you Blue.
That was perfect.
So we'll see how to do that.
It's a insert command.
So we'll see that and get lots of practice lots of exercises inserting data into tables and then the
other thing we're going to see in this section.
It's not the primary focus but it's important is selecting data back out and they won't remove blue
from the box just yet.
She's very paranoid.
She loves this box.
But the idea is rather than deleting things that's for another time another section.
How can we retrieve it out.
How can we read it or search.
So let's say insert I don't know 10 cats into a box and they all have different birthdays and breeds
and names.
I want to be able to run code like select or retrieve the last five cats added or retrieve the names
of the Russian blue cats or retrieve the names of the the last of the oldest cat in your database.
Something like that she's having a lot of fun in there.
So that will be the goal in this section is to show you those two commands.
Inserting data and then retrieving it back out.
I'm just going to leave her in there I can't can't stand to take her out.
All right we'll end it there.
Blues and during her box.
I am enjoying whatever this is.