OK let's take a look at a potential solution for this people problem.
So first thing we need to create the table using the create table statement with first name as a VAR
char 20 last name var char with the 20 character limit and age as an int.
So let's do that.
I'm just working in the cat app for now.
It's fine.
We're going to do this at the end.
So we'll start off with the create table and we'll call it people
and the first thing that we'll have is first name which is FAR FAR FAR char 20.
Next thing is last name which is the exact same.
And then finally we have age which is an ant and then our closing parentheses.
OK let's just double check it worked.
Use describe people call first name us name age Farje of our char.
It's perfect.
So now we're going to insert our first person Tina Belcher who is 13.
So insert into people and we'll start off.
Let's do first name last name age and then values and we'll do.
Tina Belcher was 13 right.
OK we hit enter.
Just double checked that it worked.
Select star from people there.
Tina is perfect.
Now we're going to insert our second person Bob Belcher who is 42 and my instruction here was do it
in a different order.
So we'll do an insert into people this time let's do it Age last name first name
values.
So age was hired God he's 42.
Last name is Belcher and first name is Bob.
Don't forget our semi-colon.
Let's do our select again.
Perfect.
It worked out.
It was supposed to be great.
So then the last insert we're going to do is a multiple insert.
We have Linda Belcher Philip Fronde and Calvin Fisher.
Oh boy this is going to be a lot to remember.
Let's start off by just typing out the basics.
Insert into people and we'll do this one with first name then my last name and then finally age just
like that.
Then we'll do values and we'll start off half.
We'll start off with Linda Belcher who is forty five I think it was.
And I'll do Comus on the new line and then we'll go with Phillip Fronde
and he is 45.
No.
Thirty eight.
I mean is this too hard.
Lastly we have Calvin fish Jodra.
I'm just going to copy fish owner who is 70 Calvin
fish over 70.
All righty.
And before I forget I need a semi-colon.
Perfect.
Let's do our select star again.
Have to use up arrow a couple of times and we have Linda Phillippe and Calvin Belcher Fronde fish over
40 5:38 70.
Perfect.
So that's it.
And I didn't specify this in the instructions but let's go ahead and delete the table.
So that's a drop table people.
Goodbye to the Belchers and the other two and we verify that it's gone.
If you tried to do select start from people we get an error but if we do show tables.
Now we only have cats.
All people are gone.
Just left with cat.