All right.
So it's your turn here.
We're going to get some practice with it delete.
So we have three different things that like to do the first one is to delete all cats that are four
years old.
So if we look at our data there's only one right now because we got rid of egg.
But I would like you.
So don't just say delete Ringo or wear breed as British Shorthair or ideas one but use age then the
next is to delete cats whose age is the same as their cat ID.
Now I had to do something similar to this with the select exercises.
Now you need to put that together with the.
So in our case it's only Jack at this point so Jack has an idea of 7 and age of 7.
But once again no cheating.
Don't just select based off of name or breed do it the way I specified please.
I mean it's up to you but the way I recommend.
Next up is to.
Oh my gosh.
All cats.
So that thing that I said I wasn't going to do because I didn't want to eat all of our data.
Well you're going gonna do it and then we'll be starting with a whole bunch of new data in the next
exercise.
Give it a shot.