So this is the read solution.
Basically it's a bunch of select statements we're going to write.
So the first one is to select all shirts but only print out their article and their color.
So back in cloud 9.
All we need to do is select and rather than just select star which gives us everything from all shirts
I mean this is correct in that we want all shirts to be listed but we wanted to narrow down the fields
we get which was Article comma color.
And there we go.
Article color T-shirt white polo shirt black tank top white and so on.
Next up select all medium shirts but only print out shirt I.D. So that's all we want.
So let's start off by just getting the medium shirts to select star from shirt wear.
And then we need to do a shirt size equals medium.
Just like that and hit enter and we get four shirts that have shirts heads of media.
But all that we want is everything excluding the shirt Id just a moment ago I think I said it backwards
on everything but the shirt ID which means we need to list everything we want out.
So select article color comma shirt size comma last worn and then we can just copy this from shirts
where shirts equals medium.
And here we go.
We have all mediums and we have the four columns we're looking for which excluded shirt ID sorry surety.
So that's it for the selecting portion to read in our crowd.
Next up update.