So we've covered creating and reading.
Now we're on to updating our shirts.
So the first problem is to update all polo shirts and change their size to be large.
So we'll start by just selecting polo shirts select star from shirts where article equals polo shirt
just like that.
OK so this is what we get and what we want to do is change shirt size to be large.
So we need to keep this copy it now and then will type out update shirts set.
And we want to change shirts size to now be large.
And where do we want to do that only wear article is polo shirt.
Hit enter.
We get three roads affected.
Three rows changed.
Now if we go back and run our same select We should see all polo shirts are now large as we could do
the same thing just to see it in the grand scheme of things.
There we go.
We have three largest now.
All polo shirt the next problem is to update the shirt last worn 15 days ago and change the last one
to be zero.
So we'll start by just selecting that shirt like we did earlier where last worn equals 15.
There it is.
Tank top blue medium last one 15 days ago and we wore it today.
It was a hot day.
Needed a tank top and we want to update it last one to be zero.
So update Schertz set last warn equal to zero where last one is currently 15.
We get one row affected one changed.
Let's do our select again.
We no longer have it.
But now if we say select where lost where and zero we have two shirts this T-shirt that was already
there in our blue tank top we just added.
Perfect.
So the final update is to update all white shirts change their size to extra small and at the same time
change their color to off white.
So this needs to happen all at once.
You can't do two lines.
I mean you could but that's against the rules for this problem.
So let's start off by just selecting all white shirts like star from shirts where color equals white.
No way.
Get rid of that extra L there.
Here we go.
So we have two shirts a T-shirt that's.
It's small and a tank top.
That's white.
That's small.
So we want to change color to be off white and shirt size to be extra small because we shrink them and
we mix them with colored stuff in the washing machine.
So their colors now off white.
So to do that let's start with the first part update shirts and we'll set color to be off white and
then we'll do the second part with a comma shirt size equals x x x or small just like that and then
we'll do our where color currently equals white and that should do it.
Fingers crossed.
No typos.
Now if we go back and select where color is white we should have nothing.
But if we say we're color is off white we should have two that are extra smalls or we could of course
do select star from shirts to check our work.
We have extra small off white X or small off white.
OK.
So that problem is just making sure that you could update multiple fields at once making sure you understood
that.
OK that's it for update.
Next we move onto the delete.