A welcome to another one of these videos at the beginning of a section where I just make a fool of myself
do something ridiculous this time.
We're working with books.
You can see it got more props.
Just really love props on this course.
And they're here for a reason because in this section we're getting introduced to our new data set.
So for the next couple of seconds we're going to be working with one dataset that I'm going to give
you and it has to do with books and books make a particularly good dataset because there is a lot of
data to model.
We've got things like you know titles up the authors how many authors there are things like reviews
ratings page count release dates tons of information for all different sizes of books and giant prop
books medium small books all that fun stuff.
And our back story here to very weak backstory is that we run a small online bookstore and we're being
just slaughtered by Amazon.
So we're fighting back.
The only way we know how much is redoing our database inventory management system so that's what we're
going to do.
We're going to fight back by redoing our database and that will be what we start the section doing.
But then once we have that data in the database we're going to move on to learning a bunch of new commands
and those commands all are called string functions.
So explain what those mean in just a little bit.
I don't want to make this video too long.
But basically they expand our way of selecting data and working with text or with strings.
Really important and kind of fun things that we can do.
So we're going to go ahead and get started.
Oh before I forget this book here it's a very important book.
This represents the book of equal knowledge.
Yeah.
Kind of regret this now but this is the book of equal knowledge.
You can ignore there's a bunch of bugs in here.
They're attracted to the light I can ignore that part.
Our book of equal knowledge doesn't have any bugs in it.
We are bug free.
Anyways I think I should probably end it here.
I'll see you in the next video.