Hello again.
Welcome to the next section.
So first of all hopefully you can see me.
I am wearing camouflage.
I know that I can make it a little challenging but I am here not just a floating head.
With that said this section is a well keep saying important everything is important but this section
is really taking us back to basics in a way we're talking about data types.
So if you remember way back I don't know Section 3 ish.
I mentioned that we would come back to data types.
When I introduced Vardar of our car I forgot to say it and integers are two data types you've been working
with which are great.
They're very useful but there's a big world outside of those.
What about things like decimals.
How do we store currency you know price information where we have information after the decimal.
How do we store things like dates and time.
Well we're going to go things like dates and times.
There's a lot of information that we need to store that doesn't neatly fit into Vardar or integers.
So this section is all about introducing and surveying those kind of different data types and it could
have done this early on in the course but I've done it in the past like that in person and I find that
students get too bogged down just worrying about all the data types when really they need to be focusing
on things like create tables and insert statements.
You know that's the focus of sequel in my essay.
Q Well we can insert or we can add new data types easily.
So that's what this section is.
We have the two we've been working with.
Now we're adding a bunch more a ton of exercises here.
Nothing you know complex with our data.
We're not you know using any brand new data set.
All we're going to focus on are the data types.
We'll see.
In particular we'll focus on dates times date times time stamps.
All of this terminology it gets a little crazy but hopefully we can simplify that in this section.
All right.
See in the next video.