So we saw not equals which is the opposite of the equal sign.
Now we're going to look at.
Not like.
And as you probably guessed not like is the opposite of like.
So just to review.
We haven't used like all that much but it is pretty common.
An important one.
It allows us to match patterns in strings usually so we can do things like select let's do all titles
and we'll just do title from books where title like and we can do things like.
Start off.
How about all books that contain How about books that start with the letter W.
Just like that.
And if we just do w on it's own Remember that doesn't really give us anything unless it's an exact match.
If the letter W. but we use the percent sign there as a placeholder.
And now this says all books at start with the letter W and anything afterwards.
Or we could expand that to be any title that has a letter W..
OK so that's it for review.
That's how like works we match these patterns.
Anything that matches this pattern where these are placeholders that present signs mean anything goes
there anything that matches this will be returned.
So all of these contain a W somewhere.
All right.
So that brings us to not like which as you have probably surmised by now it will do the opposite.
So here's an example.
Select all books with titles that don't start with the letter W..
So rather than the exclamation point equals like we had four not equals.
We just use the word not space like.
And then in this case w present sign means something that has a W and then anything after that and then
we're negating that with not so.
This in effect says it's like all the book titles that don't start with the letter W..
So if we go back.
Recall this which gives us these.
Well actually then we get rid of the percent sign at the beginning.
These are the three books that start with a W what we talked about when we talk about love.
Where I'm calling from.
And white noise.
And if we go and just add an OT now we get all book titles excluding these three.
All right so that's it for not like.
Hopefully you like that rather than not liked it I guess.
All right.
Well let's just move on.