All right.
So I'll start this video off with a quick anecdote.
Stupid story.
I have a course online right now.
It's done relatively well a lot of students and it focuses on a bunch of technologies including H.M.S.
s javascript.
We talk about no genius as well.
Talk about Mango D.B and a bunch of other tools that go along with them and at least a couple times
a day.
You know I get comments or questions or people demanding that you know it should cover ph or should
cover Ruby or why doesn't that cover C or Java.
And those are valid questions right.
People have reasons for wanting to learn different things.
So I'm not trying to diminish their concerns or not.
I'm not trying to say they shouldn't want to learn those.
But there's no way that any course can teach all of those.
And there's no reason that it should because like I said you only need one maybe two.
So the reason I bring that up is that it's kind of a contentious thing.
People especially students when people are learning to program it's overwhelming.
Everyone tells you to learn something else.
It's very confusing.
You know do you learn something that's easy to learn because it's easy to learn or is it better to learn
something that's popular and more people are using even if it means that it's tougher.
You know what's the best route.
And I think the answer is there is a different way for everyone.
It's kind of a lame copout answer.
So when you're making an online course you have to decide.
And what I decided for this course is we're focusing primarily on node and the typical kind of conventional
choice would be ph.
So I would talk about why I made that decision and the first reason is that I personally am not crazy
about BHP.
I've done some work with it some worked with wordpress.
Like I said I used to be very popular.
There's still a lot of people using it but it is no longer the reigning champion of programming languages
on the web.
Like seven years ago it was.
That was the language that you used if you wanted to make a web app.
But nowadays there's so much more competition.
People are writing things in Noad or they're writing them in Ruby and tons of other languages.
Scala closure all these different languages that you could use and they all have benefits right.
They all have kind of they came later.
They were able to see what worked what didn't work where problems were with other languages.
They all kind of tried to address different things.
So I won't go into a lot of the technical details.
There there's an interesting article online.
Is the most hated programming language.
Not that that is an excuse to not use it but it's interesting.
I'll link to it if you want to read about it.
Basically talks about how PDP got so popular back in 1995 when it started and then where does the hate
towards it come from.
And largely the consensus at least is that P2P was kind of cobbled together it wasn't a consciously
crafted as this as here.
Programming Language things are added over the years and there's inconsistency there are some security
issues but you could actually say the same thing about javascript which is a valid criticism that it
was created.
And I think it's nine or 10 days kind of as an experiment.
It wasn't some crazy planned out language and things have been added over the years and they're constantly
updating the specification for Javascript.
So that's not necessarily why I chose to not teach Ph.D. and choose a node in javascript instead.
It's really more about the data that's on this page.
This is from 2016.
It's a stack overflow server they do with how many 56000 coders who answered the survey and there's
45 questions.
So if we scroll down and click on technology and go look at the technologies tabs we can quickly see
first of all it's sequel.
Very popular good news.
And you can see here you have HP which is in 2016 around 25 percent.
If you go back to 2013 noter said it started at 35 percent then went down to 28 percent then up a little
to 29 and then down to 25 so the lowest it's been.
So you can see there are charts online that I couldn't find any that were copyright free essentially
had a license that I would be able to show you the image.
But there are charges online you can see the decline.
It's not a very steep decline but there is a decline and at the same time if we look at no japes here
which is was it seven point five percent now it's going up to 9.9 percent 13 percent 17 percent.
It's growing very quickly in comparison to other things around it.
And then also if you take a look you know javascript does appear as number one which is great because
no genius uses Javascript syntax.
It is javascript.
We'll talk about that if you're not familiar with it.
So you know if you notice a trend down here more people use javascript than any other programming language.
PH appears to be falling out of favor as node and angular merge.
That's kind of the main takeaway trend.
And if we scroll down a bit more we can take a look at the top tech on Stack Overflow see javascript's
up nice and high still.
If we look at trending stuff we basically see that it's all javascript while almost all javascript related
re-act javascript.
We've got node nowhere on here page.
Now I don't want to say that you only pick something based off of it's if it's trendy or not.
That's not the point here.
The point is more that I picked no because it is something that will prepare you for the future and
if you want to learn ph.
There are so many options out there and I didn't want to just make another version of a course that
could have been made a couple of years ago.
I wanted to make the most up to date current course.
So basically you know it's a decision that I made.
There is not one answer.
You could still make a great ph P in my s to of course today I'll probably end up adding a little P.S.
But it's not going to be the focus of the course.
And minor minor thing but it is interesting if you look at your top paying jobs or free stroll down
and look at you know what no developer an average around $85000.
The Capeci minor while $10000 difference.
So nothing.
That's why I chose to do that.
But it is interesting to see.
And then finally if you look at the correlated technologies you can see ph P and sequel there's a tight
correlation there right.
But there's also javascript and sequel which is what we're going to be focusing on and that's becoming
very very popular.
A great combination.
So that's horrible.
So that's sort of some of the data behind why I picked that.
Why I came to this decision.
If you're curious about it.
One other thing there there's a good core post about why BHP is losing popularity why people are trying
to you know and stuff and Ruby and why people are you know down on HP which hopefully the takeaway is
that that's not my intention.
I'm not trying to make Peachi seem bad.
I am just trying to show you another option.
All right.
So thankfully this was an optional video.
You didn't have to sit through this and not that you have to sit through any video but well we're done
with it now.
Thanks for sitting through that.
If you chose to.
Next up we're going to introduce our very exciting fun project.