[Autogenerated] Hello.
I'm very glad to welcome you to the school's eclipse for Java developers.
A.
My name is juicy and you'll begin by setting up a Java A C
development environment with a clips.
The Java I D offer is not that big image of a space,
but we still have three tools to choose from to develop.
Our applications are the first one is called Net Bonanza.
It used to be developed by Sun Microsystems,
which used to Stewart's Java back in the days of it
has then been developed by Oracle.
When over called both the Sun Company and then given
to the Apache Foundation by Oracle, Net Beans is freely available.
It is an open source software very I quality great
stool to build Java applications.
Then we have Inter J.
Developed by company called Jetbrains are there is a free open source.
Apache 2.0 licensed community edition of this tool and an
ultimate version with more features,
more elements in it that is a paying A software.
And then, of course, there is Eclipse,
which is the flagship software off the Cliffs Foundation,
a cliffs used to be developed by the IBM Company and then has been
given to the Eclipse Foundation or wide ago.
Now the question, you may ask is,
which of these software should I choose to develop Java applications?
The question is very complex, in fact,
and it really depends on what you want to do.
And if you want to spend money in an I.
D.
E or not.
Currently, the most widely used is with no doubt eclipse.
It's used by more than half of the Java developers,
which is country more than six million people in the world.
Net.
Baines is used by probably something like 10 to 12% of the Javadi
Ripper's on Jetbrains ER has a share of about 30 to 35%.
Now.
Those figures are not very precise.
It's in fact,
very hard to measure the Rosa and to tell what is the market share off old of those ideas