[Autogenerated] Once we have done that,
the first thing we need to do is probably to create and configure the so
called getting no filer to filter out all the elements from that project
that we do not want to put in the git repository.
This package Explorer view is not the right one to do that.
So we are going to open another view from Eclipse Window Show View,
other filter the Navigator view on open this you,
the Navigator view shows all the Fizer within a project,
including the technical files,
are created by Eclipse and the hidden files that we do not usually
see and we can see that they are 25 on one folder that we want to
filter out from what get will handle.
The two fires are the dot class path on the DOT project,
which are Eclipse Technical.
Fizer under folder is, of course,
the bean folder in which eclipse is going to put the complied classes.
That's what going to right we do not want to under these compiled code using it,
the dot get ignore fied has already been created for us by the beginner.
So let us open it.
The Bean folder is already there,
so we just want to add a the class path on that project filer and we are
also going to add the dot Settings folder that is also created by Eclipse
to stall some information on our project on.
By doing so, you can see that the respect of some file icons have changed.
Now the dot class path and the DOD project fight icons are not
marked with the question mark sign anymore. Only the dot getting no file is.