[Autogenerated] let us see now how to add a dependencies
are toe an existing maven project.
I just added some content here l A service which looks like the service we
created in a previous Majola and also a test class which unfortunately does
not complied because I do not have these Sergi and J Unit Framework
declared as dependencies of my project.
Of course, I could add them as eclipse dependent Caesar,
just as we did in the previous Majola.
That would work.
But this is not the right way to do it.
Since we are dealing with the Maven Project,
What we want to do is to add a J unit and a surge A as
dependencies through the pom XML through the Maven,
a dependency handling mechanism.
So let us go back to the Bomb X and Ella.
Of course, I could type in a directly the dependencies elements and stuff in XML,
but I can also use a maven Add dependency from the
pop up menu of this Palmer ex Mnla.
I am presented with this other dependency pain er with a
search engine here but which is disabled.
Since the index downloads are themselves disabled.
This is the default state of this pain when you open it for the first time.
So the question is, where can I enable this index downloads that is closer.
This Baena, go back to the window preferences here, filter.
The Maidana options are select the maven route optional.
And here we can tell Maybourne to download repository
index updates directly on start up.
Let us apply.
Playing closer.
We can add a dependency by typing in a here J unit, for instance.
Now,
you may also observe that nothing is displayed in this search results window.
Let us cancel this and checked one last thing in the May Virna prefer answers.
Um, here, when you click on the user settings are you have this re index.
But Erna, if you see nothing in the search results window,
you probably need to click this re index,
but IRNA it will trigger the downloading of the
index off the maven repository on.
You will be able to search for artifacts in it directly from a clips.
And by the way, since the index is rather big several 10th of megabyte, it may take a while the first time you download this index