[Autogenerated] to have a look at the state of a given repository in eclipse,
we need to open a special view window show view Other on this
special view is the history of you Open it on.
It opened this history view in the perspective.
Remember that it should try this on your own eclipse.
This view may appear in a different place as this one,
but you can drag it on, drop it just like that to see it wherever you want.
Now there is something confusing with these you is that when you open it,
there is nothing in it and you can click whoever you want in this package,
explore view or in the Navigator view the is to review remains empty.
In fact, to browse the content of the git repository,
you need to click this icona in the history of you here and it
will synchronize with the package exploded view,
for instance, and we'll show you the Comets,
pretending to the elements you have selected in a package exporter view.
So those other comets for your project,
those other commits only for the user class that we created,
and we can see that we have the beginning of the show one
code of the commit the Master Branch,
the head Vietor branch the different commit
messages we have entered a the author, the date, etcetera.