[Autogenerated] So I have prepared here two versions of Eclipse.
The first one is the Java e Neon, our version of Eclipse,
which is the first neon version released.
And the second one is the Java e oxygen to pack agia,
which is the last version off the oxygen eclipse available As of today,
I've also created to short cuts on the desktop to launch.
Those two versions are easily it is very easy to install eclipse.
In fact, you do not need to install it in a windows way.
All you need to do is to open the zip archive you've downloaded from the
Eclipse Website on Copy the content in any director you want.
So let us first launch the Java e Neon.
Our version.
The first thing eclipses asking us is to choose a directory in
which it is going to create the workspace.
Remember,
the workspace is the director in which Eclipse is going to create our
project on store all our directories and files.
Er so let us click OK,
neon is launching a and we are soon presented with the welcomes you
with a set of links to various documentation,
tutorial and configuration settings.
Let us closed is you.
We are now presented with the default Java e perspective.
We can tell that this is the Java e perspective by checking
the top right corner off this you I here.
This is the Java e perspective that is selected If
you do not have this perspective,
er it's probably because you didn't download the right version of eclipse.
Probably the java s e warm.
We're not going to go any further with this.
You I for the moment because what I would like to show you is how things can go wrong on how to fix them.