[Autogenerated] now suppose that we do not want to run
our tests using the Eclipse utilities, but directly by launching maven test,
which is the gold used in a made in space to render tests.
We have two solutions for that.
We can use the pop up menu from the pump filer here, Reynosa.
And here we can execute this palm fighter, which is not really executable.
We, the available goals cleaner generates also is installed on test.
So if we ran a maven test here in the console, let us open this one.
We're going to see the execution off maven test the running of our test,
which is a success.
But suppose that we want to do something that is not
readily available in this menu.
Like maybe unpack agia or maven Deb Roy on the special repository.
We can also create for that a runner configuration honor from
this menu here run configurations here.
We already have the ello service task that we just
executive We're going to create another one for that May
even build a new launch configuration.
Let us create maven a package.
For instance, the base directory is the Yellow Service project.
The goal we want to execute is the package.
Golda, if we want to add to provide, we just need to fit in this box here.
And we can also add perimeters here that does.
Bleier run this coder.
And this time on the console,
we can see that all the life cycle of the maven builder has been executed.
Resource is compiled.
Test resource, Sirs, This compiled test,
which is a success, and then package by calling the maven job begin,
we have created ello service Dash Zero that want the job
in the target directory of our project.
Let us check that here.
Indeed, a new directory has been created.
A Let us refresh the content and the aero service dash 0.1. The job has been properly created in this directory.