[Autogenerated] Since this is aware application,
let us create a first very simple HTML page.
We can do that with the pop up menu of the project.
New.
HTML Feiler This HTML file has to be stole.
The in a very special directory off this project on the Maven Pregnant knows
that it is going to put it in the SLC main Web APP folder,
which is exactly what we need.
There is called This filer index dot html a next.
That does make it an HTML five filer.
This is finer.
We have this fight created here It is in the SRC main Web APP folder.
This is a were welcome pager that has put some
Messager welcome to our new Web app.
Now we have some busy content.
In a way, we're BAP, and what we would like to do is run it.
In fact, it's quite simple to do that.
All we need to do is see,
like the project pop up menu on the project of older
runners and select rent on server.
Do not select a job application because we do not have
any main method in this project, so the breaking will be confused.
It is going to ask us.
Which server do you want to run?
A This application honor.
Of course, it is the Apache Tomcat server that was just installed.
We can see, like the server runtime environment here.
If we add others that they would appear here in this drop down menu.
And if we click next,
we are presented with the configuration of the instance
of Tomcat that is going to run here.
All we want to do is run the maven Web app application a lettuce click finish.
It quickly opens the servers view at the bottom of the screener with a
node representing the Tomcat server that is running A.
If we open this note, we see that I were maven.
Web project has been deployed in this Tomcat server at a welcome page
that is displayed in the internal browser of Eclipse.
We can copy paste this your ella on open it in a chrome browser, for instance for the exact same results