[Autogenerated] Now suppose we want to add a nonstandard The
play Ginna a plug in to the May even build process That is not
part of the standard maven lifecycle.
Very classical example is toe other for instance,
some good coverage and the resists for our test.
There is a breaking for that called Jack a coup.
So letters Adah this begin.
No, the Jackal.
Copra.
Gehna, is this Warner?
Let us Greek.
Okay, this begin has been a data.
We need to add some configuration to eat.
Let's may copy Paste it quickly.
This is this Warner and Executions XML supplement with one execution element I
d Prepare agent and goal Prepare Agent Let us say that for Jack a code to
generate its report we need to first launch maven verify then launch the
special Jack Cocoa Gold Cold Jack Ako report So for that we can create a new
configuration May Vonna new configuration.
Let us call it Jacko Report The base directory is of course our
project The golden We can begin by cleaning the target directory then
a called the maven Very fight fazer then a called the Jackal Co report
Gola apply runner These gold and we can see in the console that
everything is running properly.
First, the clean a maven goal has been colder.
Then the prepare Agent Jack A Gogol under standard.
The resource is compiler.
Test resources test Compile and test major gold in that order.
After that, the package lifecycle phase is colder.
Who is the maven?
Jar goal!
And then the Jackal Co report Goal has been called.
Let us reduce this console.
Check the target.
Subdirectory.
We have this site note that has been created with the Jackal Co reporting it.
Index, Let us open this in our default system editor,
which is the Chroma browser, by the way.
And we have the jackal co report that is displayed in our package.
There is this ello service class and we can check the class with
the code coverage that has been computed by Jack.
Oh,
So this is a way to add a play Ginza to the maven palmer dot xml a
specific play ginza for specific tasks and to create a run configurations within eclipse to launch them