[Autogenerated] Hello.
My name is Jos.
A.
I am very glad to welcome you back to this eclipse for Java developers calls.
This module covers the connection of Eclipse to database servers
with the example off my sequel database server.
What are you going to learn?
A.
In this Majola?
Well, basically how to work with database servers from within Eclipse,
which my look very handy A Clips comes with a sequel.
Play Ginna at least the Java e version of Eclipse,
which is the one we are talking about in this course.
First, you will configure it clips to connect to databases.
Server za.
On the example will be the mice equal later per server.
And in a second step,
you will see how to create a on configure the connection
to a particular database instance.
And then when this is done,
you will be able to create tables other and query for data import and export data from and to your database server