[Autogenerated] let us see now how we can create a several
million project in the same workspace and create dependency
between one project on the other.
And for that, we're going to re factor this code.
This is a service, and we all know that in fact,
the service should have an implementation and an interface.
And the implementation, of course, should implement this interface.
So let us rename this project Re Fekter Rename A Aero
Services that Megan is not too happy because this artifact
should be really called L o service.
Bash him.
So let us do that to have an artifact that matches the name of the project.
This class, we're going to rename it.
And I have a shortcut for that, which is al shift our hello service him.
And I am going to create another project, New Project Maven Project.
Next,
create a simple project group I d organ that Tomorrow and the artifact i d l
o dash service The version Ana is going to be 0.1 finish.
And these ello surveys will contain a a singer into face pack agia ____
that promote that service and creator on interface in it.
Hello, service finish.
Whether this only one method a public string that get message.
And of course, what I would like to do is to say,
All right, you are going to implement a look service.
Of course,
this is not going to combine because the ello service
interface is not in the same eclipse project, and I need to create a dependency from this project to the other one.