[Autogenerated] suppose now that we have some debug
to do in the coda of the serve, let or in any other Depakote off our application.
Using this interface, we can also starts Tomcat in debug mode.
Let's do that.
And to stop the running Tomcat, go back to the service you and launch it.
But this time in debug mode instead.
Off run motor, Let us creek here.
Now Tom Cat is running and instead of running in a normal mode,
it is running in debug mode.
As a stated here,
we can put a break point in a Servette launch this request
once again A a crepe sir is asking if we want to switch to
the de burgh perspective, Let us click.
Yes.
And from now on a We are debugging inside the code of our separate That is,
click if cysts to step one liner here by hovering the valuable We
have the content of the variable We can check the list of users are
Let us allowed this window a little.
Check the different users one by one if we wish and then a run the code
again by clicking the resume er but on here by the way.
All the _______ for the debug mode to control the way the
application is running are here on the task.
Wow. So this little trick enables you to de burgh your application using eclipse.