[Autogenerated] before we move all Now, I would like to show you a second point,
which is how to customize the way Eclipse formats,
your Java code.
It takes place in the window preferences at once again.
A.
You are looking for the format option here.
Java Code style for matter.
Let us see like this Wallner edit the cliffs, building a format here.
Since we're going to modify it, I'm going to call it Josie.
For instance, I prefer toe have spacers instead of tabs a toe,
India and Mike Odor.
So I am going to click here on the spaces only top policy and
choose for which is a nice default value for me.
Let me a plier and click OK, a play in closer.
Of course, this filer has not been changed since it already existed.
So let us deal ate it.
Create another Warner of the same name Hello world,
and check the creation of the main method a click finish. And now you can see that the top character has been replaced by spaces