[Autogenerated] So this is a a maven module linked to this
parent project we're going to skip once again,
this archetype selection, Anna, and creates a low application service.
I am going to call it like that just to make it different
from the existing Aero Service project.
Next, the group idea is inherited from the parent project.
On the same for the version.
Finish this ello application service appears here as a project at
the same level as the Ello application project.
But in fact,
it has been created in a subdirectory off the ello application directory here.
Now we have the same problem off this Java five declaration A.
Let us check the Palmer of this module.
Letters do some clean up.
We can see that the ello application, a parent project,
has been declared as such.
And we only have the artifact i d.
Of our applications of it project that Opie is here. Since the Group I D and the version are inherited from the parent