[Autogenerated] that is configured this project for the And for that,
we're going to open the properties of this project.
I can reach those properties from the pop up menu on
the project Node off this package.
Explorer here at the bottom A.
Oh, I can also use this out.
Enter shortcut, which is sometimes much more handy.
It gives made the following panel and I'm going to show you the Java
bill path option off this panel at first here,
I can see that our project is running using Devon Aina
from the libraries here I have the two options of German
aina the model path with the J.
D.
K on it and the class path.
This is a Jabba nine, only optional.
By the way, if you want to learn more about this model path and class path,
you can check the driver nine model calls available here on per site.
There is also a project abba with another module bath and class
path that we're going to see in a minute and the soul stab that
we are also going to see in a minute.
For the moment,
I would like to concentrate on this declaration of the jury by default,
Eclipse chose er the J.
D.
K.
It is using to rent itself as a job application.
What can we do if we want to develop, For instance, a Java eight project?
We need to change the declaration of the J.
D.
K.
At the project level.
This is going to be done in the library.
Taba.
Off this panel, click the Declaration of the J.
D.
K.
If it's a Java nine a decoration, it will be on the module path.
Here.
We can then edit this,
and we are presented with another panel that would show us all the J.
D.
K that are known a tow eclipse here.
If we click the environments button here,
Eclipse will show us all the versions off the J.
D.
K.
Noser and the associate ID installed.
Jaedicke eight.
For instance.
If I click on Java a C nine here, it shows me that it knows where a J.
D.
K.
Nine is installed on my local machine.
A.
If I click on Java eight here, it just tells me that to range over eight, it will be using Java nine in a Java eight compatible way