[Autogenerated] Okay, so I think we covered the quite a lot of ground.
So let us wrap up this module.
So what did you learn in this module?
First of all, you saw how to configure a maven project in eclipse.
It is rather technical.
There are several steps to consider.
You learned how to choose which installation of maven you want to user you.
So how to configure maven and especially where it
should go and look for its repository.
And if you're in a company environment in a professional environment,
those configuration points are bound to be set up by your team.
We saw how to run a specific maven.
Goals are standard maven goals like maven test or maybe unpack Asia
and also maven goals that are broads by pro Ginza.
And we saw a very classical example, which is the cut coverage J.
Cocopa, Gehna And we also So how toe end Aled, a parent project way.
The several modules, our example was very simple.
We had only two modules to consider,
but it can be easily extended too much more complex configuration.
And with that I think we are done with this Majola.
Thank you for watching it.
But I hope to meet you again in the next ______ of this calls,
which will be about how to handle get from within eclipse. Thank you and see you in the next module.