[Autogenerated] Tom Cata is a Java application and in fact there is a special
mechanism A at the Java virtual machine level that allows to open a port a
special de burgh port that eclipses able to connect to.
So let us do that.
Let us go back to our common light.
Tullow, let us stop our Tomcat.
Katarina, stop and let us run it again with the option Ah, DPD a start.
This option means a Java platform a D burger architecture.
In fact,
it triggers a special options at the JV M level that are fully
documented on this page with the following link.
So if you want to have more information,
you should refer to this page which contains the full
documentation of this technique.
Now, this Tomcat is launched in debug mode,
so Eclipse will be able to connect to this instance of
Tomcat to get some debug information.
To do that,
we need to create a de burger configuration from here so de burgh configuration,
but is made precisely for the beginner.
You want to select remote Java application here,
create a new launch configuration.
Let us call it Web app, Tomcat, the burger Select the project,
which is our Maybourne Web up.
And in fact,
all the other options are selected by default on this pain are correct,
the other one we are going to use and let us adder this debate
configuration to the favorites menu of the debug menu.
So let us supply closer.
Switch to the D Burger perspective of Eclipse.
Click on this D burger button from the toolbar and select Web
app Tomcat debug and see what is happening.
Now The D Back view is connecting to the instance of Tomcat we just launched,
and we have now the list of the threads that Tomcat
has been launching on our machine, So we are not ready to connect to our Web application in debug mode.