[Autogenerated] Once you've done that,
you may need to fix the configuration off this Java may even eclipse project.
There is no error Schoener in this package explore view.
But if we check the properties off this project,
you may see that so many moments are missing.
So letters fix that.
So to do that you need to see,
like the project pop up menu and go to the properties are
optional Java Bill's bath and in a source option here at
the different photos You see, that maven is complaining,
for instance, because the SRC test java is missing.
So letters at this folder create new folder SLC test java next finish.
Now it has been created.
We can also create a cell.
C main resource is our finish and it's all see,
this resource is those are the full standard
folders that maven is using toe work.
A property that is creek Okay,
apply apply in closer and now Maidana should not complain anymore.
The error message that was present on SLC to Java is not here anymore.
So you see that importing a maven Java project from a remote repository is a
lot simpler than importing a plane device you project.
The odds are that most of the time the project you will
need to import are indeed maven project.
The only caveat is that you need to install the right
begin before doing that because it is not present in the eclipse installation by default.