[Autogenerated] Now let us see how we can add external
dependencies with external jars,
a twitch of a project and let us see how we can organize.
I was source code in different directories.
Currently we only have one, which is the SRC directory.
Since we are all serious Javadi proposal, we like to write tests.
So let us create a test for this message Service Gold message service test
finish And what I want to do is off course created test here first I created
it in the same souls directory as my business class,
which is Mr Service and off course.
This I do not want to.
I would like my test to be in a separate territory.
To do that,
we need to create another source code directory
within our message service project.
So let us go back to the properties of our Project Bill Path
option here on the sole stab here we are going to add a
folder in the source for his list.
Create new folder.
I'm going to call it s L C.
That's fist finish and selected as a source folder.
Okay.
And now it appears, along with message surveys slash SRC as a source folder.
Let us Brian close.
And you can see that this associate,
that test source folder is now shown in the package Explorer.
So let us move this class from these SLC directory to the SLC test directory.
Eclipse was kind enough to also keep the package of this class.
By the way, I am going to fix the name of this class by renaming it.
There is a shortcut for this, which is out shift are like rename er and now I can write my test in it.