[Autogenerated] so eclipse on databases.
How does it work?
Let us first see the big picture of the organization.
You know that Eclipse is a Java software on as search.
Connecting to a database for Java software is built on J D B C J D B C.
Stands for Java Database connection.
It is a standard AP I available in the J.
D.
K from the very early versions off the jetty K.
So as a job application,
ANA Eclipse needs a J BBC driver to connect to the
corresponding database server.
J D B C is an a p.
I mostly made off interfaces.
There is no implementation in it,
so you need an implementation particular toe each database server toe.
Implement these jdb c a p I.
So the first step is to install this jdb see driver in eclipse so
that it can connect to the database server you need.
Then, when this is done, connection can be created and used on.
The connection is made of basically three parts first year L and 2nd and 3rd,
a user name and a password to connect to the database just as a side note.
If you're not familiar, with J.
D.
B, C or database of proclamation in Java,
you can check several JD busy courses available here on Parasite.
Let us first see more precisely.
Our things are organized.
You probably remember from an earlier module that all the
projects you can create within Eclipse arsed older in sub
folders off a workspace root folder.
In these workspace, there is a sub folder hidden called dot meta data,
in which a cliff's stalls various technical information.
This is where the J BBC driver off the database that you
want to use is going to be stored.
Of course, several J D B C drivers can be installed within a clips for Instant,
my sequel, Post Gray Secret Server, Oracle Database Server on the like.
So these J BBC driver installation is made at the workspace level,
and this made available in all the projects from this workspace.
Once you have a project that you want to connect to a database,
a particular connection to a particular database of server
instance will based old at the project level.
So if you have several projects connecting to the same database instance,
you want to create one connection per project.
This is how things are organized. Other workspace level