[Autogenerated] For that.
I need to import the J unit package if I am using J Unit once again,
this is done in the properties of this project.
So all center wants again build path here under library tub there.
J unit is not present in the workspace,
so it is known as an external jar or external dependency of this project.
There are several ways of toe.
Add it.
The most straightforward way is, in fact,
to add it as a library since Jay and it is already known by Eclipse.
So all I have to do is click on this J unit dependency here.
Next, select J Unit four.
Here.
Eclipse is telling me that it is using the four the 12 a version of
J Unit four and click the finish button here.
Now, J Unit appears as a dependency of this project.
A play on closer and you see that it has been other
the as a library to this project,
so I can use the well known test sanitation to create dis method.
Let us call it public avoider should return the allure world.
Messager.
Given that I have the message,
service equals new Mr Surveys when I called message service dot Get me surgery.
Let me put this in a variable using the control magic shortcut of Eclipse,
Miss surgery.
Then I am going to assert be care full user,
the ____ unit acid class and not the other one.
That the expected message is equal to the message I get from my test.
I'm going to create a variable expected er this should be a stranger,
and this should be in the world.
I'm going to put this here.
So this tester is a well from test.
How can I run it?
Well,
there is a plug in for Eclipse for that directly
from the pop up menu of Eclipse.
I can run as a as a J unit test and the JN it's plug in will open automatically the J unit view with my test that has been correctly run