[Autogenerated] now that we have the big picture in mind.
Er, let us jump in the live demo of this Majola.
Let us connect Eclipse Toe on existing my sequel database.
Instance.
First win still the J DBC driver.
Then we create a connection and then we play with it,
passing sequel queries back and forth to the mice.
Equal database.
Instance.
So first,
we're going to begin with an existing Java maven project
that I just created in Eclipse Java eight.
Maven project Called user Dash Devi.
It has a dependency to the my sequel connector Java Jdb
See Driver provided by my sequel.
Every database vendor provides a J DBC driver so the first step,
of course, is to find this driver which is most of the time,
very easy.
Then we have a user class which is just a plain Java Bina,
which two properties, name and age, respectively,
a string on an end and then create user class that is going to
create a set of fuser in an existing database.
The database Your area is local host slash your site on the day of a user,
and it's password are both Brewer site, of course,
never use this kind of thing in a real production environment.
Then we are just using playing a J DBC coda with a prepared statement
on a batch to create four users in the database.
And then we have a read user class,
which is just reading back the users from the database.
This database exists.
I have my sequel server open running on this local machina,
and if you want to run this code yourself,
you should have such a server available on your machine.
Installing and configuring my sequel is beyond the scope off this module, but I guess that you're able to do that yourself.