Hi, guys.
OBERING Well, I'm Dhruv Raja, and in this course, I'll cover everything you need to be ready to create
or work upon the latest version of extensions and the old.
Now, most of the material that you will find on the Internet has been outdated due to Google's radical
change from manifest version two to version three, including API structure and functionality changes.
But don't worry, as I said, I'll teach you everything you need to be ready to create or work upon
the latest versions of extensions and the old.
I have talked about this topic in various seminars and workshops and I will cover the topics in four
levels of expertise and I promise by the end of it you will have everything you need to start working
on your own.
One of the primary benefits of extension development is the low barrier to entry.
And unlike other types of software development, which often requires significant resources and expertise,
extension development is relatively simple and can be done by anyone with a basic understanding of web
technologies.
This means that it is possible to get started as an extension developer with minimal upfront investment.
If you know the basics of JavaScript and HTML, you are good to go.
Even though it is simple, it is highly profitable.
And I personally have three extensions on the web store which make more than $3,000 per month.
And a simple search on LinkedIn will tell you how in-demand these job profiles are.
That being said, let's get started with the course outline.