Hello, guys.
Welcome back to a new project.
So in this project, we will create a basic system to block unwanted sites for they data focus.
We will also provide an option to dos for experts to let you through to adverted sites.
I have provided the basic manifest and a basic pop up file, which you must be pretty familiar with
by now.
So we're going to use this as a starting point.
I'm pretty sure you must understand what all this stuff means.
But if you don't, you can just look at the previous projects and you'll be ready to go.
So.
Here we have used the starting point.
Now let's upload our extension.
As you can see, our study help Ascension is running.
Now let's see what we have to know.
We go up to the corner and this is our ascension.
We've been at Ascension so that we can access it when we want.
Uh.
So when we click on it.
So this is what we have written now.
It's pretty basic HTML and we haven't written any actual JavaScript code right now.
So we get started out right away.
You can have a quick look at our manifest.
We have other achievements and we have our source folder and assets include everything, including icons.
So let's get started.
I will provide the GitHub folder as well.
So in case you want the starting code, you can access it as well.
I'll also provide the finished code so you don't have to worry about anything.
So I'll remove this high property because when I open my pop up, it makes it bigger than it needs to
be and said, what we can do is.
Yeah.
Yeah, that looks better.
But does it do anything because we have it written in the code.
So ready to specify essentially a script that will do something interesting.
Let's specify our script tag.
And yeah, now let's add the JavaScript file.
Up one level into our source folder and we'll call it toggle notice.
So those two dots, two dots are important to say that we are it is one level up in the file hierarchy.
You must know this by now.
But even if you don't, I've just got it up for you.
So we create a JavaScript file together.
JS.
So JavaScript, you must be fairly familiar with the Vero, but if you don't, it is a scripting language
which is like the muscle for any website or any extension that it uses.
So you'll notice the pop up.
You have a button and the button will listen for an action.
So will want to specify what you want to do when that button is clicked.
So the first thing we need to do is we get a reference to our element.
So let's call it toggle button and we'll call this one down here mode level.
And you'll notice that we don't have a specific type here because that sort of script works.
So consent means that it's not changing.
So if you can make something more subtle, it's usually a good idea to use cones instead of lit.
So let's get document.createelement by ID, and now we specify what the element of that idea was and
it was toggle button.
So essentially what we're doing here is we're saying document, get, element priority.
So access the document and get the element which has the ID toggle button.
So we'll do the same thing down here.
And now we have mode level.
Now we have reference to both those variables, both those elements.
So let's create a variable called study mode and set it to false, which will specify whether study
mode is on or off.
So what you want to do is when that button is pressed, we wanted to do something.
So we'll create an image listed for that button, which we triggered when we click it.
So our event listener.
So it's a click event and after that he will specify what it will do.
So now we'll specify our function on what we want to do when it is clicked.
So let's start with the function keyword.
Let's click handler.
I can't think of any parameters that we need to add right now.
Let's include one parameter which includes details of the event.
But we can leave it blank right now.
So.
So we want to set study mode to whatever it currently isn't.
And we need to find a way to store this.
So Chrome has APIs that lets you access storage within Chrome itself.
If anyone has worked with asynchronous functions before, you know that it's a little bit tricky because
you don't have access to the results of those functions right away.
So
there a lot of synchronous code in Chrome, but there is also a lot of asynchronous code.
So accessing storage and writing storage are asynchronous functions.
So it will take us first.
I was news and then it will come back to you.
So storage.
So what did you want from here?
So we can specify same process which will be sent across all Chrome devices for the same Google ID.
So we can set or we can get.
Right now we can we want to set our study mode.
So.
These two properties you want in here?
So we can either specify an object or we can specify a callback function.
So very exciting things here.
We don't really care about what we want to do.
Like, we can log console if you want to, but we don't necessarily need a callback function, right?
So we just specify the object that you want to set.
So we set the key to be the mode and we're going to give it a value whatever study book currently is.
So notice that in the manifest we specify everything as a string here.
We don't have to do that if you're writing an object like this.
If this is a variable, it would be trickier.
But since it isn't, we can just write it without a string.
So we went ahead at the dart and.
Now we want to update the label in the pop up that tells us what is currently on or off.
So we'll set up a date label.
We can call or click harder here.
So click.
Here is a callback function.
So we are passing it as an argument.
So we don't need a parenthesis here.
So another thing we can do is we can just write the function in place here.
So we can just put it here instead of specifying the function because we don't have to use it again
and again.
So we don't even have to name it anymore and we can take this out.
Okay.
So we have a function here.
We need to specify the update level function that we have called.
We don't need a parameter in here.
What we actually need to set this mode label and we need to set its value to text value to.
So ready to change it to the same prefix that we had previously.
And then we're going to concatenate some things in here using a ternary operator.
So if study mode is on.
Then we're going to put it on.
And if it's soft, then we're going to put off.
So
and then will put an exclamation point.
So we got our day table here.
So we'll call it a date label once at the very bottom, which means page pages being brought up for
the first time.
We want it to show the steady mode of.
So when the script is read for the first time, we want to update it.
Let's test it and see if it works.
The extension is already loaded.
You can always remove it and add it again if there is an issue or you can just click the refresh button.
So the planet and open it.
So I started with this off by default.
And you can see that what we did is working just fine.
So we also set the value, but we didn't get the value, which is something that we should do right
now.
So we're going to get what are our values currently in study mode.
So we often open it previously said it to be true.
We want it to be true when we open it now.
So we said, So start, get.
And we have the same two parameters here, the object and the callback.
So what do we want?
And once we get it, what do we want to do?
So we get the mood key and it has to have a value.
So are different values going to be false?
Function has to have a parameter called result.
And this is going to hold the data about.
What do we do now with a desert so sturdy moat is equal to desert mode.
So desert holds all the values that we qualify for.
And then we get what the value we want.
So which is food.
So we are willing.
So.
This function will take all of its time, get it things and then it will update it.
So it is asynchronous.
So that is why we have to put stuff in the callback and not in a normal function.
Because it will work after we have retrieved our data.
So we are getting some of this.
Let's see.
Oh, I didn't put sink here.
You have to.
What kind of stories it is?
So we saved this file.
Clear and very fresh.
So starting this off by default.
And then we turn it on.
Let's leave it on and close the pop up.
Now, if you open it again, it gets it from storage.
And so we can see that it is on.
So we can close and open it and it will stay.
So this is persistent storage.