So without wasting any time, let's get into the coding part.
I have already opened the empty folder in VTS code and you can see that the folder name is project.
So now first of all, we have to create the manifest JSON file in Manifest or Jason.
Our whole data of the extension is there.
So what files we are going to be using and all the information about the extension will be in the manifest
audition file.
And this one is the most important file of the Chrome extension.
We have to create this manifest or JSON.
First of all, we have to mention the name of the extension.
Then its version will be, let's say, 0.1.
Then you have to mention a description about what this person will do.
So for particular widows, it will show.
You will be able to see the widows and you will be able to choose the active tabs and manage those tabs.
So we are the manifest version.
So we are using the latest version, which is the manifest version.
So we have to use our service worker here.
So instead of background, we are going to use the service workers, our service workers backgrounds.
And after that, here we have to mention the permissions.
And now let me tell you what is a service worker.
So this service worker will be independent of all the tabs and webpages as we have used the background
or JS in previous versions.
You can understand that this will run in the background.
So we have the background key.
And for that background we will have a particular service worker.
And now we can get all type of permissions.
So we have to pass that in the array.
So permissions can be tabs or it can be web URL or it can be downloads.
You can ask any type of permission you want.
You can ask for storage permission as well from this.
But for now, we are just going to use tabs here.
So now the last important thing, we have to mention the actions as well.
But I will tell you about this later as to why we need the action here.
So first of all, let's add the content script.
So that will depend upon the particular web page and the particular tab.
So this will manage all the front end, all the DOM manipulations.
So as you can understand that this content script, so it will manage all the content of her Chrome
extension or the web page so we can add popups here.
So what is a pop up like when you click on that particular extension?
So one web page will open.
One page will open.
So let me show you.
So we have this extension, React Developer Tools.
As you can see, this is the pop up.
So as you can see that this page doesn't appear to be using that.
So this pop up is there.
Now, this pop up is here.
So this is the content script.
And that is a default pop up.
So it can change automatically according to the content script.
Now will enable this fun.
And you can see that here it is not having any pop up.
So that action is for the pop up.
And then we have the content script as well.
So content script is to manage everything, but here it is taking the help of dev tools.
So that's why it is not having any content script.
Okay.
So that just means we have matches here, right?
So we can have many content script.
Some matters.
Much as we can.
They present the US in which this transcript will be injected into.
So I mentioned here all the URLs.
So that's why this code will be inserted into all the web pages.
And here we have to mention all the kinds of JavaScript files and how it will run.
For example, this will detect documents start.