So this is a starting template.
I have three images which should look a little bigger.
But we also use for the extension icon.
So I'll make a file manifest or Jason.
As I've covered in the previous videos as well.
This is the file that contains all the metadata about our extension.
So let's give the name color picker.
Okay, So our version is, let's say 1.0.
You can put anything.
It doesn't matter.
But the manifest version is important and we are working upon the latest version.
That is version three.
Now we have our background.
I've already covered.
What background does it contains?
Our service worker.
So let's make ourselves a soccer file.
So let's go to the browser and manage our extensions.
We have selected developer mode, which you need to upload your extension directly.
I will teach you how to publish a sentence later on.
So you turn on the developer mode.
And you click on Lord and Bag and then you open the folder you want.
So.
As you can see, we have had extension here.
It is the unique idea of extension and service worker.
I've already covered what it does.
If you have any doubts, you can look up it.
Look it up in the previous videos.
So let's give a custom icon.
You go to the manifest and you add a property of icons.
And you can give icons for different sizes.
I have added those icons in below in the description.
So we have and we did saw different sizes.
So now you can see that when we refresh it, we see the icon.
So let's refresh it.
Now we can see a little bit good, but it is not clickable right now because you have to do some more
work before it becomes clickable.
Let's go to manifest.
We have to add a property of actions.
Default pop up.
We have had undeclared power before.
That's why it wasn't clickable, because there was the issue upon clicking.
Now that we have added a pop up, it should become soluble now.
We create this HTML file for the popup.
So we have added a pop file.
Now alerts are a JavaScript file.
So let's see what our Pop-Pop does.
So let's refresh it.
So let's see.
It's labeled, right?
So let's see what the issue is.
Okay, so this cog icon denotes that this is our service worker.
So it's efficient.
And now you can see, like goodness, viewable and clickable.
Right now, don't worry about colors.
That's a different extension.
I have Color picker is our extension.
So when you click on it, you can see the color picker, the Ashford tag that I inserted.
So.
You could see that this these pop ups, which almost every extension has, these are these pop up table
which you can notify in actions.
So welcome to my color picker.
So we have our button class.
Change color between.
Pickle.
So let's make a div.
And let's give a class to this div and selected colored.
So we are going to show the selected color inside this div.
Let's make a span and give it a glass.
And we will show the color in this pan.
So let's name it Color grid.
And we then need this pan to show the hex value of the color.
By default, it will be empty.
So let's refresh it and let's see.
Okay.
As you can see now, we have our button here.
Or let's style it a little.
So, yeah, we have declared a stylesheet pop up dot CSS.
So we select the body first.
So since this is a pop up file, we are talking about the body of the pop up and not body of the webpage
contents, which will deal with the body of the webpage and pop up will deal with the body of the pop
up.
So we have our background color.
So let's make a diff here.
And then insert our code into it.
So.
We have created a different class rapper.
So we have our rapid.
So the first thing that we have to do is we have to sit with.
Text the line.
The text to center.
So let's check it.
So as you can see, we have changed the background color and all the things have come to the center.
So let's click the button.
And now we have our change color button.
And now we have width of 200 pixels and outline none.
Border none.
Let's put some border radius.
For round corners.
So let's do it.
Two peaks just a little bit, and we want the padding to be, let's say, five pixels.
And let's give her some Veronica the.
So let's put this color.
And of course, should we point at.
So now you can see.
So after clicking it, let's say we have a color picker.