Yeah.
So now we have our script file.
So let's get the button first.
So that we can decide what happens when it is clicked.
So change that obedient.
So let's put an interest on this.
So when it is clicked, we want it to do something.
So let's define what you wanted to do.
So let's log it when it is clicked so that we can know that we can see where it is being clicked.
So let's right click on this pop up.
Click, inspect.
And let's see.
Okay, so let's click it.
Or just a second.
Yeah.
Let's open the console.
So let's see if we are able to log the click.
And as you can see, whenever I click this button, we can see clicked.
So that means our list there is working.
So let.
So let's we want to receive an array and we have to get the first item in it.
So since we're using it, we have to use async.
So let's use the Chrome API.
If it is globally scoped.
So we use Chrome tabs.
So we use the Chrome Tabs dot query API.
So we get the active tab and the current window.
So we are filtering all those taps which are active and they are in the current window.
So let's see.
Okay.
So you can see whenever I click it, we get the first item in that array, which is the current tab.
So we have a lot of information.
So I did this 170 of this tab in which we have opened that extension.
So let's go back to the code.
Okay, so let's do chrome dart scripting.
And execute script.
So this is a method.
And we pass an object inside this method.
So we will define the target.
Storage value will also be an object in which we will give David.
So we are calling this method so that whenever we inject a script into the web page, we can do it using
this.
So we are telling it.
In which staff do we want to inject this?
So we have our tab ID from the tab that we took through the query.
And the function of the script.
Should we pick?
We have encoded it yet, but we will coded our function pick color.
So console log.
The script working.
So let's save it and go back to our browser.
So let's open this console of the web page.
Keep in mind, we have opened the console of the web page and not the popup.
As you can see, we can see the errors because you are in the deaf mode.
So when you click on it, you can see the problems we are encountering.
So our script is not working.
And that is because.
And for security reasons, we have to pass permissions.
So let's define permission.
So let's define this area.
Active tab.
And we have scripting.
If you're ever confused about what permissions you need, you can refer to the Google Docs API.
The official documentation for Chrome Manifest version three.
So let's go back to the browser and let's refresh it.
Of my API and then you pick other.
Now we have another.
So this analyst cannot access a chrome URL.
So we are getting this error because this is our this is not an actual website, right?
It is a chrome extension switch.
So let's go to an actual website.
And now when I use this extension and let's open the console.
So let's see.
As you can see now, it is working.
So this is because we are able to inject script into the web page.
So this code is being run in the courtroom and this function is being run inside a different context.
This is being in this web page, whereas the above code is not being run inside this Web page.
So this very rules are defined above cannot be used in this function.
If you want to use them, then we have to pass these arguments before injecting our function.
So that's how we can pass variables to these functions.
So let's give a dry catch here.
So if we get an error, we can log it.
So now we have to activate the picker.
So we want the APIs for the color picker.
Let eyedropper.
And so they set new eye dropper, which is a built in API.
Let's tell you something about Eyedropper.
Let's Google it.
So let's see, we have some information about this.
So as you can see, it is an experimental technology or an experimental feature.
And they are implementing it slowly into the browsers.
As you can see, the supported browsers, so it is working fully in Chrome and since we are working
on a Chrome extension, it is not an issue.
So you can get a lot of information about it, about how it can be used.
So avoid eyedropper.
Don't open.
So this is how we will activate our rubber and it will return the color we have selected.
So selected color is a weight, not eyedropper.
So console.log, select color.
Let's go back to the browser, refresh it and go to the color picker.
Let's click this button.
But nothing is happening, so we must have some of that.
So our weight is only valid.
So.
So we have to make it async.
Then only we can use a weight.
So let's try it again.
Color picker.
Let's click it.
Okay.
So now you can see it is working fine.
So as you can see, we can pick any color we want.
But as you could see, not just Chrome, we have access to the entire window, which is very impressive.
So we have access to an entire computer to pick colors.
So I will pick this color.
So as you can see in the console, we have the hex value of the color.
So now what we have to do is wherever we pick the color.
So we want to show our color below this button.
So.
You will have to set this color into a different process, which will be done here.
So how do we set this color?
So instead of storing it here, I will return it.
So I will return this function.
And I will add a second parameter of async function.
So we want a result here.
So this pop up is a process which you can see.
And the below function has been injected into the web page.
So these are two different processes, and we want to send up value from the web page to the pop up.
So we want to send it from the below function to the above function.
So this is how we can get the color.
Let's call it injection results.
So let's log these results.
So let's go to console.
It's open the console of the pop up as well as the console after that.
So we want to see a result in the console of the pop up.
So let's pick this color.
So now you can see we have an array.
And in this array we have some objects.
So including the frame ID.
And then we have a result.
And you can see we have received our color.
So.
Let's give a very cost data and we will restructure it.
So if data dot desert.
So.
It can happen.
The case that we don't get any color at all.
So before picking a color, if I press escape.
Escape key.
So if I cancel this, as you can see now, we don't get any color at all, so that will return an error.
So your new check if it is not null.
Then color should be data dot result.
Let's see what the sgv whatever this property is, we want that.
So we want to display it below this button.
So we have color gradient color value.
So let's get these here.
So we'll get this grid and the display document, dot selector and color grid.
And similarly, we can get color value, document, dot query selector, color value.
And now we have to come here and color grid dot HTML or let's rather
we want to change the background.
So let's access tile dot background colors and the color.
So we can assess the style of element this way.
But we haven't given any ccis to the grid, so let's change that.
So now we have to give it width and height.
How it should also be 20 pixels because you want a square.
And they decide about a radius to make it slightly curved to pixel.
So let's check it again.
Refresh and then open it again.
Let's pick a color.
Okay.
We cannot see anything here right now.
So let's inspect and let's see what's happening inside the console.
And we can see the result, but we cannot see it here.
So there must be some issue.
Let's check.
Okay, so there is no edit here.
The.
Okay, so we have color coded.
So the glasses.
Correct.
And the color of blue is correct as well.
So let's.
Give it a read, let's hardcoded so we see if anything is wrong.
And let's log it so that you can see that this block of code is being done.
So let's do it.
And let's open it again and pick any color.
And I've done it.
So.
Okay.
So you can see we did not see the log desert.
So this function did not run this if code did not run.
So let's take a little grid.
Let's take it again.
Suspect.
Okay.
So it is being read and it is available.
So the problem being is possibly that it is probably in line that is far as not taking width and height.
So let's change it into inline block.
Okay, let's try it again.
So let's pick our color blue.
Okay.
So now we can see right here because we have hardcoded it.
So let's change it.
Color.
Let's save and refresh.
The color OC.
So now we can see the color here.
And we can see the background colors.
So that's great.
And now we want to show the hex value as well.
So that's why we have color value and color value stored in our text.
And let's give it the color.
Let's test it again.
So now you can see we can see the hex value as well.
So let's style it a little.
So let's go to the pop up.
Go to the selected color.
So this is the dapper display flex a line items center.
And modern top.
20 pixels.
Let's set the color value.
Merging left.
Okay, so now we want space between the color box and the color text.
Late model V five pixel and looks a different way to bold.
Okay, let's test it again.
Let's pick a color.
Okay.
So now you can see it is looking a bit better.
But we want to add another feature.
That is when we pick a color.
It should be safe to the clipboard of a computer.
So that.
So that we can use it directly.
So to do that, it's pretty simple.
Let's await.
So we have navigator APIs in the browser.
So a weight navigator.
Dart clipboard.
Dart It's again an API which you can Google whenever you want it.
So.
Let's try.
So it can give at a certain time.
So we have to try and catch.
So sort out other.
Okay, so let's test it again.
So selected.
Pick a color.
And blue.
So now if I do a command V, you can see that we can see our color because it was copied to our clipboard.
So Accenture is ready now.