This is an alternate page that we want to redirect to.
So.
Yeah.
Like, I'm sure you know, basic HTML and there is nothing that you need to learn here.
I've just done it the same time and I've added this code again.
I've added all of this code below so you can just access it.
So I like the class attribute.
We want to add some space between the limits.
So.
That's why I wanted the space.
Plus.
If you're confused.
And then I've added some way to control them.
Control the extension, for example, as those button.
So yeah, like if you want to take a break or you actually need to access YouTube for the project so
you can just use the extension whenever you want.
So these are some controls in here that will add.
So we have a paragraph telling us how long we should snooze it for.
And we have put our input where we will put the number of minutes that we want to snooze it for.
And then we have an image down here, you know, just for good looks.
And then we have a script to make all of this interactive.
So let's clear our script.
So let's actually go back to background.
So I'll put one more thing in here.
We want to specify which one else it should catch.
Right.
So we'll create an array.
And it will have all the URLs that we want to catch.
So this was one area of object.
So what we want to match and how we want to match it.
You can match it against their domain.
You can match it against the exact URL.
So right now, we only care about the domain.
So we will use host contents, which means that whatever we write here is anywhere in the URL, then
it will get triggered and we will catch that with it.
You can think of other methods as well.
So let's look.
Instagram, YouTube, Twitter, Reddit.
So make sure it's in an area.
And we are going to add it on the end of the year for navigate listed.
So this parameter is going to be a URL filter.
So do this event or add this listener for certain URLs or events.
So here we will add the others that you wanted to filter, which we're going to rename this as filter.
And we are going to pass this array.
So we want to filter these words.
So whenever we are able to navigate to these URLs, extension will get triggered and our listener will
get triggered.
So let's test this right now.
If we try to go to any of these sites, it should block us every time.
So let's go to other extensions and I'll reload.
So let's try to go to one of those sites.
So, sweetie.
Yeah.
It's -- great.
It's going to the page we want.
For what?
Okay, so it's working just fine.
So as you can see, we can go to any website if we just start part of the blog.
What else?
Okay, let's see.
Look.
So.
Okay.
So that is because we close a tab after before it's updated, but it has nothing to do with the functionality
of the website, so you can just ignore it for now.
It's not breaking our extension or breaking our code.
So what's the next thing?
We're going to get back to that all star jazz.
And we want to handle the snooze button.
So very to get reference to the input so that we can see how long we need to snooze for.
So let's say minutes input equals to document dot get element by ID.
And it's the exact same thing here.
It's always a good idea to label the variable and the idea the same so that you always know what you're
talking about.
So the main thing that we want to do is just listen to the button and do a bunch of things from there.
So we had to put a North event listener.
And then we need to tell it what happens when the spotlight is clicked?
So we write the number of minutes that you want to use it for.
Minutes.
Important value.
But this is going to return a string and we want a number.
So we're going to limit it to a number in this method.
So this will convert whatever the string is to the mid.
And if it is not a number, then it will come to an end, which means not in them would.
Suave also specified a time for this input.
That is type is equal to the amount that you cannot put into any.
Cannot put anything into this, which is not a number.
So that's why we don't have to worry about any right now.
But 5 minutes is less than zero.
For example, if you put a negative number, then inside 2 minutes equal to zero.
So we are going to check if we are past the end of the snooze time.
But if the snooze hasn't finished yet, then we'll just let it go.
So we create a now user data object, which has all the data information you could ever need, including
time.
I will create another date.
And we will discuss what we want this year to be.
So we're going to do get time.
Which will be in the milliseconds.
And then we're going to add 60,000 times the number of minutes.
Yeah.
So we're adding a number of milliseconds, which.
Takes us to the date to which we want to snooze.
Through Chrome dot Storage Dot sync.
They're going to set a value.
So we specify again our object and our callback function.
In fact, we don't even need a callback function right now.
We just want to set the object.
So they're going to call this and snooze.
Because it's the loose ends and we set it to new date.
And you do it here, It's a variable.
So we're going to put it in the date value.
So you would think that if you did this, it would work, right?
But it doesn't.
Because it has some issue with different date objects.
So this is a shortcoming at the storage API.
So instead of using just NuGet, we're going to convert it into a JSON function.
Which converted into this object, which is much easier to handle for Chrome.
So whatever.
Yeah.
So if it's loose for 10 minutes, then I'm in the database for 20 minutes.
Then it will override the previous snooze value.
So great.
Now, what do we need to do?
We need to modify our web navigation events to see if they are currently snoozed or not.
So they're going to have to add extra logic in this.
So the first thing that we need to do is we need to check if we're in study mode or at all.
So we only want to do this stuff when we are in study mode.
So.
So these are great.
And we're going to get the mode where we put our study mode values.
So the default value will be false because if we haven't stored anything, then we will get false.
So after we get this, what do we want to do with it?
What you want to do is that we want to do details parameter in here.
If details dot mode.
And it is a boolean, which is either true or false.
So f side mode is on, then we want to see if we have to block them or not.
If it isn't on, then we don't want to do anything at all.
So we need to get us straight.
So again, we need to access chrome footage for that.
We are getting a hard and snooze.
And by default.
What would you put the default value?
They could put it.
That would be better.
So their default value is nil.
If you cannot get any date.
So if you put details in here, we'll have to we'll have a lot of variables with with the details.
So we need to change the variable names.
Let's name it more details.
And we'll call it a snooze.
Details.
So.
So the first thing that we need to check is if those three days is equal to null.
This means we have never snoozed.
In which case we have no problem.
Or we want to check.
If.
If the if the snooze date is less than the current date.
So the conditional first text, if we have a smooth straight line at all or if there is a smooth detail.
So we have to convert it back into a date and.
Right.
If you remember, we put it into JSON format.
So I'll convert it into a date first and then I will check if it is less than the current date or not.
If it is less than means, we still want to block it.
Pardon me If the date is less than that means that there is still some time remaining for this move.
So we want to just let it go and we don't want to block it.
So chrome dot tab sort of date.
Again, we update the tab just like we did before.
And you have to wait for it to finish since it is and is your greatest function.
The URL filters at the bottom.
Okay.
So let's go ahead and test it.
We'll deal with that extension.
Let's start with starting this off.
So let's go to YouTube.
I say the word is off, so we should not catch anything.
It's working.
So let's toggle it on.
We can't.
So that means that our extension is working fine.
Let's try to sit here for 1 minutes.
I'll click the mouse button.
And that will save it to storage.
So let's go back to YouTube.
Study mode is still on.
Oh, no.
Let's check if there are any errors.
Cannot read properties of null.
Let me see if I typed something incorrectly.
Well, I don't think I call it snooze button.
That's why I called it Snooze.
I'll change it to snooze button.
And.
Yeah.
So that should.
Let's go back.
So let's reload the extension.
So let's block it for one minute.
Let's check the console to see if there were any errors.
This time, no errors.
So let's try it now.
Go back to YouTube.
And it's going to let us through.
So that date has been saved.