So
I will now tell you how you can add the up pop up as well.
So but first, let's check the background file.
And then here we are going to write Indexed JS.
That is for the content script.
So here we are not going to write a thing for now.
Let's go here.
Now, simply go to the browser and go to the Chrome extensions.
So this interface will be there.
If you are not getting this, you can just click here, go to settings.
And under that, just click on this extensions view.
Now, now, here what I'm going to do is that you can see the developer mode.
So now we have to load the impact instance and just click on the developer mode.
And you can see the load and packed option.
And now you can see that I am under the folder.
So you can choose your folder here.
And you can then upload it so you can see that we have to manage tab extension version 0.1.
So this extension allows you to manage your tabs.
Everything is coming there.
So now you can see that we have the inspect you as well as we are under the development mode.
So you can see that the service worker and you can see that we have the unpacked extension sign as well.
So now that it is already enabled, let me pin this here.
You can see that we have this fun upon clicking on the icon.
But it can't change the data.
Also, we can manage our extension.
No, but I will inspect this.
You can see that.
Just go to console.
And in the console, nothing is coming because we have loaded the extension successfully.
But we don't have any errors.
But we haven't added in the content script yet.
So all the things that are also in the console or in the particular web page that will be done by the
content script, which will be injected into those web pages and all the other background functionality
will be done by the service worker.
So now let's move forward and let's start creating an extension.
So before that, let's install this pop here.
Let's show one pop up page so that we can create the user interface first.