Hi, guys.
Welcome to level two.
I'm glad you made it.
It's completely reasonable that you might have some doubts at this point.
Like, how do I use a service worker or anything like that?
But don't worry, that's completely reasonable.
And as we keep progressing in this course, everything will become clear.
So just stick with me.
Even if there might be some doubts in your mind.
So now we'll start Chrome APIs.
So water from API is.
Simply put, they are APIs that allow extensions to interact with the Chrome browser and perform various
tasks.
So they are an essential part of the Chrome extension ecosystem as they provide the tools and resources
that extensions need to interact with browser and web pages.
There are many different Chrome APIs available and they can be used to perform a wide range of tasks,
such as modifying the appearance and behavior of web pages.
The Chrome APIs provide access to the DOM of web pages, allowing extensions to modify the content and
layout of pages, or to add new elements.
Interacting with the browser's runtime and storage.
The Chrome APIs provide access to the browser's runtime and storage, allowing extension to store and
retrieve data or to interact with the browsers lifecycle.
The Chrome APIs also provide access to tabs in the Chrome browser, allowing extensions to create,
update and close tabs or to navigate to specific URLs.
Also, the Chrome API provide tools for intercepting and modifying network requests made by the browser
or web pages, allowing extensions to block or redirect requests or to modify the request or response.
This is precisely how ad blockers work.
Also, they could only be provided tools for sending and receiving messages between the extension and
other components, such as the background script, content scripts or other extensions.
So to use the Chrome APIs, you need to specify the APIs that the extension will use in the permissions
field in your manifest file.
For example, as you can see, tabs and web navigation and storage are APIs.
Also, when you want to use an API, it will be very similar to using an in-built function in JavaScript.
That being said, in a fit theory, let's get started with some coding.