Well hello there, Mark Wilkins checking in.
How are you today?
Ready for more security operations?
I hope you are.
That's what we're talking about in this module,
securing core AWS infrastructure, looking at it from the security point of view.
Now this course, AWS Security Operations,
is looking at everything to do with Amazon hosting your
workloads on Amazon from this security perspective.
The first module we took a look at managing access control,
this module looking at the core infrastructure.
So if you haven't done the first one,
you probably need to go back and look at that module as well.
But you can do them in any order, that's the beauty of our digital platform.
So welcome aboard, let's get started.
So first of all, why have a course focused just on AWS security?
After all Amazon is a huge product,
there are so many different ways you could look at Amazon,
but at the end of the day, it's hosted in the cloud,
there's a little bit of control that is held by Amazon and so we have
to make sure that the security is set up for this hosted service
because it's not inside our company walls.
We have to rely on Amazon and we have to make sure we secure all of our
bits based on the compliance needs of our company.
Now security is still, as I like to say,
25/7 in the cloud because it's always on and security can be solved,
but then new problems arise and you have to solve them.
So it's something that we have to keep on top of and if you're looking at this
from the point of view of doing a certification say for architecture or sysops
or maybe the new security certification itself,
you really want to have a good handle on the security offerings at Amazon.
Now let's start off with a saying from Bruce Schneier.
Now Bruce Schneier is a computer expert in the area of security and
cryptography and he's written a number of different books on what to do
with regards to security and what we don't do,
and one of his favorite sayings is "the user is going to
pick dancing pigs over security every time.
" I might say the user is going to pick cats, but we get his drift.
Now this course is going to help you with that with AWS infrastructure core
security and a working knowledge of AWS doesn't hurt,
but it's not essential, I'm not assuming anything with this class.
But we're going to move along at a pretty good speed.
This is a very well documented product and we can't cover
everything in this class and I highly recommend that you
bone up on the documentation, which is never ending from Amazon.
So the topics in this module,
we're going to start off looking at the security aspects
of EC2 instances or virtual machines.
We'll then take a look at a couple of different versions of these instances,
they could be dedicated or it might be actually the complete host.
We'll then take a look at the Amazon machine instance, what exactly is that.
Then we'll look at the security choices for our instances that we choose.
Then we'll look at security storage, i.
e.
EBS volumes, Elastic Block Storage.
We'll then take a look at the network security, the VPC.
We'll also look at the design criteria and then we'll end off with some
best practices when planning our core infrastructure. So we've got a lot to cover, let's get going.