In our first clip we're going to take a look at the concept of identity and
access management and in this clip we're going to look at a few goals of what
identity and access management means to Amazon.
Now you may think of identity and access management as user management,
access controls, authentication, identity management,
these are all terms that kind of mean the same thing,
it depends on which certification,
what level of compliance in your industry you're trying to adhere to.
So number one,
the access that's going to be granted is based on least privilege at Amazon.
We're not giving you Windows guest or you log on as a user and
you've got a bare minimum of privileges,
no you've got to kind of earn all your security with Amazon and once we
grant access we then define what control we have,
i.
e.
administration wise, against the user, a group or the role,
the access to the resources.
This is typically required my most certification standards,
including HIPPA, NIST, FEDRAMP, ITAR, ISO,
there's a lot of different information security compliance standards out
there and they all have a common goal of granting access based on least
privilege and then controlling the access to resources.
Now how do we find out that Amazon is living up to the
security controls that they talk about?
Well the SOC-2 audit will reaffirm that the security
controls are in place and functional right now.
Remember they're being audited kind of 24/7 365 days of the year.
Now when we talk IAM,
it's going to define some of the resources that I want to access,
namely storage and machines, i.
e.
instances, and we start with a policy for authentication.
And we start with the users,
we have to have a user account to authenticate to Amazon.
Or at the very least we need to have some level of federation
where Amazon knows who we are and then essentially you could
look at the IAM as an add-on, okay I've authenticated,
I've got an Active Directory environment synchronized from
on-prem to Amazon and once Amazon knows who I am,
I'm verified, then I can have a policy for accessing the resources at AWS.
Of course I should do that by a group of users.
Even if I have a single user, put that user in a group.
The odds are what that user does, there'll be more users,
it'll be easier to manage at the group level.
Now the users and groups are going to have a password policy,
so this is something that we should consider,
this probably matches what you're doing on-prem,
so implementing a password policy best practice,
obviously.
We then have authorization levels once I've authenticated,
for the users, for the groups of users, and for the resources.
So we've got a policy for authentication,
once we get through that hoop then hey what am I allowed to do?
One of the concepts that's going to be coming up in this
module is the aspect of roles for resources,
how do I manage that resource since it's not a human,
so something we'll be discussing.
So we're going to take a look at the authentication options,
some that IAM participates with,
and other ones are a part of what I can do at AWS.
First of all,
the email address and the password of the first person that signs up
and creates the AWS account will be the root user,
and that's what will be used for authentication,
initial authentication.
That's not what we want to do for our users,
we don't want our users to use these credentials,
we want to have an IAM username and manage that user in groups.
We also, when I create an account, whether it's a root account or through IAM,
there's access keys that are under the hood of my account,
an access key for authentication and a secret access key that allows
me to do things like automation with that account,
access via a script controlling the APIs.
So access keys, we'll expand upon that a little later in this class as well.
We also have key pairs that are primarily used if I'm dealing with
an instance and I have to log on to the instance and if I'm logging
onto the instance for the first time,
they'll be administrative credentials that are set up.
This is the only time that Amazon is supplying credentials.
So there are key pairs for authentication to the Linux and
Windows boxes that are used for the first time.
I also can invoke multi-factor authentication and should invoke
multi-factor authentication for the root account and any user that I
have created through identity and access management.
So when they log on they can get a code on their phone that they
have to enter to authenticate to Amazon as well.
So that's a starting point looking at identity and access management and some of the pieces of identity and access management.