So let's start with this concept of elastic load balancing,
focusing on the term elastic.
So in the cloud, very common on any network really,
this wasn't invented for cloud, but cloud takes advantage of this,
and the idea is that the load balancer is going to distribute incoming traffic,
so requests to buy coffee from Wired Brain Coffee,
we just don't want one web server, we want a bunch of web servers.
How many web servers?
That's a good question,
but the load balancer can only balance the instances that are in the pool,
that have been provided, so in our case,
EC2 instances.
Now one of the features of Amazon is, of course,
balancing your failover across one or multiple availability zones,
or one or more datacenters within the region,
and that's exactly what the load balancer can do.
So the choices, at AWS, we've got two choices.
The first one is the classic,
the load balancer that distributes traffic across the multiple instances,
we've been talking about that.
So there's our instances,
traffic being balanced based on incoming traffic from clients.
This is balancing up to layer 4, that's its job,
and that's as high as it can go in the stack.
Now the other choice is the application load balancer,
and this is distributing application traffic across multiple targets,
maybe not just a web application, maybe an application,
maybe a different type of application than you're thinking of.
So we can set up these groupings of targets and
distribute the traffic across these targets.
This can balance up to layer 7.
Now this application load balancer has a couple of distinct purposes at Amazon,
and we'll get to that.
The key difference here is one can balance IP requests up to layer 4,
typically to a web server, the application load balancer says,
I can do the whole stack.
To reiterate,
the classic load balancer is designed for web tier load balancing integrated,
here's something new, with auto scaling groups.
Highly recommended that you look at the documentation for auto scaling groups.
Again, we can't cover everything in this class,
but one of the key features of load balancing at AWS is the load
balancer can be automatically filled with a set number of
instances as traffic increases and decreases.
So take a look at that.
Here in this class, more focused on the security point.
Now the application load balancer designed for,
as we know applications layer 7,
but for microservices or container-based architectures.
Think Docker.
Ah Docker, Docker is a container service and becoming very popular,
what if I want to load balance multiple containers on a single,
large instance?
Do a little research on containers if that's something
that you're doing within your company. So there's a look at the two options for load balancers at AWS.