So in this clip we're going to start our journey.
We'll look at the security of the infrastructure
that's hosting our virtual machines.
So the design of EC2, Elastic Cloud Compute,
I like to think of that as kind of the Einstein joke,
so typically in the stack we're going to have a virtual machine,
it's hosted by the XEN hypervisor, it's heavily customized.
Xen is a very popular hypervisor that many,
many cloud providers use and Amazon customizes this for their needs,
what they think they have to do in the background,
they do that job for us.
If you're used to say VMware or Hyper-V, KVM, Amazon does this for us.
We start at the virtual machine level in the stack,
below that, that's their job.
And those instances that we can choose are either going to be Linux or Windows,
typically a 64-bit box these days, and this is really cloud.
If you want the shortest definition of what is cloud,
it's Linux or Windows virtual machines hosted in somebody else's data center and
there is numerous Linux distributions and numerous Windows server distributions
and these will change based on the date and time that you're in the console
looking at building something in Amazon.
So for example, these days you could get 2016 server,
I'll bet a year from now you won't get 2008.
What they offer might be different from what you want to use.
So can you bring your own images?
Can you set up a job and load up your virtual machines
onto a USB hard drive and send that to Amazon and have
them load that into your account?
Yeah you can.
Now if you talk to engineers at Amazon,
the feature that they are utilizing when they're designing features for AWS
usually involves the latest distribution of Linux or Windows.
So you could be causing yourself some security problems and performance
problems by adhering to an old version of the operating system.
Best practice is to use the latest version of the operating
system that you're deploying on if possible.
Now we also have images that are loaded for us,
Amazon machine instances,
and we can start with a certain size and usually when you start on the
cloud you won't pick the exact size of instance,
i.
e.
the RAM, CPU and network components you need.
So you can resize these without rebuilding from scratch.
You can turn off the instance, choose a bigger chunk of hardware,
virtual hardware, turn it back on, virtual scaling.
And lastly,
there's lots of choices for the isolation of your company's workloads,
for the security of the instances,
many different sizes and you can choose not to run
in a multi-tenant environment,
and we're going to get into those idiosyncrasies in this module.
Now let's get into a little more design,
this slide entitled isolation security because there is a degree
of isolation you want your stuff to be separated at the very
least by network access control lists.
So let's look at this.
At the bottom you would expect some physical hardware,
we haven't figured out how to get rid of that physical hardware.
I think we're never going to figure that out.
Physical interfaces,
on top of that a special firewall layer that Amazon utilizes,
so they have in the stack a couple of unique pieces that they utilize.
As far as the customer is concerned, Customer A or Customer B,
for example, sitting on top of the Xen hypervisor,
how do they get out to the network?
Well they have to decide, i.
e.
the customer has to decide on the virtual network cards and how they're set up,
what networks they're associated with, are they public,
are they private?
How do I secure traffic with my security groups?
So we've got a stack there that's providing a
certain level of security isolation.
So a little more detail,
the Xen hypervisor is going to run the guest operating system in Ring 1.
CPUs have a number of these modes of operation from 0 to 3 called rings,
so if we're running the guest operating system in Ring number 1,
let's have a bit of isolation by executing the host operating system,
i.
e.
the hypervisor, executing in Ring 0, so we have some separation.
And then we have our applications, which we want to separate even further.
So with our applications in mind, the applications run in Ring 3,
so there's security separation between the host,
the virtual machine itself, and then the application.
So clear separation between the guest and the hypervisor,
so we've got some security separation.
Now each virtual instance has an operating system, you choose it.
So the operating system that you know, such as firewalls,
IP tables, for example,
or maybe specific security features in the operating
system that you might be enabling as well,
just the same as you did on-prem,
you can do this the same exact way at Amazon and that's your
control feature and you're in charge of that.
Amazon doesn't care what you do, they would prefer that it's heavily secured,
of course.
The instances are fully isolated from each other,
Customer A, Customer B, and as mentioned,
the security groups, the firewall, protects the ingress and egress access.
Additional firewall information, we don't get to control this layer,
but Amazon does,
there's an additional AWS firewall located at the hypervisor level where
they've put additional protections to protect the customer.
So in regards to this AWS firewall layer,
well the packets have to pass through this layer from the physical interface,
moving up to the virtual NICs for the customer.
So in effect,
each instance can be treated as if they're on a completely separate
physical host because of this additional firewall layer.
That may not be enough for you, but this is a starting point for AWS.
Now all instances are going to be using virtual disks.
We don't have access to the raw device itself, but we get virtual disks.
And we have a very interesting virtualization layer.
So when shut an instance down,
the storage is automatically reset and the memory is scrubbed,
the memory is not returned to the pool of memory on the physical host
that's available until it's completely scrubbed.
So let's summarize some additional points just to keep it top of mind
when looking at what we do at AWS for instance security.
So available security options for the EC2 instance.
The instances are located, in addition,
in a VPC at the very least the default VPC.
In this day and age it's going to be in a virtual private network
with a customer specified IP address range.
From that network location we have security groups and network ACLs to
control all of the inbound and outbound traffic.
You have to use security groups, it's optional for the network ACLs.
We have dedicated hosts or dedicated instances for additional security,
but you don't have to do everything in the multitenant
environment if you don't want to.
In order to securely connect to our instances we can use on-prem hardware
and set up an IPsec VPN to connect to the Amazon resource.
You have root access to all of your instances and it's up to you to
control that password once Amazon creates the instance,
passes it over to you,
once you reset those passwords only you know what they are.
Now the SLA for EC2 instances is 99.
95% available per region.
What I mean by this is you have to design your DR,
if you just have one instance running and if you have no failover,
you're going to find you don't have much of an SLA.
They're giving you the toolbox so you can make the decisions
on how you should operate in the cloud.
Each instance also has assigned to it a public and private IP address.
When you set up your instances,
you can make these choices as to how you want this to actually be set up.
And we're going to be expanding upon all of these points throughout this module. So there's a look at initial security for EC2 instances.